good morning everyone today is 2020
January 20th Monday three o clock in
afternoon San Francisco time and good
morning everyone
today we we have a lot of tons of things
to talk about we're gonna do Emacs
we're gonna do let me show you what
what's in store today okay so we're
gonna talk for one hour and more than
one hour actually wait what's this web
pack index that's not what we want okay
we got I got tons of let's go to talk
show okay so talk show let me just show
you what's in store today well we're
back notes I don't care about way back
so what's in store today we gonna talk
about Emacs in keyboards Emacs Emacs
live coding eMac this live coding UI
design and art and when we talk about
art it's gonna be lots of stuff okay so
let me show you let me give you a
walkthrough of what's in my tabs so what
is is okay so let me show you one by one
so keyboards second life it is either a
Mac based function that works on string
or region hyphenated words this is about
literature okay
vocabulary okay and then we have Second
Life Alice in Wonderland okay so this
this is Second Life and that's my friend
this is this this girl this woman she is
a friend we played second life together
for four for four years and she's got
she's beautiful Alice so so we talk
about Second Life Chinese there's a
community of Chinese and there is art
this is art okay art is you know half of
art is about women girls beautiful not
just women not old women you don't see
old women in art much but mostly it's
young women look at this look at this
one oh my god gorgeous you know
the eroticism the rape Pross Pasadena
okay this is this is 9/16 why today you
have raped this rape diet a great you
know rape every day that's white white
men's what rape part of it okay that
that's because it's a foundation of
Western society and then we have we have
these Chinese names in Chinese stuff
these are Chinese memes and emojis
fascinating so we have lots of tons of
things to go through and the this Korean
girl Korean girl again
look at her attire what an attire and
women has this kind of attire
one thousand 1 million designs you know
with showing showing showing showing
their body you know 1 1 million 1
billion designs of it why because that
is the foundation of human animals after
food then it's about sex without you see
without these kind of things without we
go is extinct you know that's the power
of these things
but you know modern society you know
they don't know they don't know they
forgot they don't know what the modern
society we have today we have all these
young girls they are doing camps cam
shows did you know good morning Justin
good morning Nanshan Chico sicko and
just Inc happy birthday Justin - so
today's just inspir day so and what's
I'm buying a Canisius advantaged
advantage - silver economic keyboard yay
fantastic so Justin is going to get a
Kinesis keyboard which is the one I use
and I show these a million times let me
see if I can show it again oops
whoops okay I mean let me get it to show
okay so
modify the video and modify it and I
mean just the things
okay so modify that and modify that
actually you can see it I think there it
is so here is here is a Kinesis okay and
I started to use this trackball this is
Oh trackball I don't think it's that
good I don't recommend it okay you know
this this trackball has the design of
this trackball has been 20 years since
2000-2001 or something so I do not
recommend that tripod let's go back
oh and so you can see my bedroom so this
is this is my bunkers okay you know you
just [ __ ] on the floor [ __ ] and toilet
papers that is Sally's life that is my
life for the past 10 years and in fact
I've been sleeping on the floor for 20
years I led a ascetic life no pressure
no pressure for me until until maybe
went where I'm successful who knows when
and I'm gonna I'm gonna die pretty soon
then we have facial expressions now
facial expressions if you don't know
facial expressions guys now human facial
expressions we have actually thousands
of muscles on your face and that makes
up most of the body language even if you
don't know you don't hear what they are
talking about but you can see you can
tell what they are you know their
emotions they are what they are thinking
weird whether they are angry or whether
they are open they are open
to chat or they are open to sex you know
or you know in in cream ales male or
female or if they are angry or if this
is a good time to talk to them you know
facial expressions and and modern
society with with technology we have
these animations you know the animations
they actually capture you know in order
to do this looking look at this you know
it's not now this girl apparently she's
angry you know locate the way in so so
modern society we have technology 3d
animations that that actually capture
the facial expressions you know you can
tell how good is the technology just by
looking these animations because when
you watch these animations if they you
know if they you know if you can detect
emotions or that just like a real person
then you know the technology is really
good so today you know let me tell you
about the story of facial expressions
you know technology we have been wait in
my whole life check status okay I'm good
on this video so modern technology the
you know we know a turn about facial
expressions so properly this is part of
psychology you know psychology study of
psychology and biology and and newest
neuroscience brain science so we we
don't know that you know you know what's
the force behind the understanding of
facial expressions in a scientific way
the force the main force of that is
actually animations the entertainment
industry 3d animations such as those
made by Disney or Pixar
you know because in order in order to do
this animation or Shrek you know there's
an animation check in order to
make a dog or Mickey Mouse or whatever
to show you know realistic emotions you
have to understand the human face the
you know the very exacting detail you
know it takes decades to understand it
then you can try to name then you create
the 3d animation to emulate it so that
is not trivial and so what but one of
the interesting thing is that you might
think that oh the study of human facial
expression is by you know it's part of
psychology or brain sciences yeah it's
true but actually the the money where
does the money came from it came from
the animation industry the entertainment
industry because because these companies
Disney or Pixar they need to you know
they make movies and they make money
money money is talking here so they want
to make money in order to do so they
have to make great realistic animations
and you know that in order to do that
they have to study human facial
expressions to exacting detail you know
so that is how that is actually how
today after 20 years we have animations
that's so realistic you can see all the
nuance nuances and details and it's
basically a cat you know so that well
okay so the interesting thing the point
I want to make is that the fewer behind
this research is actually from
entertainment industry not from you know
academia psychology department that is
interesting because you thought oh
because you know it's part of psychology
or newer numr science or whatever well
actually he's the the fewer of it came
from the entertainment industry movies
and in fact I also want to mention that
in fact that much of AI today you know
the AI technology where do they came
from
you might think oh they came from
academia no that's not true I would
claim okay the fewer of AI technology in
the past 20 years most of it more than
50% of it came from the entertainment
industry specifically games you know
video games you know because just like
just like the facial expression in
movies you know the video games they
want you know the companies they want to
make money so they do games in order to
do get good games you have good you have
to understand AI technology and so
there's this tremendous research about
that so that's my claim okay the more
than half of AI technology in the past
20 years came from not from academia but
from the gaming industry that is my
cream so it's you know that's the point
I want to make this is kind of maybe
it's counterintuitive so BM cosas says
what do you think about Commerce funding
academia what about Big Pharma
developing drugs what can I say about
that you know that's a come you know so
what about commerce you know big
corporations funding academia and what
about big big drug companies developing
drugs so I would say that's natural okay
I I'm not sure what to say about that
but basically my thinking my philosophy
my point of view is that society we need
in short we need capitalism capitalism
is the you know I don't want to use the
word capitalism because once you use
these jargons then nobody has a brain
anymore everyone think about their you
know their perception of capitalism
whatever that means
okay they don't know okay if you think
you know what is capital is
communism [ __ ] [ __ ] go [ __ ] yourself
once you use these words it's this is
cease to have meaning but what I'm
trying to say is that I believe in I
believe Society human animals our
society you know earth the way we grow
is by natural you know free free
exchange of things so and in fact that
that is a root of capitalism okay I
don't want to use that word but free
trade okay basically for example I want
to sell you something you can buy it if
you want to but if you don't want to
don't buy it
that is freedom that is that is that is
the most natural and the most prosper
the the the reason we do things okay
that is the reason we do things okay no
other reason we have each one of us two
things to benefit us okay and only us
basically me I I do things to benefit me
my family or my friends or my my race my
country not your country okay not you
your race or whatever that is a
fundamental nature of human animals you
cannot escape it it's not like oh I'm
trying to do good I'm trying to be a
saint I'm trying to harm no animals no
you you are a [ __ ] okay if you
really believe that you you end up doing
evil things so anyway I believe you know
we so this is how human society works
everyone you just do things to benefit
themselves and if you want to name this
system and that name would be capitalism
okay that's what capitalism is about or
free trade okay so so I I believe this
is the most natural and this is also it
turns out this is also the way for human
society to be the most prosperous okay
the most proper prosperous so that's
that is my that's my belief that's what
I believe that's I think is my
philosophy so given that so so so what
about
corporations funding academia and drug
companies developing drugs
I think that's natural okay that's
that's actually natural and that is
actually good but however I want to put
out some warnings you know some some
some some other points because when
people say that oh you know big
corporations is funding academia or drug
companies of you know funding drug
research what people are mostly thinking
when they ask that question not you okay
I mean in general when people ask that
question
they are implying you know it's kind of
implying or bringing up the issue about
corruption basically you know you have
some big corporations they are funding
research you know all your companies
they fund research about about you know
how about solar power so so obviously
they are going to be biased because they
are going to tell you know solar power
doesn't do think good things you know
the the electric cars does is no good
actually we found by our study by our
research we found that you know oh yo
it's actually more the better okay that
says that's an issue you know this
that's the issue people are thinking you
know with these big corporations they
fund research which in general and
naturally they are biased towards
themselves and that is true I believe
that is true but however we see this
also we have a problem kind of so we
have to so what I'm trying to say my
opinion about this is that we have to
understand the situation okay so on one
hand I believe in free trade ok free
trade and capitalism so the
corporation's the fund research is
actually natural natural and good in my
opinion but however we must also
understand there's a corruption issue
it's coherent you know this kind of this
line of thinking is coherent because
like I said before each one of us two
things to benefit ourselves so this big
corporation
two things to benefit themselves so when
they fund research you know usually it's
biased okay or like okay in modern
society they die they lied and you know
they tell you okay we funded some
independent research but actually it's
not independent at all you know all your
companies or drug companies or or Google
you know today Google Facebook they are
all [ __ ] very fact so of all things
considered what I'm saying is that you
have to understand what's going on okay
so what we want is first of all we want
freedom free trade we want freedom of
individual I want at least I want I want
freedom you know free trade without
government nothing okay I don't want a
minimum wage I don't want a fat [ __ ]
minimum wage okay I don't want you know
governed government-sponsored you know
what rent rent control you know I ain't
no good I don't want come I don't want
government nothing okay some of it is
good okay but let's not get too complex
I want just to quickly tell you my views
so I don't want so I I so I like free
trade but meanwhile we also you know
once you understand these things you
must also note that about the corruption
issue corruption you know when you when
your company becomes big huge they you
know they fund academia everything that
just benefit them so that is actually
corruption the problem came from
corruption not free trade okay now free
trade is powerful because when company
is corrupt I can see it I can tell you
know most of you guys probably agree you
can tell Google is [ __ ] everything
Google Facebook these corporations all
your companies they are doing in fact
they are [ __ ] around every day we can
tell so when that happens we choose some
other company you know so yeah okay so
you Bubo you're gonna do that okay I'm
not gonna use Google anymore I'm gonna
use something else so that is the power
of free trade you don't like my Emacs
tutorial go buy some other people's
tutorial that is free trade okay so when
what happens if if they are if there is
a corruption for example I'm selling my
Emacs
tutorial but actually I'm too lazy you
know I my tutorial is actually not bad I
mean not good then you don't buy my
stuff you buy other people's stuff
that's free trade ok but what so people
today because of the power struggle
because corruption because people don't
understand you know people are none
thinking the [ __ ] the open-source
[ __ ] programmers and the free
software foundation [ __ ] these
people they don't understand how human
animals work they understand so they
they are just pushing pushing random
ideology that is why we get corruption
that is why today Google Facebook you
know they are controlling everything
then because you know Google for example
if you don't like them don't use this
use some other companies but the problem
is there are no other companies there's
only Google in Facebook and Twitter why
because they they become corrupt they
they they get governments or they get
people you guys the open-source
[ __ ] ok they get you people they
they they push our propaganda our
ideology so that so that other companies
cannot begin cannot you know begin to
challenge challenge them that is why ok
this is the reason I think that's a
problem this is the reason why we have
Google you know facebook treater
Microsoft you know just a few big
corporations like they control
everything but in you know back to that
free trade thing you know nobody this
will not happen because if you don't
like Google just use somewhere else
except Google created a situation in
public and out the open-source [ __ ] you
know you know many of you guys
open-source [ __ ] you know be chanting
ever sold so they they create a
situation so that they want you to
believe something else they want you to
start to believe Oh capitalism is no
good oh the companies they must have you
know rules about ethical rules about you
know ethical this or that that that this
is why this is why they become more and
more powerful that is my opinion
so Justin Scarr safai says so are you
more prone to Anika Z's anarchism no not
at all what did I just wasted 15 minutes
of talking why would I be prone to
anarchism no I'm not I'm not for
anarchism at all well I I believe in
free trade but I do want some I want
some sort of minimum government okay I'm
not you need to be it's a big and
complex topic okay and anarchism like
depending what you mean like the mean
anarchism is another big political world
you know like constant conservatives
then progressives then capitalism and
communism once you mentioned the jargon
the brain is cut nobody understand a
thing when this when they see an ax
kisum do you think of one thing you know
you think is a the person be think is V
person see think is see so every does he
not all enemies way I can Anna you know
Anna Casey means is [ __ ] you are a
[ __ ] and the other guy says no you
are rocket and anarchism is good you
know that's what happens in politics
because the word loses meaning nobody
you know vast majority people they when
they talk about politics they have no
idea you know they just jargons chaga
anarchism you know capitalism you know
every communism they have no idea what's
going on especially in today's society
yeah things are extremely complex but
anyway anarchism
so apparently anarchism is there are two
actually there are two main schools they
are quite a few schools of anarchism so
that you have you have you know as far
as I know okay I know I as far as I know
you have one school of anarchism that
sees that is pro free trade okay there's
a jargon I forgot what but anyway
there's a anarchism that's pro free
trade then there's the other anarchism
that's that's
anti-free trade that's like communism
socialism you know
so you have different anarchism so
anyway anyway that's getting very
complex things pinko okay so pinko says
pinkie o says i love when this man says
[ __ ] this [ __ ] dad okay so if you have
not already joined this code okay we
have vibrant discord vibrant people
great people and you can find my disco
link in youtube or on saudi website and
we haven't began to talk about today's
stuff against today i want to talk about
Emacs and lots of other stuff so that is
neap toning pain on YouTube let me show
you a video of it now let's see if I can
do it this is a natural position
normally it's like that but now but I
can do it and see this this pinch
holding will be first of all focus on
one hand okay you have to put I have to
kind of relax to do this so anyway
that's one hand then then you have two
hands together they can go on forever
okay there there that is so we have a
lot of topics and we started to talk
about anarchism in the free trade and
capitalism stuff so the writing style of
sorry this is another stuff so so many
things okay I'm working on my website
and I have thousands tab open I have I
have about six thousand essays I've
written on my website sorry dot info
sorry doc woody English I have about six
domains five five or so domains and I
have six thousand essay so tutorials or
come
Terri's on various things technology art
and stuff and the maintaining you know
maintaining them is everyday you know it
takes a lot of time so anyway so I want
to so what are we so what what is the
direction are we going I want to do some
Emacs and because that involves let's do
some Emacs ok because I'm going to do
some Emacs coding that involves a user
interface design and Majid so just in
scarf I say so you need to specify your
concise meaning of words that's unless
you know you can it's not you cannot be
possibly be done you know it once you
started to talk about economic systems
you know professors and great
philosophers has been doing that and you
know for thousands of years new Emacs
says local labor versus imported or our
sauce labor huh that's another big topic
so local labor versus imported or also
labor you know meaning of these
political issues there is no there is no
right question okay there is no is it's
not like oh we just do this in it's good
you know many of these political
questions there's no right answer so
rather than you know saying what I think
which one should it be I mean it doesn't
make sense I mean the I can tell you
know one of the wrong answer is is
saying this is good or that is bad okay
that that would be the wrong answer
there's no right answer to many of these
complex political you know issues
the reason they become hot buttons is
because because in general people people
don't understand nothing you know people
don't understand nothing they just they
watch TV or today they watch Netflix you
know they just get brain
the corporation's put billions of money
in advertisements that's what you see
every day consumerism you know that's a
jargon you know that's so what you see
every day what you know is from what do
you see every day and what do you see
every day your life your life your your
your life but you know every everything
you do since you were born
ah I put out by these corporations at
least in America you know TV
entertainments movies Hollywood so that
that becomes that's your brain and that
is a big part of modern society or shall
we say postmodern society yes so so what
is the alternative for example what so
what can we do well you have to think
okay again there is no ultimate question
like many people when they are thinking
oh I'm for EM for capitalism
oh and no capitalism is no good we
should be socialism that's all crap okay
there's no note that you know you cannot
pitch and hole into some just you know
local labor is good or immigration
immigration is good oh it's bad it's
nothing like that it's very complex
question rather so the solution there is
no solution okay there is no like one
answer solution that's what people want
you know let's see you know sorry do you
do you have can you give us a solution
you know one sentence solution that
solves everything there's no such thing
you just have to think so great people
in history this okay my opinion about
this is that you what you need is
education that's the that's almost the
most important thing okay if you want
one solution I would say it's education
okay now when when I mention the word
education that that does not mean
institutionalize education that does not
mean oh everyone should go to high
school you know this institutionalized
college you know not necessarily so
the education just means education you
learn things you get knowledge you you
know man I
you know you ideally you know you want
everyone to have good understanding you
know good learning that's part of
Education you know even before before
the era where we have colleges we have
universities you know for example before
we have universities let's say 300 years
ago you still have education you have
you know you have disciplines you have
you learn from people from from a master
from experts you have --crafts --crafts
--crafts man and also you learn from
your parents you know you learn things
and you learn to be nice you learn what
not to do what's good to do you learn
not to lie not to steal that's a
education okay then you learn up also
about specific things like keyboards
computing programming
you know or sculpture painting you know
specific skills you learn things
learning things is fundamental in human
animals things you know since things
10,000 years ago you have to learn
things so that's actually that's that's
called education okay it's not
necessarily the institutionalized
education especially today you know we
have this Harvard this Stanford this MIT
this Ivy League [ __ ] okay these are they
have become they have become a huge
giant corruption they Chung out people
who are brainless you know though
especially in today's you know social
justice they check out these people who
are like journalists they I major I have
a degree in journalism I have a degree
in community communication is this this
empty facts okay so anyway so education
that's I think that if you want one you
know if there is one solution to
society's problems doesn't matter today
or 10,000 years ago my belief my
understanding is that you know
education you want people to be learned
you know you want you know the moorland
did better and then there's a question
okay how do you do that again there's no
answer okay how do you get everyone to
be learnt there's no simple answer to
solution to that you just have to you
know you you have to do things so how
long have I been talking I have been
talking for 34 minutes so let's do some
Emacs shall we
Cooney Mac says okay so yeah let's let's
do some max let me tell you okay some
you know a friend
I want to thank you know the one of my
friend who has donated to me well I like
donations okay so people you guys if you
like my stuff watch my video give me
some money okay give me a few bucks so
one of the questions who is this guy
what's his name I can remember his name
but usually when I'm talking I forgot
but anyway we can see the name on
Twitter but I'm not not logged into
Twitter so I have to like I have to log
into Twitter okay so let's do that and
then I have to type password okay so
let's let's type passwords
Oh Oh these while you've been seeing me
without without seeing my screen okay so
anyway so let me go to Twitter and
logging okay so
yeah I mean so let's switch back to saw
scene so actually I want to do some
Emacs so so notifications and
live stream discord coat okay coach
asked me can I recommend coat yeah thank
you code for money so code asked me can
I recommend some keyboards cheap Chinese
keyboards you know they are a turn today
actually so you just go to my website
you go to you know search for Saudi
keyboard then you go to the PC keyboard
then I can tell you what I recommend if
you just want the cheap Chinese
mechanical keyboard so I can recommend
this one and this one and this one so
you just go through my website and visit
them ok and you buy them buy them make
the economy great again so let me post
the link to my youth to my YouTube here
actually pop this window out and oh that
window now needs to go here and actually
go here so yeah let me show you the
which cheap keyboards to buy so this one
is good water-resistant Chinese
keyboards from China they are so cheap
there right they are like you can get
one for $30 $30 $40 you know just buy
them mechanical and water resistant you
know one thing about Chinese kewal from
China is that most people will think oh
it's from China it's gonna break you
know in three days
actually no you know so China keyboards
has been on a scene for like five years
four years for now so I've been looking
at them you know the comments reviews
what people say and actually there's not
much fat reviews they are actually good
reliable and super cheap $30 so you know
they are actually I think
they are driving they are making you
know Logitech and all these other
companies they are eating their market
significantly you talk too slow who me
what do you mean you mean I should go
around topic faster so anyway so so this
one I recommend Chinese cheap Chinese
keyboards and this optical switch ones
so they are a few varieties you can I
think you can find one without being
ugly for example this one is I think
okay so this optical keyboard I think I
recommend I'd recommend okay
and also there's this one this one I
have it's it's there this one is that is
my photo oh that is my video actually I
showed a video of it so talk show
so this one is God thin keys okay very
thin keys
so that's three I can recommend so I
actually I want to go to start to do
Emacs so let's close that I want to show
you eMac stuff okay then let me do Emacs
then close that Emacs blah okay so
so how long have I been talking I've
been talking for 40 minutes okay so
start up show so okay so let me move let
me show you this let's let me show you
what I want to do magnify wait
curse that magnify and saw start command
log mod so on this window you can see
all my commands such as that okay so I'm
gonna
okay so my Emacs I'm going to show you a
command okay first of all let's go to a
Wikipedia article let me show you what
the command do okay no Emacs I want to
go to Wikipedia article so they are copy
the URL back to Emacs and paste it here
okay so I'm gonna show you a command of
Emacs okay so let's also go to so here
is the Emacs article let's let's create
another link yeah this is gosling Emacs
okay let's just say that okay
let's save him okay yeah
now let's just use that Gosling in Emacs
okay so we have two links here okay now
I press a key to make them into a
Wikipedia link now you can watch on the
pink purple panel the command name okay
so I'm gonna do it now do it
you see HTML any link if I do it okay so
we got two links and now make a list and
showing browser okay so you can see we
have two links to Wikipedia you can
click on that but what I want I have a
command that removes or Wikipedia links
on my website why do I want to remove
here links because I talked about this
before in my previous video because
Wikipedia has become corrupt and you
know I talked about it before you just
go to my YouTube search for Wikipedia
you'll find it do not donate to
Wikipedia okay okay so I have I have
about 7,000 links to Wikipedia on my
website okay so in the past created
since the past 15 years so let me show
you
okay on this page you can find it on my
website sorry dog Wikipedia links you
will see as of 2016
I have 7,000 links to Wikipedia for each
one I have linked to for my website I
have read about 10 more 10 times you
know 10 more articles so I have read
tons of Wikipedia articles in the past
20 years
you know since Wikipedia began in 2003
also but beginning in 2006 I'm going to
stop linking to Wikipedia and in fact
I'm actually removing my 7,000 you know
he existing links to Wikipedia because
time has changed because and we also
because Wikipedia has become corrupt you
know back then ten years ago you know
not everyone knows about Wikipedia so I
linked to them for my website why I'm
talking about Emacs or when I'm talking
about UNIX command line for example OS
or whatever command I linked Wikipedia
so people can find more information very
useful education but today time has
changed you know in the Internet the
culture the politics your society you
know it's constantly changing
today time has changed everyone every
[ __ ] idiot knows about Wikipedia in
fact everyone is so we you know
information is so you work with
ubiquitous everywhere that today some
people they are bored you know they play
video games they are tired of it you
know they they are poor every day as you
have 1,001 medium video games they are
all tired of it then you have pong you
know pong but you also have 1 billion of
it you you you know is so much that you
get tired you get tired of it then
Wikipedia knowledge information they
tell you everything about any
you also you know you get tired of it
you you you know so information is
everywhere so it doesn't you know it's
not like when you read my wiki you know
my article I'll link to Wikipedia you're
gonna click you know nobody you don't
you don't care you know you already know
it most people already know it so it
does not make sense for me to link to
Wikipedia anymore okay it doesn't make
sense so I want to I'm trying to remove
them there are seven thousand things
it's hard to I don't want to remove them
by a script because because you know
sometimes that will change the meaning
of the writing you know because you know
so brother I do it on a case-by-case
basis
wait do you guys are seeing me okay you
are seeing my page okay good so I want
to remove them case-by-case basis like
when I read one page of my website I
remove it so that's one of the reason I
want to remove Wikipedia links the other
reason is that wikipedia has become
corrupt you know the guy the Jimbo
whales that the is I think he's not a
good person
you know he's getting people to donate
so they have millions 92 you know
millions of money it's it goes to his
pocket okay so do not donate to
Wikipedia and in fact let wikipedia die
the [ __ ] with video let it die
because it is not going to be a loss to
us wikipedia if if wikipedia disappear
overnight today by tomorrow by next
buying a month or two you have lots of
tons of equivalent okay you are not
going to lose information it's not like
Oh Wikipedia if Wikipedia tired tomorrow
it's like oh you cannot any find
information anymore
no in fact possibly after half a year
you will have much more diverse and
richer information that is my opinion
so do not support Wikipedia 20 years ago
we've he Wikipedia was a great thing
okay but not today
things change no you know you have to
keep thinking about what's going on in
society so and the other reason I don't
like I don't want to link with to
Wikipedia anymore is because they have
become very biased they they become the
one of the one of the theme that's
manipulated by those who are powerful
powerful organizations they go in
political parties you know they're going
they manipulate they erase history in
Wikipedia you know they you know they
find ways to do that they change
articles for example today we have the
social justice kind of way of thinking
lots of them so they they are very
powerful they are run by you know they
are in Google in Facebook in New York
New York Times in notes those mainstream
powerful corporations they have millions
of dollars so they go edit Wikipedia you
know they try to change they change you
know they they control your thought that
is what wikipedia has become so that is
another big reason I'm removing my links
to Wikipedia okay that's why
okay back to back to the Emacs I was
going to show you my Emacs commands
about so I wrote these commands to
remove Wikipedia for example I'm gonna
call command let me show you okay so I
call command I put that I've cook I put
a cursor on a Wikipedia out link and I
call this command okay cuz I'll remove
Wikipedia link enter God you see the
link is gone it just becomes the plain
text no Emacs okay so I can do that then
there is another command that will
remove all
Bowlings on the current buffer okay so
let me try it let me show it so this
command is called remove sod remove all
Wikipedia links I press enter you see
all links on the current file to
Wikipedia how good they are just
replaced by the words okay so that's
that's two commands I wrote okay so so
that's a demo of it but let me show you
what I want to do okay so so let's go to
the source code of the command okay so
so you can see the source code here is
the source code you see that so that's
the source code for one of the command
Sun remove all Wikipedia links and the
other one is above it sorry move
Wikipedia link okay actually I want to
go to the bathroom and let me check how
am i doing anyway are you guys still
here check this code i pm'd you know
just type it here you PM me you know
just in like I don't have time to you
know if I click on your name then is
going to show our past discussions it
might be private so I don't want to show
it right now so if you you know just
type whatever here or type in public
just in type in public like you know I
cannot answer you know this is a
frequent issue with me because every
everyone you know because I write a
public blog you know I have a thousand
or two followers so everyone started to
email me privately or private chat in
Twitter or on discord I cannot deal with
them I cannot answer questions to each
one because each one the it pretty soon
is one hour for each person I don't have
time to
do that you know sorry about that so
opposed to public you know post to
public any questions post to public
unless you know I don't have money you
know I'm I live in poverty so unless you
have okay so I'm going to read your
questions after the discussion so unless
you pay me you know you pay me ten
dollars donate fifty dollars you know
then hundred dollars I answer your
questions for two hours so again the
other thing I'm doing is I do Emax this
tutorial or JavaScript tutorial one or
one home video so if you like to have
that pay me $100 I do it for three hours
so you get three hours dedicated
no-nonsense
tutorial so in these three hours Europe
your learn email is or JavaScript coding
from the ground up so if you any of you
guys like that then PME okay do it pay
me a hundred dollars and let's do it
just pay me okay because I had you know
then you have a lot of people who just
started to talk to me but they
eventually did it they don't pay you
know I don't I don't I mean poverty of
poverty so if you pay me to that that's
good so anyway so let's go back to what
I want to do so I have these commands
let me show you okay so we remove
Wikipedia link that's one of the command
I want to move them right now they are
in my init file but what I want to is
what I want to do is I want to move them
into my HTML package okay so that's what
I want to do so I think maybe I should
do that so how long I've been talking 45
is 56 okay let me do that so let me show
you okay so actually so I have a lot to
show so let me open another window
okay so another window well so let's go
to HTML so here is my HTML mod 4400
lines so here's the URL you can go to
this is my HTML mod so I want to move
these two commands into it so first
first of all what I do is I want to
change the name from that to that so I
want to add the prefix our HTML because
in Emacs this you do not have name space
so every package must have a prefix that
serves as a function of name space so I
need to change your name okay before I
change the name I need to search in my
in a directory so here is my in a
directory so I need to search if
anywhere I use the name because I need
to change the name in every file in the
directory so let's do that so I have a
basic here okay so let's do that so I
call some find/replace
self and replace text and so co-ed I
paste names I'll remove Wikipedia link
okay then change it to saw HTML remove
will keep healing do it in this
directory or ER files right change to
file yes
fix case yes fix case in replacement yes
make a backup yes okay it's done so here
is a result you can see two places it
changed in two vials okay
now okay that's good now let's do one
more one more discs are remove at
Wikipedia link wait let's do one more
this one cuz I'll remove or Wikipedia
Bing okay
Coke's are fine replace text paste it
and I want to change to some HTML -
remove all Wikipedia link okay okay okay
okay okay okay okay then two places
changed okay now I'm just going to cut
these two files this source code cut it
and cut it cut okay now I open the HTML
file
I mean excit ml source code okay then I
need to paste them here so I need to
find the position to paste them so let
me find where do I want to paste so so I
want I'm going to call a least matching
lines defund so I'm going to see wait so
I'm going to show all lines that
contains word different definition of
functions so that way I can find where
do I want to I want to the new functions
where do I want it to go
we keep Headey our link okay so so here
are all the functions in this package
okay I'm just going to put it somewhere
here okay this is probably I have to
think about where do I actually want it
because you know you have I have 100
functions in this code how do you order
them that's actually a general question
there is no right answer to that so
let's just say let's just say here okay
so open that yeah okay so yeah I just
closed the buffer okay here
okay so I'm going to put it here
okay so paste so you see I just paste it
so you can see now those this one and
wait maybe do it properly so these two
functions now it's inside TM your mod ok
now save it now go to the top I want to
change this version number line so copy
paste okay delete it and call the date
so we're here we have a new function
name I mean the new version number here
so actually let me add change so version
8.1 point something so save it then I'm
going to call magic okay that's it so
that is it for about the task of moving
these two commands to this package let's
restart Emacs so I'm gonna wait I'm
gonna go to untitled do I want to save
it no quit Emacs 10 people watching so
now I'm going to go to share terminal
magnify close that terminal a new
terminal start Emacs okay and actually I
need to go to the bathroom for be right
back in 30 seconds I need to go to a
bathroom
so I'm back
so I'm back and let's get on to wait so
this should be fixed like that okay so
are you guys still here
ten people so any comments any comments
comments guys comment whoever you are
ten people okay so so what are we doing
now so we just restarted Emax right
and now okay now the next topic so
previously we just I just demonstrated
how I moved two functions into the new
package into this package now I'm going
to show you wait did Emacs just restart
it yes okay so I need to start command
log mod ok so now I
so now what I'm going to is this is a
new topic okay I'm going to show you now
match it okay match it is a Emacs
package for using git so let's do it
so match it status okay call the command
magic status and why is it taking so
long
okay there it is let's magnify so there
it is
so I move here on stage to change okay
so I open it tab to event so you can see
so magic is showing me the diff so it's
showing me I have added these two blocks
of code right so I just did that so now
I want to commit it okay so first of all
let me copy the name here copy let me go
to here open a new buffer actually let's
do it here open a new buffer paste it
what I want is this I want is one second
so what I want is these two names okay
so the rest I don't care so I want to
say two new functions okay so this is
basic okay hold on a second
and let's put that so I want to say that
so this is going to be my commit message
okay
so cut that close it back to match it
and first of all I want to add so
imagine you just press s you move the
cursor to the file you want to add press
s so now you see it's staged you can see
is a staged okay now I want to commit
so commit is control C control see
weight control C C not wait what I'm
using some fly keys so that's actually
what's going on oh it's CC actually so
you press C and C to commit okay so here
you see it pops up buffer and lets you
type come in messages here so I paste
what I wanted so I say two new functions
okay so so this there's a idiocy in
magic mod ok so this guy actually
responded to my talk there's a idiocy
Magic Man you know the these typical
programmers they are used to the idea of
lines should not be longer than 70
characters something like that to this
day where does this came from this
convention came from punch cards you
know the punch cards 50 years ago but
this convention is still with with us
because this idiot
this idiot programmers so they for
example why do they for example let me
show you okay so right now I have this
thing in one line in one single line and
obviously it's more than 70 characters
let me show the ruler okay
ruler mod so you can see this line is
more than 70 characters you can see the
part you know there's a you know so it's
more than 70 characters and now you can
also see that the match it mod
automatically when when your character
is beyond 76
it makes them read this is what magic
Mart doing Magic Mart is doing this it
make it read so that you know it wants
you to know that oh you have a line
longer than 70 characters therefore
maybe you should cut it is idiocy
supported by magic mod you see what
magic mod is trying to do here is that
one is trying to follow the convention
the convention of the programmers this
this idiot this idiotic FAQ from
programmers from the UNIX lineage
because in UNIX it is UNIX that that
enforce this convention to this day they
tell everyone to cut their lines you
know line lines should not be no longer
than 76 characters otherwise they
truncate it silently
that's what UNIX is doing back in 30
years ago to this day so anyway we we
got this convention I talked about this
many times in my video so so magic magic
mod is trying to follow the convention
you know the doing this and also magic
mod is is part you know we can blame
magic mod is part of this criminal can
you know it's still trying to do trying
to spread this convention that is what
magic mod is doing it's trying to you
know it's helping spreading this idiotic
convention okay so anyway you see so I
have a long line and it's trying to it's
highlighting you know whatever be on 76
is read okay now as far as why why this
convention is bad I'm not going to talk
about it today because I talked about it
in past videos and I have like 10 I have
like 10 or 20 or 30 articles about it
you can search for Kasauli 70 charts you
know you
find it so anyway so so match it is
doing this now let me cut it this line
okay let me cut it too so I want to cut
it into two lines now you see now I have
cut it into two lines so the first line
is not it's no longer than 76 characters
but however notice match it is still
making the second line red why let me
show you okay so if you press a return
now it's good now it doesn't show us red
but however if you don't have a return
it make it red because because this this
this programmer this hacker type of
programmers comebacks ok this idiot
idiots they so what's nice what's wrong
now now all my lines are below you know
within 70 character 76 characters why
are they still making it red why do they
want you know like a new line why well
this is a kind of a new convention
because this kid get [ __ ] this kid
unix you know loving people
this UNIX philosophy this kid [ __ ]
these idiots they think ok they
developed they developed a convention
that that says that you should you know
the first line should not be more than
70 characters but then if you're going
to have more timelines then you should
have a empty line as a second line
that's their convention okay this is
idiot okay that's that's so why is that
idiot because it's idiotic for the same
reason that a line should not be 70 more
than 76 characters is EDX idiotic it's
the same reason because these people
these people when they they they look at
lines as kind of formatting that's how
they look at lines but you should not
look at programming source code that way
rather you should look at programming
source code is from a semantic or
synthetic unit point of view not
formatting okay not line not newline you
know that line based you know the
hard-coded formatting way you should
look at from a semantic unit point of
view okay that's the reason you know I
have again I have articles you can read
about them I'm not going to go into them
so that's one thing okay so I don't
think this convention of having a space
is good you know the thing about kit is
that you have you know this UNIX
[ __ ] you have get they tell you oh
you need to source control you you know
you need to use source control
once you use source control then then
then it has 1 million 1 billion
conventions you know it's not like you
start to use kit you learnt get you know
they everything falls in place no but
because then get then you have 1 million
conventions about git about conventions
about how you should you know these
sockets this unique UNIX people idiots
they are you know it is they creating
complexity Empire on top of complexity
they could you know it's like a
complexity all the way the thing is
about these UNIX [ __ ] is that is
that they think you know they think they
are the god you know they if you don't
follow their advice they think you are
idiot but in fact they are idea they are
the most criminal [ __ ] when it
comes to programming conventions ok so
anyway let me go let me move on ok so so
so much it is telling you you should
have two lines let me show you ok so
anyway so this is my commit message I
want it to lines and I don't want I
don't want a [ __ ] empty lines you
know doing that so let's do this ok so
now I press control C control C to
commit ok do it then here is the [ __ ]
problem another this is a different
topic ok here now look at the bottom the
Bava the magic tells me that second line
is not empty commit anyway so magic is
popping of mace message you know giving
giving me some sort of warning about
some kind of you know convention the
[ __ ] magic that's a problem okay this is
a separate issue previously we talked
about why you know seventy short lines
it's no good we talked about why this
[ __ ] idiotic conventions okay that's
one thing here is a different topic this
topic is about user interface about why
programs should not pop up this prompt
you know asking questions like every
time you do a command then it pops up oh
oh because the morning something
something something do you actually want
to do it you should that should not
happen okay well this is a minor minor
issue compared to the line length
problem we talked about this is a minor
issue but but in my opinion so if you
want to do a good user interface design
try to avoid these popping of questions
okay
for example Apple Apple throughout you
know Apple Apple's design Apple UI is
usually usually usually very good and
they avoid these popping of questions if
you have a question just just do it okay
just do backup or whatever just do it
and maybe pop then then display your
message
afterwards after the command is that you
you should avoid popping up a prompt
that stops everything you know that
stops the flow so so this is what I'm
talking about so match it is doing that
okay okay I say yes okay now it's
committed now I want to push to my
server okay capital P then P now I push
to the server okay it's done now so if
you go through my github
go to such sorry github size HTML mod us
see the code update on my website okay I
think that's about that's it for today's
talk we talked about huge number of
things
I hope it's fun for you guys so let's
see the comments I'm writing Wikipedia
are scraping code I'm a VM user but
interesting in learning some Emacs okay
well you found BM cosas and BM cosas
join this code okay so because once you
joined this code then we can talk we can
chat every day and sometimes we do live
streams sometimes I have other people on
this code so it's fun to join so George
says you should do a discord to tow your
own language learning you mean you mean
you mean natural human languages yeah we
can do that well but I prefer YouTube
because YouTube yeah you know because
YouTube I have some incentive to get to
make money YouTube so Penn closed say
Spanky oh say is true but you can do
ignore commit any way back from wrong
one in UK Rhonda Oh Rhonda okay so you
are actually in UK you went to Rhonda
but you are back okay so that's it for
today guys thank you guys for watching
so I mentioned yesterday I did a
complete revamp of my of my Emacs
tutorial so you guys you know so sighs
chair mail mod eMac these so you know go
by it
okay just click on a button and they pay
me okay Emacs to Rovio the other one
of one of my to Toby or how do you
recommend he's JavaScript in depth these
two to Tory tutorials are very good okay
so okay thank you guys and bye see you
next time