good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show today is uh 2020
December
14th uh noon San Francisco time and
today we are going to do some randomish
stuff so we are going to talk about emac
emac lisp or keyboard or JavaScript
uh and uh so if you have any comments uh
the topics you like me to uh talk about
post in the comment okay Post in the
comment say hi if you are here say
hi so uh let's see if I'm alive and uh
one more check check video audio check
good okay so I don't know what I'm going
to talk about today so uh randomish so
we're going to talk about emac let's go
to my emac blog and uh on the pink
window you can see all my emac command
Calles uh so if you don't know what I'm
doing just look up the command name
search for it and you'll find the
code so we're going to talk about random
things emac blog so you are looking at
my emac blog and uh you know some they
are they are quite uh you know there's
always interesting stuffs to talk about
and then uh or I'm going to go through
my keyboard blog uh interesting things
to talk about okay then or JavaScript
blog or web dev blog so there is you
know many things so once I start like
once I started to talk about some topic
it's going to be non-stop for example
here is the here is the or css selector
syntax okay you know as as as you
know I watched the birth of CSS and HTML
since
1995 so I know uh well everything about
C CSS okay and uh this is raw knowledge
unlike today's you know Frameworks or
what what
whatnot CSS so uh so again so you know
comment okay I I love to see your
comments post your questions or whatever
you are thinking so hi guys uh Al uh
Alerio Alerio and Boo and David and Ying
hey good morning a lot of new guys
interesting people say where you came
from okay Around the World Around the
World in a day so what topic you guys
like uh to see the most because you know
I'm I'm going random so once I start to
talk about something it's likely to be
nonstop uh so emac emac list or keyboard
let's go to my keyboard blog uh keyboard
blog
um uh and JavaScript or Dev or some
other interesting things let me show you
some of the interesting things on my
blog okay so you see this is my Firefox
and uh you have I have tons of tabs
usually 20 or more tabs and you know
among my browsers like uh usually I have
Firefox open Safari open and usually
also Chrome open three browsers
typically uh for 20 years years 20 plus
years and for each browser I have like
20 or so tabs on in Firefox browser I
use it for my Dev you know most all
these are my websites so let me show you
okay so this is my keyboard blog so this
is all single key press okay one single
key press you you see I can fly through
my uh tabs so this is my web de blog
with web de blog is usually about
JavaScript HTML CSS technology for the
you know you know as I observed or as I
write my tutorials for the past 20 years
now here's the interesting one uh here
is a Internet Explorer anime girl you
know this is a Japanese thing and for
Americans it's like oh no no no you
cannot do that you know so this there's
a uh huge cultural differences you see
in Japan everything is you know they
have a girl to represent everything like
young girl you know very young very very
young you know what I mean young girls
so in Japan they have this internet
anime uh Internet Explorer anime girl
okay or Windows 10 you know to promote
Windows 10 and look at this one this
this is a Microsoft ergonomic keyword I
talked about uh two days ago yesterday a
few days ago in my last episode so you
know Japanese they are truly the the top
experts at illustration the Japanese Co
culture they they are truly are and
illustration among all artworks visual
artworks you know maybe painting classic
painting you know impressionist or
whatever or abstract you know
abstraction or whatever paintings the
the type of painting the type of visual
artwork I love the most is illustration
okay now illustration uh it is not fancy
it's not academic it's not you know but
that you know the that is the thing I
like the most be uh illustration and
typically usually I prefer black and
white ink you know pencil work so let me
show you let me go to my art blog so
we missed art blog so so I have a art
blog that uh you know you have all sort
of art okay now for example this one is
a
classic you might call it anime but this
is from
1970s okay 1970 Japanese anime now this
uh I when I was small I was watching it
in Taiwan so this is uh this one is
called candy candy you can look it
up uh and there's a video of it you if
you use Chrome browser you can watch the
video you know it's amazing the open
source [ __ ] you know in Firefox Firefox
is supposed to be the open source you
know the Love by open source people five
Fox but however there is this video okay
let me one single key press to copy the
uh you see one single press to copy the
URL now switch to emac press three keys
to open this website so one single key
press to show in browser back to emac so
this is you can see this is the page
okay and we go down and there's a video
you see here is a video this is MKV
format now this video format is the one
loved by open Source [ __ ] the open
source people the Linux Unix you know
people they love it mkb because it's
open source it's a no patent you know
blah blah blah however when you have
this format the video in Firefox it
doesn't [ __ ] show the [ __ ] the open
source the open source is filled with
lies they don't they don't recognize it
okay now again uh if you uh want me to
talk about something just type it I'm
going to read it because once I start to
talk about something it's going to be
nonstop so right now I'm starting to uh
uh rent on the open source [ __ ] you
see so we have you know the open source
[ __ ] Fanatics every day they say oh
oh for video you need to use MKV format
because it's better it's technically
better it's uh better compression and so
on so on on and on and they say oh
Firefox you need to uh you know use
Firefox but then in Firefox this open
source uh video format it does not
[ __ ] show now let me show you uh uh
in Chrome okay so emac command okay hold
on a second undo let's show the pink
window okay uh wait you see the pink
window now I'm going to call command
call a command opening Chrome browser
okay open in
Chrome so you open this page in Chrome
and you then then there you can see the
video shows so it's kind ofy you know
it's like ironic it's not just it's not
even ironic this open source lie
[ __ ] so in Chrome this greedy you
know Google the greedy the uh Global
Empire is
shows okay let me let me show you hold
on a
second
uh's see okay so it opened a a new
window I don't want a new window because
I let's try it again because I don't
have Chrome open so you see now we are
uh looking at this page in Chrome
browser and you can see the
video now this video is uh you know
1970s uh cartoon and and you can look up
on that so let me read the read the
comments uh and let's see what we're
going to talk about today so I was
talking about you know I was going to
show you SE several of my tabs okay so
um so show my artwork blog I was saying
I was saying the line
artwork of all type of artworks you can
you can see uh L and the Swang this is
the classic Western classic you know all
kind of artwork you know you have modern
you have uh okay okay those are
sculpture you have the painting you have
real realism okay you have um this style
is called um I forgot anyway so you you
have all kind of
uh uh oops you don't want to show that
in in white men's Society uh that's like
taboo in in
the any anyway so in you see you can see
all sort of artwork okay
and and it is true that in artworks most
of the time you'll see naked females
because you'll see you know you'll see
you know most of the time uh from Asian
to today that is because girls are the
most important element we
appreciate
uh uh female you know young girls uh uh
Beauty okay that because they are the mo
you know because basically because they
bear children they they are you know uh
girls they are the uh kind of the
critical elements of
humanity okay so so I'm saying I was I
was saying you know all of all sort of
artworks the one I like the most is uh
uh illustration for example this you you
kind of call this is uh called
illustration okay and Japanese uh does
it the
best okay so so that's about some
artwork okay so so I was going to show
you some of my uh blogs uh very
interesting stuff okay keyboards we
talked about all the time maybe we uh
don't want to talk about that today now
emac we talk about all the
time uh this is today's talk show page
and this is my Chinese blog okay Chinese
many interesting things Linguistics uh
you know Chinese characters uh history
of the characters for example let me
show you the list of simplified and
versus traditional characters okay you
can see the black are the traditional
characters the uh blue are the
simplified characters
then I study you know when you study
these kind of things uh it's almost uh
endless okay you can spend 10 years two
decades you know 20 years to study
Chinese characters because you trace you
know this a history uh of Chinese
characters
atmology so for example uh if you are
into design you know lots of you are you
know we are into nerds we are into
programming languages design of things
you know you user interface well Chinese
and and Linguistics Chinese characters
there's also of course you can look at
it from a design point of view so design
point of view so simplified versus
traditional what you
know uh which one is better uh from many
different uh perspectives you know which
one is more efficient which one is uh
better in many ways you know depending
on how you how what's your
Criterion so you can you can dive into
it you know you can spend 20 years into
it so I you know I have interest in in
that so I I did some about the
traditional versus simplified some of
them are bad some of them are
good uh and uh you know lots of so this
is my Chinese Blog then you have so here
is a photo of San Francisco this is a
pic
picaresque uh you know uh you know you
have the Pyramid of San Francisco and
also this building I don't know what
style is this this building does anyone
know okay
so so I'm showing you some of my blogs
and now this is modern society we need
supplements so I am starting to take
supplements okay let's let's uh let's
let's look at some other um okay this is
one of my old article on the on what
characters are allowed in file
names uh it differs on depending on Mac
OS or Windows or Linux and
uh basically it depends on the file
system uh each one is using this this is
written in 2009 so 11 years ago and this
page is interesting because this page
you know what is assault rifle oh Jesus
that's a sensor word I
shouldn't now now my YouTube is going to
be
censored okay so let's not you know
don't don't write don't comment on these
things okay don't talk about things
that's Google is going to censor me okay
so this is interesting because this uh
this picture is from Second Life okay
Second Life this this is These are 3D
actual 3D models people build in second
life it's quite amazing in several ways
because first of all Second Life 3d
system is is extremely lousy it's the
worst [ __ ] possible you know you know
what I'm talking about 3D system 3D
modeling systems so you have blender you
know that's one one of the most famous
you know open source blender you have uh
3D Max or you have wavefront Adas you
know they change name and they change
corporations every few years they change
hands so you have Auto Cad for example
so these are three cat systems you know
uh uh CAD stand for computer aided
computer AED design you know systems you
need it for for buildings you know
architecture for buildings for uh
machinery for building cars for you know
3D modeling systems and also for
animation especially in the past 10
years because you know all the ads all
the movies Hollywood you know
so but second life I talked about second
life before just search for S second
life I'm not going to show you the page
but second well actually it's here okay
Second Life Second Life is uh extremely
interest okay where is it uh oops Yeah
that's not the page I want to go to but
just search for S Second Life
okay so second life but second life you
know if second life is a game like a
game system you know like 3D games but
however it allows everyone to build
everything everything in it is built by
people like you know by by players we go
and so but Second Life the 3D modeling
system in Second Life Is the is the
worst crap
possible I talked about this before let
let's go to Second Life let me show you
okay let me talk about it one more time
so Second Life uh [ __ ]
no you know the it shows up some of the
censorable
things um you know Google is going to
censor I don't want to go there
so let's search for Linden script Linden
script is a programming language in
Second Life okay uh so I have a tutorial
of it of
course you know you know Second Life
Second Life uh programming language
called Linden script is quite
interesting so anyway let me go to my
second live page so these These are the
second life and and here you can see
this is the second live uh uh second
live build tutorial okay so this is how
you build things so so it has a 3D
modeling system you can call it let me
show you some of the interesting things
uh build in Second Life For example this
archit Ure you know all these everything
you see I'm showing right now is built
by people unlik you know other games 3D
games it's it's made by the artist of
the company you can usually you cannot
change it and if you do change it it's
called mod you know you create your own
but in Second Life it's not like that
everything everything is spilled by all
everything you see is build by
users so this is build by users this
this is uh this is interesting if you
are into math okay this is uh this is a
uh r. CED
based building and this is actually
apartment so this guy mathematician okay
I talked about him before is uh my
friend uh Henry what is his name Cipher
surface okay his real name is Henry you
can you can just search for his name you
know you'll see his website and this is
also by
him uh wait Henry I um anyway anyway
Henry San okay he's a
mathematician so this is this one is
interesting because it's it shows a
model uh you know let's say prototype or
idea conceptual idea where you can have
a building apartment building uh made of
uh r. cedron and what's interesting
about second life it's a virtual real
reality system so you actually go in and
you can actually uh you know you leave
you stand inside of this you know like a
person you go you walk in you know so
all these are second life so so so I was
saying so this are you know second life
has a 3D system you know a modeling
system you build people people build all
these things you are seeing yeah second
life is amazing I spent like uh five
years almost every day eight five hours
a day in it leave in it
so why I I'm mentioning Second Life okay
so I you know by by way I was mentioning
it because
then then I found people build this you
know this this machine let's not use the
word okay they build this very accurate
okay then I started to look at you know
the terminologies and you know for these
kind of
thing uh but anyway so that's that's
what uh this is about this is uh people
build these things using you know using
the most lousy 3D modeling system you
know it's almost like it's impossible to
do it but people people did it uh using
the second life system you know so this
is analogous to for example we went to
the moon you know we 50 years ago we
went to something like 50 years ago we
went to the moon right and back then you
don't have you don't even have computers
you barely have computers but we did it
so the human Human animals we are
capable of you know you know like today
we programmers We complain oh you know
this language is lousy because this or
that you know too complex is
bad but actually we are capable of using
whatever complex system we we we will
bear through it we we will you know
whenever if there's a need usually or
desire we will be able to do it doesn't
matter how bad how lousy is a tool and
this and you know going to The Landing
you know going to the Moon is a example
you know we went to the moon before even
we have good
computers you know back then the you
know memory you know today we have Giga
100 gigabytes of memory back then it's
like uh eight
megabytes I'm not I don't think you even
have megabytes you have hundreds bites
things like that so in the same way
people build things using the most lousy
3D system and they build uh the most
accurate model of you know this these
kind of
things uh so that's that's that blog
about then okay then uh I have you know
this now this part is about cam paga
okay Cam pag is a person I respect the
most uh the in intellectual I respect
one of the most let's say top three of
English you know Western people I
respect the most Camille Paglia and
every time she writes she I learn a lot
from her writings you know uh for
example look at the words okay the red
word words
Theus Demi M Randy gnomes superious
chcken uh Cher okay she used the
words uh in the most proper way you know
so I study a lot I learn a lot from her
writings so anyway these are some of
my uh blogs diversity okay and this one
this one is also interesting there is
there is there is this Chinese gu
Chinese guy whose name is Lio jiso okay
uh incredible person uh words from save
a hand or two you know there's a point
so his name his nickname online in China
is Leo jiso and if you translate that
into English that means save a hand or
two now that's a pun
okay so what does it mean save a handle
too that means you know in kungu usually
you know in kungu usually the master
when he teach his disciples you know
students he will save one trick or two
so that the student can never beat him
you know that's a saying you know that's
a kind of a saying in Chinese uh and
applies to other Masters too you
know it's just it's just a saying it's
not necessarily true it's just a saying
you know you save you save a hand or two
you know that meaning you save a trick
so that uh whoops uh wait I don't want
to go to we wo okay
so so anyway so that's his nickname save
a hand or two uh but he is a he is a
expert in Chinese uh writing and he it's
very funny okay
he so this guy on Chi Chinese blog
he he s you know he basically criticize
people
so usually girls okay girls you know
they the girls they they have their you
know clothing purse and they take photo
selfies all the time right so the girls
send him their pictures and he will make
a criticism of it within like 250 words
Chinese characters
also and he is extremely funny and using
you know know his writing skills is uh
very
um how shall I say Advanced you know
very good so anyway let's look at the so
I I I rambled for uh long let's look at
the comments and see what we're going to
talk about today so I already talked
about for uh 30
minutes okay so let's read the comments
uh from London okay uh voloder from
London we have a few London friends and
from and and David fish from Netherlands
yes I I think I recall from
Netherlands and 1 hour north of New York
New York New York new USA the app Big
Apple hey good morning Alan ELO British
and other friends and
Chicago iPhone comment uh AK okay
so I guess I just rambled for 30 minutes
okay let me continue reading the uh good
morning Alan so what you up
to
uh emac lisp and common lisp okay so we
have a J5 he wants to talk about emac LP
and common disp actually I talked about
that a lot you know almost you know
every other of my videos do you have any
specific
questions uh David fish started using
Vim a couple of months ago started to
get into emx and think about using Doom
emac okay that's good Doom emac emac
user since 1996
SP sh emac user since 1996 that's three
years before
me mostly for python mod slowly learning
emac Leist that's good so we have a emac
oldb and alio says Microsoft Windows uh
girl came from Japan but silver light
girl was Taiwan oh I didn't know there's
a silver silver light girl but we are
going into history silver light also uh
passed away you
know let's see if we can find pictures
let's
see okay
so yeah well you know we don't want to
get into not safe for work [ __ ] you know
the the social justice [ __ ] the the
Western white people the Western
technocrat you know the Western white
people they have the idea of not safe
for work [ __ ] them which became which is
the Forerunner of the social justice it
gradually became the social justice
thing safe for work you know every time
I talk you know I've been I rented about
this for for many times especially on
Discord okay my Discord
Forum if you like my stuff you can join
my Discord Forum you you know you you
can find the link Discord but I would
recommend you know I uh you know join
use your real name okay use your real
name and put your photo it's preferred
that way you don't have to but it's
preferred that way let's let's have a
society where we every each one of us is
responsible okay responsible and uh
honest and uh
we can talk about all things not in the
today's you know internet where every
website is like Anonymous [ __ ] and you
go there and you [ __ ] around and then
you delete your account you erase
everything you know it's not like that
okay so if you join Kali Discord keep in
mind that we you know it's pre we you
know I I like to create something you
know a place we can talk about anything
but uh a different from other website
different from YouTube redit Hacker News
[ __ ] okay you can talk about anything
but you be responsible for it okay that
way it's better for society so we can
grow we can you know make you know we
can truly make the society a better
place not you know not the social
justice [ __ ] or the corporate you know
the advertisement and you know all
that so I was saying so uh silver girl
okay yeah so I was talking about not
safe for work you know every time I talk
about that people don't understand you
know white people you know American
culture they don't understand what do
you mean what do you mean like you
know then I have to explain for one
hour because it's a cultural difference
you know on one hand the American
[ __ ] the social justice people you
know they say oh
multiculturalism
multiculturalism you know they want they
want to ECT different cultures but when
when the culture is actually different
they don't give a [ __ ] they don't you
know they want they want
multiculturalism but they they want not
safe for work they want democracy and
you know they want everything they want
their American
way uh so what is multiculturalism to
them well it's just like uh you know you
just put on you know you have Chinese
eyes they accept you have different skin
color they they love they love that you
put on weird hats or weird beard they
like that they oh yeah multiculturalism
but if you have any opinion that's
different from theirs you are [ __ ]
that's a social justice [ __ ] and
begin by okay that's today today it's
pretty bad you know you can see you know
if you know about politics you know
what's going on it's a big you know uh
uh what they call a diversion you know
uhhuh and they blame someone for it yeah
no okay but anyway so before that it
came from where does it came from it
came from the the white yepes working in
technology the programmers you know
those people work at Google you know
Google you know those silicon valy
people they be you know also in emx
community especially you know I know a
lot you know a lot of
them they in IMX community so they have
the they have the mentality they have
the cultural norm you know and one of
the thing is not safe for work you know
everyone approve you know that that's
part of their you know that's part of
their how their brain works you know
something must be not safe for work
therefore you should you know you should
put a warning or something [ __ ]
them okay so uh I'm not going to should
I talk about why I mean
exactly maybe not depends on your
comments okay if you comment and uh then
I'll um talk about that so today is uh
random talk okay so let's see l so this
is supposed to be the silver light
girl from Taiwan oh Taiwan um you know
Taiwan is pretty sad okay there so there
it is
Taiwan this is from Taiwan the
democracy you know the
anti-china sponsored by United
States I was born in Taiwan okay I'm a I
I am a
Taiwan uh you know i' rather not talk
about it because you
know because I have Taiwan friends you
know maybe you are from Taiwan I don't
know if you are alio maybe you are are
you uh so but you know when you talk
about something like if
I I talk about USA I criticize then some
people will you know dis you know uh try
to distance themselves from me you know
they don't like it right in the same way
if I criticize Hong Kong people or
Taiwan then people will uh not like
it but I think that's normal you know
that's how things are in society but I
think that's not what we should do you
know we
should that's not a healthy way uh a
healthy situation you should accept you
should accept people who have different
opinions from you okay otherwise we get
into a condition where everyone everyone
you know all the things they say are
just nice things no n non offensive
that's what they say you know that's the
one of the Jon offend you know offending
you know you should not say offensive
things so everything you hear is just
the nice words you know like nice uh
meaningless
nothing uh represented by especially by
the com you know commercials like the tv
ads or Google ad from Google or ad from
Facebook you know they are all nice they
they are going to help the world they
are going going
to help the poor and
everything but in ity are they you think
Google is going to help help the poor
and all that no they they help
themselves to get more more and more
powerful typically Mo moralist
okay that's uh from the moralist you
know before I hate I hate to say before
it came from Christians but now it's
social
justice again so anyway so this uh so
you can for you English people for you
guys guys for you guys ignorant of
Chinese we can look at the Wikipedia
English
version
okay so so this is uh
Hikaru zawa is a virtual brand
ambassador and product mascot created by
Microsoft Taiwan Branch as a more
anthropomorphism character created for
the development technology platform
Microsoft silver
light okay let let me give you my
opinion there is some commentary about
that
sentence you see this thing this this
creature this mascot is created by Tai
in Taiwan you know Taiwan Taiwan is not
Japan but however it's got a Japanese
name you
see this is her Chinese name okay but in
English it became this you know there
there's no uh they became a Japanese
name this uh is kind of uh in you know
shall we say it
interesting uh
aspect why is that you know so this this
maskot there are several cultur
interesting things going on here first
of all culturally this American will
never do that you know American the
white American the social dist is Fox
you know they see this like how can you
how can you [ __ ] create a you know a
teenager you know I don't know what how
old is she
probably less than 18 okay they create a
mascot for technology thing to rep you
know and they call it brand ambassador
you know fancy words virtual brand
ambassador so first of all this is
something that Americans is you know
they they it's a taboo they you know
it's American
Taboo but however in Asia okay if you
you know Asian culture is completely
different so [ __ ] Japan especially Japan
this is this is is the thing of Japan
but Taiwan culturally when it comes to
Fashion or pop culture
Taiwan follows Japan and Korea and USA
okay typically taiwan's pop culture they
follow uh either Japan or USA typically
both both very much so in here you know
the Taiwan they created this you know
following the
Japan uh so you have uh you know a
Chinese name but but then but then you
have a Japanese name for it so that's
interesting what how how you know how
how is that it has a Japanese
name uh I can offer
some well I can offer I can tell you a
bit why okay let's see the character
design figure drawing were made by Shia
the Doan painter okay I don't know who
is she and the duing work by uh okay
maybe she is she
Japanese you know then then she's got
three other sisters my
God this is Asian thing afterwards
Microsoft Taiwan continuously conducted
a series of official campaigns including
related software special wallpapers web
page games related activities and
amature parties
anyway so anyway it's using a Japanese
name uh I
suppose because this this kind of uh pop
culture is a Japanese thing so therefore
they just use a Japanese name so it's
more uh you know uh following the you
know following the
flow and also if it has a Japanese name
then in Japan it becomes more smooth you
know Japanese then we'll use you know
we'll accept and use this and promote it
with this mascot so I suppose that's uh
why but you know
but on the other hand you
know the thing interesting about this is
you know
Chinese you know for example when if
American created some thing you know
American don't give it a Japanese name
you know right you know American if
American created something it's you know
just use American name then Japanese
will use the American
name on in the same in the T that's
basically uh that's essentially true for
any any Nation something if something
especially China if Chinese you know the
China Chinese when they created
something something they don't they
don't give a they don't use a Japanese
name or a Korean name or or some other
or American name they use the Chinese
name you know if you like it you you
follow the Chinese
name but Taiwan Taiwan is kind of a
Taiwan they taian you know I hate to say
they don't have a identity okay they are
manipulated you know they they are kind
of they they are kind of in a struggle
for identity they they constantly need
other nations you know the world
approval you you know so meanwhile they
are Taiwan is like manipulated by
USA anyway
so so that is why okay so if this
character is created China in China you
will never have a Japanese name to go
with
it okay that's that's my uh that's
that's about
that so let's keep the so that's maybe
that's it for today random talk talking
about random using sofly keys okay sorry
today is not technical topics
uh am I losing audience I guess not
uh I come from Hong Kong this is my D
ganger okay oh you are from Hong Kong
cool and Ying from India okay we do have
international
crowd uh okay
so yeah so lots of interesting things
let's see how long have been have I been
talking and
maybe 43 minutes okay maybe another 10
minutes uh okay so some questions so
these are old
comments 30 minutes
ago as you girl came from Japan too aure
girl okay I didn't know this aure so I'm
new to pointers been wondering about
this so we can read pointer data in the
hip if I write a program and run it on a
server can I access the server's hip
memory can the server stop it okay
Thomas osen asked that question so he's
asking about
pointers uh pointers in C or C++
language well I don't I don't know
anything about that okay and uh and uh
basically I despise pointers pointers
the concept pointers okay let me let me
make a dramatic statement
okay pointers is the the worst Concept
in programming language is the most the
most harmful of all bad concept cep in
programming language pointers and
references are the most the one that
that did the most damage in programming
languages okay that is my claim now am I
serious about that
uh yes I'm serious about that but I need
to make some uh uh you know I I need to
rephrase
it because pointers and references
obviously they are very practical and
useful and also necessary Concepts in
programming languages especially back
especially 30 years ago because we don't
have computers as fast so essentially
here's the thing essentially the concept
of pointers and references in
programming languages you know uh
usually they exist in lowlevel languages
such as C
C++ actually they exist in python in
JavaScript in Ruby as well because you
you kind of need it to implement things
but but however the concept gradually
become lower becomes you know they are
not exposed to the programmer in C or
C++ these low-level programming
languages the concept of pointers or
references is all important it's exposed
to the programmer you you uh you
explicitly manipulate pointers you know
you you have So-Cal pointer
arithmetics but in higher languages such
as python uh Ruby or even JavaScript or
pH or I guess PHP to you also have the
pointers concept but however they you
you you you still have it but it's not
as explicit you know it's rather it's
like it's like implementation detail
especially when you talk about uh array
uh list
array uh tple you know these kind of
data types then you need you because you
are passing pointers otherwise you have
to copy it you know uh requires a lot
memory so pointers and references they
are uh extremely practical and
almost necessary Concept in programming
languages but I claim they are the most
they created the most damage in
programming
language languages because
because people do not realize especially
this these compiler writers this type of
the computer scientists you know the
hacker types the [ __ ] they do you
know they typically they don't know
mathematics they they don't know the
abstract math so poters to them is like
the only way it's a practical you know
it's it's practical it's almost the only
way you cannot almost cannot avoid it
but actually we can the important okay
here's my point the important thing
about
the important thing the critical thing
you have to understand is
that you have to understand why do you
need pointers why is it there you know
you you you need to have the overview of
all things the entire programming
computer science the history of it you
need to understand the onology you know
the relationship of all the concepts
once you have the big picture then then
you truly understand how things are so
but two most these compiler writers you
know they they they are like they are
extreme nerds they just focus you know
they are expert at compiler writing or
programming C or C++ these
[ __ ] they they don't see they don't
understand the big picture they don't
understand the the mathematics so
therefore to them pointer is is pointers
and references is the all important
thing so so in their understanding they
missed they missed the overall picture
of why certain things are important in
relation to the whole
thing so they created a situation where
programmers uh become ignorant you know
they don't they don't know they don't
know why pointers or references they
don't know the importance of of their
importance in relation to the whole
thing that's the problem that is the
problem okay the problem is not because
pointer is no good pointer is essential
okay pointers and reference is are
essential Concepts in in computer
science because in Practical computer
science because when you actually create
a computer you know you know Electronics
or or yeah mostly electronic computers
not mechanical but when you do
electronic computers you engineering
it's part of engineering so in other
words pointers and references they are
byproducts of Computer Engineering but
for most programmers these hacker types
who write compilers they do not
understand they do not know that they do
not they never thought of it as a
byproduct of uh Computer Engineering to
them is just something essential okay
that is the problem they do not
understand they never thought of it is a
byproduct of Computer Engineering now
remember again I'm not saying it's not
necessary okay in it's it's becoming
more and more unnecessary it's
especially important in a 30 years ago
when when memories you know we don't
have much processing power CPU or memory
uh you know Computer
Resources so my point is that they are
byproduct of uh com uh Computer
Engineering and my point is that most
programmers especially these hacker
types you know they know a lot about C
and C++ they do not recognize that it's
a byproduct of Computer Engineering
therefore they created a huge harm and
damage in the progress of programming
languages okay they because they you
know because they don't know it's a
byproduct product of a computer
engineering so they create you know they
keep spreading these Point as you know
this this thing that's the
problem but gradually today as we as as
computer get gets more and more powerful
and as programming language becomes
higher and higher level so so for
example we have PHP per Ruby python
JavaScript and even
hascal uh and and even Mathematica okay
these are very high level languages the
concept of pointers becomes less and
less and less important because because
the concept of Po pointers and
references they become subsumed into the
implementation details you see so as a
programmer you know we are programmers
we are interested in programming you
know we do we we write code as a
programmer in a in a programming
language we are no
longer uh need to know what's a point of
reference anymore because they become
part of the implementation detail you
see that's a that's a consequence of my
what I'm talking about you see what I'm
you know let me repeat what I'm saying
is that pointers and the references they
are byproduct of of Computer Engineering
okay byproduct they are not
essential but they are there because
they are byproduct because they are
actually necessary when you you know
otherwise it's too slow it's
impractical now as a consequence of that
as we can you know as as I'm trying to
say why I'm correct okay so as time
progresses today we don't see much
pointers you know they become
implementation detail because why
because they are actually not essential
okay they are not essential programming
Concepts they the concept of pointers
and references do not exist in the
theoretical computer science of of
algorithms or theoretical computer
science they don't don't they don't
exist they exist only as a you know as a
practical you know byproduct of Computer
Engineering okay that's my big point
about
poins so I don't know why are you ask
asking me that because I don't know C
and C++ so I don't really know the uh
anyway the details you know the
technical details about about
those okay I read more uh I read a few
more uh things and uh that's it for
today I guess
uh let's see how long have I been
talking 53 minutes
Apple Safari start to support web P
images now yes it took them a long time
you have to update I haven't updated yet
you have to update to the uh latest
operating system Mac OS what they call
it you know there a fancy name oh yeah
BX sir BX sir I guess I'm going to
upgrade
soon uh so Apple so there's a big lots
of features you know know uh long time
due added to
Safari okay so pointers okay so can you
make an example for adding can you make
an example for adding new language
support in or Babble for uh Unix
expression language
maybe oh yeah I did that okay this is a
big topic I can talk about
an so oh back so we are talking about
emac and we are talking about o mod o
mod okay so let me show you let's go to
my emac emac blog uh go to my emac blog
go to my emac tutorial and go down
you'll see or mod so where is it o mod
uh rectangle uh shell view doc working
with brackets power editing Oak mod okay
Oak mod
tutorial and you go
down you go all the way down there's a
uh navigation menu then you go
to uh source code markup so in OG mod
you can have you know you can have quite
a few languages you can mark up the
source code and you can also run it so
this
this this is called o o bab okay it's it
was a module it's it was a add-on to Oak
mod so about 5 years ago I did a project
for someone David uh David David
something you know he he's a great guy
he helped me so he paid me to to do this
project to add a language called VC cak
I think byy to add a language to Oak bab
so I spent like two weeks diving into
Oak mod Oak bab to create a support for
another a new language
basically uh that was five years ago so
uh and uh so the question
is can you make an example for adding
new language support yeah I can well
that that will take one hour and also
that's going to be extremely technical
I cannot do it now because I don't
remember you know it's 5 years ago and
that's going to be too technical iMac
this to to do it online nobody would be
interested because it's you know that's
going to be real serious iMac list
coding uh because you you have to dive
into Old bab code so for example let's
copy that let me let me show you some
example so all back so what's the
command name so let's see so I I am I'm
going to read my tutorial so okay
so uh structure temp oh insert structure
template okay so CC o bab okay I I have
to I have to begin so open a new buffer
magnify paste the code uh meta X
org mod okay now we are in OG
mod okay now magnify so we have o
Babble this is O
mod and this feature of having
a
uh program Lang language source code in
or file is called org Babel BL L BL e b
a BL e uh b b okay o bab that's a
feature so you can actually evaluate the
code you can have imagist python uh Ruby
PHP like 10 other languages
okay uh for example let's see python
okay let's add
that so here is the python code you can
evaluate that code by coding uh I don't
use it I don't use it so let's
see cc is for evaluate right let's try
it okay uh [ __ ] I hate I hate this meta
keys in Oak
mod okay run
it where is the result okay you see
result 10 let's say uh + 9 run
it
what 9 10 11 12 the result should be 12
run
it evaluate this python blog uh why is
it not updating result yeah let's try it
again okay control CCC evaluate and I
don't remember what's the
let's evaluate the emac this so 3 +
three okay
evaluated okay there it is the up it
updated the result you see so let's say
3 +
10 so you see the result update becomes
13 now for the python part I don't know
something is wrong because it's not
updating the result let's say 3 + 10
when
it yeah it's not you know I have I have
to look into so anyway that that is the
um o Babble you can you can also edit
the code so what's a key for edit the
code you know it's uh fairly powerful
yeah a lot of people use it so contrl x
contrl s okay contrl X control
s file to save what what the [ __ ]
wait uh contrl C apostrophe actually
control C apostrophy there it is so you
can
see it uh you see it move the code to uh
a new pen so I'm done
exit CC okay
CC edit then exit CC okay contrl c
contrl
c oh
wait control C apostrophe yeah now I'm
back now
um gr it
yeah I don't know why for some reason
python does not insert the
result but anyway let's what I'm trying
to do is to look into the code
so so let me show you okay
so describe key
CC okay so so you are looking at Oak mod
map okay so go to the
go to the uh file so here is a source
code for the key contrl c contrl c in
org so now we go to diet so here is all
the org files now we hide
the the the details and you can search
for
bab okay we are trying to find the code
for Oak Babble but apparently see you
don't have a file name named bab oh
tangle okay I guess maybe they renamed
it uh let's let's
shrink so let's see what are
these Pearl or cam or Pearl so I guess
all these are or bble features uh for
example here we have
python uh here we have scheme
here we have
Ruby uh okay let's open Ruby okay so
yeah so this is part of Oak Babel I know
because Eric short short he wrote it in
the beginning about 10 years
ago uh and when I was implementing the
new language actually I emailed him to
ask him a question so you know about
five years ago I dived de deeply into
this so here's a source code you know B
to uh so yeah anyway I'm not going to
talk about that because that's going to
be too
technical okay I think that's it uh
anush does that answer your
question okay another uh keyboard
question best key binding for a
programmable keypad
had oh yeah that's interesting uh using
Sly Keys oh
uh well maybe that's it for
today made young girls use young you
might get in trouble just
saying okay I heard that APL was kind of
inspired by Chinese characters you
really I'm not sure about
that uh India okay
okay great thank you guys uh I think
that's it for
today I have a question about kesis
Advantage keyboard shoot just type your
questions you know type type your
questions now I answer them like right
away type it
now and that's it for
today any questions you have uh type now
and we're going to
close so as far as
programable
uh what key binding to use so I can show
you a programmable keypad so you just go
to my keypad just go to S programmable
keypad so I have Al on that and
essentially that's what I use okay I
showed this many times but
um so you can see my
keyboard This is my kesis advantage this
one and this is this is the
um ultimate hacking keypad so I use this
keypad key keyboard as my mro
programmable keypad so each one of these
key is a mar so for example this one is
the last app okay you see last window so
once in I I mean browser these two are
switching tabs okay previous tab you see
previous tab I can fly through them you
see and uh this button is close Okay
close or I made a mistake the
open you see close reopen see close
close close reopen reopen
reopen so and this one is uh uh full
screen and this is volume up and
down this uh this is screenshot and this
is uh size up size down so so that's how
I use my keypad
ducky pocket is the keypad on my watch
list I'm coning to upgrade okay uh I
just recently got the keypad keyboard
but it has the old
firmware okay so if you uh want some
idea about what keypad I mean what uh
shortcut to use on keyboard just go to
my
um you see I have I show a example for
example here is how I use my um actually
let me show you the live version
okay ultimate hacking keyboard the
software then that's it for
today uh if you like my stuff uh patreon
me p me or buy my emac tutorial or buy
my uh JavaScript in depth
tutorial okay here's here is my how I
use my
keypad it takes a while to
launch okay and you click on Mac so
automat hacking keyboard is the most
most
powerful and with the most easy to use
uh software to program the
keys okay so here is my current settings
for my keypad let me
explain so the
uh close window
reload reopen last
closed next tab previous tab copy URL in
current tab last
window cut copy paste select
all next window of the current
APP and this is a sync to my emac server
okay volume down volume up
screenshot copy to clipboard screenshot
but save to a
file zoom out zoom
in uh this is full screen toggle full
screen this is uh forward tab I mean
forward page backward
page uh this is you know open the find
the find the find file thing anyway some
some other esoteric this is new tab and
so on so that's what I that's how I
um that's my recommendation so so these
these shortcuts
are are used for uh General purpose in
any application so mostly they deal with
switching window in browsers you know
half of them deal with browsers because
browsers browser is the app we almost
everyone uses the
most then copy cut paste you know new
tab close tab refresh close window next
tab volume up down you know all one
single press so you don't have to
control old or
whatever okay that's it for today thank
you guys for watching uh bye my stuff
bye guys