welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh actually I'm not ready yet so let me
go to livestream I need to get my juice
you know my juice running and I'm alive
good morning break the loop so this is a
grape juice this is what I drink I drink
juice every day half a bottle almost
every day for for like 20 years this is
my water grape this is I always drink
hundred percent juice it must say 100
percent so no sugar nothing like that
you know sometimes it's apple juice
grape juice red grape or white grape
apple juice apple juice I love Pampa
juice and they must always be hundred
percent juice it says you know there's a
law that says you know in order to put
that hundred percent you must have you
know juice but they are usually made
from concentrate you know they not you
know supposed to you know the fresh
fruit juice is almost always better but
you know those are more expensive and
some people think that these juice you
know from concentrators and stuff they
don't think it's good actually I think
it's that's that's that's not true you
know there's no chemical there's no
chemical no sugar and that's all though
it's concentrated meaning you know they
extract the juice they evaporate the
water something like that then they add
water back but I don't think it's bad so
I've been drinking juice like this you
know it this is my like my water
for 40 years every day so today's topic
I don't have a topic actually I'm
thinking of going through YouTube and
you know going through YouTube stuff
because young YouTube you know talking
about random stuff non-technical
socially and commentary and about
programming communities and so on
because I noticed that a lot people I
mean even those who follow me they don't
really know you know like often I talk
about programming language design issues
or some esoteric detail like even
closure I got a comment from a friend
who follows me often and from a lot of
the people I got you know every time I
talk about something I don't know I
don't mean to point to you know like
particular person because actually this
is accumulated experience I mean I'm
talking about lots of guys from you know
who follow me and I have the sense that
and you know so one guy yeah I thought
you know he's in China and he studies
you know from what I see his post he
studies programming languages and he
studies Idriss which is a very advanced
you know the next generation of Haskell
basically and he also studied studies
racket scheme list you know so I thought
he must know closure but from his
comment you know he's made a comment on
my youtube saying that the saying that
you know it seems to suggest that
talking about closure is you know
difficult to listen to because you know
and but also you know like my topics
like I all many often talk about many of
these for me language design topics and
truly really they are not you know the
it's kind of advanced you know it's a
sorry state of things in society where
the more advanced the less people you're
gonna get you know watching you or
following you because that's kind of
just reality like you know if you talk
about math you know professional math
like professional mathematicians when
they talk about math you got if you are
really good you know like you know if
you are the best you know if you want
the world's most prestigious math Awards
like this guy you know some of them you
know they sometimes to videos you get
ten thousand people watching the video
it at most that you know that that's
suppose you are the best in a world you
know out of seven billion people you
know you got thirty thousand people in
general if you are just let's say you
are random math professor
you know you teach math you know that's
your job you teach math every day but
the number of people you know who watch
the video you know under thousands you
know that's kind of a sad state of
things on the other hand those [ __ ]
teen girls they watch makeup videos
makeup makeup drama makeup and gamers on
youtube [ __ ] chameleon ten ten
million followers you know and there are
thousands of them ten million followers
you know what the [ __ ]
so so I'm thinking so I might talk about
programming languages you know this is
at heart too esoteric esoteric for me
language design issues closure ontology
of programming languages you know I get
the feeling that you know the streets
really not that many people I mean so I
mean this is this are my followers you
know you guys but still in general not
you know there's a lot less people but
if I talk about
you know none technical topic like what
happening what's the drama improving
communities the drama in emacs dev
communities richest oh man oh what he
did again then you got then people bump
it up you know drama ISM always like
this this thing you know people just
like your drama is attraction central
central attraction hi Andrew so let me
read the comments I have a question for
you great have you ever had a conflict
with a co-worker I guess I have yes
was there ever a co-worker that you
disliked or did not get along with yeah
absolutely
why did you dislike them and how did it
work out okay I let me tell you so my my
job experience with you know you know
cooperation it's not you know just a few
years so in 1995 a wolf I'm research has
half a year but there was a big story
you know I was an intern okay I was
supposed to be your intern I was
supposed to be just there for a month
for the summer of 1995 but I ended up
staying for half a year and I left okay
but you know but so the during the short
time I was there I made he I was you
know decided this you know the there's
company forums you know private to the
company where the program was there you
know employees talk about chat random
things so they are talking about
something I forgot you know they're
talking and so I I was you know I also
join in the chat and I was talking I was
talking about my experience of one day I
microwaved
a spider okay spider you microwave of an
oven you know it's not something you
know it's not something that I'm proud
to talk about but as you can see this is
not something you wanna you want to you
know say I I forgot what is the context
I think they are comparing
like you know this is 1995 remember this
is very different from today's kind of
things so but so 1995 and you know most
of the people programmers are nerds you
know let's talk about these things all
the time and they are comparing like
hooves what's the strangest thing you
did something so I was you know I was I
was I was I was not a you know social
person with tact so I did it I just
talked about you know one day I was
putting a spider in a microwave and that
blew up and you know then then I made my
enemies you know so but I don't remember
that you know that's this is 1995 so
it's like 25 years ago I know there are
some people I kind of you know I don't
remember the name so but that's that's
known ago okay so that's one thing but
so my other work experiencing a
corporation is around 1998 to 2002
Edna Tapia and we are startup we have
like five engineers I mean I mostly it's
Natalia but I worked you know a year
before that at dream power which which
is a start-up you know it's all startups
so but anyway not hope yet they are
people who don't like I don't get not
really I don't really have you know like
God you know I typically don't you don't
you know in a social situation I don't I
usually keep to myself I don't express
my views but I know that I'm kind of odd
odd Paul you know they find you weird
because I'm a ski so it I don't talk to
people I'm a loner you know the the way
people understand is by the way by the
word loner I prefer to be alone
you know and in social situations like
going a meeting
I usually don't speak up because when I
do speak of its kind it tends to be like
everyone is like shark
you know maybe your offensive or
something okay but anyway but it's
different now here in my you know
because I'm doing video this is so talk
show you are seeing well you know I'm
talking whatever I want you know I don't
I don't have you know social environment
that limits me except you know Google
they are doing censorship anyway so in
social meetings I usually you know when
they talk about some ideas or decisions
or something I usually don't speak up
I've wondered why because I know why
because this may be offensive to to for
me to say because you know usually like
their ideas you know I don't like like
like usually I don't speak up then but
when you stunt speak up people think you
are not you know you maybe they think
you don't have you know they think you
are not yeah I mean you are technically
speaking you are not contributing
because in a meeting you supposed to you
know everyone you know if you have a
pinion you say it you know maybe they
have some question about engineering
design decision what should we do should
we do it this way or that way
you know but usually I don't because
because I you know I know myself you
know I am NOT to you know I'm often not
fluent in social situations and I'm
usually not able to speak my mind
communicate what my my ideas in a smooth
manner you know no more way no more
people okay [ __ ] [ __ ] no more people you
know so so so I know that I mean this is
it's just for me experience so I don't
usually speak up and often their
decisions their thoughts are idiotic
okay to me because usually when they
talk about some decisions I can take I
know right away this is wrong this is
just this is factually wrong you are
thinking you know this is just wrong
and I mean I also have my personal floss
okay so because you know I tend to be
eyes as far as I know I observed from
people's reaction I tend to be let's say
some people call me Mac the Mac no
maniac macro maniac you know you know
and always concerned about myself you
know my fine intelligence so anyway so I
so so usually I don't speak up and often
when they talk about things I can tell
right away they are wrong but I'm not
able to you know come up and hey you
know says express myself in a smooth
manner you know say oh oh I hope you
know like for example when some wing in
a meeting let's say in a decision they
asked a question you know what what's
you you guys opinion and and if you know
right away there's a mistake there you
know you might you might you know raise
your hand or something and say oh by the
way I saw that situation you know last
year and so therefore this is actually
the right way is this way then people oh
yeah yeah oh oh thanks
you know they understand but I cannot
did you know I cannot do that without
effort without you know you know so so
usually I if I say something ends up
like no that's just stupid
you know directly like that that's
idiotic
okay that's so so there's that and then
there's also the issue of conflict like
you know when like you know so in this
meeting you have a question and everyone
you know they asked your opinions so if
I say that my opinion then some people
may not agree okay so you know I say
okay a string should be you should call
this function to do to it let's say I
say that but then they then let's say my
coworker let's say even a friend you
know in my meeting in a meeting he say
none actually no that's not true because
you know this or that you know maybe he
raised that issue but then you know if I
agree then that's fine but if I don't
agree
again I'm not able to express my my
disagreement in a smooth way you know I
started to just say things that's you
know that unpopular and you know you
know yeah so you know this is all about
you know social interaction and
disabilities it's well it's something
you know something along that line of
you know not able to interact with
people in a smooth way and also because
of all these reasons also I tend usually
when I have a pinion and this happens in
my my in my video as well like I kind of
think you know you everyone knows that
already so I don't say it you know I
don't I don't you know I feel like if I
say it then it's like maybe I'm too
flashy you know the you know
self-conscious you know that so I don't
usually I don't do that but you know as
I'm doing more videos I you know I this
you know in the past month past half a
year I started to you know you learn
things so I started to talk more
smoothly about you know things I want to
say especially I mean the important the
point here there's one point I want to
mention is that actually the lot of
things when I'm talking about sometimes
I can't die tend to like just hand
waving you know not talking about
something too much but actually I should
you know you should just confidently
when we went even small things take your
time the confidence to confidently talk
about that express it fully because
actually about people they just don't
know you know that's that's that's
that's that's that's what
the about that question okay it seems
that there's a lot comments let me
answer them so how many people five let
me guess 800 people so yeah so know it
makeup videos yeah hey sorry hey Andrew
what's your sleep schedule yeah I
mentioned that several times I don't
have one this is surprising and it's
hard to stick to for people to realize
like I do not really have is sleeping
schedule that means in the past 20 years
at least I sometimes sleep in the
daytime like in you know sleep at 8 o
clock in the morning and wake up at you
know - okay
something like that sometimes I sleep at
10 o clock in the morning and wake up
you know sometimes I do two cycles per
day so I sleep for four hours wake up
for four for eight hours or for you know
something like that then sleep again for
four hours do this for half a year so
before the pass at least 20 years it's
like that you know you know but when I
have if I have a job of course you
cannot usually you cannot do that but
when typically when I have a job the
situation is I stay up at night until
like five or six Simoni
yeah so I don't have a sleep sleeping
schedule so that is why you see me round
the clock you know the word time around
the car now so let me show you a video
graph okay it's day and night let's
let's show you go to Emacs blog search
for day and night and search it
so this is 2009 January what is it I
don't know what it is it's such for I
know not let's search for actually let's
go to my image directory and let's
search for github Jesus every time I
want to find something I cannot find it
something way can I write okay let's
search for night let's search for our
what let's search for day get ok so
let's go to programming block then sorry
dot info let's search for let's go to
image directory let's search for night
let's search for github
let's see what is this this is github
oh yeah that's stupid github let's
search for let's see what is this github
angry pink unicorn I let's search for
asleep
no match okay let's go to sleep yeah I
have a you know github they used to have
a graph that shows you the hours you
contributed over the past month or over
the past you or something I forgot
what's a period but if you look at you
know so I have a screenshot of my graph
you know the dots of the hours
throughout 24 hours a day it's easy you
know it's all over there is no empty
period but I cannot find the image I
feel like I'm you know I have to find
that image now good heart of kids
okay good morning Aldo so let me read
you just let me read the comments then
break the loop says you know what is a
crazy thing on YouTube open opening toys
video for kids they get like 10 million
views oh my god
no I didn't know that so let's go to
YouTube the source of drama and
everything YouTube is fantastic so you
tube opening toys okay
opening toys by the way I've been trying
to look up the Lex Lex Skye you told me
yesterday break the loop the leg Skye so
then I ran into these Stefan wolf arms
video max Friedman I haven't found out
what exactly he likes Friedman is the
dead Joe Rogan's video I watched the
first like 15 minutes or 20 minutes
it seems pouring I haven't you know and
he does not seems to have a Wikipedia
entry 100 toy openings that's amazing
you have a kid
break the loop you know yeah so video
YouTube the videos on YouTube are
amazing
like I talked about it yesterday it's
like a sea you know you can you only
know like a drop in the ocean like you
don't know what is out there unless you
know a word to search for you know so
it's like I mean I have never come
across you know all these video or toy
opening videos but you know apparently
like you said they are like thousands of
them and by the way also about half a
year ago Tim Tim cast Tim poor Tim cast
this guy reported on news where they
have these creepy videos for children
that
you know it's like bored it's really
creepy it's extremely extremely weird
and also it's it's being on the news for
the recent yield also that they are
apparently there are alot para knows
their children or child to make youtube
videos so apparently that there seems to
be a lot videos of children I mean not
adult is just children you know doing
video YouTube videos and apparently
there are a lot views you know you make
money so you know because there's being
on the news that some parents are
abusing their kids to force them to make
youtube videos because I suppose after a
while the kid the kids gets tired you
know they maybe sometimes they don't
want to but the parents says you have to
old you know beat them or something like
that so yeah so YouTube is just
incredible you know so and also the
other thing I mentioned the in the other
talk is that the video format today the
technology allow us to do the video
format is actually far more natural
significantly then then reading and
writing
you know then textual information
textual information is kind of
artificial you know we programmers or
lots of nerds
you know think you know reading and
writing is the best thing it's a
literature it's the you know it's the
educated way to learn things so but but
it's actually it's kind of you know
advanced level because the video format
with human expression and talking
directly that is actually magnitude more
natural and and I think that is also the
reason things like YouTube exploded you
know that I get tremendous videos
because most people you know you you
know you just want you you are not every
day you are not spending you are not
thinking oh and
to master something I need to learn some
new knowledge you know it's not like
that you know most people vast majority
including us programmers we just you
know you spend your day you want to
watch videos even for learning you don't
want to like you know almost like a
professor you know like doing a research
you know you know it's not like that you
just you know watch videos that's very
natural thing so when I first found out
about them like opening egg toys videos
I was flabbergasted how many millions of
views they got yeah it's quite amazing
so let's see let's order them by theater
sort by view count Oh
oh my god this one is nine hundred
sixty-seven million views and it's only
three years ago Wow
so so let me you know guess how much
money this particular video made in
general it's like 1,000 views gives you
one dollar so 967 million views is is
like nine hundred sixty seven thousand
dollars yeah that's how much you earn so
this video by itself is earning 1
million dollars my god what is it you
know and YouTube you know the Google
organization they knew it you know they
have all the stats they don't you know
they are extremely evil they don't you
know they always appear you know in the
in Google blocks and so on to tell us
how we are helping humanity and so on
this or that but act you know these
things they know and they know you know
like I mean
you know teamcast reported half a years
ago this thousands of extremely creepy
children's videos that talk about for
example they talk about spider-man that
they have cartoon of spider-man okay
something
spider-man is taking a you know a shot
in the ass you know the like the you
know syringe the you know the needles
and spider-man piece pieces on you know
some of the pieces on eggs or something
you know very weird and things you can
you can find it if you search I suppose
if you such children spider-man key you
you'll find those kind of reports so
that was on the news you know you have
like thousands of them and they are
making a lot money and YouTube you know
it's I'm pretty sure YouTube you know
Google they know it but they haven't had
no not saying anything because it's
money it's money for them so anyway so
so when I first found out okay so leave
a kid along with an iPad their watch
videos like ten times
yeah good money and true yeah that's
what I heard you know because you know
the algorithm just keeps fraying the
morning Jack do good morning to China
why do I use Mac OS actually I answer
that you know before too as well because
the basis basically the reason is that I
got this Mac OS free Mac OS Mini free
from a professor because I did work for
him so that's my keyboard that's my
mouse it's like I'm showing this every
time I do a video so I got a Mac OS Mini
in 2000
17 you know he gave me free and sigh so
it's good and by the way my go is is is
is just good that I talked about this a
few times you know I used Mac OS from
1991 to 2008 or 2009 then I used Windows
for three years then I used the Linux
for four years and by the way I was
Solaris sis of the mean from 2000 from
1998 to 2002 you know so I came from the
UNIX background and and then X sucks
donkey ass by a magnitude you know all
that things you hear from the Linux
people they say it's it's complete
[ __ ] you your brains are completely
completely brainwashed like there's no
comparison scientifically in any way so
if you are the type of guy who says oh I
usually no exam then as compared to Mac
OS Oh in Windows is is is about the same
or even better I mean even if you say
it's about same your brain you got a
problem okay you can ask me to explain
that if you want anyone I'll explain in
detail you are like you you are actually
technically you are you are kind of
delusional you you you and that's that's
not surprising either I mean it's not
you know don't be surprised by that
because a lot of people in code you know
food you know you code they they they
you know they believe impossible things
such as the end is coming you know the
enemy's coming UFO is you know we are
controlled by aliens they are really a
lot of people seriously believing that
and this did in code you get you know
they are quite a lot of the Scientology
Falun Gong and Moon you know quite a lot
and also this ties to religion you know
religion you know I don't care I'd you
know you know religion do you believe
you know lots of things
you know God Adam you know women is made
a rib of a bone from a man you know then
some people you know you may think oh
that's just allegory you know it's just
it's not you know of course you don't
really believe that it's true but
actually a lot of people to believe that
you know so when you look at these
people
religion know people in code obviously
you know - so you can see it clearly
they are kind they are kind of
delusional but also it gives you it
shows you concretely how people can
believe something why other people you
know it's just pre past preposterous to
most other people so in my belief in my
opinion okay it's the same way happening
to the you know those people who like to
say that Linux is better better than Mac
OS you know yeah maybe in the server
okay but not as a desktop I'm talking
about as user interface desktop how easy
to use how easy to install
I see for my followers I still have
people you know trying to tell me that
he live exist I have no problem it has a
you are delusional
sorry why I switched to PC okay so this
is after I explained how wires we
switched from Mac to Windows in 2009
yeah so I switched to Windows I used I
was on Windows for like as my desktop
okay for like three or four years then I
switched to Linux about three years or
four then in 2017 August and back to Mac
because I got a free Mac you know and as
far as which is better and so on you
know the it's which one is whether they
stay the same
for the past 20 years basically Linux is
great I really love Linux because it's
not controlled by corporations
you know corporations control things
they have greed they have you know
possible government backdoors they have
whatever you know and and you pay you
have to pay every month every year okay
so Linux this way but however it's also
the worst of you know what's almost in
every way every way how you use the
system as a desktop at least okay in
Linux is the worst thing every way you
know it it wastes your time you know I
have you know if anyone wants me to talk
about this in technical details I can do
that for one hour
I mean I'm gimpy I'm going to give you
technical programming kernel whatever
memory usage technical details how Linux
is just a magnitude was they Mac or
Windows okay but it's not just that what
I want to say I'd you know I don't
really want that I because when I'm
using the notes you know it's open
source it's free I really wanted to be
great successful you know but it just
you know it's so sad it's not happening
and the you know it's it's it's just it
never is it will never happen is you
know we being I mean I mean I've been
open source for 20 years you know the
Linux open source free software started
30 years ago 40 years ago almost you
know so I I really want to it to succeed
but it's not why I can tell you why
directly short answer because it's a
coat because it has formed into this
code thinking you know this everyday you
see people talking about oh I use Linux
I think it's great it's even easier to
use the Mac or Windows it's is you know
it's better Linux is is not you know
it's in this worst state because of
these people because these people they
they they it's a it's a code therefore
you have this
Tonetta and and now this ideology often
saw part of it is open source you
believe you want to believe in ideology
you have a vision but but your vision so
what do you see what you do what you
perceive is not reality so every day you
keep saying fake news basically force
stuff you keep saying when Linux is
apparently to any person in the world to
your dad to your parents to any worker
apparently it's the worst one but you
keep saying oh it's no problem it's
actually better than window it is these
people that you know that forever keeps
Linux not going anywhere it's like this
it's not gonna going anywhere it's it's
really kind of sad yeah I I know these
kind of things because you know I'm I
wallow in a community of open-source in
UNIX that that is my community I'm a
nerd I'm a hacker type you know so you
know when people ask me what do I use
Mac you know usually I'm guessing you
are leaning you know you not not used
specifically but you know I get this
question a lot you know I can tell you
know a lot of my followers you know I
into Linux way a lot of them and they
also Mac OS users and yeah and Mac OS
users Mac OS is yeah so its own problems
okay Linux has this trouble the good
thing about Linux is it's open its open
source okay and it's you know it that's
good but it's actually technically as
far as desktop goes it's a worst it's
not just was between Mac and Windows
it's the it's a magnitude was it's it's
worse to the situation there's no
comparison okay whatever you hear
whatever opinions that's not this it's
just it's just delusional that's my
opinion and I can you know if you know I
know there's a Luke Smith guy and anyway
anyway if you want if you don't you want
the argument I can debate with you you
know I I can talk about this for hours
okay that's Linux but Mac has its own
problems you know Mac and Windows Mac is
you know the Apple corporation Apple
Corporation in the 1990s is truly the
the most internet innovative company in
the world they they advanced computer to
the to the masses by you know it did you
know they amended desktop publishing
which in turn you know give us a lot
freedoms you know the it moves the
publishing business out of you know into
homes into each person you can you know
begin to publish publish and so on you
have laser printers that you have the
first one to bundle with CD player units
they are the first one to actually push
Mouse forward you know Mouse for every
one computer mouse they are the first
one to introduce graphical user
interface truly that makes people you
know actually be able to use computers
not just nerds
they are also the first sort you know
lots of you know they are also the first
to to have us be building like they
follow technology innovation like they
are innovation Apple you know Apple
throughout 1990s up to about 2005 I
would say okay well actually you can say
let's say to 2010
okay giving them credit so Apple is
great but then but then but the other
thing is Apple is like cooperation and
they squeeze money at every possible way
they can you know so comparatively Apple
products the same power you know the
same CPU the same memories and all the
same apples computer is like twice as
expensive right
try so one half times more expensive
than a PC okay and you know exact same
mouse you know every peripheral if it's
sold for Windows let's say it's $50 but
if it's sold for Mac
it's $100 that's that applies to any
almost every peripheral mouse pain or
whatever you know that's that's a
situation so Apple has also associated
with these snobby elite kind of
community people the Mac users they are
fanatic
yeah they you know so this so this this
is kind of problem okay but I was still
I was a Apple fan through our 1990s but
however since maybe around 2010 Apple
has become a I would say rather
extremely evil and also they ceased they
have ceased in innovation kind of you
know Apple also created the phone for us
you know how we everyone has a phone now
smartphone that's because of Apple you
know Microsoft you know they try to do
it they failed because Apple has the
knack of marketing you know so-called
you know Steve Jobs is a greatest
salesman anyway so much Apple but in in
the past five or so years
Apple has become one of the I would say
rather a very evil company you know in
the ethical sense similar it's just like
Google Google and Facebook they for
example all these companies you know
they have 1,000 patents they see you
each other they do whatever they can
they hire you know the most expensive
load lawyers you Apple suing Microsoft
suing Google Google suing Apple because
you know they do that but meanwhile they
lie you know Apple they say they are
going they are you know using recycled
material and all that [ __ ] but
actually they they prevent you from
fixing Apple products
now this stays this this fact is
becoming very popular you search you
find all or articles or video YouTube
videos about that you know they prevent
people from fixing a perform or or
your Mac you know they they they build
things so that they are you know
integrated not replaceable you cannot
replace it because why because they want
you to buy a new Mac every one year or
two or new phone every time there's a
new phone they they push their software
so that your phone becomes slower now
that is extremely evil that that is
illegal okay so people are suing Apple
for that but but it's not just this one
incident you know so you begin to see
there's lots of you know for example the
for example I show you this Apple thing
okay
you see app of this Activity Monitor
okay let me show you so you have this
Activity Monitor this is like CPU
monitor like you know Linux top then you
have this energy panel you know the
energy panel so supposedly it shows you
energy impact you know oh how great it
is you know so why why this panel
suppose they actually don't know but I
do know what's what they want to achieve
here it's kind of like it tells you they
are trying to be you know lately they
are trying to save energy you know for
the environment and so on
but meanwhile they prevent people fixing
their phone so every year every you know
you have tens of thousands millions of
phone just throw away you know like we
we are entering this era so every two
years when there's a new phone what do
you do with your phone you you know you
either sell it or throw away use when
you when you sow it eventually people
are gonna throw away too because you
know you know you throw away phone that
you know that's so anyway so that's
Apple and Microsoft is pretty much the
same story Microsoft you know they they
are product GUI is not as good as Apple
it just kind of stupid but however it's
much better its usable and much better
than Linux okay Mike you know Microsoft
and when you buy a computer usually it's
bundled you know
you you know you can use it but then
there's you know they you don't know if
they are tracking you you know all those
kind of things
Microsoft is renowned for you know so
yeah so you have these three choices
Linux Mac or Windows yeah neither one of
them is really great so if you ask me if
I have which one would I get that
depends if I have money I probably just
buy Apple you know if I let's say if I
have a job you know
I'll buy Apple out you know just use
Apple now if I have if I don't have
money like right now and a lot of people
watch me I know
so are these kind of weird very poor
situation no money no job not working
you know this one no you're wandering
around then obvious choice is Linux what
can you do you know you know yeah you
know but if you are average people then
you just go with Microsoft you know
Microsoft it's not very expensive you
know then especially if you are chemists
you know then you just buy a PC with
Microsoft so ok that's that's a lot talk
on that topic let's see five people
watching
okay so Lex treatment is an engineer
academic working on alternate autonomous
driving at MIT okay he also has his own
podcast interviewing people okay so like
that Stefan what gufa what okay I do not
have kids okay no plan to oh my friend
has two kids and I've been seeing them
watching opening toy videos
imagine making millions of dollars
opening toys on camera unbelievable yeah
so I'm going to watch you know this
video later just to see just to see what
the hell it is
yeah so I guess they just play you know
opening toys and opening toys and play
with it you know it's only seven minutes
this video got them 1 million dollars my
god so yeah so about making money you
know there's a lot opportunities out
there I think so you know I think that's
true there's really a lot opportunities
you have to find it you just have to
find it so so andrew says how did you
get the Emax toolbar to blend in with
that background I said I talked that you
know someone asked me this before the
the this this this that is a bug
actually because if I helps on a second
oops so if I open a new window you see
this is how it should look like you know
with a bar a top but not on the others
for example for example let me close
this window so I you can see the bar
here right now hold on a second
now I'm gonna create Emacs and go to my
terminal and start it again you will see
that bar disappears this is a bug in
Emacs 26 I'm sure I'm not sure exactly
why it happens you know you see it's
actually it's actually no good you know
but I've got you know I've just got used
to it it's you see if I open a new
window the bar shows up again so that is
actually a bug into Emacs 26
maybe you could write record and upload
a video on this channel about why Linux
is worse it may be quite successful what
if one if then right since all the tech
youtubers yeah I'm thinking I've been
thinking about that because you know
right now with my talk show the way it
is going is not going anywhere you know
each video you get 50 watches so maybe a
hundred you know and and I know why
because I'm talking random I don't have
fixed topics and you know sometimes just
rambling and and no fixed schedule so
people don't know when to come out and
what topic it is and I also mentioned
this several times in my talks because
but but I also I also know what to do if
I really want to become popular for
example instead of you know instead of
like live chat you know live childish
usually is not good you do a video
10-minute you know one way to learn is
always watch other people how other
people do watch how you know other
successful people so for example you go
to youtube you see a lot of people have
millions followers you know you look at
them I have I have done that you know
what kind of topics and and what what it
what what what style how long it the
video lasts you know you know I have
done that because you know also I'm
doing websites so I know a lot about
these things so for example if I want to
be popular you know first of all stop
swearing like [ __ ] [ __ ] me so [ __ ] that
okay so stop that because that's not you
know that's not conductive to your you
know to to to get a lot of followers
okay then you know be focus like you
know every day you have to follow a
schedule this is important if you want
to be popular or make money okay every
day at specific time let's say 8 o clock
to 10 o clock in the morning okay post a
video like 10 minutes
fifteen minutes focus on a specific
topic you know I have you know for
example for me I might I might do it for
you know Emacs every day just do a short
Emacs topic that will be popular because
you know a lot of people they don't they
don't care about your opinions of
philosophy they want to you know learn
something that's that's one way to go
okay I mean there so there are many
styles but one of the ways you know I
focus on Emacs every day 10 minutes
short Emacs tutorial something about
Emacs maybe once in a while I talk about
the Emacs community you know as a
non-technical one you know talk about
Richard Stallman what's going on you
know give people updates you know do
that regularly you know and maybe once
every week or every two weeks I do a
live show like you know life then people
can ask me questions so that's that's
one way to go I'm pretty sure that way
you know you'll get more popular and you
know you'll be more popular but but
that's not me okay that's that's because
if I want to do that then maybe I've
already I would have you know just work
in your company that would make you know
no brainers ten thousand dollars a month
but then so that's one way or the other
way is you know so if you don't want if
you want you know Emacs for all it's
worth it's really a niche subject you
know if you talk about Emacs the the
most you can have the audience is very
limited and also particularly because of
the open source Emacs is heavily tied to
free software and open source
communities so these people in general
you know they are nerds or hackers in
general they don't pay you know you know
you a lot of people may not agree you
may not agree but in general they don't
hate they don't either they are poor
themselves you know they are like just
wandering jobless you know or they have
you know they have strong belief in open
source and free software foundation okay
but these beliefs do not prevent you
from paying you still can pay people but
in general they don't they are like that
that's why I don't like this open source
you know they are kind of easy eat
ideology okay at one time they say oh we
will donate you know don't put ads you
know I like it I like your website very
much I will put money to it I don't like
Google ads take it off you know yeah
when when ads becomes a issue on the
news everyone says that
in reality nobody does it okay oh no
Avensis do that year a few if you put
ads you have hundred times more money
that's because I know I because that's I
have done this for like 20 years you
know you you ask for donation you get
you know ten dollars a month you don't
ask for donation you put Google ads you
get hundred you get the thousand you
know a hundred dollars a month a few
hundred okay if you don't do anything
else just you know slap on ads and
forget about it yeah you so so you get
hungry time so more money you you know
so that's one thing so open source free
software Emacs people you know you don't
you know you are not going to make money
out of them not not 10% from make enough
to be for living okay not forget about
that you know you do be happy if you can
get a if if the money you make from
doing Emacs tutorial can can supply you
with food money then that's you should
be happy enough you know you because the
Emacs people this or that they don't pay
okay so so Emacs is a niche thing so you
know and I mean Emacs for 20 years I
heard all the talks and and it's not
doing me any good good you know and you
spend you spend like I spend like full
time on it you know let's say three
hours a day every day
Saturday and Sunday you know you don't
get money and you know all my packages
and you know yeah this you know these
people so I really this day so he'll
really despise these open source people
then then then you have the hypocrites
okay this there are a lot of people you
know they they work for Google they work
for Facebook a day so they make $10,000
a month twenty thousand dollars a month
they reach in fat they have you know all
Apple toys they can buy any Apple best
computer when it comes out or Apple came
out with a new Mac you know they buy it
right away
then next year they you know they get a
new one you know they they have all the
toys so they have they drive Tesla you
know oh yeah we are saving the earth
they drive Tesla and so on but then at
night they to open-source you say oh
yeah I'm for the good of the world that
so they do open source coding you know
they they want to do open source so what
does that mean that means they they rob
they these people fed you know being fed
from this extremely evil and greedy
corporations none open-source okay the
Google product they you know the is not
open source my ass some of them okay
just for the public relations but any
you know they they are 100 patents there
are thousands of patents Google Facebook
you know or these companies so this
program must work for them at night then
they do open source oh yeah they they
they check out their software put on
github so what does this does what's the
effect that means they they rob oh the
other open-source programmers I like me
okay who do not work for this greedy
evil corporations because I have this I
cannot compete with them they have the
tools and everything and they work in
the corporate environment then they
churn out you know library says also use
this you know you cannot even compete
because as you know you go
github everything there's a library and
they are all pushing for their libraries
you know they are all pushing oh yeah
the especially these corporate [ __ ]
these open-source programmers who work
for Google and Facebook by date you know
they work at Google by night they say we
are open source and they push their you
know their own libraries like like on
our Mac maggot on the Emacs repository
they push you cannot compete them
because they create beautiful logos you
know they have time they create
beautiful animations and they have a
bunch of followers because open-source
fat oh yeah we also so all the open
source fans support him you know push
magic magic and and all the helm and you
know software they they they become this
giant thing you know and what I do i
what what can I do Oh sod that guy that
guy [ __ ] that that's a [ __ ] he
complains about open source all day and
night and you know he swear at people
you know and you don't get followers yes
so that's what happens this so this so
this what they are doing they are just
hypocrite they are just these these
programmers were open so why they open
source they make they feel better so
they can feel better working for Google
you know taking the dirty money you know
there are two to two thousand twenty
thousand a month and they feel they feel
good oh I'm I'm an open source I'm for
the you know good of the world then did
then though I help women I help the poor
the feminism social justice that's what
happens that's what they are
okay so back to the question so yeah as
far as you know making money that's you
know so I you know a twofold for my own
videos you know so besides Emacs there
are a lot of other ways I can do I can
talk about you know anyway the thing is
you know that's that's not my thing okay
you know I I am poor for a reason
because because I can't do that
you know I don't want to I don't want to
do things you know that's kind of
dictated by money you know so my idea is
you know I do whatever I you know I do
whatever I do if you you know if if
people [ __ ] you know if you've followed
me and you liked it then you put money
yeah that's the ideal you know if
everyone can do that is in a society
that that would be actually a true
you know like utopia of the open source
kind of way you know you you do things
people like it people donate you know
but you know but in the reality that's
not actually happens you know 1000 when
you're it's more like 1000 people like
your stuff you know they like not not
not just me okay I can I having I know
other people you know Tim poo and many
people I have I have observed this kind
of things you know a lot of people on
YouTube you know they make all this
videos great content some people that
you follow them all the time but you
don't pay basically 1000 people you know
maybe you get one one people you know
paying you for it and also me one of
these corporations you know they they
become they they are so powerful and you
know Google Facebook and Microsoft and
also news organizations they they create
fake news to they did they kind of just
like they they create you know by
whatever means they can you know with
money with their powerful money they
create situations so that so that they
will thrive forever more you know the
money will come to them forever more
where are those of you you know who are
you know independent that you know
insignificant
individual person you are going to get
less and less powerful and they they
actually like company like Google they
act
we intentionally force that to happen by
by quite a lot of ways okay and so today
I see those open-source people you are
like you are just you are doing good to
nobody and in fact you are doing harm to
yourself you know you become this niche
forever niche and niche and niche and
powerless group that in society
borderline on being illegal because
Google and Facebook and you know every
day they point at you look at these you
know you know and they have newspapers
you know they have wide propaganda
that's ten thousand times then whatever
you say people will believe like you
cannot even believe what you read you
know how do you know what is true you
don't know these days you know hacker
cans can be bought
you know like today maybe you have so
much into open source and tomorrow
microsoft says hey you are hired you
know come on board and you run you run
into go work work for Microsoft you know
and you're thinking change you you start
to think oh yeah
I am going to join Microsoft you know
you make a blog announcer I'm going to
join Microsoft but I'm there to to help
them change their mind to push for open
source that's a lie that's that's a lie
you tell yourself so that you can work
for Microsoft you know that's that's
basically what human people do that's
you know human nature that's that's how
if you don't you know pay attention to
human nature used that's how the word
are is the way they are so let's see so
so let's see the comments and imagine
making media so how did I again you max
so Andrew says maybe you could write
okay so
so big loops that break the roof says
did you hear the news about the United
States
barring companies from working with
Hawaii Hawaii Huawei yeah that's a
that's big news for the past few months
so how ways Android phones will not get
updated after three months and we all
now have access to Google store apps oh
I didn't know about that that yeah but
I've been here I've been hearing that on
the news for the past three months and
and actually I know some of these
stories are not true some I don't know
the details for sure
I haven't actually you know studied that
the issue but from you know little I
have seen I know there are some articles
that's just propaganda for example I
think by I don't remember where but but
usually by news you know US news
organizations like New York Times or you
know these big corporations they they
publish or some of the academia you know
that like front end of the government
government backed or corporation backed
front end some academic organic group
okay they published a study like they
published a study about how far away you
know exactly what is Huawei is tie with
China's government okay so in this study
or paper you know like you know academic
paper they like supposedly independent
they will say basically the conclusion
is that is that Huawei is actually just
a front-end of Chinese government okay
that's that's basically that's what they
want to tell you okay so meaning that
you know mean that on a surface where is
the cooperation but actually no it's
just China that the government of China
so therefore you know we should spend
far way because you know you know China
is controlling the chips and so on so
that paper is just force their paper is
a propaganda that that I'm pre
I know for sure okay let's say
ninety-nine ninety-nine percent I you
know I'm not going to devote you know
days to study research this issue but
anyway I'm like 99% sure that that
public eight that paper is just blatant
propaganda like so many we have so many
of that today like if you are really
interested like today information they
are sea of information but it's
different from twenty years ago when
internet was not there okay
today even we have we have sea of
information we are buried by info and
half of it you know almost all of it is
fake news but the difference between
today and thirty years ago is that today
if you as a person if you really want to
know the truth you can find out first of
all remove all the prejudice or bias you
have within yourself for example like if
you are American you know pretend you
are Chinese you know you pretend you are
you know you are painting with someone
for $10,000 or you know one month of
your pay your whatever you make for one
month you are making a bet such that you
want to create a report a proof that
Chinese is right China is right okay
whatever is the issue but US is actually
the bad guy you know first of all
pretend that you know then you try to do
this research in other words you know
you want to look both ways okay yeah so
today's situation there's a sea of
information but each person if you
really want to know the truth you can
find out you can actually you know
digging website from website you know
infamy you'll find out you know what is
true what is not true
but there's a problem the problem is
once you found out you know you found
out so many truth what you're gonna do
is almost nothing you can do
yeah that's the situation today because
because you know I have looked a lot
into a lot of things you know take an
example for my for my for example let's
say my my opinion about Linux my opinion
about open source free software or or
Emacs you know maybe you say I'm biased
but let's suppose I'm not for a moment
ok so I know this truth about UNIX you
know open open so what am I gonna do
there's nothing I can do because they
are an army there's an army of
open-source it is an ideology ok this
also there are thousands of open-source
fans whatever you say the moment you say
let's say I'm quitting suppose I'm using
the Linux and I run into a problem
that's really a stupid problem ok nasty
problem suppose I post on Twitter you
are going to get like you know a lot of
people they were immediately tell you no
no you should contribute your code no
you are wrong because you know whatever
you say gets wipe out you know the same
thing if you post read it you know
nobody you get banned or you get thumbs
down nobody gonna see it you know that's
that's what happens on Twitter as well
so this is suppose you know suppose I'm
talking about Linux and stuff
Emacs stuff but anyway but you can
imagine you know something about palette
politics some issue on the news that you
dig you really know the truth you know
what you're gonna do then what you're
gonna do next
this is it's very hard to do anything
because because you try to say it on
Twitter you get banned you know they
they they then you know these
corporations they spread propaganda like
that's what that's the meaning of
propaganda they find all possible ways
you know the FBI the government you know
they have psychologists you know who
specializes in you know human
controlling thought you know they have
all you know you know so this is very
little you can do
so it's the round corner versus straight
edge I forgot what's that about yeah
so I M W says isn't that like the same
thing as putting ads on your page
doesn't that make you a bit of a
hypocrite no no let me explain that okay
now I personally believe that everyone
is a hypocrite in some way yeah that's
true but let me explain my website so I
have a web site beginning in 1997 okay I
don't have a domain in 1997 I don't have
a domain of my own but back in 99 1997
my website my the domain is best calm
and Tod saw okay sorry I think 6i that
is my domain
okay I mean that's my URL back in 1997
to 2000 and you can still find traces of
it you know from web archive link to
that website by this told me okay so
anyway so if you search if you try to
search this string you'll find history
of it okay
so from 1997 to 2000 that is my URL then
in 2000 I have sorry dog okay
and I don't have any ads I don't have in
fact the entire Emacs tutorial my entire
you next tutorial is seeing a zip file
download you know you can click to
download three no ads the entire unix
tutorial so anyway so from from from
2000 to 2009 or 2010 I have solid oak
they're just one domain one domain and
everything is free I don't have any ads
okay and people download my Emacs
suitable I I have logs you know I have
logs oh my god you know it
I have gone through poverty that I lost
files left and right so I don't know so
but I may still I think that this I
think is somewhere there I have logs
people download my Emacs tutorial the
zip file you know lots of times and you
know and some people use the web corner
to call everything when I don't have the
zip file you know so I don't have I
don't have any Google Ads
until around 2010 I was like dying from
hunger then I started to put ads okay
Google ads and in fact Google Google
Google banned me you know left and right
you know anyway that's a long story I
can talk and for another hour about that
with proof with documentation okay but
the point is you know you if you know
that's what that's one of the thing you
know the open-source [ __ ] they
blame you like oh you have ads no I
don't have ads for ten years until you
know the day I was literally like dying
of hunger like I want to I'm hungry I'd
you know not because oh I don't want to
eat something because I'm tired of it I
don't have not a thing to eat oh you
know I want to buy a banana that's 50
cents I don't have 50 cents I'm digging
through trash to eat this is this is
around 2011 so that's why I put ads then
well you know the open source market
then you have ads then people go to your
site they see ads oh yeah oh he's
putting ads there doesn't you know this
guy no we don't we cannot trust him you
know that's what open-source - now I
don't mean you but but people has
comment you know this is I know you know
I know this you know because I've been
running websites for you know twenty
first years as lots of comments you know
I can show you the actual post and you
know but you know it's not do that maybe
because it's it's you know it's not
worthwhile to go go over
so yeah so there's open source you know
there are scams you know so so the
moment you have ads and you know that
people start to you know say all the bad
things about you ignoring that you have
like ten years or five years you know
whatever you have things there for free
for people the entire Emacs tutorials
since 2006 like Tech you can go to
wayback machine and see the archive
yourself way back machine you wouldn't
you you don't see ads okay everything I
can I say is you can prove it
I'm not going to do this you can do it
let's do it let's go to okay way back
way back machine okay so let's go here
internet wayback machine go there and
okay let's go to sorry dog HTTP sorry
dog
okay you can see that these these
domains started in 2000 year 2000 okay
let's go to 2008 knits let's pick 2008
and let's pick a date it's March 29th
okay so that's my that's my website
there is no there's no there's no ads
you know everything is just like
everything in one domain and where is
the Emax here
Emacs tutorial and Emacs this tutorial
70 pages so let's click on Emacs to
tutorial
so you see that's my website banking
mm what 2008 yeah so you know yeah so
okay
okay today I'm well the topic just went
from Mac OS and rent my rant about Linux
and open source actually I rant about
this quite a few times in the past
videos as well that's um that's a
problem that's a issue because because
to me you know today's talk is kind of
waste wasted because I've talked about
these few times in the past about open
source you know about open source things
so I got eight people watching steal so
that's my Linux tutorial yeah Linux no
no no okay so no what is this oh yeah so
one day what is is Sardinas one day I'm
going to start my only noxious and
properties this is this force is random
yeah
no virtual screen no bitmap yeah that
that's kind of a this this page is is my
quick blog I don't it's like I don't
even remember it exists no Shabana yeah
that's also code this bit this is
written in 2013 keyboard user interface
and you see this item here no sheep and
where is it no shell script no sheep
I'll I know you know if you guys are
young you don't know what is a sheep and
why she ban lie is the first character
in a line of a shell script basically
the pound sign or the dot or the you
know hashtag sign input today people few
people know that you know this is one of
the things one of the UNIX philosophy
facts okay one of the UNIX philosophy
[ __ ] they they they they cling to
she by the technically that it's called
she
ban lie okay why is she banshee man is
Sheba is an English word meaning like
meaning like the whole thing okay but it
just so happened in sec she bad and the
Lin Lena the eunuchs [ __ ] they love
this kind of word play or jargons okay
anyway let's call it Shivan because
that's the first character in a shell
script has special meaning because the
way eunuchs execute find executables is
by looking you know at the first
character you know that's a hack
basically it's a you know you're eunuchs
is full of these hacks full of these ad
hoc you know one one of situation you
know without any particular reason you
know just so that they can get something
to walk you know so you know that's
that's one so this is one of the thing
every UNIX [ __ ] the UNIX philosophy
people elite hacker types they will tell
you they will insist that you must have
this line okay now today you guys may
not know but this is this is this is
like history now they will in CD if you
don't do that they will you know they
will flame you they will call say you
are a troll or something but today this
kind of it's like going away it's it's
just like Perl you know it's people
don't know about it anymore and people
do not use it anymore
why because it's just no good it's it's
extremely bad design it's not it's not
something you want to do so anyway
that's about the sheep I lie so anyway
back to this article yeah I wrote this
this is one of the article I didn't yeah
I almost forgot you know Jay one of the
rant but your cousin is funny hilarious
yeah so so rmw says oh yeah okay okay
and so that the new language say it's
not fake news momentous news of Google
or cutting of its Android relationship
with Huawei in response to government
ban
you know China is really incredible they
are you know growing
so what is Chinese Internet's reaction
to the trade war I haven't really
followed that I don't know for sure well
first of all because let's go to Twitter
actually I'm not logged in sometimes
around 2013 or 2002 like two years four
years ago I spent two years in China
China's online forum you know one of
China's online forums so that I talked
to Chinese programmers everyday you know
it's like IRC you know it's one of the
it's like IRC so I talked to Chinese
programmers in Chinese of course mostly
you know so I talk to them every day so
you get to know people you know you
actually know them you know I mean
meaning that you know what they are
thinking that that's a key point you
know you have to mix in with the
community then you you know you talk
with them play with them whatever
everyday then you understand you know
their mindset what you know whatever
news you can see their reaction you
really you really learn it you know so I
spent two years doing that but I haven't
I haven't been really talking to the
Chinese program or Chinese programming
community in the past few years so I
don't really know what's what do they
think but I think most you know most
Chinese people you know in general the
population they don't they don't think
about these things they don't think you
know they don't yeah in fact you know I
yeah they don't think about these things
they just they're just happy they are
just happy using their phone and no
China China they have it's in many ways
you know I don't want you know I think
this is actually true in many ways
Chinese has already surpassed us in
many ways like you can actually see you
know for real you know the
infrastructure in the trains the
transportation the skyscrapers in each
city like you go there you see all these
fantastic skyscrapers and trains and all
that you don't see that in u.s. you know
the it's kind of I think that's about it
for today
eight people okay so I I feel today is
kind of wasted stick because it's me
ranting against open source stuff and
Linux people and to me it felt it felt
like you know it's not news you know I
because it's not something I want to do
because I got tired of it the the thing
is you know most people when you do a
show you know like my talk show if you
are entertainers or public speaker it's
a more like almost like every time you
go to a city you know doing a lecture or
whatever performance or whatever people
always want you to ask the same question
for the millionth time you know they
want they want a singer to sing to sing
the same song for the millionth time
because they haven't heard it before you
know that's the that's what happens when
you are a single person but you are
dealing with you know massive number of
crowd you know so yeah I hear that
happening to other you know to singers
for example singers performers
celebrities or or public speakers you
know you always have the you know they
get they get asked about the same
question all the time okay so yeah so
today is that you I could just rent
let's see what else
yeah 19 minutes okay so yeah thank you
guys for watching see you next time I
felt that that like I wanted to talk
about something I don't even I didn't
get a chance to begin to actually
there's something I wanted to talk about
but the new language says army is a chip
designer it was acquired by Japanese
Telecom as those days anyway if you
enjoyed alright thanks guys bye