hello guys welcome to another episode of
EX talk show today we are going to do
Advent of
code day four problem uh yeah let's do
day four okay I haven't read the problem
yet but let's get on so today's talk
show let's start code wolam
language uh okay so pop it out and I
have wolam language started there and uh
day three I haven't finished yet uh you
know I can finish it quickly but let's
you know let's I didn't realize that you
can jump to uh different days of the
problem but anyway let's get on with day
four and today I try to do as fast as
possible and basically just finish it in
30 minutes or an hour okay let's hope we
can do that let's see if I can do that
uh and uh uh yeah so you know don't
worry about fancy you know uh I want to
create the shortest code of all
programming languages now that is
Trivial in wolam language you know if
you been coding wolam language for a
year or two any of these problems you
just go with the simplest solution the
first solution that comes to your mind
that solution is going to be the
shortest of all programming
languages now actually possibly except
APL okay APL the uh hot
dog just mention APL APL yeah AP is uh
you cannot beat it you can kind of but
depending on the problem anyway but if
you want to create a wolam language
solution solution that is the shortest
among all other wolam language Solutions
then that is a difficult part okay so
that is you know
um that is a bit more difficult because
you you know uh you are competing anyway
let's get on with uh day four okay so
day four problem I haven't read it
before let's see the gondola takes you
up strangely though the ground doesn't
seem to be coming with
you you are not climbing a mountain as a
circle of snow Island recedes below you
an entire new land mass suddenly appears
above
you the gondola carries you to the
surface of the new island and lurches
into the station okay as you exit the
gondola the first thing you notice is
that the air here is much warmer than it
was on Snow Island it's also quite
humid warmer and humid is this where the
water source is the next thing you
notice is an elf sitting on the floor
across the station in what seems to be a
pile of colorful Square cards
okay oh hello the elf excitedly runs
over to you how may I be of service you
ask about water
sources I'm not sure I just operate the
gondola lift that does sound like
something we have though this is island
island after all I bet the gardener
would know he's on a different Island
though uh the small kind surrounded by
water not the floating
kind okay uh we really need to come up
with a better naming scheme tell you
what if you can help me with something
quick I'll let you borrow my boat and
you can go visit the Gardner I got all
these scratch cards as a gift but I
can't figure out what I've want okay now
there's a link some annoying link you
know probably to ah God
Wikipedia scratch card yeah
okay so he's got a bunch of scratch
cards as a gift but I can't figure out
what I want okay the elf leads you over
to the pile of colorful cards there you
discover dozens of scratch cards or with
their a peg covering already scratch off
pick one up it looks like each card has
two lists of
numbers each card has two lists of
numbers separated by a vertical bar
okay okay uh a list of winning numbers
and then a list of numbers you
have you organize the information into a
table your person input okay I'm not
sure uh okay so let's just put it down
here
each card has two lists of numbers so
there are two
lists each list is a list of numbers
separated by vertical bar the vertical
bar separate these two
lists so the first list is a list of
winning numbers then the second one is a
list of numbers you have okay list of
numbers winning numbers and the list of
numbers I have on each
card uh and uh you organize the
information into a table okay
so then as far as the Al has been able
to figure out you have to figure out
which of the numbers you have appear in
the list of winning numbers the first
match makes the card worth one
point and each ma match after the first
double the point value of that card so
double is like multiply by two okay for
example so here is probably your
input so let's
uh okay
so that's a
string input equals to
okay okay yeah so a bunch of cards and
let's let's just make it like that a
bunch of cards each one has a two list
of numbers okay this the first part is
winning numbers the second part is your
numbers okay then you want to match them
up now if there's a match you get one
point now if there's a second match you
double your
score then third match you double it
again probably okay in above example
card one has five winning numbers 41 48
and so on uh can you see
it oh
[ __ ]
uh so what is the importance of
ergonomic design is wolfan poetry is
this okay
so you know [ __ ] posters go away okay so
we are doing wolf and uh I mean advant
of code so here's the
problem uh Advent of C day four so right
now so so you
have so this is the card you are giving
a bunch of cards each one has two lists
a list of winning numbers and list of
your numbers in the above example card
one uh got five winning numbers 41
48 okay and uh 17 okay and eight numbers
you have okay uh something something 53
okay of the numbers you have four of
them 40 83 17 and 86 are winning numbers
okay uh check 48 check 83 check 17 check
86 check
okay that means c one is worth eight
point one for the first match then
double three times for each of the three
match after the first
okay
so so it's it's a it's a geometric
progression wait yeah so it's 1 + 1 * 2
* 2 * 2 so 1 * 2 is 2 2 * 2 is 4 4 * 2
is 8 so 8 point that's right so the the
you know the formula is
basically uh actually we can write this
in W language product and the product is
x * 2
x
* you know basically want 1 * 2 * 3 * 4
okay so let's just so X goes from one to
four okay so basically that's
it uh we can we can actually run
it no this is no this is 1 2 3 4 so this
is product of 1 * 2 * 3 * 4 that's not
what you want what you want is
um you you just want power
so two rais to the 4th
power except the first one so 2 ra to
the 4 minus one so you
got four winning numbers
minus the first one because it start
with one uh something like that uh it's
eight right
so
so that's kind of the formula okay so
for cards you want four numbers so you
minus one and two raised to that power
okay that's basically how you get the
score so car two has winning numbers 32
and and 61 so worth two point and so on
and blah blah blah worth one point okay
uh and the C five has no winning numbers
so zero okay so in this example the L
profile Square so the answer is 13 so
the answer
is 13 for this problem okay
uh how many points are there worth in
total okay let's get your personal input
very very easy trivial problem
okay uh let's say
Advent X Advan let's say four okay let's
just say that four now okay
magnify show
space okay
202 lines okay this is a trivial problem
okay copy the file path close it shrink
the window and uh and the input equals
to read
string read string this file path now
let's to be sure let's see what is
the
uh the documentation for read string
okay so we are
correct read string and the file path
yeah so okay so remove that remove that
and we
can R Let's see we got the
input okay so yeah so that's
correct so we got so V trival problem
okay let's see if I can how fast I can
finish
this now the the Sam nasty guy you know
you're going to get
banned so okay so uh yeah so so you got
um so so you got a first bunch of
numbers you got second L of numbers you
want to compare which was a very easy
trivial uh so let's let's start to do
it I'm going to member Q so member Q
takes a
list okay so the let's say the first
member que takes two items the the first
one is a
um okay actually you need to pass it
because some of the numbers got two two
empty
lines yeah okay but but let's go on
let's show the algorithm
here okay
so that's a list and uh then you have a
second list that's the winning numbers
okay then you got the car number okay so
these are the winning
numbers am I good yeah okay so I believe
that we'll just return the Leist of
matching
numbers members okay the documentation
return true if element uh no we don't
want member Q we want
subset of match okay so let's see so you
have Union
intersection intersection is you want so
you don't want member Q so intersection
is the function name not
interval okay let's look up
documentation for intersection
intersection a bunch of lists give a
sorted list of elements common to all
that's right so intersection two list
okay first list uh second list order
doesn't
matter okay so let's run
that okay so the result is four so okay
so we already almost solved the problem
so what uh what you want to do is you
just
um split stream
uh string split okay uh string split
okay the the naming of the function find
language string
split of input and split
by split by lines okay so that's new
line character
so input two okay so let's just say that
then then
you then you map each okay
so okay I'm going to make sure I finish
this problem
so uh map input
to so now you got a bunch of lines as
the least for each one you want to uh
split
okay
for each one you want to split now this
time
by by that by that um vertical line
okay yeah so so this way we'll give you
two parts okay let's just let's just do
this quickly input
three equals to okay so let's run
them okay let's run the whole
thing run
it
okay you forgot something I forgot so
here we here this is a function so we
need to put a uh M percent meaning
that's a function okay so intersection
this one we don't need copy all select
all paste run
it so we got oh God yeah that's too much
input there that's because we oh yeah we
let's let's work with the the
uh let's work with the where is the read
string oh yeah let's work with
the the short input okay so input input
then split string then input three copy
all select all paste shift
enter okay so we got
uh so here is let's see so now let's see
input
three we want to take the first element
okay exactly
now of of the first element we want to
uh first element then take the first
element of that okay correct
then okay now so far they are all
strings each element is a string okay no
problem so now we just intersect okay
so uh let me let me show let me do this
okay line one equals to equals to input
[Music]
three the first line
okay that's right so now we we got the
line one so what we do with line one we
just apply the intersection okay so
intersection
intersection line one first
part line one
second part
okay
nonatomic wait why is it
nonatomic nonatomic expression
[Music]
expected so what is line
one oh you split you you right now it's
uh each line is a list of two strings so
you need to split again so each string
becomes a element
okay uh let's just let's just use the
simplest way to solve this okay let's
not get let's worry about efficiency
later so right now so you just split by
white space so you don't need so line
four input
three okay now each element is actually
an element okay so
now uh there it is that's line one and
now
intersection fantastic okay
so so that how many so you know you just
calculate the
length the length of that then you okay
then you just apply this for formula
okay so this formula is
four is the length Okay so
let's length
at
argument okay
uh so that is a function there uh so
that is a function apply that function
to this
okay a
okay so that is the that is the score
for line one now all you have to do is
just do the same thing for each and
every line okay now let's see if I can
make it one shot without trial and
error any anyone else is
watching concurrent viewers night okay
say hi if you are here
okay uh streams current bit rate is
lower blah blah blah okay uh success you
know I'm just going to make this one
line single line solution
without uh trying again okay so here are
the solutions
so okay
so
so the input so we uh you want to okay
so function map maap
at input okay so the function will
[Music]
be so first of all split it
into split it by new line yeah we need
to do
that first you split by new line then
you need to split again you need to
split
like two more
times
okay let's put it
here okay okay am I doing good yeah I
hope so
so
so so the second time you need to split
by that okay
so
there okay so
actually uh let's see the documentation
we want
the is there a functional notation
no
you don't you know don't don't worry
about what I'm
saying I'm trying to get shorter
notation um okay no functional notation
I'll just write it this way
then okay so that's function then you
then you split Again
by
uh by
space so you don't by default it split
by space okay so basically this is a
function okay you have
that then you apply this function so
basically let me show
you okay so you you you
map you map this function to the
input
then
you what this function does is it is
that is split by new line then split
by the vertical line then split by y
space okay so in this case you don't
even need that uh and you don't need the
parent Nether and uh you know I'm pretty
sure it work
but I was I was saying I'm not going to
do any trial and error but anyway so
once you do that okay once you do that
what you get is
a you know what you get is the nice
input a list of list then
you apply this function
yeah so then so you got this whole thing
then what you do is
[Music]
you
okay let me let me show
you so this whole thing put them inside
the par then what you do is you apply
another
function
[Music]
you yeah so this is a function you want
line one line two Okay so you
want let's write a
function and
uh this function
will
take okay so let me let me get fancy
here let's just do that okay so you take
the first part and the last part then do
the intersection then what you want is
the length of that okay
so length at okay apply the length
length function to the result
then then of out of that you basically
do um yeah so this
is
I'm getting very fancy
here so you get the length of the
intersections which is a total number of
the count of of of of the winning
numbers you have then minus one then
raised to the second power so this is a
function so you apply this function to
that input that's right so there there
there map there that's solution oh wait
so what you get once you get that is you
get a list of numbers each number is the
is your
score and all you have to do is use some
name up is that
right worth in total how many point yeah
you just Su them up okay so sum is
total
okay that is a
solution let's try
it nonatomic expression okay I got it
wrong somewhere failed I failed in this
blind coding okay so let's we have to
see so let's let's be more be more
careful
here so let's try this
part yeah so that is the the nice input
each one
is wait what what exactly is
that yeah I'm not sure what exactly is
this XX equals true okay so
now take the first part and
see what part
specification is longer than depth of
object what what do you mean
what
so we map this function to the
input and
uh
yeah High Q
intent
so
uh so what what what is our input did we
screw up the input input so the
input
input is the input a
string yeah the input is string and uh
okay let me finish
this so the
input oh yeah not at not map to that's
right that's right so this is actually
not map
to so okay so I got
it
you don't need to map you just put the
input here okay so you put the input
there and
uh okay so let me just work this
out
and okay maybe that's a
solution huh
wait uh we copied uh we didn't copy the
whole
thing okay
no uh
close
okay so you need a map
here
that's right so let's try
it
14 am I correct
please so in this example the elf's pile
of scratch Pad scratch cards is worth 13
point I got 14 so something is wrong
somewhere okay let's remove the total
let's
see
where does the half came from okay so
last two lines something wrong with the
last two
lines let's
see why is that let's just try to fix
this
okay let's see what is what is our exact
input here
plus plus why are we getting the
plus
no oh okay wait
total okay we want to see what this line
does here is what is
wrong oh yeah you need wait you need a
map why is
it I have a you see I have a slash
here but it's no slash there h what's
going
on yeah so this is what I
expect that's
right and each one of them is a string
each element okay so this should be the
solution but
why
so let's see where did we got it wrong
okay
so now this is a solution now let's
let's just compute let's
see
let's just map
that to this
input right so 4 2 2 1 so that's a
number of
match Cod one is full match C two is two
4 2 2 1 that's right so this is
correct
now
4221 so now if you apply this this
multiplication this two to the power why
is
it
uh is you see we apply this function we
map this function into the last
output
oh so when it's zero you you become
that's why the
power is wrong so you you got a two rais
to a negative-1 power so that becomes 1
/ two yeah
so what you want
is so when it's zero you ignore
it when it's one result yeah so when
it's zero ignore it so you know we can
easily do a if
expression
um yes so okay so you know there are
many ways to do this
but but
let's yeah okay let's do this okay
delete delete cases okay now let's say
this is the
input
and uh zero okay
minute yeah so we can just apply that
there
so okay let's look up the documentation
let's see if I can put it in a put into
a operator form yes you can okay
fantastic fantastic so I'm just going to
say delete case is
zero then
add fantastic so here is a solution
wait okay here is a
solution uh uh
what oh oh okay you forgot
to
uh yeah the so so you got
a operator precedence wrong so you need
to actually
let's see operator
precedence yeah so this this part needs
to
be parenthesized
okay
what
oh you forgot
wait oh you need to apply the delete
cases after the intersection
obviously okay
no after the length so you do the
intersection then you do the length of
them then you do the delete cases then
you raise to the power that's
right so now you just say
total okay so I think this this is is
it why is it Z4
Jesus is this 13 or 14 13 H something is
[Music]
wrong okay intersection
intersection
length Okay so yeah so this this
is okay
so so let's do it
here so you do that
you map
them you get a bunch of intersections
then you do the delete
cases delete
cases at okay at the whole
expression
okay then
you no wait you need the length first
okay you got a bunch of intersections
then you need
to yeah so you need to
get put here then you remove the zero
then then you apply this
function two to the power okay I think
that's
it now let's make sure the operator
precedence is
correct okay
you once you got that then you apply
delete
cases then you apply the map then you
get the total okay so I think that's it
now you need to
yeah 13
fantastic okay that's a solution let's
remove let's clean up the code how many
minutes 47 not too
bad could have been better but okay not
too bad first of all so let's restart
now let's load our
own
input okay run it that's our own input
now let's just run this
code shortest solution possible okay you
need you didn't need to put that
there
okay R it 23 235 are you sure I'm
sure let's
see okay so you need to copy it
copy
answer are you
sure yes shut the [ __ ] up that's the
right answer of
course
okay Sam says a bunch of things what is
the purpose of pass is your code
base what is the best
way how does
[Music]
CSV how does that CSV work how does that
CSV work which aspect of that shorthand
operation works with
[Music]
the oh okay so in what case does this
apply in regular expression in Fire
Organization great content in Channel I
don't know what you are saying are you
trolling or what I don't know Sam what
are you
saying okay you're like a pass what uh
okay I don't know if you are trolling or
not so anyway so here is the solution
for day four problem one okay
uh of course one line solution we can
make it shorter now how many characters
are
there 150 you know can you make it
shorter yeah let's do it let's try 2
minutes okay I don't want to be stuck
with this because usually that's what I
do I stuck with this um um you know
making it shorter so uh can you make it
shorter yeah so first of
all uh and uh first and
last
than and uh
you know for example we can save three
characters by just putting this part
into the cases we save three
characters because now I don't need uh
the extra parent and this parent I don't
need anymore because now so let's remove
it uh you know
this is what uh you know all this is
silly
because the they are many ways
to determine what is the shortest
solution and uh a better you know
typically in the C idiots coding word
the shortest solution means the least
number of character count or the bite
count that's the most tic concept so a
better concept is actually you count the
number of tokens of that
language so that so that if you you know
if you solved one problem but however
your function name is 100 characters
that only count as one in other words
function name shouldn't you know count
as
like uh you know into the shortest or
longest you know so you should count
token
and even a better idea in W language is
they count number of
leaves so anyway so here is kind of
shorter but you can can you make it
shorter still yeah for example
um anyway let's not worry about it so
let me show you the token idea
so you can leave count okay so there is
a leaf count so given this thing you can
count how many
Leaf so you know wufan language
expression is like Le it's a you you can
think of it of it as a tree abstract
syntax Tree in fact any language
automatically become that when you
compile even C so when you have a tree
any expression is a tree so you count
the leaves okay that's what this slea
count does so let's show you I can show
you so you what you have to do is you
have to say hold otherwise this thing is
going to evaluate to a number and then
leave count is just one so you have to
hold then you know then this is our
input then leave count 31 so this is a
typical way in wam language coding
competition how you determine if a code
is shortest you do the leavea count okay
now of course in other languages you
don't even have that you
it's like to to to write this sleeve
count takes how many lines few hundred
you know because more than because you
to do that first of all you have to
write the par of the language first then
you got the abstract abstract syntax
tree then you can count the leaves okay
so but anyway if you don't have leave
count usually you can just do token
count I mean in most other languages
since since their names are not symbols
like lisp so in see in Java in Python
you can't even do token count because
you have to pass your source code first
in order to determine what's a token you
know then you need the token grammar and
then uh anyway but but a simple ways you
simply count uh each word as a token you
know separated by space that's a kind of
cheating I mean that's a sloppy way so
anyway so that's a that's a solution for
day for um number one
okay okay Sam one more message one more
trolling message from you you get banned
okay uh this so today it's just the Sam
so you people here say hi Okay so Q
intent anyone else so anyway that's a
solution for day one so what we should
we do should we continue to uh part two
uh let's
see we are 15 minutes uh why not
okay okay so so let's yeah so this is
good code
yeah uh and this part is called
explanation
okay then put the code explanation at
the bottom then uh that's it
so that's our
solution a r of code
2023 day four part one okay now let's
put it back let's syntax color it so
there is today's
solution now day two let's see if we can
do day I mean uh part two let's see
quickly I'm going to give it 10 minutes
no
more coffee let me stretch for a
minute
so part
two just as you are about to report your
findings to the elf one of the one of
you realizes that the rules have
actually been printed on the back of
every card this whole
time there's no such thing as points
instead scratch cards only cost you to
win more scratch cards equal to the
number of winning numbers you have okay
specifically you win copies of the
scratch cards below the winning card
equal to the number of
matches so you win copies of the SC
match cards below the winning
card equal to the number of
matches oh okay so let's say you have
one of the card let's say there are
three
matches so that means you go down three
lines something like
that so for example if C 10 were to have
five matching numbers you would you
would win one copy each of
cards 11 12 13 14 15 okay so you go go
down five of them grab the next five of
them okay so check number of
mattress suppose it's n then you grab
the next n cards something like that
okay uh score like noral scratch cards
and have same c number as the car uh so
if you win a copy of card 10 and it has
five matching numbers it would then win
a copy of the same cards that the
original card 10
Won H what if you win a copy of card 10
and it
has five matching numbers it would then
win a copy of the same cards that
original card 10 w What the fact what do
you mean card 11 12 13 14 and
15 this process repeats until none of
the copies cause you to win any more
cards yeah [ __ ]
idiotic
this time the above example goes
differently what do you mean differently
okay they Chang the
input I'm not really happy with the
Advent of
code so this state two typically they
don't change you know the input so you
know because when you design a personel
you should stick with
one or be consistent so anyway so here
is
the input so the the the example
input is it the same or not it is the
same 191 11 83 36
okay so what do you mean this time the
above example goes
differently
card one has four matching numbers
okay so you win one copy each of the
next four cards 2 three four five
okay your original card
two has two matching numbers okay this
this one so you win one copy each of car
okay your copy of card two also wins one
copy each of card three and four what
what oh so
what so the copy of card two also
wins one copy of each card three and
four
it doesn't make
sense so let's go on your four instance
of car three one original in three
copies oh
Jesus
your eight instances of card
four so I got four instance of card
four
one original and seven
copies have one matching number so you
win eight copies of card
five so the idea is that now each card
has a
multiplicity this multiplicity is
determined by preceding
cards
okay and
uh okay but what is the score
though so your
14th your 14 instances of card five one
original and 13 copies have no matching
numbers and win no more
cards your one instance of card
six one original has no mat numbers and
wins no more cards okay what is the
problem once all of the originals and
copies have been processed you end up
with one instance of card one two card
one two instance of card two four
instance of card three and eight
instance of card four and 14 instance of
card five and one instance of card car
six okay the instance means
multiplicity and that is determined by
previous cards they are matching numbers
kind
of so in total this example pile this
example pile of scratch cards causes you
to ultimately have 13 scratch
cards counting the
original so basically the problem is the
total of
Multiplicity okay seems
easy uh total of
Multiplicity process all the original
and copied scratch part cards until no
more scratch cards are W including the
original set of scratch cards how many
total scratch cards do you end up end up
with okay this problem is just
multiplicity and uh very
easy uh we just um very
easy each card instead of saying card we
just call it line the [ __ ] do away do
away with the
eles E
problems uh so get the total of
multiplicity of each
line so the multiplicity is determined
by uh that's hard to explain it's better
to explain in other way uh but let's not
explain it let's just do it okay so
so so we don't know the answer so uh uh
so so just like before we got
this we got this
um we need we need this part for sure
just like
before okay uh wait we don't need the
total
okay screwed up
something is
it uh what
oh this is the this is the total I mean
this that's not the total input we want
the total
input okay total
input okay then evaluate this part so
yeah so that's the number of matches per
card so once you got this you want to
count multiplicity okay so uh which is
easy
you
you okay so
you you you you okay so you want
multiplicity so the first one so
basically first of all you want a map
index index okay you don't need the
powers anymore you want map index okay
map index takes two arguments the second
is a list the first is a function of
two arguments okay the first argument is
the the element in the list the second
argument is
the
index of that list so this way we know
which number is which card for example
if this is you know this first line is
index one second line is index two
okay do we need
that uh we kind of need so hold on a
second so let's
see so each number
number means go down the next
to each number means go you know grab
the next two lines or next n
lines okay if we don't if you don't you
know let's don't worry about efficiency
or anything let's just do it
quickly it's it's very easy so you
just
okay so you
just in this case you don't want delete
cases no let's try that again let's see
what
is yeah so each so this is a input so
let's
say XX equals to that okay this is the
main input we want to work with let's
name it
XX so
so then you map indexed to
XX search
that the
first argument is the number of the next
cards okay so you want to take
the
multiplicity okay
so
H maybe you need some kind of recursive
solution do you okay you just map index
let's
see if you use map index you get this so
this so let's say the first
line the first line
means grab the next four
lines each one of
them their winning number their winning
number count
must increase by
one so what so what is it you are trying
to
do you are trying
[Music]
to so there are quite a few ways to do
this so how do you the some so for each
line you get a number which is a number
of match for each line you get a number
this
number is a number you want plus how
many times this card has been selected
by
previous
uh you
know that's that is the
multiplicity so ultimately you want this
number times the
multiplicity
so ultimately this is a key ultimately
Your solution is that for each line you
have a number that's number of
match multiply by the multiplicity of
that line okay then you sum sum all
these together a
number number match multiply by
multiplicity of this line line then you
just sum sum all these all the lines
together okay so now the number we know
the number for each line is just you
know this solution the problem is to get
the
multiplicity so we have to determine the
multiplicity for line one the
multiplicity for line two and so
on and The Way It Is defined is by
can we can we just use a map or do we
have to use recursion let's
see the multiplicity is defined by for
each
line if there's winning number you know
if there's four match then that means
the next
four that means you add
one to each of the next four
lines okay so you cannot like in one
shot get the multiplicity of a
line because when you process each line
they you know they indicate which line
which the next end
lines should have should increase their
multiplicity so what do you know that so
first of all what you know is
that okay so if this line is number is
four the number match is four that means
the next four lines each one
gets multiplicity gets
incremented
so yeah you can use map
index
so okay let's so let's
define multip list okay let's
see
a
no that's not what we
want
that's what we
want okay so to begin
with this list
indicates each Line's Multiplicity
okay I'm getting
tired
okay
and
see okay I want to finish the
problem right back
hurts because I'm getting
old
so
multiplicity that's what that's the
thing you want to
compute so
you so you
map you map over that
so each number indicates the next end
lines so you can
directly add add
equal that's right so multiplicity
so
so what you want
is map
index
okay that's better so multiplicity
equals to
that what's going
on
don't tell
me okay so this is better
okay this this gives you the
multiplicity the initial okay so then we
map indexed we want to focus on that
part so when it's four
so the map indexed so the when it's
four that means
you increment
each
so you that means
[Music]
you
the current
index
so the argument two is a current
index the current
index
hello
x29 okay uh let's see some of the
approaches let me think
about
again
you know what we can do is we
can let me just show it
okay so if you run this this is what you
get H
what oh yeah yeah so you cannot do
that you know this second part is just
the
index
so so
[Music]
the the multiplicity of a
line
each give you the
next four so
essentially so you need
to yeah okay so let's do this so each
one you get that and and uh you get you
want the table okay so you want the
table so if you get number four here you
want get you want it to return the list
of the next four
indexes so for example this number two
for the second line you want it to
return 34 meaning grab the third line
and fourth line okay so for this two on
the third line you wanted to
return 4 five because this two is on the
third
line so two numbers after third line is
four five so this number
one is on the fourth line so one means
grab the next line so it returns five
meaning the line five just line so each
of these number you want it to return a
least of the numbers that's uh that's
kind of
the yeah
so
so so we can we can do that but
um okay let's just focus on a simple
solution
first uh so each number
[Music]
you okay
easy range
that range that
plus okay it's so easy let's
see
yeah so that's what we want let's see if
we okay something is
wrong
uh oh yeah you cannot add one can you
no
what
you can so why can't you oh yeah so you
need yeah because
um because the when you map index when
you use the function map index it
doesn't return just a single number for
the
index it actually returns a bracket
because because that way you because W
language is everything is a tree unlike
python or others where a list is usually
flat so anyway so this will do this will
do the trick you
see so compare we're going
somewhere okay so
compare the input so we don't want this
part so you see we are working on this
input this is a number of match for each
line so we want to turn this input into
this
input okay
so then once you we have
that for each of these we just add one
to
the to the index to to
yeah
to the
multiplicity okay where is the
multiplicity
here right and then we just
do
okay then we map over
this
[Music]
to the
multiplicity so then we go over this
list for
each
number that means increment the
multiplicity okay so we don't even we
can just do a
count fascinating that's right so we
don't have to add one add one add one we
just do a count sum them up here so yeah
that's easy so you got this bunch of
numbers you want
to unique and uh count okay
so you so for each of these
number the number indicates the index
the line number
you want to uniy and count unique
occurrences of
each then that result you just add to
the multiplicity
okay so how do you what is a function
for
Unique uh you know so this is not
good oh yeah
unique elements let's
see unique elements list gives the
element for each list that are not in
any other
list okay so that's not what we what we
want what we want
is Count
duplicate something like count
duplicate okay okay bound count bite
count character count count distinct
there it is Count
distinct that's
it okay
so
what oh wait wait so
this copy the input put the input
here uh
no oh count distinct gives you a number
of distinct elements but what you want
is the they dup
duplicity okay let's see count distinct
let's see the
documentation if there is
options you see that's right count
distinct by delete duplicate delete free
counts count distinct by gives a number
of distinct
values of so this this function can't
distinct by is you apply a function
first you know use the function to
determine
distinctiveness that's right for example
you can see from this
example um then let's count distinct
by
um yeah so in this case distinct is just
two A and B that's right so this is not
the function we want we want let's see
count
distinct we want the we don't want to
actually count the distinct we want to
count
each duplicate okay we want to count the
duplicate so let's see DD
duplicate okay
so delete adjacent duplicate delete
duplicate
by partition okay let's see partition in
know we want to group by okay so let's
see
gather so gather gather El of list into
sub list of identical elements that's
the that's the one we want gather how
nice that's why everything so
short gather okay so gather this is the
input let's try
it yeah that doesn't work because we
need to flatten the list
first
okay that's
right now once you have that it's it um
you can simply count the
length you know map a function just
count length and we are done uh but is
there a simpler like we can skip this
step if there's a simpler a function a
building function such that it it
gathers the distinct elements
together but not just that we we all we
want is we want to count the number of
um distinct elements Ga element in your
sub list of into identical list okay so
so is there a shortcut Group by merge
tally
Tally Tes is the
one that's right there it is Tad you see
that's why wam function is usually
programming wam function is a matter of
finding the right function you know
because there are seven 7,000 functions
by default you want to spend your time
that exactly this is exactly what we
want
so two uh so what is
this five occurs three times four occurs
three times three occurs twice two
occurs one time exactly so T is we what
we want okay let's get on with this
let's uh
tally okay so let's just copy
that tally something okay uh we
want
so XX is we have
XX okay we
have
okay we have
multiplicity okay then we we map that
into XX
by by what what was the
function oh yeah the the the function
map
index oh yeah
there yeah
so let's try
again that's right so we got that and we
then we flatten it we don't need it Nest
it we can flatten
it then we
can tally it okay so this just make it
very
short flat and tally then we map the
whole
thing
to
to to the XX okay so let's write out
okay map a function to xx and the
function will
be
uh wait
so
actually so we got this list and so we
map a function yeah we do need to map a
function
map okay so the second part is a list
which is thatat the first part is a
function okay it's uh let let's write
the full form way okay so it's easier to
understand for everyone so we write the
function maps to that
the the first element is uh
the line
number that's right
so so the first element is the line
number
XY
the second element
is multiplicity okay then what we have
to do is
[Music]
we
this is not functional approach but but
we can just code
it uh multiplicity
list am I doing good
yeah it's kind of boring okay
so so this equals
to
let's say
dup kind of like
that
okay
okay something
wrong too many parameters in line number
two what oh yeah because this only take
yeah that's right so you only take one
argument okay so line number is X the
first
one
okay and duplicity is X
second okay like
that uh and what is that that
and yeah so uh the result doesn't matter
we what we want is the multiplicity list
okay then just total uh
okay 13 13
again no it should be
okay
something did we do it
right
okay let's
see okay this is not good actually
there's so much better ways to do this
yeah but to
think so we don't
want we don't want this we don't want
Define we don't need ex to Define
variables multiplicity list bad idea so
we can
simply map
index this is
good
that's right and for those
that's okay let's clean this
up T gathered count distin very
interesting all very
[Music]
interesting
okay uh so this is all we
need this is the key okay this part is a
key so let's let's put out the important
things okay the important things is this
part and
then and
that okay but before we do
that that okay
so
each one of those are
index and
uh and if they are
empty if it's
zero
what you get with range zero I think you
get
zero oh yeah you get empty least
okay so what we want
is okay so you do that
then if it's zero you
want if it's zero you don't
care if it's zero that
means so does this
count the non winning scratch card s
once all of the originals and copies
have been processed you will end up with
one instance of card one two instance of
card two and something card three a
instance of four 14 instance five and
one instance of
six in total this example pile of
scratch cards you causes you to
ultimately have
30 scratch cards
so even
those scratch cards that is not a
winning card you also count it you count
it as one okay that's why that's why we
have a error
here so even the card doesn't have any
winning numbers you also count it you
know because all you want is number of
copy of scratch cards you
have
so
so what we want here
is okay we modify this
expression map
indexed
okay
if
equals to
zero if the winning count is equals to
zero then you simply add you simply
return
the you you simply return
the the index of that card number so
here
is
two
otherwise that's right so let's make
sure we are correct
here we don't need the
p
that's right so this is a better so you
see the Fifth Line you get five because
even though it's not a winning card but
you still count it one time because you
got that scratch part scratch scratch
card same thing for number six right so
once we got that then we
tally you see then we
[Music]
we then we
uh then
what then we yeah so what this
means
so this means the second card has one
duplic
multiplicity the third line has two
copies instance the fourth line has
three the fifth has
four let's see one instance of six
that's
right 14 inance of card
five so this is
incorrect
ah God hello finally someone's
here how's the problem coming along
hello K Merry Christmas hello Thiago and
lunita lunita so we did we are doing day
four we solved the first part easily and
now we are on the second
part uh which is also easily solving it
but now it's like oh 50
minutes okay so but we are close you
know we are not stuck in somewhere but
it's
just um okay
close
so yeah we need to stop this is 2 hours
now but let's finish this okay we are
very
close
um
so
now uh seems are we are wrong why is
that wrong so this part means the first
card
is has four matching numbers the second
card has two matching numbers the third
has two okay now this part
means oh okay so you forgot it should be
one that's
right e okay
stupid yeah that's what we want that's a
format uh wait why is it
just
what
the
if it's
zero if it's zero this should be just
that
okay
otherwise so the first card has four
match four matching numbers so that
means the 23 second third fourth fifth
should all
increment they got the multiplicity
okay so that's that's right so
far and
uh what is uh what is wrong here
this
is so this means 2 3 4 five
six this is second
line happens once third line happens
twice no this is not right something is
wrong
yeah I need to finish this no more
coffee
you don't need the extra bracket why do
you do
that
much
better you
need
oh you forgot to count it self that's
right so you
here you forgot to count
itself [ __ ]
idiotic so when whenever you process a
card you need to count
itself that's right
so
so if you are on the first
line Let's see we don't need the
multiplicity list remove that so for
example
here you need to for example the first
line for mat
numbers that means you need to return a
list that is 1 2 3 4
5 why 1 2 3 4 5 because one is a line
itself then 2 3 4 5 is the next four
lines
index so the second line is two they
should return 2 three
uh uh 2 3 4 not 34 because you need
to wait
wait
uh okay I see what's going on yeah
so okay so let's not so yeah so I have
kind
of yeah you don't don't include don't
include itself because the original copy
is always always count you just add the
total number of
lines you know to your solution so don't
generate itself here
so so in that case when it's when it's
equals to
zero what do you do uh let's
see
that's better do not include
itself now what about 1 2 3 four the
four fourth line the fourth line 1 2 3 4
is one one means include the next one
five okay yeah so this is better so
don't do the if okay so once you have
that then what's
next then
you okay then you T and
flatten
then you
multiply then so yeah so this is this
means the result here
means means on the second line you have
two
multiplicity on the third line you have
one M uh I mean on the
what on the first line
wait
what
God okay so on the second line you have
only one
multiplicity on the third line you have
two multiplicity not counting
itself so what one once you get this you
want
to let me do
this
14 so the answer is 14 plus the number
of lines 1 2 3 4 5
six so which is 20 which is incorrect
it's supposed to be
30 right
uh
multiplicity let's check let's
read concurrent view
six
God call one his for maging numbers
so so you win one copy each of the next
four cards two three four
five
oh you you need to take the
second F
[ __ ] okay so you going to do this
again that
that
that now 9 + 6 is
wrong what the [ __ ] is this problem your
copy of C two also wins one car
copy each cards of cards three and
four your four instance of card
three have two magic numbers so you win
four
copies
right your four instance of c
three oh so there's a multiply somewhere
so your four instance of car three so
you have four instance of car
three okay card three has two matching
numbers so your four instance of c three
you have four instance of car three
because because you you have car three
has itself a copy original copy plus
plus you wanton it twice before so you
have why four why why for instance of
copy of cod did you see did you use set
intersection two yeah that's the you can
see the solution to the first problem
here okay that's a solution to the first
problem but we are trying to solve this
second problem the second problem you
see the intersection is here you know
that that's this
XX so that gives us
[Music]
already so we already have the the
winning count yeah so
okay
so but now the issue is with this
Multiplicity um so it says your four
instance of card
three so card three has four instance
why why is that Cod one has four
matching numbers so you win one copy
each of the next four cards 2 three 4
five okay your orinal card two has two
matching
numbers
Okay C two has two magic
numbers so you win one copy of each card
three and
four that's
right your copy of card
two also wins one copy of each of C
three and four
oh right here copy of card
two so card
two gets you card three and four wins
you card three and
four but for each copy of card
two you have three and four
again
okay so so so this number needs to
multiply okay so I got it
close so each so each instance of the
card let's let's summarize the problem
again so you have a bunch of cards each
card is numbered 1 2 3 4 5 and so
on for each
card you have the matching number a
count of ma matched number for example
card one has four match number card two
s
two and for each card you have the
concept of
Multiplicity mean which
means
basically a total instance you know the
in in Al's Jon it's a instance of number
of instance you have so the concept is
multiplicity in
mathematics so here we this the
card so let's see should we include
itself
so then we map
index it should include
itself so it's not total you see this
two you see this two one two need needs
2+ * 1 3 needs 2 *
wait what is this
m so each card has multiply
so your so what is you need to
re oh you need to
reevaluate okay oh so you solve this
problem fiago a card that won wins more
cards I use recursion for this you need
to re-evaluate each new card too yeah
you know
uh I think this works we just need
to
I'm getting tired we just need to
multiply them
together you know so I'm not using
recursion myself I use the index number
for
each but do I have to wait so unless I
actually solve the problem so I can't be
sure so so what is the issue here
so each card has a
multiplicity
right
yeah copy of card also wins one copy of
each card three and
four your four instance of car
three your four instance of car three I
only got two instance 2 + three original
itself so I only have three instance of
car
three so here it says your four instance
of car
three one original and three copies
where with [ __ ] stupid
problem your ininal car two has two
matching
numbers so you got card three here you
want from card one then you want card
three again from card
two so you want card three twice plus
the original copy so you have three
instance of cod
three yeah well but it says
four well is because your copy of card
two also wins one copy each of car three
in
so your your copy of card
two which give us 34
so now okay so you you need to process
this yes
recursively once you got this this list
so we can use
reduce so for example the first card
gives you 2 3 4
five then the second card gives you
added three four so the first card in
other words the first card gives you 1 2
3 4
5 card
number the second card give you gives
you 2 three 4 the third gives you 3 four
five okay but
however when you count the
multiplicity oh sh [ __ ] this two three
four
five ah [ __ ] I'm getting tired and this
is getting too long maybe I I should
stop stop or
continue those six you 11 now it's 11
people watching should I stop or should
I continue but I need to take a break
though
[ __ ] if I continue I need to take a
break five minutes 10
minutes uh I think I should
stop let's see who is talking in
Discord
nobody
yeah take a break okay lunita says thank
you 2 hours is too much hello I'm new at
coding High School how can I improve
skills should I should I waste all my
time as coding right now I have
holiday yeah okay so I'm going to I
think I'm going to stop because it
doesn't make sense just watching me
sitting here do nothing uh I mean it's
too bad I didn't finish problem two
problem one is so easy problem two is
very close I mean I can do this very
very
close uh day four problem two very close
Okay
so uh yeah but I'm tired
doesn't make sense to continue because
if I continue I need to take a break and
uh you know 10 minutes
walk uh yeah so it's better to
stop yeah install a gen to that that's
the way to
go okay bye guys thank you guys for
watching
for