good morning guys welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show I'm going to
talk about random things today so it's
just going to be random
okay so I've seen I've seen these last
few weeks ago I have seen this study
they talk about carbon Deoxys dioxide
emissions per capita in 2016 so this is
about this is you know before when we
read pollutions around the world it's
usually by country so by that measure
usually China is the worst I think yeah
but then I saw this study this article I
forgot what you are what's the name
what's the title
but the article talks about pollution
you know the carbon dioxide dioxide
emission by people but you know divided
by the number of people in that country
so and with respect to that then
actually China is not doing so bad in
fact you know it becames us you know
becomes the worst country you know if
you judge by people poor people and I
was thinking that actually makes more
sense because you know you know how much
people you have you know it really
depends on each person you know like you
you have to compute by how much each
person is producing pollution in a world
so it makes sense to divide by people
you know so in that regard this you know
the worst is actually USA so you have
USA Canada and what's this country
you know Saudi Arabia or something over
there and oh in this country this
country I forgot what's a name and then
Russia in Australia so that's actually
that's quite interesting you know you
know how in USA you have you know USA is
a rich country each person often has
more than one car and and you have this
luxury truck that eats a lot gas so you
know this is something interesting so
the so there's that let me put it down
here and we're gonna talk about key
words some talk show you know there's so
much to do so much to do and so much
things going on in a world that you know
it just is actually it's just copy that
and paste it here
[Music]
yeah so that's that's about that now
let's let's look at some keyboard I'm
just going to talk randomly okay now
this keyboard is Unicom keyboard it's
very popular now the reason this is
popular actually the reason it's popular
is because I be a model M keyboard now
if you know anything about keyboard you
know you know that this keyboard is the
most famous keyboard one of the law in
keyboard you know a lot of hackers
programmers love this keyboard because
this is actually really the the the
keyboard with the highest quality the
IBM model M
in fact IBM model M is is actually worse
than its predecessor predecessor the IBM
model F I think I have a page about the
model F yeah model F model F is actually
higher quality with Perkins string key
mechanism but anyway model M is a better
one
then they try to reduce the cost of
building the keyboard so they created
this model in keyboard so model F is
made from 1981 to 1989 t 1981 to 1994 so
anyway but most people know model M
because you know it's just because it's
it's this is this is kind of it it's you
know a long long ago long time ago
thirty twenty years ago from phone today
so anyway the good thing about model m
is that the key the key switch mechanism
is what's called a buck range string so
this is how it works you know you have a
string inside you press the key and at
one point does the
spring cannot hold it anymore and it it
it breaks to the side and collapse and
that's when it the key lost our
resistance and you know it just suddenly
you can press it down so that's so it's
very crisp the the key press the feel is
very quick crispy and precise and that's
why a lot of people love it you know
this is a classic mechanical keyboard
what's called mechanical keyboard but
one issue with it
we're known is that it's very loud
so that's how it sounds like but you
cannot probably you can probably not
hear it well because my system is not
set up correctly or something like
anyway so model M keyboard okay this is
the classic now of course IBM do not
make it anymore
and instead IBM do not make this
keyboard anymore but however the unique
comp company the guy who works for IBM
you know who works at the manufacturer
the factory or something he bought the
patent the design and he start to make
it so that his company is called unique
comp and you can still buy it today
so this Unicom is basically the same
thing as the model M keyboard you can
buy it it's not expensive it's like $80
to $100 there are there are several
models so if you love mechanical
keyboard and you don't you know you
don't care for economic ones then this
is a good choice the only issue is that
it's very loud you know Tata Tata very
loud so it's not suitable if you work in
a OpenOffice company good morning guys
Jean look couger Hey
haven't seen you here before are you in
France judging based on your name
good morning London you are back great
to see you again so so this IBM model M
is great okay so I mean it's so bad you
know come let's see what else to say
about this keyboard so if you like
mechanical keyboard this is one of the
best and you know $8,200 you can buy it
and and also interesting is that they
have they have a version
with the APL labeling on a key cap now
if you if you don't know what APL is it
is one of the popular you know it's one
of the hackers programming language okay
let me show you what this is APL APO is
a programming language back in 1970s
it's kind of still alive today and when
it was invented it was one of it one of
the unusual programming language because
it does not use you know the English
letters it does not use that you
actually uses all these weird math
symbols so let me show you the APL
symbols so the AP our programming
language uses these characters so if you
are studying API language you know if
you are a programmer you know if you are
interested in programming language
design which is a lot of my file
followers then you might want to you
know have a keyboard that has the APL
caps labels on it
so you can you can buy this one but
actually I don't you know you can buy
these for the APL keycaps but I don't
think that's the best solution because
if you really want API key caps you know
you should buy a key caps separate so
you can just buy you know you can just
instead you should buy let me show you
you should just buy you know pick one of
the ergonomic keyboard you know one of
your favorite favorite then you buy you
go by key caps
let me show you where fun keyboards so
you buy one of these keyboards you know
depending on your preferences and so on
then there are key caps that you can buy
let me show you where
some of the keep caps are extremely
beautiful and fancy for example you have
these donut shape ski caps this artistic
this out typically called artisan I
think artisan keycaps I don't know if
artisan is a brand name or you know a
specific brand name or what anyway these
are artistic keycaps there are great
varieties of design and these are not
cheap by the way usually it's like $20
up $200 some of them even more on more
than $100 you know they are a lot of
them handmade you know like they are
they are limited edition you know they
are made by artists so so you can buy
and you can also make them yourself you
know 3d 3d printing so there are a lot
of these keycaps they sell you know you
you have to go to you know you can visit
my website and find out where to buy
them actually I have a page here let's
see
yes APL is a ray language actually let
me show you maybe I can show you some of
the APL source code the APL symbols
might be worth it just for the
aesthetics yes yeah it's quite
interesting the Apr symbols yeah so
anyway I have a page here that shows
where to buy key caps so you might you
know check it out
so besides these artistic key caps so we
have this alien xenomorph you know it
means you know they are beautiful but
the expensive like you know $20 each or
more $50 each
so all these key caps and they are also
you know great different creations like
this one is mostly painting you know
painting on the key caps but then they
are also mass-produced ones like these
but however I do not know and there are
this ones which which are translucent so
if you put them on your RGB you know
gaming keyboards it looks pretty
you know the whole key lights up by the
way so so but I have not actually seen I
have not actually seen a image let me
show you
key caps
key camps factories so let me copy that
actually I'm gonna post the links to
here so you guys can see it so copy that
copy that
and I'm gonna show you the API
programming language there it is
so API programming language so that
article this article I discuss how you
can actually create a key binding so
that you can type in APL let's let's
move this here
yeah so so this page shows you how to
create an API key binding you know if
you program if you are interested in the
API language you know it's funny API is
a arrey arrey language it's let's see if
I can find a PL source code Unicode
characters APL create your own so let's
go to the APL symbols okay so actually
let's copy that
okay I'm just going to show you let that
any questions comments pace it okay I
mean type in the chat box I like to see
them opinions and anything oh yeah let
me post it here so you can go have a
look let's see how it looks
ah 200 each stupid pot and that's
so bad anyway so okay so artistic
keyboards and how to create a VL so
let's see let's look at the AP our
source code
okay so actually there are several you
know yeah API is very interesting
programming language so you see there
are these several of these keyboards
that has API keys on it for example this
one
IBM five one zero zero from 1975 you see
this the this this keyboard this
computer has API keys on it and also
also this one mca model 70 microcomputer
1972 so you see back then you know in
the 1970s api is one of the I guess
popular somewhat popular language but
also I have not actually seen I don't
remember I have actually seeing keycaps
with API you know a set of key caps you
can buy but however you know there are
companies if you are interested you can
go you know these go to these websites
that sell keycaps they actually can
print it for you so you just tell them
what symbols you want they can print it
for you I've I don't remember how how
much it cost you know for a set of keys
I think it's maybe $50 to $100 for a
full full set for your keyboard yeah if
he are symbols layout yeah let's see
what else I'm trying to find the page
where I have example programming APL I
can I don't see it here but let's go
through my programming blog let's go to
APL
yeah there it is here it is okay a PL
symbol meaning now these are what the
symbol means the operators in apa our
language you know it's kind of weird for
Grammy language but but yes it's a real
language so a real language means it's
similar to MATLAB or Mathematica where
for example for example when you want to
program please
hold on a second let me show you the APL
script so here is a example let's see
here's the example of APL source code
you know it looks like that
let's see if I have APL mod APL mod I
thought I thought a PR mod is building
Emacs but maybe not but anyway this is
AP our source code
a PL mod there's no a PL mod wait I
thought it's fielding so anyway a PR
language is like matlab mathematica so
it's a it's so-called array programming
language so what does I mean that means
like typically in Python in Ruby in
JavaScript in this when you have a list
and you want to apply a function to all
the elements of the list you have to use
the map function so you say map takes
two arguments the first argument is a
function the second second argument is a
list and the result will be a list where
the function is applied to each element
in the list
now array languages basically you do not
have the map function but however every
operation is automatically mapped so
when you want to map a function to a
list you simply you know call the
function with the list as argument
it automatically map you know it's just
as if you know you are doing a map
operation so so that is the that is the
essence and also the power of array
languages because when you have a
argument to a function if the argument
is a not is not at least the function
just you know work on an argument like
like every other language but if the
argument is a list or nested list you
know like a matrix make matrix or tree
whatever shape you know if the argument
is released the function automatically
map into them so the result is also a
list with you know just like if you are
calling a map but it's all just
automatic transparent so that that is
the essence of array languages and
Mathematica APL and MATLAB are examples
typically any math language
math oriented languages has this kind of
property has this feature
arrey arrey language hi Daniel
so here is the APL let's put it in my
talk show here so that later on I can
kind of so anyway API
so IBM model M keyboard that's that's
great okay so let's talk about some
other things then let's switch to
another topic so I got a bunch of
keyboard topics today we let's just talk
about keyboards and if you have a
question feel free you know just ask me
about to see your comments and opinions
and by the way so I have this page I
want to show you now this this this one
this page is fascinating okay let me
show you this computer language
character frequency let's go to actually
let's go to Google Chrome
no I haven't actually I haven't studied
APL but APL is like if you program in
Mathematica APL the whole basically the
whole entirety of APL is it's like
subsumed or subset of Mathematica so
easy you know it's like I think array
languages they or depending on how
severe you know is a race situation it's
kind of all similar you know but
Mathematica you know a PR kind of
mathematical subsumes it everything you
can do in APL you can almost trance
translated to Mathematica almost
function by function you know it's just
the same thing and when you know so I
was the Mathematica programmer right you
know for 10 years through our 1990s and
why when I began to learn this in you
know 1998 I was you know Mathematica is
actually actually a lisp so so I was you
know I started to learn this and I was
surprised that Lisp actually do not you
know it's a problem with least in this
community they do not rely on nested
lists and the structure of lists that
much you know they do not you know you
know just like every you know like every
other programming languages Perl Python
Ruby JavaScript okay when you have a
list
most of the time like 99 percent of the
time you just have a flat list it's rare
it's rare to have a nested list
I mean you if you have one level nesting
that's also common
you know let's say especially if you
work in linear algebra or things like
that that's common but it's very rare to
have a list or a tree that's heavily
nested you know in even in Lisp you know
in these programming languages but in
Mathematica it's like it's it's
it's normal I mean it's also most of the
time all your list is always nested you
know like there's so many levels of less
and you can nesting and you can map
almost any function that work with the
list the function has a option that the
scans you can specify at what level of
the nesting to map to you know but in
this you know in common list scheme
lists in racket in images you don't have
that that that concept is almost fari
you know so to me it's a big surprise
that the list list percent communities
they even though they're languages is
list processing but they they lack you
know they lack any notion I mean they
don't the notion of nested list is it's
not very common
I mean if of course if you ask this
program they say oh it's so common it's
so common to rely on these structures
but yeah it's common compared to Java or
you know other languages not really but
if you compare to Mathematica you see
the list does nothing you know it is you
know you're you know you cannot and
often you do not work with nested list
structures so that was very surprising
to me and what you know one reason I
have some so many rants against this
mispers because they are just patently
false but you know but these people they
don't they don't know but they think
they are right to the point that every
time you say something different they
they go they go full force to attack you
but meanwhile if you ask them - have you
ever worked with API or Mathematica you
know 99% of them is no what are those
you know so you know so that that is
that is why these issues keyboards are
more fun so it is much more painful to
manipulate in n-dimensional this
arrey in na RA languages yes indeed
nested for loops are not fun yes exactly
so this this idea of mapping to you know
whenever like in Mathematica any
function that work on least you have a
option that can specify you know a lab
where at what level of the tree you want
the function to map to so what does I
mean for example if you have a directory
right and a directory we can have
directory inside so you have nested
directory sub directories and
subdirectories directories can also have
directories inside so you have levels of
nesting you know you have levels in your
depth
you know depth one depth - you know
depth three in Mathematica its core
level its proper to call the level of
the depth but in UNIX usually just say
depth like depth - depth we you know
let's say level okay level of depth so
anyway so like sub directories you know
nested subterfuge directories you have
different levels and when you apply a
function to them you can say for example
finding you know text processing script
to do find replace and sometimes you
want to only work on let's say the third
level but no more and and and no the
second and level over second level files
you what you want to you want to do and
your script on specifically the third
level of nesting files you know in a
subdirectory so that's what it means you
map a function to you know a specific
level you can do that in math America
but in list in Lisp you know in this for
any other language almost any other
Python Ruby JavaScript you you like you
never like basically you never see it
done you you have to write it you know
your your own function you know you have
to write your own and so so anyway in
Mathematica this is this is piolin for
every every function that
works with lists also let me show you
another important thing not just a
specific level you can also say I want
to map this function to any second level
and fourth level and fifth level okay
you can do that or you can say I want to
map this function to you know a nested
list but I only want I want to map it to
all the Leafs of the of these nested
beasts you know Leafs meaning the last
level you know that you know you know
like when you have a tree you want you
to map only to the leaves you know so
you can do that all you have to just say
is level negative one you know when you
have a negative level that counts from
the bottom so this is in you know when
when you need to do this and when you
have a function that you know does that
with the option argument argument it's
extremely convenient and powerful but
again in this you never see it you know
so I was utterly surprised you know for
you know impact in 1999 to this day you
don't see that in you don't see that in
this not even closer
I don't think closure has it not even
the modern disclosure not racket not
schemed is not common I'm not sure about
not yeah I'm pretty sure not in
companies and you don't see it in
JavaScript Java Python either so you
know the they just this industry of
programmers so why not you know how come
they don't have it because I think it's
because in industrial programming you
don't really see much of that need and
also when you don't have symbolic
pattern matching you know you don't have
that much of need for it however when
when do you have the need you have the
need when you deal with mathematics when
you are doing when you are doing
scientific programming okay that's one
thing and also when you have symbolic
pattern matching that means basically
your code is about transformation of a
source code
so you do that's basically the essence
of mathematica transformation of the
code which is one of the major
application in in computer algebra
system meanings solve equations or
derivatives or integrals symbolically
things like that you need you know
symbolic path imagine so when you have
that then you do want to map to you know
level of things yeah so math so you know
so I was very disappointed by all these
industrial programmers I mean again the
thing is like it's okay if they you know
it so happens you know I came from this
language you came from that language you
know my language has this set of
opinions your language has different
assumptions that's fine but the thing
about this industrial programming these
hacker types or UNIX philosophy type of
people these okay the thing
about them is that whenever you try to
express your opinion for example when I
say how come please do not have this you
know did how come they don't you know
you don't program the structure you
don't see structure in this much or how
come a function cannot map to specific
level of nested list you know sometimes
you when you are in chat you discuss
these things they attack you like they
like the opinion is deeply set like like
they what do you mean you idiot that's
what they do that's that is why I have
these problems with this you know this
is what I call elite hacker types of
programmers I mean they are they are
just wrong you know patently wrong so
let's go back to okay so I have this
page that's very interesting now this
page allows you to let me show you
do we have computer language
okay so let me show you so yeah so yeah
so this is a page that computes let's
magnify the calc character the character
frequency in real time as you type for
example let's try T it's let's try you
see so it computes you know the
frequency of characters or letters in
real time and you can also you can you
can only count you can you can make it
so it only counts punctuation and you
can make it also count only digits let's
see nope and punctuation digits no space
no punctuation oh yeah so you can also
count it four digits you know so you
know so one of the use of these so I try
to compute you know when you design
keyboard keybinding keyboard layout you
want to find out in what programming you
know which punctuation characters are
used most often so I wrote this app so I
have statistics for : JavaScript
I have several JavaScript graph from
different JavaScript projects you know
just just so you can see maybe there's a
differences you know bit but basically
they are you know they they have the
same pattern of which punctuation
characters are used more often for
example in JavaScript parentheses and
dot you know these are very common so
anyway I have C C++ the underscore is
the most common character because they
are used in variable names I suppose and
in Java you know
the most common character is the dot you
know because Chava you have thought
something object that some thought
you know method and PHP the most popular
character is the dollar sign because
every variable start with that and so I
have Python Ruby pearl bash but I want I
want I am an over them combined so this
so this page is useful you know if you
are studying the efficiency of keyboard
layout for example or rack Commack you
know workman quality or and programmers
will rack you know programmers were
active differ from Warrick bye
let me show you see
programmers of keyboard layout so we can
go to keybinding layout layout
alternative layout so you have vorak and
you have programmers for wack
programmers for act they basically just
change the punctuation they are just for
act but they changed the punctuation
arrangement and number arrangement the
idea is that for programmers you know
you want you need to type you know
parentheses and so on much more often so
they make it you know better for arrange
rearrange the punctuation for
programmers but then now you have the
question you know if you have a program
which function is actually most used so
that that is why I created this
JavaScript app and to study this thing
and and what I so so so it actually
depends on what programming language you
code that matters a lot but anyway I
want to add a Haskell one does anyone
know a Haskell repo okay see you see you
John look
so anyway this is computer language
character frequency and this app I wrote
it's great because I can paste the whole
thing and it computes you know
instantaneously so you can copy a whole
repo you know 4,000 lines or more and
you're computed so that does anyone come
on guys give me a has cow repo give me a
heck of a pole and so we can do that so
you know I don't have a list here but
for this the answer is obvious let's go
through a for example let's go to so
this is my list code supply keys and
there are count words there are hundred
thirty-five thousand characters so I
copy it and I go here select or paste it
so this is this is Emacs Lisp
so obviously the parentheses is most
used and also the - ok the - the - is
most most used character because in
Emacs Lisp the - is used in variable
names so - first I was surprised
actually I thought the parenthesis would
would actually be first so - first then
parenthesis then the quote double quote
for string that makes sense okay so this
this is Lisp you know so I want a
Haskell so anyone give me a Haskell rep
oh oh oh some other language you know
let's just do it this is you know let's
do it give me give me some language so
we can post yeah so anyway so let's go
back random talk let this go back to
some of other keyboard of interest so
let me copy that
okay let's talk about this optical thing
optical mechanical what
yeah let's add that so so so if you
don't know you know there are many
keyboard key switches and one one of the
one of the modern one this this was like
created two years ago or a year ago 2017
yeah two years ago so they use optical
you know it's a new technology optical
mechanical switch so you know they have
a infrared or laser you know light here
and when you press it down it blocks the
light that means you know when the light
passes its own you know something like
that so this is optical mechanical
switch so it the advantage is that then
you do you do not have metal contact
because normally you know in a normal
switch you always have a metal contact
for example this is rubber dome so you
have you know two electronic stuff but
anyway for no more switch this is very
popular Cherry MX so you see there's
this metal thing
you see the way it works is that this is
a you know electronic terminal endpoint
and this this is another endpoint so you
press the key down when it's all the way
down this this thing contact that thing
then the switches on you know so this
contact is over you can see over here
you see that's a metal contact now when
you have this metal thing you know it's
wrong you know you have the issue of
rusting you have the issue of dust you
know you cannot have any dust you know
between a contact and you have also the
issue of water you know if you you know
spilled your coffee it's a problem so
you kind of least have these problems
but optical switch remove so reduces
those problems so I think you know I
really think it this is great and
however in a keyboard community you know
there are some there are a lot people
who are so very much interested in these
kind of things they talk about it all
the time
but it seems this has not become as
popular as I thought you know I think
this is very great optical switch and by
the way they are not very expensive
you know why might think it's very
expensive not really this one optical
switch is only $100 I think 72 dollars
you know yeah so I think it's really
good you know it's only 72 dollars and
you have variations this one $99 yeah so
you know
you know they are you know not economic
keyboards I must use economic ones so
you know I cannot use these but
otherwise it would be very interesting I
think you know I would go for optical
switch so optical switch
so Daniel says I have four cherry MX
switch keyboards tapping on $120
keyboard now first to steno machines Wow
you have actually two steno machines how
much like can you like can you post
photos of it I love to see them steno
machines and how much you paid them for
I thought those are like those real same
steno machines are like over $1,000 the
surge of optical keyboard switches I
don't know I'm not sure what you mean
yeah so Danielle if you can show photos
of the steno machines that would be
great okay so
oh okay so one of them is over $500 used
okay so so you know you actually type on
steno
so many keyboards here to talk about so
let's let's talk about the Czech boss
you know so so I have a review of track
balls and you know you know you have all
these varieties of track balls and one
of the frequent as frequently asked
question is where to buy track balls so
I have a page that talks about them you
can buy them and usually usually you do
you know you see this one is very
expensive $20 it's almost like you know
for 20 20 dollars you can buy a
brand-new track track ball like this one
you know so they sell the you know they
sell it very expensive but so but there
are a lot alternatives actually there
are cheaper ones today look at this one
this one is I think ten dollars okay
yeah so there are cheaper ones
and there are some alternatives you can
you know these crystals on this page you
know I give you some alternatives and
this one is very interesting because
this is this this are specially designed
they are translucent so if you have a
LED light that shines it will it will
not act like a magnifier you know like
focused you know like instead the whole
bow will light up so it's you know
designed for trackball and you can use
crystals so you know this guy use the
crystal oh ok so see you Danielle
okay race race three key ball so this
keyboard is also very interesting this
keyboard is for those of you who prefer
compact you know but not necessarily
tiny you know some people some of these
geeks
you know keyboard geeks they they want
they like extremely compact keyboard you
know they think you know saving this one
row or you know saving this one row one
column is great I don't think so but
anyway this one is for those of you who
prefer compact and full size you know
foo Keys full number of keys keyboard
without the number pad but the the great
thing about this one is that it's
programmable and actually it is driver
less programmable meaning that to swap
the keys or to reassign out you know cap
locks to escape or anything you can
reprogram the keys by simply pressing
the keys on the keyboard you do not have
to install driver you do not know do you
have to launch the software to reprogram
the keys so that means you can carry
this keyboard anywhere you know to your
walk to you know walk between work or
travel you know plug it in into any Mac
Linux or Windows the keyboard will work
exactly as you programmed you know
without having to you know set up
preferences and so on so this is great
you know I recommend it but again you
know I don't use I have to have a organ
ami keyboard so I don't use this one so
that so that is that
so the c.m stone Nova touch keyboard
this one is interesting
it began in 2016 let's see if it's still
available yeah it's not available
anymore it's kind of gone because it
never picked up the reason this one is
popular is because you know there is
this happy hacking keyboard let me show
you where close close close
Unicom close habit happy hacking okay
this this happy cracking keyboard this
is very popular among hackers and one of
the reason is popular is because it's
key switch you know it's using this
topper key switch a lot of people love
it so but the problem with the topper
key switch is that the the key stem is
incompatible with cherry MX so meaning
that if you want to add your own key
caps you have limited options you know
you cannot buy from those you know fancy
artistic keycaps we showed you the
earlier earlier so what people would
like is to have topper key switch
mechanism but the stem they wanted to be
cherry MX compatible so they can you
know switch any key caps they want so
that is why this cm stone Nova touch is
invented you know so it's it's topper
switch but however their key cap is the
same as a cherry MX keycaps you know so
on the right side you see this is this
is the
IMX keycap on the left is this nova
touch key cap so that you can you know
you can put in any trivia max key cap on
it so that that was the selling point
the creation of this keyboard but it
failed you know back in 2016 when it
came up it was you know big news and
turns out not many people you know
bought it so that's that's about that
keyboard CM nova touch the idiocy of
hacking hacking keyboard so that's about
keyboard I I'm thinking maybe I'll talk
about something else maybe one more one
more thing about keyboard this one habit
keyboard now in the past three years
this thing keyboard became popular you
know this thing keycap keyboards you
know you have very small act actuation
length you know like it's like similar
to laptops you know people are used to
laptops so maybe they this thing
keyboard became popular so this one is a
good one actually I have a unit here I'm
kind of lazy to pick it up but you know
this is a good one I would recommend it
so any anything else let me know what
type something I think I'm done with
keyboard it's you know then I'm going to
remove all these make them one based
lots of keyboards
I'm kind of bored talking about
keyboards unless you have some questions
then you ask me and I'll talk about
keyboards but otherwise let me see what
I do what I'm gonna do I'm just going to
do random stuff it's not talk show okay
so this is Mike's a talk show so lots of
keywords in omission stuff so let's talk
about this thing
yeah JavaScript okay so actually go here
so there are a lot of things going on
you know in the world so there's a lot
of things to do a lot of things I want
to do one of the things so I created
this page last week this you see this
this computes the efficiency of the
arrangement bi key arrangement hjkl
versus ijkl so you can put your mouse
here and change the value and you can
see the score changes in real time you
just put your mouse there and score it
up up or down
or you can use the arrow keys up and
down to control any one of these okay so
that's a new feature I just added you
can look at javascript code if you look
at the source page so that is that and I
want to do the same I want to do a
similar thing for this another
application so let's pull it here
close that
so I grow this application I want to do
that so let's let's just code it that
then go to
okay maybe that's it for today so thank
you for watching so I'm gonna wait for
10 seconds if no more questions then now
close it today I'm going to code and do
stuff and I'll probably start another
one later today in five hours or
something like that and also actually I
think I'm going to set up a schedule for
Microsoft or show so for the next week
it's something like let's see so today
Sunday May 12 and so for the next week
what time should it be should it should
it be like in the noon or should it be
actually I don't know should it be
anyway I'll figure it out I have I just
I don't know what I'm doing I'm gonna
kind of that is like typically anyway
yeah I'll see you guys I'll I'll
announce it you know I don't know where
know what you know see you guys