good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show today is August
11th 2019 right now it's about 9 o'clock
a.m. in the morning San Francisco time
and today we do not have a fixed topic
so the today's topic is going to be
random it's something in relate you know
something about keyboard programming
math or Unicode and let me adjust the
window so you can see it let's get
prepared okay so so I'm just going to go
over my blogs and let's see what we're
gonna talk about math extremely
interesting so let's okay so let's start
talking about keyboard then let's talk
about keyboard
okay so what's new in keyboard so jwz
you know jade jwz the famous program he
he coded the netscape back in 1990 early
1990s netscape is very famous hacker he
is Emacs user in fact his ex Emacs user
he he [ __ ] well he well he coded Emacs
so you know he is very famous and he he
reviewed the autumn ultimate hacking
keyboard let me show you so this is the
auto ultimate hacking keyboard and I did
a review so we got one guy here say hi
oh so anyway so let's look at his blog
so he actually wrote a review of the
ultimate hacking keyboard you know he
bought it
and it turns out he is very abrasive
you know rude as hell you know like he
is you know he has always been that way
he is one of the program who talks a lot
and see so anyway so he he did a review
and basically the conclusion is that
it's no good he doesn't like it well
mostly because this is this is a
so-called six sixty percent keyboard now
60 percent keyboard basically means it
only has 60 keys you know a typical
keyboard a typical keyboard like you
know one you know one of these let's see
typical like that you have one hundred
ten or hundred five keys but then you
have the compact which is about 70 keys
something like that then you have 60
percent keyboard you know people like to
call sixty percent you know it means
like that like this you know six
typically like 60 keys so the ultimate
hacking keyboard the autumn of hacking
keyboard I have it I did a review so you
can check out my review with this I did
a video two videos on it so it looks
like that you know a 60% so he does not
like it mostly because it's a 60%
keyboard you know it doesn't have much
keys and I don't like it neither you
know it becomes fashionable a lot of
people like these kind of keyboard and
by the way 60% is a stupid name you know
he just covered you know just called 60
keys keyboard not 60% so he doesn't like
it and mostly because you know it's
lacking you know it doesn't have the
function key rows and function French
function keys are extremely useful
I'm so sorry my my grass is so he
doesn't like it and he's his manner is
pretty rude you know that's his style
and you know you see you read the
comments and the back and you see the
the guy who created the automat hacking
keyboard the guy who actually kindly
reply to his post but that's no help you
know he's okay so this is Lazio mundaka
he created the Ottoman hacking keyboard
he actually replied it and in the most
kind way possible because the jwz is
basically just framing you know he just
oh I don't like it this or that so that
guy kind CV pride and then jwz also
responded and it's pretty rude you know
so he didn't he didn't like it because
mostly because it's you know just not
many keys you don't have function keys
and also you don't have escape key you
see that is a it is a problem you know
you know but if you like you know
basically like the creator said you know
basically this is a compact keyboard so
when you buy it you know you you you
know better be sure you like compact
keyboard and as far as compact keyboard
goes this is one of the best and
probably I would say it's the best
compact keyboard so if you like compact
keyboard you know that's you know that's
probably the best
okay so jwz actually he has he has more
than one keyboard reviews you know he's
got RSI jwc let me show you hi guys say
hi I got three people watching say hi
okay so sorry jwz is I so Jade jamie
zawinski that's his name and Richard
Stallman
they both have serious is I you know you
know to the to the degree that they
cannot type anymore let me find an
article say hi he okay
just type type your opinions or
questions so celebrity programmers they
await oh my god these people copied my
website when I was like let's show it so
famous programmers with repetitive
strain injury now these are famous
programmers you know who damaged their
hand they cannot type like Richard
Stallman he used to hire a secretary to
type for him so Richard Stallman jwz
it's so severe you know and the civil
bunch of others this was his set up back
in 2005 and you know many other people
so anyway so he's got severe RSI
problems and let's go back to so that is
why you know he review keyboards so he
reviewed the automat hacking he also
reviewed the Mafia's a GoPro and the
Kinesis freestyle edge so he doesn't
have a picture let me show you what is
matheus a GoPro okay and let me show you
what is Canisius freestyle edge so this
is mafia a GoPro the problem with this
keyboard is that it's got a lousy
quality you know so you you buy it
sometimes the key repeat you know so
it's not a you know you know you hear if
you read reviews you see that often like
people complain the quality is not so
good so and similarly he also made the
same complaint he
Spock and he also reviewed this one
Kinesis freestyle edge keyboard now this
keyboard came out in 2017 and I do not
have it but I judge it to be excellent
you know it's one it's the it's the best
if you prefer you know full you know
number of keys like this one's got 92
keys plus it has two rows functional
keys so anyway total of 92 keys so this
is excellent
all these are mechanical key switches
hey Demetri the me hey Demetri so you
won so and and turns out this is also
his favorite keyboard so this one is the
Mafia's oh go okay he doesn't like I you
know I you know because of the bad
quality otherwise you know otherwise the
design is pretty good
but you know they they they the quality
is not so good so that's why and but the
Canisius freestyle edge is excellent and
he jwz has reviews here so it's
excellent so you know so if you are
buying a keyboard among these three
you know Kinesis freestyle edge let me
show you I'm gonna check the comments in
a second so Kinesis freestyle edge
that's excellent
ultimate hacking is also excellent and
the Mafia's a GoPro is not so good okay
so you want to spend your money you know
between these two it's up to you because
one is compact the other one is rather
full yeah let me tell you something
about this like so Kinesis trees you
know both are mechanical keys the
Canisius freestyle edge both are fully
programmable
excellent they are programmable with the
internal memory and and the Canisius
freestyle edge is it has got driverless
driverless programming that means to
swap a key or program a key you know you
can just press the keys to program it
you it is not necessary to run you know
to start launch the driver software
but however driver software is you know
available because a driver software
allows you to remap keys you know you
know massive it's it's and you have a
visual you can see a diagram so anyway
this one's got driverless it's
driverless programmable but the autumn
map hacking keyboard is not travel as
programmable but you know but however
the programmability I think the automat
ultimate hacking Kibo is much better
because anyway check check check out my
reviews and Ottoman hacking is a bit
more expensive like quite a bit more
expensive so hey Dmitri Dmitri where you
from are you from Russia Dmitry the name
is from Russia right that's a Russian
name right it's actually let's look up
the name so the mystery says I'm a
programmer I don't do I don't do typing
I just stare at the screen and press
buttons that is fantastic
so Dmitry are you the guy who asked
about JavaScript so maybe we can talk
about that in Moscow oh cool so yeah so
do you want to talk about the JavaScript
B you know so let me know yeah so
okay yeah so yeah so JavaScript so okay
so you know jwz get off get off my
screen
get off my screen so so that was jwz you
know I have kind of of kind of fall out
with him anyway that's a so anyway so oh
yeah so that's related to the topic
actually hey john lewis i got your link
now thanks saw one link i'm so yeah so
remind me what link I don't remember you
know so we talked so let's okay so let
me talk about the yeah there is a
unpleasant unpleasant incident with the
creator of the JavaScript guy whose name
you know his name is Brenda Ike I had a
unpleasant encounter you know with him
you know it's pretty sad you know
because I was you know I'm very
supportive of him you know since he you
know the incident where you know since
the Mozilla incident where about three
or four years ago so I'm very supportive
supported supportive of him and I follow
him on Twitter but you know this guy a
Brandon Brent Brenda Ike let me let me
show let me let's go let me show you the
my blog I I have started to write a blog
about it several interesting things
going on you see this unicode cultural
Unicode symbols culture you know unicode
symbology this is study of Unicode
symbols so these are Chinese prosperity
symbols then you have these Christian
symbols
anyway let's [ __ ] let's get
let's talk about the branding I've been
done like then maybe we talk about some
of the other things and you have this
Arabic bismillah bismillah then you have
[Music]
okay let's let's look at Brenda like so
John Lewis says when you post it master
done you did not give me any link did
not know it is YouTube I don't remember
which one and yeah because you know all
the you know because a lot people they
you know you guys use pseudonyms so and
you posted a link on master than what
link you did not give any dink did not
know it is you yeah I I don't know what
you are referring to yeah yeah say it
remind me okay so let's let's talk about
Brenda Ike
oh okay these talk oh yeah you know I
have a problem with that you know I
haven't really spent time to figure out
the YouTube stuff because every you know
is supposed to have a link when you ya
supposed to be this link but but it
looks in anyways I have haven't tried it
yeah sorry about that anyway so let's
let's get to the Brenda Brenda hike
syntax OOP okay let it schnitz this
stuff on the beginning Unicode home
symbol power six Python syntax OOP
homotopy type theory bismallah category
theory talk show internet map binary
xMAP scripting okay so
okay so let's let's go through my blog
okay
the ha e and D okay it's not there it's
such for JavaScript okay here why can't
I find it JavaScript August 3rd oh there
Brendan Eich August no bastard
so they mean even go to the Twitter so
here is what happened you know let's go
to Twitter these are so do you code
JavaScript Dimitri you go JavaScript
wait a minute something wrong with the
pictures you see this oh yeah okay
finally it shows so anyway I was talking
to this guy oh by the way he's this guy
for the Fredrick Brennan is also very
interesting guy Fredrick Brennan is the
creator of 8chan you know you might have
heard because of the recent you know
incidents a a Chinese become you know
look it up 8chan okay I just look at
look it up I don't want to talk about it
I don't want to mention it because
censorship in and stuff you know just
such for a channel on the news you yo
you're kind of see he's all over the
news
so anyway the this guy Frederic Brennan
is was the creator of the a Chang
website okay he was the creator so
anyway he was talking to I don't know
who is this guy Joe but they were
talking and this Joe Dimitri are you
still there Dimitri say something yeah I
mean do you coach JavaScript okay so so
so yeah let me so let me focus on
talking about this so anyway some so
Frederic Brennan was talking with you
know Joe this guy talk in this Joe guy
is really silly you know he's saying why
should I use let instead of AA and you
know like he doesn't know you know let
and BA if you go JavaScript you know
that in JavaScript 2015 there is a it's
an entire new language
you know change egg my script you know
basically JavaScript JavaScript since
basically they created almost a entire
new language you know with lots of
features and one of the feature is the
introduction of the let keyword what the
let keyword does is that okay so what
you know like before let you have var
there's a lot of problem with a valve
for example the the the scope of our I
have to explained I have to explain it a
lot you know we are getting off track
but I'm kind of aimless in directionless
right now because I you know I could
start to talk about var and that then
this is becoming a tutorial of
JavaScript oh I can just talk focus on
the you know personal issues this flame
was in stuff with these people anyway so
it's yeah so anyway so you have raw
JavaScript okay let me show you quickly
so so JavaScript you have this VAR thing
okay bow x equals to 3 now there's now
this is there's a lot of problems with
this bow because you know it has the
scope of AA is functional scope meaning
that you know typically in a language in
in I guess Co I don't know
see but Perl or something typically if
you have a bracket like that you know
the curly bracket then the variable will
be local to within that bracket but this
is not a case in JavaScript in
JavaScript the scope of our is fun it's
called functional scope meaning that
okay so let me let me write a function
so let's say function f
okay let's let's say function f returns
three okay that's a function in
JavaScript now now if you have a
variable inside let's say okay let's
comment this out so we have a function
and okay so that's that's a function in
JavaScript okay that's a function now
you can code a function f then you can
call f you know and let's run it okay I
need to save this xx star jeaious okay
you see the answer is three now the
variable when you use var you know to
declare a variable the scope of the
variable is called functional scope
which means the scope of variable is
inside this function but however if you
have something like that Wow y equals to
four let's say this doesn't work you see
this doesn't work the scope you know the
the scope of our is the nearest outer
function if there is no nearest what
outer function is global so the scope of
our here is global for example I can
print Y and let's see you see you get
four and and in a same way for example
let's let's see let's see if I move this
in inside here
so okay so so far so what do you get you
get four because you know first of all
you have you said three to X but here
you said four to X this this does not
mean local you see so when you return
it's for let's run it you see four so
this is very nasty so there is no way to
have local variables
unless it's inside a function so what
this means is that when people when
people want to have a local variable
this is what they do okay let me show
you so if you want the local variable
you do this
this this is what you do okay so you see
you create a function you create a
function so this is a function and this
is your local variable and then you do
whatever body here then you evaluate the
function right away you know with the
bracket you see so so let's this
summarize so you have a function here
this function is evaluated evaluated
right away and you have a variable
inside and whatever body here so you see
if you want a local you know a locally
scope variable this is what you do so
you see this is this is a walk around
you know it is tremendous idiotic
you know it's extremely idiotic
essentially this thing what this thing
does
in normal programming languages you just
say that you see in almost every
programming language this is what you do
but in JavaScript you do this you know
before 2015 everyone is doing that in
fact everyone is doing it today because
you know people try to be compatible so
they want to create JavaScript in
browsers they want to remain you know
five years backward compatible so they
compile JavaScript and it spit spit out
3 2015 code like that you know you see a
lot you see this everywhere basically so
this is extremely stupid
so therefore in 2015 when JavaScript
created you know the new version called
es2015 a comma script 2015 you know they
have aspect every year since so they
they added true you know a whole lot of
features like more than 10 major
features basically it's like a entire
new language ok so so in yes 15 what do
you do is is like this ok you like that
you see you can have you
you can use let let fix fixes the
problem of the VAR you know the neva has
lots other problems not just this not
just the scope la ba has lots of other
problems you know if ya you know like
you can read my tutorial you know so you
know go read my tutorial offline so I
show you what the I show you the syntax
of our then I show you the Declaration
order that's another extreme complexity
you know vah vah has what's called name
hoisting but it does not host the value
okay that that that's a major problem
and and this page i explained the
function scope it's called funky it's
called function level scope okay
so so and and that's not all also when
you have a VAR it also becomes a
property of the global variable you know
I can show you I can show you here but
then this is going to turn into a
JavaScript tutorial today
which one do I prefer you mean I prefer
I'd probably prefer the first one yeah
so John Lewis says I'm not JavaScript
programmer does that mean if you place
var x equals 2/3 within function that it
becomes global no it's not okay I mean
this is JavaScript is rather very
convoluted language so if you want to
know if you have encoded JavaScript ue4
you probably don't want to know
it's very convoluted but you know if you
Co JavaScript and you don't care about
all browsers you know more than five you
know more than five years old browsers
then you can stick to using ES 2015 you
know for example never use var basically
that's what people recommend you know if
you don't care about you know 5 years
old older browser
you know browsers older than before 2015
actually even browsers before 2016 or
2017 because browser
you know this SPECT es 2015 came out in
2015 so when it came out you know
browser have not implemented every
feature yet so typically you wait for
like two years so you know so if you
code you know if you code you know these
features 2015 features then you can say
that you know browsers after 2018 will
be ok but 2017 version of browsers is
probably something's gonna break so
that's a problem anyway that's a
progress right you you you have to
create new specs you know new features
so anyway what was I saying
so yeah so if you do not care about
backward compatibility you can always
just use 2015 feature
like whatever it replaces for example
VAR typically it's you know recommended
you never useful unless you are coding
you know like you for very old browsers
it has lots of problems yeah anyway so
that's let me let me get so I guess I'm
I'm not explaining this but let's forget
about that
anyway anyway so so basically anyone who
studied JavaScript and used 30 2015 we
all know I mean - you know JavaScript
2015 created a whole bunch of features I
mean it's like it's truly is a new
language I mean you could say that
however the the JavaScript committee
they did they decided to be 100%
backward compatible so it's not like
Python 2 2 5 and 3 where you have
incompatibility its 100% compatible so
they do not you know make features
absolute rather they just add on top of
it so they you know they didn't change
the meaning of ah you know why is still
there they just added new you know they
added let so you know you can just you
know using let and not useful
so anyway 2015 added a whole bunch of
features and you know some of them I
guess people are feel very you know they
are very complicated lots of features
but one of the least controversial is
let you know everyone you know anyone
who actually coach I was we all know you
know that is one of the most needed
wanted feature no controversy you know
you won't let because you know it's it's
you know you know instead of writing
this monstrosity you know just because
you want a local variable you have to
wrap
function around it and evaluate it by
the way you know instead of using you
know just that so but for some reason
this guy you know I don't know you know
he don't get at this guy Joe you know
his question oh why do we need that and
you know he is totally hey hey you know
I don't want to maybe he's got reasons I
don't I don't know but it's kind of very
silly
so anyway so I you know because I follow
Fredrik Brennan the HM guy so I replied
you know how you oh my god are you crazy
look at what he says I like all the
variables in JavaScript have the exact
same rules of engagement anyway so I
replied you know telling him that let is
the least controversial you know so what
are you talking about anyway so the
conversation so we had some conversation
I mean this is just friendly chat
no voice not global good night you make
the remark siren I mean this his
programming no bow it's not global the
scope of our okay let me try to explain
this the scope of var is the closest
outer function bracket so so you you
know you look outside you find the
nearest function you know the value you
know you try to find if this U of I is
inside a function okay if it is inside
the function like like so you know like
right now we have you know it's a
function it's inside a function then the
scope of our whatever that variable is
you know inside this function okay if la
does not find a function for example
there is no increasing
function then that is global okay that
that that is a scope Wow right do you
see so so so okay yeah so you know so
what is missing is that what if you want
a local variable you know you want a
local variable for some you know let's
say you want a local variable
temporarily but you are not inside a
function you know there's no way to do
it you know well one way is that you you
you create a function just for this
purpose you see right now we have a
function here you create a function and
you know then put that you have put your
variable inside it therefore it has you
know a scope you know just just within
this function and do whatever you want
to do with the variable and you have to
evaluate the function right away you
know put the parenthesis that evaluate
the function right away did so that so
that this code block actually runs
because otherwise it's just a function
declaration it doesn't actually run you
see what I mean that's why you know so
people do these you see this code
everywhere you know this is called
anyway so you see this everywhere this
is so that you can have you know this
variable local that's that's all verbal
scope he's on the Honda Tommy yeah okay
so anyway so I was chatting you know
with them
okay so brynne Fredrik so you know I was
saying you know yeah let me get to the
Brenda hikes thing so I was saying you
know I was telling brain brain was
telling Fredrick that four reasons the
JavaScript committee decided to be
hundred percent backward compatible this
is and this is understandable and also
look at Python 2 versus Python three
situation a big failure you know so in
programming there's a issue you know so
look at Python 2 in Python 3 you know so
Python the guy doc Ike you know created
Python 3 because he wanted to fix some
problems what he perceived as a problem
in Python 2 namely the string you know
you have Unicode processing problem
string is you know I have difficulties
dealing with Unicode so in his mind he
want to create something fresh from the
ground up he won the perfect language so
he created Python 3 and he decided it's
not going to be backward compatible I
don't and this is almost like this is
like nine years ago and so it turns out
you know nobody want you know when you
do that when you make something
incompatible like people most people are
used to habit they don't want to change
you know I don't want to change you know
I don't want just because something oh
this is a better way I have to relearn
everything you know this this happens
with keyboard you know Cortile or
whatever you know it almost happened
with anything you know you have it
people don't want to change so so Python
3 now after almost 10 years you only got
like six sixty percent adoption you know
most people are still sticking with
around two and although you know let's
see
you know I wrote a lark I made fun of it
and you see when you have a program yeah
you know on one hand you want to improve
but when you improve you have this
backward compatibility problem because
you know typically for the creator you
know in my vision you know I just want
to create a fix whatever problems and
you know deprecated whatever I think
it's ugly you know I want to I want to
have a perfect language you know but if
you don't you know do
backward-compatible it creates a
practical problem because in the real
world nobody wants to change you know
they don't want to change just because
so that you know you you think you you
are creating a perfection you know so
yeah so so Python 3 he'll have this
problem you know they decided to be not
backward-compatible and it's not trivial
it's actually not trivial to convert
your Python 2 code to Python 3 it's
unless it's like 10 ninths of code
otherwise it's not easy so you know
Python 2 you know parent got this issue
so when it comes to JavaScript so they
decided oh you know look at I think they
got problems they decided we okay we're
gonna have 100% backward compatible
you know so so that's so yeah so
JavaScript they decided to be backward
compatible but anyway I made a comment
okay so so I said but you know but the
JavaScript committee also decided not to
have a pragma like use javascript 2015
stream you know I I then I mentioned I
once asked I once asked Brendan Eich why
not I didn't fully understand agree with
the reasons he gave to me is use Jes
2015 string is clean I think common
reason again is his fear pragma bloat so
basically what I'm saying so let me
explain what's going on
so so you have a language such as
JavaScript now javascript is a very
lousy language because it's it's
designed and implemented in ten days ten
days that's that's it that's a history
of JavaScript it's designed you know
thought up design the whole thing is and
implemented in ten days so it's got huge
backup problems you know one day I
should talk about all the JavaScript
problems extremely convoluted okay but
you know the Beast is out this is 1995
you know you have billions people using
it all the browser's so when you want to
you know now after 20 years after 25
years and you want to improve it what
you're gonna do you know if you if you
do like Python you know you just remove
whatever you think is is bad design you
know mistakes then you got problems
because all the browser's you know
billions of web websites will break you
know so so anyway so javascript people
they decided okay they're gonna be
hundred percent compatible and they just
add new features you know so so as a new
purpose of programa you just use the new
features avoid using the old features
so this way or the website you know or
on CD you know they all still work
that's what they do but however this
this still got problems you see this is
not the perfect solution because you see
JavaScript is so bad a language you know
var is one example why is one example
you know you have these so-called
functional skills scope like no language
does that you cannot have local stuff so
anyway so to solve the problem you can
tell people ok don't don't use var
anymore from now on you sled ok so that
can ok so that you can solve it that way
you know but they are other problems
with JavaScript you cannot solve it that
way one example is is array yeah a lot
of you know a lot problems not just the
way javascript has a whole bunch of like
would you say you know lots of problems
array so way so array so you know I'm
not going to go into details but
basically jump the problem is JavaScript
array is not real way in JavaScript you
don't really have a rea JavaScript array
is basically a JavaScript object that
mask you know that pretends to be a way
so you know typically when we have array
you have indexes right you can have 0
for the first element you know one you
know index one is a second second item
and you know but you go by index but in
JavaScript it doesn't actually have true
array even though it doesn't have a true
away way what do you have is you have
object you know object is in JavaScript
object is like like pythons dictionary
or hash table in Ruby
okay it's just a collection of key-value
pairs so you have a object and basically
the way JavaScript arrays basically it's
a object key value pairs
without older but you pretend like you
pretend it's a way so when you when you
create array idiot it is actually an
object and those you know index array
index 0 1 2 and so on that actually are
keys to the values and you have this
magical length property you know like
length is a magical key such that its
value automatically changes when you add
a more element to the array so it's like
very extremely convoluted okay so that's
one of the problem of JavaScript and
also look when you say a type of you
know array
it says objects because it's just
totally screwed up language you know you
say type of you know it returns object
so anyway that's a situation with
JavaScript away any imagine you know
arrays well one of the most fundamental
data type in any programming language
you know but in JavaScript you have this
situation and it gets you know it's not
not that's not all and this lots of
problems when you for example you have a
way you remove some element in the
middle then of a sudden this array
becomes so-called a it becomes suck so
called
a sparse array basically what means is
that it loses efficiency property it
basically becomes the object you know it
stops pretending to be array anymore it
actually becomes an object when you
remove you know when you remove lots of
elements in array in the middle that you
know so anyway it's it's even you know
you take a lot of time actually to
explain because it's
very convoluted no languages like that
not even PO you know pro is not no
languages like this okay so back to the
watts yeah that's what I mean watts hey
hey
Ben Benjamin so I'm gonna read a
commenting a bit so let me get back to
the way JavaScript problems so
JavaScript so okay so erase one with the
problem one of the big what you know
they like nasty size nasty cancer sale
in JavaScript okay so but javascript the
people they decided they need to be
hundred percent compatible so and they
decided you know they are just and they
are just going to add new features as a
way to fix all these wats but when it
comes to something like array which is
you know deep you know deep part of your
body that's a cancer cell you you cannot
just fix it by having new features
because this is co this is this look
this is the co of the language you know
unless I guess one way is that you tell
people not to use a way anymore and you
create something new away you know that
so that people stop using away but they
didn't do that but anyway so what I'm
saying what I'm getting into is that
some some think some watts you cannot
fix by just piling on new features and
one of the example is you can say that
one of the example is array so what do
you what how do you solve this problem
you know on one hand you won't try to be
hundred percent backward compatible but
if you do that then your language remain
ugly you know remain these giant watts
there forever because you know this
there's array there so but one solution
you know I think it's a good solution is
that you can have what's called a pragma
you know like like you know
it's like a hack you know at the top of
the language you say use JavaScript 2015
you know in JavaScript you has this use
strict I don't know if you know about
that
you know so anyway so you have this use
strict they created this use strict back
in 2015 what was it before anyway you
put this string use strict you know it's
a string at top of your source code when
JavaScript compiler you know a string
doesn't do anything you know it it's
just a string it's not doing anything
but when JavaScript compiler sees that
you know it will actually compile you
know you will in interpret your code
differently so that's this this this
kind of thing is called pragma you know
I PRA GMA or sometimes it's called
directive I don't know what's or engine
of those names but anyways it's
sometimes called pragma or directive I
think it came from C is that right does
anyone know yeah yeah maybe they copied
from power I know it primp oh it's
called
directive Oh pragma so anyway so
JavaScript created this you strict you
know it's kind of like a hack it's
really it's ugly but but by having these
it's kind of so when you do this now you
can fix your language problems you see
so for example if we say so so what I'm
thinking is that we should JavaScript
should create a used J's 2015 so when
compiler sees this then any array will
become you know without the words you
know they will become a true or true
array you know so this is one way to fix
problems in the language you know
because from from from this day on
when I write the JavaScript code I can
in the beginning I say used JavaScript
2015 that tells the compiler you know my
code is going to be a new JavaScript
language not the old you know that's
kind of one way to fix it you still have
this ugly hack you know this fragment
thing at the beginning but but that's
one way to you know clear out all the
words of the language
meanwhile the all the old code you know
all the old code they don't have this
line you know they don't have this use
you know most of probably you know you
don't have this line so they will still
walk but you know since now every
programmer you know add this line then
the meaning of the code changes you know
it's a new language you know so we've we
can read up all the problems of the old
language so I think this is you know a
good solution that's what I'm saying you
know that's what I'm trying to say in
this message you know talking to them so
that's what I'm saying so but one time
about a year or two ago I asked Brendan
Eich you know white white you know why
doesn't JavaScript introduce this use
J's 2015 pragma and he told me the
answer but basically he pointed out to
this this as old discussion this is this
distortion nine years ago okay so he
point you know this is a discussion
among some other guy marques Miller I
don't know who he is but anyway he
probably implement JavaScript or
something and between and him you know
he also Brendan Eich you see that's him
so this is back in 2010 Hanako and it's
very it's hard to read because first of
all it's not years old so that you know
they were talking about things happened
nine years ago you know they they they
were you know they were talking harmony
harmony was the
code for es2015 the code name you know
so it's very old and it's hard to read
because another thing with Brendan Eich
is that he's a nerd and usually I've
noticed you know because you know I've
been reading him now and then I noticed
he doesn't he doesn't I don't think he
expressed things well I mean he's often
it sometimes it's hard to understand
what exactly he's saying and he also
tends to be kind of rude oh yeah what
not necess like jwz okay like that jamie
zawinski guy he tends he's a nerd and he
tends to be antagonistic like when you
example if you talk to him I'm saying
okay this is my perception okay this is
my judgment of this guy like I mean even
in a friendly context he tends to be
like antagonistic you know like like you
know like can't that kind of style it
the way he and also how to understand
you know not you know any anyway so so
about a year or two ago I asked him you
know I asked him because you know I I
want to support him you know and I don't
mean like I just asked him for a
question you know answer me you know
because I like I like I want to support
him so back then I asked him and he gave
me answer and I think I don't remember
but I think he pointed me to me this
article this you know this long thread
you know this is huge page of the 30
pages of discussion it's hard to
understand how to read so back then I
think I look at it I don't you know you
you have to spend like more than an hour
to understand what's going on you know
because very complex you and don't long
ago so I I mentioned you know this is so
I mentioned in this thread this is like
five days ago I mentioned to
you know I was chatting with Frederick
Brennan
so I mentioned okay I asked Brendan Eich
a year ago why JavaScript doesn't use
Jarius 2015 and I told Brent I put I
told Frederick that okay Brendan I gave
me some answer but I don't fully
understand and I don't agree because I
vaguely recall you know I tried to read
this I you know I try to get a sense
what's going on what what what is a
reason he says I get a sense you know
it's too long and how to understand but
I kind of get a sense you know I don't
agree you know I kind of get a sense
because why white so but I do understand
you know so why do they not want to have
you know this programmer because one
reason is that when you have a
programmer like that then suppose you
know two years later then people who
start to want to another people want to
demand another programmer you know like
J's 2017 then you know in 2020 people
want you know J's 2020 then your
language becomes filled with this pragma
hacks you know like each one is a
different basically each one is like a
different language you know JavaScript
becomes this bag of hakama like and you
know like do this order matter so things
like that you know and I learned later
it turns out it's a compiler problem -
because compiler has to you know each
time you add this you you add this
programmer to your language the compiler
becomes more complicated because each
one of these farmers like a new language
but the compiler needs to be remained
backward compatible so each one so the
it's almost like the compiler turbo in
size it needs to pass different
languages so that's kind of the reason I
get out of it you know the which are
couette a
a park pragma bloat you know okay so so
Brendan Eich you know he answered you
know the reason you know CII
attacked Brendan Eich in this in this oh
my god a trader is so anyway I attacked
him so he answered the reason is not
just fear of Arkham upload he says but
rather hold on second
I clicked somewhere by mistake let me go
back okay okay so he says so Brendan
Eich says the reason is not just fear
pragma bloat but rather the real end
combinatorially explosive cost of pragma
blood okay so he's saying that each time
you add a pragma the compiler basically
needs to pass that new language you know
so then he pointed this link you know
this link we we've just seen he point
this link and he says I gave that reason
to you before you know this okay so you
know I didn't so you know it so he so I
you know he great thank you
you know he showed the link again so I
said you know I said Brendan thanks you
know you know I'm very polite you know
to add to this point I'm very supported
supportive of him the reason I attacked
him because so that possibly he could
you know he have a chance to you know
first of all it increases his repartee
reputation so that people can follow him
you know because you know these his name
people might follow him and also he
could you know possibly if he wants to
he could explain to me and other people
what is his reason you know he's
thinking you know so I say okay Brendan
thanks you know I don't quite
but I don't quite understand you you
argue against normal mods but also
Walmart combo explosion but you also
suggest Nuland
tag instead you know also in my mind use
trick and use J's 2015 would be only to
you know so what I'm saying is that you
know because the link he gave is nine
years old and in this link you know if
you actually take an hour to read it he
actually back then it is fact and he
suggests you know back then he is saying
he is telling people he's recommending
let me show you what he is recommending
he he's recommending this okay
he's recommending things like that he
want a new language tag no no second
name okay he wants he back then he's
suggesting that you know script land
JavaScript 2015 he actually said here
you know somewhere here you know it's
kind of very long article you know the
forty fifty pages so you know the thing
is this this nine years old discussion
is very complicated in the end you know
it and it it delves into you know the co
of JavaScript and also it you know it's
very old you know if they were talking
about Years 5 and stuff so it's any same
person we own this is not easy to read
even if you are you know I I you know I
wrote you know Chavez came in depth so I
know the very how code details but this
is still hard to read so this anyway my
the the thing is that this sprint and I
guy you know he's like very rude you
know you know so first his first
response is that okay he explained in
sayings and gave the link and iced and
he says I gave the reason to you before
and I didn't I didn't take any issue
with that
then I replied okay then I replied but
you know Thank You Brendan but I there's
something I don't understand because I'm
trying to I want to get answer you know
if he is willing to answer you know what
is your reason Brendon you know what
what do you think actually he's not the
leader of JavaScript you know the
JavaScript in committee he doesn't have
power actually today you know you know
today he doesn't have a power to tell
the JavaScript community you know yes
2019 2020 what to do if yeah he has
actually very little power but I'm
talking to him because you know so
Brendan towers your
you know like what what do you what what
do you think should be why do you think
you know there's no you Street things
like that and he but anyway after a few
more discussions you know this guy
Brendan Eich he's you know he's and kind
of idiotic anyway yeah you know I
haven't I haven't you know this you know
the tea I have to go he goes to this
thread and he explained you know those
things in detail you can read it so
basically I try to ask him because the
answer the link he gave is not too clear
because on one hand you know like on in
this he's got many issues ok on this
link he sent nine years ago he is
[ __ ] arguing with this guy this
Marquess deep Miller you know he's very
rude this this Brendan Eich very rude
because mark mark Miller said that he
visit you know Google via IV a team and
v8 team told him you know don't you know
we don't want no more pragmas and he is
arguing again is that he you know
Brendan Eich is like Van Dyke is saying
we want you know a new language tag you
know things like that so so the point is
you don't get the exactly you know I'm
trying to understand what exactly
Brendan Eich wants then he's you know
she showed me this link long night years
ago link and and you don't you can't
make sense out of it and in fact Brendan
Eich is saying that you should use a new
language tag then anyway so this gets
complicated to explain so so I'm you
know so so far so good and but you know
I don't understand so I'm asking Brendan
actually I didn't even bother ask him I
was talking to Fredrik okay then he just
replied he just Streep write to me
automatically because he's a nerd okay
he's this antagonistic type of guy and
he go around arguing with all the people
on Twitter every
day you know typically all the coders
like him you know I'm like that too okay
but typically like someone of his status
typically you become CEOs or what you
open New York you know you become CEO of
a new company or something you don't
bother coding stuff you don't talk you
don't argue about programming languages
anymore you know but he sniffing is a
classic nerd he go around telling you
know arguing with people about language
design you know JavaScript details so
anyway he he replied to my question okay
so I was you know talking to Fredrik you
know Brendan guy then he just came back
and he and telling me telling me things
and very idiotic things so this this
message you know so let's see what we
were we talking about JavaScript leaders
Google so
so yeah I was talking to Fredrik but
then he come back and says know the
answers to use get as lint standard J as
typescript act completely idiotic you
know getting rereading the inspect
thread makes me angry because this
thread you know it it roped me into the
wrong way because up to not you know
there's more actually it's up to this
point you know I find it very
distasteful because I was all this while
oh this while I was like really
supported of him and in nowhere I was
rude to him nowhere but he is like he
you know I don't know maybe he's not
it's you know maybe he thought I was a
troll or something because of my because
on Twitter I post a lot of other things
maybe but maybe and maybe not because
he's just like that you know this
Brandon guy anyway it's idiotic Brenda
okay guy forgot you know this is so many
things to say about actually I'm kind of
tired because this is my sleeping time
you know I'm going to go to bed so I'm
kind of unfocused and rambling about and
very very idiotic in you know the
Brendan Eich you know to the point you
know I'm still following him
you have to realize I'm following him
and he knows and in fact a few months
ago you know I was helping the Brendan
Eich you know his team fixing some brave
browser bug and he's he's just rude and
and also he it seems to me his head is
like buried in the JavaScript drama you
know he becoming stupid I don't know -
OH - what
you know the thing that bothered me that
is last message like this one you know
like I wasn't talking you know I wasn't
I was not being rude and I was not
bothering him in fact all this while I
was trying to not even trying you know I
might I'm not I didn't do anything to
him then he's you know he's look at his
last message and I meant what I wrote at
this you know it's like oh I I mean what
I wrote that is the only observable
evidence you bring is your shift in
rhetoric which is not good on its face
don't tempt me to mute what the [ __ ] is
that [ __ ] scum you know I in no way
you know like anyone you know you guys
can read this thread okay in no way I
was trying to insult him in any way in
fact you know that I would not in any in
fact my attitude was like I was you know
I was trying to support him but also I
was not like putting out a message to
him so that you know bothering him
knowing anyway he just like started to
have this attitude for some out of
nowhere
and it and the last message is like oh
oh you know he's telling me I'd you know
he wrote what he means whatever [ __ ]
rude message and you know and he's
saying I'm you know he only the only
observable evidence you bring is your
shifting be toric but the fact is skom
observable evidence you bring like what
would give me evidence [ __ ]
[ __ ] him are we are we liking a court
like you are suing me and I'm suing your
ass so he's like starting to use the
face observable evidence this [ __ ]
you know he's like blaming me for some
certain evidence that you bring is your
shifting rhetoric like unto rhetoric oh
my god don't attempting and then don't
tempt me to mute this is a [ __ ]
scumbag
and all this well I'm still right now
following him you know when he broke
when I saw these I was getting you know
angry you know it kind of you know it
hurts you know because all these well
you know I you know there's nothing
wrong I've done yeah and you know so at
this point you know typically like sorry
you know I would I should pack right
away I don't like mildew like do you
think I can't do I cared he mute me you
know this guy you know in this modern
age you can anyone can [ __ ] mute any
other like typically anyone would just
go [ __ ] yourself you know do I like are
you paying me you you know he's not pay
me I don't owe him money he's not you
know donate Timmy to anything and I owe
this way I was trying to piece you know
I I was you know supported with him and
he's saying mute what the [ __ ] is he
thinking you know that's that's not oh
and also he's anyway so basically what
happened is that he is thinking you know
somehow he's thinking you know I'm
he's think you know I think he's
thinking I'm trying to start oh you know
some kind of a flame war and anyway so
I'm kind of tired so I kind of like
graham board over and and focused and
even anyway so it's yeah he's a true and
you know he's he's a nerd you know he's
one of the primary nerd and you know
he's you know 60 years old something
like that you know I'm 50 you know I'm
old enough you know and he's like
probably 10 years old than me or
something and he's CEO of rave and stuff
you know he's but he's still you know
arguing with people about programming
language you see it all the time like
you go to his Twitter you know you go to
his Twitter
and you you know look at his reprise
that's you know that's when you see he
how he replies to other people and you
can see that he's like arguing like like
you know typical programmers oh my
language is better no use new language
is stupid you know he's doing that with
other people all the time
almost like hitting random like he just
random people
he's [ __ ] idiotic Brendan Hey look
let's see this one okay who owns your
attention that's he's trying to peddle
brave you know it's look at he's I must
be talking like for over two hours or
something like not making any sense okay
I'm talking way too much and let's look
at okay let's let's see he let's see his
reprise yeah he's arguing let's see his
let's go to treats and we fries okay
let's see let's stop the auto click so I
don't let him so don't don't forget A
Scanner Darkly which has adopted
something something suicide watch funny
wonder howl on this edit we all asked
what is this
Wikipedia Jeffrey abstain
anyway so anyway when I saw that he's
message like you know when I saw that I
was kind of angry I was angry for like
half a day you know and you know I kind
of respect him so I didn't I I end up
not responding you know okay let it go
you know I wasn't even I was thinking
you know then I was thinking you know
I'm going to make a video like I'm New
York South talk-show I'm gonna talk
about it
the next day you know when I was so
fresh but then I was thinking you know
let's just just let it go you know
because you know things like it's like
that you know if you just let it go you
you forget about that you know you move
on with Aveda
better things but but you know you know
if you know me you know I'm known as a
troll but I kind of like him okay the
kind of behavior mentality so I when I
saw that I have written a reply right
away like a [ __ ] stink you know not
not in a bad way though but you know
like like us a nerd you know you shoot
back exactly what you wanted you know
like like tell him to go [ __ ] himself
but meanwhile you I mean not in a rude
way but you know like you eeks Express
exactly where he did you wrong okay you
express that and you should back with
satire poetry you know like things like
that and I have written a reply right
away
let's see if I have it here I tried to
blog it but I kind of abandoned because
I haven't done either there it is there
it is you know you have to keep you know
within the Twitter limit to 280
characters so this is my reply I didn't
send but I wrote this right away slow
Brendan you are a true nerd always
antagonistic I feel estranged cause one
I was trying to
promote your take on why no mod okay and
and with the emoji to JavaScript is good
because we should use typescript plus
linty instead you know that's a question
mark sarcastic question mark because you
know this idiotic Brendan Eich like he's
saying I have to explain a thread which
was skipped you know he's saying that
you know we should use typescript you
know I was saying you know I okay let me
try to explain so the thread you know I
was you know I was saying you know we
should use the you know I was recommend
you know I was you know when we were
talking about this I give my you know I
was saying that this used 2015 is a good
thing because that way we can get rid of
the wats meanwhile improve with the
language and he was saying that the
problem this problem are creates is that
you have combinatorial pragma bloat okay
and I was saying I was saying yeah I
understand but we only have two pragmas
you know just these two because you
strict is already there so we possibly
only have one more pragma you know but I
understand you know this is the sleeper
you know sleep per erode like people
don't want pragma because then next year
2020 you know 2021 people say okay just
one more just one more
but I understand that but I'm saying you
know let's just have to you know you
strict is already there which is a kind
of mistake okay it doesn't do much then
I'm saying just let's just add one and
let let me give you my justification why
we need you know another programmer you
know jump Java Script 2015 because
before 2015 javascript is the Oh
language since 2000 you know yes Eggman
script 2015 we added you know this 20 do
you know entirely it's basically a new
language you know
therefore my my thinking you know I'm
you know I'm trying to explain my
thinking since we are on this subject
you know about the pragma so I'm you
know I just posed in fact I was
explaining to this the other guy not
been done you know so my thinking is
that okay we just have one you know two
total of two Fatima's this way we we can
totally fix you know the old JavaScript
huge package of cancer you know we can
totally have a new language and only two
pragma no more okay and because but
because because the old JavaScript
language is you know truly bad is cancer
that you know then he saw my paw he saw
you know you see I was okay here is the
threat you know I was trying to talk to
Frederic you know my friend you know
about why I think we need you know a new
mod I was talking to Fredrik then the
Brendan Eich luck comes in and he tells
he says no he says the answer is to use
of market [ __ ] Twitter you know if
I'm being treated with this pop-up [ __ ]
you know he comes in he says the answer
is to use linked you know lint is a tool
that cleans up your code kind of in
standard jazz standard jazz is is
another this kind of a convention
started by this guy by this Pharaoh sky
which is a young code JavaScript star
standard J's basically it's a convention
for example javascript has lots of
problems then one of the problem is the
semicolon problem so there's a question
whether to use or not to use semicolon
you know if you don't use job
semicolon javascript compiler has a
feature that will add semicolon to your
code but it's not it's done so badly
such that sometimes they create create
bugs so this is another major issue with
JavaScript you might have heard so that
is why so anyway so these many styles no
universal agreement some people say you
always need semicolon for example the
the the guy who created Jason you know
that guy he says you know he's opinion
you in Google Google code called
Google's coding convention for
javascript is to say always use
semicolon okay I have articles it
details about that
let's see style guide okay you can read
the details you know wait okay so so you
know this style guide covers lots of
JavaScript problems but there's also
dedicated article about semicolon in
JavaScript it's a big frame war okay
they are too you know about semicolon
there are two different schools one SKU
is that you should always use semicolon
you know and the other school which is
this furrow sky this new new new kid in
town and and one of the sect is stand
quiz called standard Jas okay that's the
name for their convention this school
one of their rule is that you should
never use semicolon if you don't use
semicolon you have other things then you
you you should never have a line that
starts with our way you know the square
bracket otherwise you have bugs you have
problems so if you never use semicolon
then your code should never have a
newline that start with a square bracket
okay that's a that's a thing that's the
thing you have to know so anyway so
standard J is is a username for
convention in JavaScript started by
think for Oh sky is it's quite popular
okay it's it's kind of a new generation
they're like they do that and then
there's a typescript as you know
typescript is a rapper it's like an
add-on language to JavaScript adding the
types you know so the Brendan so so I
was saying javascript is pretty bad
therefore if we have if we can have a
new use strict you know 2015 that could
fix you know all the problems with the
old JavaScript you know paves the road
for the new in Brendan he comes to me
and he says no the answer is to use get
lint
you know lint is a tool in standard jsn
typescript act this avoids combinatorial
mod explosion in engine which avoids
adding bugs and performance cliffs and
he says you are off target to make vague
most hate assertion that is not even
wrong it is merely impound durable
useless this extremely he is getting you
know starting to piss piss me off
because this is you know he is saying
that so I was saying you know so let me
read what I said okay
and in fact I was answering to my friend
Frederic okay so I was saying we could
argue the the hakama use J's 2015 open
store to 2020 act patos but we all agree
that JavaScript
2015 is truly a new language a pragma
lets us fix the life-threatening wats
in JavaScript this is critical because
even now most hackers hey JavaScript we
will never code it you know if you
always you know go ask : people Russ
people Python people you know closure
people Haskell people these people they
hate JavaScript you know because I've
been trying you know all my followers
you know
I know that you know they hate
JavaScript and Brendan comes in he
thinks he says you know so he think so
he think I'm like trolling or something
you know and he is telling people that
you should use the link tool and the
standard JS convention and typescript as
a way to fix JavaScript and he's saying
you know most hey desertion that is not
even wrong it's merely in past impound a
rule you impound durable useless so it's
like you know so we are not on the same
Road you know I'm trying to explain to
Fredrik you know like why I think you we
need you know why I think you know this
new pragma is a good thing because the
old JavaScript is truly bad language so
if we could have this one time pragma
together we have total of two
programmers then we can really fix this
language and I think this is critical
because today a lot people truly hate
JavaScript you know you ask all the
Haskell has got closure these people
Python people Julia people you know any
people you know have a love for language
they all hate JavaScript the [ __ ]
Brendan Eich what are you thinking and
he's saying oh you have to you just just
use no the answer is to use lint use
standard J's use another typescript
language wrapper on top of the already
complicated JavaScript and he say I'm
off target to make Lake most hate
assertions that is not even wrong it is
merely imponderable you say so you know
so we are on different roads here so I
replied you know that is strange things
you are saying you know is at this point
you know I'm not you know I'm still
don't I'm not getting you know any sense
of bad vibes you know I'm just
I saw his point you know I'm trying to
okay what a strange thing you are saying
you you know you as an old hacker knew
no one loves the language that depends
on wrapper language and linting tools
you know meaning to us you know when
people hate JavaScript you don't tell
them oh just use this link tool you know
what a [ __ ] idiot
you know who says that you know you know
suppose you create a lousy language then
you say oh just use the mint tool or use
the district on top of it so I try to
explain you know hackers do not like
chavez javascript is a matter of fact
you know what are you talking about you
know JavaScript plus JavaScript 2015 is
so bad the Industrial you know like
today you know Industrial envision it
being just a bytecode middleman that's
what happening today
you know because JavaScript you know
today you have this you know JavaScript
gets so complex you have lots of
language that compiles to JavaScript oh
then you have the ASM you know the
assembly you know like basically you
consider JavaScript as a assembly you
know so you use you you coding other
languages that compares to JavaScript so
so there's a trend you know the commonly
accepted that JavaScript is like web of
sames assembly language you know nobody
like you don't coach JavaScript you code
other languages that compile to
JavaScript so I say this I didn't think
it's controversial at all you know
then this Feroz guy you know he says you
know these young people I guess I don't
know what how they maybe they you know
for some reason maybe because my
Twitter's you know other posts they
think I'm a troll I don't know
so this first guy is a you know young
guy young star you know he says law
there are literally millions of happy
people who love writing javascript can
you guys like you read this can you
believe it he says I'm a bubble he says
there are literally millions of happy
people who love writing JavaScript thank
you
well I can see that is factually true
you know there is
new generation you know javascript is
extremely popular you know yeah they
love it but they they are like Chum you
know like when I talk to my followers
you know what do you think of JavaScript
just like nobody wants to touch it it's
like giddy ugly like like yeah a lot
meaning of happy people those are
idiotic people who don't know see who
don't know least who don't know what a
[ __ ] is coding they just you know
poor libraries that's what the [ __ ]
you idiots are but anyway I understand
you know they I replied you know how for
us and so far it's you know I don't see
any bad vibes you know at this point I
still didn't see anything bad so I just
kinda creeped i hi fellows you are a
young generation JavaScript script star
most JavaScript star new generation
IMing a bubble as much as you are you
know look at least Haskell Python Perl
communities where you'll find a person
like in JavaScript you know this is true
who likes JavaScript you know a lot Ruby
coders they like JavaScript they are in
urgent need the same kind of generation
Ruby coders in you so this is not and
also I mentioned this is not young
versus old because Haskell coders you
know today's has got lots of Haskell
told us they most of them are also young
generation okay so this is not like our
generations versus new a lot Haskell
coders they are new generation and they
hate JavaScript then the Brendan Eich
you know that he comes in again you are
just not you you are just noting tribal
behavior which cuts many ways do not
cherry-pick you know so I anyway I think
I'm gonna stop because I I'm kind of
tired
you know I'm just like Randy in randomly
making no sense at this point I guess so
yeah I guess how many people are
watching
I get more info watching
people watching me anyway so what do you
guys think you know do you tell me your
response like do you do you think I'm
crazy or what who is going insane here
you know back in the days you know like
today for this you know for this time
I'm thinking you know I just let it go
so back in the days I should back right
away [ __ ] idiot and I'm going to book
as this thread to all the people so so
you know I this is what this is this is
what I am you know back in the days in
the 2000 say in computer language you
know people call me a troll in these
groups I'm gonna post this you know I'm
gonna capture spins you know the full
record of this entire thread without me
you know trying to edit or anything
nothing like that I'm going to capture
this I'm gonna you know frame it you
know in broadcast it to fold all the
words to see I want people to see who is
the [ __ ]
who is impolite who is not the flat
[ __ ] idiot not getting what's
going on this Brendan Eich and this you
know for us I by the way they are not
bad okay they are not doing anything
wrong it's not that serious but but you
know this there's something you know
this not you know they are doing you
know they are not being I mean for us he
didn't do anything wrong okay
but the Brendan Eich at the end he's you
know don't don't tempt me to mute
[ __ ] who care about you don't tempt
me to do I care you know anyway
you know so anyway that's a situation
there so let me let me read the comments
so Jean Louie says it appears that
JavaScript design decisions are from one
person or few with our social consent I
think scheme has social consent on how
language should develop no actually
javascript is designed you know they
have this committee it's it's actually
by social
and they have you know you can follow
and look up I kind of follow up but not
not very tightly right now every year
they have a new version like new spec me
you know there's a JavaScript 2019 I
don't know if 2019 is out yet anyway
every year they have a new spec and they
have procedures like how they make the
decision basically anyone can
participate you know you can if you want
to you make up your proposal and they
have several steps to go through and you
know I can show you I can show you the
places anyway
let's let's try to find it okay TC 34
something yeah I'm kind of tired so I
kind of like rambling rambling and
focused yeah TC 34 let's see JavaScript
ECMAScript 2019 okay let's see if I can
find that
but anyway it's there's a committee and
you can read about this guy this this is
a this is a great JavaScript expert this
to ality guy this guy dr. Excel Ron
schmao
he's a great JavaScript expert and he he
writes blog about the latest JavaScript
often you know all the time so a word on
Java a word on Ahmed script version so
okay so tc39 tc39 is the the name for
the process for new egg mafia
you know he explains how he works so you
know so actually it's a it's kind of by
a committee and Brendan like you know he
doesn't have any power you know I'm
asking him on the trailers threat just
because you know I want to get his
opinion yeah but I know he doesn't like
he doesn't have any power on the on the
new JavaScript decisions and in fact
sometimes he want things this way but
they don't want it that way you know
things like that okay hi rah - were you
so John Lewis says okay so Benjamin says
many nerds are very rude even Lina's two
votes
yeah Lena's to vote is another one yeah
that's exactly he's a talker you know he
and and when it comes to writing he
flames to people all the time so Elena's
towards and I don't know if we include
Brendan Eich in in in that group Brendan
Eich doesn't swear though he doesn't say
you know go [ __ ] yourself he doesn't do
that though I haven't decided see but
jamie zawinski does you know the the
other guy I was talking about in the
beginning of this video on keyboard he
is easy desert flame people Johnny says
being rude is a choice for people but we
are all related
so being rude to a known person is about
same as being true to oneself or to
friends and family
okay I'm kind of tired javis leader is
Google ah he's a troll he only made
great because Mozilla didn't want him
anymore
okay we are stuck with JavaScript
forever because of the web even if
everyone hates it so it's important to
improve so Benjamin says javascript is
popular for people who go to code camps
because they want a tech job exactly and
so they know yeah so Ryan Ward
Ryan Ward says I love for Whammy on my
calculator in Casio be basic in middle
school does I make it a good language of
course not I'm sure some people love
JavaScript but that doesn't mean it's
because the language is good yeah okay
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching that is yeah I'm tired and just
this is just giant rainbow okay thank
you guys bye guys any questions any any
last words
type it
yeah so so what do you guys think you
know I'm not too crazy right anyway so
on the news is this guy Jeffrey absurd
Epstein
supposedly he killed himself but by the
way he you know he's got a private
island and Marvin Minsky which one which
is one of the greatest AI artificial
intelligence researcher also went to the
island in fact Marvin Minsky is one of
the accused for you know having to do
with the girls and also Gerard Sussman
the scheme big I also went to the
Ireland so you know that that's a big
political thing okay that's it okay okay
um thank you guys for watching bye