good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show today is July
10th 2019 3 o clock p.m. California time
and today we are going to do a goal and
a live goal and programming and we are
going to write a small script that
process thousands 5 thousands of files
10 thousands of files to generate a list
of links basically so in this you will
learn you know if you are new to this is
kind of for beginners and you will learn
you know if you don't know goal and
you'll learn some goal and you hope
hopefully you learned something about :
or inspire you to learn the goal and
language now of programming languages I
love : because of the industrial
languages a man Perl Python Ruby Java
JavaScript for example including closure
you know for example all these languages
: is my favorite so these are industrial
languages my favorite languages exact of
them all is actually Mathematica but
that is a math language or science
oriented math language anyway so in
industrial languages my favorite is :
because : is is actually the same the
most simple to learn the concept of :
you know the programming language model
is very simple it's simpler than Python
Perl Ruby JavaScript ok and 3 and it is
fast let's see sorry : it's fast
it's almost as fast as see you know so I
have a tutorial about : you can you know
if you like to study :
read from my tutorial so it's simple the
language is very simple and it's super
fast it's as as fast as you can get
these similar to see the speed of : and
it can be compiled or it can be run as a
script just like Python or Perl like you
don't have to go through the Commun Oh
read Co compile then run the code this
loop you just write it and run it you
can if you want you know just like
python ruby and but if you want you can
also compare it so you got a binary and
send it to a friend and your friend can
run the program so it becomes a
independent application you know your
friend do not need does not need to
install you know got the goal and you
know language which is the case for you
know if it is Python or Ruby
so so this is a good great advantage you
can just compare the code and you run
anywhere you know actually does so it's
it's the language is very simple and
it's very fast faster like six times in
general six times faster than Ruby
Python pro and it can be compiled or run
as a scripting language and the
documentation of Golan is superb is the
most it's the best documentation ever
you know it's a you know I read you know
ten tenths of documentation in the past
thirty years
the Golan is tops one of the top you
know top you know the great
documentation Israel actually among all
programming languages in technology
programming language expect or
programming language documentation or
the the documentation for application
for such as Apache UNIX you know UNIX
main page paint main pages and you know
many you know documentation so goal and
documentation is is the best most most
the documentation Xin
the programming industry is crap it's
like below the standard even but go line
is is truly great yeah so simple
language very fast you you use it as a
script or it can be compiled you know
you can use it as a system language is
it's designed to be a system language
like C or C++ and then it the
documentation is superb and it supports
functional programming
I am always haha I have always been a
functional programmer for the you know
this beginning in the 1990s with
Mathematica I do not like
object-oriented programming at all in my
own programming I never do use the
object oriented model
I always just do functional programming
style you just write functions no
objects then oh no you know this
inheritance crap okay so golden supports
functional programming well you know
colon is not extreme like Haskell where
you have then then you have like monads
okay you have currying you have you know
all those less practical things but
Colin's supposed function of programming
because very well because a function can
return a function function is a is a is
a expression you know by itself function
can return a function and function can
take a function as argument so in that
purse you know in that respect it really
is what you need
so : so let's start coding : okay so
let's begin so let's see how many of you
are watching two or three people so if
you like I mean okay so you are you are
here and once again so let's you know
say hi or seen something oh hey good
morning break the loop hey saw well well
what was your engine amount of
the motivation in learning what you are
simply curious about its syntax so I
don't know if I already answered that
question so my original motive a
motivation for learning go why was i
studying go in the beginning I forgot at
the moment but anyway I wouldn't here's
what I can tell you at the beginning
when I first heard that Google you know
somebody in the Google Rob Pike and
friends you know they created : this is
like 10 years ago so it's like 2008 also
you know when that you know many
languages are coming up so when I first
heard that Google created goal and I
think it's crap you know I thought I
will never learn it I you know because
you know I saw back then I was thinking
so the so we we have you know we have
Java you know created in 1995 I can't
understand Java you know again except we
need a new language Java because it has
a new virtual machine you know the model
you know you like supposed to run
everywhere by having this virtual
machine where where every everywhere
where Java runs you have to install this
virtual machine and that concept is not
new with Java anyway you know but
however it was Java is the this is about
the supposed it's the first one to make
that concept popular you would run a
java you run a virtual machine you know
at the end so Java and Java is kind of
supposed to be a replacement of C first
for us now C++ I despise okay it's a
wholly complicated you know crap you
know a pile piles of a pound
you know let's see press worse okay
so why people use it because they
achieve you know speed they grow they
become popular because of the UNIX
philosophy you know basically you create
a virus get people used to it then it
becomes popular industry has to support
then you you know add a little bit you
know features and try to fix it you know
that's us that's my my perspective of
the entire C C++ and D you know that
kind of line of you know the popularity
in industry so I thought Java was you
know there's a good reason for Java to
exist because you know it can replace C+
first you know I'll say you know it's
decide you know a coherent fee without
you know not picking back on the history
the baggage of see you know so you have
Java like the new okay but you know Java
is I don't like I don't think I I don't
like Java at all but anyway so I think
there's a reason for it to get invented
so anyway 1995 send in do you have
JavaScript anyway so what so what was I
saying so I was saying yeah so when okay
so you have Java so Mac from some
Microsystems then the Microsoft you know
they get jealous they had to create
c-sharp you know like what the
so what why do you need c-sharp why are
you doing it so it's C sharp turns out
is is you know some people will
criticize will claim it's just a copy of
Java you know a like a copycat but
according to the inventor you know
according through some people you know
they don't think it that way they think
actually so you know there are arguments
about why C sharp is necessary but at
you know anyway case it's necessary in a
sense it's Microsoft's version because
when you create a language and everyone
wants to use it you have advantages as
the owner of the language you have quite
a lot of that advantage so Microsoft is
not gonna you know you know that your
Sun Microsystems do stuff so so they
create the c-sharp you know then you
know so and you know many languages and
they are kind of similar okay
which is in general not a good thing to
programmers because as from an
engineering perspective you rather want
you know one system you know you don't
want to placate like copy a little
variation here just because different
corporate interests you know you know so
anyway so that that's you know the
ending you have C shop then and then you
have F sharp now F shop is interesting
now if you don't know F shop is a
functional programming language it's
based upon the oak ammo which is based
upon camel which is based upon M L now
the mal stand for meta language which is
what Haskell is based upon so mal the
meta language you know usually called
mal and there are several variations
there is another variation called
standard ml so you have this in the
beginning you have ml which is meta
language it's designed to do proofs in
mathematics it's a functional language
it's you know so mu is this is like
1970s I think so you have ml meta
language then you have some variations
standard ml then you have you have camel
then you have Oh camel which is
originally it means it means object
camel okay then you have F sharp
somewhere in between then you have
Haskell okay you know it's the this so
this bunch of languages are in one
family they are like close you know
almost the same so ff-shop so why do why
does Microsoft to F sharp you know of
course you know it's a good thing in a
sense that first of all Microsoft want
their own versions you know Microsoft is
an industrial cooperation while the
Haskell and ma are they are typically
using academia in research so they don't
have much exposure to you know to the
vast majority of programmers
and you know they are some you know so
it's time you know because you know that
we have technological progress so
Microsoft decided it's it's mature now
to introduce functional language as part
of the Microsoft you know call product
you know and to the you know vast
majority of programmers industry
programmers
it's kind of very pure you know
functional programming f-sharp is you
know based of Kokomo so Microsoft
created f-sharp this is around I think
two thousand five two thousand seven two
thousand five and this is also you know
in mm it's also the time where a Haskell
became increasingly popular so anyway so
you know we have so many languages right
so so then around 2008 then and then
Google Inc created : and I read okay oh
it's from Google and oh it's based on
UNIX philosophy well they didn't say
that but it's based on the guy who who
fathers you know who advocate see the
eunuch UNIX philosophy crap okay it's
it's created by Rob Pike and friends you
know you know Rob pack the UNIX people
I despise I you know I talked about this
many times in my videos I despise the
UNIX philosophy I think it's a code it
has no content absolutely so so I heard
okay Golan you know this UNIX philosophy
you know Rob Pike created : so hey so my
opinion is it's it's you know I'm not
you know it's it's a worst it's probably
the worst possible
okay so that was back in 2007 also when
we created but maybe three five four
years ago I think four years ago
let's see goal and it stuck in my
tutorial I so I started to write this
tutor
in 2016 so I yeah I guess around 2016 I
started to learn Golan but why I don't
remember actually why I you know what
what is the impulse whatever
what's the reason that made me start to
learn : I don't yeah I don't remember I
could find out though because you know
because I write blogs so if I go to my
programming blog and go to swimming blog
archive then just go through the you
know years after year you know studying
maybe 2014 yeah you know you might I
might find you know my blog where I
talked about something about Golan you
know that that's one of the advantage of
keeping a diary that's what that's the
purpose of diary so I don't remember
what how I got into Golan now but but I
do remember when I don't go then you
know I read I read that you know when
you start to learn language usually the
first task is that there are so many
tutorials you know you search for :
tutorial they are like tens of them and
you have to judge you know use your
experience to judge which one is
actually good
which one is just crap you know created
by this you know small corporate small
companies they just want ad money you
know they just they hire people like for
$1 an hour or something like that you
know cheap to create to pump out a
tutorial for Golan for Thomas Cuba for
everything for PHP you know you know so
because they are because a lot of people
you know they want to get into
programming you know they have no
engineering background they are not
interested in math or they know is that
they heard Oh
programmers can make a lot money they
heard so they want to get into
programming so when you know you typed
any programming tutorial : or whatever
language JavaScript you will find a
bunch of these websites they they are
just like the almost like spam they you
know the
just create sites to attract to get ads
money you know basically so and you can
always you know what you can always tell
from these this website basically the
first thing you know the first like
litmus test is that it's a website
pretty you know for example it's they
say : okay let's say : tutorial you know
you know the way you judge you might
still have yeah okay so you know the way
you judge for example : to Tokyo okay
this is official : but whatever that is
go to Tokyo yeah this go tutorial this
from this tutorial point tutorial point
is one of the commercial you know is one
of the low quality in my opinion website
that creates tutorials for every
language you know they they focus on you
know their audience their primary
audience is people who has no
engineering background not necessarily
interesting programming you know they
they focus on the masses so anyway so
the first the lid much you know when one
way you can tell which tutorial soccer
decide if you check their website if
they looks all pretty like this one like
like here you know oh no go pretty logo
nice you know graphics like nice logo
nice you know social network links you
know actually you have two
yeah social networks you know they want
you to spread then you know it's it's
it's the the content of the site is
probably not not that good anyway I
digressed a lot actually and also look
at this you know they they pop up
this they want you to subscribe or
whatever you know is and they make
money they do actually they do make a
lot money and you know this anyway so
anyway I do remember that you know one
thing I remember about : he said I start
to read it it's very simple
that's that's the first thing that
attract you know I find it good it the
the whole language like I am Telling You
you can learn you know in your day or
two basically almost the whole like
which is not the case with Python
you know because each language you know
at least Python Java they kind they all
have a model or Haskell or camera you
know they they all kind of have a model
behind like how how that how the
language work works and and this model
is almost never explicitly talked about
instead instead as a programmer when you
learn a language you simply just work
you know you just get the feel of it you
know you know but this model is never
really explicitly talked about no
document documented for example like you
know for example if you say : versus
Python versus Rubio versus Java
JavaScript any language you know you you
compare you know so what's the
difference between them nobody almost
basically only your handful people can
actually explain because you know like I
can explain what's the difference
between : any two language let say
between : o or Python you know pythons
very popular well I can start to explain
oh you if you ask yourself or any other
programmer they can start to explain you
know if they have experience let's say
five years programming they can start
OCO lines like this or and you know you
really you know the they have this or
that functions different features colons
number is that you know Python is
untyped you know colon is type they can
explain in this loose manner
okay this loose manner but but then you
for example then you ask them so what's
the difference between type in and
untyped they they you know because it's
actually very complex is the whole thing
is in entire complex so very few people
actually can explain the real wait weeks
brain differences the real way to
explain the differences between
languages is is you know to properly
explain is to actually invoke to to to
describe you know each language they
have a model actually they have kind of
a semantic model behind them and that is
like almost never explained or
documented why because because it's very
difficult it's extremely difficult to
actually explicitly explain or codify or
you know - right right out how the how
the model how the language actually
works it's very difficult you know so
that that is why okay so let me read
some comments I I talked about for 20
minutes let me read some comments then
we start - then we start to code :
greetings
Bartholomew bass Alamo
the Battle of MU J s Bethel o meu
JavaScript okay so your JavaScript code
greeting stick ways hikes are you
inspire me to make my own Do It Yourself
keyboard cool great so okay so so let's
start coding : okay so if then we need
I'm going to give you a I'm going to
tell you why what are we going to do
okay so I'm going to if you go to my
website homepage scroll all the way to
the bottom you will see a site map a
site map is basically a list of links
all your you know basically all the
pages on your web website it was popular
popular in mm so anyway so this this is
my site map I can randomize the the
links I have like $3,000 costs
so you know sometimes I cannot find you
know the article what what did I just
click I think I clicked on a ad by
mistake
so anyway sitemap okay so what we want
to do is to to create a go landscape to
generate this content so every month for
example every month I render script and
this page will be generated for me
instead of man manually but so let me
show you okay go
sorry sitemap change sitemap go okay
Oh bathroom okay those Jas does not
stand for JavaScript okay so here okay
so a sitemap now let me explain first
first of all there is a different
meaning let me explain what's a sitemap
there's this more than that okay so so
let me show you a sitemap file so go
through my web page go to what's going
on okay so back go to sorry
info sitemap okay sitemap is this file
there is a standard called
sitemap okay and this is this is the
file
it's basically XML file you can see it's
an XML file and each line is a URL
essentially and that that that is it so
this file is named sitemap out XML it's
a XML file and this is a standard is
there suspect if you just search for
sitemap and this sitemap is in your home
directory of any web site optional it's
optional you don't have it's not
necessary but it's good to have so
what's the purpose of side
the purpose of sitemap is that search
engines you know web crawlers Google
Microsoft Bing or you know any search
engine they can easily find all the
content on you on any domain you know
any website you know so they can index
it so this is easy you know this is a
mechanism how they do that
it's a optional without sitemap then you
know the search engine the web crawler
has to like visit every of your website
every every page and they try to extract
the page and try to follow those links
you know then eventually they get a list
of all the URL on your website so that's
very inefficient so they created this
Google I think Google is part of the
original creator who created this site
map around 2002 or something
to facilitate to help you know help
themselves basically so that's that that
that's what site map is okay so I
actually so I actually I have a code to
generate sitemap in colon and also in
eMac this and also
so I actually so I have a so this is
this is actually a emag Lisp code to
generate site map and so anyway so
anyway I have this : script it's already
written that generates the site map this
file so let's go to my goal and script
so this is my goal and script to
generate send map it's 295 295 you can
see a let's go to the directory this is
the file so this is the directory start
web
sorry info and and if you scroll down so
you can see this sitemap file I open it
you know and this file is 3600 lines
okay now let's delete it so select the
whole thing it okay select the whole
thing delete it save okay now let's go
to directory refresh you can see it's
now 0 bytes basically we delete it it's
just e the whole file okay so it's gone
delete I deleted and now I'm going to
regenerate it by running this : script
so I run it it's running it will
actually generate the sitemap file for
all my domains sorry
in folk sorry okay and so on so you see
it says file saved to here and I'll save
to you know it generates a bunch of
sitemap files for each of my domain so
you can see here is the calidad info now
if i go back to the directory refresh
you can see the sitemap file is back
let's open it you know it's still it's
just you know the scriptures generated
so you see so that is great this is very
useful you know cola and creating
sitemap so every time you know every
month I just run this script you know
any generate sitemap any comments
questions comments in opinions posted
okay I'd love to see that so let's see
okay so so but what what are we going to
do you see it generates a sitemap dot
XML file but that that file is not this
page because this page is you know this
page is from you know you go to the
bottom you know you go to you click on
sitemap this this page is for users for
people to visit while the sitemap dot
XML that file is for for machines for
web crawlers to quote so what I want is
to modify my goal and code this code
let's make a backup so make a goat
modify this script so that it actually
every time I create a sitemap dot XML it
will also update and generate this page
so let me let's open this page and see
what it looks like so this is a page you
know excel code sitemap okay so let's go
down so you can see last update July 8
and you got this bunch of let's view it
locally
okay let's view it in my Firefox browser
so this this is the sitemap page you
know 3,000 4,000 lines so every time
every month you know I
have to regenerate this this list of
links manually for example let's delete
the whole thing okay showing browser now
the whole list is good so how do i
generate it how do i generate it i go to
my site map file sorry info okay is
exciting for a sitemap XML file I open
it this is a sitemap sitemap XML copy
the whole content close it create a new
buffer paste it okay and the switch to X
HTML mod okay now I call the command to
remove all the tags you see these tags
let's say way XML a way why it's not
okay so it's colored okay so you see all
these tags I want to remove them all is
instead of an XML I want just the least
you know all these I want to create a
linked list of links so I delete so
first thing I do is delete all the tags
I can I can call this command so HTML
remove HTML tags so all the tags are
removed then I call another command it's
it's let's just do it
so I call command sapphire link of I it
will take wait wait
so I call command wait
let's go command okay so the command is
line is to list so it's cord echo it it
will take three seconds because there
are thousands of them oh we're actually
this wait this is oh it's done okay so
you see it turns the whole thing into a
list then I copy the whole thing close
this file and you
I paste it here I paste it here and show
in browser so now I got the you know new
you know list of links so what what I
want to do is to do this in goal and you
know to make it automatic okay that's a
lot of talk so let's let's start coding
so you go in goal and let's start coding
should we are we so is the good so far
so we should start coding : yeah let's
start coding : so let me take a break
and you know think we you know we gather
my thoughts and we will not
oh so Derek ways says how does the list
get the titles of the link well that
yeah that's a part of the Emacs command
so let me show you
so that's part of the wait
he's my Emacs stuck okay no okay so let
me show you the is it gonna index blog I
don't know where that is
so anyway go let's go to my computing
block okay so I let me show you the
command so so so suppose I have a file
path okay let's go here okay so so go
here let's say you know here's a file
path of my blog and I just go a command
it becomes a link but however if I
called the HTML lines to list each line
also becomes a link if it is a file path
of my website you know it's very
convenient and what does so so we can
look at the code for example the code
code is that okay so so it's part of the
exciting moment we go into it here is
the source code this so here is a
function and if you search for title
yeah so here is the actually here there
is a function that excited email get
HTML file title basically it takes a
file path and it returns the title of
the file the title of the file is is
from the you know the title tag that
that's how it you know that is so it's
just Emacs stuff Emacs so eMac in Emacs
please so many technologies too
so anyway that's you know that's a
that's a advantage of learning MA at
least you can just create what you need
to be done you know for yourself you
know so I'm thinkin so now we need to do
great so we we need to code goal and I
guess a lot so are you guys interested
in : because I I guess I talked a lot
for 40 minutes okay so we if we're gonna
go to goal and this this is only 200
lines of code
now I'm guessing you guys anyone know
goal and you know because in general
people don't so you saw I you know I'm
thinking I need to explain but it's this
let me just code it then yeah let me
just start to code it yeah and you know
so it's best less about tutorial then
anyway so okay let's just start code so
so anyway so here is a list of paths
each one is a path to a domain website
domain okay so great so let's to goal
and so each one is a domain name and
let's comment out because we just need
to do one let's just do Kesari down info
as an example because that's what we
need to do we need to when it generates
so here's what happens okay let me let's
specify more clearly what's going to
happen so this : script it will take a
file path the file path is supposed to
be the route path of a website okay you
take a list of file path
let's just focus on one so you take a
route of a file path of a website okay
then you will go into that directory it
will visit every HTML file
you know thousand in dot HTML then it
will create basically a create create a
list of all the files then it will put
all of them into the file name sitemap
at the root directory so that's what it
does that that is a essence what this
little script does it takes the root
file path it visit visits every file in
that directory and just generate the
report in XML format you know and
inputting you know the output is the new
file set mapped out XML and it has some
features such as you know there are
certain paths certain directory name you
want to be excluded you know for example
this
these are documentation like Miro
documentation I don't want to be part of
my website so this directory will be
excluded you know things like that you
know and and also get directory you know
it should be excluded so yeah so this
that's what this script does so yeah let
me go over the general structure so you
you you know you know you declare
package every every go language every go
file must have a package so if you
create a script the package should be
just the main yeah I'm trying to so that
that is the basic of : so you know like
if you visit my : tutorial you are see
this is basically the structure the
structure of every : source code file
every goal and source code every one of
them have these parts package
men okay then import something something
that very import you can a bunch of them
then function men every goal I must have
that every goal and final source code so
back to our code so we have package man
we have we have import let's go let's go
back you know it's the same thing here
so package man then import then then
then you have then you have you have a
main or let me show you where okay so
then you have let's focus on one place
instead of jumping jumping around so you
need package man then you have a bunch
of import library names then you have
let's go down then you have men okay
here at the bottom every go file must
have this main function this is when the
program start to run okay so all the
things before that they are just trunk
function definitions
you know like off or variable
definitions like kind of global constant
function definitions so so in the end
the whole program is just this min we
are running this so what does it do so
it so that let's look at the main okay
so it declares a variable out bytes
which is a sequence kind of a you know
it's it's basically just array of bytes
then for each directory to process you
know so it's pretty simple for each
directory to process we we set the path
to URL directory path to URL
get matched so what does it mean path to
URL so what does get matched does get
matched returns that pair from mmm whose
key is prefix in X evening what
is some kind of file name filter anyway
so
so for each directory to process you get
path to URL then out bytes then out by D
equals to sitemap these path to URL then
saved to path file path join then write
to file then just print so it's so
simple but I have to wrap my brain
around it so what so so this is the
whole this is the thing this program is
doing but what exactly is easier doing
so out by is just a sequence of bytes so
in : you create you know basically it's
like a stream so eventually you are
saving out bytes to file you can easy
save two variables save to path so here
is the path to save to destination of
file name file path we the to process so
anyway so this is a save to pass then
you write it out fights you know you
write the bytes you just generated to
the file path then you just print you
know it's done okay so you so you did
declare bytes
that's the byte to output then you say
sitemap we pass to URL so what what is
this V so what does sitemap do so let's
look at so it looks like so sitemap
returns a bunch of bytes right so it's
the site sitemap generates the
or sitemap file it returns a bunch of
bytes then you save these bytes to a
file so that's so sad map returns the
bytes essentially yet that represents a
sitemap file so how does it work it out
it takes two functions so let's look a
sitemap function so sitemap function is
this chunk like 20 lines so let's look
at look at look at the Declaration so
sitemap takes a directory string then it
takes a another string path to URL okay
I understand so it takes two arguments
two strings and it returns a byte okay
the the return value represents the
whole XML file so you can see the first
line you see it's trying to generate the
XML file the first line then you know
you know it generates the whole XML file
basically but anyway it takes two
arguments to stream so what are those
strings so the the first string I should
have some documentation I didn't do
documentation so dou X okay the
directory the first argument is a
directory to descend into that's the X
then the second argument has to URL way
way um
I'm surprised I didn't write
documentation for these paths to URL and
now looking at it you know I wrote these
like four months ago it's not true
obvious it's not very obvious you know
the idea of programmed so this is not
good you know that well I mean in the
industry if you look at the source code
they are much far worse you know this is
actually clinging and short very clean
code but still it's not ideal because
ideally you look at like if you look at
the main it should be all just obvious
then you know you look at for one you
know have ten seconds you understand
every function what exactly it's doing
but in my case it's not so slight you
know so so you look at the main so it
declare out bite okay that's easy to
understand then it loops through
directory to process so directory to
process is very simple it's a list of
you know directories we want to go into
you know the root directory for each
website okay so that's directory to
process then so you look through them
when you look through them you give them
two values this is the syntax of for
loop of a range so the first variable is
underscore that means it's a bit that
that basically is an index like 0 1 2 3
4 and so on we don't need that so that's
why we use underscore the second one V
is a variable so V is actually each of
the value of the list that's right
II V is each of the roots path okay so
these just a directory ok so far so good
so V is just the directory let's make a
backup let's modify it so you know we
replaced by the
rude okay and it's clinging about miss
so V is rude okay so Jude Jude Jude okay
that that should be it let's run it
again
so it is look at it should walk it's
done okay so now it's still walking so
so weak so we got so far
Ruta we go through that each ruder is
the directory okay then what we do is
that I learned to make long variable
parameter names so that they are self
document document maintain yes yeah I I
also do that I you know that's actually
my habit too because my variable in
function names tends to be long like 30
30 characters you know this interesting
thing right try to code :
you know goal and is in the community in
the style you know in assists sis system
programming how they could you know the
the is basically C and c plus plus
community and this community therefore
my style is rather different from
scripting community bash Python Perl
JavaScript these scripting languages
there's a difference there's a bit
different so in C kind of languages they
tend to be short very short characters
so so what I was saying is a wide when I
try to go why sorry to code goal and
it's interesting because it changed
it's new it's fresh you know it changed
changes your habit change change my
habit change a little bit to follow the
goal and conventions you know they you
know they don't want
elaborate 30 character names they
weren't used typically a short you know
anyways
say anyway so ruta is a directory so the
first thing we want to do is to yeah I
prefer long name you know it's the
interesting question because I don't you
know I think there is no right answer
because I think it's like people say
there's actually this it just depends on
some kind of balance depending on the
context different depending on the
function what situation
what meaning of the variable at the time
it's kind of depends on that that
because on one hand you you could go
overboard with long names like when you
have lots of low names then it becomes
less readable on the other hand if you
name everything you know one or two
characters that's obviously bad you know
so so another interesting thing is that
we actually you know as a programming
practice convention we don't have a
solid science on this issue you know
ideally we could have you know let's say
there's a solid subject you know like
like science scientific based study like
maybe we have us eventually we might
have maybe 10 10 or 20 years later but
we right now we don't have like Assad
solid science about like exact formula
or algorithm that says when exactly is a
variable name you know what how many
characters it should be that's too much
too hopeful right now like right now all
the programming you know this is part of
the problem in programming you know
debates or among different languages
like oh which one is better or your
language is better or mines whether you
know we have tons of these debates you
know arguments sometimes city and you
know once in a while every year we
PhD thesis you know they try to study
for example there are several PhD study
you know research about the naming of
variables like whether snake case is
better or camel case is better like
which one is so actually more readable
which one takes more training you know
which one actually you know you know
there are several study but it turns out
it's not conclusive you know like they
don't have a good answer to that
greetings Tenniel greetings so so anyway
we digressed anyway let's back to this I
don't think I'm doing a good job of this
to me this goal encoding we just keep
digressing but anyway so so get matched
what does get matched to get match takes
two arguments so the first one is a
directory root directory of a website
path and the second argument is the path
to URL that is confusing what what is
the path to URL
[Music]
oh okay I see okay so the path to URL is
kind is a hash table in goal and you
don't have a hash table well in Cola and
hash table is actually called map data
structure they have a data structure
called map okay
so the keys are string and the value is
also a string that's how you declare it
in : it's a hash table or in Python it's
called a dictionary so the path to URL
is a dictionary so keys are the route
the path of a website of a domain the
value is its domain name basically the
URL so we need these obviously so you
need you know the keys are the directory
path the value is the actual domain name
so you need this so this hash table this
dictionary is called the path to URL Oh
okay so so this skit matched function
takes two arguments a root directory and
our dictionary so let's see what does it
do so get matched return a pair from
okay so this is so bad documentation
like how much return the pair from mm
returns up here from mmm from okay I see
what it is so so basically given a root
path of a website you want to get the
don't domain name so how we do that is
via this get matched function you know
okay so I get what and so I see what
it's doing so you know so get matched
actually
take a dictionary or you know take this
structure to get the result
so basically given a file path that's a
root path of a website you want to get
the actual tone domain name cost for
that so that's what this get matched
does so this path to URL this path to
URL is actually a list of two items the
first item is the file path to a website
domain the second item is the actual URL
for that that okay path to URL that's
also badly named you know it's bad you
know it's not really path to URL it's
actually just a pair of you know yeah
yeah it's it's not good name because
path to your you you know when you think
a path to your URL you think of it as a
function it's not a function he's just
you know it just you know it in gold on
its array you know it's just a you know
it's a slice it's it's just a array of
two items anyway so bad so okay so now I
understand path to URL then we get to
the side map okay now it's easy to
understand site map takes a Rooter and
takes a so this is all so badly
structured so site map takes two
argument a root directory you know then
the second argument kind of repeats the
first argument the sake second egg egg
argument actually should just be a
domain name string that correspond to
this root but instead the
second argument is at least with two
elements the surface element is ruder
the second element is a director is a
domain name anyway so so that's that's
what site map is okay so so actually I
think I'm you know I'm going to just
skip the coding today because it's
already one hour unless you guys want to
see it because we already talked for one
hour okay
oh boy we avoid that words okay yes so
clean code I have heard is the more what
the you hear when when people when
someone reading in your code the unclear
your code actually is yeah the more you
hear what the the less clean code
it is yeah that makes sense
so anyway I digress Rollins yeah so easy
it's actually so now actually we
understand what this site map is doing
site map is the heart of the whole thing
basically so the site map boy does is
that it takes a route path stream then
it takes basically the second it needs a
domain name for that stream then it
generates a site map and the output as
you know is a byte stream you know is a
byte slice slice a bytes a sequence of
bytes then we look into the code you can
see so what does what is it doing so it
use append to append the output so first
of all we declare the output output is a
sequence of bytes and the first sequence
you know the first puncher is basically
this
in XML for the sitemap then it just call
append so app and output then you append
the second line and you know then then
you start to walk yeah so it then use
okay wait you define a function that
walks a directory yeah so we need to go
into a directory we need to find Oh HTML
files then transform from a file path
into a URL you know with the help of the
domain name so that is this function
this this P Walker function so then we
actually call the worker function you
know with the fire route right we call
the walk function we call the P Walker
function we wait let's go back
so we call the worker function so what
does the worker function do basically
the worker function just append stuff to
the output variable you know just
basically for each file
edie encounters in your directory for
each file it just append a line to the
output you know then then it yeah it
just does that so it works by side
effect it's not functional programming
in the in this case it's kind of
necessary in that way because go line is
not Haskell you know so you need so for
each file you just need to append a line
to the output XML so after that so we
call the file path walk then call the
pee walker function that that basically
basically traverse the directory then we
checked the arrow go line is known for
error checking which is very annoying
then you know then it's done you just
append the last line for the XML file
URL set then return output you know the
output is a sequence of bytes yeah that
all makes sense so this is the sitemap
function yeah so here we call the
sitemap function it returns the sequence
of bytes we assigned to out by saying we
just saved to the file so that's that's
how it does pretty bad I mean the bet
the code is not bad but it's not optimal
because it's not optimal in this it's
actually very efficient you know I wrote
this code I know it's very extremely
efficient you cannot be part
to be more efficient in other words
there is no inefficiencies but however
it can be refactored
because we see for example the get
matched is a bad name
yeah it's not and the said map is also
[Music]
you know it should be maybe called
January sitemap is a better name instead
of just said man also the argument it
should be a domain name a second
argument you know like when you code to
yourself is everything is obvious you
know especially like now I'm from here
with this code now I can start to do
what we originally need to do which is
you know which is also ok so what we
need to do now is to so after all this
is done ok we saw right here we need to
open this file open this this file I
mean let me write it down so open this
file actually there's a file path local
file path so so we need to open this
file ok this file which corresponds to
this URL so we need to open this file
delete you know find the well let's
delete the list of links generate a new
list of links based on XML file based on
our XML the based on the XML we already
generated because you see we already
generated XML file where each line is
basically the file the domain name the
URL so we so you can see so right now we
can see it doesn't work we cannot just
do it because we need to because when
the sitemap the way sitemap function
works is that is simply Traverse into a
directory for each file it encounters it
just add that line into the output which
is a byte sequence you know just you
know into a five into the base sequence
output it does not it does not actually
generate a structure of all the files
you know like a list of files it does
not generate a list of files rather it
directly dump you know the file path to
the XML file therefore but now we
actually need you know at least a file
so we run into a problem because we
don't have a structure that's list of
files so we need to either modify you
know the sitemap functions so that way
so instead of just directly output you
know append to the output instead of it
instead of that we actually generate the
list of files then we can do you know we
can convert the whole list into a output
XML file so that way we have a list of
files then now we need to generate the
list of files over here on this page we
can use that structure so that's what we
need to do so
so then insert into the page and save it
yeah so that's what we need to do god so
at this point should i we already talked
for our kind of should I start to code
it you know we could yeah we could
actually start to code now no you know
now we you know we spend the time to
look into actually this is this is not
this is actually a real live coding yeah
doesn't make sense you know it really
live codings like that it takes time to
read the code to understand what you
know the code you haven't touched for a
few months now I do I do understand how
it works now I know now we have we have
a clear steps you know of what we need
to do you know aspect and we know how to
do that so we need what we need to do is
we go to the site map function we go
through this function and we need to
first of all the first thing is to
modify the code so that it generate it
generate a list of files instead of you
know directory direct output
yeah we can do that
yeah so um so what went our intent so
I'm thinking let's do ten more minutes
okay ten more minutes doesn't matter we
finish it or not then thou be it for
today because this is getting long and
you know a lot talking and I'm tired too
I don't have my power drinks I wait
do I have you see this is my issue let's
see if I can you see my inner my energy
drinks this is and I need a new one so
let me get pipe and pineapple flavored
pen this is a cheap brand of redbull
essentially that's what it is a cheap
brand of redbull and it's two dollars a
pop I've been drinking these kind of
energy drinks for like five years six
years oh my god it's actually no good
it's addictive I used to drink sugar at
once in that that that destruction that
that's very destructive to your body son
I never drink pop drinks with sugar like
Coke Pepsi I never in my in my life well
you know when I was young maybe once you
know you know I when I was younger like
1300 below I drink that but as adults
since 15 I never drink Pepsi you know
any any sort of the sugar dream never in
but however five years ago I started to
drink this energy drink sugar at once I
I did that for
like four years three years or so and
that's very bad it does bad things to
your body you know in your body in your
thighs you know especially girls you
know women this is of great concern to
females on their thighs they have what's
called sailor loose you know the like
you can you know it doesn't look good
you know that's kind of say the rules
you know when you drink sugar a drink
you start I start to have that you know
sugar drink so sugar is the thing you
don't want so now I don't drink any
sugared energy energy energy drink
anymore okay so yeah maybe I should stop
now I mean your random talking a lot so
actually that's good that's what saw
talk show is so thank you guys for
watching thank you dick ways so that
ways so what what so so you are also
program away are you from and I like
like in USA or in what country that's
always interesting and one question okay
so what question cake they know yeah oh
yeah you you were here before so what's
up Danielle
rust versus see okay I can actually I
can talk about that right now because I
actually I don't have much to talk about
that okay because first of all I don't
know see you at all okay you know people
may get any impression I know see
actually I don't know see I do not know
see I do not know C++ you know yeah III
I despise them I hate them
no dude I don't know C actually started
like I meaning that I've never coded
more than ten lines of C or I've ever
did is maybe hello what you know a
factorial when I was learning it you
know I'm not you know I never actually
spent much time doing it so I never I
don't know C I don't know C prospers and
what so in my programming experience
mostly I do web programming and the
scientific programming that's mostly
server you know web you know web server
phone in front a number or back in and
scientific programming mostly
mathematics geometry visualization in
Mathematica mostly and I was mostly in
1990s and 2000s and I still do today
geometric you know geometry
visualization of math fantastic so and
III have a thing about programming
languages so I learned oh and also I
most my experience I'm a functional
programmer I mentioned before especially
with Mathematica and I never used Opie
technology I never in my code you know
when you woke up in a company maybe
you're it's different because you have
to follow you know programs that already
exist you know Opie style whatever but
in my own code I never used Opie you
know in JavaScript not in JavaScript not
in Python not in :
you know colon has interface as the the
interface mechanism in colon is the Opie
mechanism for : oh oh
Golan doesn't have a you know object
like Java or Python
Golan doesn't have that but rather it
has interface and struct that's how you
have the whole Opie paradin so anyway so
I don't use Opie at all in this in any
language I don't I'd because I don't
like it I don't like I don't think it's
good and most my so I love poor me
languages so most my experience and my
my prospects perspective my I came from
a math bike background so first of all
I'm a mathematician first if if that you
know math is very difficult you know you
could say I'm an amateur mathematician
so math first then eyes you know
programming so my perspective is more
more math oriented and high-level
language oriented so I don't actually
have much experience with system
programming like see and and and no
experience with experience with C or C
first verse I don't know Linux kernel I
don't know about drivers how to read a
driver you know those kind of thing I
don't know I you know I don't have much
experience I don't I don't have any
experience I don't I don't I never coded
assembly language you know but I study
them I especially in past few years I I
tried to study some some some of them so
my opinion about see about rust versus
see I don't have much your opinion you
accept that they are low level languages
I don't like them okay don't you step
and and see yeah I I don't like them
because not okay here's here's what's
important I mean maybe it's fun to say
okay it's what talk show is about being
dramatic okay I don't like them not
because they are low level languages
okay obviously low level languages such
as C rust assembly they are incredibly
they are fundamental they are absolutely
essential they are the
cleaning of all programming languages
you need them okay assembly of course
obviously machine language assembly you
see you need them absolutely
personally I don't I don't like them
because you know I tend to be the math
oriented high level
I prefer high level languages but of
course the low level languages are
critical and important but that's not
the reason I don't like see you or us
the reason I don't like see it's not
rust okay but C C and C plus the first
is because the way they are designed
I mean they are all Anglo level language
okay that's fine but the way they are
designed in many ways in my opinion is
the worst crap it's a from the UNIX
philosophy okay the the the
the the the you know you know the UNIX
philosophy they are the virus they see
and UNIX is what creating in my opinion
this is a dramatic saying okay they are
thus the the father of everything that's
wrong about computing industry so every
time you run into a problem
bad design you know no documentation I
blame it on C&C and UNIX okay and okay
so what about rust so so as far as
language is concerned the newer newer
language are always better then then
then the decade before that so every
decade you decade you have new languages
in general they are just better period
okay so rust and see I I would think
Russ is good you know so I would in my
ideas so you know first of all like I
said before technically technically I
don't know anything about them so take
my opinion is just opinion
I don't like rust either because you
know because it's a fad it's a fashion
you know because especially industrial
programming most programmers is
especially these elite hacker types they
tell you what to do every day they tell
you you know how you should format your
code these
people on Hacker News you know you know
the that they tend to all are big fans
of rust
you know because why because verse
allows you to control memory and so on
and compilers and you know those
complicated stuff they tend to Oh like
love it like for example on social media
on Twitter you will see a lot of people
old rust oh yeah you know we this is so
cool what's this this is that that but
this seems to not like :
because : is just simpler and higher
kind of kind of high level you see more
like ooh you know more you know this fat
on rust you know you see this phenomenon
so that's what I'm saying so that's why
I don't like them so technically I
cannot comment on rust well Russ was you
know technique here
I don't know technique technical details
about them but but I can say for sure
rusty is better than C so if you want to
learn rust versus C not for a job but
just for you know your own I would
choose rust for sure
because you may experience the
conclusions that the later language like
after 10 years is always better
that's just the way things are because
there are tremendous changes in industry
in CPU you know later are always better
like after a period of 10 years not less
and see you know I don't actually yeah
so but then there's the situation where
rust
there's a fad phenomenon with rust and
that I don't like so my comment about
them is just mostly a kind of social
social ones yeah about raw C&C so that
that's it that's it for today so the so
the new essays so path Allah meeya says
well people people praise the see force
P so much do you think speed is
important nowadays
much as qeh tea has become you know see
you know speak yeah you know that you
know why see and all these garbage
garbage is thrive because one thing
sweet like was you know that's
why they they become this virus that
spread you know they will say oh because
we have asked I'm faster than you see
and UNIX is such that they they they are
the worst engineering the worst
architecture than the no brainer no
design no you know sloppy you know and
thinking not extensible that because
there's no design went into it all they
care is one thing that every dummy we
all know about this thing's sweet
you know they they were very fast so so
so so that's why that's one of the
fundamental reason see lives the UNIX
virus and see you know you have this
garbage it just strives you know they
anyway that's kind of a you know rant
that's my okay tenuous a so the most
important thing about UNIX is that
hordes of people ends up running running
away screaming from their proprietary
systems so to flock to frog to UNIX the
most important thing about UNIX is that
hordes of people and ended up running
away screaming from there no that's not
well that then the now say is so many
some so many of those coming coming a
word of closed or proprietary operating
systems Ward Gardens no that's that's
that's better I know what you are saying
you are saying basically you are saying
so like Microsoft and and you know they
know that's that's that's that that's
what people would call apocryphal
history that's what UNIX lovers love to
say they they believe that they think oh
because UNIX is free see that's not true
UNIX was proprietary
very evil the most evil proprietary
system from AT&T okay that's a history
of UNIX it just happens to be you know
Linux came from that you know happens to
be GPL licensed and FreeBSD you know it
was you know Kim is another offshoot of
the UNIX system you know hey this is
sorry rent so for example sabe UNIX
pestilence you know I'm gonna show you
some historical images how UNIX was the
hated commercial that huge you know like
like what you would regard as you know
Apple Microsoft you know a lot we were
these people yeah UNIX fans you know so
I'm gonna show you some some artifact
you know this this our code artifact you
see this t-shirt that's FreeBSD okay
this is this is back then toss it was
running FreeBSD okay okay dude look at
this one you got is BSD daemon you know
this mascot called his name is PC I
think was it miss your Chuck this is
some confusion there anyway you did this
this PSD mascot logo okay now he is
poking the AT&T logo Death Star
now this is what used to be AT&T logo
eighty and Auntie go let's see what's
their current logo I think it's a
variation you know you see there's there
it is it yeah this this is a modern one
the old logo is a bit different it's got
most stripes so anyway that's AT&T okay
they used to remember they used in I
this is before my time in 70s or
something they used to be this powerful
monopoly you know
but so-called so-called monopoly they
got broken up by the government into
different companies but anyway AT&T owns
UNIX UNIX is was proprietary by AT&T so
you see this these comics on a t-shirt
you know that's making fun of it you
know the free the berkeley for point in
pop for you know people forgot history
by the way I'm not saying you are wrong
okay so I mean definitely did I mean the
UNIX I mean definitely there is some
some connotation I don't know where it
originates I mean the point is that
definitely there is certain Association
of free software open source with UNIX I
mean I don't know when it began I think
it's starting with FreeBSD okay but but
you know it definitely is not the
history of UNIX in originally you see
remember the name GNU you know the free
software foundation goon project which
is a project to create a free operating
system you know what it stands for it
stands for glue is not Unix
now look at that cute demon you know
this by the way this is Linux conference
back in 2000 I went to this is not
Factory this is not my photo but anyway
so kunu is not Unix
remember that name what it does what
does it stand for no is not Unix
why is that so what do you need you know
why do they these cool new people make
you know create a name that snow is not
Unix that you know part of the reason
it's a snob again is Unix the
proprietary system you know say so we
are not UNIX you go yourself
you know is not Unix that's that's my
perspective that's my interpretation of
it okay you know I've run into many UNIX
fans of course they don't have that
interpretation they would like to they
prefer to think oh it's just a fun you
know it
the fun way to to promote eunuchs and
new you know this so anyways
so that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
that's it long read everything looks
like almost every video ends up me
ranting again is you know if open either
open source or UNIX philosophy oh you
know free software foundation anyway
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching fight