foreign
talk show so today's topic is random if
you don't know already sound talk show
is mostly talking about programming live
coding programming languages design and
sometimes random okay so today is random
so if you have questions comments posted
here now okay and uh pay me okay PayPal
or patreon or you can use super chat so
if you are here say hi okay uh you know
if you are watching offline then you
know play in speed 1.5 or some something
so because I'm going to be chatty and
slow okay so I'm using emacs let me show
you today's uh you know the keyboard I'm
using so okay so this is Club 80. I had
I have like 50 minutes review about a
month or two ago on YouTube okay on
YouTube and and I'm also also on Odyssey
hello so uh grab 80 keyboard fantastic
and I started to program it let me show
you I'm gonna show you okay uh glove 80
fantastic glove 80. so search for Sally
glove 80 review you'll find it there's
also a one hour video review and on the
this keyboard This is Ultimate hacking
keyboard it's also fantastic and I'm
using it as a keyboard Macro for example
I press this key is switch to last
window okay fantastic and for example I
go to the browser and I press these two
keys
uh okay you cannot see my browser but
you have a switch you know it's all
keyboard Marcos
so that's about my keyboard and Logitech
G
5 112 I believe that's my mouse the spin
wheel is fantastic you can just spin it
it'll spin for 20 seconds or 30 seconds
so that's my setup so let's switch to
the topic so you can see okay so
comments and questions okay so let me
talk about uh some uh let's start with
keyboards random okay you direct what I
talk you know ask me questions so grab
80 is this keyboard
um wait uh cancel cancel I want magnify
the screen so you can see I have full
reviews and there's a video review there
and so I've been using it for over a
month now it's fantastic I got my new
key switch and I started to program it
so for example this key
it says shift there but for me it's tab
it's actually tab okay so you can
program the keyboard it's programmable
so let me go to the uh let me tell you
so watch my video okay so you got full
review of it uh but let me tell you
about the programmability okay so new
experience uh you can connect to up to
four four or five Bluetooth keyboards
battery uh you know so anyway so let me
just jump to something new so I
programmed the keyboard keyboard
firmware so programming the keyboard
that means you can remap any keys to any
other Keys you want you can have several
layers it's the keyboard firmware is zmk
open source software okay and it's the
most powerful it's you know similar to
qmk
I believe it's a fork originally but
anyway zmk is the one that allows you to
have Bluetooth and that's also what
kinesis 360.
for
you know Kinesis 3360 is a new keyboard
let me show you okay so you can see you
have gravity you know those I have thumb
up those are fantastic I recommend these
okay which one to choose depends on you
because they differ in price they differ
in weight in portability in two piece or
one piece you know it
there's no one single best keyboard
depends on your preferences you know
whether you you know and sum up
Bluetooth some are not you know for
example I prefer wired for my desktop
and it's of course I also need wire
Bluetooth in fact but you know so anyway
depends on your preferences those uh
thumb up are good ones grab 80 Kinesis
Advantage 2 and kinetics Kinesis 360 360
there are two versions one is Bluetooth
one is wired okay so the Kinesis 360 the
Bluetooth one is also using zmk
which is what glove 80 uses okay so
those are great and the
and Xpose is I highly recommend two uh
very much
I have three Expos now I gave it I gave
one away uh yeah and there's Apple maker
okay so these are good some you know
those are the keyboard I recommend so
zmk so let's go back to uh club 80. now
so my my view of this keyboard is
fantastic it's one of the best okay you
know I can say which one is exactly the
best like I said it depends on but
anyway it's it's it depends on you you
know your preferences are many subtle
things but I you but this is I would
consider uh one of the top three or two
well depending on whether you like curve
the ball then if you do then it's top
three among these three I would say okay
so anyway so gravity so but this uh
flow okay yeah I must say so to program
the keyboard is the software is not uh
intuitive I heard that you know the zmk
on 26 360 pro is worse okay so anyways
if you want Bluetooth and you if you
want this kind of curved keyboard this
is probably the best you get okay so so
let me talk about the programming yeah
so the programming part you know to
remap the keys you can also create
Marcos key Marcos like for example for
example I press these two so I actually
I didn't program this one but
but for example this is this is a
demonstration of key macro so I press
this key to go back to previous tab and
this key Next Step previous step Next
Step next next previous previous you
know it's a fantastic so you can program
your key to do key marker so let's go
back
um
yeah and you can do remap for example
this key is tab so
so my point here but however to program
it is a bit tedious okay a little bit
tedious comparatively compared to for
example they are today there are many
um you know for example there's bio
software uh used by Expose which is a
user interface to the qmk those are
extremely easy to program okay so let me
show you so for example I also
programmed this key to be Windows key
right now I have uh I have Windows
sticky key on so I just you know I don't
you know so anyway so so for example via
software
is one of the best user interface okay
now you you are looking at it no devices
connected okay I don't have my expose
plugged in right now so that's why you
see empty uh so and also the ultimate
hacking keyboard for example I can also
show it to you uh
uhk agent
okay so for example you can see my
keyboard markers you know these are my
keyboard markers
extremely easy to program so you know
you can click this key you can it you if
you want it to be a key press for
example this key right now it's paste so
you say V and hold down control you just
click there and you know you you do that
or you can you can make that key to to
do some changing of layer or you can
make that key to do keyboard mouse or
you can make that key to do keyboard
macro you know
um type in text or whatever
and or you can make that key to switch
switch layout so layout is like profiles
you know you can have a several profiles
so anyway
so my point here is that this is a
programming keyboard user interface
software this is for the ultimate
hacking keyboard and the name of this
software is uhk Agent it's also open
source on GitHub you can search for it
so this is a great
user interface design
because I when I used it the first time
I don't have to read any documentation
or manual at all you know you just open
it and you immediately you know what to
do okay that's one example the other
example I showed is the wire but I don't
have it I don't have the xpos connected
so I cannot show you
but but then the club 80
so com comparatively speaking the
programmability is a bit tedious
uh and you have to basically so let me
show you a in a minute in a minute ask
questions okay today is uh your
questions I answered uh but first up I
want to talk about keyboard a little bit
oh and I also created
I'm gonna show you in a bit okay so
anyway to create a layout you go to this
website uh enable JavaScript so turn on
JavaScript
so you can now download my layout folks
offline Keys you can see this key on the
right now is it's tab
I changed about three keys so
you know so
Okay so
that's glove 80 programmability so you
go to the website you click the buttons
you for example I click this one uh then
you can
um wait
oh yeah you have to you you have to turn
JavaScript login then you have to yeah
you have to clone
you have to click clone to edit so clone
it and then for example you want to
change this key then you click and you
know you can edit
you know let's say make the number five
do
e type letter e for example so you go to
that website you can program it then you
have to click and download the software
build firmware so it'll take 10 10
seconds you need to register account or
if you don't want to register account
you have to build a the zmk software you
know you can you have to compile it
because it's open source so but
otherwise you register account then you
change your keys you click builds
firmware then you can save it you know
it automatically save then you press
some keys under your glove 80
let's go back here so here is basically
what you have to do you press some keys
then
then load the firmware to the keyboard
okay so it's a bit tedious but I heard
you know if you want Bluetooth
open source software
as powerful as qmk zmk there's no other
okay this is uh about the best you get
okay what uh what questions uh his
matters start with his master stock
worth the effort of course
ask something question important okay
don't talk don't need
this is not Fortune so the question is
Master stock worth the effort that
depends on you if you are eat it you're
gonna lose money
but you can buy Blue Chip stocks so put
it there put it there for 10 years then
you'll be good okay that also depends on
lots of things okay
but I don't suppose that's your question
because
so hello JR says hello because I have a
quick question about career advice what
would recommend a Java software
programmer should do if they are lacking
some motivation due to stress about
finding a good place to earn some money
uh
what would recommend a Java software
programmer would do
Okay so
yes I suppose the question is you are a
Java programmer but you lack motivation
due to stress or and about finding a
good place to when someone you that's
that's
that question does not make much sense
okay so if you want to program and if if
you want to make money Java Java is one
of the best language Java
see C plus plus
C sharp python JavaScript for example
and even in Ruby you know these are the
top five most popular languages so if
you want to find a job in any one of
these language there are tons of it okay
so that's a job okay so but your
question is you are a Java programmer
but you lack motivate motivation well
get some motivation you know you know
maybe maybe programming is not your
interest then
maybe you should look somewhere else I
mean programming you can make a lot of
money is is actually the best almost the
best
profession
you can do that gets you the most money
okay in terms of ease and and how much
money you make and how much effort you
have to spend programming is the best
job period okay programming you can you
if you are smart you can be like a
Zuckerberg the scumbag become a
billionaire in five years in three years
okay or you can you know
if you are a mediocre you know if you
are not too much into well you get by
you get a lot of money working in you
know if you can get Google into Google
you make a lot of money if you cannot
get into Google you still make a lot of
money lots of jobs
in USA for example I'm talking about so
in other countries that's that's depends
on the country you know I don't know but
but in USA you can make a lot of money
by be a programmer you don't have to
be a hacker or really like get into
something something you know you just be
your average programmer you'll be good
okay so if so your question is you you
want to you are programming Java but you
don't have motivation well
either change your job or
circuit you know just do your job that's
your job you that's the job you pick
Java programming you make money okay if
you get if you are
if you cannot find motivation then quit
it's it's a matter of choice okay that's
what I say
oh my God so how many keyboards you use
simultaneously you know typically just
two you know on my desktop
so anyway so back to group 80 so keep
questions coming okay and pay me you get
uh you get my better
answers dedicated to your question so
so gravity okay it's a fantastic okay uh
uh but the programming is a bit tedious
but you know
okay so that's about group of 80. so let
me I want to uh so let me talk about
random about other things okay so what's
the other question
uh how many keyboards do you use
simultaneous okay emac settings art mob
says emac settings and configuration are
often complicated
is a half GUI arrangement for making the
setting easy to get lost just saying
yeah of course emacs is emacs is editor
such that you have to spend time at
least like three months dedicated study
to master it but once you master it
basically it's more flexible and
powerful than than basically all editors
out there okay the price you have to pay
is you have to be you have to spend a
lot of time and you have to be technical
okay but it's gonna be good for 10 years
for 20 years for your life if you are a
programmer okay that's what I do so
emacs we are talking about emacs for
example I'm using emacs stuff like keys
xhtml mod you know I can press one key
to select for example matching tags you
know expand it expand it you know expand
to the above you know and also you know
so and on the pink window is all the
commands and keystrokes I call so you
can see I can move by blocks of text up
or down this is supreme better than page
up or page down so so you can see that
command is star end of line or block
foreign
so anyway emacs we are talking about so
that's emacs so
yeah okay so I want to yeah so let's go
back to talk about keyboard a little bit
so
some interesting things okay uh and here
is yeah here is
girl maybe layout
design folks sound like Keys okay so you
can find it just search for stuff like
Keys okay
okay so and then I want to show you some
keyboard news Okay Mac
M1A a Macbook Mia I bought it
half a year ago it's fantastic okay so I
recommend it and the Apple M1 chip is
the best thing you know Intel Intel is
the worst
one of the bad company and Intel chips
you know the it's uh it's a baggage of
30 40 years baggage Intel chips worst so
Apple M1 chip is fantastic okay so I
recommended Apple Escape key so there's
new some new articles about key as you
know I have a keyboard blog I study
there are 1 000 articles
in this keyboard blog right now and uh
you know it's I've been writing it for
the past 15 years
and uh you know so there is a section
all about Keys you know all the keys you
want to know the space key for example
why is the space bar a bar why is it not
just a key so here is a reason in
history
you know the reason it's a buy is
because
uh the reason it's about is because
typewriters
thank you so
you know so I have lots of keyboard
articles so the then there's a big big
fat enter key you know there are several
standards uh different countries have
their different uh standards big fat
Enter key and the Unicode symbols to
represent the
Enter key or sometimes it's labeled
return for example on the Mac the enter
key on the main keyboard is labeled
return always for the past 40 years but
on Windows they are always labeled enter
and typically with one of these
Unicode symbols so anyway I'm talking
about you know my blog about or every
aspect about keyboard and so you got
label then for example you can in this
page you can see all apples keyboards in
history
you know apple apple keyboards you know
I was Apple user since 1990 1991 you
know so I've been using apple on and off
you know
for 20 years more than 20 years so I I
used
lots of these for example starting my
first one is this keyboard okay Apple
standard keyboard 1987. uh this is
actually not the keyboard I have but I
use it you know at work anyway
so
then the first Apple laptop you know
this is this is 1989 you know back then
when I was a student you know I was I
wasn't even in college yet so I was
coveting or you know this this keyboard
I mean this uh this computer you know
this is like the best
out there so anyway there are lots of
keyboards so back to my point so about
the return key then I did a survey on
what label and what symbol what icon
what life
keyboard use to represent the enter key
so I actually looked at tensor keyboard
and here's a here's a result basically
this if you are talking about symbols
they use this for symbols okay so it's a
survey and I show you examples of each
usage on the keyboard
and here is Apple keyboard for Russian
you know so you can see so anyway so so
this is about different keyboards right
so yeah different details about keyboard
and stuff
and back to you know so the history of
each key
shift key control key control key
position on the keyboard you know many
of the nodes will say that oh the old
keyboard have control besides the a
that's Force okay that's fake news
especially emacs idiots emacs phonetics
you know they like to claim oh Microsoft
it up you know the the key to the
left of the your pinky should be the
control because all the old keyboard are
like that
that's fake news that's you know they
wanna believe the these emacs phonetics
they wanna believe they create Fables
it's Force okay so here is the article
you can see each of the old Asian
terminals they don't have
control it's not always so it's actually
half and half okay the Ctrl key
you know it's not beside a okay so you
can just check out you know the history
of keys
so then there's Escape key for example
the history of Escape key what does it
do where did where does it come from and
what how is it used today on Windows or
Mac on
you know on Linux Linux basically follow
copy everything Windows okay so whatever
the key do on Windows Linux copy it like
stealing okay that's the open source
phoneticism
okay so so what I'm saying is that so
there's also compose key old graph and
that key what's the difference and so on
and which one should you use they
basically they do the same thing okay so
you have old graph key
you know he is the example odd graph key
answer Microsystems keyboard I I use
this keyboard
into around 2000 around the year 1999
for three years at work so this is a
photo of my keyboard on some Micro
Systems Unix system this is my office in
2001.
pretty big you don't see this anymore
you know since the since about 2000
since about 2010 you don't have this
office anymore I had an office this big
and two you know computers so 2001 so
um and some ecosystems okay that's Unix
okay so about keyboard so uh the point
is that you know I've been working a lot
on keyboard and the top key
uh very interesting you know this this
keyboard from 1960
three about 1970 or 1960s this keyboard
is the mother of the command key the
Windows key okay
because of the meta key this is the
keyboard that began the meta key
okay then eventually it evolved into
Apple's command key then windows in 1992
or 1993 they kind of copied they they
made it into the Windows key okay they
all originated the first very idea is
from this lisp
keyboard The Meta key in fact this is
actually not even a list keyboard this
keyboard is the
the son of this keyboard okay so this is
a cell keyboard at Stanford artificial
intelligence research by John McCarthy
you know the creator of lisp
anyway so speaking of artificial
intelligence we are you know there's a
lot chat API going on today it's
incredible okay that's a
Society changing right now this year
okay so anyway keyboard news so I want
to say something about so you know you
can read my articles
um
keyboard Keys okay and I bought a
electric shaver I'm gonna answer your
question now so electric shaver I bought
this one
because my old one died you know I had
one that's 15 years old so I bought this
one forty dollars fifty dollars
fantastic okay so you can use this to
shave your balls shave your okay
shape shave your penis
this one so I did some research what's
the difference between the ball Shavers
you know dedicated Bowl Shavers Main
scape or something you know there are
quite a few what's the difference
between those and the just the average
trimmer
apparently there's no difference you
know they just put the label both shaver
then they can add forty dollars to the
price tag
so anyway I bought this one it's
fantastic okay uh
I don't have much beard I don't have
beard you know as a Asian Chinese guy I
don't have beard so my I only have some
mustache and uh you know Cinco tea I
don't shave much
once a month basically and I all I do is
just mob it mop using the electric
shaver mopping around my mouth
for
basically one minute and that's it
that's done so this is fantastic
okay electric shaver and then hyper 7
keyboard now this is you know this this
is inspired by this keyboard uh inspired
by the space cadet keyboard you must
have
heard if you are a Emax user or this
programmer space space cadet okay
so and this and uh and uh the so it's
got 183 keys
183 you know
the 40
keyboarders
it's a spite of the 40
nerds I don't like 40 keyboards Okay so
uh and uh the point and here it's what's
new is this keyboard is expensive 400
500 you if you want it and uh but what's
new is that this great guy
awesome 22 Thomas you know he did a
review his review is always good you
know he he got this keyboard and he did
a review of it hyper7 okay
so let's see what's the question your
thoughts on Haskell usefulness for
general purpose difficulty perhaps a
little history or Alternatives as
appreciated okay so Haskell you know I
have a actually I started to learn you
know I I know about you know I'm a big
fan of functional programming since
1990s because Wolfram language wufam
language then is my first language I
program wolfam language for
um okay so let me let me let me talk
about Haskell okay so I programmed the
Wolfram language for for night most of
1990s before before I know what's what
is what is uh networking I don't know
anything about computer okay I'm I'm
mostly a mathematician so in the 1990s
beginning in 1992 I was I was a student
of of mathematics okay because I want to
be I'm ambitious I want to be the
greatest mathematician among other
things I wanted to be also the the
billion millionaire and The Pianist and
also the greatest struggler but things
didn't turn out that way okay
so
so Mathematica so you can see so let's
you know I have tons of articles on
Mathematica
so let me show you you know the the
things that I want to talk about so you
can look at my woofam Language tutorial
um then you have wufem language and this
okay so
for example I wrote an article about my
impression of lisp from coming from
Wolfram language from Mathematica it was
known as wolfam language I mean it was
known as Mathematica Mathematica is a
product but the language is called
Wolfram language starting around 2015 or
so
so anyway so
um
yeah so this this topic I talked a lot
in fact so Wolfram language and lisp
okay so anyway in the 1990s I'm a
Wolfram language
expert okay so you can say that
this article I posted recently about my
impression but anyway let's let's get
back to the Haskell question Okay so
my first language is wufam language I
read the book you know the thick wolf
and Mathematica book three times cover
to cover in different years so I'm a
master of Wolfram language and I went to
work for them uh for for a bit for a
while so in in 1995 okay and then so
language is basically lisp and APL okay
that's the that's the inheritance that's
a Heritage okay woven language is
basically basically a combination of
lisp programming language and APL APL is
basically array-based programming
language you can if you don't know APL
it basically is any function works on
our array in most other languages any
function works on a string you know one
argument of string or number and it
returns a string or a number or you know
most languages but in array-based
programming language which APL is the
same example you don't you don't you in
the argument are usually just a list
array okay so the argument are typically
either at least a way you call it array
or multi-dimensional array
two-dimensional way or three dimensional
four so every value is array so when you
call a function you know F something
that argument is almost always a array
so the function
basically applies to the every element
in the array that's what array
programming means okay so that's what
APL is okay APL language
uh you know I have like one million
articles um so the the question is do I
want to show it because if I show
everything
so APL so let me just show a few okay so
APL language
uh click on that and so
you know called APL symbol so this uh
APL programming language you know the
APL stands for a programming language it
also uses this
uh mathematical characters today's
Unicode okay so this is the the first
original APL keyboard it's IBM
2741 printing terminal that's the first
APL
computer it's not a computer it's just a
terminal anyway this is what how it
started APL so anyway Wolfram language
is a synthesis of lisp and APL okay so
here's the APR symbols basically
functions and operators and what they
mean okay and here uh Wolfram language
is a synthesis of lisp and APL
so in every way Wolfram language is lisp
okay nested you know basically nested
but using a using square bracket instead
of parentheses so you know I talked
about this watch my video I have like
two or three dedicated video on Wolfram
language and this
okay so and APL you know and as as you
know lisp is a functional programming
language okay and APL is also functional
programming language Okay so
Wolfram language is synthesis of APL and
list this when APR plus mathematics plus
you know Wolfram you know Stefan
wolfram's
um basically what you call
um
computer algebra system that means you
can use the programming language to
solve equations you just you know you
you have a function called serve then
type equation as argument and you'll
spit out the solution you can solve
linear algebra Matrix equations
differential equations partial
differential equations systems of linear
equations or systems of arbitrary
equations or logical equations you know
lots of equation you are involving and
or not you know true and false lots of
equations you know so let's go or you
know solve equations so
that's called computer algebra system so
that's what Wolfram language is list
programming language APR programming
language and computer algebra system the
in short you know that's basically what
Wolfram language does and it's a term
you write as far as the characteristics
of the language how does it do
computation it's called term rewriting
system okay you don't see that anywhere
uh there's no example of such in the
common programming languages not go land
not Haskell not earth land not or camo
not camo not meta language not not
anything terms writing system is
basically unique there are there are
other examples but but for example it's
called q and pure you can look up
Wikipedia that's term variant system but
basically it's
esoteric more esoteric than Haskell you
don't hear it so term writing system
basically wolf and language okay
but my point okay so my point is that my
my first seven years is Wolfram language
is and it's all function of programming
and because of the similarity to lisp
and because lisp is knowing AI which is
artificial intelligence research
throughout 1980s it's all written in
lisp so I have a strong interest in in
the beginning in my beginning career
with functional programming so that's
how I got into emacs I got to in the
eventually emac base and you know
but the the main thing about them is
functional programming you know because
I'm I'm kind of a stranger I don't I
didn't go to college more kind of so I
don't have the traditional
programmers background you know usually
you go to college or you started young I
didn't okay so anyway I began because
I'm a mathematician I want to be a
greatest mathematician and I'm also
interested in computers so I want the
best tool so I started to
you know so this wolf and language best
tool for mathematics
I don't know what is functional
programming I don't know what is the
different types of you know I don't know
what is
you know I so I bought Mathematica and I
started to read the manual word by word
covered by two cover
you know so
I became a master a master of it but
then it's very different from the
industry or programming language like
Unix C web like what the what the
are those you know that's my
beginning impression so I started to you
know
so anyway back to the point so function
of programming is what I love but you
don't see that in this is this remember
this is in 90s okay functional
programming did not became kind of
mainstream like most people have no idea
like the C C plus plus Java they don't
know they don't know what this what it
is only until about 2010
functional programming started to become
popular because JavaScript forced most
of all JavaScript okay JavaScript and
then Haskell a little bit Haskell okay
function with who I mean because
JavaScript because JavaScript is based
on skin disk scheme this is one of the
best
functional programming language
you know so function performing is what
I'm into but when you look at industrial
programmers in this you know they don't
know nothing about it especially back
then
so I started of course so I you know
back then so I I know about Haskell
or camo meta language camel which or
camo came from in F-sharp then you know
there's Miranda Miranda is a commercial
function of programming language and oil
and so I decided to look into them I
started to try to learn Haskell but I
failed you know so you can find my
Haskell tutorial
back in the day I tried to learn it you
know 2005. Casas escort tutorial like
one Haskell a day you know that's you
know the the goal was to learn you know
one hour just read about whatever about
high school one hour a day and be
persistent that didn't go anywhere I
ended up you know didn't learn much so I
you know so that failed and remember
this is back in 2005. it's very
different from today today if you want
to learn how there's lots of resources
1000 YouTube and uh and practical too
but back then when you want to learn
Haskell is academic jargons the first
problem they want to do is solve
derivatives derivative of mathematics
like most programmers you don't know
what is relatively even but it's
different today so back then I tried to
learn it it didn't go anywhere so
and my point here is that I know about
Haskell you know back then you know
since 1990s there's lots of FAQs
before Wikipedia there's FAQs so anyways
so so
I I was a fan of the pure you know the
of the you know I was I was most I was
kind of uh I'm always into well-designed
languages so back then I was very much a
fan of wannabe you know a fan wannabe of
Haskell because of the all the
mathematical properties of Haskell
because no effect you know no effect
and lazy evaluation which from academic
point of view that means the ability to
have infinite list
number of items infinite list okay lazy
evaluation and lots of other properties
you know no mutation you know
but actually I never learned much of it
but I create I was a fan wannabe so I
created this for example logo Haskell
logo I created this logo for example you
can grab and use and all this symbology
I love symbols as you know Unicode
symbols and what each of these symbols
mean okay so
uh and there's a collection of other
Haskell logos you know for example this
one is dead for 10 years yeah high
school project you know back then it's
academic you don't it's not like today
so and then you have the early Haskell
compiler logo herx98 then also the
original Haskell logo then this one a
new one is also dead today is of course
this one
2009 so 2009 is actually the year
Haskell kind of revived so all of a
certain because of the CPU you know CPU
don't get faster anymore so you started
to have
course you know dual core multi-core and
uh
functional programming kind of uh it
kind of helps it kind of promotes
functional programming because you don't
have
you don't have shared states that makes
parallel Computing parallelism much
simpler so anyway so 19 2009 is about
the time Haskell got the Revival Haskell
is pretty old Haskell is from 1990 so
um 19
1989 or early 1990s okay from it's a
it's created by a committee of active
academicians in in Academia
okay so it's pretty old but 2009 is the
time it got a Revival and it began to be
used by the industry industry coders
it's used in Facebook you know and uh
and other companies you know other full
commercial Enterprise companies so but
so but myself I actually just never
learned that you know after 2005 you
know started
for a few months didn't go anywhere I
just didn't learn it then I also started
to learn old camo
uh and or camo is actually got me far
much further than Haskell okay so a
bunch of um
so let me go to let me search for the
camo okay so let me show you
uh so yeah so uh here is a logo design
for programming let's search okay or
camo
so I also have a kind of a semi tutorial
on a camo and several articles for
example history of camel and Haskell
syntax uh camera syntax sucks or camo
tutorial there it is okay Mobile by
example so here are several articles
these are camel books in F sharp books I
collected back in 2010
uh by now those people are all bad by
now because they are outdated
so F sharp is a derivative of of ocamo
it's basically just a camel with uh some
syntax changes okay and then the most
famous or camo promoter is this guy very
smart guy yaron Minsky okay
he is working at Jane Street trading
trading stocks okay
uh am I still going am I guys say
something okay am I making sense
14 people watching fantastic well I have
14 people watching
uh relatively
sizable today okay so ocamo greatest
promoter is this guy Jane Street okay
and then the this article oh camo
official tutorials suck it truly sucks
donkey donkey ass you know
here you have a camera's official
tutorial okay and then here's a you know
passage or camo doesn't have a basic
unsigned integer type but you can get
the same effect using native int as far
as I can tell a camera doesn't have
single Precision floating Point numbers
at all
you have this passage in official POG
official or camera tutorial like what
the I'm reading official
programming you know official or camo
tutorial and it's telling me he doesn't
know what he's talking about it's a
situation that's you know I I don't know
if they change but that's a state you
know or camo
but however you know and and you know
it's pretty idiotic you know the you
know
documentation you know documentation in
programming industry it's pretty lousy
it's bad over
you know python is the worst Python and
Unix man page that's the worst
possible but the the interesting thing
is that that these python people and
Unix phonetics when they they don't
agree they think it's the best thing
Unix man page incomprehensible and they
they they are thrilled by it that's the
situation they don't know the industrial
programmers they don't know what they're
talking about they don't know what is
technical writing they don't they they
can't their brain just wired they are
incapable and they don't know they can
recognize a real good good technical
writing okay that's another topic I have
tense you know tens of articles on
technical writing and documentation
anyway so another article about okamo in
Haskell this is where Haskell and okamos
their syntax came from their syntax is
very similar but but it sucks okay it's
an EDI it's the most oh camera and
Haskell syntax both or camo is worse
okay but they are similar they are in
the same category their syntax came from
this paper by this PJ London supposedly
a hot shot
back then in the 1960s okay this is
written in 1965.
the next 700 programming languages by PJ
Laden he's a hot shot back then I don't
know what he did actually so I tried to
read it it's incomprehensible it's a
idiotic writing okay he he is you know
this guy don't know how to write okay
but you know it's like jumbo you know
very confusing but for some reason I
don't know the history exactly this guy
is a big shot but I re I read Wikipedia
I don't know what he has done anyway he
at least you know maybe he's what you
you might say you know Hot Shot you know
like today you have several celebrities
you know they're talking about things
and every day is on Hacker News you know
that that's kind of like that after 10
years it's nobody remembers okay you
know the today's hot shot whatever you
are the Hot Shot guys you are following
on Twitter or Hacker News you know
idiots
so I think these these guys probably one
of such but anyway back then he's
very popular and influential so because
of this paper
that's how Haskell and okamo syntax came
to be okay I think it's idiotic actually
I should finish reading this paper
because I tried to read it it's it's
like
pretty idiotic okay
so anyway this article is about the
syntax of Haskell and okamo okay so then
and then
um then a camera syntax sucks this this
is this is
I try to explain why it sucks okay
uh okay so and here is my tutorial so
the point I want to make here is that I
spend about let's say two months
studying or camo and I also spend two or
three months in fact 10 years
um want to believe Haskell but in a
short time I learned much more of camo
okay oh camo is so here's the point
here's the answer
uh Luis to your question I don't like
Haskell okay you know I don't like
Haskell despite despite I have like 10
years really truly I truly want to
believe it because my kind of my Purity
and academic preferences I prefer
mathematical properties for 10 years for
for you know 10 for about 10 years I
truly want to believe Haskell and uh
it's just no good okay oh camo on the
other hand is the quiet
programming language okay quiet nobody
you know talk about it much but okamo
has lots of well-known programs written
in it for example almost all the math
proof systems COG
h-o-l
are all written or camo and the Unison
the file sync syncing Tool uh also
written in a camel and E donkey did
someone just mentioned e donkey the most
popular
um
point to point file file sharing system
is also written or camel so lots of
things are turning or camel quietly okay
nobody you know but since 2009 every
idiot is talking about Haskell every
idiot despise despise them
that's my opinion this is my personal
opinion so
today
I have a lot of things to do you know I
want to study neural networks much more
differential geometry much more and type
Theory proof systems
the the mathematical not the programming
you know I despise everything Haskell
people say about proofs about type
Theory okay take that from me
anything you hear about type types
proofs about proof theory about type
systems if they are from if they are a
programmer from the Haskell you know
they are programmer background from
Ascot it's pure okay that's how
much I despise the Haskell you know I
wanted to you know it's not good okay so
if you are a programmer if you are if
you are a programmer you like functional
programming and you prefer some kind of
more pure I would highly I much more
recommend or camel than Haskell okay I
just want to express my
you know my I don't like Haskell okay I
don't like Haskell you know then I keep
asking questions about people who have
experience in both I just I don't like
Haskell and the lazy evaluation you know
since
even you know I've been looking at
Haskell for you know since the 1990s
like dribbling about oh this is great
this is you know mathematical but but
now I'm old after 30 years of knowing
about programming languages in detail in
various you know studies
Haskell lazy evaluation lazy evaluation
is no good okay you don't want a
programming language with lazy
evaluation okay that's my opinion laser
evaluation is no good in fact XML you
know the Doom object document object
model they have lazy evaluation which
which is complex hard to understand this
is no it's not good okay so anyway
so I must also add I don't know actually
o camo or Haskell that much okay I don't
know them that much I don't haven't
actually read some sizable program uh so
you know just take it you know it's just
my opinion you can disregard I just
don't like
Haskell okay now if you they are
language you know so I have lots of
things to do differential geometry
neural networks machine learning
different approaches besides you know
neural network there's also a symbolic
logical approach which are more more
interested proof Theory
so I want to study a homotopy type
Theory from the mathematician point of
view not from any programmers
you know oh this is type theory for
programmers those are okay anything
about type theory if it came from
programmer I regarded as pure I
don't want even to to to just see what
it's saying you know that's how I regard
it okay I hope you
um agree with I mean I you know that's
my opinion I think it's a good opinion
you know I don't want so anyway so yeah
so but there are several programming
languages I may want to learn so okamo
is one I you know I've I've been
thinking Haskell but okamo okay not
heska oh camo has several variations
today there is a camo in JavaScript
Syntax for example called
um
they keep changing names but um you know
you can search it or camo in JavaScript
you'll find it okay
so there are several syntax variations
and
then okay besides okamo and Haskell for
consideration I also for example Julia
is a language I really think is great
Julia okay Julia is a mathematical
language uh functional very functional
Julia okay Julia or camo I would be
uh if I'm going to learn a new language
Julia and okamo I would be much more
interested and also erlan or Olan
derivatives you know there are a few
erlang so because earlan has this
um uh different property a kind of
unusual than all the then our camera in
Ascot because Earl and focus on this
this this this parallel virtual machine
uh actor based model so
it's not just functional programming but
it has this kind of uh parallel
programming system to go with it so
that's erlen so that that I'm interested
in Olan is another language that's quiet
okay you don't hear phonetics talking of
Fanboy is talking about it all day and
night like at the Haskell and Russ
idiots you know Haskell and rust is like
the Fanboys is talking traveling all day
and night everywhere it's idiots
but okamo in erlan they are used in
industry tried and true okay proven
and it's no it's it's not just toy
industry you know the stocks for example
we talked about the Gen gen Streets
doing stocks and the airline is used in
telephony you know the cell phone
industry
heavily and old camo is used in
mathematical proof systems Cog Cog the
programming language COG
Coq okay Cog and uh and several others
okay they are all most most of them are
written or camo okay so that's my
opinion about it
none trivia okay this you're getting
into the foundation of mathematics
serious mathematics okay
so when I saw your comment you know you
started to you you know you haven't
heard of a camera much and you decided
to learn Haskell and I was disappointed
I was disappointed okay that's it I
think that's it for today
um
yeah so I really want I want to
learn I need just I need to so many so
you know so much things to learn
and I don't have much time you know
neural network by itself It Is Just
Gonna Take Years and differential
geometry and type proof systems proof
Theory and type Theory which is part of
proof Theory so those subjects I really
want to get into so as for programming
languages
you know I I got other things
you know I so much want to learn
programming language it's fun I and I
can start right away but that's not
if you really think about
for me for example what's more important
you know learning another functional
programming language is not
really important that that would be a
trap that I will fall into probably you
know maybe maybe after a few months I
started to do a camp or camera or Julia
that would be a trap for me that would
be a waste of time you know the more
important is get into the proof proof
Theory neural networks and stuff
uh okay that's that's it about it today
anything else
um so how long have I been talking
three okay one hour so just one hour
um
so yeah so that's it um what else let's
see
okay that's it I think we we shut down
in a minute
thank you Luis
okay thank you so thank you guys for
watching
I'm gonna just do emacs and paste the
links here and so I can like copy uh
wait
what
and do and do okay back copy here
paste back here close copy paste so all
keyboard markers you see I'm using
history about camera syntax
and Haskell syntax or camera syntax
sucks yes it does okay more tutorial my
lousy tutorial it's probably not good
today so I wrote you know a few
tutorials
13 years ago or camo I didn't go
far
okay close that hasca logo that's
interesting copy it make a link show in
browser
so that's good close Haskell logo close
IBM so this is the first
terminal for APR programming language
okay
APL symbols let's paste it okay APR
symbols and APR symbols meaning and code
examples
this in Mathematica okay my favorite
language okay
Mathematica movement research Club 80
okay gravity keyboard
look
[Music]
um
yeah so much to learn and yeah you know
the AI the chat gbt is incredible but
there's a lot to talk about that you
know because some some people will say
you know because it's one of the fad
kind of you know everyone is talking
about chat GPT or AI you know then
you'll say somebody say oh it's gonna
It's Gonna Change the World it's gonna
we're gonna have a AGI artificial
general intelligence meaning basically
it has a mind of its own it becomes it
becomes a man basically
so oh we're gonna have that then there
will be naysayers they'll say oh you
worry too much actually it's nothing
gonna happen you know then there's there
will be people saying oh it's gonna
program us you're gonna have gonna be
jobless
next month
so
I have my opinions too but but I you
know so I think my opinion is superior
than this even even those you know
forgive me is for saying even those are
professionals you know professors in
fact
well because
you know opinions you have to know a lot
of things to have really solid opinions
anyway I'm just talking
uh but that's you know that's indeed a
very interesting topic I think AI is
really gonna have a major impact
comparative to for example in the scale
of for example the invention of
smartphone which essentially changed
Society to some significant way it
changes changes change how we live
smartphone for example when you drive
now in USA for example everyone is using
Maps you know the Google Maps drive and
the way how you do things and also
changed a new generation who don't know
much of anything anymore they
me you know so signif so so the
smartphone had a significant impact on
Humanity okay and the the one thing
before that it's even greater is
internet
you know for example with our internet I
wouldn't be doing live stream and in
fact I'm doing live stream that's also
because the smartphone because it is a
smartphone where everyone not just
programmers not just nerds but
everyone's got it and everyone can do
stream live so smartphone is significant
impact to society
so when we say when I say you know AI is
oh it's gonna be a major change you have
to do some comparatively speaking the
context so what I'm saying is that in my
opinion my just my own opinion AI is
very significant okay you'll hear some
people say oh this is nothing it's like
nothing happened no I think in my
opinion I think it's a significant as
the smartphone and the far more
depending on you know how many years you
want to wait I think it's far more and
whether it's gonna become
a man
you know out of the agis or so-called
AGI also called strong AI meaning that
basically it becomes a self-conscious
nobody knows okay nobody knows will that
happen or not you know some people will
say oh it's gonna come in soon but
actually we don't know we don't know if
if that's possible at all but in any
case I think it is a significant impact
coming
and and right away you can touch it you
can feel it you know in fact it's
already changing Twitter for example
because in a few months everything will
be Bots and you can you cannot tell so
Twitter Elon Musk they started to
uh make you know kind of
make sure that you have to pay because
if you pay this much significant you
know then
you cannot have you know AI bot Farms
you know that would be very expensive
that that would less likely to happen so
you can actually trust any people who
reply to you or any people you come in
contact on social network any website
how do you know it's not about you don't
know actually you would you wouldn't be
able to tell in the coming months that
will that's already like happening okay
you wouldn't be able to tell so there's
a significant change going on because
now all the website is about to change
something like that we don't know
exactly what yet
so Twitter is now you know LMS is
starting to say so you have to pay that
that's one way to prevent that from
happening so anyway so anyway bye guys