good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
today is 2021 uh
10 o'clock 10 30
april 1st uh let's start
so today's topic is going to be
um technical and random
uh i got i gotta put i have a little bit
cross-eyed
so let me put my patch on
so now i can i can see better
so let's start clear recent history
star start command log mod so
here on the left window you can see all
the command i type
so first of all go go to my emacs
settings and i need to set the bigger
font so copy that
new buffer paste it in magnify
uh go to xr emac this mod
and modify this line if among windows
set the font to 14 for all buffers
so evaluated now it's good so now
if i open any new buffer type it's going
to be big fonts
okay so close that so today i'm going to
talk about uh you know randomize your
questions
your questions dictate what i'm going to
talk about
but okay so let me begin by mathematica
okay so i want to talk about mathematica
so uh questions comments posted okay
and donate don't forget this donate
button
you get a delegate dedicated answer
if you put money to my pocket good
morning
fasting so i use an eye patch to
uh die to straw bismuth
double vision yeah so today's topic i'm
going to
actually i'm going to start to show you
some mathematica because that's
my thing i've been coding uh quite a lot
mathematica
in the past few days because i need to
catch up i haven't been coding
mathematica for
15 years so i'm going to
so ask your questions okay but let me
begin for you know
let me continue talking about
mathematica
the wolfram language okay mathematica uh
wolfram land dog so i'm going to give
you a quick
very condensed uh introduction to
programmers
on how do you program wufang language
okay now there are three steps to learn
wolfram language
you know it's got 6000 functions
building
so it's overwhelming so first of all you
go to the
ufam language documentation center and
you know first step is to use wufam
language as
a graphing calculator for example data
visualization
you know you pick whatever category you
are interested
sound visualization ai graphics uh math
you know whatever
so let me quickly demonstrate so you go
to
any one of these and let's pick
something interesting okay string plot
um
okay so actually so if i'm gonna talk
about this this
is gonna going to be long okay so
copied uh so let's go to mathematica
okay
okay this is going to be long talk
because i
i was thinking let me just do it fast
but
there's so much talk to talk about so
um actually
paste that evaluate
yeah you have to copy the other thing
at least stream plot okay so first
of all
uh delete that delete that let's magnify
these
250 okay so first of all you define the
data
then list stream plot
okay and data
so you got that so for so first step is
to play
uh with wufang language as a fancy
graphing calculator
now the second thing you want to do uh
to master wufang language i mean
to get an introduction of wufam language
is
is you read the this book
stefan wufang's book okay wufam language
by stefan
from tutorial uh there are like
40 50 chapters and if you are a
programmer you can finish each chapter
like in few minutes in five minutes also
so that's the second thing you want to
do now the third thing you want to do
to master to really once you after you
get an introduction you know good
uh basic understanding you know how it's
it looks like you want to you want to go
to
um this section call language and
structure
and basically read every each and every
one of these sections that's how you
master mathematica okay
so that's uh that's how to learn
mathematica and let me just
also mention you can get mathematica for
free uh
buy buy a raspberry pi it's bundled with
raspberry pi
free okay so but you can also you can
only run it on raspberry pi
or you can actually download the wolfram
engine the wolfram scripting language
for free yeah entirely you just register
so that's how you get mathematica for
free
okay so that's that's about that that's
getting mathematical for free and that's
uh
how how do you learn uh how do you
master ufam language
i mean yeah that's uh the three ways
okay
follow my steps you know follow this
in order play with it as a graphing
calculator
or then after that read stefan wolfman's
introduction book
then master the wufang language section
okay now i'm going to start to teach you
wufam language okay i'm going to go
through
um the basic of programming construct
about ufam language so first of all
uh python tutorial so
for you python or list programmers let
me just follow my tutorial
and i show you how to do it in wufang
language
so we have python3 in one hour okay so
first of all let me show you
uh let's magnify this
yeah okay so now i go to
ufam language yeah so now i go to
how do you math master mathematica okay
so
actually let's start a new window so
three plus one let's magnify
actually i do need this
so i can see better so that's
so you evaluate three plus one so first
of all how do you do strings
strings is a common thing so string
mathematica is
this is a string
okay and you can also use unicode
so let's see uh let's try a unicode
heart or
a bunch of unicode okay so make them
a string copy back to mathematica
paste it you can see
okay wait what's going oh yeah you you
got uh you cannot have
okay so you cannot have emo
emoji what's going on
okay so you can have stream but but
what's going on with
uh here why is that
why can't i have the oh yeah so i got a
syntax zero probably
so you can also have emojis as part of
the string any unicode
chinese or other languages so that's how
you
uh do string now what about quotient
string
like raw string
now language doesn't have raw string
okay and for example if you want
new line you cannot do
that okay this is
wrong
oh okay it works um yeah yeah
yes it works so you can also have for
example tab you know the typical
uh unix c language string yeah so
string and tab i mean new line
tab just backslash
and what about if you want to uh
have a raw string quote
now 15 years ago i don't think you can
do that but
i'm not sure today so let's you know let
me just skip that
multi-line stream so like normally you
would do
yeah it uh
there is no such feature in language at
least
uh you know 15 years ago but i don't
know about today so let's look
at uh maybe
okay let's look at the documentation
let's see what the wolfram language
possibly it has updated
so stream manipulation let's see
let's click on stream manipulation so
that's a string
string join string length string
expression
now this string expression is new
okay this is new in what year is this
in 2004 so that's the version i don't
know
uh 2004. anyway let's skip that okay so
so this is how you do string so let's
move on because there are lots of things
what about
string manipulation like substring
length
so length is easy you just do length
something okay so
uh string length okay so you actually
you need string length
right
uh abc
okay string length three
uh string length then
arithmetics so arithmetic is
easy three plus three three
times two three divided by
a bunch of numbers
it gives you uh you know it gives
gives you a uh fraction
you know exact numerical result
and if you want numerical result you can
if the
if the input is numerical i just put a
dot
then it gives you the um
the approximate number for that
so similarly you know that's how you do
so for modular
rhythmic uh so modular arithmetics
so you do mod yeah i think so
so for example uh five
in mod two you got one
okay so so that's uh
all you can think of that as remainder
five divided by two you
you want the remainder
and power
power is you know just like that
and language also support okay let's
skip that
true and false so in language true is by
this symbol okay
and force is uh force f-a-a-f-a-l-s-e
uh and you have uh functions like that
for example if 3 less than 2
then print
uh let's say then then x
okay otherwise y so it's symbolic
so that's how you do if expression now
in mathematica in many languages true
and force
you know many different values evaluate
two force for example in python
zero is also fourth force or empty
string is also force
or empty list is also force now in wufan
language there's nothing like that
only true returns true the and only this
symbol force returns force
otherwise if you have something
mathematica cannot tell
whether it's true or false you get you
get
for example x minus x
less than three is that true or false so
if i evaluate it
it returns that expression by itself
it doesn't change nothing uh and this is
actu this is a feature
you know this is not a flow this is a
feature because
in mathematica everything is symbolic so
this is
so if you give you know if xe less than
if you know is that true or false so
this is a symbolic result
now if you now if you set x equals to 2
then you evaluate that
again it will actually give you answer
so you can you can you know be this is a
feature because you can compute you you
know you can do
very long expressions with symbolic
items in it
then you know you so you get a symbolic
result the first
you know this is actually the answer the
answer of
x whether x is less than 3
is exactly that when x is unknown so
you see this that that's what um
this is why it's a feature you don't
know if you
you know do a lot of mathematica you'll
know later on because this is
useful because
because that's a this you know this is
the actual answer the symbol
symbolic answer if x is unknown
okay so that's uh if and else and true
and false what about loop okay
in mathematica mathematically is a
functional language in general you don't
loops
you don't do loop like if like for loop
while loop but however mathematica is
like
actually so-called multi-parading you
can do any of these procedural
construct for example let's do a loop
okay
so do for example i equals to
1 now i i forgot what's the syntax for
do
but i believe that's it so um
i plus plus okay so let's see if that
works i forgot what's the syntax okay
that doesn't work
so um let's look at uh documentation for
do
do expression and okay so this is how
you
do it
so let's say i from 1 to 10 and each one
uh
accumulate you know so
so um yeah
okay so here is what you do i
from one two nine okay
uh i plus plus
okay so this will add you know the sum
summation of i one to nine evaluate it
oh okay so do doesn't return a result
yeah so you have to evaluate i again
what
so this is a procedural um
yeah so you have to return you have to
do it you have this is a procedural
this is how you do procedural
programming in mathematica you have to
say a return
so so i plus plus
semicolon return i
okay what's going on
oh yeah so i forgot mathematica doesn't
you know do the
c like syntax this is the way to
everything is in function form okay
there you go
so why is it only two
expression imax i mean imax
stuck stuck in these uninteresting
things
so fasting has a question personal
question do you feel you wasted time
with your work on emacs that's a
that's the impression i got when
watching one of your previous streams
okay
so let me answer that later okay
so in general you know so so so how do
we
so actually so let's figure out about
the do okay so
you can use return break continue
through inside loop
okay unless an explicit return is used
the value uh returned by 2 is new
so why is this not
yeah let's just do this
so that works
okay so that works
if you say return i
here
that's one uh
because you know any uh that
well this is pretty bad
you know basically nobody you know you
nobody use do
in mathematica that's a procedural
programming you can do it but
but you know i've been coding
mathematica for 10 years you basically
never use it so i
you know forgot so anyway there's also a
while statement
test and body so while so
why are x less than
10 x
print x okay so so actually we can use
print this
is uh uh this is infinite loop
alt dot
to cancel mathematica oh okay so wait
yeah so i got into an infinite loop
infinite loop go
so i have to kill it okay
no that doesn't work have you programmed
the mathematica
uh you have to have programmed it in it
otherwise um you wouldn't
know so okay so let's open
let's open my packages again yeah it's
just too feminine
from desktop
concurrent users 14 okay so new notebook
so we
i feel kind of
screwed up and boring
because i need to i need to get to many
of the interesting parts and functional
programming about mathematica
but i'm trying to cover some of the
procedural programming construct you can
you know mathematica has all that
use but you know you can basically if
you are coming from python or c or java
you know
type you know those languages you can
you can
uh use all these constructs and they all
work fine they
they work perfectly fine but however
once you
started to become familiar with uh
with magic with mathematic with math uh
wufam language you
you basically never use these constructs
okay so there's a section a tutorial on
procedural programming
so you can see
you know the wolfram language stands out
from you know this
this is a lot of marketing things the
wolfram language stands out from
traditional computer languages in
supporting many programming paradigms
procedural programming is the only
paradigm available in languages like c
and java as well as most scripting
languages
the wolfram language supports all
standard procedural programming
constructs
note note the word or yes but often
extends them through integration into
its more generic
general symbolic programming environment
so anyway
so it's telling you basically don't use
it well actually you know
you can use it but that's not the style
if you want uh
uh explore mathematic mathematical
features so you have you know
if which uh which
switch and return
throw a catch
uh prints
those are pretty uh you know common from
c uh
and there's also four loop for loop okay
let me show you a for loop
uh for loops the syntax is i i equals to
one okay
i equals 1 test i
less than 10 okay then increment
let's say 2 then body
let's say print i okay
uh what's going on wow jesus another
another infinite infinite loop because i
forgot to
increment i
uh
so that's a bad thing about
procedural programming you get into
infinite groups okay so
who found language start over
okay so so there it is we are back
and let's get the documentation up
so anyway so you have procedural
programming so what else i want we i
want to cover
actually i should cover procedure you
know i
really should cover it because otherwise
for beginners you don't know
how to use the others because the
functional programming
constructs for doing loops you know
you may not be familiar with so i need
to show you the procedures you know
so when you begin mathematica you might
as well do
all the while loop and do loops so
let's let's do a four okay for loop
uh so first of all look at look up
the syntax for for loop
you know and you know let's just copy it
yeah instead of me typing you know for
example
i start from i equals to zero
uh then test is i less than four
then increment i forgot the increment
then print i
okay so any of these but
by the way any of these can be uh any of
the arguments can be
uh arbitrary big huge
expressions uh so for example i can
do i squared so
uh let's cover so let's just you know
cover the really basic so you know
you know about four loops right so for
loops if you
go to uh so there are two guides
one is all the looping constructs in
mathematica
so if you come from c or python or java
or javascript you will be familiar with
do
while for and
uh you know and throw break continue
return and catch
so that's typically procedural
programming
languages uh loop constructs but you see
this
this article is about looping constructs
so if you want to do functional
programming
you use table okay table is much is
extremely powerful let me tell you for
you python programmers
table is equivalent to pythons
the so-called list comprehension okay
python this
configuration is idiotic
including haskell okay uh haskell and
python you know they think
they have the this comprehension um
construct basically that allows you
to construct nested arrays
raised or nested arrays that's what
least comprehension
is uh it's available in python you know
with a special syntax basically a
a language within a language mini
language for
just for this syntax uh list
comprehension it's also idiotic name
and in you know so i have article on
why this comprehension is bad this
comprehension
is a little language it's an exception
in syntax and semantics like
yeah who enter here or rules don't apply
so that's what basically uh
list comprehension is it's a special
mini language within a language that
allows you to construct
array or nested array that's what it is
okay uh and in haskell it's the same
thing and it's it
it's it's extremely idiotic in common
list
you have the similar thing it's called
loop
but in mathematica so they so uh the
table function
actually is similar okay so let me show
you so
x for for example x 10
uh evaluate you get uh array of 1 to 10
okay so now you can say so instead of 10
let's say
3 to 9 so that gets
you from 3 to 9 okay now you can say
let's say 3 to 90 in increment
of 5. okay so you get the list
in increment of 5. now let's say you
want nested
let me show you know table is one of the
most
general purpose the most powerful
general purpose construct in mathematica
that is also the most frequently used so
let me take some time to
explain the table thing so you can
generate array
now let me show you how to generate a
list nested array okay
so let's say one two five
now instead of x let's say uh let's say
let's let's say function x and y okay
then then you say x from 1 to 5
and y from 1 to let's say 3.
enter so you can see you get a nested
array
of the function you know this function
is symbolic
now if you define a function let's say
let me show you
okay let me show you quickly how to
define a function okay
this is pattern matching okay so
this is the basic the most base common
way to define a function
so let's say f x y takes two arguments
it just add them up okay define it now
if you reevaluate the table thing
you see you got numbers so table let's
try this let's do the table again okay
now let's
not use f let's say list
okay so you get this nested list and
it can be arbitrary dimensions so that's
two dimension
so let's add another dimension
x y and z okay so z
and you can actually you know you
this part the first argument to table
can be any arbitrary expression
so let's say x so first of all let's
just try x
y z okay that's the simplest
uh let's make it two so it doesn't okay
so here is our
function i mean here is a sin
uh wait okay that's when it's purple
that means you have a bad syntax
bracket mismatch so this table function
uh so this type of function returns you
know
let's say x y or we forgot z let's add z
okay so one one one two you know
x uh x goes from one to
five in increment of one y goes from one
to three
in increment of one and z goes to just
one two in increment of one
so you can see one one one one
two then one two one one two two
why do we have just two elements because
z you know just two elements one two the
last part is one two one two
and the third part one three one one
three two
okay so let's say let's let's change z
from inc uh with increment of zero point
two
so you can see one one one
and one one one point two one one one
point four one one one point six
so this is actually three dimensional
matrix and you can add
different increments for any of x y z or
add more dimensions if you want okay
and uh okay let's run that and let's
let me show you um let me show you a
matrix form okay
so this way it will actually display it
in a trade traditional matrix form
so and like i said before
uh it's x and y z can be
any any expression the first argument so
let's say
x plus y plus z
okay so you got you know just numbers
this is a three-dimensional matrix
uh and you know it can be arbitrary
complex number
uh uh expression let's say
let's leave it okay so because i don't
want to get too complex
so table is the most fundamental
and common uh
function to generate a list
or nested list or a tree uh yeah or tree
or matrix
so uh so what what what's the next
okay let's go back to the python
tutorial
uh where is my python tutorial yeah so
true and enforce conditional if
that's in mathematica loop iteration so
we have file
we have wire we have do loop we have for
loop
then we have table which is the most
general way to
to uh iterate kind of so now you come to
list okay
so the basic data structure of
mathematica so this
is just um this is a list
one two three that's a syntax for a list
and um okay so that that's that okay so
this
this this is the most fundamental data
structure in mathematica
you use like 99 of the time
because mathematica is like like
in my previous video i've talked about
mathematica
the nature of mathematica is like um
lisp
okay the nature of mathematica is like
uh lisp
so so that so so list is the most
fundamental uh data structure
like used night used in 90 of the time
in fact throughout 1990s mathematica
doesn't have any other
data structure except these
not even hash tables not even associated
array
the only thing you have the data
structure is this
for you know until maybe 2004
the mathematica added associated list
hash table and all that
so why is that is that a flaw no i
wouldn't i don't think so because
you know that takes some explanation to
do
the reason you only have list is that
this
list is the only okay this
this is the only
data structure that
can be represented in a textual form
you know programming languages we are
talking about syntax right the source
code is all syntax
now the only
essentially the only um
of all data structures list is the most
general
that can be represented centered as a
text a sequence of
things but how do you for example how do
you represent
a hash table well you just have uh all
you have to do is
you just have a nested list where each
element is
again a list of two elements
you know the first element and second
element you consider the first element
to be the key
you consider the second element to be a
key now
another requirement for hash table or
dictionary python dictionary is that
you know the key must be unique right so
so that seems to contradict so you are
saying this
is general but the key is not unique but
the reason for that is that because
when you rip you know that's that's a
semantic issue
remember we we are you know separating
syntax and semantics
whether keys are unique that's a
semantic issue that's not a
syntactic issue anyway so let's skip so
let's so that's how you do list
in mathematica and we have seen them all
these are actually
uh also lists if you show them
in in you know in the normal form you
can see their lists
so turpo again so in many languages you
have turpo or vectors
or array in c is called array so
basically
it's just uh it's just again it's just a
list where you don't
where the you cannot add elements or
or take away elements so again that come
back
to why i say this is a general form so
why why don't you
why do you want to add a data structure
that's
vector you know where you cannot you
actually put a limitation
to the language you know when you have
an array a c array
or in in image called vector or in
python called tuple
basically that's a list where you cannot
change
you know you cannot change the length
so in some sense why do you want to do
that
you are actually adding limitation to
the language
okay so the reason they do that
the reason programming languages do that
which is actually adding a limitation i
mean if you don't want to increase the
lead
increase the length or decrease lengths
just don't
add element to it you know what's you
know you just don't add an element to it
don't take away element to it
so why do you have to have a special
data type like turbo
vector array that that specifically
you know do not allow you to add or take
away elements
the reason is efficiency you see
these languages they are concerned you
know because in order to implement it
because of the memory because the
hardware and blah blah blah
and in float you know that sort of crap
because of implementation limitation
they created this data structure that
does not allow you to add you know uh
increased length or decreasing because
you know
implementation limitation
so so for example let's put
let's uh let's get uh another way
another point of
another way to say it is that imagine if
you have a very smart compiler
like haskell you know has got static
analysis so if you look
you know the compiler will look at your
source code we and
analyze it and it will see oh you never
actually added
an element to a list and you never
decreased
you know take taken any elements away
it will automatically automatically
compile your list
into what you know python calls turpo or
z
course array or emac discourse vector
so if you have a smart compiler you know
that automatically happens
so in other words the reason these
languages have these things because they
are
they are computer engineering
by-products
okay they are not they are not something
needed by the programmer
you know by by the programmer by the
master they are actually
something you know they got they are
trying to the compiler writers trying to
implement this
you know uh thing and it's a big problem
so instead of trying to solve it
they just throw it up into the language
to
to become a problem for the programmer
so every time
when you use python or lisp or c
you have to actually decide beforehand
whether you are going to add elements or
take away elements
to the list you know that's a so that's
a thinking that's a
you know that's a point of view that's
that's why
i say you know this tuple
tuple your vector or array idea is
a by-product of computer engineering
because if you read
if you want a list that doesn't grow or
shrink you simply don't
go or shrink it you there's no you know
you don't need to
have a special data structure so that's
what i'm saying so
mathematica the list is the
is the only necessary and
essentially essentially if you add any
data structure other than list
you are actually creating a by-product
of computer engineering because as a
programmer you don't need it okay
this is a point of view actually you
know i need to uh take a lot of time to
expand this because
for most people they hear at least
there's they'll think
oh my god what kind of is this
uh but okay so yeah so it
um should um
it will take sometimes to go you know
maybe another day to go into detail why
you know this
this perspective this kind of this kind
of
perspective okay so anyway so you see
how this
is done but anyway in mathematica i i'm
not sure i yeah
they have added they have actually added
data
structures that's not just a list
okay so we can go back so you can go uh
let's see
so let me show you how do you actually
do turpo in mathematica okay
so you go to code language structures
and you go to
structure data sets no i don't i think
that's much more complex
so anyway associations okay so this is
how you do
this is basically hash table in
mathematica
they are added in year
so let's look at association they are
added in
year 2014 pretty late
2014 imagine mathematica began in 1989
i think so for the first
15 20 for the for the first 25
years there is no such thing as hash
table
or dictionary or associated associate
list you know in in
this terminology there's no such thing
because
like i said that's what that's what i
have been explaining in the past 10
minutes
you don't it is actually not
in you know in certain
in certain point of view in in certain
essential mathematical point of view
anything other than a list is
redundant it's not just redundant it's
actually it's violates
it it's a you are actually you know
anything other than this
is actually um computer engineering side
effect
that's that's what i'm trying to say
okay so um but you know in 2015
in 2014 after 25 years they added a
association list so that i i suppose
also it's convenient for programmers
because you know mufam language is
growing and
and you know just like how why wufang
language has
two for loop while loop then you know
they
and increment you know plus plus they
added those
so that it's more you know compatible
convenient
so um so that's okay so that's what i'm
saying
uh so let's go back to association so
i believe they also added turpos okay
so let's see
now i need to go to a page documentation
page where they talk about data
structures
let's see structured data set okay
uh so they added quite a few all these
are new okay all these are new
since um
you know they were added in the past 10
or 20 years
data set a general hierarchy called data
set containing nested these
associations okay
i believe they added turpo but
i'm not sure where is it so let's see
so you go to the documentation page
data manipulation and analysis
uh
let's see structured data set no not
that
structured data set is something much
more complex
i'm not sure it even exists
in um
in most languages let's see okay let's
see what uh wait database connectivity
data manipulation and analysis structure
data sets
so what are they data set let's see
okay so actually i'm not sure what's the
purpose of data
set uh apparently it looks to me
just uh mixed
a mixed nested list or
associations you know associated array
i'm not sure why you need a special
uh function to represent that
so dataset is new in
2014 yeah so it's new in 2014.
it's not essential okay so query
query represents a query that can be
applied to a data set object
in which successive operators are
applied successfully okay
that's also new
okay i'm not sure where is turpo okay so
let's see
turpo yeah there it is turples
okay so this yeah so i don't think
wufang language has turple
now this this function tuples actually
uh gives you um
basically combinatorics okay
so turple one two three take two at a
time
uh turpos okay turbos
yeah so it gives you all possible
combinations of two items
from this list so that's not
you know the turbo i don't yeah i don't
so like i said before there's no
such data structure that limits you to
just you know you cannot add elements
like c
array or uh emac list
vector or python turbo okay so
so that's about data structure so let's
see uh
so turple python sequence types we can
we can skip that so dictionary
in wolfen language is just um
let's skip that
okay so how am i doing so actually how
long have i been talking
i've been talking for 15 minutes
i haven't got to the many very
interesting things
yet so
so you have a module you can also have a
module or basically how do you use
libraries in
language
and how do you define a function in
how do you define class and object
wufang language doesn't have class and
object
uh not not in the well you can easily
create them
you know object oriented thing
uh
oh okay sit ali see that is aged
like me you have to say that because
otherwise i thought oh you guys are
young teenagers
20 years something
you know who found language so you have
to look um
yeah so one of the common question is
and that's also a problem from
for wufan research
you know wufang language so wufang
language most people
think of wufan language or you know they
think of it as a application like
mathematica okay
uh where's my so most people when they
when most people see um language they
just think oh
you know it's just like a fancy graphing
calculator
uh you can do lots of these
uh oh this i showed the other day let me
show you something else
okay function um
graph plot so this plots arbitrary graph
function visualization let's see
function visualization this is more
interesting
so most people think of wufam language
as
a you know just like fancy application
you can
you know solve equations do derivatives
integrals uh and just compute and you
know
you don't you know people don't think of
it as
a programming language but that's what
actually
that's what it is okay so like in my
previous video
uh i did like four videos about wufang
language you should watch them
uh in in the past month i mentioned
how mufam language is basically
like a lisp language okay
the reason programmers
don't see you know don't program it
as like a programming language you know
most people don't use it because
there are two reasons for that the first
reason
is that in the 19
in the 1990s you know wufang language is
created mostly for mathematicians and
physicists okay
so they are not programmers in general
they know physics and they know
mathematics
they need because and also in
engineering
you know material science chemistry you
know going
a rocket creating a rocket sending
people to mars
you know building uh designing a car
engine
and things like that you need you know a
lot of mathematics
so engineering physics chemistry you
know hard sciences
these people use language
mathematica as a tool to design
solve problems now these people are not
programmers but they you know they might
do a little programming like how
when you use cad you know autocad or
3d modeling you know those people have
a scripting language built in so that
you can you know
do some scripting but in general they
are not programmers you know programmers
is
like in a different industry you know
programmers
who from stephen ulfan wrote mathematica
in c language
so programmers they create software so
so because of the audience of
mathematica users physicists and
mathematicians and engineers they are
not programmers
so that is why wu from lang you know
mathematica is seen
as a tool you know that's you know these
people use you know
then so now let's go to after year 2000s
you know or after year 2010
you begin to have lots of languages for
example the language
r and the language math lab
you know those again those just like
mathematica they are math oriented
languages
so do programmers know about them not
really
so programmers don't you know they they
might think of
r is uh you know a language to do
science just like mathematica but
most people most industrial programmers
never called it r
or matlab so again so so that's that is
why programmers usually don't
know i mean if you are in college you
might have you know when you study math
or physics
maybe you use mathematica but not for
you know as a programming language
same thing for the language r
and julia i mean r and matlab these are
popular
now now going to uh now let's jump to
2010. beginning around 2010 there's a
lot of artificial
intelligence programming you know began
by google
and facebook and so on machine learning
big data you know
science data visualization so
that's when programmers started so
that's when programmers and
mathematicians or statisticians
started to mix so you have some
you know you started to have a lot of
mathematicians or engineers so
they also need to be provision
programmers and
you know for machine learning because
you have massive amount of data
and you know you need to know
mathematics statistics especially
to do uh neural networks machine
learning stuff
so and and programmers you know started
to
you know because for example you work at
google then suddenly you have lots of
data you need to
begin to learn statistics to do you know
you are not just coding
you you need to know mathematic
mathematics that's why there's kind of a
merge
so when this happened most people for
example python
python become very popular in data
sciences you know massive data
and stuff and also a lot of programmers
started to learn r
or matlab or julia julia's new language
math oriented language
obs studio reconnections successful
okay i think maybe that's it for today
that kind of rambled a lot 15 people
still watching oh i need to
answer some questions uh
yeah so so after year 2010
people begin you know there's a merge of
programmers and
uh mathematicians or engineers
and python becomes very popular part of
uh part of the reason is because of that
what about mathematica mathematica is
still
you know because since year 2000 there
is
a movement of open source now because
mathematica is not open source
so so that kind of cut off
you know uh the opportunity a lot of
people
for knowing wufam language because you
know for many of these open source
phonetics
when they see something that's not open
source they will not use it
so that especially programmers so again
especially programmers not not
physicists
not mathematicians not engineers because
for those people
there's no opens there's very little
open source tools
you know uh for example matlab is not
free
i is free okay anyway so
among programmers in particular they
have you know
you have a lot of people who became
open source fanatics so they don't
you know they blind themselves they
don't see anything that's not open
source they don't understand
they don't see it they don't real they
close the door on themselves
so what they see they might know about r
they might know about uh python but
they wouldn't know anything about matlab
or mathematica for example
i mean the general trend
so that so that is the reason that is
the reason programmers
still don't know uh mathematica is a
kind of very powerful programming
language that's my
explanation
okay when i did my uh undergrad in
computer science not too long ago
remember being confused by the fact that
a senior of mine
used mathematica for his thiefs okay
yeah
so let me answer some of the bot has a
question but are you still here
so last question is um
so two questions okay first question but
what do you think about
uh richard stollman question uh richard
storman situation okay
uh for that it's really easy okay
you just go to
uh
just go to my website search for ogo
emacs richard showman
so you can see i have quite a lot of
articles about richard stowman
uh now if you scroll down you you know
once you find any richest roman article
you just scroll down
there is a index of essentially
lots of articles about richard stoneman
you know he has
created lots of dramas
so in 2009 richard stollman
resigned from free software foundation
okay 2010
september so i have kind of collected
all sort of uh things you know that i
tells you the story
why he got why is he resigned he
you know he got pushed off basically not
not willingly he got essentially forced
to resign so i have an article on that
you know i i
logged some of the details and
and also some of my opinions so this
article you should go read
okay but go read this article
and i talked about it before
now of course you are asking you know
what's
you probably are asking what's my
opinion about the current situation
because richard snowman
apparently he uh you know he
he said he's rejoined he's becoming free
software foundation
uh leader again and then there's a lot
of controversy
because some people don't like him
uh
so whether so i i don't agree okay i
think
those people are not bad are not good
people i think those
people are bad people however richard
stoneman himself
you know he has not he i be in my
opinion richard stollman has done
nothing
wrong absolutely nothing
to you know for this incident
however on a separate issue
richard stoneman is a has become
problematic because
he has not been coding for like 20 years
10 or 20 probably 20. he has
he has not been coding for 20 years and
his personal life is like secluded from
the real world
you know he become one of those new age
guru
like he tells you like he can fly you
know
he became a guru like some india yoga
you know guru
he he you know he sits there do nothing
every day
and gets donation because people think
he's a god
you know you can see a lot of that in
memes you know just roman
so and he has become you know secluded
you know um out of touch with reality
he have no idea what is going on in
programming industry no idea at all
he you know so i again so but
especially you you watch a lot of my
videos but you know
you should know i have quite a lot
collection of articles on richard
snowman
of the things he done that is wrong
okay so he become out of touch
and saying stupid you know idiotic
things that
does great harm to emax
you know the progress of emacs
so for this reason
i'm not sure he he's a good you know he
should
you know lead free software that you
know that's he's got problems
on the other hand
if he leaves free software
the free software is is going to be
something else
i'm absolutely certain of a certain of
that
free software foundation without richard
snowman whatever problem he has richard
so man is problematic
but however once he's gone like he has
been removed for a while now
you know this free software is the
nature of free software foundation and
the
emacs is already changed it's gonna be
something
else okay it's gonna be something else i
would not want to touch i don't want to
touch it
you know you don't know i don't know
what will happen meanwhile he himself is
not
a good leader he shouldn't be he does
fit he does not deserve to be our leader
anymore for emacs or for a free software
foundation
i don't believe so and also i would say
he has become weak a weak
person and you know because due to the
incident in 2019 he just oh
i resigned he's become weak he does not
does not deserve
to be our leader so i don't know so as
far as i'm concerned
the free software foundation is already
dead you know
like it doesn't matter whether with
richard snowman or without it's like
irrelevant it becomes some kind of
entity
like many of the political uh nonprofit
organizations
it becomes just a entity that gets
lots of your money donation and they do
things
they do things that's harmful for
humanity for the good of humanity
that's my opinion but
so about second question what do you
think of people what do you think of
people
using oop languages to program in
functional style
okay that's you know first of all many
op languages
they do not support functional
programming
maybe a little bit not much you cannot
do much with it for example
perl java
python okay let me just pick these three
examples
these three examples are the worst okay
now pearl for example pearl
they say they are multi-parading you
know lots of these language they
they claim they are multi-parading pearl
and python but actually no
if you use perl if you are a functional
programmer like me
i'm a functional programmer i love
functional programming i never
i will never code anything oop in my own
project
unless i work at you know uh you know at
a job
where they already have a software it's
already written the code is using orp
then you do orp
in my own code there's not one single
line of object oriented programming
i think that's so that i think that's a
very well actually it's you know
sometimes it's useful
but personally i think it's
no good and in general it's no good
okay so i make two claims in general oop
paradigm op style programming is
now this is my claim it it's its value
in programming industry is over hyped to
by far too much
it has only sometimes useful okay that's
my claim
uh so op is op language is
such as java
and python especially java and python
um so what so so then why is a lot of
people crazy for op for example java
python or even javascript
you know most vast majority of
javascript code
is op how do i um
how do i conciliate how do i resolve
that how do i
what what's my answer you know look look
all these people
you must be wrong because all these
people many of them are smart
programmers they are doing op
what's my response my response is look
at religion okay
there are millions of people who believe
in god there are million people who
believes in some kind of cult
scientology falun gong and many others
they believe people can fly
they be and there are a lot of people
millions
literally millions of people who believe
in people can you know
parapsychology psychokinesis they can
you know know
they can bend spoons okay there are
millions literally millions of people
believing that
that is my response why so many people
believe in op
okay it's just uh and and also
a lot of people believe in chinese
medicine they believe you don't need
surgery okay
you know chinese medicine is a big thing
it's a
cultural part of it so that's my answer
so what why most people believe in op
and meanwhile i say op is like of little
value
well culture culture okay cultural
reasons programmers okay
so so i don't believe in opm
and my personal code i don't code op at
all i do functional programming
so let me go back to the so so many
languages
especially java java is just pure p
language okay in java language
you know java don't even claim they are
multi-parading
java is pretty much a pure op language
so if you code in such language
basically you cannot do uh functional
programming you can do a little bit
i you know i believe java 10 years ago
started to support lambda
yeah but the whole thing is op okay you
cannot do it
now for pearl and python they
both claim to be multi-parading you know
that's
that's you know if if you look
at if you talk to poor people and
and python people you know some of the
phonetics
you know they'll say oh yeah we can do
everything op you know functional
programming can do
no actually that's not true perl the
nature of pearl is a procedural language
they do not actually support orp nor do
they support
functional programming okay they do
support somewhat
but you kind of you you are you are kind
of forcing it
okay so perl is mostly a procedural
language like
like assignment procedural or sometimes
called imperative language
it does support orp and it does support
functional programming
uh i would say pretty well okay
but but it's like hack okay
now for python case python is mostly aop
language okay
python is mostly aop language
it claims to support functional
programming but it's like it's like a
lie
because if you are a functional
programmer you run into lots of problems
it cannot do the most obvious problem is
that
the most patent the obvious in
shortcoming is that
its lambda the function is like crippled
okay i have article you know just search
for saudi python lambda i have quite a
few
articles on that
okay so so i have like three articles so
lambda in python three thousand
this is when guido von rossum guido van
rossum trying to
uh create python three claiming
something something something
you know and here's another important
article
why python lambda is broken and cannot
be fixed
now this is a critical article first of
all i give you some
uh scheme this expert's opinion
you know he's saying the same thing
python you know python lambda is
is no good is is cripples you know makes
python not a functional language at all
then i also give the opinion that
a critical opinion where the syntax the
python lambda
why python cannot do lambda well or it
cannot do functional programming because
the syntax
because you know the layout the the you
know the
the layout syntax you know the tab
that the syntax actually creates a
limitation
this is the funda this is the core
reason this is the
uh gist this is the essential reason
python lambda
cannot be fixed you know not because of
a
decision by geido rather it's because
the syntax
the python syntax created a limitation
that makes python lambda
impossible a difficult or difficult or
inconvenient
inconvenient to be a full lambda
therefore it
you know once if if you have a language
whose lambda is
kind of crippled then your language
basically cannot do functional
programming well
so so i'm saying this
uh the context you know i'm saying this
because a lot of people think that
syntax is not important they think that
semantic is more important in a
programming language
they think that syntax can be just
arbitrary
meanwhile the semantics can be can be
can be um created to can be designed
to do any type of language that is
false okay the reason i'm saying this is
important
because it has to do with the common
misconception
where syntax is not important in the
python case
python cannot be a functional language
or can never
become a fully functional programming
language
it's because the syntax the python
syntax
created a limitation that is my claim
okay
and you you can read my articles for the
details
so answer the question you know uh what
do you think of people using op language
through programming functional style
first of all mini language just cannot
do it
so java cannot do it period for perl and
python you kind of can do it you can
try to push it but it's not satisfactory
if you are really a functional
programmer uh it doesn't work well
okay so that's my answer
so fasting's question uh i have a
question uh
so you guys donate okay put money
i'm gonna answer your question so
vazin's question i have a
uh somewhat a personal question do you
feel you wasted
uh with your working emacs that's the
impression i got
watching one of your uh previous streams
well the answer is yes and no okay so
so you you live your life you made
some you know i'm 52 so i'm kind of
a bit old than most of you i guess
so if you are young you know so
anyway you live your life during your
life you have made some choices
and uh in my life i spent like 20 years
devoted to emacs okay i made some
choices
i'm you know i'm into i spend my life
among in the unix community not windows
and not mac either i use the mac but
mostly my pro
all the programming language i i know
the technology is about
is around unix linux python all the open
source you know
bash and so on so in your life you made
some decisions
and so do i regret
uh spend my time in emacs or unex
yes and no okay i you know you i can't i
can't
i cannot say i regret it uh
you know because it's a choice i made uh
on the other hand i could you know if i
i might say you know i might
i might have a better life if i
was not a so much
open source you know in the hacker
community that much
if i actually focused on creating
software
uh doesn't matter what platform you know
if i focus on creating software then
i might have i might be better off or
study mathematics you know if i focus
on my my life on studying mathematics or
you know creating software
i might have a better life you know or
better like i might i might be happier
today
so that is my retro in retrospect you
know it's always always easy to
look back and criticize you know if i
start over maybe
i'll have a better i'll have a better
life but maybe not
okay so that might be uh
um you know something to think about
so because i spent a lot of time when
you are in the unix community
you also tend to be the kind of person
you know uh
you open source phonetics and also for
me for example
arguing about programming languages so i
spent
half of my life you know basically a few
few hours every day
to debate with people about programming
languages
about linux about which which operating
system to use
you know this sort of thing and this
this kind of this
this is kind of the main thing among
hackers okay
it's a waste of time okay so it is
and it has uh you know it has you know
in a sense
it has done damage to my life
in retro in retrospect but not
necessarily so because otherwise i
wouldn't be
who i am you know if i didn't you know
anyway so that's my kind of opinion
so paul edwards says isn't pro
in javascript based on the lambda
calculus
no far from it what are you talking
about
c plus first has a lambda function as
well but yes i have only used them as
procedural yeah
see you know the function of programming
has a long history
beginning in 1980s
uh even 19 1960s okay this
lisp is the first functional programming
language
now of course for you young peoples here
today
the idea the concept of functional
language
is different from older people because
for you guys today
today's new young people you might think
oh haskell is a functional language
because
you know no side effect you have you
know you have a
few of you know haskell you know you
don't
allow side effects you don't have
mutable variables and all that
it's pure and ocamo you know basically
there are not many
pascal is almost the only pure
functional language then
or camel you know and
but today's young people when you look
at this you might
think oh that's not functional language
at all because you have lots of
variables
and in fact lots of global variables and
you change them all the time
in this okay so today's people you might
think
only haskell or something like haskell
is is functional
that's not true okay functional
programming began
you this is actually the first one
in 1960s then there's uh ocamo
camel the father the father of a camel
is camel
the father of camel is you know the
camel is called meta language okay then
then then there's a few others okay um
there are a few others and any anyway
this
is the father functional language okay
so
uh
so okay so functional you know
functional why is functional language
not popular
before you know except this this was
very popular in 1980s
well one of the reasons because
functional language
is one hard to implement okay c
and similar you know c is the c is
very easy c is extremely
easy to implement like if you are idiot
you can implement c
okay if you don't have a brand you can
implement c and if you don't have a
brand you can code c
now if you want to implement a function
language language like this
it's harder it's much more harder okay
memory management and
all sorts of things that becomes
everywhere today that becomes every in
every language
so that is why c becomes very very
popular it's like it's
you know some people say it's a virus
you know it's the worst
possible virus then some people try
to improve it
incrementally so this this this um
snake oil seller you know the c plus sky
oh he sees very popular and see oh i'll
just change i'll just add this thing add
this add this a little bit thing to fix
c so that's why c plus first is created
then another uh you know guy comes in oh
i'll just
you know actually i think this way is
better let me just fix c
you know tweak this and tweak that then
you have java
okay c c plus plus java
then another guy comes in oh i'll just
actually trick this thing
i think it will be better then you got d
the language d
okay which is also object oriented
so they are all crap okay they are all
based on the see the worst
that's the yc popular because it's
the most easy idiotic
uh language to implement you know this
doesn't require
a design no design it doesn't require a
brain
okay if you want to do anything
different that's difficult that much
that's more difficult
but anyway there's a problem with
functional programming
because in to run list requires lots of
memory resources
and it's super slow so if if you want
artificial intelligence yeah you can do
that
but the code is very slow so
so this is the reason functional
programming is not
popular but beginning in 2000 around
late you know around let's say just of
2010 you know because we
you know the cpu the hardware becomes
very fast
faster and faster and we have
multi-cores now
so because of that you know it
one chip doesn't get faster anymore you
have multi-core so there are two
primary push for functional programming
one
is that the hardware becomes very fast
and lots of memory memory is very cheap
you know today so functional programming
actually works now
you know so haskell becomes super
popular
and and and for example closure as well
so that's why functional programming
becomes
in javascript okay it becomes to be very
popular
you know programmers started to know oh
lambda oh we should have lambda
and java added lambda then c plus plus
added lambda okay
they begin to become popular in 2010.
the other reason functional programming
started to spread
among industry programmers is that they
you know the chips don't get faster
anymore so what you need is
you need parallel computation you need
parallel algorithms
and in order to do that in order to
write power
parallel com algorithms functional
programming
where a function without side effect is
extremely helpful
because well anyway just take my words
for it
it's because you don't because otherwise
it's hard to deal with uh concurrency
okay so you want functional programming
so
for these two reasons functional
programming
uh you know become popular and they got
added to java in 2008 i think or 2010
then
i added to c in 2020.
okay that's my that's concludes my talk
today uh okay
today is a super loan rant i guess
um
one hour and 25 minutes okay if you like
my stuff donate okay patreon me
paypal me buy my javascript tutorial buy
my emacs tutorial
just search for saudi javascript saudi
emaclist thank you guys bye
so
you