hello guys welcome to another episode of
Zatoichi Oh today is 2019 October
today is November 1st November 1st
Friday 7 o clock in the afternoon
evening San Francisco time good morning
Alan
so we are going to do Emacs Emacs in the
email is all Emacs for one hour
Omo so Alan what do you think should
should we start B or Emacs you know
install and setup my Emacs from scratch
or should we do the the other
miscellaneous we might be able to do
both
we will see so Allen give us a topic but
otherwise I'm going to start with
writing a command open in visual studio
code vs code that is I installed that
and it seems it's fantastic I'm going to
show you ok visual studio code so we're
gonna start in in a second in five
seconds I mean clean clean my glasses
you see these very bad glasses from
Walmart
Oh super chat oh my god
Thank You Alan super chat fantastic so
Alan so super chat means okay means so
so making Stouffer's Challenger
let's do mag install okay that's to
American install from scratch but I want
to do I want to cover this should be
very fast create a command to open the
current buffer in Visual Studio code
okay so let's do let's install Emacs
from scratch okay so let's let's stop
let's stop that okay and I'm going to
hold on a second let's go through my go
through my home directory and you see
that Emacs T this is my this is my
Emacs convict and I'm going to rename it
rename it with today's date as a backup
so yep we are going to start fresh and
I'm going to quit Emacs okay let's see
to accurate yes quit
no such file directory opening our food
plans okay well yeah that's the problem
is okay hold on a second smacks Emacs is
refusing to quit because of handsy are
we we need my Emacs dot d config
directory so the smacks is trying to
save things to it and it's so therefore
Emacs
refused to quit and this is very
annoying
so let's recreate let's see
okay let's rename it back okay quit okay
quit Emacs
good morning BOTS Oh My gods body's
still here sell out right away okay we
we are going to focus on the eMac
installation
so which Emacs do I install you go to
the Emacs and practical Emacs tutorial
where to download and Windows Mac so
these are all pretty odd Mac binaries so
you go here this is the one I use okay
this is a plain blue Emacs no extra
stuff you install it then you can
install other stuff so you just click
download so actually I have already done
so I'm going to just launch it because
that's so simple step you don't need
raise it okay so I have actually several
versions of Emacs oh they don't show it
here interesting so but we can show it
in
applications so you see I have several
versions of Emacs twenty five twenty six
twenty six point one twenty six so we're
gonna launch Emacs Oh hold on a second
we did a mistake
emacs 26.3 app is an application
downloaded from the internet you are you
sure yes I'm sure
shut the [ __ ] up you know since they
since these Apple stores Microsoft
stores iPhone stores Google stores they
stop you from being able just to run
programs so anyway so the this is my
Emacs in it let's rename it let's rename
it
let's see because I want to start Emacs
without any in it okay what's going on
okay
Emacs do the Emacs froze okay this is a
bad start mood
what is going on because now it seems I
cannot I'm unable to quit so first of
all desktop save mod stop it ok then so
I want to create mix
let's quit again so let's go back to
shell good morning Andrew
so let's go back to shell so we're gonna
list directories let's magnify so we're
gonna rename the Emacs study the my
Emacs in it file so Emacs study where is
it that Emacs dot T so we named oh I
forgot my Unix commands which in move ok
UNIX stupid UNIX move dot Emacs tardy to
the Emacs tardy and today State 2019
1101 ok we renamed it now we start Emacs
ok we can start it this way from shell
there it is very fast so we are going to
install Emacs from scratch and I need to
do you know for Mac for my own use I
need to do lots of things so first of
all go to the directory control X let's
see let's turn on keys
okay go to the directory top go to the
home directory so you see it created a
it created a magnify and see how do i
magnify you see when you are in good
the default Emacs everything is a pain
okay so it created wait
anyways it created a Emacs empty dot
Emacs dotty so we are going to create a
unit file so control X control F name it
in it dot DL so this is my unit file and
let's put set background color okay set
background color all the keys let's say
honey true okay and we need to put
parentheses okay so now save it quit now
let's restart Emacs first of all we
created a unifier error god it's arrow
so open dot Emacs tardy sash in it wait
why is is not set background color why
is it this arrow control X control e to
evaluate it so a known color honey drew
is a non-color what oh honey do okay
so save it create Emacs restart Emacs
there we have it so we created a unit
file we have the background we wanted
that's the way you find out whether
you're in it violet
you simply put something in the like
change background color then you know
Emax found the unity file and used it so
let's open the Emacs init file again no
proceeding light pumps so you have a lot
to setup when you you know when you
start fresh so we got init file the next
thing we need I really need is sapphire
keys so let's go to let's get sapphire
keys
so Aaron says another topic once you get
Windows CE max up is learning his
PowerShell integration to empower ya
para Shou is fantastic you probably
could do it on the Mac yes PowerShell is
yeah open-source everywhere PowerShell
is now on the Mac as well actually I
have it installed actually so you can
type which psi I think which PowerShell
huh I thought I have it installed which
PS man PS no not peers I'm pretty sure I
installed it but I forgot what's the
command which psi-man PowerShell so
anyway we got the we gotta you need file
now I need to install shot flag keys
this is the efficient key binding it's
like Emacs I mean it's like vim its
model but the key binding is designed
based on economics and statistics of
command call so it's the most efficient
so we're gonna get the list code here
okay and show it raw
this is gonna okay then copy everything
select all copy go back to Emacs now I
want to go to tired so meta X meta x
tired okay I want to go to diet I want
to create a directory called Lisp so
here's a new directory Lisp
how do I let's magnify the I want to
magnify so where is that command text
properties not text properties
I have not used the does anyone remember
the command to magnify the font size to
operate tools buffers not buffers
options and finishing options
set default fonts oh yeah okay yeah so
there it is let's do that this is
okay that's that's no good
let's do it again
sixteen I guess sixteen
okay sixteen so we created a directory
list here and we're gonna open a new
buffer called saw fly key start al and
we're gonna paste the entire supply keys
Marc said so paste is meta why wait what
what is control why I think why is it
wait what's the default paste I forgot
let's just use the menu yeah it should
be CY but it's not working so let's go
back here select all copy back to Emacs
control Y okay there it is now we save
it the file save it now it's saved now
go to the top what's Emacs keys to go to
the top I don't remember
haven't used Emacs default keys for a
long time so so anyway we saved this fox
off like he's now we close it okay it's
there we close it and now let's go
through stuff like his home page to set
it up this is taking longer than I
expected to set the whole Emacs setup
so now the phone size is good so we go
back to South Frankie's home page we
want to go to our home page because
there are some key binding the
configuration I need to set up socks off
like his home page it's waiting for it
okay there it is we want to go to the
home page click and video introduction
and here is the command I need we are
installing manually so let's copy this
section copy so we go back to Emacs init
file open it and paste paste looks up
flag is in it so we are turning Emacs to
load loaded in this I mean add a load
path in this sleep directs lisp
directory that's the convention when you
instead when you have your you know your
the packages you download it for
yourself by convention you should be in
this list directory so we're gonna
require supply keys and set keyboard
layout we need we need wall racks so
let's say black okay and so we required
we set the keyboard then we turn it on
so control X control s save the file now
now now we will start Emacs and now it
should work
good morning z tron crazy you guys are
not sleeping yet over what time is it in
germany 4 o'clock 5 o'clock in morning
so we are going to restart Emacs but
before we do that let's make sure our
code there is no problem so the
you know we do that by evaluating each
of the lisps command so control X E so
we just evaluate evaluate this line then
we control X key
now we load itself like he's now control
X E now we have set the keyboard layout
to varrock now control X e turn wrong
soft like he's now I'm really flying you
see now now I can do the to lots of
things so say you know okay so that's
good as possible values of saw Frankie
supports many of these other layouts
Commack quality chords chords e Walkman
asset E and so on so so that that is now
let's restart Emacs so okay so save it
wait save okay now quit Emacs now we
start Emacs back to shell
restart Emacs okay
now the font went back to the it's
annoying but but I do have soft like he
song because you can see you can see in
the mini buffer in the status bar the
this is this line is called mod lying
technically you can see suffer keys so
I'm using some fly keys to move around
now let's set up the phone problem
I want the large font so how do you do
that so let's go through the Emacs setup
I don't remember you know what is the
font setup so fun setup we look up here
and text and actually the easiest way
actually just go through my github in it
so sorry github
3.18 a.m. that's great so Emacs in it so
one of the alright so this is my Emacs
in it file one of the most basic in it
thing I need is the settings so we let's
open that so basically this settings
file contains everything that does not
require any package it's just basic
setup of Emacs so let's copy the entire
thing copy it go to the let's go to the
Emacs init file okay so go to about
Emacs dot B and let's create a new file
okay here is my settings file I just
pasted it let's magnify let's see now I
can magnify okay no not okay so now this
is a settings file we save it okay wait
we save it settings start il okay
magnify magnify copy the file path close
it okay close it init file magnified
magnify magnify open the ini' file
magnify magnify and let's put load ok
let's see what I do I need to do
eval error no such file load settings
okay so you want to I want to load the
settings file but let's look at E max in
its it setup
any questions any questions comments so
what we want to do is that we want to
create a command eMac basic command to
load the settings file in the you know
in a unit file another way is that we
can paste the entire settings in a unit
file but I prefer to put them in put for
different customizations in different
files like key bindings basic settings
other packages customization in
different files then then in the unifier
you load them so that way is more
manageable so how do you do that in neat
package install packages install
packages manually
let's see define Keys customize so let's
see install packages manually
yeah load load should work but I do not
know why is it not working let's see
okay it's not working is because because
I remember we have to we have to add the
load path so load path that okay so it
tells you to load yeah
so evaluate that now load settings
fantastic it's done now let's restart
Emacs closed do I want to save any file
yes save desktop yes
directory for desktop
okay that so now let's restart Emacs now
everything should be very good ok
warning your load path seems to contain
your hold on a second is this arrow it
says your load path seems to contain
Emacs tardy directory this is likely to
cause problems consider using a certain
subdirectory okay let's do that so we
move that and now go to the directory
magnifier magnify and open the lisp
directory and put the settings file over
there okay you see so now close that
close that refresh open unit file okay
that's good so let's quit Emacs save any
file yes start Emacs again perfect
now let's look at settings files the
font is still too small for you know
every time we restart the font is small
let's open that file let's open the
settings file we want it so that when we
restart the phone is already large so
look at settings file hope and enlarge
it font did I say font size somewhere so
anyway so that that is basically how I
set up my stuff I have a lot things
other things to install I need to
install my packages for example my
JavaScript mod my email is smart my HTML
mod you know a bunch of other things so
if you have a question you know you want
to get answered let me know we can go
into that direction so Alan says when do
you when when you do add to list does
that automatically load or the year of
out no it does not
you simply add the path to the you know
to the load path so then when you load
some fire Emacs will search those paths
to find it so so we want to set up font
here okay I don't know so I apparently I
don't have it in here such toc-toc oh so
you have a bunch of convenient things
tired recent F blink
cruz' global display line numbers smart
you see you have line numbers on the
side that's done by this one a bunch of
conveniences okay but it doesn't contain
font so let's look at how do you set up
font so go back to in it set up
go back to font set up front set up how
to change font size how to find a
current font used how to set default
font there it is
copy that and now go back to my unit
file actually well actually go through
my go to my unit file so close that
enlarge open unit file let's say let's
fill it here so it says when when the
font when men when men low is part of
the font family list is available then
you then you set frame font manual 14
let's see it's evaluator that works so
save it
quit restart Emacs now it now you should
be have a good default font
okay I'm not sure about that it's open
is this larger it doesn't seems to be
larger it's open wait
let's open a new buffer this is okay
let's try 15 evaluated yeah it's it's
okay now it's larger now close it say we
start Emacs now it's it's good so we got
fun setup we I have a lot of things I
need to install for example my packages
but okay so so let's start to write code
to launch the current buffer in in vs
code let's just try it let's just start
to do that well before we do do that I
do want to load my Emacs Lisp mod I'm
used to my Emacs Lee smart so let's do
that so go to some packages stuff like
he's we got that sorry max this mod this
is a great mod if you use a Mac this if
you co eMac this so let's download it we
can also download it download it for our
mapper but let's go to github okay hold
on a second let's open a new tab go to
github so get the raw source code
hi Vitruvius Lee everyday I'm learning
this everyday saw talk show you are
watching son talk show so copy the whole
code copy the whole code and go back to
the init directory this is too big and
this is we need to adjust the frame size
go back to the init directory go to the
Lisp directory open a new buffer paste
the whole thing go to the top save this
file say name it us what's the name saw
a lisp mod da ta l okay now copy the
file path close it close it go through
the init file and we need to load okay
so load that's what you need to do so if
we load it if I know I'd learned execute
this line of code now you see right now
I'm in Emacs Lee smart he says at the
bottom and in the Mott line you see
there but now I just loaded Harley smart
so now if we close this buffer and we
open it it should be issues exactly
smart and the color will be different
let's find out
so okay close it save it open it again
you see now it says summation Elise
that's cuz I eMac this mod so I have
many conveniences for example effect I
can press one button the whole block of
code is intended so that's that's so now
we got emag Lee smart let's try to write
the command to open show current buffer
in Visual Studio code okay well let's
let's restart Emacs
and another thing I noticed is that if
you if I open
you buffer it's um it's like fullscreen
it's gigantic
again never mind let's restart Emacs
okay so save a brief Sabre breathe okay
yes
okay so let's write a command to open
current buffer in Visual Studio now
let's go to let's go through practical
Emacs I have a similar command that's
already written let's see if we can find
it search for open open file in external
app okay so here is a bunch of similar
command we can just copy and modify so
here is opening external app opening
desktop open terminal open in TextEdit
so this one and opening in Safari let's
see open in terminal let's see open in
desktop let's use this showing desktop
let's see
actually let's copy the opening text
edit wait hold on a second
let's do it from scratch okay so let's
open a new buffer go to the lisp
directory open a new foot buffer save it
as save it as some commands okay command
dot yeah okay save it now today's stage
now save it copy the file path go to the
init directory again we want to load it
so copy it load okay we are going to
load that file okay so let's go back to
commands so we're gonna define a
function open let's sakes are open in vs
code okay open current buffer in vs code
okay so how do we do that we can go back
here and look at
it's knits copy that
pace it here there is something we want
so condition so condition we have
several conditions if we are on Windows
then do something here okay and if we
are on a Mac do something if we are on a
Linux then Co different commands so oops
so I'll make you the way you say it is
Darwin check check the variable system
type has the value of Darwin
okay so oops so on Linux it's good news
/ Linux okay so when it's on Windows you
do something when in some Mac you do
something this is the one we we are
concerned right now so we're just gonna
code stuff here we are just going to
ignore so if we are on Windows or Linux
we just ignore it for now so when we are
on a Mac what we do so let's see if that
okay easy so when we are on Darwin we do
this okay let's so when we are Meg we
call shell command wait we we call shell
command then we call open open R vs path
let's see we call the Mac open command
then the path should be the path should
be the current buffers path how do we
get that we get that by doing this thing
so let's copy it here so so create a
variable path and the value will be if
buffer Vaio name exists then use that
but for filename but for filename
returns the the path of the current
buffer now however if the current buffer
is not associated associated with a file
it's a for example new buffer then
then what you do you you give the
current directory okay so yeah so if the
current buffer is a file then use that
open that file otherwise try to open the
directory the current directory the
buffer the buffer is created in so okay
so now we need to go open let's see how
we on a Mac how do you Co how do you get
BS code to open the file by command
command line so how to do that how to do
that we can see how to do that here
there it is okay let's try to copy this
that's how you do that
copy that
so that is how you do it okay so and see
right so this is how you do it so you
call the command format then open then
then type the vs code name now what is
the vs code name let's see
okay so vs code name let's copy hit
so Visual Studio code I think you need a
backslash oops
open a wish visual studio code app named
path I think that's it now let's go to
the shell man open let's see the open
command ace application that's right
okay so let's let's try it if it works
and the rest we don't need so here is
our command
we evaluate it and let's call saw open
in BS code envious
code unable to find application name
Visual Studio code okay so there is a
space issue I mean this so let's try
double backslash okay save it
evaluate the command save it then code
yay successful fantastic now you see now
now it doesn't have syntax coloring for
least code so in Visual Studio you need
to install you know I just installed
Visual Studio so okay so you got a
search marketplace to install a
extension that this syntax highlight you
know that installs the syntax coloring
for Lisp fantastic but this is great so
we got our code to work so not so how
long have I been talking any questions
type it now okay
and we okay 46 minutes not too bad we
you know that's a great thing we did
today so let me read the comments
so you can do this for for venture in
dart files what do you mean but true V I
go sleep because my eyes and my brain
badly hurts
good night Z strong hello Freddy
and good night Z Tron and Ireland
oh cool congratulations being monetized
yes now we can opener vs code from Emacs
this is the most monetizing okay
so anything else you guys you guys Emacs
users any questions so let's go back to
the topics let's see what else are
interesting we can talk about so go back
to topics so now I need to go to you
know I don't know so this is a fresh
install I do not have my bookmarks I do
not have you know tons of other things I
need in my daily life for example right
now I want to go to my son talk show
page but there's no bookmark so I would
have to open home directory web
directory sorry
info okay then go to talk show directory
enter okay then this is my talk show
directory delete or the backup delete
them yes okay yes or no now Emacs
asks you to type yes or no you have to
type the full name which which is very
annoying so let's go to my image in ink
fat in a file to change that so let me
show you so open back to the Emacs init
file so let's see if we have it in it
yeah so we're gonna say 80 years
okay describe function
heylia's we want to make ideas I forgot
what's the command so well we can find
out here so describe function hello
describe function alias no match
okay I forgot what's a function name
there's a there's another way to find
out within Emacs so we can do control
you control you meta X troppo then type
ideas okay
our deaf ideas so it's it's not areas
Steff areas deaf areas okay there we
have it the alternative way to find
email is functions is you just go
through my Emacs tutorial you know you
can that's another way so now we are we
want to define an alias a symbol so what
what is the let's describe function to
see the documentation of alias def areas
okay so we want to change yes or no oh
no function to Y or in I think save it
so let's describe function ah yes or no
yes or no is a command Emacs command
that that requires users that prompts
users to type yes or no the entire world
so let's call describe function
yes or no
P ok there's a pedia so it says ask user
yes-or-no question so this function name
is yes or no P P stand for predicate
whenever a function name ends in - p o--
p usually that means it returns yes or
no immediate returns true or false so
now we want to change whenever we want
to make ideas of that to Y or MP
okay so let's describe function y OMP so
Y o NP is the same thing as yes or no P
except it only requires users to type Y
or n or space space for y so Emacs has
both of them because you know Emacs
thinks that when you want to for example
Davido directory you want you you want
force users to type for years or no in
case of mistakes but usually those
mistakes doesn't happen Y or Y or n is
enough so I want to make this area so
evaluate it it's evaluated save it now
let's go back to let's go back to let's
look at the buffers let's go back to my
talkshow page directory refresh expand
the window now you see those back up I
want to delete them let's do it again so
press the tilde key to mark them press X
press X to delete them - I want to
delete them so now it says Y Oh Han you
see it doesn't require me to type 4
years old so I press space now it's all
deleted so that's you know that's one of
the convenience of Emacs now we go to
santosh your index showing browser okay
so okay so I don't have closed don't
save reopen I want to show in browser so
the key is you see right now it's using
default Emacs default HTML mod I have my
own HTML mod so in default HTML mod if
you want to go to the browser you press
ctrl-c ctrl-v
I think yeah okay it did okay so now it
shows in browser okay so next thing you
know we are we let's install oxide Gmail
mod maybe so let's see what's the
comments so do you usually just
copy/paste your useful code from your
website or do you ever automatically
sync with github and stuff I do it both
ways because I do it both ways and it
depends you know because I need github
because some people are using github for
example sophocles orcas I am actually
smart this to us it's somewhat popular
so I need to always update the github
but meanwhile I also always need to
update my website those are my tutorials
so it depends on a package or things I
typically do both yeah
I tend to focus you know the priority
would be my website because kid hub is
is you know it's third-party you know
these companies they can go away anytime
soon and you know after a few years old
it's what you should use kidlat things
like that they change all the time so
but my web page for me is like permanent
so Freddie says no that sounds a bit
different for those who don't know rat
poison
I need rat poison for Windows okay so
these third parties won't go away this
is what we have learned from your anti
open source okay anything anything else
so let's install I'm just gonna do
random then I want to install my HTML
mod so sorry
HTML mod github okay so on my web page
you go to my web page then you go to
github to get the source code you know
actually all the source code is also in
my home directory like if we go to my
you know my
Emacs T my previous start Emacs T you
know it's all here so yeah I just open
it did a backup dd-does backup and and
[Music]
where is my stuff ALPA not air pad Lisp
no not here
transient ALPA Asia wait how to save
ALPA Asia where is my
where is my own bunch of fires
let's see open in it oh it's on my okay
so it's in this directory in my kit
directory so go there then go to the
directory then then here you can see all
my own mods that I'm loading wait where
are my mods
so anyway so you can see you see oh you
see my kid directory so you can see it's
it's over there for example here is my
email is mod in my kid directory then
let's search folks our HTML mod there it
is so you see it's in my kid directory
so here is the source code for its HTML
mod copy the whole thing close it close
it or you can copy from my github you
know it's the same thing
so copy close close close go back to my
Emacs in it close go back to my close go
back to my Emacs init file go to the
directory go to this project we open a
new buffer paste the entirety of HTML
mod save it by that name go to the
directory refresh you see this is the
file and now we need to go back to the
go back to go back to the init file to
load it
there but however that won't work
because HTML mod is a big one you
require these for other things
shall we prepare a socket thing so CSS
mod and HTML eyes so you need to install
those four things that's gonna take five
minutes yeah hey hey Freddy so any any
any other questions let's let's see what
today's topic let's see what we're gonna
do anything else let's go to so comment
this out because that won't work until
we install a bunch of the other packages
oh yeah nothing compared to web pack min
so now let's go to our talk show what is
this oh this is my talk show you see
this oriented because right now I'm
using this HTML plus the Emacs default
HTML mod so all the keys and commands
are different from what I used to but
anyway let's look at you know let's just
walk it out let's see what else we want
to do so write a command for vs code
hoping in vs code we did that modify XR
new page command to add a title yeah so
that's list emag beast coding set
default mod for new buffer to HTML
that's default that's you know these are
just random Emacs topics actually so
let's go back and install looks HTML MA
it's finish
that so so let's go back to install HTML
mod okay open the file go to the
directory Lisp
it requires sorry place payers
okay so copy add new buffer get soggy
place payers sit good morning this time
I was able to where are you from CID
what country other topics non-technical
in honor of no no not November
what is no not November what are your
thoughts on abstinence in fasting in
general okay I think let's talk about
that next tomorrow also you know today
we're gonna just do folk on technical
stuff I am from Mexico but currently
live in Japan Wow Wow that's great so
how long you be in Japan see Sid is a
mathematician and Sid thus spectral
theory spectral theory is very advanced
like I have no idea what is about but
I'd heard another mathematician Jung
something Jeong Jeong you know he he was
telling people what it is about spectral
theory SPE CGT RAL theory it's a theory
in like topology and differential
geometry is alright I think there are
several like several different theories
about spectral so a spectral theory in
math is a inclusive term for theories
extending the eigenvector in nineteen
gun value theory of a single square
matrix to a much broader theory of the
structure of operators in a variety of
mathematic
spaces okay okay so it's a result of
studies of linear algebra and the
solutions of systems of linear equations
in their generalizations the theories
connected to that of analytic functions
because the spectral properties of an
operator are related to analytic
functions of the spectral parameter okay
I have some basic idea but much of it
just fly by so Sid says currently I'm
studying spectrum of differential
operator
oh that's and sometimes graphs
differential operators so that's
differential geometry right anyway I
don't understand this so are you in
Japan for vacation or are you taking a
vacation short term or long term are you
or are you teaching there so let's go
back let's get back to install the sod
replace pay us and that you know let's
install this HTML package and I think
that would be here today so github site
tml mod wait we didn't find it where is
it
sorry place pay us so this one so get
the package get the raw code copy or
now go to the directory open a new
buffer paste it go to the top copy the
name save it
bikes I'll replace payer start yeah ok
saved now close refresh there the there
we have it now what's the next one we
need to install cuz I'll get things ok
get hub get hub some good things there
it is open it
show raw select or copy open it save it
go to the top copy the name save by that
name then close now next thing we need
is so CSS mode get hurt so CSS mode so
MATLAB plus Emacs thoughts I haven't
used MATLAB so I can't really say MATLAB
is another you know math application and
if you want to so so basically are you
talk you are talking about MATLAB plus
Emacs
I I think you rather use them separately
because MATLAB has this notebook
interface where you can have graphics
and formulas paragraphs headers things
like that anywhere it's like you know
you can you can track graphics and place
it at anywhere so in that respect if you
use it in Emacs you can I think they are
interface I mean some some people have
written Emacs packages to interface with
Matt MATLAB but if you do that all you
get is is a you know command-line
interface you type something it returns
you know it's and I don't think you got
graphics
so you are wasting a lot features of
MATLAB so if you want to use MATLAB I
would recommend just use MATLAB
directory the directory so anyway let's
show the roll package of this and saw
CSS mod copy yet open a new buffer paste
it and save the file as a CSS mod save
it close it and last thing we need is
HTML eyes mod so get her HTML dies so
it's by this guy
this guy is from Finland I know him like
kind of I mean I talked to him since
like 15 years ago he was a ex Emacs user
and he is against new you know the
richest Tolman you know in open source
you have factions so so he wrote is
since 1997 so this is a great package
what it does I recommend it what it does
is that it turns Emacs buffers coloring
into HTML so you can turn this whole
page into HTML with color so that's what
I need so open the new new new buffer
paste the code 18 about 2000 lines so
save this file save it
HTML eyes save ok close it now go to
tired you can see I have installed all
these packages now let's go back to my
init file and now we can load saj tml
mod that should walk let's let's call
the code execute vennett it works no
error let's go to let's show the message
buffer let's see if there are any errors
no error so that means everything is
perfect now now let's say
it closed in it file closing it file
let's switch to our talk show page you
see when now the mod is HTML plus that's
the default Emacs HTML mod in Emacs 26
that's new in Emacs 26 before it's just
called HTML mod but anyway now if I
close this file
and we open it you see now it says son
HTML that is my HTML mod so now now I'm
more flexible in you know because now
I'm more comfortable because I know you
know I've been using my mod for years 14
years so now I want to show in browser
okay so anyway I forgot what's a I see
y'all need to set up some other keys so
that is why my current key doesn't work
oh oh yeah I remember CC to eat okay no
CC and let's see what commands
the HTML converter no it's not like
markdown let me show you what it does
okay so for his for example let me show
you what that package does so for
example and that that should be it for
today
one hour in 12 minutes okay so for
example if you have let's say Python
code okay do you call Python or
JavaScript
let's see JavaScript okay javascript is
very popular save it let's open a new
buffer let's let's make it a JavaScript
mod okay Jay is smart okay now let's say
console.log 3 + 4 let's say constant
let's say let X equal to 5 and
console.log X okay so that's JavaScript
code okay so let's magnify so you see
part of it is syntax colored now you
want to show this in your blog with all
the syntax crowing okay let's remove
this line just this time okay so what
you can do now since we have installed
the HTML is mod so what you can do is
you call a command HTML lies then you
can have several choices file region
buffer you know so let's try file but
before we do that we need to save this
file so let's save this file xx star J
yes okay now let's call HTM all lies
fire okay call it and he asks you the
fire okay current file yes yes okay now
if you go to the tired you see that it
created this HTML file now you open it
you see it's all syntax
wait this is wrong
wait let's show'em browser okay
wels URL can Cena sure I have a command
that shows in this in browser but it's
not you know you see my any file
somewhere but so I can't I need to show
this paging browser so what's the Emacs
command browse browse buffer browse you
are our buffer ok there it is you see
now this however it does not have syntax
currying of that why is that it should
color the syntax let's close it let's
let's try python I'm not sure why
because you see there's a color there
but it's not getting it I think maybe
it's because JavaScript because the CSS
or something so let's try a new one
python x equals to 5 let's save it
xx let's save this file as xx dot py ok
so now it's python now let's print x
okay now this is Python code okay now
let's say x equals to a string some
string okay now we have lots of colors
now we call the command now wait
save it first wait save it
code a command HTML lies file ok yes
this file now go to the directory it
generated this HTML file now we open it
this is bad they didn't you see they are
not coloring correctly for some reason
they are not coloring correctly because
they are not putting span tags there
should be spent span tags on this that's
the purpose of that package you prefer
MD no you know you got the you got idea
wrong because you haven't seen my you
know my actual setup we can we can do
that if we switch to my actual setup you
can see the power let me show you then
that will be it for today okay
so for example we go to know no you know
no Emacs it's better than MD ok so let's
for example so this is the so let's wrap
up wrap wrap up for today so this is the
Emacs in it we created today everything
we created today so but however let's
let's turn off desktop mod desk top mod
wait save this
okay so now let's you know so this is
today so let's rename it new okay now
let's put this is my previous setup my
you know before we begin today so let's
rename it back to Emacs T so this
directory this is my you know that my
original set up now if we start Emacs
your see wait right
this is still wrong oh yeah not now it's
right so you can see then you can see
you know everything my old set up it's
like thousands of thousands tens of
thousands stuff so now if we start we
start Emacs
okay let's quit Emacs save a brief no
and let's restart then you will see the
the power of that thing that HTML eyes
okay this is my normal setup now let's
go to Kentucky oh okay and today's state
I mean this is today's entry so now for
example if I want to do a Python hold on
a second let me turn that off and
actually let me saw start command log
mod so you can see all my Emacs commands
on the left
okay so now let's I want to do a Python
let's say Python 3 okay now start a new
buffer let's say this is Python 3 print
let's say x equals to some string okay
now let's say print print X okay learn
it because I have everything set up so I
can run it you know now okay now this is
good now close it paste it here show in
browser you see everything is nice and I
want to color it you see it's not
colored now I color it show in browser
you see it's colored this coloring is
stunned by that HTML is mod and you can
do for eMac this you can do for Python
you know let's do JavaScript you can do
JavaScript showing browsers so for
example let x equals 2 let y equals 2
sub ok console.log X Y okay you want it
good and remove it paste it here show in
browser
there it is JavaScript I want to color
it color it showing browser now it's
colored and you can also have least Ruby
and other languages : you know so all
this the syntax coloring part where you
know when I do this
for example let's remove the syntax
Korean you see now there is no syntax
coloring but now I call command the the
command that actually add all those fan
tags is stunned by that HTML mod so
that's you know so like right now I
press okey now look I press a key it
adds all these span tags to color it and
the command I just caught is you can see
here sashimi are we do syntax coloring
and showing browser so now it's all
colored but the
let's go let's let's look at the source
code so so this is a command I just
called saw HTML we do syntax coloring in
buffer now let's go to the source code
so here you are seeing my HTML mod which
we installed today previously so but if
you look at this this is a wrapper okay
so if you look at this it's calling HTML
ice region this calling this command and
that command is written it's here and
that command is actually calling HTML
string so actually it's a bit
complicated so let's go through the
definition so here this command is the
heart of the thing
HTML I stream and it is calling this
this is the key this one hTML is buffer
that command came from that HTML HTML
eyes package we we were installing
before but why is that not showing you
know not doing things correctly it's
it's doing correctly but there's some
minor details you know we have to look I
forgot I don't know what's going on so
okay so that's it good night good night
Alan good night guys Thank You Alan for
the Alan right thank thank you that for
the super chat and thank you guys for
coming and that's it for today bye guys
and tomorrow startup show tomorrow I'm
not sure what time it is it will be we
will be we will see you know you go to
my YouTube YouTube channel you go to the
community community tab you might see my
time thank you guys but but ruvi and
ready bye guys