good morning everyone today is 2019
October 30th Wednesday feel crack 30
minutes after 3:00 in the afternoon San
Francisco time this is Startalk show and
today we are gonna we are going to do
JavaScript and JavaScript loop function
of programming style how do you do a
loop with break now my neighbor my
roommate is playing music services we
didn't hear the first 10 seconds of your
scream we I only started like four okay
the first 10 second okay okay so yeah
maybe next time I wait for 10 seconds no
but usually if you watch the video after
the livestream you see the full thing
good morning Emily good morning Bart
c'mon easy Tron crazy and mad so all you
guys are from Germany Germany except
Emily's from UK and good morning Freddie
so bar says about the gitlab retracting
tracking feature I don't know anything
about that so okay so let's just get on
with today's topic ten watching great so
today we're gonna let's just nits begin
then let's begin today's topic we are
going to talk about in functional
programming style how do you when you
when you need to do a loop but with a
break how do you do that in functional
for me and also we're going to talk
about functional programming map the map
function and some syntactic and semantic
issues of math these both of these
topics are related and we are going to
do it mostly in JavaScript with respect
to JavaScript so let's begin okay so
let's do a let's do age JavaScript end
okay so for example JavaScript good
morning Albert
good morning Kathy you in the middle of
saying time date when it started to show
okay I don't know why is that I think
that only happens in live stream because
if you watch the YouTube video after the
live stream is it seems full so if I do
wait for 5 or 10 seconds then possibly
the YouTube video will be you know the
first 5 seconds will have no sound and
that that is usually annoying and I
think most people will be watching you
know from the YouTube so I don't know
what to do yet we are see so we are
going to do JavaScript so first of all
JavaScript first of all we want to
create an array let's say from 0 to 10
now JavaScript is very annoying there's
no way to do it for but we can let me
show you ok so let's start
start command log mod so for you
those of you Emacs users and stuff like
key users you can see all my Emacs
commands on the Left window so we are
going to create a constant array and we
are going to create such as 0 1 2 1 2 3
we want to create array there is no way
to do that in JavaScript ok so let me
show you so let's say I ain't a a so
that works but if you want to do 1 to
100 you know it's tedious to write it
manually so one way to do it is you can
you can do this constant a2 and what you
do is this is a bit complicated and it's
using javascript ACMA script 2015
feature I'm going to explain so what you
say is I think let's say my keys okay
alright that's how you do it I think
let's try it
change a to doing it it works
wow I see something new here you see
this is new they they they started to
print it in two lines you see I haven't
noticed this before maybe because I
updated not yeah I guess last week or so
I update it not and anyway so this is
how you do a JavaScript array let's just
make it one line so this is how you
generate a way from it's going on
what something is going on here wait I
don't what
something is going on with my Emacs okay
this this this new not is having a
problems what is going on some hope you
learn your region so I try to watch
what is this character space so I'm
trying to copy this line but it does not
copy the whole line okay this WS what
the is this turbulence turnoff
minor mod delete n space
oh the wait that's why space mods so
turn that off and what is this term of
minor mod first four it's okay this is
frustrating today because we don't know
what's going on today this JavaScript
not returns in two lines okay let's make
it one line copy let's see something is
wrong I mean okay this is bad bad start
today hello beautiful people so we so we
are bad start today so we are trying to
generate array in JavaScript so this is
one way to do it okay so actually this
is one way to do it let's just continue
okay and but what if you want to array
let's say form from 10 to 20 now this
method cannot work
now how does this work let me tell you
how this works so arraign I is a
arrey night generates an array of nine
elements each element is zero ok
javascript is very complicated so let me
show you let's go to my JavaScript
tutorial not web dev JavaScript so you
go to my JavaScript tutorial and you go
to JavaScript reference then you go to
array array prototype not a repo type
array array so array here and you go to
array constructor so what is the array
constructor array constructor is just
this function array so I mean this
function array okay now this array
constructor is very complicated
extremely complicated because it depends
on what argument or how many argument
you feed to it the result will be
different for example if you say new
array something that's equivalent to
array itself without using the new this
is not always the case with with
constructors in Java Script so but but
if you for the array function that's the
case new or no new is equivalent
equivalent now if you call array without
any argument it returns on an empty
array now if you put away in where n is
an integer it will generate it will
generate an array with n slots however
each member is undefined
it basically just you know it just
generator away with what you call it
generates you know if you say array for
example if we say array nigh it
generator array of length 9 but each
element is actually there's no element
not even undefined so it's it's so this
for example okay so we are getting into
the extreme comfort
of JavaScript so what I've been trying
to say is that when you call this the
results when you call this for example
the result is different from lots of
problems to today so the result of that
is different from that rather the result
of this is that okay
you have very complex and it and and
these two are different so that is a way
ain't that that's what it returns but if
you call array with multiple elements
then it's it's basically exactly the
same as a literal expression of array so
you see that's the array constructor and
and there's no way to generate array
with element 0 1 2 3 4 so on so but
anyway let's get back to how does this
work
so this generates array with nine
elements
well nice lots each one is not it's not
it's not even field not even undefined
so that is that it generates array of
nice lots then the method key will
return the index of the array so in this
case will be 0 to 0 to 8 so that's this
part then the these three dots is called
spread operator in JavaScript what it
does is that it takes an operand to the
right of it and that operand must be a
iterable in JavaScript
okay now array is a eatable object so so
when you put spread operator to an
iterable object the result is a
basically it turns that eatable object
into a actual array
now in this case arrays already are
iterable so when what happens when you
turn it into an actuary it's your array
so it doesn't make it much sense so
basically the end result of this this
expression is just that okay so how do I
evaluate JavaScript well I have this
function okay so you can you can get it
for my website let's call it let's see
what's the name of the function so the
the function name is this Saru and
current file and it's defined in sawfly
keys and you can also get it on my
website here showing browser so you if
you search for Lanka and file you can
get that command that's how I run
JavaScript in Emacs
you just put this in your init file and
make sure you have not jazz installed
and it will work okay so that is array
so we're getting we are not getting I'm
I'm I'm not doing so first thing
generating array in JavaScript okay
we're gonna get to the thing we want to
talk about in a moment
so array constructor the complex piece
of JavaScript array constructor okay
there is no built-in range function okay
so here are some of the things we
covered so far there is no building
range function in JavaScript okay then
then let's go back to the code here so
there is no building function so what
what do you how do you write a range
function the most efficient way let me
show you the most efficient way to
create a array with range function is by
using a loop surprise so let me show you
how to do that so we're gonna do suppose
we want to we want suppose we want range
3 9 2 let's say 3 22 let's say Mean Max
step we want this function so I'm going
to define this function range so let's
see how we do it
constant arrow function range and the
input should be two values main max step
and the function will be first of all u
[Music]
max minus min divided by step and
math.floor
that is increment that is steps that is
in okay so that is a number of steps you
need to do so actually this is interval
so step is interval and n is the total
of steps you need to do so we create a
loop for of loop so first of all we
define our way constant result empty
array okay then for each number for
actually for loop not four of four
that's right for loop so for loop
no indian-style that's right actually I
don't have my I'm using such of escape
mod and I don't have
I haven't implemented the indentation
yet so that's a pain actually because
the way I wanted is that I want to press
the key and the whole buffer will be
reformatted I don't want manually you
know I can I can intend you know I can I
can like manually in turn each time but
I don't want to do that I want to press
a key the whole block of code such as in
this case the whole thing will be
indented I haven't implemented that yet
so so anyway so constant range we're
going to create a range function to
generate array and constant so this is
number steps so this is result so for I
equal I from zero to less than n I
increment then
for each of that resort that push
push me plus I times step okay that that
is I believe that is what we want to do
we push to the result so when it's done
return result stupid JavaScript with be
okay
so that is function let's try it range
wrench ten to twenty instead in step up
to console.log printed run it arrow
math.floor incorrect F L oh oh oh are
one too many oh one perfect
you see perfect ten twelve fourteen
sixteen eighteen that's what we want you
see this is one shot codeine no trial
and error because you understand the
language well coded one shot you studied
for ten years then you coded one time
and it's correct let's try another
example one to two in step in step of
zero point to run it perfect
well so anyway that's how you generate
our way okay so I actually I have this
written already
you go to JavaScript tutorial web dev
tutorial JavaScript you go to array
understanding JavaScript array array how
to range function to generate array so
there it is now remember we mentioned
this method the first method the problem
with the first method he
is that it can its it it only does you
know it the it begin with you cannot
specify starting number and you know
ending you cannot specify a wrench you
know can you specify a in turbo you can
only say you know you will start from 0
and integer only so therefore that's why
you need to write a function in
JavaScript JavaScript sucks in so many
ways and this is this is one way it
sucks it does not have a building
function to be other array so typically
in web programming community you have
you know low - no - has a function do
that you load other libraries like 5
lines for example for example I I have
this code now I'm going to push this to
NPM and other people's can download my
library to generate a rape so anyway
that's that's a rate range okay that's
how you do it so the complexity so hold
on a second so the complexity of
JavaScript let me copy let me cut that
okay so let me put the JavaScript code
paste it here color it showing browser
so we cover this generating array in
JavaScript they are you know there's no
building function and we covered the
JavaScript the complexities of
JavaScript array constructor you know
it's it's it's very bad then we covered
know billion function - yeah so we cover
that okay let's get on to the next
problem
the next problem we want to do is
the next problem we want to do is we are
talking about loop so the question is
typically when you want you want to do a
loop for example we have a loop here we
have a for each loop but if you are
writing a functional programming style
that's not what you want you rather want
you you don't want to you know do the
increment you know this this Inc you
know these minor steps you want to Co a
function that do them in one shot such
as map however there is a problem let's
show the problem okay so that's D D D D
D D that three that DV that so that us
we want to do a loop and okay first of
all range let's say zero to ten
okay console.log
so that's what we want wait this is
spooking me I don't understand there is
something wrong here that
command log mod a brief softride keys
what is his summation process okay
anyway so so we are creating a range
from zero to ten actually this should be
first one math.floor actually that may
not be right
yeah there is there is something wrong
with the for some reason I cannot copy
them I mean this is something with my
Emacs here let's quit Emacs it start
Emacs oh because is it because I'm in
Emacs 26.3 I just upgraded like
yesterday okay so let's check some
so what is that that's Haskell I was
safe or let in I plus first oh yeah I
got it wrong wait I forgot know what I
don't know I just you know this this
code is solid okay whatever I code it
there this code minus or equal to total
steps yeah it should be minus or equal
to total steps okay I need to relax I'm
not doing something is I'm not doing
something right something is wrong here
but let's just look at do I still have
the problem of copy paste yes I still
have the problem of that so let's quit
let's switch switch to Emacs old version
twenty six point two and one twenty six
point three let's see if that happens
again you see the problem is that I have
a key let's try it
okay so magnify run it okay it looks
like same problem looks like this is a
Java this is not jeaious of great
problem you see what happens is that
normally let's let's try this five okay
oh you see normally the whole thing will
be in one line but for some reason
because maybe because my not jeaious
upgrade or maybe because my Emacs update
now it becomes two lines okay that's
fine but we can make it one into one
line and now I want to copy your line
copy this line saw start command log mod
okay so to copy this line I normally
press a key I press a key Sarkozy Lionel
region the whole line should be copied
but that's not the case
you see if I paste here I got just that
that's incorrect so apparently it
depends where is my cursor now I copy
the it now I paste it it's easy it's
wrong so let's try it again
copy paste you see it's supposed to copy
the whole line but I have no idea what
what is going on so that is frustrating
something I have to figure out something
in Emacs let's see did I modify my code
by mistake stock up here on your region
I don't think so and you know that is
why I'm trying to find out turn on turn
on the show space white space mod let's
compact the line copy again it does is
not working okay let's let's look at
message buffer to see if are we getting
any errors let's copy again copy the
line you see if you see if I move the
cursor anywhere I can press a key to
copy your line and I can paste you got
the full line I can leave from if my
cursor is here I press a
to copy the line and I paste it's a full
line but when Wayne's over here I copy
the line something is wrong there you
see I go back here I paste I don't get
the full thing copy the line okay so
this talk is good should should I
continue fixing this problem the time to
switch two years code I don't know what
the is going on with this so if I
copy the whole buffer you see that works
now maybe it's because I'm in different
ma let's switch to text mod okay
magnify copy that I you see still
doesn't work what is this character coma
what is this character called 1:46
period what is this character space
what is this character copy is a copy
this is wrong copy
very annoying
I think definitely something wrong with
it okay let's let's go on then let me
get a drink and let's go on this and
let's keep going on it's let's read the
comments
you are in the middle of saying time
date when he started to show okay Kathy
would you be nice everyone hello
beautiful are we doing the JavaScript
today yes kind of how are you evaluating
a JavaScript okay sounds like it's not
that evaluated yes so all the window
blah probably won't work the same but
good for server-side and just JavaScript
language stuff signature no intense
style equivalent to go format maybe you
can review competing options yes he I
want something similar to go format I
just press a button it formats the whole
thing I need to write that I haven't
done that yet so is this defining range
function a place where for loop is
needed and functional programming map
stuff isn't prepared preferred for
JavaScript least yes actually
okay let's let me get down you know I
need to focus for some reason I'm not
doing well today am not relaxed or
something so today's topic we are we are
talking about that you know we are
talking about range function for array
copy
did I have that I don't have it okay so
let's go back hold on second yeah no way
is it tok-san talkshow okay let's get
the gate down get on to the talk show so
so magnet this will make it one buffer
magnify constructor and range function
for array okay so so we are talking
about functional issues with functional
programming related to loop okay things
like for each and map function basically
the question is if you want to do loop
for example a for loop you have array
you have a list of numbers you want to
find the first let's say even number you
know you have a list of random integers
you want to find the first even number
once you find it stop
so how do you do that you know typically
when you use a loop you can just you
know for each you know and once you find
that you you break you know there's a
break keyword for loop but that's not
functional programming because in
functional programming you prefer you
want to do everything with a function
not for the for loop is not a function
it's like doing it's like a special
syntax for particular control you know
the branch control like do this if this
then that you know you jump around you
know then you repeat you in functional
programming you don't want to do that
functional programming everything is a
function without side-effect just Co
function so that's what you want but
however when you want to do a loop you
want to find the first element then you
want to break how do you do that you
don't want to use a map because if you
use a map it's going to continue to map
the whole array so so that is a topic we
that that is the first topic we are
going to talk about and we are going to
use JavaScript as an example but this is
actually a issue in other languages
because basically except Haskell
I don't know how haskell do it how do
you
do it hostage justine how do you do in
Haskell when you want to do when you
have a you know like array or something
at least you you you want to apply a
function you know you once you find
something is true you want to break you
don't want to continue to save you know
to make it you don't want to waste a
cycle you know to keep because you
already found it you want to break it
how do you do that in Eska I don't know
so just think maybe do you know so but
in general in in almost all the
languages I know that suppose functional
programming there is no way there is
basically no way but there's one way you
know there is a way in JavaScript it's
but it's very convoluted rather you do
not want to use it so so basically the
what I'm saying is that when you are
doing functional programming you know
this JavaScript like semi functional
languages even even this yes even even
in this you have to you still have to
like to loop some kind of so let me show
you how did how to do that so but why
are we talking about generating array in
JavaScript because first of all we need
a way that's you know by I'm just
mentioning that on the side javascript
is a suck is a language that sucks
it does not have a building range
function there therefore you have to
write it so that is what I'm showing in
a first phase before we show we talked
about the loop with break in functional
style so so we are talking about you
know how do you write a range function
now the writing or range function in
JavaScript is very interesting and
related to our topic as well because we
have shown that in JavaScript there is
no way there's no range function P odine
the only kind of close way to do it is
is this we explained how that works and
that relies on JavaScript eggman script
2015 and this in fact this is very
a convoluted concept because you are
using you are coding or array
constructor giving it an argument it
does not generate actually generate
array with nine elements where each
element let's say is undefined or zero
it's actually not that it just generates
an array with nice slots and each
element is not it's not it's not field
let's say it's not field because it's
different from the from the literal
value undefined so like I would like we
mentioned before you if you have you
know if you say array night it just you
just got an array of nine slots where
each element there is no element like
you don't say there's an element there's
just array with nice slots this is
different from an array with my element
where each one is the value undefined so
so this is an extreme one of the extreme
complexity of JavaScript okay so that is
that is a constructor array night it
returns array with nice thoughts then
you say you call the you you call this
method keys it returns basically returns
the index of the array so in this case
it returns 0 0 1 2 3 4 9 you know 0 to 9
it does not actually return an array it
returns a it returns a iterable object
so in japanese so what is the trouble in
JavaScript it's very very complicated ok
if you like to know you can read my
tutorial about it report it iterables
in and iterable object and iterators so
you go to javascript in depth all the
way to the bottom you have first of all
you need to understand what's the
interface in javascript which is
completely different from java python ok
it's not it's not like java python
interface you know in javascript
so anyway you have each robo and you
have iterator you have those kind of
things so anyway so the key the key
method of array the keys method it
returns a each horrible object it's not
that way okay
it's an iterable object such that each
element is the index of the array so
basically it's like zero to nine so once
you gotta eat rubber but what you really
want is an actual rate so then you use
this spread operator okay so you can see
spread operator this article spread out
spread operator will take the iterable
and turn that into a actual array kind
of so so this so this single line this
single expression by itself takes I
would say if you really want to
understand it completely will take you a
few few hours just to understand that
and that and that returns I turned on
safari by mistake
so this expression you know with all its
complexities it just returned an array
you know zero zero to eight of nine
elements but javascript do not have you
know if you want a range to be different
you cannot do that therefore you need to
write a range function now when you
write a range function so how do you do
you know how do you do how do you write
a range functions if javascript does not
have a built-in range function okay we
can write one by loop so this is this is
related to what we are the our main
topic about using math to do a loop so
when we write a range function in
JavaScript notice that we are using a
for loop you know it works right here
you know we are using a for loop T and
it works but however if you are a
functional programmer you know you don't
want for oops right you want to avoid
Loup so how do you do that there is no
way okay there's basically no way it's
like impossible well it's it's possible
because it's possible but but any
solution that's not using a for loop
will be very inefficient for example
this expression by itself is pretty
inefficient because you are generating a
array of empty slots then you are
applying these keys to to get the
indexes you know then you are turning
the whole thing into a actual array with
using the spread operator so this
expression by itself is rather fairly
inefficient you know and it's
incomprehensible and the semantics is
also convoluted so this is one reason
this is one one of the like hundreds you
know ten big reasons one of the reason
that javascript is very very very
convoluted bad language but anyway let's
get back to how do you write a range
function so you write a range a function
like that but however it's using a for
loop so as a functional programmer you
don't want that so how do you do that
basically there is no way any functional
programming method to generate to write
to create a range function will be much
more inefficient let me show you an
example okay so let's let's try to write
another function that does functional
programming using the functional
programming to generate a range for
example we can say so we define constant
function range to okay we okay so mean
max step like before and what we want
here is we want functional programming
so we don't want for loop so how do you
do that
okay so just like before we call array
we need okay let's try this we need this
number like how many items are there so
we do array n items then that returns
that returns it's impossible actually
you see that returns it doesn't you know
it that returns array without any
element it just have that number of
slots because I was thinking of doing a
map so once you have a ray you can map a
function to it for example map so map
arrow function then we can say X plus X
me
it wait wait this should be actually
something like that and we need to find
out I we can do that but anyway the this
map will not work because because this
thing is actually not it's array within
slots but there's no element you cannot
map to it why because we can try so
create a new JavaScript save it X X X
dot JavaScript okay today's date you
know we can we can try this you you are
see why this does not work let's say 5
let's say map X first one okay now let's
say console.log let's print it you see
arrow what's the error because syntax
arrow
okay missing X wait missing X oh you
you're the semicolon semicolon is
another major problem in JavaScript so
let's do it again
you are net you see the result is five
empty items why is that because because
this array 5 returns array with five
slots however each slot each member is
is is not a thing is not even a element
at all you just have five potential
slots so it's it's it's not undefined
either so so actually
you see so you cannot you cannot use a
map to these things so that's that is a
problem so back to the question so how
do you write a function arrange function
with in a functional programming style
without using loop basically you cannot
like impossible in JavaScript so that
concludes hot you know one that topic so
let me see the comments do you have a
good way to do that about what Freddie
says okay so time to switch to vs code
hello beautiful people disagree you are
doing well today broken environment is
not your fault
thank you very says I have a basic
question I want to call a function which
creates a dictionary with many nested
values dictionary with many nested
values with strings arrays act in it but
I also want to specify in a function of
few values for some of the values of the
dick like what do you mean I guess this
is hard to know what you mean I mean
it's hard to explain but all the rest
get a default value okay so
so you want to create Indic you want to
create basically maybe let me try if
this is what you want you in JavaScript
you want to create a dictionary
javascript does not have a dictionary
okay so what do you mean is either
object you know the JavaScript object
which is a pair of things disappear
collection pairs or you want to use
JavaScript map object so here is another
extreme complexity of JavaScript so
normally when you when you want a
collection of pairs like key value pairs
typically you use a JavaScript object
you know like this cat dog you know this
is a JavaScript object key value pairs
but however object is very very
problematic it's not in a beginning it's
not designed to be a dictionary it's not
designed to be your hash table you know
Dictionary Python code dictionary ruby
code hash table per host hash table java
code map but it's the same idea it's
basically an ordered list of key value
pairs okay so in JavaScript you can the
JavaScript object represent that but but
it's it's not designed to be that
however in ACMA script 2015 you have a
real hash table they call it map so I
have a tutorial here so this is the map
object so JavaScript code a map object
so this object is a special object that
is designed to to to to represent a
collection of key value pairs like
pythons dictionary rubies hash table
Chavez map or you know things like that
so so
javascript also could cause it a map so
you can create a map and so on and what
and your question is so you want
basically you as I think you are saying
you want to create a map in JavaScript
such that such that you want to specify
some of the keys while others
the keys are undefined like it takes a
default key well I'm not sure exactly
what you mean and you know in English or
in a map or hash table or dictionary the
keys must be or unique so I'm not sure
what what do you mean but anyway I think
I should continue with what we are doing
today so I would want ideally the
initialization of the dictionary with
default values and then on intuition of
the key value pairs of the dictionary
which might be quite nested and includes
even a race like I don't see what you
mean like what do you mean an iteration
of the key value pairs do you have a
good way yeah I you know in this kind of
thing is it
I don't think I can understand because
you know that's too short so the new
language says arrays are iterable but
there are many other building objects
that are iterable as well not many not
many but the iterable
objects in JavaScript are array array
map set
that's about it so if we go to eat robo
purpose of each Robo what is eatable
object and the standard eatable object
stream oh yeah I missed the string
string array set map that is that is it
you can rain I feel and then iterate oh
jeez that is a good answer
thank you hello beautiful people that
they that that is the best answer today
best comment you are right yeah
Sophie Oh Theo is a fear is Eggman
script 2015 stuff or was it 2016 so
that's a great idea
so let's let's try it let's try that
great idea thank you beautiful people
feel right let's try feel zero yeah so
once you feel it let's see if I I do
have a let's see JavaScript JavaScript
reference array you know we are so
behind from our main topic today which
is about map and every you know it
that's a easy subject for me to talk
about but but I want to go with the
extra step I thought you know why not
let's just cover about how to how to
write a range function in JavaScript and
that we can have an hour and not done
yet okay but but it's interesting stuff
I hope so let's see array array field
yeah we want to know about the field
function there it is indeed fat
fantastic so you that's a great answer
thank you so much in fact this is a
great answer that actually are we oh I
think I think I will modify my tutorial
for the generating very possibly so
anyway so and so you
and do this so I let's try so hello
beautiful people says feel feel a value
of okay so let's say feel zero start
index in index we don't care we want to
feel the whole thing so once once you
feel it then you can map then you can
map
I think map takes a third argument which
is rarely used we and we need that
because we need the index of the array
so so let's see
okay so feel and then map so let's go to
map javascript reference array prototype
map map okay so map the function the
function takes three arguments and
ailment current index in my array okay
so here is what we do so we we need a
function here arrow function so the
current element and the current index
okay so what how we want to feel it we
want to so for each element will be I
press weight will be X plus I times step
I think that work let's hope that it it
does so this we need a return value so a
parentheses not square bracket not not a
curly bracket so that I hope we'll walk
this will be just return
okay let's let's hope so let's nits
let's try it
range okay so copy copy paste the whole
range to range to Burnett
wait range 2 1 2 3 4 we are printing
four things 1 2 3 4 5 wait news 5 things
here what's going on
so console.log ok let's not print that
run it again ok there is yeah so it
works I think it works
we just need to modify this a bit oh
yeah we forgot to add ad me run it again
perfect so actually let's rearrange this
a bit doing it again
perfect so that is fantastic that that
is that is fantastic today I so I need
to so this is so this is a functional
way to write a range function in
JavaScript but it is it it is I know I
know for sure it is slower than this one
I know for sure so okay so that that
finishes one topic let's get on to the
loop in the map so let's see so you can
use a array for each or whatever
Danielle says a function that's based
that basically takes on a starting index
in any index then return a list of all
integers from start to end so language
done in array from
so Daniel solution array that foam
which so is it radon from I don't know
map scene sets now so a recursive range
function where you only needs to build
yes thank you
I mean object basically give me default
object level one so the question answer
to Fred's question we can do that but
it's probably getting complicated let me
finish
today's topic so the news is so happy to
help so gotta go okay
Helen so okay so how long we've been
talking God today is so bad it I feel so
bad so anyway so we got week now we got
a rave range function and let's let's
let's do loop then let's do a loop so
let's do a loop so we got our range
function let's let's just use this one
for now actually is just use that
so we want what we want is we want to
that that multiple lines annoying annoys
me because I failed something is wrong
with it you see there is definitely
something semantic going on with this
expression because because let's try
this oh no wait it's the same okay so
anyway so we got a array we want to
define a function we want to we want to
get the first even number when when it's
true then stop it okay so let's define a
function constant arrow function even is
even okay so if if X mod 2 equals to 0
now I don't know how do you say how do
you say mod in JavaScript
let's look javascript basics and the
JavaScript arithmetics stream methods
stream stream methods with medic
operators
power negation their remainder operator
so so what you want is that so if that
returns 0 then return actually return we
want to return the index ok
so return the element and the index and
wait it should return true whole thing
is good so actually if expression so
so that's our function so if X divided
by two is zero returns true otherwise
return false so this is is even function
so let's try is even for true that's
good so that works now we want to write
a loop for for loop okay x equals two
less than that if is even a - array I is
true then console.log
okay that should print or even numbers
in array let's write on it so 0 2 4 6 8
that's correct
so but this is using a loop we don't
want that okay so wait so if if it's
even then print it then break okay we
don't want we just want to find the
first one and the way when we found it
we want to stop so ran it zero so zero
is the first one we found it we break so
this is how you do it and this is using
a loop not functional programming style
but however we want to do a functional
form in style so so the way we do that
is you can use a two every so every we
are apply a function to each element in
our array in turn so if this function
returns true for all of them then the
result of the every is true if there is
some value that's false then the return
value is false so basically every make
sure that every value if you apply the
function to every value in array it must
be all true the first time is this
element that's that's not true
basically we will stop computing here
you know the rest of it so you can so so
you can as a side-effect of the
evaluating order of every function you
can abuse it as to emulate the behavior
of for which break you see you see every
by itself is a logical function
it just makes sure you know if every if
if this function applied to all elements
of the array is true then it returns
true however there's a side-effect it
does this evaluation in order so the
first time you know when it sees a
element that's F returns false it will
stop computing you stop computing the
rest
of the elements so that is a side effect
so therefore we can abuse it to do what
we want you know instead of using a loop
so let's do it so so every so we want to
write a function here arrow function
arrow function so X here so the and the
function is actually the function it
just is even okay
that's it so we can console.log print
that work it returns force because some
element are force the actually we need
to this is this is getting complicated
you see what we want to do we I want to
show you I want to demonstrate what
every is doing in order to do that
actually so let's let's do that okay so
let's me we need a arrow function here
okay so every you need a function so the
function will be like that so let's
let's do that so the function X if X
divided by 2 where the remainder is 0
then you say true then you return true
and also you want to you cannot use if
expression JavaScript is so complicated
you cannot use the expression you have
to use the if statement so let's do that
so if X is even then you you print X
then you return X otherwise you return
false okay return false this is kind of
very complicated expression JavaScript
functional programming in JavaScript
okay so here is our function now let's
try to make it more readable
so there there it is so here is our
function this function it takes one
argument so if it's even we print it
first then we return it we return
actually we return true we need to
return true otherwise we return false so
we are calling these yeah let's do it
let's see so there you go you see it did
not go through every element in our
array because otherwise it would have
printed 0 1 2 3 4 and so on it didn't
print so it simply prints 0 and returned
force so that is how you use how you
abuse the evaluation order specification
of the function every to simulate to
emulate a functional programming style
of doing a loop and break without
actually having a loop in break and this
is very problematic because as we as you
can see here the for loop is actually
much simpler to understand because
JavaScript got lots of problems even
though it's supposed functional
programming but you can see the syntax
is you know on a whole considered as a
whole is very complicated you know with
the semicolon you know it's unlike a
programming language that is designed
for functional programming such as Lisp
Mathematica API has cow those you know
you use functional programming you can
understand it due to the syntax but in
JavaScript you got things like this you
know if the whole thing is one in one
line it's it's impossible to read but
anyway so here is a way to avoid using
loop with break in kind of a functional
programming style but not really because
same tactically
it is like functional programming
because you have you know you have array
you have a method which is a function
then you have another function here you
know it looks syntactically
syntactically it looks like a functional
programming but actually it's not
because you are you are actually abusing
the spec for the evaluation order of the
every function so that that is kind of
the thing I want to say about this so so
we show two things we I showed you know
how you can emulate loop with break in a
functional form in style in JavaScript
so that's how you do it but however I
also showed several I want to you know
III in my opinion also showed that
javascript is very convoluted in many
ways one of the ways the syntax you know
once you're writing a functional style
it's hard to read you know is it's hard
to read what what what what this thing
is and also we I'm talking about we are
we are able to do this because we are
abusing the evaluation order of the
every function that's how we can achieve
this you know it's because the the
moment it finds something force it stops
evaluating the rest of it because you
already know the final result should be
force so we are abusing the evaluation
oder so when you have things like that
such as the every function that means
that every function has side effect it's
not truly a functional thing so we are
just so there's a lot of complexities
going on so in the end I would not
recommend you you know when you want a
loop with break you just do doop with
break you don't do this for in every
yes it's it's called short circuit
circuiting exactly it's it's called
short circuiting that's what people call
it so anyway so that I've you know that
completes the the kind of main topic I
want to talk about and this is also
related to the let's copy it okay so
let's copy yet let's copy it put it here
color syntax it so that covered you know
the thing I want to talk about the the
every you know every you can do that you
know use every other loop with break and
by the way there's also you know
normally if you want to do functional
programming of a loop you can use for
each you know that's like you know let's
like a loop but in a functional
programming style you can use for each
but however for each does not allows you
to break the loop he does not have a
optional you know parameter where you
can putting a function whenever that
function returns force stop the for each
that would be a part more proper way to
have the loop with break functionality
in a functional style so the proper way
for JavaScript to go is actually for the
for each function to have a optional
argument it should be a function that
returns true or false
you know whenever it returns true or you
know whenever it returns false that the
for each should stop that is a proper
way but since it does not so we are
using you know we are using for every to
emulate loop with a break or we can also
use some where is it some some is just
like every you know when you when you
have every the function must return true
for every element
for some is that every element must
return force you know as long as you
know some is true he stops he's kind of
the opposite so we can also use use we
can also use some to emulate loop with
break so that finished one topic and you
know so these things you know what I
want to show today you see these things
are these many issues are complex and
related because you see we are trying to
do functional style and we are trying to
avoid loop but then there's the issue of
how do you do something that is a loop
but you want to break so that is a
problem and when talking about this
problem it comes to you know some issues
comes to our mind that is you know
issues like you are you know there's
issues like evaluation order of a
function you see such as this every
function you see the evaluation order
does not really change the spit you know
you know the semantics the meaning of
what every function do because the every
method is simply returned true if a
function is returns true for every
element so it does not necessarily need
to stop when you reach a element that's
false the reason it stops is like
short-circuit you know it just saved
time you know since it already know the
result final resort is force it needs
not to continue but however the very
fact you have this specification order
you know the the space you know
specifying order that's cool sub
something else that's because the moment
you have this you know order thing
evaluation order thing which does not
change the meaning of the
function the mathematical meaning of a
function it rather it's about kind of
computing efficiency issue so the moment
a programming language suspect specified
this kind of evaluation order and
shortcut then something funny comes up
that is we can we can a beauty we can
kind of abuse this every function to
emulate kind of a functional programming
style of a loop with rake you see so
what I'm trying to do you see my
intention about this topic today's topic
is about is about these complexities
that comes up this this rather
non-trivial subtle complexities so
that's you know that's that's the first
part about you know using you know every
to emulate loop with break and this
applies to many other languages as well
and you know I think you can it applies
to Python like you can think about how
Python does it how other list I mean
even this typically they don't support
they don't support you know loop with
break in a functional style so for
example in eMac this to do that you
simply do a while loop
okay it becomes becomes very idiotic you
just do a while loop you know and in so
the question I don't know how haskell
does it so just a nice gun but otherwise
justing maybe did he answer
he can give he can tell us how how ask
i'll do it well I ain't ask I don't
think the problem even comes up because
you if you want to find something you
know you know array the you you want to
find the first item and stop I think has
cow has like ways to you don't even you
know you don't write loops pay anyway so
so this problem as far as I know it's a
problem in other languages such as
Python PHP
email is for sure this language I know
for sure you got this problem and also
in scheme disp you got these problems
you know whenever you want to break a
loop you see in our example we are using
this very simple example of even you
know if we if a number is even we want
to break but in real life it's it may
not be that simple the function may have
to check the database or maybe you know
or each element in the array is actually
a window object or geometry you know a
polygon somewhere you want to find you
know then your function is not simply
you know check if that number is true
even or odd but your function is
checking some qualities about polygons
above that you know math complicated
math object or window object or whatever
so in real life this problem comes up
you know you want a break with Lu you
want a loop with a break so that
concludes that thing now the things
related to that thing I want to talk
about is this the syntactic and semantic
difference of map function I'm about
done in five minutes I can finish
so this syntactic and semantic
difference of map function so what I'm
talking about you can read this article
but I can but we already kind of covered
that already because you can see when we
try to use functional programming style
to emulate loop with break we end up
with this solution you know using every
so on a surface the code looks like
functional programming but actually it's
not because first of all every has a
side-effect you know it stops it stops
something waiting wait you know found
the element that's false that's not
functional that's not pure functional
okay then we are using with so I mean so
the
so the thing is on a surface
syntactically it looks like functional
programming but not semantics
semantically and also the reason these
code works is that because every has
this you know specification about when
to stop computing which is not part of
the functional specification because as
far as the functional specification is
that input and output remember that's
functional programming so every is a
function so the input is array and a
function right and the output is that is
either true or false
if the functional applied to every
element is all true they returns true
otherwise it returns false you see
that's the function of spec for every
but however it also has this
computational you know evaluation order
thing which has nothing to do with the
functional spec you know the
input-output spec but rather is about
kind of efficiency of a computing so you
see on one hand this the whole thing
looks like syntactically functional but
semantically is not and it involves this
complicated thing so that that is when
so when you understand that then you
look at the map function the map
function has exactly the same problem
exactly the same problem because map
function so functionally speaking you
know in a functional programming point
of view the function of the map
specification is that the input is a
function in the list okay in JavaScript
it's array okay so function in the list
array that's the input the output is a
is another list where each element is
the function applied to every each
element of the array of the list okay so
that's the input and output that's the
functional perspective you know input
output of the map function but however
just like the every function the map
function has a
evaluation strategy evaluation odor
specification in the language for
example we are seeing the JavaScript
suspect the egg mod 2015 spec for the
map function essentially you know it's
very complicated to read but essentially
it's it tells you that in order to
implement JavaScript map correctly if
you want to pass you know JavaScript
standard you actually are doing a loop
you see you can see the last line is
says increased K by Y by one so it's
telling you that when you implement map
in JavaScript you have to go by order
like like apply F to the first element
apply F to the sacrament you have to do
that by order so what is a consequence
of saying that because remember first
let me repeat the functional
specification of the map function is
that you take a list you'd have to a
function that's the input the output is
the is the list where each element is a
function applied to every element okay
that's the input and output but however
because of practical computation the
spec says you need to do this by order
now they know there is a very important
subtleties just like the every case you
know the you know the case we talked
about before there's an important
consequence that consequence is that the
consequence is that if your function
that that is an input to map if that
function does not have side effect then
the order does not matter okay but
however if your function has side effect
then this spec says that it has to
follow order then it has significant
consequences because because then if you
don't follow order that we saw will be
different so you see what I mean
so I don't know I don't know what if I'm
making too much sense today so maybe
maybe that's it for today let me read
the comments
so sohbats do you think I'm do it like
am I making sense or maybe if I'm going
too slow like being repetitive yeah so
some and every young empty array are
weird
so javascript has tons of these problems
really turned some of this one but
javascript is truly bad fredy says yes
if this stuff is in one line it really
makes it hard to read yes and yes this
is kind of code by tenfold code by a
tenfold that I am dealing right now left
behind by my superiors okay given
finding the first element passing tests
you can use some array don't find some
array don't find yes that yes that's
true
yeah hello beautiful people yeah that
that is true but I'm trying to you know
I'm trying to show an example about this
syntactic and semantic issue so you see
I find this interesting because nobody
when we talk about functional
programming you know we think of you
know you know it's like what do you mean
by functional programming but I hope you
know what I find very interesting is
that you see we have this fairly very
complex subtleties you know going on
because this this on one hand you truly
it just looks like functional you almost
like even if you read you know
functional JavaScript book you know they
tell you oh how to do functional form in
JavaScript you know purely functional
programming you know Facebook has
functional forming libraries and so on
you see this kind of thing but this
there's you should I don't yeah usually
they don't talk about I don't think so
they
there is a complex issues beneath about
this evaluation order so if we continue
with our article about the map with a
consequence so the next issue so so for
example we showed JavaScript the spec
says that the map must execute by
following order you know this is kind of
you know the spec says that if you want
to create a JavaScript standard
compliant implementation you have to do
that now at least let's look at least
example now this is well known as a
functional programming language now in
emag list look at what it says
you see it says map car so map car is
map you know in this new code map car it
says apply function to each element of
sequence in turn and return a list of
the results you see it says in turn
so in eMac this even in emag B's it also
specifies that the map function must you
know follow the order must apply the
first one first apply the second first
even though you know from a functional
programming point of view the map
function doesn't really care about odor
because as long as your function is does
not have side effect
side effects such as changing a global
variable or changing the list you are
mapping to like on the fly
that's very bad or not C and the C type
c plus first type of programmers they
like to do that because that's why i
don't I never like those you know low
level stuff they do that because they
they are trying to get you know
efficiency to apply tricks you know to
get you know CPU memory they know how
they are organized they trying to make
it faster anyway so you see even list
language they specify that you the map
function applying order so what is a
consequence the consequence of the spec
is that
so the first question we can ask is that
whether a language spec let's say you
are creating a language you are all you
know your favorite language when you
have a map function should you specify
what order it applies should you that is
the open question you know when you
design a question this question will
come up this is going to be one over the
question should your map function
specified the application oder now we
can think about so so so the answer is
whether yes or no but what are the
consequences you know the thing is that
if the function to the map has no side
effect then the order does not matter
okay you don't have to specify older
because doesn't matter which order the
result will always be be the same if the
function to map is you know without side
effect it's a pure function like a
NASCAR however if the if your function
possibly may or may not you know it
cannot guarantee it doesn't have side
effect then the older really matters you
need to specify your order and the
simplest order is you know just apply
the first one first so this so you got
this issue here you got this issue you
know design issue language issue
language design issue and and it's a
problem because because so so why do you
you know so okay if your function may
have side effect then you want older but
when you have older then you got a
problem because okay first of all let me
talk about what what is the advantage of
not specifying order like what is a
advantage if your function is always
pure function to the map that has great
advantages because if your function to
map is not has not side effect that
means you can apply parallel computing
the compiler can take your code it
cannot
if you know if you have array of 1,000
items let's say 1 billion items and you
need to apply map a function to each one
of them so if the function is pure you
know no side effect then you can do
parallel computing you know for example
at Google you can have you can apply if
to you know using 1000 processors you
know 1 billion processors it's at the
same time you know you'll just walk
because they have no side effect so that
is a advantage so if your language do
not specify order it kind of yeah
there's another complication is that if
your language do not actually specify an
order it kind of forced the programmer
to always have a function that does not
have side effect because once you have a
side effect and the language spec does
not guarantee an order then your result
will be arbitrarily different each time
you run because so that that is when you
kind of forced programmer to not a user
function that has side effect this is in
fact true for scheme this specification
for a long time I'd I don't know what's
the situation now you know scheme safe
specification their functions do not
specify a evaluation order as far as if
I remember because this evaluation order
is very interesting we mentioned today
this is the main topic today because
it's like if you don't specify on order
you are if you specify order you
are also that's that's the case
because the if you don't specify order
then then then then that means you know
you want your function to be pure
functions no side effect then the other
question is and how do you enforce in
your language how do you enforce that
function do not have side effect you
know if you have a language like has cow
okay mo you know F sharp strongly typed
functional farming language then you can
do that okay it's already part of the
language but in the case of JavaScript
Python Ruby PHP you got a problem or
Java or possibly Java and C++ you know
you got a problem because how do you
know you got a problem of how do you
enforce how do you how does a compiler
know that the function does not have
side effect so things like that so it's
very interesting so anyway that that's
that's what I want to talk about today
so let's see any chance to in a bit
earlier for my talk show I don't know
that's that's always a problem I'll try
it okay so yeah so that's it for today
thank you guys for watching any more
comments we shut down in one minute yeah
we shutting down in one minute guys so
any questions about that
let me read the comments I so many
comments today and
I haven't been reading them
okay so that's it for today I think
tomorrow maybe we do eMac this we
haven't done that for a while and
Freddie your question you need to
specify it out like actually Freddie
like yeah Freddie I think your question
is too complicated because give me
default object level 1 t4 yeah I don't
you know it's I think it's you need to
specify it out because it's you know
it's form program itself is often quite
complicated you have to write a lot text
to understand you know what is mint yeah
I don't really know what you mean by the
defaults
yeah okay okay thank you guys bye guys