good morning good evening everyone
welcome to another episode of sound talk
show start coding EAC this today so if
you are here say hi if you are not here
skip at skip around and play at 1.5
speed so we're going to do emac this
coding okay so we're going to write a
command that increment digits let me
show you hello uh oh it's 11:00 so let
let me see let's see uh increment digit
okay so can you see my screen let's stop
that stop
that okay
so yeah you can see my screen okay so
let's here is a digit number three and
uh the pink window shows all my command
calls and uh keystrokes so key strokes
on the left command name on the right
you can search the command name on the
web you'll probably find the source code
on my website okay so for example I want
to delete this so for example show this
in browser so you got the URL there so
that is you know let you know let me
show you press a key that's select
element you see or you know so I can uh
for example if my cluer is here select
the element that's link select again
that's the list item select again that's
a you URL Ur which is a unordered list
which correspond to this you know
YouTube link so for example my C is here
I press the key that's smart delete and
that the whole URL is I mean the whole
unorder list is going
undo so anyway so that's a pink window
command names and keystroke on the left
I'm using Sly
Keys okay you you can get it for free
it's the most efficient key binding
system so here is the source code here
is a web page starfly Keys the most
efficient key binding system for emac so
that means if you are a
coder uh you can use this and use emac
that'll be more efficient than anything
than Vim than VSS code or what have you
meaning less keystrokes to do the same
thing okay so essentially it's a it's a
set of key binding designed like uh
model system more efficient than
Vim less key strokes to do the same
thing for mostly programmers or writers
okay but you have to learn emac
emac okay so s Keys that's what I'm
using I'm using V keyboard layout and uh
let's begin coding okay let's uh start
coding so let's do a demo so you see
this a number three I want to increase
it call the command you can see s
increment number there now it becomes
four then I can press up Arrow key or
hold it to increase the number you see
or down arrow to decrease it you see and
it it'll go into negative okay okay into
it into that behavior which is not good
but anyway increase decrease okay so
that is is the command for example let
me try another command let me try again
on a different number so this is the
date you can see the command insert date
and you can insert a variety of date
formats so you do that
by uh control U first then do it then
you'll ask you what kind of um date you
want let's see all
digits okay then you got this 2020 5 0 1
23rd 18 means 18:00 military style 6:00
p.m. 7 Minutes 51 seconds now let's call
the increment number so undo increment
number so you can now you see you can
increase the
number okay so this is convenient
because often times if you have
something you know you don't want
to you know let's say you want to change
this to eight then you have to delete
then
08 uh what 08 A8 you see it's you know I
pre so it's better if you can just
increment and also this increment
command once you call it you can press
the hold down the arrow key up or down
or you can use the mouse mouse wheel so
you see now you see using the mouse
wheel Fant fantastic now if you can see
can you see my other
Mouse uh no okay so but uh okay well if
I put this here you cannot see
what okay this way you can
see okay so you see this this mouse got
a spin wheel it just infinitely spins
okay so if you have a mouse now go back
to Max let's say let's say three okay
now call the command incr number now I
put I just spin the mouse okay let's try
again so I'm trying to put closer you so
you can
see okay so call the command five and
scroll wheel to increase and if I just
push it you see it spins so it incre
Mega increment this is like the
uh Wheel of Fortune okay let's see if
I'm going to get a odd number or even
number now if I if I get a even number
that means I win okay now
sping is Big Money big seven
okay okay so you see the power of
the spin so fantastic okay this is the
power of
emac increment number okay now there's a
problem I want to make a modification
why because for example uh 2025 October
23rd now today is not I mean that's
August today is what 2025 January so I
need to decrease it so I do it you know
then it becomes
9 8 7 6 5 4 3 2 1 however
it got rid of the
zero that's not good you know typically
you you don't you know you want to keep
it so I'm going we're going to rewrite
the command so that it only change the
current digit okay and also when there
is no digit around the cruiser when you
call it right now if I call it it says
error CH under cursor is not a decimal
number you
see you see so for example I call it
call it error CH under curer is not a
decimal number so but if I put a number
and call it then becomes four you know
then I can Arrow up or down you see
fantastic but I want it to be so that if
I call it if there's no number just
insert one okay and also another so
that's one issue to fix another issue
is uh you know you don't want to get rid
of a zero and you don't want it to add a
negative in front you know so this is
wrong uh so it should just only act on
the current digit one digit only and
it'll cycle zero to nine and back to
zero you know so let's do
that okay
so let's write it okay
modification
needed work on
only um only one digit okay that's what
I want and if there is no digit insert
one
okay don't
go don't go into
negative if reach
n Go to zero
and vice versa okay so it's a cycle so
that's the what I want okay so delete
that delete that showing browser
fantastic okay now let's put the mouse
back am I doing good are you guys
enjoying this coding session let's use
my um my track B again track B track B
is
nice so far so good so far so good guys
five people watching okay so okay let's
do
it so I need to uh decrease the font
size a little
bit
what what
the okay very nice thank you
GCS so I want to decrease the font size
a little bit okay so what is
the um oh okay negative
okay uh negative
yeah okay back to back to our size okay
showing browser okay let's start to code
so put a code imag this yes fantastic
pop it out fantastic we are in business
now defend uh not not delete file defend
okay that's a function definition
template now since we already have
written this
command before let's look at the source
code so describe key this is a key I use
there it
is miscellaneous in this file open it
there it it isar increment number okay
and then there isar decrement number
okay copy it back here uh back to here
okay let's paste it
here okay so let's increase so so we
got this is the previous code in fact we
did this
live on 2024 May 88th so if you want
watch it you can we we coded this live
from scratch so and we also talked about
other things emac this
coding calculation pad calculation pad
yeah increment inclement digit how to
change
Behavior Zoom
idsy okay several things there but
anyway let's let's code this should we
code from scratch or should should we
just
modify that's a question uh for you guys
okay so I want to change just the digit
okay
okay let's code from scratch shall
we uh okay let's code scratch since I'm
experienced emac this code since
2016 so by now I've coded emac this 10
years uh so I can afford to create from
scratch like with my eyes
closed not exactly Clos okay uh this
function we are named let's see uh okay
let's see name it
that uh wait
increment uh digit under curer
okay
if under Cruiser is not a digit simply
insert one okay
when reach is
nine go to
zero vice
versa use Arrow
up down keys to
increment
or or decrement
okay and uh all score wheel find
fantastic documentation the more the all
important thing typical
programmers ignore they don't know how
to write documentation all
important okay so
now so first so we need to write another
command is called decrement okay so it's
uh got how many we got to do this
quickly 17 minutes okay so let's uh so
cluer position first of all check what
is the current digit okay
uh CH after so let's see if if we are on
a number it should change the character
to the right or to the
left uh technically it should change to
the
left because now this is a little bit
tricky issue you see the question now is
is a user interface design issue you
know you're going to write this function
to increment or decrement but suppose
the cruiser is the cursor is here you
know on the three now if you call this
command should it just increment the
three or the two you
see intuitively we think it's three
because because obviously the cursor is
highlighting that
character but you see a cursor is
actually a beam you know it's actually a
I beam there's a unic Code character for
that uh let's
see okay so
Beam not that okay I beam you see that
is actually a a Unicode
character that uh indicates APF
functional symbol I beam okay it's from
APR anyway never mind let's not digress
okay so anyway the question is should it
should it you know should it increment
on the right side of the ciser or the
left because the cruiser is actually an
IAM but why does emac put a rectangle
highlighting to the right of the right
side of the CER that is because
historical reasons because back then
okay let's digress a little bit um no
problem uh just digress a tiny bit okay
history of keyboards so you see these
are history of keyboards you know this
is this one is from 1970 you know back
then computers looks like that this you
know cost cost you
$50,000 $50,000 my friend for this thing
and the power of this thing is a
fraction of your cell phone okay but
50,000 something oh actually
3,000 $3,000 okay 4,000 but but but you
know how you know this mon monochrom
this is only two colors okay you know
how big is this it's like 40 characters
by 20 characters okay so if you have a
terminal that would
be uh wait so for example we got a
Powershell terminal let's increase the
size okay in fact Let Let me let me show
you something fun okay so let's for
example go to uh go to web
[Music]
web info go
to talk show okay so you can do du so
you least uh you know this directories
and let's do something funky let me show
you okay this like PR pretending this is
the terminal back then in
1970s okay so you go to
settings uh settings
appearance and
uh what is this colors in
rendering okay hold on second let me get
this okay
appearance position application theme
position of newly created tabs this is a
little bit digression do you guys mind
comments okay comments and answer always
show tabs use a click acrylic material
in the tab row don't know what the
that means
active terminal title always on top no
tab width pain animation always display
an icon in the notification area high
terminal in the notification area
automatic uh hold on a second where is
it rendering color themes no rendering
must
be
what disable partial
swap no okay okay this is taking a
bit I want
to okay start
up startup default profile power shell
default terminal
application okay so we wasting time
right
now but hold on second are you guys
seeing this in startup you can select
the size n rows by m columns okay thank
you uh but
let Okay so
but anyway the you know the old monitor
they are very tiny like like uh actually
80 columns by by 25 rows you know so
it's like in you know it's like stamp
sized on today's monitor but I wanted to
show I wanted to find
something profile default
okay here oh yeah here okay appearance
yeah retro terminal effects that's what
we want okay so let's see the okay let's
open a new window control tab uh control
shift
Tab and the no that's not retro
not
defaults
appearance oh you need to save wait
defaults uh defaults and uh appearance
and the Retro terminal effects on
save you see with
save yeah there it is okay now close
this setting there it is now close this
now I
magnify now this is like classic
terminal actually I need to turn it red
um I mean I need to turn it like green
or orange then you see the kind of the
Retro terminal okay uh fascinating retro
computer you know this is Classic this
is where VI Vim editor originated VI so
anyway so so anyway back then your
screen size is about you know just like
like that
small okay digress so much so let's go
back yeah so the question yeah we back
to the question the question is why emac
shows a
curer um you know on the right you know
highlight the right side that's because
back in the days you you cannot display
ibeam because the monitor is not is not
little raster monitor it's actually Char
character by character so these monitors
they cannot show Graphics they cannot
draw a line they can just simply
display characters you know 80 by by 40
something like that so you need a way to
indicate where is the curser so they
they just back you know they just make
it background highlight so when you see
that curser shape that means that's when
you type that character appears there
you know instead of being an ibam in
fact we can change emac to show ibam
Okay so let's try you know let's just
play around
uh okay describe variable
Cruiser type okay
show okay so Cruiser type you can have
several type let's see your bar
okay uh don't display the cruiser or you
can even hide it box okay box and the
bar or har har okay so now let's try it
okay
setq
uh setq Cur
type and uh let's
say ah okay oh actually because I'm
using flight s flight keys so when I
switch to insert mod now it's a bar you
see actually yeah so we don't actually
need to test so if I switch to uh
command mod it's a it's a square but if
I search switch to insert mod it's a bar
you see insert mod now it's a bar so
anyway that's a history you know why why
does emx show a block after the curser
position that's
because you know the monitor in in know
old age came from that so but it's
actually so back to the design question
should you do it before the cursor or
after I think it should be before okay
so but then it becomes counterintuitive
anyway
anyway let's just code it okay so Char
Char after Char before
okay
uh so if CH
before
uh CH before Returns the character
before the cruiser okay that's not a
good way to do
it
uh oh God okay we digressed so so much
we got 30 minutes to
go uh so good so far so good okay
so love my digressions
fantastic more colors on the keyboard
there on the screen yes you see I have
you know I type so much then I started
to have hand pen again in the past two
days right here left hand uh so anyway
so let's let's get this you know we want
to finish this so first of all you want
to
determine uh okay so so let's say okay
so okay let okay begin and end position
okay and begin position is um let's say
another one xp0
okay so xp0 is point point Returns the
current Cur position which is a integer
okay then uh let's remove that
so then
uh so Char is a current Char okay so
Char will be
[Music]
um set X Char equals to the point and
before it okay so both sub string no
properties okay now let's shrink this a
little bit so you can see so that we
grab from the current point
to uh to before okay
so so minus one minus one point to the
point so that's one
character um now
next H
God so next actually so we don't need
this okay
CH okay so we got a character so
if if the character is um if the
character is equals to any of the digit
okay if match
string okay regular expression 0 to9
okay then what is the String the string
is this character and optional we don't
care okay so if if the character before
the curer is a digit
then uh then what you do then then you
just
um then you just to take the
Char and uh string to
number string to
number then Char is a string convert it
to number then increment it okay
increment plus one that's right
then um then in fact then you
delete then you so you got that
character okay so but first of all you
need to um delete you need to delete
backward okay delete Char now delete
chart which direction it deletes let's
see delete chart deletes the following
and characters the following okay so you
need a negative so delete that
character then grab it then insert okay
so insert this uh this thing you need to
do number two string okay back to number
two string okay so let's clean the code
a little bit okay so we got that that
that okay so we got a character now if
the character is actually a digit then
um then then you remove that digit okay
then you insert okay so wait hold on
second so there's something else you
need to be careful when you insert
because what if it's not
so if it's nine then you add one it
becomes 10 that's not what you want so
you want to make
sure
uh so
insert okay
if
uh if x
Char if
string equal
X sh is equals to
9 then just
insert uh then just insert um
zero okay so this
actually paste it there and remove
that what is what's going on
okay so so let's so if it's nine then
insert zero
otherwise uh otherwise do this okay okay
you need to do this inside here
otherwise otherwise string to number
then
increment then number to
string then insert okay so you need to
actually uh insert
okay so that is
um
what so
wait so if stream
match okay then delete Char then insert
okay so let's refactor the insert okay
but hold on a
second okay so yeah we need that so this
this part is when it's not um when it's
not a digit so when it's not a digit all
you have to do is simply insert one okay
when there's no digit just insert one
okay uh since it's uh okay so you don't
need that so let's refactor this code
here let's
see let's make it insert
okay if is not insert zero otherwise you
don't need the insert there
otherwise
that okay I think it
works okay so I think that's that works
so now let's
Okay uh are we sure so save it go back
to the file by compile it yes it didn't
tell you any error that means at least
syntactically looks good delete it open
it EV evaluate the buffer now we can try
it let's say
eight okay
um am I doing good am I doing good sto
sto hi sto sto is a AI machine learning
expert he just wrote a he showed me he's
you know he wrote a large
language model you know the AI chart
bot so he is in China and he's coming to
America to the university here fantastic
congratulations so let's say eight so
let's call it call the number nine seems
to work now increment Inc wait what
let's try
again okay ARS out of
range okay so let's say three do it do
it work okay now if there's no number do
it fantastic now if it's zero do it
fantastic now if it's
n do it oh it works fantastic
wait no number do it yeah so it does it
to the number in front of the cruiser
which is what we designed it for now all
we have to do is write a uh decrement
number okay
okay actually we instead of writing two
functions you know increment decrement
we can actually combine it by you know
by by the parameter but let's not let's
do the simple
way okay so this this one is for
decrement
uh so instead of all the increment we
just say decrement okay
yeah okay so decr there so decrement so
decrement digit under CER if CER is not
digit s uh simply insert one okay now
when re is n Go when when it's
zero go to nine okay then Arrow up and
down okay use all scope wheel that's
okay and uh now we just need to change
the increment to decrement so so where
does it go for so if it's nine we
don't okay now this is decrement so if
it's zero it goes to 9
okay and otherwise uh otherwise it's all
DEC okay so plus is negative uh is there
a function one negative yes there is one
negative just decrements a number an
integer okay so I think that's it so we
got a DEC so evaluate the buffer so emac
knows these two functions jump to the
diet backup jump to the diet press a key
to bite compile yes do you want to yes
okay no error open the bite compile
looks like that delete it we don't need
it I do bite compile to make sure sure
it tells me if there's error because
when you do bite compile it helps in
detecting errors okay now all these back
of files
crap delete them mark it press key
delete sure yes okay so this are my 10
file directories actually so uh usually
I just manually D some of them
okay okay where is our code I forgot no
God where is our code oh here okay
uh what oh yeah here okay so evaluate
the buffer now let's try now if there's
no number do it uh argument out of range
what do it wait oh because it's in you
know right now it's a error because you
are at the beginning of a buffer there
is no character in front of it okay
let's fix it a little
bit
uh okay so
if uh Point Min Point minimum is the
smallest
um Cruiser position in a buffer okay so
if point mean equals to
33 equal actually we are done you know
because yeah 42 minutes okay so if point
minim is equal
to
point then that means that means you are
at the beginning of a buffer there's
nothing in front of it then that in that
when that's the case you just um inser
insert okay you just like just insert
one so like this here okay
so yeah
[Music]
okay it gets more complicated okay
so okay so if that's the case then you
just do that other wise delete that move
here that part put it there there it is
still not too complicated is it
acceptable yes EV go here now call
it uh still wrong okay EV the buff
wait if p mean equals to
point yeah Evol the
buffer okay go here go here call
it uh I go the
range buer
entitled set Q out of the range oh
because here you
see uh yeah so we got to fix
that so you got to do this here okay be
the arrow came from this line because
your character your Cruiser is at the
beginning of the buffer so there's
nothing in front of it then over here
you are trying to get the current
position and minus
one which which means you know the
current position that that position is
basically one minus one is zero but you
cannot but the buffer the the smallest
uh beginning of buffer is one so when
you say zero to something it says
there's error so that's why this line
This is this part is wrong
so if that then you just simply insert
okay otherwise then otherwise over here
then you uh then you do that okay and
then you don't need that that that that
that
otherwise that
okay is it accept
acceptable yes okay evaluate the buffer
back here call it fantastic and
beautiful can you
increase uh wait do it increase
what wait do it
incre do it increase please
what
oh um I know what's wrong you know I
what what we want is you know once you
call it it increase it and you want now
to be able to press an arrow key so that
it keeps going so once the command done
you want to assign an the up Arrow key
to call the command
itself we don't have it here so let's
add the code
so well the code is is already uh is
actually here okay so let me show you
okay so you just need to add
that okay so add that
there uh what this code means you create
a key map okay assign it to
xmap then you set a key to this key map
of the up Arrow key so when up arrow is
pressed you callar increment number okay
similarly for down arrow for decent
number and square wheel up and square
wheel down okay so this is a part you
want you want to add to this command but
and also uh to here
okay okay beautify it evaluate it back
to here delete that delete that Cod the
command now let's try the square
wheel
increase back do it again
incre do it again
decrease no it's not
working evaluate what the is going
on
delete C up Arrow no didn't work wait
what I thought
I ah wait what increment increment
increment increment yeah the command
name is correct delete
that decrement decrement decrement
decrement decrement
okay wait what is going on so that
uh wait let's see oh I I forgot this
part this set transion map okay I forgot
it yeah you need that okay so actually
copy
that okay paste that there you don't
need that no
copy back
here paste that delete prettyy eval the
buffer go here delete call the command
fantastic now let's try the scroll
wheel up
what do it up fantastic fantastic down
fantastic fantastic that's it fantastic
we
done okay put it back colorify the HTML
showing browser that is the fruit of
today now instead of increment number
and decrement number that's it should be
named renamed increment digit and
decrement digit because unlike before
now it only works on single digit now
let's try okay now let's try some date
okay now let's say I want to change
to uh December okay call the
command uh oh one shot okay now remember
it works on the the number in front of
it okay
so so let's repeat you know go back
through zero fantastic so you you can
just like
fantastic you know there is a still
issue like whether you want to change it
before or after it's hard decision about
this user interface but anyway we are
done okay thank you guys now Okay so
you know pay me so you go TOA emac blog
so you know recently I generated a new
emac the entire uh emac blog so about
9,000 Pages something uh so there is 900
Pages here and uh then misenus there is
250 pages so all together 1,00 Pages
plus about 2,000 Pages for emac dis and
emac manual which is
included uh for example you can look at
it go to the bottom 1,000 something
Pages open X widget showing browser you
know that's a manual I
included uh on my website so you buy it
so emac tutorial you get practical emac
you get everything everything you need
to know about emac
initialization
customization you can learn all about
emac key binding you can learn you know
once you mastered you know you you
become familiar with emac you can learn
emac lisp lisp Basics tells you about
lisp data structures string string
string functions format string regular
expression number arithmetics convert
number string buing you know convert
number string which we used today uh
string to number see number to string
and uh equality variable conditionals if
then else Loop list data structures or
important list Vector sequence type and
so on and how do you define a function
like we did today so this section is
about lisp the language Basics then next
you have emac lisp
specifics such as the cruiser position
of a buffer how do you delete text how
do you move Cruiser how do you search
text in a buffer so these are specific
to emac the editor emac LP and then you
can learn how to write a major mod okay
so you can buy of course pay me you know
as like a sponsor you know you just pay
me some amount cheap $35
$32 in fact I I need to change this to
some $50 you know that's uh okay
so yeah so support me go to sad emac
tutorial you can you know just or just
donate to me donate by PayPal or you can
uh go to my homepage C code all the way
at the
bottom now you patreon Amazon gift card
pay PayPal okay does a decrement digit
check for Point meme no that needs to be
fixed okay so but you know um but I'm
not going to do it online because uh
because I'm I mean my goal is just to
show you guys how to do it but it's
trivial you know so you need to also
kind of
fix the uh de equipment you usually you
don't because you see let me explain and
Y actually we don't uh I don't think we
need to fix it you you can if you want
to but you the see the reason
is there is no key binding for the dec
number
directly there is I only have a key
binding for the increment number why
because once you call uh once you call
the increment number then you can just
scroll wheel to decrement or increment
so if you want to incre decrement you
just call it and just decrease
twice so the advantage is that you save
one key spot for other commands kind of
you know but if you want to you can just
create another key binding for for the
decrement but since we don't we only
need one key binding therefore we don't
you know we never call decrement
directly for example we can call it our
decrement number if we call it now it's
going to be error you see because
there's no digit in front but we don't
usually we don't you know you just call
the increment then you can okay you can
increase or decrease that's it for today
thank you guys for watching
bye fantastic and beautiful
okay so guys you can join my Discord
okay I've been very alive on Discord I
mean I mean the myar Twitter of course
Kar Discord here but also Kar Twitter
x.com so I've been starting to you know
Trump become president so so there's a
lot of changes the
Dei is gun now it's illegal like
diversity equity and
inclusiveness basically means
lgbtq trans BLM and the code of conduct
that's a thing relevant to us code of
conduct you know for example this gido
van Rome guy from
python he says I've always f that
feminism was right and we need to change
the whole
society he needs to we need to change
the whole society for
feminism gang rosam says I also
unfollowed a bunch of the white male oh
my God Jesus what a crime the white male
opinion leaders and have started to
follow more pie ladies oh the all
important ladies girl
girls he says male attitude is hurting
the programming
space he says I'm hurting the
programming space this guo van Ram guy
says I'm hurting the programming space
Oh my God he says open source projects
especially large well-known open source
projects have been slow in comparison to
to the rest of the tech industry in
letting women into their teams says says
this
guy well I think if you are concerned
about women you need to talk to the
Kardashians bye guys