hello guys welcome to another episode of
excel talk show welcome to another
episode of sound talk show so we are
going to do emac least Auto format
exploration so this guy a great guy he
wrote this automatic formatting of emac
Beast code
so that for example
let's go to uh emacs it is called softly
keys so you see all these are emacs
these codes so I want a tool just like
go format or dental format for
JavaScript or
they are and there's also one for python
so you just press one button and it will
reformat your entirety of the whole file
code okay so for example let's this is a
function that's
emac this mod
so you know you can press the button
he'll reformat it but what I want this
this is not enough okay this is emacs
mod
what what I want if you have the whole
thing in one single line let's see
uh let's see that okay uh
hold on a second so
you know the whole thing in one single
line this is still valid emac this is
code I want to press a button and it'll
format it my side emac be smart cannot
do that okay but this is critical this
this is the key okay this is the key for
the auto format tool if the auto format
tool cannot format a valid code in one
single line into multiple lines then
that's no good okay all the linked all
the all the things before go format
before year 2008 around there it's all
okay so I want this tool this tool
has been now because of the go go
language became very popular and I want
so I want that so uh this supposedly you
know so first thing you want to do is
you want to reformat use whatever you
have done the tool to reformat the
entirety of emac this code that comes
with emacs and see if it still works you
cannot you cannot have zero you know you
cannot have any errors okay so that's a
critical thing so for example let's look
up tired you know diode is a um you know
biod emac this feature you know that
goes to the list directories so you can
then you jump to a source code you can
see and go up one level you can see all
these directories are emac beast code
that bundles with emacs
uh and uh so you should be able to call
you know whatever this command in this
package then reformat the entirety of
all these directories files okay then
and restart emacs should not be any
problem
okay so that is the goal of this tool
this is this is the most critical the
revolution in programming industry in
programming language in in formatting
code okay so you no longer have the
style guide for Mountain style guide you
should be automatically automated in
systematic according to a certain rule
how things should be formatted okay so
this is a critical tool I talked about
this
um
quite a few times as I've been writing
about these since
2005 okay
so
so I did so this is today's talk show
page and I did a talk show before
demonstrating the wufan language I mean
I'm talking about this issue so you
should go there
um you know you go you search for go to
Saudi website and search for computer
languages syntax passing for editor so
here is a collected article I have about
all these tools I talked about in this
video you know part of my uh talk show a
few weeks ago
uh and uh so all the collected articles
on how how can you do that in gold gold
language in Python
JavaScript in Powershell
and uh then the Emax wrapper so you can
code them in emacs and have them Auto
formatted by calling those tools then I
have written okay so here is about
passes about
um
select line extend selection uh this
this is all related to line truncation
you know the Unix uh
the Unix problem you know all originated
from the Unix problem of line truncation
and the C
programming language that that created
this huge damage in computer industry so
starting with Golan go go language go
format they started to fix that and that
kind of revolutionized started
Revolution
okay so today I'm going I'm going to
explore you know I'm going to try out
test this um
this idea man
42's code supposedly he told me you know
he he he told me many times that yes
this really works so I'm going to try it
uh video check audio check uh okay let's
go there where is my uh gray browser
okay so emacs yeah uh he mentioned again
yeah so now it's our mailbox so let's
let's let's let's go about and let's do
it okay comments and questions posted
okay hello good Google user in Halo
Ashton
pop this out
put it here
and the pink window you can see all my
command course and the keystrokes in
Emax
okay so let's let's let's just um
try this
okay I'm going to go relaxed you know
like I'm just gonna do my things and if
you are watching offline you know make
it play at 1.5 or something I don't want
to rush and
you know so any comments or questions
posted okay so this I hope this will be
fantastic
now what is this written in
um
so here is some t
and here is grapefruit juice
uh
he make this Auto format why is there a
python this is written in Python that's
not good
Yep this is written in Python
no good
this is a first bad issue okay you
should write in e-macb not python
part of the reason is you know python is
not built in in many linuxes it's not
building on Microsoft Windows it's not
building a Mac okay and that's there's a
practical issue so people have to
download these two and also since we are
doing emacs you know in particular emac
beasts you know you should um
have it you know in iMac beeps this so
you know people don't have to download
another programming language
okay so it's written in Python
and what is this I suppose this is just
a wrapper
okay this is gonna take a while to
explode to explore
um
so let's why don't we just scrap the
code okay so you this is you know ideas
man
Campbell Campbell button
he's a open source guy
so he you know doesn't use GitHub and he
switched to you know that fox thing
something lab then now now there's this
bug something code bug so he switched to
Goldberg
so how do I okay so here is
um download Gip I want to copy the repo
can we do that yeah
uh it's where do we go okay so let's go
to
um
okay let's put it in my emacs in a
directory
Okay so
uh so this is the so can we just get it
yeah I think so start the shell
get clone
let's let's try if that works
code bug supposedly you know the
codeberg.org is supposedly open source
the repository website
so here's the code
license okay glue
gpl3 no general public license okay
so here's the python code let's see
2400 lines okay I like to look look at
how things are so
okay so it's written in part in Python
and the
so we have you know this decorator
you know that that's that's almost like
a macro
python is a very very bad language
okay so four thousand two thousand four
hundred lines classes okay so let's look
at
um
so let's look at the functions
okay so that's python so
then you have the e-mac lisp Auto format
let's see what is this
uh
Auto format this code on Save
it's search for python least matching
lines
Define custom Edis Auto format python
Bing so indeed so you are calling Python
3 to do it
okay so you need uh so now these
matching lines this is uh
Define custom
okay so it's used in two places one is
here
and one is here okay
so uh Define custom the python binary to
call to run auto format uh utility okay
anyway so that's python I mean that's
the emac Beast wrapper
override Json
okay that's probably about the style so
something
so let's read read me okay okay I mean
rst
and rst is you know the Ruby it's a
formatting you know it's like markdown
but it's more fancy used by Ruby or
something
and do you want to apply the local
variable list is read
list in readme.isd Contents value that
may not be safe you know so this is part
of emacs that allows you to evaluate
some code when you open a file
and usually it's very annoying because
when you open it
oh wait
you know you'll ask you do you want to
run those code usually I say no
wait let's try open again no
so this is readme.rst this is package
photo format emac is available okay so
that's a basically this readme file
there I suppose
um
reliable test with emacs 28 Source okay
uh over 6 1.6 million lines okay let's
read here
project using it that's all his packages
Justine hello oh my God Justin Justine
you still alive great to see you again
happy New Year
Justin is a professional mathematician
by the way
just seeing it's a professional you know
Advanced professional mathematician
studying some specialized number Theory
or something
right
so example project so all these are
basically his own code so that doesn't
mean much
motivation this tool removes the need to
manually format okay
reliable tested with emac 28 Source over
1.6 million lines of code okay
enforce this maximum line with using
field column keeps keep blank blank
lines okay that's one of the issue when
you format the format you don't for
example
in code you have comment you know if you
don't if you didn't write the
reformatting tool correctly you just
remove all the comments
or reform and the comment that's not not
usually that's not good usually you want
to keep the comments the way they are
the way they are formatted usually
worst is just signal format you know so
you know writing these two is not
trivial at all
keep trading comments at the end of
lines okay uh keep trading comments at
end of lines without joining joining
clients which may change their meaning
okay let's magnify
forgot to magnify extract function
arguments from locally defined functions
with support for including definitions
from external files
what parallel computation Ah that's it
that's a nice feature so it does
parallel
usage enable Elis Auto format mod minor
mod so it's
yeah
okay so you have to
enable this minor mod this will form an
image this purpose on Save okay I don't
want that depending on you know that
variable
no no that's fluff okay well that's
important but first of all I want to
make sure I want to know I want to check
the quality of the actual thing the
python code that formats all files in a
directory so once I once it's very good
very fast then I will maybe
load the emacs format you know the Emax
wrapper to call it automatically
or or just press a key to do it you know
okay since it's likely you will work on
code bases that don't have Auto format
enabled
this checks for the existence of that
Edis Auto format file in the purpose
directory
okay so one bad point so far
I mean one one one bad point is that
it's written in Python okay so already
so let me start to uh write notes about
it
written in Python
better is written
in English it's almost yeah that's
important actually you want it you know
you don't want writing python
this is emacs you write in the language
you know it come with
then
okay it's a minor kind of minor if it
works very good then it's very good the
documentation then it says stock
issue okay
it requires
you to
call and use the Edis wrapper
command okay
better is to
show the actual
command to call the python mod
python script directory
okay so that's uh that's my criticism
so it doesn't say you know it doesn't
even say how do you call the python
script
you know depending on the script because
uh in the
hello
why the sad face
you know because depends on let's see
you know many so this this is the python
script that's the core engine
heartbreaking moment for python lover
the python is a circus language
truly in my opinion it's one of the
worst
well you know there are some there are
so much worse uh worse ones but pattern
is one of the among the top five most
popular python is the worst well better
than C but better than c c or better
than C or C plus plus
foreign
[Music]
but we want a documentation how do you
run this python code I mean this python
code is the engine it's a heart of this
formatter
so you you want to tell people expose it
you know you know not just for emac bisp
users
this this code formatting this code
should eventually be useful for all
these languages
so you want to make that you know this
this this
you know as an independent script that
can format any parenthesized
these
code at least it might be in common is
because skim this enclosure they have
they have lots of different syntax you
know
and uh so anyway so even if it's just
for emacs you should
say in my opinion you should have you
know tell people what what does this
python code what what argument does it
take does it take
a directory or a file is there any
documentation here
you know we haven't read it all yet but
we'll see
okay
import what what is this import
Define function ID okay I don't know
okay it doesn't say so we have to
manually find find out okay
but basically it's asking you to install
this emac this wrapper
okay requirements emacs 27 okay python
3.8 okay it requires 3.8 which is the
latest
version okay
um do I have python yes I do okay oh
yeah I have 3.9 okay that's good
performance the first reformat may be
slow as they are likely to be a large
number of changes be applied back into
emacs running again is typically fast
enough
this is no good
oh God disappointing
this is this is crap okay well a bit
exaggeration you know after reading this
I'm not going to try anymore
it says basically it says the first time
we you you reformat a large emac this
code okay the first time you reformat
let's see you know this is stuff like he
said let's copy or paste it here seleco
and make it all one line okay so wait
that's coming yeah it takes a long time
uh Jesus now four you know two
thousand lines now becomes one line and
emacs first
because emacs have a problem dealing
with long lines
yeah okay so there it is okay
so you know so it it is saying that the
first time you do it it'll be it'll be
slow because there's a lot of code you
will try to reformat but but once the
code is already in kind of the formatted
way
so they are much less change to make
therefore you'll be faster
but that's that's losing the point if my
code is already formatted you know
um you know 90 percent
I'm not gonna need your
referral matter
Jesus
that's why I'm saying you know these
people you got you know those you know
you gotta you gotta be professional okay
go land those professional tools you
know this this this is I don't think
it's gonna be good okay
okay emacs stuck because of the long
lines now now I have to
I mean every operation now even if you
do cancel you take uh you know 10
seconds and it's close okay
close okay so now if you go to let me
show you okay
many other professional tools okay you
look at
okay so there's go format come with go
go land okay you don't even have two
yeah let's magnify okay so hold on a
second
so this go format a building has a tool
G of format okay building it can run all
files in your directory in a second in
within one second you suppose you have
1000 files
in a directory and suppose each file is
2000 lines okay
and suppose each of those files are all
one single line but still valid goal
line code okay you can run go format in
one second you'll do them you'll finish
them all one million lines okay let's go
format same thing
with the pythons for matter there are
several there are yab and black okay
here's the instruction on how to use
them basically same thing one million
lines of code in one single line you do
it press the button in one second you'll
be done
okay
same thing with tenno okay Deno for
JavaScript come with Daniel you know
they are all very professionally written
they are written or written in C
Okay C or Golan you know low level
language Powershell I'm not sure how
it's written but you know and I don't I
don't know how fast it is
but
um
but then
you know I I'm I'm pretty sure even
without testing at this point I'm not
going to use it it's not going to be
good for me
because the if my code is already 90
formatted why do I need your your
formatter 4
the the the goal of the formatter is is
is a a compiler it's a parcel compiler
that
whose job is to format very fast card
okay so I know you know sorry for the
flame you know but um
the comments okay the commands let's try
it
currently only utfa encoding is
supported okay
okay installation so
there is no mention about the python
script how do you run it it's just uh
the lisp so it primarily just intended
to run for you know
it's just intend to format just for
emacs users formatting emac basic code
uh performance okay running against
typically fast enough to being able down
save without notice going into and yeah
that that's that's useless useless of
course the code is already formatted of
course
then it's fast sure
but that's you know
that's not performance performance is
you you know if you format a file one
gigabyte all in one single line how fast
can you do it that's what performance
means
uh okay so
well what you're gonna do so uh yeah so
we want to test it for still so
okay where is the code okay let's go to
yeah where's the code
diet close close
switch directory
okay let's go here
okay let's run it let's try to install
it then
open that
so let's follow the direction see how to
even it
Elis Auto format mod
Elis Auto format buffer automatic format
account buffer doesn't depend on the
minor mod
okay so that that is what I want to call
okay so now eval the hope of a done
let's compile it okay
drop in diet press capital B to compile
it so here's a compiled file then press
capital L to load it so now we are we
have loaded the compiled
uh Auto format code okay so now
let's go go to some
uh emac be smart okay I mean go to some
emac this code okay so soft like keys
okay so copy it and create a new buffer
save it and save it as x x
dot El
ah this this got a problem you know the
the the vertical uh you know anyway
there's another thing so here we have a
copy of soft light Keys four thousand
lines and I want to
let's just run the first command okay
so this command now should work
uh it probably won't work because
because my python is probably set up
correctly so let's see the documentation
first
is an interactive compile this function
okay Auto format the current buffer okay
I want to use that okay so let's call it
so hold on a second let's delete all
let's just remove that one okay
save it
call it meta X
meta X do that do it
let's see if it works
it's taking too long
searching for program no file or
directory Found Jesus if that's the case
why is it taking that long
so he's trying to find Python 3 you know
I mean the you know he's trying to
without space or anything so you have to
you have to modify the python
um file location
it didn't say it doesn't say
you see it's
you know you should document you need to
document that because a lot of people at
least half of the people do not have
Python 3 because python has been you
know they deprecated python 27 I mean
they deprecated python too so a lot of
installation is just Python Meaning
python 3.
you know so the python situation is
chaotic you know python 2 and 3 and the
packet of one was some idiot they refuse
he refused to create a fire
extension.py3 you know they he wants to
people think that py you know he's he
want everyone to just upgrade you know
but that's not actually the case
so there's a problem of you know of
fuzziness of ambiguity you know it's a
headache you know the python 203 what's
the command name you know depending on
which system on Windows and Linux you
know on what district distribution
distribution of Linux which Linux are
you using sometimes it's Python 3 means
Python 3 sometimes python means python
3. you know it's a chaotic so
so
you need
so we have here
is close Okay so that's the one I want
so okay because let's go there so in
this read me I mean
here there is this this
python Bing you should document it
okay yeah there it is great
optionally said python binary use when
python is not in your path indeed well
you know it's not python is in my path
it's just not the Python 3 it's assuming
okay so let's we need to set this okay
so
so okay so let's create
um emac this code
you know let's uh let's
you know I know emac this so therefore
I kind of know how to fix it
but for other people
it's a problem you know
you know
so so you
said so let's just set that okay
I said that variable to
just python okay I believe
uh
yeah python okay uh maybe you actually
have to set the full path
don't know
I don't should do let's just try that
evaluate it okay
now the square variable
okay value is python that should be
maybe that's good okay
okay so now we have that now let's go
back to
stuff like keys
closes offline keys I don't want to
screw that up
so now let's try the command again meta
X Elise Auto format buffer
error outputs
source file newer than byte compile file
using old file web
I'm not sure okay it's not done yet
so emacs still doesn't let me type
anything
you know sometimes in emacs 28 I get
that
you know saying that it's it's saying
that the byte compiled file
is older than the source code file
but I thought I fixed that uh
okay I hope
I don't know why why is it calling that
you know see that
I uh is it actually calling that
function there
it shouldn't
it's press Arrow key it it doesn't work
it's not good
still running
hello Greg and Doc
okay so we talked for 40 minutes
okay I don't think this is good it's
stuck
let's see uh
Ctrl shift Escape
emacs very high okay it's still running
10 of CPU and stuff
it's no good it's it's it froze or
something
arrow keys doesn't work okay so uh
I'm sorry I'm sorry but it's not good
uh I would great it fail okay I would
grade it fail
so you know writing this is not trivial
you know writing a auto formatter that's
actually professional in quality this
this is not this this is just a toy you
know
yeah you're gonna wait how long you're
gonna wait yeah I mean right you know I
just tried it
and now it's stuck you know that
you know something is wrong you know
it's just one single file
two thousand lines and it's almost all
formatted already
then I got this error you know then then
my emac stuck
and it's still running
he's still stuck
I have to force quit I think
did I do anything wrong no I think I did
you know
I read the document okay now it's out
so now it's out
so so what okay so it you see it did
format this line
so it did its job
okay so what he's trying to say here
saving fire okay
let's go to directory okay
so it just changed okay now let's try it
again
okay now save the file
now let's look
do it
okay it's it's good it's done
yeah
yeah so
yeah okay so let's try something out
small complex okay so let's
suppose let's make this whole thing one
line it's still valid code you know
because I can evaluate it and encode the
code you see co-works you see that
this command is moved to beginning of
line or block
so you see I can call it is still work
okay so this line now let's see
let's call it let's see what it does
this is too long this is you know taking
too long
okay now it does
okay not bad okay not fair not fair but
you know
so let's fix this problem this I don't
know
uh see that
let's open that
okay who is
generated generated passes support file
okay so it's actually using it's
actually calling this
uh
you know emac this
code Library it's actually using this
emac this Live library
you know the see that see that is very
complex you know it's supposed to be a
parser
engine for
for Java and stuff but nobody uses so
it's very com because it's too complex
to see that thing
so okay so it's actually using this file
and now let's compile that file so so
that we fix the Emax error a bitching
that this is newer than that so we just
compiled it okay refresh okay
good
okay let's see what is this
exactly do Source wi generated passes
support fire
generated parser support file
source code template Lexa
okay rejects analyzer source code okay
okay so so close that
close that
now back to our test
let's try again
undo okay
now make a backup
Now call that command again e this Auto
format book
it's too slow this is only 2 000 lines
okay it works and now we don't have that
Arrow anymore
fantastic okay
so it works
so what do I
um
so it does work
and uh
okay so good
now let's see
if we compact that
and uh
to that
let's do some more okay
so this line also become that
okay one single line
it should still be valid whenever
there's a comment then you must be
careful because when you when there's a
comment then you
make them one line it won't it'll be a
problem because the whole thing becomes
common
but so far let's make all this one line
okay
so no comment is good
so make one line okay so we have like
five or four
faith
faces that's all single line
make a backup
call the command do it
it's too slow it's too slow this is not
acceptable
you know and I'm on a pretty fast
machine you know I'm a gaming machine
yeah God you know in in in any of those
gold land you know they know JavaScript
they they do 50 000 lines in half a
second
this this is this is too slow God Jesus
yeah okay
so yeah okay so that's it that's it for
today
um
it says it's it's it's better than
nothing you know like I have done
nothing I I wanted to write this since
like 15 years ago but it's not easy so
uh it's better than nothing it's still
running God it's just five five single
lines it's still running
but better than nothing but do I use it
no you know because the point is that if
I gonna use it
I want I like this single line style
because as I have demonstrated in
Wolfram language you know for example
you look at this code wufan's language
goes one step further by
um
by uh oh you need to actually format it
oh yeah but I added lime I added line
breaks there myself did I
uh
yeah you can see
you know yeah so you see they the line
breaks there because you have a
semicolon but actually the whole thing
is a single line because you can copy it
you know this is still running and this
is not good
uh let's start a new Emax instance
you know I set up my emacs so that so
that uh
so that what's going on here
what
oh I didn't run it what
let's try again okay
run it do it
I already pressed enter
okay now it's done
okay check
check good
it good it's good okay so it's good
yeah it's not it's not bad it's not it's
not bad so
let's try this
call it do it
ah it's too slow it's too slow
do it
yeah okay it's not bad
uh
okay yeah but
I I well I can I'm not I cannot use it
so you know so it's not easy you know
it's better than nothing it's not easy
it's it's you know I haven't done
anything so it's it's it's a it's a
start
so I would say you have to rewrite this
in
in emac lisp okay
yeah do that we write this in emac this
so the question is can you can you
implement this in python or emac this
and expect expect it to be as fast as
those in Golan or JavaScript
uh probably not because those are
written in C but however
can you rewrite it so that let's say
let's say it's just let's say it's five
times slower than those in go format or
demo format
five times slower no more okay you know
we give it that's plenty room because
emac is is not
as fast as C but let's say five times
slower if it's
no more than five times slower than I
would say it's except acceptable
because I I tried this Daniel in Dental
you know 50 000 lines in one file
you know in in uh and and it's less than
half a second instant
uh
so the question is can it is possible I
think so I think so
but the problem is in order for that Hub
to happen
you cannot
you have to write a real parser okay
like read a character character by
character you have to write the real
password I don't think this you can
you know you can do some kind of a text
processing that's what this code is
doing
field column trading parents uh step
over
new line characters instead of data
speed Okay so
yeah so this is doing it by
text processing
let's see what kind of functions are
there
function ID has hash prefix special case
calculator yet so this is not a parcel
this is just doing
text processing
okay
so thank you I mean you know
Campbell Barrel pattern is probably
watching my videos and you know he will
see it later so you know maybe he's here
and it's great okay but you know I think
there's a lot of room to Improvement for
improvement
uh uh I cannot use it you know because I
want I want a real parcel okay like like
now there's a three-seater in uh emacs
29 that's that that is a real person
so either you know can use that or
something you know you have to write a
real password in emac this you can write
in email like this real password
these text processing way is just
um not good enough okay that's
but still it's you know it's uh it's it
works okay so that's it for me
that's it for me today now let's I want
to do some more um tests okay let's see
let's do some more tests okay
do I need
one line
takes two seconds three seconds yeah so
this file is only 5 000 lines okay
so let's say I remove these
and make this whole thing one line
remove that comment
what is this
stuff like he's Define my minor mod
okay
there's a comment here yeah that's bad
okay so and do
you know so emacs
e-mac B's common syntax is a problem
because it's a line based you know when
you don't when you have a
programming language syntax that's
semantic unit and not line based like
HTML XML Wolfram language and this
except except the line the comment
because it's line based
but if you have a syntax that's not line
based then you can
you can arbitrarily compact any um
code
on the Fly and uncompact it you know by
by this Auto formatter so you don't even
need those um
those hide you know part of the code you
don't need that and it's and you
is simple to do so okay okay let's try
this again
try it
two three
four four seconds yeah
it works it works
fantastic
poet
it works
let's remove all the comments let's see
oh anyway that's it that's it for today
thank you guys for watching bye