good morning guys
welcome to another episode of South Park
show you are watching Santa Joe and
today is 2019 this is Saturday December
14th in USA of course now it's 12:30 in
the afternoon and totally in the
afternoon in San Francisco time welcome
to San Francisco you want to go to San
Francisco you take the train and today
I'm going to show you the fantastic
writing of Chinese and vectors ok
mathematics mathematics in geometry the
all important stuff you don't remember
in school oh ok so how are you guys so
let's see I'm still setting up I came ok
so apparently when the video is going
young this becomes scratchy you see I'm
trying to draw a circle then but it it's
not as smooth can you see can you guys
see so today we are going to talk about
vectors for example this is X and this
is y and we have a point here and the
coordinate of this point will be a a and
B okay so could scratch that so undo
what is undo oh I don't have a key for
and do ok so I mean I don't have a so
that is a point for example and that
point will be the coordinate will be a B
because this is a and because this is B
so each point in the plane is
represented by two numbers a pair of
numbers a and B and it works like that
so this this thing is called a point or
you can call it a vector now this is
mathematics 101
basic mathematics precalculus okay and
when you are learning vectors then
becomes linear algebra then it becomes
fantastic fantastic Oracle so how are
you guys we have three people watching
and nobody is healed yet and you guys
what is is okay so you guys join my
disco channel okay make it popular
okay so let's so what do you what are we
going to do so we are going to well I
was planning to talk about JavaScript
okay I mean not not JavaScript we are
going to coach JavaScript
so let's okay so let me show you I'm
gonna show you everything so you can see
here is my system okay here's my hand
I'm drawing here this this is the device
okay underneath it you see I can okay so
I hold my camera so I want to I want to
track this so it becomes elongated strip
and in this window what you see is all
my Emacs commands okay so for example I
click here you can see over there
mouse movement okay and I can select so
all my Emacs command shows on this
window and and so I'm using the pin so
this this I'm showing you because so
that you can go by it right here okay
you go to sorry keyboard blog then you
can find this page then oops then you
buy this one okay this thing is cheap
$40.00 only come on in but Bartholomew
Jas Jay Jay Jay Jay Simpson how are you
doing but so but you're gonna buy this
one well but you are in Germany so and
you know
of course I have my Canisius keyboard
and I have this fantastic spinkweed okay
I'm gonna show you the power of the
swing swing cui okay one second and
we're gonna keep going we're gonna do
the mathematics so part but where is he
where is the girl where is the Z trunk
crazy your partner she hasn't been to
the show for a while so you see so this
is my sake go blog and you go over to my
where is it my mouse section okay you go
over to my mouse section you can see the
demonstration of the spin you fantastic
fantastic and this is the mouse okay
this one this one you go buy it cheap
okay so that's about that where is
bamboo well I don't have the bamboo
version you know I have the one the
version I have is the one I have is the
one I have is a cheap Chinese made
version okay and so I'm gonna show you
stuff and first of all so let's copy
this page and I paste paste paste it
okay so so some of you guys can go buy
it that's how I make my bread okay so
let's go back drawing tablet okay so I'm
gonna paste it here joint habit and
Logitech pen go back here and good
mornings each one crazy say something is
it wrong so Logitech so so we actually
I'm thinking you know we are going to do
the the mathematics
you know vector so that's not so let's
learn something you know but you should
learn it you know you you watch every
movie every of my video but you you have
to learn something I mean not not
aside from watching it for entertainment
purposes a you could also follow through
and and and if you do that you don't
need to go to universities anymore
because you are learning lots of stuff
here you have to do homework like every
hour video there is one hour of homework
okay so that's about my tablet but
before I show you something let me show
you let me demonstrate Chinese writing
okay actually a Chinese the most
complicated writing system actually
Japanese is actually more complicated
because Japanese where is my camera
pointing at okay one second so because
actually Japanese so here I can you can
see you can see I write okay so I guess
should I you know chit know I guess so
Japanese it turns out where do I want to
go the you know Japanese turns out the
right Japanese writing system is more
complex than Chinese because because it
actually uses all the Chinese characters
not all but three thousands of it so
this is impressed they have the Japanese
phonetic symbols but anyway I'm going to
show you I'm going to show you Chinese
writing system today okay so I mean I'm
going to demonstrate that but mostly I'm
going to show you about the vectors math
I think we're gonna do that so wait how
long have I been talking let's stop this
yeah let's stop that and let's go back
to where to to to here so you guys can
see it right yeah so the demonstration
so let's write some Chinese oh yeah so
so to write some Chinese let's go to
okay there is slight lag yo e TN lag how
do you say lag in Chinese you know I
haven't I don't speak Chinese at home so
I you know I rarely speak Chinese and I
haven't written Chinese for for 10 years
also so that's how you write Chinese
some of the Chinese characters this is
Chinese okay so when okay middle
language now but however let's write
let's go to so Hadees - have you ever
seen
Chinese writing Chinese have you ever
thought okay but you are the only one
here who is talking so you are the
center of my attention so let's go to
savvy Chinese let's go there and that's
we retrace Chinese chess yes that's good
Chinese input methods
yes that's good we talked about we
talked about Japanese input methods
yesterday and this drum keyboard is
fantastic it's fun book the Chinese
typewriter history okay that there is a
book
intro to Chinese punctuation yes you
guys can read that and Emacs Chinese
input of course you can use Emacs to
type Chinese and yesterday we did a
demonstration of typing Japanese in real
time in fact that's my first time time
being Japanese okay so actually let me
go to Chinese over here so Chinese okay
so this this is a list of the most
frequently used Chinese characters
that's this list okay the most
frequently used Chinese characters so
let's go over here let's go over here
let's pace it okay and and I'm going to
show you how to how do I write this okay
so let's see so you are seeing that
window then you need to I need to go to
Wrangler is good morning landlords
so new landlords always have interesting
things to tell us so new window okay I'm
going to write these Chinese characters
my friends okay so actually that I have
to write it a little bit slowly because
there is lag when I'm doing video ok
that
I can write faster because but if I
write faster there's the lag so let's
write the first the first column the
yeah :
okay
okay so we are up here and the Tongan
this towards means of course now there's
some strokes are not showing because I'm
running too fast so there is some it
doesn't I have to write I have to write
it slowly because otherwise the stroke
doesn't show up
I blame to the computer I don't have a
powerful enough computer in fact I
anyway that's demonstration of some of
the Chinese writings so bar says the
near anger who's been talking about me
on discord
who else me talking about you so so are
you are you on this code what is your ID
discover parody okay so that's about
Chinese we're gonna closely stop okay
closely style discard changes well do
should we said say with them save save
save us okay well actually we don't want
to save it we want to export you know
the Kim idiotic they started to have
export instead of save well I can
understand why because so saving
documents actually I don't want saving
documents stupid now then it's gonna ask
you these things close that it's discard
changes so don't you have a Mac which
would mean you have no computer at all
don't you have a Mac which would mean
you have no computer at all not not
funny way not humorous that's a failed
joke your your joke failed so what I'm
what are we going to do today so well
the plan is that I'm going to start to
code JavaScript let's get on with it
then okay so
okay so let's get on with coding
JavaScript so let's beginning that and
let's let's yeah let's begin to do that
coding so stop with these Chinese
keywords we don't okay close at Chinese
drum keyboard guys look at this
fantastic this fantastic Oracle Chinese
drum keyboards that's how you use it now
this is actually a April Fool's Day of
Google Japan about ten years ago and all
the Nerds posting this every year the
idiotic nerds because when they see this
they think oh oh my god this is so you
know they find it they find it funny I
don't you know it's really not funny if
you know Chinese you know well because
the Americans are european that speakers
they are not familiar with these
thousands of characters so when they see
this it's more funny to them and but if
you are chinese or japanese you you grew
up with it it's it's not really that
funny okay but anyway that is this
japanese one like like if you read
chinese you can tell all these
characters in fact all these characters
on this keyboard you can tell it's fake
why because these characters many of
them are rarely used you know in Chinese
cultures literally you have practically
you need to know every let's say high
school student knows three thousand four
thousand Chinese characters if you in
college if you graduate college you know
maybe six thousand five six thousand
Chinese characters but if you look at in
the dictionary there are like ten
thousand thirty twenty thousand thirty
thousand characters you know so if you
look at that vast majority of them are
rarely used so anyway so that's Chinese
characters okay
and this
then you have this one this this is
mostly Japanese kana Japanese keyboards
okay so you got these photos
okay so let's close that let's get back
to vectors then mathematics math the
mathematics of vectors
intro to Chinese punctuation now this
you guys might find it interesting
because because you know I show you how
Chinese function punctuation are used
and how it differs from English ones but
basically they are the same okay well
basically let's say 200 years ago when
you write Chinese
you don't write concretions in general
you don't you don't have punctuation you
don't write you don't use them you might
use space but you don't really use
punctuation 200 years ago then then you
started to add punctuation but anyway so
that that is about that copy cross back
to Emacs back to Emacs here and Chinese
from keyword punctuation from keyboard
magnify and delete that and showing
browser so BA says don't you have a Mac
so bad embosses okay okay so let's shall
we go to the start to talk about vectors
there are six people watching I suppose
I should okay let's go to victors so
vectors now the serious stuff
mathematics commence the serious stuff
let's see some art blog so first of all
I need to go to start row wait sure okay
so I need to find the so by the way
we were doing this
this doesn't even we were doing this the
other day that is why we are we want to
write vectors I mean that's why we want
to write the matrices matrix and the
stuff okay so let's see typescript
okay so actually so here are the bunch
of vector functions and today we are
going to write we are going to write
write vector function vector and matrix
functions okay
in JavaScript okay so first of all begin
a JavaScript language okay so move it
there then we gonna copy some of these
here so we have easier time so hold on a
second let's close it's open a new
window where not that oh god I hate this
let's start Emacs again fresh start
close that window close that window so I
got my Emacs that's opened a new window
move it here and start command log mod
and create a new window and let's make
this window set background color
yeah least colored is free comfy crash
hacker welcome aboard
crash hacker is a hacker of high order
crash Shaka is a artificial intelligence
on visual wreck image recognition
good morning crash hacker good morning
good a good night to Japan so what are
we doing here I got confused okay we
need to get to get some vectors going
yeah so crash hacker this is probably
gonna be boring to you
artificial intelligence on um you know
image face recognition was it face
recognition or what I mean what exactly
can you tell us that would be
interesting yeah tell us
shaaka what is your research about
meanwhile I do this vector here I do
this vector stuff here you know the
basics mathematics of writing JavaScript
functions to do rotation matrices linear
transformation matrices and there it is
okay so that that okay so okay so
skeletal what skeletal Oh Rica
oh I remember so you have a human for
example the camera is pointing at a
sports stadium soccer or football and
people are moving and so you have a
camera pointed at it and you want to
determine basically you want to you want
the computer to draw a skeleton like
stick figures knowing where is the
joints where is the arm right so
basically the fundamentals of you know
image recognition recomment and from
videos yes that's right
follow your channel what do you mean you
follow my channel my youtube channel the
morning to cool for school
so too cool for school are you a
JavaScript coder
I forgot and where you from I forgot all
that so I'm a little bit confused so
let's start coding okay so actually if
we're gonna start coding I mean if we go
I'm gonna start to explain these things
and we are not going to be chatting
anymore because there's a lot to do here
so let's just let's just begin typing
okay so so actually magnify we are going
to write a bunch of functions that does
matrix and vector okay and the
multiplication and these functions will
work in any dimension dimensions for
example like we talked before when we
have a vector you can see on this page
that's a two-dimensional vector
represented by two points but in three
dimension you have X Y and you have
z-axis you know going up and so you it's
represented by three numbers so each
point in space or you can call it
vectors is represented by three numbers
now in fourth dimension don't worry
about what it is but mathematic
mathematically in fourth dimension it's
the same thing it's just a number it's a
point in fourth dimension is a number
represented by four numbers and same
thing for fifth dimension sixth
dimension so that so we are going to
write a function that computers in
arbitrary dimensions so let's get back
to
so let's begin so first of all we define
some of the conveniences functions so
this range this range function create a
range this range function just like
Python range it creates array and the
dot product of two functions two vectors
okay so let's modify this I'm gonna show
you okay so actually TV oh that so so
dot vector product of two vectors what
else does it mean it means we want for
example we have a b c dot a b c dot by x
y z is equals to is a times X P times Y
C times Z and you actually you add them
together okay so it's like that
PR OD UC T this is what that product
means okay okay this toolbox annoying
can we get rid of it over here so okay
so comfy skeletal smh what does sm h
what does sm h means so hello everyone
so cool for school so crash hacker says
yeah so it can be used to post
estimations and generate poses oh okay I
know what you talked about no this is
completely different and you also you
are also pretty good okay let's let's
continuing with the vector step I don't
know how you know let's didn't we be
already been talking about 30 minutes
it's let's do another 30 minutes let's
see where we go so that product okay so
this is what that product means and we
are just going to write a function for
it and now we already have a function
you can see now this is typescript
syntax let me remove the typescript okay
now it's now it's JavaScript so so this
this function does the dot product of a
vector in two dimensions you see that's
not what you want we want a function
that's generalized for any dimension of
vectors we we want to you know when the
vector has three numbers or four numbers
we can add two of them together
that's called a dot product okay so how
do you do that okay so vector dot two
vectors vectors can be of any dimension
okay so this is part of the JavaScript
tutorial so this these vectors we we
will it will be vector
dot-dot-dot let me show you the advanced
use of JavaScript
Eggman script 2015 so this is actually
the were the way we write it so let's
say vector not vector okay so Vic vector
dot dot means you have one or more
vectors so this is actually represent
one or more vectors and you want the
result to be let me show you here but I
forgot the syntax so let's look up the
syntax so you go to sorry JavaScript
in-depth then you let's see okay so wait
so close that close that close that so
sorry JavaScript in-depth then you go to
Java screaming in-depth that's correct
you want let constant variable okay so
we we want destructuring assignment
actually we want we are defining a
function so we want this we want this
argument this structure so this is how
you do it actually do I need to explain
it actually I should but I don't know
what I am doing
so actually argument the structure this
structure is not what we want
what we want is the rest per am okay you
see there it is so I got it incorrect so
let's go to rest params okay but by the
way by oh by the way you go to my talk
show and by my tutorial okay let's put
it here so JavaScript you know my
JavaScript in depth I mentioned this a
few times you this is JavaScript in
depth you got the best book in you know
I claim this is to be the best
JavaScript book in English language okay
including or printed ones so
you like it you might give it a shot you
like it you buy it okay so that's that's
about that so let's back to the
javascript rest from rest parameters
okay function rest parameters so so you
give it three dots followed by a name
the three dots followed by a name in
function body the name is received as an
array okay so that's that's that's what
it is so let's go back to the code
where's our code there
so here the vector the vector is a
vector of any dimension so so basically
its array but what we want to do here so
you see we want to do this we want to do
that but we wanted to be any dimension
so the addition can be done by your
reduce function okay
later on but first of all you need so
you are given on a bunch of vectors in
array which is a nested array so you are
you are given a array each element is a
vector and that vector may have four
elements you know four numbers four
dimensional vector anyway so so you have
a array each element is a vector now
what you want to do is is you want to
add the corresponding components of a
vector into one into together I mean you
want to multiply like like this okay
like like like this example here a plus
a times X P times Y C times Z or like
this so how do you do how we do it so
so you see this this how do you do it I
have to think you know the easiest way
is to write a for loop but I don't want
to use for loop we want to use
functional programming so anyway let me
think for a minute okay so you got a
bunch of vectors and the result will be
one single vector right the result will
be one single vector actually yeah
that's it I got it so vector dot reduce
reduce it
so you see what what does why reduce
because we the input is a bunch of
vectors you know a bunch of elements are
you so array and the result will be just
one thing so basically reduce collapse
the array so that reduce now in reduce
first of all we need to give a function
so arrow function so we get we give it a
arrow function and the arrow function
will be a vector okay okay so this
should be vectors because there are many
of them okay and here we say vector okay
this is represent one single vector and
the thing one single vector will return
so your function so this function this
arrow function will be applied to two
vectors do I make sense like do I make
sense or am I just talking to myself
okay you see this this this function
here okay this is getting a bit
complicated so initial value I don't
think we need it so let's make it clear
here okay so here you have a function
the function the input is oh the input
vector 1 and with a vector 1 and vector
2 okay so that's the input because we
are calling reduce so it takes two
vectors then the result will be like
that ok so basically like that
how do you its how do you express this
so let me let me just type it out so
this is this would be like this okay so
this would be a1 a2 a3 a4 let's say for
for vector I mean a four dimensional
vector and over here it will be b1 b2 b3
b4 okay
and the result should be the result
should be the component of that added by
the component of that so it will be
something like this okay so let me write
it not add but multiply okay so so we
there it is so a2 times b2 a3 times B 3
a 4 times B 4 okay so actually this is
the result we want okay so actually like
that if the input are two four
dimensional vectors like that then our
reduced function should return this so a
1 B 1 a 2 B 2 a 3 B 3 a 4 B 4 it returns
one single vector of that dimension
right that's our first reduce needs to
do but the problem is you see the
problem is we need to express you see in
this formula we have the explicit
components we are using the explicit
components but over here over here the
v1 v2 we do not know how many dimensions
it is
so so how do you do this I have to think
actually I have to think about this so
okay so this is getting Oh 3% everyone
is gone gone home
okay I'm just gonna walk out myself then
okay so so we need to sell this reduce
so we need to write a function a 1 a 2
vectors okay so we don't need we don't
know the dimension it returns the vector
okay so it returns a vector we don't
know the length
map so can we use map No
well how do you do this
first of all is the reduce correct yes
it's correct the problem is to turn this
into into this line that without using
the components so two vectors becomes
one vector so two vectors becomes one
vector
yeah actually I don't know how to do
that unless maybe unless you use loop
for loop but we we don't want to use for
loop that's the thing so if if
javascript has parallel map in
Mathematica it's called map thread or in
Common Lisp in wisp you have a map
function that takes a second argument
basically the argument can be arbitrary
number of lists then it will map
parallel that's what we need but
JavaScript do not have that let's go
look at JavaScript array functions so
array let's look at array parents and so
on and array prototype okay let's see
you away from array 2 now let's look at
array prototype
okay so array prototype you got bunch of
functions so lengths constructor pop
push shift and shifts price feel copy
with no entries keys values map for each
okay yeah for each right for each that's
what we need to do
stupid JavaScript okay for each for each
element in array you give it a arrow
function okay so arrow function I so
let's look at for each you need also the
index and the function is passed three
arguments okay so the function is passed
three arguments as we I mean current
element that's x then the current index
that's I okay that's what we need so
this function can admin connect index
okay so it returns
not for each actually we need map
there it is X time so that is that okay
and in fact we got that so that's how
you express it we one map then the
element of V 1 and the index so element
of V 1 times the corresponding element
in V 2 that's how you do it so that how
you program with C+ first now I'm doing
JavaScript so once we have that you see
once we do this the result is one vector
of n summation then we just do another
reduce okay we just do dot reduce again
functional programming now this time
it's easy all we have to do is just add
them all together so a B no the add add
the vectors elements together so so so
this this so a B you just say a plus B
yeah actually that's it okay so actually
this is our function this is actually
done although it's hard to read I mean
they mean create so this is a function
dot product of two vectors vectors can
be of any dimension and the first one is
not product of two vectors vector must
be 2d okay so actually let's let's make
it simpler okay I mean let's make it
easier to see what we are doing so for
example vector dot this one we
we'll be code vector dot 2d okay and
this one will be vector dot 3d so so
this will be a 2 a 3 B 3 then plus a 3
times P 3 can you see that yeah so now
what about 40 and 50 and 60 and so on so
we are creating this new function that
does everything in one shot one banging
shot okay so this this is our fantastic
function so let me clear the code a
little bit so it's easier to see so it
becomes vectored reduce okay actually
this
let's click clear the code okay
vector reduce map and yeah that's a code
I don't know if you can read it it's
kind of you know functional programming
in JavaScript the JavaScript syntax is
very bad so that's why it's hard to
format them so it's readable but anyway
so I think this is how it works okay
actually so vector actually the dot dot
dot should be P before not after
okay wait is it before after so let's go
back to JavaScript in-depth and let's go
look at the rest parameters so it should
be in before okay so this is a
generalized version
let's test okay let's just test see if
it works so first of all F range let's
say five okay and constant error
function so constant constant so let's
say my array
my my back
okay back a yeah that doesn't make sense
you know what we doing vector a is
equals to 1 2 3 okay let's just say 1 2
vector B 3 4 now we gonna call
okay so let's run this let's see okay so
I got some arrow here and none oh yeah
we don't we don't need this wrench
remove that okay let's do it again so
the result is 11 so that means 1 plus 3
is 4 2 plus 4 is 6 1 plus 3 is 4 2 plus
4 is 6 4 times 4 what wait 1 times 3 is
3 2 times 4 is 8
a plus 3 is 11 so that is why the result
is you have incorrect so this is correct
now let's use our fancy version okay
let's see if it works
you know our fancy generalized version
let's run at 11 success success okay so
actually now let's do this again okay so
actually so yes
so let's instead of constant let's say
let okay so this time we're gonna have
three numbers let's say with random
number okay and this is gonna be 3d ok
and Vav - oh actually dot product yeah
so actually our code is actually far
more generalized than we need because
the argument to our code at most is just
two vectors
here we have actually we we made it so
that it allows any arbitrary of vectors
but that product is only defined for two
vectors so anyway so our code turns out
to be more generalized so anyway let's
run these to see it if it works run it
okay let V a so what is the problem
identify a VA has already been think
declared you know shut up so okay so
okay so let's change them back to
constant okay so now we see VD okay run
it okay so I need to change here too we
see VD vennett fantastic they agree you
can see the result we actually saw we
are done with this generalized
generalized dot function dot product of
two vectors vectors can be of any
dimension okay so what what are we gonna
do now so it's kind of is it boring he's
already fifteen minutes
he said boring actually we have you know
originally I have a lot to do but
actually explaining it takes a lot of
time so here is the other code for so
bit so basically on the Left window you
can see all these code but these code
are designed for two-dimensional vectors
only so actually so let me show you so
you can see you have the dot product of
two vectors but that's only for
two-dimensional vectors hey good morning
George and then we have angle between
two vectors yeah so this code also need
to be generalized to put three dimension
and you have okay so you have vector
lengths this also needs to be
generalized for higher dimension
actually that works so let's write it
okay
returns the length of the vector now the
vector the length here means the
geometry of length not you know number
of elements the geometry of length which
means it's you see it means here to here
can we do it
oh yeah because I have Auto Creek on so
that's the L length and that is our code
to here so that's this code that's this
code actually we don't need a number
here
so V is a vector and the math hypo T is
is a function from JavaScript 2015 so
this is a powerful code it just returns
the length of the vector doesn't matter
what how many intervention it is you
know what it does you know but do you
know the math function of it so what not
so what so what are we gonna do
should we continue with this or talk
random because we already screwed up I
think let's see should we continue about
vectors or should we go somewhere else
and maybe that's it for today because
already let's see what what our people
are saying here ooh
King King William ah so Radiohead what
is this Oh God
King herring
okay here's what we're gonna do we're
gonna write we're gonna continue for a
bit let's continue this so this
hypotenuse you know what it means
let me show you what it means okay so
okay so let me show you okay so we turn
the length of vector of 2d vector of a
2d vector okay so we learned 2d okay
share research on Kong land oh that's
that's a great suggestion
screw the mathematics because it's kind
of boring and I'm not you know really
doing it in a concentrated way you know
in fact we did two videos on these math
vectors but every time it takes a long
time it's like I suppose that's that's
not big
well partly because I'm doing video well
what I'm saying is that you know if you
look at the professors they do they do
they teach these things it does take a
long time you have to explain all the
things so Kong LAN what about so share
research Zhang :
Oh what I don't have any so what what
what is am I gonna talk about that so I
was reading okay so I was reading
volapük okay Val of hook this is a
constructed language you know I had a
interested
I had an interest about constructed
languages in since 1990s so back then
you don't have internet so I went to the
library I
you know quite a few books about them
you know there's a Esperanto at the time
Esperanto is the most popular one still
is today so you have Esperanto and you
know constructed languages so let me let
me give you let me give you guys a short
account of what these constructed
languages are about so constructed
languages they are out of you know is
used to be they we call it artificial
languages but I think since 2010 or some
things people started to say constructed
languages more popular for reasons I
don't know why I suppose you know the
the phrase constructed languages is more
suitable because they are constructed so
why why do people you know it's just
these are languages intended for human
communication these languages are
created out of out of the blue unlike
natural languages such as English French
Chinese Japanese Korean you know this
Spanish these are natural naturally
developed languages but since modern
days we started to know that you know
why don't we create a language out of
the blue why do people want to do that
for a few reasons
one reason is that natural languages is
very complex okay
for example in English you have a whole
bunch of complex grammars and exceptions
inspiring exceptions in pronunciation
and the roots the words roots doesn't
make sense for example for example let's
see what an example let's see okay let's
go to worry English my body English proc
okay so I I have some example here I
remember there's lots of examples for
example there it is sweet
asleep sexual and a sexual you see that
there you see when you
sexual and a sexual the you you know
you're adding you add the prefix there a
to mean almost like none of it
so sexual is like you know something you
know human was sexual but if you say uh
sexual that means you are not you don't
have sex you are not interested in sex
so you don't you know no sex so the
prefix a is kind of means none oh you
know so but however you have sleep in
asleep but the a the the the word asleep
does not mean no sleep it means you are
sleeping so there is a kind of a
inconsistency you see and also also
since you have a if you had a a in front
of a word to mean none of it then does
that mean every word that start with a
also means none of it none of the it of
the following word no it doesn't mean
that because because English is not you
know such a consistent you know regular
language and we have lots of this kind
of examples so sexual sexual sleeper
sleeps linguistic or conflict that is
English then you have an I in okay so
for example let me show you this a
versus UN versus in for example is for
example flammable flammable inflammable
that's that's popular example okay okay
flammable fire then you have in
inflammable they mean same thing they
mean something but however the problem
is that when you add the prefix in
usually it means it doesn't you know
it's like being active for example
active inactive you know they are
opposite
but however the flammable and
inflammable they are not opposite they
mean the same thing so you have this
problem the inconsistent inconsistency
problem of English and this doesn't just
happen in English so you see flammable
inflammable here is it means capable
being set on fire
flammable it means the same thing as
final flammable but however the active
inactive they are opposite then you also
have an undo for example and do do and
undo then you have understand understand
so but it doesn't mean understand you
know it doesn't mean and stand not like
not the stand
what is the entomology of understand so
you have this kind of funny see you know
these these situations and this is not
this are not surprising at all because
because almost every language this
happens for example you also have you
have also English you have quasi pseudo
and semi ok that's in very interesting
prefixes quasi pseudo semi they they
have slightly different meanings so and
and this happens in French in Chinese
almost every language in Spanish almost
everywhere inconsistent because they are
not regular these are natural languages
now so therefore people won't want to
have a people started to have an idea
that why don't we just create a language
by design so there is no such problem
such as this and there's no irregularity
in Israeli no irregularity in grammar no
irregularity in in pronunciation so it
should be things should be extremely
simple so people children for example
can easily don't learn the
learn the language okay so so that is
you know because education is a big
thing you know in every country
you worry about education because
education is quite important you worry
about it you try to reform spelling or
you try to have spelling bees to
encourage people to understand how
things are spelled why is it so
difficult because it's quite up
you know that's natural language very
complex so you each government in each
country they spend you have committees
educational committees you have you know
language awareness you know things like
that they you want people to to be
educated addition writing and you know
increase literacy you don't want people
to be illiterate you know when you look
at word statistics literacy so almost
the most important one of the most
important quantity you know call of you
know how to see how advanced is the
country because so reading is important
so that's why you know because this
education because you know so people
want to start it you think they can
create a language then if we all just
adopt this language then all this
problem will be solved you saw billions
of dollars things like that so that's
kind of the the origin of constructed
languages one of the reason okay that's
one of the reason there are other
reasons now the other reason is that for
example when you have United you end you
know the you and the United Nations
things like that every country go there
and talk you know about important things
so but the language is a barrier you
knows English French Spanish Chinese
Japanese you can understand each other
so the idea is that if you have a
constructed language each person can
speak this language and we can all
communicate
that's a that's the that's the other
significant reason the goal of consort
it's constructive language so everyone
can you don't you you no longer have the
language barrier problem and it's easy
to learn so you know you use our our
problems so that's two issues okay there
are also other issues such as cultural
issues code culture issues because
language is kind of intimacy I mean it's
kind of tied to the culture for example
you have American culture you United
Kingdom culture you speak English and
because language is developed by people
out of a region you know over the past
thousands of years so the language the
words in the language what they means
tends to be associated with this
particular culture English you know
United Kingdom in America on the other
hand Chinese for example Chinese
language they developed in Asia they
have their you know you have many words
and concepts you know and you don't have
English so when you when when two
countries or multiple countries get
together when you want to speak one
language there is the problem of you
know like language is is is a very much
a political issue for example in Canada
there are official languages Capek you
know québécois the French Canadian
Canadian French language but also
English you know what you were you know
you might think oh what why to mean
let's let's just change it or just to
English but that's a problem because
those people respect speaks québécois on
the east eastern side of the Canada the
it's a party you know the that means
they have to learn their children have
to learn a new language it also means
they are learning a language that
doesn't reflect their culture
so it's a problem you know you know they
wouldn't want to just let's switch to
English
meanwhile in the same way if you switch
to French then the English because you
know it's a problem in the same way you
don't want for example you don't want
Chinese to tell you let's let's let the
word language be Chinese and in the same
way English to actually you know and
also when a country invents invade
another country for example Japan
invades you know China you know in World
War two
once they invade the country they
typically often okay they force the
people to speak their language why no
because the language is very much
associated with culture you know you you
want to spread your language and and
English to English you know in in
history English swear to are forced upon
other people you know to speak English
India for example and then then then
German for example Germany eyes I think
that also happens anyway so so my point
here is that language is very tightly
associated with a culture or race or
country and if you are thinking about
internet international language you have
a problem of choosing one language to be
the international language because all
the others don't want just to adopt your
language to be to be the International
one so that's another reason for the for
the rise of the photog for the purpose
of constructed language that's these
nerds are thinking I mean that that's
that's ideal you know that's an idea of
situation let's country let's create a
language that is you know let's sit
together create design a language that
is easy to learn that house doesn't have
cultural bias you know it's not learn
English it's not German it's not French
you know it's like neutral you know new
language
and everyone can learn it and use it for
international communication so that's
the three primary reason for for the
rise of constructed languages extremely
easy to learn neutral no cultural bias
neutral and and to be used as a lingua
franca you know the international
language yeah so that that's essentially
that's that's a that's the you know the
the force behind the reasons for
constructive language so I was you know
I was so in 1990s I was interested in
them I read a bunch of books I did you
know I read at least the first the first
chapters and you know the discussion
about constructive and languages so so
you have so the first one of these of
this is this one the the value POC okay
this one is created in the 1880s okay
and 1880 and it kind of died because
there is struggle there is I mean this
so for example you know it's interesting
I read today so this guy your hand
Martin Schuyler shy German
people okay a German person he okay hold
on a second he so he created it he is a
Roman Catholic priest and you know he
says he felt that God has told him in a
dream to create an international
language that's kind of seedy now
remember this is 1880s
you know today with the anti card
movement you know the atheist movement
going strong the you know the the the
the the really you know the the Catholic
or religious
religion has kind of waned much so so
today's society is you know pretty much
profane not not like before because
before in 1880's you like everyone has
to go to churches and to lots of other
things so anyway he you know so he
created so I mean you if you look at
look back at the engine you find it kind
of funny so you have this priest Roman
Catholic priest he he felt that God told
him to do it so he created it okay but
then you see they have conferences you
know then they have arguments because
the followers who speak this language
you know who learned this language they
have conventions you know this 1818 80s
they have conventions and they they
think you know there needs to be some
change or improvements to the language
but however this guy refused you know he
doesn't want any change he think my
design is the best I don't want any
change so the people started to have
arguments then open you know the like
serious arguments like they fighting for
power you know the the Institute of this
you know the so he was president and he
doesn't you know one day he don't you
don't want to have anything to do with
the organization anymore because so he
started another you know this Academy
yeah Academy of Valu Park you know so
there's serious arguments and eventually
and other people you know because he
doesn't want to change so other people
created new constructed languages you
know for example now be this one now by
now this is one of them in the quite a
few according to Wikipedia so basically
in the end this this just the death the
death of value Park because people don't
agree they want to you know they want to
struggle you know the idea you know when
so when this happens happen you know
when these
valeu puppies created everyone is like
oh this should be the international
language you know solve a lot of
problems you know peace on earth like
that he actually is not peace on earth
when you know when you want some change
I don't agree I want my way to be the
way like like like free software
foundation and open source and the Linux
the Linux distros and there's funny it's
funny there is a line wreck okay there's
a line I'm Rick a charming young student
of guac once tried to acquire Vala puck
but it sounded so bad that her friends
called her mad and she quit in less than
a walk a walk is a week I think so
someone you know some observer created
this lime wreck to describe the
situation of this Val of hawk at the
time this is all samara park so anyway
in 1987 three years basically you know
seven years then Esperanto Esperanto
arose you know so this guy created
Esperanto you know this is other so
that's another entirely new different
one so that's that's about what I you
know don't know about constructed
languages okay so so that's it I think
so guys you snow here so that's its
that's that's it I think George
so George what do you think do you have
like opinions what do you think about
constructed languages let's see I'm
gonna shut down in a minute or two I
think any comments any guys you have ten
people here so any comments we can I'm
gonna shut down in a minute so yeah so
you have Esperanto then you have you
have quite a few today you have like 10
or 20 of them at least you know and also
some of them some of the by the way so I
talked about that VeloPark
in Esperanto these are two primary
constructed languages that are designed
to be a international language okay but
besides these they are other constructed
languages that's designed for other
purposes for example in the in a novel
Lord of the Rings and that guy created
you know a couple of languages the
elvish language we talked about
yesterday or before in length so he
created the elvish language why because
it's a hobby you know it's a hobby for
him he's learning linguist so he created
the elvish language for for his novel
partly for his novel Lord of the Rings
but partly also just because it's fun to
do for him so he created this complexity
right and so so so but right but there's
also loads wrong but anyway so you have
the elvish language for that's that's
the purpose of that is for the for
entertainment for hobby you know for a
Lord of the Rings
the novel but then for example in Star
Trek you also have the Kringle
language you know created out of the
science fiction and what superb is also
so so the elvish language in Klingon
their purpose is different from the
Esperanto envelope so Esperanto
VeloPark they are designed to be
international language but the elvish
language in Klingon they are kind of
just for hobby for fun for you know for
create you know for fun on the other
hand you have things like lachemann and
Lachlan they are created they are
created the purpose of them is to study
the language structure
I mean Lachlan and lushbough they are
created so that they are trying to
create a language that is based on logic
you know the mathematical sense of logic
so they want they are trying to explore
you know in other words to explore what
is the most you know the logic logic
needs logic allottee of language can you
do that like you know so that's that's
the purpose of LaVon and George say
smart and her Bruce supposedly is the
only successful Colin is that true can
we I mean okay so I guess why I guess I
can take what you say it for granted but
the problem is so George says modern
Hebrew is the only successful
constructed language you see the problem
is how do you obsess me I mean how can
you call this a constructive language I
think then that's a blur blurring the
line because you know that's I think
that's kind of blurring the line I think
yeah
because because okay so I don't know I
don't know what's the deal but for me to
answer that question well I have to
answer that because you know because I
have to make a judgment whether that's
correct statement so the statement is
model modern Hebrew supposedly is the
only successful con line constructed
language so so I have to think about I
have to decide whether modern Hebrew
count is a constructed language now in
order to decide on that I need to know
to what degree it is constructed so I
think that is a key so you know I'm just
talking about my thoughts and sharing my
you know thought flow about these issues
so to what degree modern Hebrew is
constructed I don't know so I have to
read this article so I don't know what
are you joking are you half joking
George touch Church probably know a lot
about these things
George is Georgie is very knowledgeable
in brought kind of brought what we okay
I think that's it for today so thank you
guys for watching bye guys
Oh bops sohbats so so I know not a joke
that's what people say oh okay so okay I
are gonna check out what's going on
there so but we might you know actually
what's this so this to chat okay
actually that's to chat offline I mean I
can't you know I want to to to do life
but I can't just you know it would be
much better if we can talk like offline
then you know then we you know we then
then we see where to go you know we can
talk to a lot of people not just you and
me and also many others you know who
watch my video you know we and in fact
we've done that before so we are missing
you but so if you join that would be
much fun I cannot Twitter you I cannot
you know master than you know it's it's
no fun yeah and it's not like I have if
you if it's gonna be email then it's
gonna be you know it's become say walk
you know but this is what's really fun
so yeah so let's talk okay bye guys