good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sun talk show
today is august 17
2020 seven o'clock in the
evening san francisco time and today we
are going to do
emacs and emacs list we're gonna talk
about it
and we're gonna do coding uh probably
so let me show the background image so
this background image is basically
photo someone took on my emacs website
uh it's just some sign ux
land development consultants i'm not
sure what that is but apparently some
company named
emacs that's a background image
and today we're gonna do actually i have
several topics okay
and uh several topics
and let me um so you guys
pick which one which topic i should do
okay you guys pick one let me
let me post the uh link here
i mean let me write the text out
magnify so on the on the right window
you can see all my emacs keys and
comments
um okay so let me
so pick a topic let me know which topic
you want i'm going to post the topic
topics here so good morning
papamu lunarus
and so here is other topics
type type it and pick one okay
um i'm gonna do any one of these
good morning papa mung and good morning
daniel langlois haven't seen you
for a while for a long time uh and in
fact the near langlow is
you probably already know you would be
glad to know
that your huge contribution to saffron
keys
the rewriting of the engine has been
implemented
so thank you for that uh yeah so i'm
using it
right now so that's that that is
fantastic
so so pick one of these topics okay
let me know which one uh
we gonna do okay so
so do that so let me type it
pick a topic type
it or else we're gonna start
yeah daniel langlois so
so one of the topic is so
so let me let me let me explain okay so
display hdr for example in html mod
you know i can type in microsoft html
mod i can type hr
and you have that which is a line break
horizontal
ruler rule i want to display it
displayed in emax with a line like that
so i can visually see it right now it's
not working
well right yeah because what you are
seeing here
is actually the form feed character
so that is let me show you describe
char so that character is called
form feed okay and it has a code point
of 12. it's one of the ascii character
code point 12. now normally in
emacs it will show up like that you
probably have seen
because the form feed is a tradition
it's a convention it's like
a convention from 1980s to indicate a
section in your source code
okay so so yeah so so okay so let's do
that so
papa moon says write the command to
remove paragraph
tag and and also this display h
as a horizontal line
okay let's do that damn it youtube not
allowing a new line okay yeah let's do
that then let's
let's let's start to do that close that
close
so close that so here is my talk show
page showing browser
so we are going to code hr so let's
begin
so so first of all let me explain what's
going on okay so first
uh yeah so form feed sorry
e max form feed
search in browser because i have
articles about that i have quite a few
articles about these
so form feed it's a it's a ascii
character
uh code point 12. it's a
in invisible unprintable ascii character
okay
it's you know imprint you know some
ascii characters are not printable
printable such as new line uh such as uh
carriage returns such as tabs you know
so this is one of them
from feed and by convention it's 1980s
convention they use this to indicate
a section break in your source code
for example in e-max list you'll see it
in lots of places
for example let's let's do some live
uh workflow demo so let's go to the
uh let's go to a diode okay
for example let's go to e shell
so we are in isha now so i want to look
up the
uh source code for isha so i
i what i do is um i call describe key
then press the key for isha
so here is the result so i can just
press tab
to go into it so now we are looking at
the source code of isha
by the way on the right on the pink
window on the purple window is
all the commands and keystrokes i call
you can so if you don't know what i'm
doing you can just
look it up and here you'll probably
find the source code on my website so
you see if i move cursor it's going to
show in the ping window
so anyway we are in the ishao source
code
and let's go to the top let's see if we
can see that form
feed character
okay so wait isha is not this short nah
this is wrong
the isha you know so isha is uh written
by john wigley which is the current
emacs leader the maintainer they call
he he has been for the past four or five
years
so let's go to the yeah eshow has
actually that's just uh that's just the
first page it has lots you know it's not
just
it's thousands of lines so let's go to
any of the isha
uh source code let's see if we can spot
that
form feed character okay i don't think
this guy uses that convention
okay i'm not seeing it okay let's close
it let's try
another one let's let's try shell okay
the
shell key stroke is
um yeah so let's describe function
control h f shell
okay so here is the documentation for
xiao
and let's tab to go into the source code
okay here we are at shell source code
and magnify
go down go down
wait interesting i don't see the phone
feed character
i thought i would see it here because
this is one of the old source code
so let's actually search list matching
lines
then i'm going to type the phone feed
character how do you type it
you press ctrl q ctrl l
okay so in the mini mini buffer you can
see that
so if i press enter no match found
okay so it's not in the source code of
diode
neither so wait amazing
we tried to source code files and we
don't see it
now let's try some other we need to find
some old
uh mod it should be in direct but maybe
the new people removed it that's that's
unlikely so let's try another one
let's try cc mod okay c
mod cc mod so this control describe
function control f
control h f then c mod
let's say c mod okay
okay here is the um here is the
documentation for cmat
cc mod tab into it enter
then we are looking at the source code
of cc mod
go to the top scroll down we don't i
don't think i see it
now let's call these matching lines
ctrl q control l to type the form feed
character enter there it is we found it
now go to it you see you see it there
now you now you see it's displayed as a
line
but actually that's that's because i did
something in my init file
but because you are reading you are
looking at i'm using
some e-max least smart you can see in
the
mod line i'm using my own e-max least
mod
but let's switch it to emax
this smart the default so control
meta x e max b smart
enter you see that that
you see you don't see the line anymore
you see you see this l
so so this l that is the form feed
character so you move the cursor
on the character then you call describe
char
i have a keystroke for that then you can
see
the description of that character you
see code point 12
and the the name of the character is
phone feed
by the way in unicode in unicode at some
point they change the name you see you
you it was used
it used to be called form feed but in
unicode version
9 or something 2010 or something
they changed the name into
into a uh into this name control so
so the first 10 characters in unicode in
ascii
unprintable characters they are all just
named control i i
i'm not sure why they do that i don't
think it's a good thing to do because
they must have reasons but anyway the
first 10 also characters is all named
control now
so anyway since we are talking about
this okay close that close that
so what was that mod net mod is cc mod
copy the file path close it paste it
here
link it and phone feed and phone feed
character okay
go to the browser copy the url back to
emacs
paste the link here so we have the log
of what we talked about showing browser
so we are talking about the phone feed
character
uh you can read that page that page
gives you a lot details and philosophy
about about
how should you demarcate a section in
source code
you know usually there are many ways for
example here are the
some of the typical ways you see using
the common character
so anyway that's a form feed character
but there's one more thing let me show
you
you go to a browser open a new page
cassari ascii table
okay any question and comments okay type
in the chat box
i'm gonna read it and reply so you look
at ascii
uh tables so here is the ascii table
form feed is one of them so let's
magnify
so you see from feed is here
so you have foam feed you have line feed
you have horizontal tab you have
backspace you have bail
you have some other esoteric esoteric
ones such as
acknowledgement inquiry end of
transmission by the way this
end of transmission you must be familiar
because in terminal
you press ctrl d to exit the terminal
you know they they have kind of rich
history and you have newer character
which is often used to indicate end of
file
so you have the familiar horizontal tab
line feed but then line feed vertical
tab form feed
which we don't use much anymore you have
carriage return
then you have uh others
okay so that's the ascii character okay
copy the url back to emacs
paste it here
uh showing browser
uh okay we got something wrong here
let's remove the
showing browser okay
so we talked about phone feed so what's
the trick of showing the phone feed okay
let me show you i it's it's another one
of my page i mentioned it
uh go to the form feed so if you just
want to
if you just want a practical tip on how
to
display the phone feed as a line then go
to this page okay
show form feed as a line
so let me paste it here
topic notes uh
did i close it i close it go to talk
show
today today's talk show magnify
okay and we are going to actually look
at the code on how to do it
i need to do this fast because i'm not
sure we can do it
uh how long have i been talking so
okay
so we've been talking for 15 minutes
okay let me let me start to do this
uh so what we want to do is because we
are going to borrow some code i need to
look at this
because i don't know how to do it
offhand
so show form feed as a line
by the way there's some very interesting
uh questions
let me let me let me continue talking
okay
so form feed i i actually do use that in
my code for example if i go to cassava
keys
uh you go to the top you can see magnify
you can see
wait oh i removed those okay never mind
i used to use the phone v character but
anyway i have a keystroke to insert
so how do you insert from feed control q
control l that's how you insert it
and uh but i actually i have a
shortcut key so i just call
insert from feed then you just insert
that character so let's go back let's
it's not save it so that's how you so
so so let's now
now let's study how do you actually do
it
so actually i have this command start
show form feed a slide
uh let's describe function and let's do
let's copy it okay copy it back to emacs
okay consortium show form feeders line
describe
function paste it and show the
documentation and go to the source code
so it's part of
stuff like keys so copy it copy the code
close it
then we're gonna create a emax list
code here and paste it and we gonna
uh we're gonna start to code it so let's
go over the code let's see what's going
on
so by the way there are many several
packages
online on mailpi and elsewhere on the
emacs wiki
that that shows the form feed as a line
but however you know i've tried several
of them they all have a problem
uh the problem is the problem was
ah actually i don't remember now it's
been several years now
this topic
let's see if i uh explained it
here somewhere
i maybe i have i have written about it
somewhere but
anyway the point is that many all these
packages
there are several of them and in several
of them written by the
greatest emac list coders you know for
example there's one written by
by this guy who wrote diode plus
this weird and old e-max
this programmer he's a this programmer
he also wrote what's his name diaper
it's it's um
i should remember the name but if i if
we look at diet plus then we all know
the name
drew adams okay i remember the name now
i don't see the name
anyway drew adams is the old emac
oh this programmer he has actually
written
a this article in some computer science
journal
drew adams you know i think he's maybe
60 something like
that's that's my guess so drew drew adam
is a expert listener and and
he has written quite a lot packages
however uh if i remember correctly one
of the package he wrote
is displaying form feed as a line but
however that has a problem
the problem was that
sometimes it doesn't work i i forgot
exactly what's the problem
um but anyway so sometimes it doesn't
work
or or something else i i cannot remember
right now but anyway there are several
packages all have that problem until a
few years ago
this guy uh john wigley i mean
not john wiggly steve purcell he wrote
the version
and his version worked
so and one day i asked him so why is it
your version work
why is it others doesn't work he doesn't
know you know he doesn't know
neither you know it's a problem i i
couldn't find out what's the problem
i i couldn't find a book so anyway so
so then i look at his package and i
extracted the code so i rewrote it i
mean i
studied his code so so here's
my uh kind of show kind of just short
version
you know be i don't want a package like
these days there are you know a few
thousand packages on mailpad each one is
like
when you write a package you you have to
declare you know require packages
but actually all you need is a function
all you need is these
10 10 lines of code you don't need a
package so you just grab this put in
your
uh init file and your work
so for example let's switch to uh text
mod
okay let me show you how it works
let me i mean let me demo okay so switch
to uh fundamental mod
now fundamental mod is a plain basic
mark that does nothing
okay then you insert
then you insert control q control l
you see you can insert a form feed
character
character you have a form feed okay
then then it does not display or display
as a line but however now if i call the
command
saw phone feed this line then it shows
the line
you see it if your font size is large
then it becomes the line becomes
uh large so now let's go back to
ximaxlysmart okay we're gonna code this
so i don't remember how it's it's done
so let's look at the code
any any comments questions hello world
new mexico
so so so let's look at the code so
program
okay we don't need the whole program
actually
so when not buffer display table
um oh my god we're gonna look into this
we're not both a display table so so
basically
let's the outline of the code is when
so this means when the buffer does not
have the variable above a display table
when the buffer display table so that
variable
is a built-in variable it's a built-in
local buffer variable
meaning that each buffer may have a
different value the variable this
variable may have a different value in
in different buffers so it says
when the value of the buffer display
variable is neil
then it's going to create one okay
so that's what this line means so what
so let's look at what
what what is buffer display variable so
let's call describe
va describe variable okay
okay here's a documentation for it so it
says buffer display variable is a
variable defined in c
source code its value is shown below
so the documentation is automatically
becomes buffer local when
set right so documentation display
table that controls display of the
content of current buffer okay
so it so basically right so
we are trying we are going to use this
variable to
to modify how it displays the phone feed
character
so it says if this variable is new the
value of that
uh standard desktop variable is used
okay
uh each window can have its own
overriding display table okay so yeah
then it goes on to explain in detail so
let's
ignore it for now so so that's so
so we created a buffer displayed
variable i mean both a display table
then
okay so it's very simple so a set
we are going to set the variable so
buffer display table
okay we are going to set this variable
and what's the value of this variable
this v the value of this variable is
some kind of um
what's the data structure it's some kind
of um it explains here
it's a character table
yeah character table now character table
i believe is some kind of vector
i mean it's uh yeah i think
it's a specialized vector in images
you know you can look up we don't need
to worry about it for now so so
basically we want to set
so it's a vector it's a vector of
pairs yeah probably but anyway so we
want to a set a set is setting a vector
let's
describe function and let's look up so
describe
function a set now wait
uh
yeah array you know vector is array
image
so a set array index and element okay so
so we are going to set this array buffer
display table
and the index okay so i understand so
so it takes two arguments so so it takes
two arguments the first argument
is the index of the vector the second
argument is the element you want to you
know the new value so
so back to the code this element
so this this thing this question mark
backslash then then
that that is a syntax for the character
from feed so so which is ascii 12
right ascii 12 or 13
yeah ascii 12 so that is actually the
syntax for for the form feed
i mean that's the syntax for the
character form feed
which
okay so but in emacs a character has the
same
emacs a character is
indistinguishable from the integer so
when you have a character it's basically
just means the
the id of the chord point of that
character so
this character the syntax for the
character it just evaluates to the
number
12 the integer 12. so basically
you know we set the index 12th
index by
by this value vector contact
okay now i know what it's doing so you
know
so basically what what what it is doing
is just trying to
change the display of one single
character so when you when you see that
character we change it to
um to this
make life you know this a sequence of
dashes
then we just redraw frame
okay now we know how this works but it's
not going to work for us
because the key thing here
is the character we are changing the
display of a character
but for the html hdr it's not going to
work
yeah okay so we made the
showing browser okay so
okay so essentially we failed we cannot
use this code to do what we want
but is it possible uh yes i think it's
possible you have to
um okay but
yes it's possible but i do not i know
how to do it
offhand but i'm not
uh ready i'm not ready i'm not
it's not um i cannot do it right away
off my
head so how you do it
you go to emacs list tutorial
you go to my emac list tutorial then you
can see
you go to how to write the major mod
okay
then you go to the topic um
overlay highlighting
okay so i think this
okay i think we might use these uh to do
that
but actually i do not know how to do it
offhand so
that's gonna be a lot
yeah i don't know i don't know how to do
it offhand
that's gonna be you're gonna you're just
gonna be watching me
live coding it and we cannot finish it
in
30 minutes
okay so what we should do now should we
so we have two options we skip this
and do the next one which is easier
write a command to remove paragraph tag
this is pretty easy we can do it in five
minutes
or we continue
we continue i'm going to try to code
this and i'm sure
we cannot finish in 30 minutes in 30
more minutes i we i cannot finish it
but so what you get is you just you'll
be
looking at how i code
how i call emacs list how i go about
trying to find out about things and my
workflow
so which one uh pick one type guys guys
pick one
let's see how long have i been talking
pick one okay i wait for your answer
i've been talking for 31 minutes
meanwhile actually i can i can easily
finish that paragraph thing
uh
so meanwhile you know the emacs 27 came
out you know i did the video
a few days ago um and that ended up
uh as a giant rant so emacs 27
actually i'm going through the emacs 27
news which is like
1 000 2000 line
lines uh documentation about what has
been changed
i'm going through all of them and
extract
the interesting ones for you to see
so so far this is what i have so far
i have still i have still a thousand
lines to read
so i'm starting to write this short
account
and then you know then i'm going to
write a tutorial
uh you know rewrite these so that you
can easily know exactly which command to
call
what configuration you have to do
any comments no comments comment guys
comments like which topic okay
uh okay let me just begin
let me just begin start to code the
paragraph then then maybe we come back
to this okay let's quote the paragraph
so we want to write a code that
remove a paragraph tag
let's write ev's code to
remove paragraph tag okay
uh add a tag so for example
elise function okay let's say
html remove paragraph
okay make it a code make it a code
show in browser
so you can see here so we have a
paragraph so i want to write the command
so i
just press a button and it'll remove
this
p and this p so let's begin to do it
okay add a template go to
go to there uh paste it that's a
function name
defund okay so define a function
okay different yeah that's the template
okay that's what we want uh and this
will be
dog string
version
remove paragraph tag okay then let's
begin
so first of all remove paragraph tag
go to the beginning of um save exercise
let me do this quickly uh
uh if you don't know you know you just
you can always call describe function to
see what the function do
okay i i i've been doing live coding
quite a
while now so i'm not going to explain
every detail
and meanwhile i'll look at on the pink
window to see what command i'm calling
so uh let position one
okay position two that's a beginning and
end position
of the of the of the location we want
of the region so let's go to first of
all we want to grab the block
like like this is a block so users do
not have to
do a region before they call the command
so say save excursion uh search backward
uh search backward right
so
a new line two new lines
bound add no error okay
then for char
two okay then set
position one point point is the location
of your cursor that's
that returns the position of the cursor
okay
then search forward
so this part will locate the beginning
of the
beginning of the line after the empty
lines
so that's what this do so that returns
the position one
which is the beginning of the line after
the empty lines
now we want to find the end of the
position
before the empty lines so now search
forward
okay a new line two new lines
okay then backward char
move back two characters then
set position two
point okay pretty fine
so that we have set
so now we got the position
now we want the new variable
uh input string okay that's a variable
set
input string equals to both
string node properties okay start end
position one position two so that will
return
so so far the code will return the input
stream will be
the paragraph that is under cursor
which is for example if i call the
command now it will return basically
this part
so that's our input string so so now
narrow to region
okay now save
uh save
uh save session what what is the say we
want to call narrow to region
save restriction okay
when you call narrow to region you want
to call save restriction before
okay save restriction narrow to region
position one position two so that
so that emax will ignore all the buffers
all the parts that's not
in the region so we can work on the
region do replacement without worrying
about
changing other parts so that's narrow to
region then
we go back to uh
go to char buffer minimum
point minimum okay
minimum returns the position of the
minimum
i mean basically the beginning of buffer
that returns the position of the
beginning of buffer which is
usually one i think it's always always
one
so we move the character to the
beginning of buffer then
we search for word
search forward for the paragraph tag so
while we do a
while loop okay wait search for word uh
search forward bound near no error
true no error uh
okay okay we search for word and we
then we replace match
uh new text empty string okay
ignore the rest of that
so this part this part will replace
the occurrence of the the one one of the
paragraph
okay then let's do it again search
forward
yeah let's do it again then let's do the
uh
the closing paragraph tag tag okay that
i think that's it let's clean
uh clean up the code
okay eval buffer
go to a html page
go to sound talk show let's work on this
part okay so you see there's a paragraph
showing browser showing browser you see
we got this paragraph thing
now we try the command we try it we we
call the command now
it should remove that and that
let's call it xsa
html remove paragraph it done
successful one time one shot it works
successfully
okay undo now we just want to grab the
code and put it here
okay so go back to the code buffer
where is it delete it
and copy to uh clipboard
paste it here show in browser
we have the code here today's code so
wait hold on a second
we want to syntax color
showing browser refresh there it is
so so that is that
um and so maybe that's it for today
[Music]
any any questions any comments nobody
wait is this is strange am i still like
going
video check voice check i guess i'm
still going
okay so i'm thinking
that'll be yet today
seven viewers okay uh any any questions
any any questions comments
comments guys say hi or something i
think maybe that's it for today then oh
i
i'm gonna drink my drink
uh so how long have i been talking for
42 minutes uh
let's see anything else i want to say
okay that that that's it that's it for
today thank you guys for watching
uh george hey george
niminshiko nim nimshiko you are not a
programmer
okay but you are watching my video but
but you do use emacs or do you not use
emacs at all
i mean but you are my friend though
thank you for coming to watch my show
and george says emac any emacs packages
you recommend for beginner
uh yes i can recommend a few and george
you are a vim user and now you are
checking out emacs and software keys
uh that's great so let me show you some
of the command i recommend
some of the packages okay so
in order to do that let's go to my
emacs config directory
so you can see here's my emax
okay diet okay master diet george i
highly recommend diet
you know diet is the where you can um
these it's like once you master diet you
you can copy files you can delete files
for example let's let's copy delete
move you don't need to use shell anymore
you know uh in diode is much more
efficient for example let's split the
buffer
uh you know go into this directory you
see a bunch of files i
you know these are emacs backups so i
want to remove them so i just press a
key
mark them all press another key he asked
me if i want to delete yes
okay i press it but you know then it's
all good
you know so instead of in in shell you
have to do
rm then you know some scrub you know the
emac is so visual you can see what you
are doing right away
for example you can mark files um you
know you can
mark some files things like that okay
copy paste delete
change permission change the unix mod
you know the uh change mod
change owner change group and all that
the the easiest way to learn diode is
you can look at once you are in direct
you have like three uh menus
you see this one of them operate okay
one menu
and another menu for mark
and another menu for rejects
okay there actually another menu
actually
once you are entirely you have like four
five more menus
it but if you exit diet wait what
what's going on if you switch to another
buffer
you know then you see all the all the
menus are good
the the menu comes in only when you are
in diet
let's go back to diet now
so let me show you the packages i
recommend so also i have a
diet tutorial in my emacs let's go to it
okay in my emacs tutorial you go to
emacs tutorial then you can go to
diet so i first of all i talk about
files how do you open files and some of
the
uh efficient commands then buffer then
diet you know i
you know if so you guys if you are new
to emacs
of course i recommend reading going
through my tutorial and i recommend
you go through them one by one in order
okay
roughly in the first week go through
them
one by one in order and read three or
five articles a day
or more then when you need to do
something you don't know how to ask a
question
ask me or ask you know other people on
reddit or elsewhere
then when you you when you need
something a package
you know then you then you download that
package
do not you know you know alternatively
you can just download some pre-installed
you know the
bundled uh or download packages
permissibly like
people say oh this is great package you
just download it without
first first knowing what emacs the plain
emacs
offers yeah you know that's why you you
know that's one of the great
advantage of emacs is that you go
through you explore it
yourself then you customize to it
to exactly what you need that's one way
of course you can also try space mags
and others
which is which bundles everything
but anyway so if you want to do it my
way
of course my my own recommendation is
that you go
you go through my tutorial then you use
stuff like keys
stuff like keys is such that you you
barely need other packages i mean there
are many other packages
helm for example many people swear by
that
and quite a few others you know helm iv
and and so on
and ace windows and so on
but you know if you
follow my workflow you don't need them
okay don't
and i would even claim my way with
sapphire's keys is faster and more
efficient simpler too
simpler faster more efficient
that's just my of course my my biased
opinion
so so so i do have a uh
tutorial on diet you can read it so
anyway let's go back to the
um to uh alpha okay
so alpha so here is the packages i
actually
uh used myself okay first of all i
recommend smacks
very much uh what what that does is that
when you call meta x for example let's
call
i don't even have a key for meta x
anymore because now if i do a meta
let's see uh let's see if i still have
the key meta x
yeah so you see when you do meta x
actually i don't think i'm doing any
meta x hold on a second so
so anyway smacks smacks is a
replacement for meta x so it's much more
enhanced
so when you do meta x which is called
extended command you know call command
by name
when you use max it offers uh
flex matching so you just type the words
in your command your show you know give
you a list
but on the other hand if you use meta x
which is um
called extended command okay uh
the full name is execute extended
command this one okay
you see that one so that's meta x
so let's call meta x right now i'm doing
meta x
so you see now if i if i type something
let's say
saw
let's say excel remove paragraph okay
excite html remove paragraph
but i don't remember the names you know
i don't remember what
what it begins let's say just paragraph
it doesn't show you see it doesn't offer
me that command
but if you use smacks you're just you'll
show you know
for example let's try smix magnify
i just type p-a-r-a
you see it shows on the third item you
know then i can
arrow down and call it so smix
is much better so okay smix
magic if you use git you know git and
github magic
is great magic okay um
so i use so i also use go mod for golan
key frequency which okay let me show you
okay
uh key frequency show
key frequency so here it locks all your
keys in emacs
across sessions so i can say i can tell
in the past several months i don't
remember when you know i've been using
this command previous line for 40
425 000 times i have been calling
next line for four 4 4 422
000 times and so on you know older stem
so this is fantastic if you want to
study
what command you use most frequently
once you know that you can make them
easy keys
so this so this package is key frequency
okay uh so here's magit
and powershell powershell i believe
that's you know for the windows
powershell if you use powershell
uh then that's it that's about it that's
very few and online mod earlier mod if
i'm
learning online programming language
that's it
the other packages are installed by um
by magic like some of these packages
such as magic when you install it
it install a bunch of others it installs
a sync
it then you install stash i hate i hate
i despise the dash package
i explained it before but
and it also installed transient i think
yeah and it also installed with editor
so though all these are dependencies of
the
magic mod i don't like any dependency
packages
in general it's kind of necessary
sometimes but anyway
so the other package i have installed
here is company mod so company mod it
does
completion in the traditional ide way
for example if you use
uh vs code or microsoft visual uh
visual studio you know you have a pop-up
that shows
for example you can also see here
in a browser command option i
that gives you the java javascript
console then you can say console it
then it pops up you know
completion keyword condition in the
traditional way
so if you want that in emacs you what
you do is
uh use the company mod which is
you know you know i have it installed
but i don't use it
but i do actually i do recommend it
because it's kind of
it's not necessary i don't use it myself
okay that's that's that's about the few
ones i
i actually use myself i don't use any
others
yeah so that that that that is um
that is my recommendation so i think
that's it for today thank you
so thank you guys for coming thank you
guys
and uh go buy my emacs tutorial okay
bye guys