welcome to another episode of talk show
today we are going to code emac LP
nonstop so let me introduce my keyboard
This is glove 80 fantastic keyboard This
is automate hacking keyboard fantastic
this is newa
m505 track B fantastic I just reviewed
yesterday on my YouTube and this is
Logitech 502 this is my Workhorse and
actually I love the new so I'm going to
uh try to use the tracko for for a while
so let's begin uh emac emac this is for
you guys using emac or interested in
learning emac B uh yeah emac LP
particularly coding emac LP so what
we're going to do today is we are going
to write a command that grabs YouTube
live stream uh grabs the YouTube uh
thumb now so for example let me show you
so for example you go to keyboard blog
there's a video uh you know ca talk show
so copy the URL let's open it in emx and
show in browser okay back to emx so you
can see there's a lot embedded video
here so you can see uh you know for
example you know this this block is this
first video on glove 80 review and and
this more so what I want is you know
over the past 20 years I've been
blogging for 25 years uh for 30 years
since 1997 so many often you know
YouTube began in 2006 also uh you know
after 10 years sometimes the uh video is
G um and so I wish to remove all the Ed
so instead of the Ed what I want is
usually just just a screenshot for for
example let me show you a example so
this is emac workflow okay so I press a
key I copy this you know this uh
thumbnail kind of so it automatically
save to the my screenshot pictures
folder so I go here and I call a command
on the Ping window is all my command
names and keystrokes I'm using vac
keyboard layout and I'm using a uh s
Keys search it you find it s flag keys
so I have so I did a screenshot and I
press the key this will automatically
move that screenshot to here so you can
see and uh the command you can see is
HTML move image file okay I think if you
search that you you probably will find
the source code so you can use it so now
in showing browser so you can see I got
uh so I got a screenshot this is not a
video this is just a screenshot
shot so that's what I want so instead
instead of you know instead instead of
the embedded video which you can play
right away uh I want just a screenshot
and then the
link uh you know let's say put a link
here and let's uh press this key to
normalize the YouTube url because
YouTube url has so many forms for
example this form is for embedded and
this form is like you know the the nor
the standard that YouTube promotes when
you right click copy URL that's what you
get so then make a link and and okay
make a link remove that line showing
browser so this is what I want to be so
no embed because every time you embed a
YouTube video it increases like five me
uh was it five or 50 megabytes of RAM
use so it you know
anyway so also because YouTube you know
Google has been very corrupted so
whenever you embed something that means
it actually call JavaScript it can do
literally anything to your
website if Google choose to do so or
whoever so these days I'm trying to
avoid ined but I do have thousands of
embedded videos on my website you know
the there are like like 10,000 HTML
Pages written in the past 30 years so
there's a lots of videos so I'm
gradually removing them by converting
each each of the
video embedded video into just a
screenshot and a link why screenshot is
is critical because after 5 years or two
or
10 the link is dead you know YouTube
remove the video or sometimes the person
who did the video they they remove or
made it private so you have no idea what
it is about something you wrote five or
10 years ago so you always want a
screenshot so this also happens to in
bed you know when someone when the video
is gun you have no you know you have no
video you have no idea what it is about
so the screenshot give you a a a
snapshot of the memory of the record of
what's what you linked to
so so so I have like 1,000 you know uh
embedded videos so I want to write a
command today so that we automatically
grab instead of me manually making a
screenshot you know it'll automatically
grab the thumbnail of the YouTube and
put in my directory so I can easily
convert it like press a key and it'll
convert you know this form
to this form so that's what we're going
to do okay so today so for now uh yeah
okay so let's let's let's start to uh
let's start to work on that so today's
talk show page let's put a link there uh
this is a sample page so write a emac
this command to grab to get uh to grab
URL thumbnail okay let's begin writing
it uh okay so wait
so EAC this code paste it there here
okay so then pop it out so we're going
to Define so this uh Define a function
and uh let's just name it grab
YouTube image uh let's say thumbnail
okay that's a command name and let and
this is the documentation let's put it
there uh write the emac this
command grab the YouTube thumbnail and
save it in current folder current is
whatever the current buffer current
purpose
directory uh created version okay so
let's uh so let's begin writing it so
how do you grab a YouTube uh URL so you
can click on here if you have a
questions comments say hi okay hello uh
juang so to grab a URL this is what you
do so let me show
you uh
so if the
YouTube url is like that basically you
want to grab the ID every YouTube video
there's ID uh so ID is usually here so
once you get ID then then the the the
the image for that thumbnail is in this
URL so this is what we need to do so
first of all when you get a YouTube url
you want to okay first of all you need
to grab the location the beginning
position and end position of the of the
YouTube okay so um so let's do that okay
so okay so
xp1 my convention or variables begin
with the letter X X P1 P2 is position
one position two so uh what we can do is
thing at Point
okay uh bounce of thing at point so that
will that will uh so here you need to
put a UR URL okay so that will return it
the
boundary uh cons pair the beginning
position and end position of the URL the
cruiser is on so so let's say uh
BDS bounce okay bounce boundary let's
just write out in four so set boundary
equals to that and put the boundary as a
local variable okay so we got the
beginning end position and then you just
set
xp1 to Car X boundary that's a beginning
position and same thing for xp2 instead
here you want
C so that's how you get the beginning
position and end position of the URL the
cruiser is on okay then so once you get
that then you uh create another local
variable X URL and X URL set it
to um set it
to uh yeah so so you want to grab the
text um buff of substring no properties
okay so you give two positions and that
will will grab the string the text in
between so save that as X URL okay we
got that then the next job is once you
got URL you want to extract the ID
so uh this is technical because you have
to know this is I mean not not not I
mean this is not just emac this but it
depends on the YouTube whatever websites
API so I already have a command written
so let's look up
uh
YouTube okay so um let's
see uh HTML YouTube embed let's let's go
look at I have already the command
written in s HTML mod so you can see all
these uh varieties of YouTube uh URL
formats so let's search for uh defund
list or Ming lines and search for
YouTube there it is get YouTube ID so
this
function pass the parameter of URL it
will return the YouTube ID so you can
see the YouTube link format variations
okay so we just going to call this
command uh this command is pretty short
short you can like copy it and use it
yourself okay so but we going to just
call this
command uh yeah let's do that close
close close close Okay
so uh so you need to create a new
variable uh X ID okay
so set X ID equals to you want call that
function and pass it a URL okay then we
got the
YouTube the that video's ID so once you
got ID
the you you want to so we got uh so
let's comment this out so that you know
just for reference so once you got um
the ID so you can the image thumbnail
URL is this one so uh so let's create a
new variable to create this image
thumbnail
so set Q X
thumbnail uh URL okay let's just all
lower case so thumbnail URL will be
equals
to uh let's copy
that and will equals to concact okay
concact a
string
um so we can do that this
[Music]
way okay okay
so here is the ID
part um so here we need to put ID
U
ID okay I believe that's it so this is
the thumbnail image
URL comments and questions ju are you
going to play black myth Wong next month
no I haven't been gaming uh for over 10
years
so thumbnail URL so this uh this is kind
of to I mean let's let okay we need a
local variable here and let's make it
easier to read
um so let's put a
okay so you got the thumbnail URL
so next thing to do is you need to grab
it you need to fetch it uh
via um I think emac Lis has a command to
fetch URL but I'm not sure off hand what
exactly it is so what we can do is we
can make a shell call you know for
example the popular way to get uh URL or
web content is we get or the other one
is um curl okay so these two are
popular external commands to get URL and
in fact curl is built in in Powershell
okay on windows so GCM get command name
curl you can see curl is right there so
let's magnify this is in Powershell and
let's magnify the
window uh the font so you can see curl
is build in the open source so we can
just use Curl to get it I don't think I
have we get um GCM we get I don't I
don't have that I don't need it uh but
in
fact in Powers shell you also have a
command to get URL but not curl
so so okay so let's let's digress a bit
so I have a PO shot tutorial if you into
you know if you're on Windows you must
learn poers shell so this my tutorial
provides you the precise and concise and
very easy to understand comprehensive
you know basically you
know
uh not comprehensive because I mean
power sh is a huge thing but so you can
learn all the how tools of the common
things you need to do uh for example
compress decompress archive uh list
directories and and and search File by
string grab and also so in depth that
teaches you the Powershell technical
details it's very different from bash or
zshell it's very different from Unix
shell because power shell is basically
object based system every time you pipe
it's object so so there's some
critical Notions that's different from
bash you can learn you know how about
how to program power shell power shell
in depth so in power shell so we were
talking about grab URL I mean grab the
web content so you can see if we go here
there is a uh I talked about that this a
page let's see date mty trash launch app
file launchers admin clear command
history uh there get web pay get get
download web page call we get so there
it is so the buildin PO command is
invoke web request or shorten it as
irw so so you can see GCM i r w magnify
uh I don't know if you can see it oh you
cannot see it so let's move
here so let's see GCM curl so you can
see curl is build in now GCM
iwr is invoke invoke web request so oh
yeah so that's how you do it so you know
so I have a choice I can either use Curl
or I can use
um Powers shell so let's see what is my
need I'm writing a emac
disp uh yeah in that case you want to
use Curl because emac is you know half
of emac users is on Linux and curl is
the wider the much more
popular uh thing so so curl but I forgot
what is the curl's syntax so let's go to
my Linux
tutorial and uh and search for curl and
I have the basic syntax here so download
image sequence download one web page C
capital o- capital O okay yep that's
okay that's what we're going to
use so we're going to call Shell uh
shell
command commments and questions hello
programming typo programming uh Mark
Jefferson leevon Leon says what are your
thoughts on Rust rust is
crap rust is crap loved by the memory
bit ders okay so I recommend Goan pure
simple Goan and uh FSH for Microsoft or
or camo if you are on Linux okay that's
what I recommend go land
F
shop from Microsoft or or camo from you
know on Linux okay that's the three
language top three and otherwise I also
recommend um Julia okay Julia and of
course I recommend Mathematica wolam
language uh if you have seen my videos
um you know you know let me show you so
wolam Language tutorial you can download
it's the most
Supreme uh high level Language by by a
magnitude than all of them so but it's
not industrial language okay this is a
the the purpose is a bit different so
for industrial coding I recommend Goan
Goan is the the easy the most popular
okay Goan FSH or camel or Julia Julia is
less popular it's like kind of a new
okay that's what I
recommend so so uh I have a very
important question how can I become a
million as fastest as possible
idiot Mark Jefferson there's a good
answer to that
question pay you want to be a
millionair whether you know how and you
know well basically you have to pay for
it okay so the question becomes how much
does it cost how much does it cost to
become a medon
that's the question you have to answer
for yourself okay like how much effort
like the cost you know just like
everything else like like this is a
great track board you know glove 80 is a
great keyboard how much is it 300
something okay is it worth to you are
you willing to pay that price to get
this product are you willing so you want
to be a millionair how much does it cost
are you willing to do it that's a
question okay so back to uh let's go
back to code so shell command so we're
going to call Shell command we going to
call a shell command to we're going to
call the curl um shell command okay so
this is getting
involved uh so refresh so you can see
what we are doing for those of you come
here
late we are grabbing given a YouTube url
we want to download the thumbnail image
of that YouTube okay so shell command
curl um let's see okay so let's see yeah
so we're going to need to go curl let's
see what's a Syntax for Shell command
Okay so shell command allows you to call
a shell command
so so command name capital or URL so we
need we kind of need this
thing so let's do a form
format okay so the URL will be xur L
that's the argument so it's
here okay so basically that's our sh
command then option output
buffer uh we don't care error buffer we
don't care okay so for now let's ignore
it so that's what we want so let's see
are we good uh let's compact this a
little
bit okay
so okay we call Shell command C curl and
that should download it to the current
folder of the image okay now remember
the image name is the max
default uh yeah
okay so now we I think we are almost
done so now we after the shell command
we essentially get the got the image
then
we then
[Music]
we let's just say insert okay so let's
just say
insert that okay the image name okay so
that's let's run it okay run the buffer
so now emac know the command grab
YouTube thumbnail let's try
it okay so let's try it let's put it
back syntax C showing browser so here is
today's talk show fruit but now let's
try uh to work you know grab a URL so
let's go to
a page for example here uh so we want to
delete this one we did before delete
showing browser so now let's try this
image okay
so so delete it undo close this and
let's put that
here okay so actually delete that to
delete that
to uh figure delete that okay so we got
the YouTube okay actually let's just
copy it paste it here okay actually we
don't need to so we just put a cruiser
somewhere inside the URL and coal
command and that should do it so put a
cruiser on the URL a YouTube url meta
X grab YouTube thumbnail let's hope it
works do
it fantastic looks like it works oh you
see it inserted you see it inserted this
max resolution okay that's a mistake we
shouldn't do that but anyway so let's
jump to diet let's you know go to the
directory and uh hide all this and uh
and
refresh and uh search for
Max uh okay so the file is not
here okay so let's let's pop this out
again let's see the file is named
Max Max res default okay go to ex talk
show this matching lines
Max
huh okay so the it's downloaded it it it
downloaded somewhere but but I don't
know where did it download so let's look
at the message Lo
so it downloaded oh that's right that I
know what's going on because when we
when we call this command wait
uh wait is it here search Max no search
Max no where did it download it to
so we are running the curl Das o output
right so it
should have downloaded
this
file okay but it's not here close it put
it back go to diet search for Max is not
here uh maybe it's this one
and I don't know what that is okay I
don't want to open let's see July 7th
1228 yeah must be must be that one open
it okay
so okay it downloaded the whole
HTML so is it because wait so you know
it downloaded some kind a full
HTML page okay
so so let's let's we need to fix our
Command something went wrong so when you
curl so okay so before we call the Shell
command let's
print uh messages let's
see let's see if we got the new URL
correctly
evaluate back to uh put it
let's oh okay so that that is a YouTube
ID that file name okay put a cruiser
here call it grab YouTube
thumbnail and
uh okay and uh go to the message buer
this is the new URL now let's just
try if this work
okay curl Das o Capital let's go to
poell
magnify
okay and uh paste curl let's see if that
worked okay so now let's go to the diet
search for
Max there it
is there it is you see it grabbed the
thumbnail beautiful that's what we want
exactly
so okay so that curl worked so let's
copy this uh let's put it here so that
this curl command
worked so why is it
why is it in our the ad it's not working
I mean I mean in our uh emac this
comments and
questions emac has URL copy
file uh URL copy file okay maybe that's
useful let's see URL copy file okay
let's see what that is thank you
juang URL copy file is an autoloaded
loaded native compile list function in
url handlers thank you hang so let's see
what this exactly URL copy file
URL new name optional okay if already
exists okay copy URL to new name both
arguments Must Be Strings okay
H okay that's what we need uh it looks
like I'm not too sure yet let's look at
the source code URL retrieve
synchronously okay that seems to be the
command we need okay great thank you
thank you juang so we we I mean I will
think about
this that's probably what I use but for
now let's continue with that because I
don't know how to use this yet then you
know it's going to be 10 minutes
debugging so let's go with what I'm
familiar for
now so this sh command why is it not
working I don't know
so so let's so let's declare a new
name X
command and uh and uh
and set that to there and also declare
there so we got a
command so this is the shell command
we're going to call and uh let's
print okay so I mean let's yeah let's
message X
command let's see if we got correct okay
so comment that out eval the buffer Now
call it now let's show the message
buffer okay now call it oh we need to
put uh you need to put the curer on a
URL so let's go back here
let's uh CER on the URL let's copy that
back here let's let's say here okay so
put a CER on URL call it grab YouTube
url grab YouTube thumbnail do
it okay
so the X command is calling
that oh that is incorrect you see we got
it this command is incorrect so it's
getting
and okay so what so what is going on so
this is the output so
let's debug
okay so this this is the wrong
URL oh this part should be thumbnail URL
how
idiotic obviously not the original URL
but you know
so that should that should be it
okay so eval the buffer go back to talk
show and and go to the directory and uh
remove that so we you know and also
search for
Max delete that okay it's deleted so now
let's do it again Cod the command grab
YouTube thumbnail do
it uh and and then go to diet search for
Max
refresh okay did we call it it's not
here go back here a okay so did you call
it no you didn't call the Shell command
so you need to call the Shell command
obviously so let's put it
here okay now this is getting long let's
I mean this clean up a bit okay messages
we don't
need uh this we don't need okay then get
that messages we don't
need and this is original URL copy okay
that we will have to do delete that
delete
that and this we will have
to uh put it here as a comment so people
can understand what's going
on okay
and
uh okay
so okay so
now we call the sh command yeah eval the
buffer go back here go to S Talk Show C
put a cruiser on a YouTube url call it
do it
fantastic drop to diet diet jump so you
can see all my commands in the pink
Window search for Max there it is
fantastic
so that is actually job complete okay so
fantastic so we can consider this job is
done correctly so now our code now let's
do a final cleanup
so grab YouTube url thumbnail and save
it in current folder that's right let's
say du because the Unix people
is they prefer the the directory you
know if you say folder they think you
are an
idiot but but truly the Linux Unix are
the
idiots uh so we got so this final clean
up for you so after you call the Shell
command let's put the
message
uh image thumb now saved in um yeah
let's just you know so
that uh let's just put it here saved
saved in in that directory
okay uh I mean in this file okay so what
is this this we don't need uh
[Music]
um okay for
example this is a sample um URL okay so
okay that's it put it back wait eval it
put it back colorify it showing
browser okay and then we need to clean
up some of the uh the curl here so we
don't so this this is we don't need that
anymore
um yeah we don't need that anymore
fantastic
so that's it I mean that's it for this
command but for myself I need to do a
bit you know few more things because I
want to be able to press a key on any
embedded iframe from YouTube then it
becomes it generates a new you uh new
HTML with the screenshot and with the
URL to the YouTube instead of the ined
so but but the heart of the program is
done here if you want to know how to do
that you know I I had
like uh 50 or 100 YouTube tutorials on
how to how to code that okay I think
that's it for
today okay okay so how long have I been
42 minutes okay that uh I think that's
it for today let's see anything
else okay great thank you guys for
watching if you like my stuff don't
forget to donate okay with money gets
everything go so you go to cali. info
then you can scroll down you know my
website lots of
tutorials uh you can buy my emac
tutorial including with emac this
comprehensive you know
so go
to code and then you can buy my emac
tutorial you can buy my JavaScript
tutorial which is in depth about 600
Pages or something uh you can you know
check out my w language this you know
goand and or this or you can just pay me
okay patreon me Amazon gift card me pay
about me you know if you work for Google
you know you can donate to
me a
th000 if you like my stuff if you have
been you know enjoying my stuff bye
guys thank you
uh yeah shut down