good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show today we are
going to do the today's topic is
ontology of dot notation versus pipe
versus function chaining so this is a
technical topic this is related to
programming language design stuff okay
so that is the topic for today and let's
get on so close this window kibo blog
close okay that I need to block my
keyboards terms of walk you see these
gorgeous pictures these pictures
actually I collected quite a while ago a
year or two ago
so anyway today's topic is dot notation
pipes chain function chaining in
programming languages and today's 2019
January 2020 January 2nd Thursday 4
o'clock in the afternoon oh I'm actually
early I'm 5 minutes early so good
morning Justin good morning Emily and
great to see you Kathy Kathy H Kathy H
and Emily are in United Kingdom's
I hope one day I can meet you guys I
don't know how remote that chances are
and good morning just interesting is in
British Columbia Canada
what an interesting name British
Columbia Canada
so in Vancouver Vancouver so today's
topic so let's do today's topic and but
before we begin it's digress
we love digressions okay so let's
digress and and it's to Emacs
let's get this Emacs command to have
Emily's color
so I'm going to start command log mod
okay which is this command you are
seeing right there okay I'm gonna start
a command some meta xxxx our common log
mod okay Mina X sub command start
command lock okay you see now this
window on the left you can see all my
Emacs commands whenever I move cruiser
or delete things or copy and paste
things all the commands on the Left
window but however I wanted to be
colored you see I wanted to set
background color 3 so this o is Emily's
color so this color I want okay and so
let's do it instead of calling the
command and fix it manually every time
let's do it make the command change the
color so let's restart Emacs you cakes
are can meet up right
are you are you guys going to have a
meet-up Kathy Kathy and Emily and Vulcan
so if you have not already these people
in Saudi discord okay join this code and
let me send out you know let's send out
its let's do it okay Santosh okay
go to the top search for this code and
there it is the discord ID the
invitation you need a invitation to join
him
so that's Saudis code and let's stop
this we are doing pre dude to today's
talk show then we are going to get on to
the topic about our notation the
fantastic that the the great topic of
programming language design in all the
issues all the issues near you you never
seen you never heard of you from these
hacker types they tell you about rust
rust in Haskell Rosen Haskell every
de las cadenas PDS d-33 VST but they
Annie Max and wim but their their vision
their perspective is limited if I may
say so okay you know how do you get your
how do you widen your perspective well
the first thing you do is you eliminate
any mainstream information no pain no
gain any information that comes to you
easily you don't want that okay you want
information only you strive hard to dig
to find it then your thoughts your ideas
will be fresh
otherwise your ideas your thoughts your
opinions about programming languages
about urban systems about politics is is
is is is is the same as your friends you
know this is your neighborhood whatever
it's a same so so here is a summary of
the of the advice you want whenever
there is is information you know today
we say our society is information
overload right
too much information we cannot we don't
have time to digest they are thousands
of books your friends recommend to you
about operating systems about Haskell
about programming languages about about
mathematics you know you don't have time
you do know you know all the great books
in Wikipedia you can read Wikipedia all
day every day so much information but
you don't have time to digest it even
though many of these information are
great you know for example your friends
will tell you about great books in math
or programming but you don't have time
anyway my point is so information
overload especially the current events
like politics Twitter you know everyday
this [ __ ] news everyday mainstream
fake news so information and and and on
social networks on discord on Twitter
you know you get information from
friends information overload so okay I'm
digressing but what I'm saying is that
you want any okay here here is a summary
here is the gist okay any information
that comes to you easily without you
spending effort without you having pain
to get it those information you should
try to ignore it like almost like
completely like that's what I do
actually that's what I've been doing for
you know 20 years so I have weird
opinions okay so you know whether it's
good or not it's up to you to decide but
the the the one thing for sure is my
opinion are usually a bit weird okay
yeah and many of you too many of you
guys so so so my what I want to say is
that any information here's the thing
any information may be you know poor I
mean technical stuff you learn
mathematics or may it be news or
political opinions or geography or
history whatever any information that
comes to you easy such that you didn't
spend much effort to gain it such as on
Twitter on social networks Oh news news
news arco sometime posted oh this is a
great news article Oh news article on
Hacker News hacker news [ __ ] one 1000
thumbs ups you know those those
information they come to you easily you
you didn't spend days or one hour or so
or even 10 minutes through to actually
learn something you just read it you
know on Hacker News you know every every
[ __ ] hacker types go to hacker news
you read it oh all the different you
know great things so Google is doing
something oh they have a a I new AI
library you know whatever [ __ ] so those
are information you know you you get you
know if almost every one of most of us
unless you are very you know most of us
you get those those information every
day they come to you easily so ignore
them why because they came to you easy
you didn't have pain you didn't suffer
to get it okay
so what you want is information that you
know like like you know the bodybuilders
you know bodybuilding so we have a we
have a member who is Ripper I think he's
into bodybuilding you know he do
bodybuilding although I don't know what
he do exactly but he seems he's into
bodybuilding when I was younger I read a
lot about bodybuilding because I was
kind of like a street performer juggler
you know I want to be one of the goal my
goal is to be the greatest juggler he's
kind of funny anyway so bodybuilding you
know in bodybuilding they have a saying
no pain no gain
okay so if you didn't you know like you
do push-ups
oh the the trenches push-up you cannot
not do it but you have to do it then you
can then your muscle go because that's
actually physiology that's true if you
you know to weights and you don't you
you you know you don't you don't you
don't your muscles don't get to the
point of some sort of pain then your
muscle doesn't doesn't grow you know
because it's already used to it so
anyway no pain no gain that's the same
so it's the same thing with information
in my kind of dramatic way of saying it
okay you know I might be exaggerating a
bit but but that is a thing so any
information that comes to you without
you go through a lot to get it that's no
good tends to be no good okay so you can
owe them so what what do you mean by
that so what do I mean by that for
example you want to you know okay in
anyway I'm digressing about that but I
should give an example though for
example you yeah anyway I'm digressing
so let's get back to Emacs then so good
morning Matt hola and
moaning crash hacker from Japan great to
see you and Matt is right now Matt is in
Central America what country was at
Central America great so okay so let's
start the command let's start modifying
Emacs first okay so let's go the command
okay sauce start command log mod you see
that you see the name at a mini poverty
button so now I press ctrl H F that
shows me the the describe function the
functions documentation of this command
so it says South start command log is an
interactive disclosure in in that file
okay so by the way so you can do this
too okay normally you code describe
function describe describe function ok
normally that's what you do you code
description function and you type the
function name saw start command lock mod
that's how you get to the that's how you
get this in inline documentation for the
function described function that's a
command name but another way to do it is
that if you have Smacks installed okay
let's see where wait how we okay so
actually this is not the page we want
let's go to today's today's talk show
page ok so if you have Smacks installed
let me show you what source mix SME X so
that's what I'm using it's a it's an
enhanced version of meta X ok ok I'm
sorry to talk about the basics of Emacs
so anyway met IX the full name for meta
X is let me tell you how to find it so
if you know a key and you want to find
you want to know what is a command bound
to that key what you do is you call
describe key okay so let's let's do it
this swipe key you see that command
describe key metrics
spikey so I press it enter now it asked
me to type a key so now I type meta X
okay you see so now now this window pops
up now this window pops up and this
window so it says M X runs the command
execute extended command there it is let
me repeat so if you know if you know a
key and you want to know what is a
function bound to the key the way you do
it is you call em X describe key then
type the key then Emacs will tell you so
we have found that you know this command
is so MX the the key MX is the command
is execute extended command and I was
saying what about snacks snacks is a in
hand is a package that is enhanced
version of execute extended command
which is what I use and why am i
mentioning smacks because smacks allows
you to okay I am getting big complex
more advanced okay this makes allows you
to for example I cost mix and I type
start saw start command log mod so I'm
about to hit enter to run that command
but before I run a command I want to
know what I forgot what it does so at
this point you can press ctrl H F then
it will it will show the in line dock so
it's kind of a shortcut to describe
function okay into that do I make sense
I think this is a bit complex
complicated advanced you know the thing
is when you are doing a talk show most
people they just want you know they are
in tune for only the basic stuff because
you know of course many of you guys know
what I'm doing but
but but you narrowed your audience is
significantly like most of them they
don't know like you know that's the
typical way things are
most people are beginners in everything
including including us you know because
when we are doing programming we are
advanced or Emacs but when but vast
majority of other things in life we know
nothing about such as business not room
a business law restaurants restaurant
industry we know nothing about you know
there are 1000 1 million things in the
world and we know one of them that is
programming the the rest nine hundred
ninety nine hundred ninety thousand
things we don't know so in the same way
in general on YouTube you know the most
people are always beginners including us
so anyway let's let's get back to let's
get back to modify this command okay
start exhaust start command log mod so
I'm going to call describe function on
it okay and it shows me the you see the
inline dock and I want to jump to the
file so here is the code here is decode
and I want to modify it so I want to do
is to add a color to the background so
what I do is let's see where okay
okay at the end so in here set
background color okay what is the
command set background color okay
actually we are digressing a lot but we
gonna begin soon so set background color
and I want feasel so th I okay I forgot
what's the name so let's open a new
buffer set background color th is TL e
there it is
so type that here and done okay and now
I'd run the command now it's evaluated
now I close this window now I move to
this let me show you okay let me show
you here so you can see so I so I now I
call sauce start command lock mod enter
fantastic its workings
you see it's working so now I don't I
run any command you can see it shows on
the left actually there's one more thing
I want to do because the other thing I
want to do is I want to make it narrow
like that so we can add it to the
command should we do that
nobody is saying anything guys comment
so actually let's begin today's topic
today's the ontology of dot notation
UNIX pipe and function chaining okay so
this is programming language design
related issue so before we begin on that
let me just finish this command change
today states version number okay and
save it and close
okay now let's talk about dot notation
CISOs are everyone's favorite food is
this so what is thisis anyway I don't
even know what he feels I thought it's a
plant like thorny plant th is PL e so
there it is let's call the command and
look up with such feasel Sophie so is
the common name of a group of flowering
flowering plants characterized by
thieves with sharp prickles on the
margins indeed oh that looks like that
[Laughter]
okay Jesus everyone is a donkey from the
weenie poo oh I don't know what does
that reference to I mean well I know
it's winnie pooh it's a cartoon but i
haven't watched it so let's let's talk
about today's thing okay so let me show
you today's Opie notation okay let me
talk let me tell you about the Opie
notation this so we're gonna talk about
this for 30 minutes or something and
this is Cathy oh my god Cathy London
Emacs hacking guys London Emacs hacking
Meetup okay you guys gonna go yes indeed
London London guys guys okay so there it
is a meet-up okay so let me post that
YouTube is censoring us okay so then
only I can post things something like
that
so that's London
emacs meet up so great thing so you guys
you know you guys in UK okay meet up so
okay let me talk about our notation so
let's begin and we gonna talk about this
the JavaScript Ruby the oh you know it's
Dom notation is a very popular notation
in mostly object-oriented languages okay
so first of all so I have several
articles about that about the ontology
and by the way do you know what I mean
by ontology because ontology is well I
did a video on that it's not going to
but okay but let's just go go one by one
about them down notation taught before
dot o P dot notation dot before data or
after okay let me let me tell you about
that
so normally so let's see
Python okay let's do a Python example so
Python okay hold on a second so python
you have I have encoded Python for years
so xx okay so I need to magnify xx
equals to something okay and then let's
say SS start split okay split okay split
on space you see so now let's print YY
okay let's run it there it is the here
is the output okay so it splits a string
into two parts into a array list okay so
you can see here is add a notation now
the SS is a string it's a meat you know
it's a primary so data we want to work
on so you have data then taught then a
speed method which is a function so so
in this exam
the important thing is the data so it's
in front its before before the dot but
however that's not always the case
there are quite a few complications in
in this start notation Opie dot notation
you know this notation is used in Java
in Java Script in in Java JavaScript in
Python ok it's one [ __ ] up where the Oh
object-oriented programming is one [ __ ]
up through out inside out and today we
are going to show let me tell you my
opinions about one of the [ __ ]
major so so so so in this example you
have a ton notation that's what it is
and the data comes before the dot you
see usually so this is SS this part is
the in JavaScript in Python it's an
object in Ruby its object JavaScript
Python Ruby object okay in in Java
yeah it's also object in Java so object
you know which is the data then thought
and method you applied the method on the
data that's how it's supposed to me you
know the table notation opie
object-oriented programming now but it's
not always the case that the the the
data comes before the dot for example
let me show you this Python okay I
haven't coded Python so I need to get
into I need to copy and code paste code
okay so hold on a second let's let's put
that here okay so we have a Python
example now let's show another example
here okay I'm gonna show you another
example this is Python regular
expressions
okay so here we have a Python regular
expression that knits now let me show
you okay so I'm not going to go into
programming details I'm just going to
talk about the dot notation so here you
see okay so so here here you have a
string so this code we is a regular
expression matching email address okay
so actually I okay so so here is a
string and you want to you want to get
the email address in that string so what
you do is you have this regular
expression this import V that's I is a
regular expression package okay so you
call Ari
you see we that is a macho name you know
the regular expression module then you
dot such okay then you dot such that's a
function then then you give option you
know so the first argument is a regular
expression here that pattern matches the
email address in general then that the
text is the string so you want to match
this string by by this regular
expression and the way you do it you
know you [ __ ] such but you see that
dot notation in this example that we is
not data right that that we is a package
name in other words is it serves as a
namespace it's not data okay so
typically in OB you think you know like
data dot methods but here it's different
it's inconsistent you have a package
name that they method then then they
inside the parentheses you have you know
whatever you want to do you know your
your text your data or so so it's here
is the example that's showing that it is
inconsistent okay so that's that's what
I want to show
so we have you know the inconsistency
here now let me show you let's talk
about okay so I have showed example in
Python where the data come before the
dot and another example comes after the
dot now this happens in JavaScript as
well
you have many examples and it happens in
Java
in fact this happens in in general in I
think almost all fee languages
it happens in Python in JavaScript in
Java okay how does it happen in Java for
example one of the most common example
is math starts something so let me show
you
JavaScript math method methods okay so
here is the JavaScript you have all
these math methods so you have math dot
function name then parenthesis whatever
so you owe this method you see the the
thing that comes before the dot is not a
object okay even in JavaScript it's not
even technically it's not a object it's
just you know because I've read the
JavaScript suspect it's not even an
object it's a you know it's just the
purpose of that is just a namespace okay
so so that's that's some of the examples
okay that's the main thing I want to say
about that dot notation so you can see
so the the point here is that sometimes
the dot the data comes before the dot
sometimes after okay so they mean maybe
I should go faster am I getting boring
like sometimes I'm kind of slow and
repetitive ten viewers
try okay 30 minutes okay let's go faster
so that's one example okay now let me
show you another example dot not dot J's
if you don't know not RJ is a JavaScript
engine you can run
in your in your terminal for example I
can start not okay for example not so
you see so now I can start to type
JavaScript three plus two okay let's do
a ray okay two three four so we have an
array you know so let's let's do some
more so x equals two okay so now X is
array and let's get the first element
index 0 2 so you see so not jeaious is a
basically a JavaScript engine so you can
install so you can run JavaScript
without you know learning it inside the
browser that's what I do
so not yes so not just in not yes you of
course you also have this start notation
but it turns out in notches the the dot
every dot you know it's used the when
you have a X start Y the X part is
always just a namespace it's never it's
never a you know data object it's just a
namespace for example here is a typical
example code integer in not yes okay
you have required something you assign
it to a name then you call that you know
then you code P dot something you know
that that p is just namespace so the
point of this Arco is just showing that
is just showing you that this dot
notation the semantics of the dot
notation differs okay
sometimes it's data sometimes it's a
namespace
okay so that's that's that's about this
is easy right now it's very simple it's
but it's going to get complex this is
because this is about you see this is
about when you okay why are we talking
about this because as a programmer you
will see every day program must talk
about programming issues like they
complain oh I like training functions oh
I don't like you know function chain oh
I like dot notation no I don't like that
on that notation so program I must argue
so everyone has opinions but I do too so
but but I think one of the good thing
you want to do is you want to dive into
details because you see it can get this
this seemingly you know it's a fun topic
you know every like this this is talked
often about that notation about function
chaining
because it's a dramatic issue about
programming style you know some
programmers they they like function
chaining
like typically in JavaScript Python Ruby
you have something dot something start
something you know thought about that
people think oh this is so great but
some people don't like it because they
think you know some people don't like it
because you know white people talk about
this often programmers because this is
eventually it's a programming style you
know programmers love talking about
programming style because it's the most
fundamental basic brainless thing
everyone can talk about you know it's
like the bike shade shade pop you know
what color should the bike shade be
meanwhile the difficult problems nobody
understands so nobody has opinions on
that but the basic most useless issues
everyone has opinion like you know like
you know programming style stuff you
programming idioms and is poor in style
and as especially you know the dumb
notation that's why a lot of people talk
about it but what I want to say is that
they are you you know for issues like
this you can dive deeper ok dive deeper
then you'll find so what what were you
were you find you see this this will
relate depending on how philosophical
how deep you want to go it relates to
programming language syntax design human
captain cognition system you know
numeral science there is a big branch of
science about human [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] on
ization functions how do we perceive how
do we understand things you know which
which way we can understand the fastest
which way is the fastest to learn you
know there are big research about that
it's a subfield of psychotic so called
multi discipline field psychology new
neuroscience education educational
science or whatever you may have micro
ed you know oh experimental you know all
you to statistics research survey survey
for example camel case versus snake case
which one is better there are few
articles about that you know research
papers so people measured your eye
movements you know to see whether camel
case or snake cases which one is
actually easier to read you know things
like that so so my roommate just left I
think so
so what does this pertain to so it
pertains to syntax language design
syntax design human cognition systems
you know how we perceive how we you know
and in the history of math notations
and also how notations influenced
thought so it it it can get into
linguistics deep linguistics how how
writing systems influence your thought
for example we know foreign languages
different in your list with lots of
parentheses or versus Java you look at
the program you have different ways of
solving problems
and in fact it has to do with syntax
okay syntax has a lot to do with it so
how does syntax influence your the way
you look at problems it's related okay
it's not it syntax does not dictate how
you think but however it does influence
how you look at problems you you know
this if you have studied the history of
mathematics how notation
you know notation the math notations
they have driven the the the the future
path of mathematics of especially matrix
you know the matrix notation they have
driven you know in some cases they have
created a complete new branch of vibrant
verdant mathematics
okay so notation so what that's what I'm
saying you want to dive deeper that's
that's why that's my interest okay let's
just say that's that that is I happen to
be interested so I have I have quite a
few articles on these dot notation
verses pipe notation thing now I'm gonna
talk about pipe notation in a bit but
but this is why I think you know this is
why I find this interesting not okay
this is not your common Python style
guide [ __ ] idiots
you know the Ruby style guide you know
that there are some Emacs people I know
who like to you know post oh this is the
Emacs community a agreed upon style
guide everyone we should follow the
fuck-fuck heads this people you know
Ruby Python style guide Ruby style guide
emag misfit style guide [ __ ] them you
know you read them they didn't they
never did they don't know that they
don't have depth okay that's my rent
okay so let me talk about that this okay
so let's talk about the next thing pipe
notation okay
he just means to ossify so cough I
so let's see what is the difference
between camel case and snake case oh
that's easy
so camel case is like this okay let me
get it to it okay so no no second so
camel case camel case
okay equals to three okay and the snake
case is like that you see so that's the
camel case was a snake case in fact I
have an article on that I have read all
articles there is exist about camel case
versus snake case because I have this is
one of my obsession
I have argon this written in 2015 and
basically I've read quite a few articles
about oh you know research papers or or
blogs other programmers blogs about
camel case versus snake case and a bunch
of style guides you know from different
languages so that's that's about camel
case versus snake case okay let me post
it to today's talk show okay so just
code and okay there we have it that's
today's talk show topics camel case
versus snake is so next thing let's talk
about UNIX pipe notation the [ __ ]
UNIX pipes notation the the UNIX revos
let me tell you what is the pipe
notation okay so maybe the best thing to
do is by example so do I have anything
sensitive here no okay so let's do LS so
you see this is a typical UNIX command
that shows my directory so LS
- al incomprehensible [ __ ] okay so now I
have this all my directories a means
show all and all means long form okay so
so this is you know LS - al and now
let's say I want to find all my file
name or directories that contains the
word Google let's just say ok so - al
pipe ok but but vertical bar and grep
Google ok empty because I need to
capitalize school ok G okay so you see
so now I have shown all the files that
contains the word Google by using great
you know that's UNIX command so let's
let's do another one let's see
[Music]
actually let's go through my Emacs
directory so CD web ago Emacs okay and L
and do LS - al ok so that's my Emacs
directory actually CD to Emacs okay and
do a L so we got a whole bunch of stuff
so you got like thousands of fine you
know 700 files so let's do so let's do
LS ok LS - al type - I want to know how
many files are there so pipe to count WC
WC is what count okay so it says I have
895 files ok 895 files but but but the
important thing here is that I am using
the word vertical line that that stand
for pipe it shows you know I'm showing
you some examples so I want to let's
let's do it again so let's I want to
grab all files that contains the word
Emacs okay so you know s - eh
pipe grab Emax there it is a lot fires
again and I want to now I want to know
how many are there so I pipe again WC
you see now it says I have 400 in one
files containing whose file name
contains the word Emacs okay but anyway
that is an example of pipe you see this
this is a out thing
so that's pipe pipe that you know that's
a very common UNIX command-line syntax
and this pipe syntax you can it's you
can think of it as a postfix notation in
other words it's similar to the table
notation that's why we are talking about
it you see for many programmers star
notation is convenient you know because
it's like function Cheney that's a
proper word function Chet you make a
chain of functions you know you know you
have data pass it to this function
passes to that function then pass fast
fast then you get a result in a similar
way
that's UNIX pipe now the proper word is
you call it post so it's a postfix
notation because the function name comes
after the argument you see you have data
then the function name then function
name you know function comes after the
the meet the data so that's that's UNIX
pipe okay and in fact the Alfred aho
okay Alfred aho guy he designed oke oke
is one of the important tool in UNIX 30
years ago so he is he and he so Alfred
aho he is also the author of this book
compiler book this book Emily yes so he
you know he did an interview and people
are asking him you know what do you
think you know when you designed pipe
you thinking about functional
programming you see this is all related
guys it's important so those of you
chanting Haskell monad you know this is
all related you know get information not
from those phases that easily come to
you but you from only only you know
value information that you actually dig
and to find it that that those are
valuable information so here I'm showing
the relation about functional
programming about that notation about
UNIX pipe they are all related and this
is about and you know it's ready to like
I mentioned before language function
design syntax then pretty soon it
becomes formal languages formal
languages huge the fundamental actually
the most important branch of computer
theoretical computer science formal
languages okay look at look it up on
Wikipedia formal languages that that
formal languages is all about syntax
nothing else
syntax syntax alone so anyway so this
guy offered aho he talks about he's
saying you know when he created oak and
the the UNIX pipe I mean he's talking
about the UNIX pipes in tax actually
that idea came from functional
programming you know function for I mean
where does that idea came from it came
from mathematics he's saying that UNIX
pipe came from math okay not monad [ __ ]
the UNIX pipe when he designed it I mean
the the when his friend you know
whatever when he designed that the UNIX
5is came from function in mathematics
okay that is what this article is about
okay
function but however the UNIX [ __ ]
the you that the UNIX philosophy the
UNIX idiots you know chanting about
Linux today Linux and you know before
it's Unix you know H&E they don't they
don't know nothing about it you see do
you see they are just they are just
following fats
they are just getting their information
from hacker news from slash dot slash
dot you know that's before hacker news
you know they they don't they don't have
a brain they don't think so when these
people when the UNIX these [ __ ]
then when they talk about IP
they don't know about this history ok
they don't know they don't they don't
know anything about math although they
idolized math but then they know nothing
about math but every day they are just
chanting chanting about UNIX or UNIX
shell or bash you know this that this or
that but they so they when they talk
about type you know they it's a code ok
it's like hope I be UNIX fab is a great
things but they did never know a thing
and in fact in fact the pipe as we know
it in UNIX system is the one of the most
[ __ ] up [ __ ] in the universe okay in
programming UNIX pipe so in this alcove
I'm explaining it you know a bit why is
it [ __ ] up let me show you okay some
examples for example LS you know so we
did LS - al right actually hold on a
second let me do a screenshot of this
window so that puts up a screenshot and
I can go here you see this is this is
today's talk show page and I go here and
I make a screenshot I hold on let me
show you the command okay so I press two
keys and say okay and say okay so let's
see what is is there it is you see
showing browser we have a screenshot I
don't even have to go to desktop okay
for so those those of you Emacs users
you might look into what I'm I did you
know these commands on my website so
there it is a screenshot okay so anyway
so we did so we so we you see so let me
explain the pipe okay why why the UNIX
pipe is one [ __ ] [ __ ] or factor
[ __ ] and that is my hatred of eunuchs
contrary to you know most of you heard
and I know most of you love Linux in
open-source you know you know but you
know anyway so so yes - al you know
that's that means show all and long form
but the - al is actually a shortcut so
the the the alternative is - a - ÿà okay
is you see you see there so let's enter
you see let's do it again
- ALS - 8 - L they are equivalent
because the syntax is such that when you
you know typically you're - is an option
but you have when you have multiple of
them you you can usually combine them so
you instead of - a - well you can just
say - al you can combine the options
usually that's that's a that's a key
that's a problem do not always it's an
entirely inconsistent [ __ ] why because
for example - al so what what do you
mean usually so let me show you an
example where you cannot you cannot just
combine the option names so I have
example I have quite quite a lot 1,000
examples here okay there it is
perversion okay let me let me show you
okay let me let me show you this Emacs
okay let's show Perl - version you see
that / - version in fact it's - Ruby -
version can we do that Ruby - version it
is let's say Python - version there is
you see - version it oh wait look there
it is the problem I thought - [ __ ]
a new option - e you see so what is the
problem you guys know what's the problem
I'm getting into right Oh am i - so you
see normally the -
is supposed to be combination of options
but not always it depends it depends on
each and every program so here so for
some of them you know the dash version
works okay works in Perl works in Ruby
but not Python because Python the
problem is when you know some command
they - several letters that's one option
that's not combination that's a problem
so it's inconsistent the syntax is
ad-hoc you know it's case by case basis
that means every time you call any UNIX
command you have to know what that
command specifically do you know the
syntax so so for every command you have
to learn a new syntax that's what it is
it's a factor of system and this is just
one of the example one of the problems
that there's a lot more ok so let me
show you ok so so so let's do Python
again let me show you the proper way to
code the Python one for some reason my
Shou is stuck ok so I don't know why my
my Shou is stuck
my shower is stuck for some reason this
happened to me recently I'm trying to
close it now
okay there it is so Python - - version
there it is that works
okay the - - is another thing the - - is
created by free software foundation by
the GNU project because they they think
they can improve it but it end up in the
more complexity so anyway so this
article is a bit long they are quite a
lot more and the most interesting thing
is the PS okay let me show you another
example PS a you wwx you see this
command shows all your processes against
PS space
uw-w x notice that there is no - so my
point here is that it's there's no that
the syntax is not consistent every
basically in practice okay this is not
in theory in practice every unix command
when you call them you have to learn
it's specific to syntax okay so you have
one you have few thousand unix commands
every one they have slightly different
syntax is one [ __ ] up okay that's that's
a UNIX philosophy I mean that's yeah
that's what UNIX philosophy is you know
the UNIX philosophy they tell you oh SMO
it's beautiful Oh each each program in
UNIX is so small and if they do it
perfect you know they do one thing well
well where are my ass okay
I haven't get into why he said yet okay
good but but this Oliver I discuss those
issues the bottom line is that is just
inconsistent it's one [ __ ] up [ __ ]
that's your UNIX philosophy you probably
don't know because you you all you know
is that it's beautiful its UNIX programs
it's most beautiful they are UNIX is
just beautiful beautiful period it in
fact is the most ugly [ __ ] possible okay
that that's about that UNIX pipe okay so
yeah so we
two things here one thing is about UNIX
pipe then the other thing is about the
UNIX UNIX Pipers functional programming
the UNIX options it's inconsistent okay
that's about that alcove then we're
gonna talk about method chaining okay
it's starting to get more complex
actually how long have I been talking of
fifty-six minutes
okay so Newton versus Lebanese okay
that's a great topic Nabi says no you
sounds like a joke it's a punchline but
if you are seriously asking this camel
case and the snake case thanks okay so a
a says C versus C plus Q I haven't run
into you know the I haven't run into
those syntaxes you know the UNIX shell
syntax they change they changed they did
change in the past thirty years and
there is no one there is no one
consistent old vision you know there is
no one way you know they change is just
randomly because that's how Unix Linux
today Linux you know since year 2000 to
year 2000 Linux took over and and in the
past 20 years Linux you know has their
own direction of change in the
command-line syntax for example today a
new generation let me show you okay so a
new generation today you have get ok let
me show you kiddies one of the exemplar
theory of the syntax changes the command
command line syntax changes that happens
happened in the Linux you know world in
the past 20 years this this begin about
you know many Unix commands they have
now this syntax and let me show you so
get help okay you see it works I can you
know we can do this in terminal as well
you see get help you see but you see the
interesting thing to note here is that
get help like what the [ __ ] you know
normally by the traditional unix way you
don't do command like that like that you
you must have - like you should be get -
- help that's a new way
Oh get - edge ok that's a tradition okay
that's a UNIX tradition beginning about
2007 or so okay it changed because this
David there became a lot programs that I
started to have this new kind of syntax
that is skit you know like a command
name then a sub command name then
options okay this is new okay I'm
telling you guys this is kind of new in
fact I have a arc on that too somewhere
let's see if I can find it because why
am because I'm observing you know I
study these kind of things I'm obsessed
you know and I study and I then I blog
about it so sorry UNIX command-line
syntax let's see if I can find an
article
that alko is buried somewhere somewhere
evolution okay command-line syntax
evolution yeah anyway that's not
important article I mean you just said
you know the starting around 2007 you
you started to have commands that takes
this form and for example in Ruby okay
let me show you Ruby okay so for example
you newbie so you go to Luke sorry Ruby
website then you can find let me show
you okay so for example I think it's
Ruby is one of the primary reason that
started to have this change in UNIX
command-line interface I think use Ruby
is one of the primary cause okay so in
Ruby if you are in Ruby if you are Ruby
community programmer
you you know Ruby has this bunch of
tools IRB is Ruby interactive you know
Ruby so you have I which is Ruby stock
reader okay it's like a man page so then
you have ruby gem you know gem is to
install you know package manager ruby
gem then you have rake rake is similar
to make okay Ruby's version of make so
you have a bunch of this Ruby
command-line tools and usually they you
know they are written they are you know
they are written in Ruby and they they I
think they didn't follow the UNIX
tradition way exactly for some reason
you know it's not it may not be a
intentional change it just happens it
just happened so you see for example you
have this ruby bundle Ruby bundle okay
that's a command command in Ruby so the
way you run it is bundle then command
then options then argument you know just
like the get help thing the gets
something kid commit kid get add you
know get you know just like it so you
have all these bunch of Ruby commands
that takes this new form so that's what
I'm saying so Ruby I think and and I'm
not sure Ruby began
or was it Python I don't know but anyway
that's some example okay so let me post
that so we have today's talk show topics
Ruby okay so next thing so yeah so
that's about the evolutions of unix
shell commands next thing method
chaining postfix operator and opie okay
so actually you know those three three
or four five more topics that's gonna
take another hour so I'm not sure I'm
not sure I we got 14 people watching oh
god okay my energy drink is gone and do
I have more energy drink I don't think
so hmm sad and now we drink tea I guess
tea
so a a says a has a counter-argument you
said you are going to demonstrate that
types are not good then you jumped to
arguments which are mere data so any
program handles them as as it wants
therefore you stress nothing here
the only convention is having are
exposed to programmers programs through
lips start meant to me if you are using
Pepsi no I haven't begin yet okay those
are just what I've talked a sofa
I just pre dude we have not started to
talk about the the kind of well this is
a lot more okay so so I'm going the next
thing we're gonna talk about is about
method chaining postfix operator and
object-oriented programming
object-oriented programming so I you
know this there's a lot I want to say
are you guys sport so hand
okay so I should continue I guess I need
to i okay so so this video is getting
long so I have to think about what am I
gonna do okay let's let me push on okay
push on for maybe 20 minutes let's see
where we are we're gonna try to finish
this topic in one video so method
chaining postfix
operators in okay okay let me this is
written four years ago so let me remind
myself what I'm talking about
okay so
okay so let me tell you what this
article is about let's go to now let's
use a JavaScript example okay so let's
do that okay so open the new one and
magnify and JavaScript and let's do a
JavaScript let's say SS okay constant
constant X okay so s is a stream okay
let's say some okay so we got a string
and what we want to do let's do a split
just like Python K xx split okay
separator some thing okay split into a
array so split by a space and that's it
okay so constant Y y equals to that okay
so this is JavaScript now we need to
print it why why okay run it there is a
result okay that's that's this is
JavaScript now in order for this to work
the nummy-nummy think let me let me try
let me think about
you see the you see the dot notation the
dot notation is convenient in the sense
that it is like UNIX pipes or function
chaining or postfix notation why is it
convenient because you know you just
have dot something dot something so it
like forms a sequence like a flow flow
of the data like pipes you know water
pipes so dot notation in object-oriented
programming is many of you of people
like it because it's like function
chaining or piping or postfix notation
that these are different ways to
describe it you know it's a stream but
let me show you let me show you some
examples about how you know like more
than one dot let's see if I have some
examples
so what what are some examples of darts
okay so I mean I want a sequence of dots
we need to come up with the example
quickly a sequence of dots so split into
a strain then okay trim okay so let's
needs to trim do I have trimmed yes we
do so split okay let's do this okay
so we begin with a stream with a space
before and after with a coma there then
we try to split by a comma then we try
to trim it remove the empty spaces so
let's run it okay I got a problem
trim is not there okay let's go to
JavaScript tutorial my JavaScript
tutorial in depth now if you guys like
my stuff by myself okay by myself I have
a link at the bottom where you can buy
my JavaScript you know I have a links
somewhere here you know where is my by
JavaScript link [ __ ] I need to I need to
promote myself okay there is there is my
patreon okay and and by JavaScript
tutorial I have the best the JavaScript
tutorial so you can support me you know
just make a token a gesture of
appreciation if you like my stuff buy it
okay so anyway so um so what I want to
do so let's we need to look at
JavaScript reference stream stream
prototype we want the function that you
know various function trim okay so there
is a trim so why is it not walking here
so trim returns a new stream wait this
page is bad because I fail to say when
is this function added I think
this function is in JavaScript es mm mm
oh yeah script
yes 2019 so it's not in not jazz yet
maybe okay so train star let's see if we
can have that dream starts
it's not in JavaScript I mean it's not
in the the not J's version I mean so for
example not - version a bad option
version you see this annoying [ __ ] this
you see this is a practical this you
know when so we talked about the UNIX
syntax inconsistency it's not just so in
theory it's practical because sometimes
it's one - virtual sentences - - version
and as we have seen in Python sometimes
it doesn't work you have to use - V it's
a practical [ __ ]
so stop chanting about the UNIX
philosophy or how great it is it is
actually not that great okay it's you
know when you are chanting it you are -
you are doing you are spreading
propaganda you are spreading fake news
and and in turn it doesn't benefit you
okay it creates problem it creates like
today's problem where Google Microsoft
they are the greatest power in promoting
open source but meanwhile they are
actually the most evil you know the you
they rob you you have no power you know
if you don't work for them you cannot
make a living you have nothing that's
that's what happens when you chant
propaganda you know code that you think
it's good but you actually it's not
Wayne's force so anyway so so what we
want to show ok so not so anyway so trim
string doesn't work I don't have it so
let's try something else
slice ok Java JavaScript is fairly bad
so ok so we cannot use stream slice ok
slice 3 ok let's see doing it starts end
ok so I don't know what's going on
oh okay so so split stream returns on
array so you cannot you know it returns
an array of two elements then if you
want to take a substring you have to map
it to you have to map okay so so there
is we we are doing multiple dots now so
map stream photo type slice okay stream
photo type
okay so it's becoming complex this is
one reason some people object the DAR
notation because then you have a one
long line so and and by the way if you
don't know what this is it's a bit
complex okay that's the way JavaScript
is so split returns a array now so you
now you want to take a substring for of
each element so now you have to call map
okay
map is a method of array and when you
map you want to code the function slice
and you have to say stream prototype
slice okay start start at let's say it's
not at one okay so we basically we are
taking a sub stream by dropping the
first character okay let's run it
why is why Smith not Jeanette
map array Maps
Eero something is not a function ah god
this is getting more complex but it's
sure you okay so the error is that it's
complaining so you see map takes one
argument one or more that needs to be a
function and here that is not a function
because that what we have there is an
expression we are doing a function call
strained out prototype does slice you
know what so we need that to be a
function so in order to do that you need
an arrow function so this is how you do
it okay so let me show you okay so this
is the this is actually the proper way
okay so let's I'm now going to explain
so well so anyway so here is the arrow
function in so lambda it's a function it
takes one argument then you know the X
is a string you slice it by dropping the
first character okay run it there we
have it
so let's change the example here okay
let's run it
okay so okay so X sum X thing we
dropping the X you know so that's how
you how it works so you you here's an
example of this is actually a real world
example of dar notation in practice you
see so you see dot then dot something
map then actually we can start again so
we can dot again you know anyway we are
getting more complex
okay so copy that to here and color it
showing browser there it is okay that's
the example of dot notation so what what
is my point my point I want to mention
is that you know dot notation is
convenient because it's like a sequence
of things a chain function chain oh it's
a function chain or UNIX pipe or postfix
notation because you think of the dart
as a postfix notation argument comes
before the function so you know it's
convenient but however in the old Veta
notation there is one requirement it
does not always work in order for our
notation to work the whatever before the
dot must be your object and whatever the
method you call must be a method of that
object so when you have a dot B dot C a
must have the method B and whatever that
returns must have the method C you see
every time you toss something it returns
something and that something must be a
object then the next method must be a
method of that object you see it needs
to have this object method relation for
each of your data dot something if
there's no such relation your thought
doesn't work so what I'm saying is that
it's not a general way it's not our
actual postfix notation it's tied to a
semantics you see so here's the thing
you see we are talking about the
connection between programming language
semantics and its syntax you see when we
look at that notation we think oh this
is great syntax you know this is just
the syntax very convenient syntax but no
that's not totally it peace
you know this syntax works if and only
if you know whatever your dot that thing
must be object and it must have a
relation with a method otherwise it
doesn't work
that is my point okay that is my point
that that is the point of this article
method chaining postfix operator and ol
P so so what was so why so so what's
what's a big deal what's the big deal
the big deal is that you cannot if you
have two arbitrary functions you can now
simply chain them they must have a
relation they must have a object method
you know relation then you can chain
them so this is kind of a limitation in
Oh P now you might say oh yeah but why
do you need to change some you know some
method that's unrelated to the object
right because oh he's designed you know
whatever data are the object always have
its method you want to call you don't
need a method outside of that object
that's not true that's not totally true
because in many situations in all people
I mean you do want sometimes you want a
method that's not in this object but you
do want to call it for example we we
almost show the example that string dot
prototype but anyway so some so even in
well-designed opie languages it does
occur and actually often okay where you
have a situation you
to call a method unlike only data but
however that method is not a method of
the data that method it belongs to some
other object so you got a problem when
that happens you cannot simply dot
something you can you know this this
chain notation this star notation breaks
you don't you cannot use it anymore but
if you are in a functional programming
language or in UNIX pipe for example it
always works you see when you pipe you
know when you pipe air a start - air to
grab - something to what count it does
not require a object method relation
between the things it's just data you
know it's just pass through but in the
dot notation it actually it's different
it requires this relation to work okay I
think maybe I'm it might like babbling
too much I don't think I'm getting tired
and I should stop and so we talked about
that I hope I hope I hope I conveyed
this thing even though it's pretty
verbose velocity but velocity is good
for you know driving in the point
so just in sci-fi so let me see just in
scoff I say stock size using a virtual
editor Emacs live in Windows now I mean
II max this is not virtual editor this
is Emacs so let me see what what are you
guys saying okay so
so crash hacker says good morning for
convenience underscore but I'm using
spaces for privacy related stuff okay
you are not using trim on string here
that's right yeah
so I corrected that trim it first right
dream okay so crash hacker says I still
don't see the advantage over pipes right
so town notation justine says what was
window written Emacs by Bill Gates was
windows written in Emacs by Bill Gates
I don't think Bo Gates uses Emacs okay
Pablo okay so what editor did Pio gates
right windows in I don't think it's
Emacs Q because if it is we I must have
heard over the past 30 years yeah I
don't think he used Emacs and and when
the time at the time when he began
Windows I don't think there is a Emacs
editor I mean there's no Emacs in you
know in whatever operating system he is
using you know that's the beginning of
personal computers he essentially
created it
okay I think maybe that's it okay so
actually I have some more things about
pipes so actually I explained most of it
what I want to talk about pipes so we
explained this wait we didn't explain
that yet so we explain method chaining
postfix operator NOP okay in summary the
Oita notation seen technically it is a
form of chaining functions or postfix
operator but but but actually it it it
it is the it depends on the function it
depends on the object method relation
for this syntax to walk okay then then
then then my roommates
Honus economic risotto
then the okay my roommates I gotta go I
think I gotta go we're gonna there's a
this another big topic I want to talk
about that is the relation of function
composition versus postfix notation
another day I guess so thank you guys
for watching bye guys
and act like actually there are kind of
a few things I want to talk about maybe
next time
so there's also closure you know closure
a dialect of this you can it has
function Chinese syntax like that and
also I want to show you this JavaScript
code I wrote which allows you to have
the function chaining pipe you know the
UNIX pipe without requiring the object
method relation between the things so
this is you know I am pretty proud of
this like one day I realized I can write
this it's pretty easy JavaScript so this
is a function that allows you that
creates a pipe you know creates a
function chaining notation basically a
function pipe without requiring the
object method relation Thank You Kathy
Thank You Kathy Kathy and thank you all
bye guys
long video we did today long the video
90 minutes