so guys welcome to another episode of s
talk show today we are going to do
Advent of code live coding in Wolf and
language and I'm going to do the
shortest code possible on Earth so
Advent of code day three live coding
okay if you are here say hi okay Shall
We Begin let's check audio check video
check oh okay so to the
code Adent code let's see if we can do
it okay so Advent of code 20203 day
three here is the problem so you are
given a
input you are given a input like that
okay so let's magnify so you are given a
input a text file so let's let's go to c
talk
show
uh okay so you are given a input like
that a text file and uh and what is the
problem sum up number adjacent to a
symbol even diagonal
diagonally periods do not count as a
symbol so for example
uh so for example let's see okay so you
are given this text so for example there
is a symbol AS risk so adjacent so that
467 is part of it now 114 is not because
you know the diagonal is you know it's
one off and uh then 35 is part of it 633
is not okay so you want all the numbers
that's neighbor of a symbol character
now what are the symbols so period does
not
count uh and uh I guess anything else
except letters again the Advent of code
is never
precise so anyway so you you want to get
all the numbers adjacent to a symbol
then you want to sum them up okay so in
this example it says one 144 and
58 144 there and
58 are not adjacent to a symbol others
are okay so you get all the numbers but
remove 144 and 58 then you sum them up
and result should be
4361 that is a Advent of code 20123 day
three problem
one okay so so I read this problem
yesterday I thought a little bit about
it it's a interesting problem uh what do
I want to say uh there is
um okay hello Joan Molina J hello ago so
the problem you know my first you know
I'm trying to actually solve this
problem today okay instead of you know
uh but meanwhile I want to talk about it
okay so the first question is like you
know again Advent of code when you solve
a when you program a problem there is
many issues for example efficiency
algorithmic efficiency
concerns uh and uh storage concerns
efficiency concerns and also uh the code
Elegance concern or the code readability
and maintenance maintainability concern
you know you can't have cryptic code
because you know if if you write a
software you know web server or whatever
you have to come back to it to uh to add
features and so on you have to maintain
it or upgrade the language version so it
must be readable so you have all these
concerns but with Advent of code it's
like all those are thrown out because
they don't care you know Advent code is
just online puzzle Whoever has the most
splashy you know you want a solution
that is most attention catching like a
drama like a clickbait oh Advent code
number number three solution oh this
language so weird or so short or so
cryptic oh this is the longest solution
possible then people is going to thumb
up okay that's a nature ofand of code so
anyway this problem I was thinking so um
so first you consider this uh text block
as as a matrix okay so each spot is one
space you know so you so those periods
are empty spots so you consider this as
n by m Matrix okay so the first question
is what is is uh if the numbers are Spar
if if this is a spar Matrix that means
there are just a few numbers for example
you have 10 million by 10 million you
know these characters okay but you only
have let's say 100 numbers in it so that
would be a sparse Matrix okay okay so
the first question is whether the
numbers are sparse because if the
numbers are sparse then your algorithm
if you want to be efficient you just
want to grab the numbers and see check
each number if they have adjacent
symbol if if the numbers are Spar
alternatively if the if this uh the
symbols are Spar for example you have 1
million by 1 million characters and uh
and uh you have a million you have three
million numbers okay however you only
have 10 symbols 10 of these
symbols then if that's a case you want
to just pass for the symbols for each
symbol you want to check if there's a
number adjacent to it okay that's a case
of the if the symbol is pass but the
problem you know Advent of code they
never say they don't say anything like
that so if you take your time you know
if you take time to make your code okay
there's another let me talk about
another issue the other issue is it
didn't say what are the symbols it just
say you know the Advent code you can see
here it just says that period are not
symbol okay okay but what kind of symbol
do you have in this example example we
see asterisk we see the number sign we
see the plus sign we see the dollar sign
but what if you have a letter is that a
symbol or not it doesn't say and uh are
these all the possible symbols there it
doesn't say the [ __ ] Advent of a
code I want to criticize it a little bit
because for vast majority of people who
are doing this I I presume uh college
students or young people or teenagers
you know they don't have better things
to do but for a professional programmer
your time is better spend you know you
you do you make a lot of money when you
are not coding you don't want to code
right so anyway I want to criticize a
bit because vast majority of people
doing this they never talk about this I
don't think so you know you rarely see
people analyze the the the problem the
criticism of the Advent the code the
puzzle and and so on okay so we have the
sit few situations where the the numbers
are Spar Spar Matrix or whether the
symbols are Spar okay
or maybe neither okay maybe they are
just like kind of random in that case
you know you say it's a
mized you know you write a program
algorithm that that is best that is most
algorithmically efficient for that
situation anyway so then the other
situation is what how many uh what are
the set of
characters for the symbol it doesn't say
so let's look up our own
input so let's see let's have a look
okay so here so
um so Does it include a b or c let's see
uh so we are in emac so we can grab for
let's say find replace uh let's say list
matching lines and let's give a bracket
A2 Z
and copy that and capitalize so that's
all possible A to Z let's see if there's
anyone okay it's none so there's no
letters so uh and uh judging by this um
okay let's do
some text processing okay copy it here
query replace back slash dot that means
a literal dot one or more enter replace
with nothing okay ban uh to replace them
all what let's do it
again
okay okay so it becomes so short now
let's make them one line okay now again
let's do fine replace okay this time
029 one or more all replace by nothing
okay replace all okay so now it becomes
shorter now
H so basically that's all the symbols
you got okay
so okay so good you see because if
you you know the spec doesn't say what
you know what's what are the set of
symbols so if the spec doesn't say
typically what you can do is you code
your program so that you find all
possible symbols of any
input if you don't do that then your
solution if if I give you another new
input but with a new symbol let's say
let's say comma okay do is there any
comma no you know I put a comma there
your program broke you
see but if you take the time to write a
generalized solution nobody cares like
you know your code is slow and you know
so on so that's a some analysis about
this situation okay so let's close that
close that so how do we solve this so we
are going just to assume we are not
going to I'm not going to like create
the most efficient whatever but however
I'm going to try I'm pretty sure I'll
succeed to come up with a shortest
possible uh solution code for this
problem okay and uh show this possible
solution and
uh not care about the generalization
okay and uh uh okay
so so okay how do you solve this you
know um it's not hard but it's a bit
tedious so there are quite a few ways
okay you go through each line you grab
the number then you see the number has a
adjacent uh symbol if if if if if so
then you put that number into a uh array
okay then you repeat that for every line
then at the end you just add up all the
numbers in the array okay that's
essentially um
it okay that's you know enough talking
that's 20 minutes let's see if I can
actually code it within an hour uh I
hope so I'm trying to let me try to be
focused on this okay so I
um Advent code so solution uh so let's
start a
um uh start the wolam language okay so
uh yeah start wolam language start
it new
notebook let's put a new notebook
here
three evaluate it and uh let's
magnify okay
so so um so first of all you want to get
the input okay so the input is
this I'm I'm trying to finish this okay
uh instead of failing okay so we got
input so what do you want to do so you
uh first of
all let's
see let's just try to solve the problem
don't worry about efficiency or anything
else uh
so uh I'm just going
to you know I'm I'm going to try to
finish this so even if that means no
talking I'm going to try to do it okay
so let me just um
string length let's see how many
um characters are there so I know it's
10 by 10 this is 10 x 10 characters but
each line you have a line break so
that's why it's
11 so you
can the most basic way is you go through
each line uh for example we are on line
two uh but how do you
find the previous line and next next
line well if you are on line to the
previous is minus one the next line is
plus one okay so you pass these lines
into a array string
split so that's one way to do it each
element is a line that's one way to do
it uh and when you are on first line you
check make sure you are you know you
don't have go to array zero or array
negative
one same thing with uh when you are are
at the end of the uh last line so that's
one way to do it
but another way is that you can um you
can consider the whole thing as one
single one single string so you don't
have to deal with each line uh but how
do you if you do that how do you find
the previous line for for example this
line uh what is this character maybe
that that's the 14th character okay so
that's a 14th character
how do you find the position of the
previous line above it so that would
be actually you can do it without going
to the previous line because they are 10
characters per line so 14
minus 10 right 14 minus 10 so for
example if this so actually we can do
actually we can actually do this uh
backward chart so let me let me try to
this okay iMac this backward chart okay
backward chart character we move the
cruiser uh backward so 14 okay so if we
have this code and we put the code
here uh actually it should be 14 + 1
because there is a End of Line character
so let's try 15 okay copy that so put
the cruiser here if we move backward 15
it should end up there
okay
so okay do it eval eval the
uh eval expression
okay okay that didn't work why is it so
it moved back there so let's try do it
again do it again eval
backward oh okay so each line line is 10
uh
so let's try each line is 10 the current
position so actually 10 not
15 well plus the end of line so it's 11
okay so let's try it
again show the pink window so you can
see all my commands eval expression
paste it do it fantastic let me let's
try again and put it
here fantastic you see
so so two ways first of all you can
split split string to make each
line uh array element or consider the
whole thing as one single string then
when you want to move to the previous
line next line you simply just move by
you know increase the index by by
11 uh but then you also you still need
to check if they
are out of bound the
index right yeah okay okay that's uh
it's kind of okay we got some thought
about that
okay so the total of number of
characters is 111 okay 110 okay so then
um so what's the easiest way let me
think about it okay
so now the whole solution is going to be
what in one single line and the function
we are going to use is string cases
which I
explained I spent one hour to to explain
this function yesterday okay now you can
look at the document mentation here
string cases wam language magnify
okay
uh it takes two arguments the first
argument is a string the second argument
is a pattern okay like regular
expression
so the overall structure is just going
to be string cases then
just total okay be because string cases
return a list of
things then with a pattern then in the
pattern part you can just
say you can just say replace it by
number okay two
expression D okay in a pattern we we
name a one of these you know we name the
number we give it a name n let's say n
okay let's say num then here we convert
the string a number string to actual
number okay so again this string case is
return a list so it just going to return
a list of numbers okay then we just
total it that's you
know okay one single line of code now in
the pattern part you see the pattern
part you will include a condition such
that if a
number is not adjacent to a symbol that
caption that that is not part of the
pattern okay so the pattern must satisfy
a condition such that if this number is
adjacent to a to a symbol okay but this
is basically the outline of the solution
okay so now let's start to code it
uh so the pattern will be okay so what
is the pattern the pattern is uh this
time let's uh let's see let's use
regular expression because I'm still
more familiar with regular
expression okay regular expression the
pattern is going to be oh wait here's
the thing if you use regular expression
then you cannot have a arbitrary
function as a condition so you have to
use the wol
F's uh string pattern syntax so that is
uh you know that's one of the power of
wolam
language because if you use regular
expression then you have
to actually it's kind of similar but but
Bas but basically you want to apply a
function to check the Matched pattern is
actually adjacent to a symbol but in wo
one the wo FS string pattern syntax you
can easily do that let me show you okay
string so string expression is the
represent a text pattern okay and uh the
syntax is condition uh uh
pattern and the function okay that's
that's what you want so the pattern will
match first then if the function returns
true then that actually is captured
otherwise no okay so that is a basic
syntax let's write write it
out okay so that's a that's a okay
that's a string expression so first of
all what is the pattern the pattern
is
digit digit character
okay the pattern is a digit character
and the function
is what is a
function okay the function is a bit hard
so we we need to write the function
number is valid okay let's let's name
our
function okay let's name our function
that valid number Q equals to
function given a
number and uh whatever whatever it does
return true or false okay so that is a
function right now it's a dummy
function it doesn't do anything always
it just always return return true for
now okay so in wame language convention
whenever you you have a symbol whose
name ends in a capital Q that means it's
a question in the list convention
typically they end in p p stand for
Pedic which came from logic basically it
means this function always return either
true or false okay so and in scheme lisp
and Ruby there convention is for the
function to ends in a question mark
okay so the reason wfam language ends in
Q not question mark is because question
mark has many other meanings so you know
there's a
tradeoff okay so that is our string
expression string pattern
okay now let's be Let's uh let's let's
digit character okay this's got to be
one more digit not
just okay digit dot dot is a Syntax for
one or more right okay
right uh then we also need to give this
pattern a name so we'll just name it num
okay so num then put a parenthesis so so
this whole line stand for a string
pattern such that the pattern is a digit
character repeated one or more times
and and it must this function on on that
pattern must return true valid number Q
Okay then if that is so then this
pattern has a name num we can refer to
it by num okay uh then we want so once
we got that for that pattern we
return this num string into a actual
number okay let's let's try let's try to
run this okay uh let's run see if that
runs please please God oh
God okay
problem what is the problem what is the
problem string or list of strings
expected at position one string cases oh
of course this string cases first
argument is
input
right okay let's run it
again
problem string case string or list of
strings expected at position one in
string cases okay string or list of
strings uh so why is it not a string
let's go back
to our
code it
says the input is a string right so why
is it why are you
complaining input input input it's a
string oh because we are evaluating this
uh wait yeah we you know we need to
commment this out so comment that out
and this part we also need to comment
out because
it's it's invalid okay now when
this
fantastic
okay so let's check okay
467 check
uh check 35 check 360 okay it seems to
check out okay we got all the numbers
now the difficult part is to write this
function valid number
Q how can you be sure it's a valid okay
so this is a difficult part now in order
to write this function we need to know
how many characters per line okay so
let's do that let me just show show you
know I'm just going to
show
uh Shar line okay so this
uh choer line equals
to CH equals to
split uh wait string split okay
input okay and split
by line break okay and uh return the
maximum of just one item okay then we
want to get the
length of that
so back slash back slash is the postfix
notation similar to the Unix vertical
line for pipe okay so we apply string
length to that okay so we move that and
also total okay so total chars equals
to okay so something like
that uh yeah
right fantastic fantastic okay uh this
is incorrect not 111 oh okay so you see
when you call string split it always
return a list so in this case you want
the first item of that list even if you
set one here you know return just the
maximum of one item but it still return
a least because that way the any
function this is a basic principle in
wolam language any function always
returns the same structure does not
matter what kind of parameters you pass
it they return structure is always the
same so string split all uh string split
always return a list even if there's you
know even you say just one item uh okay
so to get the first item you can just
say one okay run
it there it is okay wait wait the the
first part is still
wrong
uh okay what let's look up the
documentation for SP
stream
I find myself at an impass on day
10 Thiago Advanced day 10 of my journey
I'm hopeful that the de of programming
will be sty bestow their wisdom upon me
to guide me through day
10 very
Advanced I hope we I I will get to
that uh but I'm kind slow maybe that'll
become next year you
know day
10 okay so anyway so how many how many
days are there Advent of code you know
so this Christian thing until Christmas
right um but anyway Let's uh let's focus
on the code
so string split H I don't know what's
going on let's just print it okay let's
just
just let's just see what it
is uh
what CH lines okay
so
let's
wait so the split is not successful
what's going on so do you require double
back slash for
the I don't think so but what why why is
it
um always hate to be stuck
so it just Returns the whole
thing okay you mean just settling after
getting H work good luck
s getting home from work
okay so split stream
uh let's just try uh let's just try
random I don't think that's the yeah
something is wrong with my
code
okay okay now it works oh yeah okay so
why is
it
split at most and sub
strings oh okay actually you have to say
two ah I know because the first you see
we actually have a something before you
know like you know there's a difference
between that and that you know so the
actual it should be like that so if like
if it's like that it works R
it
[Music]
no
wait okay let's see two let's say
two yeah so you see this should be um
anyway should be two at most two of them
okay then you say get the first one then
you
say uh remove that then you say yeah
let's just change this to
two Okay done
it h okay so you need to print
output okay so chop line is 10 correct
okay uh this is 10 and uh and then
the total number of lines is 109 okay
okay
right okay so we got the string length
so now we need to do some modular
arithmetics that is given a position in
the
string you see here we captured the
number but however
we also need to know the
index of the
number the index within the whole
string
so you cannot so you cannot use string
cases you need the index you know you
captured the number but you also need to
know
the beginning and end of their index
because otherwise you have no
way
wait maybe there's a way this is
fantastic W language
hacking so one solution is you capture
you get the
index because without index you can't
you know check if that number is
adjacent to a
symbol okay that's one way you get the
index and in order to get index you need
to
say
uh you need to say string position I
believe give a list of starting and
ending characters position
okay
uh yeah so the this
actually yeah so instead of instead of
string cases you use string position to
get a least of beginning and end
positions for each digit
occurrence once you do that you have the
position then you you need to pass the
pos position to
um to where is
it did I just deleted yeah you then you
need to pass
your position to this so actually you
need two
arguments okay the first is a number the
second one is
position okay so this function is valid
number takes two
argument the position will be beginning
and end positions okay so that's one way
to do it the other way
now uh so if we do that then we we kind
of need uh not string cases but
string position okay so kind of like
that yeah they they have the same syntax
so that's one way to do
it but can we do it without doing the
string position
so if we don't have the string position
we just have a
number
we let's try let's think about if
there's another way some kind of pattern
matching on
symbols so one way is to get a bunch of
numbers then you also do the same thing
string cases but this time on the
symbols so you also got a bunch of
symbols yeah but how do you know their
relative position is there
way okay let me think about this I want
to get distance so I'm going to just
think about
it
is there a way to know the position I
mean with position you can solve the
problem but if you don't know the
position is there a way to Simply by
getting the pattern you know a list of
all the digits and the list of all the
symbols just by having
that are you able
to
okay I'm not I
um I don't think
so why not well
because the numbers the occurrence of
numbers and the occurrence of the
symbols they they have a
relation only when this relation is
satisfied meaning that they are adjacent
then the number is
valid so this
relation is a positional
relation right so it's a positional
relation uh but is there a way to you
know ultimately you have to somehow know
their
position uh but is it possible without
using stream position
like
I don't think so well because ultimately
you need to know their position if you
just get the patterns
then now is there a way in string cases
in a string expression to actually
return their
position I don't know so let's just look
up the
documentation for the string expression
syntax Maybe
if we are lucky maybe it it
um okay so this is too
big
um so here are the Syntax for string
expression these are string patterns we
want to know is it possible to also
extract the position they
occur pattern given in the
name so in a regular expression usually
yes in a regular expression when you
capture
something in python or emac L usually
you have a way to
know the the beginning and end
index where this capture happens yes
that's true in imag LP and also in
Python and I presume you know I I don't
remember but I think it's true in in
all in in all almost also in JavaScript
okay so so you can get the index
beginning and end index of something you
that matched a
pattern okay you can do that with
regular expression
functions okay so now the question is
can you do that with with the wolam
language string expression usually yes
because once you you know because the
string expression is supposed to be more
powerful I mean it's you know it's
supposed to be analogous to yes so so
now we are trying to find yes yeah we
are trying to find the pattern we
matched and we are trying to
find get their beginning and end
position okay and how do you do that uh
and in other languages that's usually
not part of
the pattern
syntax that is usually either a
different function or a method of the
regular expression object that return
the result uh regular expression object
then you can dot begin position or dot
end you know
so Pro so it's
likely it is true in wam language too so
you need so the string cases maybe
there's a function we can look up the
documentation let or another way is uh
we can just say
options okay
at string uh string
cases let's see
meta characters none ignore case force
overlap Force okay there is
no what what is meta
characters okay meta
characters meta characters is something
obscure
yeah meta characters is something
obscure meta characters is an option to
string position with meta characters
none no string have special
meanings uh with meta characters that
specifies the meta characters for
pattern
Escape
oh okay
Single Character matching uh but why is
there
no dedicated documentation
for yeah so it's not act it's it's
something obscure
interesting
we found we found kind of a bug you
see you know the page you found cannot
be found so this this this meta
character thing is something ofcu this
option uh and apparently it's not very
well
[Music]
documented okay M characters automatic
is equivalent to MAA characters that
that that
that okay
anyway it's not relevant to us okay so
but there is no how so the question now
is once you have a pattern once you
captured a pattern how do you get the
beginning and end position okay so that
means read the
documentation okay so we need to read
the documentation for string expression
so you know this is when I usually take
my tablet and walk and back and forth
for 10 minutes or something to read the
entirety of
this uh string expression documentation
that's what you I usually do so to
prevent my ass rot from sitting all day
so anyway let's read
it uh good evening Jesus settle in maybe
this maybe
what so we want to find the beginning
and end position okay so of a match okay
start of string there it is start of
stream start of the whole stream end of
stream end of the whole
stream wait wait no no no those are
the the start of stream is a symbol that
represent a
pattern to indicate that must start at
the beginning of a string similar to
regular Expressions correct character
okay so that is not it
so let me just uh read
it okay
[Music]
so
so you see normally in other languages
in Python in emac Lis in
JavaScript the information about the
beginning and end position of a matched
pattern is
typically
stored in a build-in variable in other
words it's not functional programming
because once you do some regular
expression match it matched
you know these begin end positions are
stored in in a totally entirely
different you know
variable
so it's not functional
programming uh okay but still the
question the question is how do you find
it in wam language with um
okay so now
we uh kind of stuck with this issue not
really you know we just haven't found
the you know answer yet there are two
approaches now one is the easy approach
just start to use the
search you you know search we find you
know find how how do I get the beginning
end position of a pattern that's the
easier way usually I don't like that
because I want to demonstrate you know I
should be able to I know where to look
uh but let's just cheat okay
so position of match okay let's see
let's see stream match let's see what it
says string and characters string
position string match
Quee uh work with string patterns okay
that take note that is kind of a
tutorial okay
uh
stream match
Q from the link pick range length at
input stream match Q pattern at input
so Sho says form the link
pick range at
length and
input okay I don't know what is that
though let's let's see so P suggest I
look into
this um the question is I don't know
what is pick very interesting let's see
what is
pick pick list selection pick out those
elements of list for which the
corresponding element of
selection is
true
yeah but if you do this you know a
number may be repeated in the
input so it's not necessarily unique and
also this is inefficient because once
you get a bunch of numbers for each
number you have to search through the
whole input again to find it I
think but there's a way to get a
position for sure you know you know
because you know like coding it makes it
looks like you know we cannot find it
but that's not the case it's just that
we haven't really spent time to find it
yet so we want to find so given once you
got a pattern match you want to find the
uh beginning and end position okay and
let me think about how is that done
usually so once you have a match you
want to know the beginning and end
position uh
again so let's check let's just check on
uh string expression documentation
again uh your ordinary stream okay so we
need
stream
maybe maybe you actually just have to
use stream
positions because you see this function
you know in wam language every function
is very
specific so if you want a position use a
string position if you if you just want
extract the cases then you use string
cases
maybe because once we use string
positions then we know the position then
we can easily
extract uh the pattern
so you know but let's
just I I haven't given up
yet to see if there's a
way so examples
okay
scope survey of the scope of standard
use cases okay so we don't
care uh use any order to match patterns
in any
order okay very
interesting by the way you cannot do
this in regular
expression uh assign or matching any
order to a
variable uh
anyway we want beginning and end
position okay applications sample
problems that can be solved with this
function uh find the primes with four
identical digits
okay find a prime with four identical
digits okay
uh properties and relations okay
okay string
count okay string free string
cases okay there is one string
position maybe we have to use stream
position now if we use stream position
then then we have to extract it okay
okay so let's okay let's move on let's
use stream position
then okay let's move on so check if the
code is the same yes okay uh the pick I
don't
think pick is is new pick is okay new in
2004 okay uh let me make sure your
suggestion is
actually works or
not pick out those elements of list for
which the corresponding element is true
okay so it's some kind of it's like a
bit
mask uh yeah I remember I read
this
so for example you have AB B CDE e then
you have a bit
mask one means pass through okay zero
means filter out so so you get
that
so so when so you are saying oh wait you
are
saying
I think you are suggesting a entirely
new solution such that we treat the
whole input as some kind
of you know Matrix then
we uh I don't know uh oh actually wait
it's actually that's another
approach so you treat the whole thing as
a list of
characters
then
you pick
out anyway that's a new
approach
uh but that's new approach I have to
think about that so for now let's focus
on what I'm
doing okay so close that so now let's
look at stream positions
yes it just this just run it okay run
it invalid okay something is wrong
string
positions uh why is it
invalid now if string
cases ah we got something wrong before
wait why is it's not working
anymore too many parameters in Num
position oh okay oh
okay because this function valid number
Q now takes two
argument so that is but here
it only gives one argument so it
complains so this is actually should be
position yeah that
work okay so string cases work okay now
let's try string positions
it okay why is
it oh yeah so when you do stream
positions OB
obviously you
get you can two expression so it uh it
returns a bunch two numbers okay so it
returns you you don't need you don't
even need this part
okay yeah so
here is it you know uh these are the
beginning and end positions of each
number
okay okay so change of plan oh
God okay I need a
break uh that's a issue with live coding
yeah you
can okay anyway so it returns that okay
now let's look at that again see what we
can do with string position so we get a
pattern you cannot actually replace it
here you can multiple patterns okay uh
Leist of results for each of the string
Okay so so you
can't yeah backu it's just more more
code okay string so you get the list of
numbers okay so
then
[Music]
you yeah so you can now you can have a
function
that uh
um you apply that to right right you map
this function okay let me just do it you
map this function
[Music]
to okay so let's do this positions
equals to that okay now all you have to
do is you map this function valid number
Q
to
to positions
okay uh and here
we
yeah I know what to do okay let me just
code it
so so
positions okay number positions so
here's a bunch of number positions and
you don't
need you don't need that
okay so this is number positions okay
it's shrink a little
bit okay
so
uh symbol positions now we get try to
get all the positions for
symbols
let's
see
yeah we can we can we can do all the
positions for symbols
too
um
okay now let's look at the Syntax for
string expression so we want to
exclude
except digit
character or
period okay that's our pattern so string
expression except
that
maybe let's test it
out
h
okay let's try the wolam language
notebook because last time it seems
easier to read there okay so we just
going to try some code
here no okay except digital character is
not a valid string oh
yeah uh wait no you can't use um
except does it take
[Music]
one instead of accept let's just
say characters
okay
okay now let's look at our input let's
just
see yeah wait where is our
input ler copy new buffer paste back
copy the file
path uh it's okay so go back here
um okay so now
let's read
string okay that's the this file is the
user input okay now let's look at the
user input let's remove like we did
before remove all
numbers and uh
remove digit
uh okay so then
we that's all the possible digits now we
want
to I mean that's all the possible
um C uh symbols okay so now we just we
can do let's use wam
language okay close that close that
close
that okay copy let's use W firm language
characters okay that
will that will return all the unique
characters
okay oh no
way uh it doesn't delete DLI cut
okay
let's just do this okay so close
that so delete
duplicate delete all duplicate from a
list okay
so
characters
input
then okay that's what we want so first
all
input that reads in the input now
uh s uh yeah we misspelled characters
okay so
unique
Char okay so that is
uh that is a list of symbol chars okay
let's try it
again yeah wa
did okay and
uh yep oh and you got digits stupid tic
digits you got you got to remove the
digits and remove the
um
period
okay uh what you can do is replace
string string rep
replace okay stream
replaced right so string
replace
input and by a
pattern okay
so let's see that
works uh
no stream
replace oh you need uh you need a yeah
you need a
rule
so those becomes empty string
yep and here you need double
backlash wait
no
uh string replace replace one or more
digit
characters and
uh
replace one or more p
period
okay this is getting long and
longer no common
okay yeah but I want to finish
this so string replace input digit
characters why is it not matching I
don't understand why why is this maybe
okay I'm just like doing trial and error
now the worst way of
programming okay that kind of worked
actually so now
now
um so why is the back slash not
working oh wait so it's not followed by
right this means followed
by string expression so you want all so
let's use
all
I don't know no that that's
not okay
it's
mhm
no uh because
[Music]
we how do I read of the period it's very
odd period one or
more why can't
I remove
period
H where am
I okay now the input is too big now
let's try the original
input here okay now let's
try
now this let's go back to the Syntax for
string expression there is a all pattern
here a pattern matching at least one of
the pattern okay so you can either use
all or or least okay so you use a
list
okay so you can use a list
here
uh okay and remove the
per so it's either a digit
character
or uh one bunch
of
period okay the period removal is
failed
oh you oh just just a period I [ __ ] I'm
so idiotic you know I've been
brainwashed by the regular expression
back slashback slash thing so a period
in a string is just a period in the
wolam string expression pattern so okay
so this expression means this pattern
means a digit character 10 more
or a period one or more replace them by
empty string and actually here we can
just say rule instead of rule delay
there it is and also replace space okay
uh space replace new
line okay oh so the number patterns is
very small I mean the number of symbols
is very small okay so you got that
that uh that put that so this this gives
you
a you see the possible symbols are just
that okay
so okay let's write it down
ah God now it's almost two
hours any else anyone else is watching
say
hi okay this is
another so we got the input we got
unique symbol characters list of unique
symbol CES not many it's just four of
them asterisk pound sign
plus and the dollar sign okay then CH
line okay hello
lron
great uh then yeah actually I need a
break got element
except so where is this
except oh yeah symbol position let's
remove
that
uh so symbol positions okay
so symbol positions now we know what are
the symbols so unique same
charts so it's
just
uh is actually just that
okay let's see
okay so what is this the first part uh
then something invalid okay character is
not valid okay so we got the syntax zor
some some code we are not using there
so yeah so here is wrong
character yeah so remove that remove
that okay now run it again let's see
what we got okay so we got a big line
one single
line okay let's
see go to the top so we got a input we
got unique symbol characters a list of
characters okay like that then we got
chart per line okay we got total number
of charts okay uh then we don't care but
the now this function we
haven't uh return implemented yet valid
number whether it's true or not uh
number positions this uh what does this
do
so input string expression number uh
number positions let's
see string cases let's common that uh
okay so now we just got number positions
let's see if that's
right
okay okay so it's one giant big of
numbers okay now let's go back to the
let's not
read our long input let's just use the
toy
input okay so the number of
positions Okay so 1 three yeah okay
that's the position of the number first
number 1 three second
number okay wrong 1 three and 2 three
and 3 three so it's actually you
see
467 then 67 then seven okay that's not
that's not what we want so the um so the
number positions here
is incorrect okay this number positions
is
incorrect make sure we that's what we
see yep so the number of positions is
incorrect okay we can evaluate it here
so you can see 1 3 2 3 3 three that's
not right
uh so here is a question about pattern
matching whether you want to match
maximum or
minimum okay uh which is an
issue but usually it's longest why is it
um stream positions okay uh let's see
stream positions let's look at the
stream positions
documentation
and options okay overlap true we we run
into that before ignore case true
yeah re string position return sequence
specifications in the form used by
string take and blah blah blah okay give
position substring
matching uh okay yeah so it gives
okay uh yeah and bio sequence bio
sequence uh okay it does not
mention okay
so what we have to do is we use the
longest which is the
default so why is it um yeah this
is problematic what you know let's let's
just try
this string positions let's just try it
okay string positions uh
string uh number number
okay uh and
uh okay so let's see what that
returns yeah you don't want the
semicolon
cuz the semicolon suppresses the
output okay
so
57 oh God this is not
good 1
three 2 three 3 three so it
it wait so is the overlap true or false
ah God so
me ignore case overlap true H we want
overlap false
okay we don't want
overlap
there it is
we so many tricky
details
okay okay stream position so so that
that that overlap Force
okay
God
okay now
run
it now better let's
check 13 yes this 68 okay looks right
then 25
26 yeah then 29 33
31 yep
okay good finally got that part right l
says W seems like a very complicated
language kind of well I would say you
know that
depends it's very different from all
industrial languages for sure but I
would say it's actually so if you are a
alien from Mars you don't know anything
about Earth or human beings uh but you
are intellig
ENT you know you just came from Mars
then you drop to Earth then you let's
say you are given uh let's say Java
python W fir language hascal lisp you
start to learn them in parallel okay
which one would this alien find the
easiest I would say that would be wfam
language okay that's my view it appears
very complex because it's very different
from the vast you know the industrial
common industrial languages most people
are familiar with C Java C++ python they
all basically do the same way you know
bash you know so but however if you are
fresh and
new I would
say yeah I'm pretty I'm pretty sure I
would I would say
it's UAM language is actually pretty
simple okay back to the problem so we
got a list of
positions we got a list of number
positions okay uh and
now since since we found a problem about
about the overlap now we need to do that
for the for the symbol positions as well
because if we don't let's see what it
returns
oh so it so happens symbols are never
consecutive it's interesting to find you
see symbols are never
consecutive
but you know if day one is any
indication maybe in a real input it
sneaks
in consecutive symbols does it actually
actually happen
somewhere I don't know but you
see symbols so happen to be never
consecutive but it is actually something
we have to look out for because the
problem does not say that symbols never
occur
together you see that's a that's a thing
about Advent of a code but from the look
of it it looks like the symbols on never
adjacent to each
other but anyway just to be sure you
know just to be safe the I mean the the
actual the correct solution is to not
assume that not assume that that uh
symbols
are never adjacent so this is the better
let's run it
you see uh okay so let's you know let's
run them
two let's run two account one is
symbol uh overlap true other one overlap
Force let's see and this time let's use
the our
input
so let's see
copy new buffer
paste so we got two of
them one is
149 okay so it's hard to tell from these
output they are the same or not okay but
what you can do is that you can say
equal then you um yeah
so
so we can see we can let me
see
equal let's see if they are equal or
not oh they are equal so actually the
symbols never
happens
consecutively
interesting hidden ship
okay so
anyway o overlap Force okay we want
actually we want overlap Force we don't
assume the symbols never
overlap okay so we got number positions
now we and then then we got symbol
positions now we need to write this
valid number this is actually the heart
of the problem and we spend almost two
hours we haven't write this code yet
yet uh actually it's good time for a
break you know because
usually when you take a break you can
look at some other approaches then
usually you know in instead of you
slaving into the details like this this
um you might find a better way and solve
it
easier but you know or we can just push
on and then let's just let's just push
on I mean we are making a lot of
progress it's not like we are stuck
somewhere right
so so so now we need to write the valid
number the valid number is it valid
given a position beginning and end
position so what we have to do is okay
we need to write this function so the
body of the function will
be
uh basically the algorithm will be check
if there is a
symbol in front or
after the number
okay then
check if there is a
symbol above the
line okay then check if there is there
is a symbol after the line okay so three
lines we we need to
check a symbol in front of a okay
so first first of all let's check check
if there is a
adjacent
uh lindra says turns out that in a super
functional language like wolm you need
to write a gazillion functions just to
replace simple Loop for C that's that's
false that's patently
false you know the one thing with doing
live stream is
that you
see why do I have all these functions I
don't need to if I'm react if I'm
actually just coding it myself you won't
see all this fun funs but then nobody
would understand what I'm doing you see
and also I use this long form you know
is there's a lot you know also I I write
them such that in such I went out my way
to write them in all this way so that
the readers you guys can understand what
I'm doing because normally you don't
write things this way you know you
uh and also I'm I'm writing these extra
variables you know just so that mostly
it's for that purpose you
know so in fact if you code wam language
you know you can look at the previous
two days solution there's one there's no
extra function outside this is like the
whole solution is one single line one
single expression there is no even
definition of a function one single
expression within 200 characters for
each Advent of code day okay and I would
say for all Advent of code in fact for
the entire history of event of code any
of this problem is one single line of
wolam
language uh in you know within let's say
500 characters the entire history of
Advent of code problem okay and further
I would claim you don't even have to
Define one single
function you know you might think I'm
exaggerating I'm not because that's the
nature of wolam language it's a it's a
[Music]
um term rewriting system you know in in
the academic computer science way of
speaking it's called term rewriting
system you don't need you
know but anyway so that's kind of
getting getting you know so anyway let's
go back to
um yeah you know kind of you know
addressing these issues gets me
energized but but I'm not solving the
problem right now so we need
to I'm tired um sitting here for like 2
hours
now um we need to write this function
so um yeah so check you know you just
have to check each line
so so given that
um so let's let's start with the easiest
case
so so now I'm thinking is there a way
actually without checking positions at
all you simply use some kind of pattern
matching such that
you you know without knowing any
position about anything but you simply
use some some string
pattern that will match your number only
if it has one of these symbols adjacent
to it you know even above it or below it
you see because now we took the time to
find out all the symbols there is
there's actually just four of
them so is it possible to write a string
pattern such
that you don't even need to know the
position
[Music]
um it is actually it may be possible and
also shico made this suggestion this
this pick that's very interesting
that that I need to think about that
actually might work because that pck
solution is just like a mask a mask for
this Matrix like you
just put the
mask onto it and whatever shows is just
the numbers you
want so but I have to think about that
but right now I'm thinking of
um is there a pattern such that is it
possible to write a string expression
pattern such
that it gets a number only if the
number
has symbols adjacent to it so in order
to do this you need your expression you
need your text pattern to
be to be
[Music]
to you need your text pattern to embed
information
about the entire
line
Plus
so you know let's say let's take the
number 633 here so you want
so if that is the case then you need a
regular expression that covers this
range
okay so let's take the number
58 now a regular expression for this
case will
cover this range
okay what about
617 okay a regular expression cover in
this case
will uh will be in this range okay so
basically including including the
diagonal
okay so let's think about this
possibility you're going to generate a
ex regular
[Music]
expression such
that
such
uh why am I not using the glove at I
talked about in my last video okay you
guys should watch my video
because this this I got a light switch
for this one watch my video two three
episode ago okay you'll see uh I'm going
to use this for a while for for a few
months
so anyway
so
this so that anyway that's another
approach very interesting you use the
regular
expression instead of position checking
okay so that's a approach for us right
now now the traditional approach would
be now once you get the beginning and
end index you minus the number of
characters per line
so you
check if there is a symbol occurring in
that yeah so maybe this is actually
simpler so you all you have to do is you
check if there is
um so suppose our index
is let's
say
27 and uh 23 and
207 okay let's say that's our beginning
end so you just
check
is
22 is a
symbol something like that okay so
let's
suppose
begin is position 22 a
symbol then is position
28 a symbol
okay so that's checking the current line
uh and if you do this you also have to
make sure that you are not you know you
are not going to the previous line you
have to make sure you are your number is
not at the beginning of
line
okay that's that's uh God
then
then once you do that
then is position 22
minus line
chart
count something like that okay okay so M
so if 58 is a number
you okay M minus line line ch ch count
minus one
okay is position that okay
so
[Music]
plus plus one
okay let's replace so this is so we
write down what we are doing okay so why
okay make sure the number so now this
xus is
then
[Music]
then okay then is uh
um something like that
okay okay this is getting
tedious and and
also we need to make sure we need to
double check
if if our uh number occurs in in the
first line or the last line because
that
way uh
okay
okay we need to make sure we don't step
out of the index
boundary okay so that is the basic
algorithm if we take this
approach H
seems
problematic
um
so right now this
problem you know it's been working on
this for two hours
now uh so far the
code is not much code actually so so far
it's like this line this line you don't
need need variables you don't need
special you know you can combine them
they become very short single
line um and and right now we are
basically just having three lines of
code because this unique for example
unique symbol characters do we need it
no uh because Advent of a code they
don't care you can manually find out
what symbols you need so you can just
hard code into your program so you don't
need this
line uh CH line you know we found we can
find it out programmatic
programmatically that's what we did but
also we can just hard code it you know
for the real input the number of car
characters per line is more
than
uh is 140 C
right so they they are all 140
characters
each
so yeah so we don't need this character
per line neither so it's
140 and the total of number of
characters we don't need it neither so
we don't need that
line and this valid number function we
do need which we have not complete yet
okay then this number of
positions we do
need yeah number positions let's give
you all the beginning end positions of
occurrence of
numbers and
uh and uh we can can we shorten it yes
we
can we can shorten it by a lot
uh and symbol positions do we need
it it's nice to have because otherwise
you have
to yeah it's actually nice to have once
you have the symbol positions you don't
have
to compute each
time
but actually now you know thinking about
this
this uh who is this shiko shiko solution
about this pick now is looking very
attractive the
pick so let me think about this about
this
because if you do this you know you kind
of just mask out like a bit
mask on this
entire character
Matrix so
you so we have you know consider this
input as a character
Matrix so you can so let's see if the
pick how does it
work list selection
okay so list
selection yeah so you take this string
input
string you replace all numbers by
one right you replace all
digits by one so you got one one
here
and that's right then you just pick
okay then what you get is a
string that contains nothing but
numbers okay that then then what you get
is a like string like that but all
characters are removed except the
numbers
okay it's very
nice
then then you can do uh can you do that
actually so yeah so
the that's
right yes you can do
that okay but instead of a string the
input must be a list that's also easily
done you just
convert a string into a sequence of a
list of
characters okay
then so now we
get so so when you do the pick we get a
list of digits and
uh the N digigit we need to replace them
by they just become empty
least they just
become EMP empty Le oh God I need to
think about
this
okay uh my wife cut my hair two days
ago
so I want to finish this
problem I'm thinking of quit the live
stream
but
yeah so we can have a matrix fantastic
right we turn
this input string into a matrix of
characters so a 2d Matrix that will
remain the shape of the input string as
a
rectangle and each element in the Matrix
will be just a single
character okay then
we we generate the
mask
by it's fairly easy to do by one of
these
uh you know we just check if a character
is a digit or not you know we check each
and every element of the
Matrix if that character is a digit then
it remains if it's not a
digit
we replace it by zero or
something
uh we can do that without even without
this this pick
function okay so but once you do that
what do you get I mean what what is the
advantage what what what does it do for
you so we get so we work with a 2d
Matrix each element is a character we
are able
to filter out out any character that's
not a
digit okay so and retain retain this
Matrix shape and we are also able to
filter
out any character that's not
a
symbol but the question remains how do
you how do you know if a number is
adjacent to a
symbol okay and the basic solution is
like we went through here the basic
solution is to tediously check the
position you know blah blah blah but is
there some kind of
like like like from the top Bird's eyes
view some kind of mask or
net that simply lets you like a cookie
stamp
that easily tells you a number is
adjacent to a symbol so we are trying to
look at that look into that using this
pick
function uh and this pick function turns
a
string a rectangular string into a 2d
Matrix uh but is it necessary to turn it
into a 2d Matrix not even I don't you
know you can I think you can work with
strings
directly so what is the so the question
is what is the advantage
of working with Matrix there's probably
some Advantage because string is by
nature not a structured data structure
with Matrix you can easily pick out you
know the second
row or the third column things like
that so with Matrix is much easier to
work with with
string you can't you you know unless
every time you split the
lines you know yeah okay so Matrix great
Advantage now back to the problem what's
is is some kind of
way like a cookie stamp that just easily
tell you trivially tells you if a number
is adjacent to
a oh yes
yes I think so yes with a
matrix with a matrix given any element
in a 2d Matrix you can find all its
[Laughter]
neighbors this is the power of wam
language okay
so given a a 2d Matrix or even 3D Matrix
you know given a matrix given any
element position of a
matrix it is mathematically defined you
know usually in math you you need to do
that to find all the neighbors of that
element okay what you know to to get all
the values of adjacent
elements I believe sometimes you need to
do that for Matrix so this becomes a
traditional math
problem
right so now you know if I'm doing this
on my own I would be looking into all
the Matrix functions okay let's let's
look for a few select criteria okay now
let's see there is a
matrix working on Matrix
guide okay conditions numerical data
uh element elements of a list handling
arrays of
data I know where to look for but um
okay let's go
there so data analysis data manipulation
and Analysis array manipulation okay
maybe you it's
there and symbol there is
a you know there is a section that
directly addresses matrices
matrices linear
algebra okay but we can hire
mathematical computation polom algebra
linear algebra there let's go tensor
right exactly so right so now we
got close to the Matrix section okay so
right now we want a function that given
a index of a
matrix find all its
neighbors okay cross Nome total
normalize projection
orthogon uh table identity Matrix
diagonal
matrix close Okay parts of Matrix there
it
is diag position upper triangular okay
we are I think I'm
I'm fairly sure this is
the right way I mean this is kind of the
simple way for this
problem this would be a spectacular way
to solve this problem and this would be
unique well except other other uh
programming
languages that does mathematics that
that focus on linear
algebra but otherwise compared to you
know vast majority of programming
languages this would be unique okay so
part of matrixes how do you extract just
the I know I know I can you know I can I
can do it but it's just that is there a
specific function I know I can do it
even without
right all you have to do you know just
yeah I know I can do it but is there a
build
in diagonal get the list of elements on
the diagonal okay
so so that is the diagonal matrix give
uh give the list of elements on the
leading diagonals of Matrix okay that
means like that
so this this gives the K diagonal
okay so you can use this part of this
you see this here is a example you
can so that gets you the diagonal Okay
[Music]
so
band let's see what is band band
represents the sequence of
positions the sequence of positions on
the diagonal band that start with IJ in
a spar array
okay in a spar array
okay so create a band diagonal matri
okay
[Music]
so but we don't want the entire we just
want the neighbor is so normally in
mathematics that's
called that kind of neighborhood is
called van Numan neighborhood
okay
because when you have a grid you can
Define the neighbors by just D just just
vertical or horizontal neighbors or you
can count also include the diagonal
neighbors okay so van Numan neighborhood
is okay the vuma neighborhood of
four neighborhood cell is classically
defined on a two-dimensional Square
latus and is composed of a central cell
and it's for adjacent cells okay so the
one I'm looking for is more
neighborhood okay so now just search the
word more so more neighborhood includes
not just vertical and horizontal but
also diagonal neighbors okay now go back
to UAM language documentation let's just
search for more if it's got
anything sud sudo
inverse dring
inverse pair okay box Matrix
oh is that what we want box Matrix
Corner neighbors there is
promising let's look up let's
look up box Matrix and Corner neighbors
Corner
neighbors is an option for various array
and image processing functions that
specifies whether diagonally adjacent
corners should be considered neighbors
of particular element exactly you
see we getting close so Corner neighbors
is an option to some functions
okay so Corner neighbors if false that
means do not include
diagonal
right which is Van Newman neighborhood
now if Corner neighbors is is true that
means includes diagonal Neighbors which
is more neighborhood okay now we just
find out okay great now is there is a
matrix example so eight connected
components morphological
components
oh maybe morphological components is
what you need I don't know what is
that
oh God box Matrix there it is chest
board distance manhatton distance that's
like uh Capi driver manhatton distance
is a distance defined such that you can
only go from one point to another by
traveling vertically or horizontally so
normally if you have like two point of a
triangle you can just directly go there
but with manhon distance you have to go
like that that that that that always
like a square so anyway we I think we
are very close so what is the Box
Matrix box
Matrix now remember our goal is given a
matrix we want its neighbors okay uh uh
we are close Okay so we
have Diamond Matrix cross Matrix oh okay
getting close and disk Matrix what
you structure matrices and convolution
kernels that's related to machine
learning I think okay so diag Diamond
Matrix gives a matrix whose elements are
one in a diamond shaped region that
extends our index okay we we care about
um we care about extracting elements not
generating
matrices okay the answer is somewhere uh
is close Okay cross Matrix cross Matrix
gives a matrix whose elements are
in a centered cross shaped
region that extends our positions along
each index Direction and are zero
otherwise okay so basically across you
know yeah so but what we want is
actually we just want a function
that gives us the adjacent index
actually we don't even need a uh
building function
because yeah it's just you know to get
the adjacent index you just X - 1 + 1
and y - 1 + 1 but then you need to do
boundary boundary check that is the TDS
part you need to know if you at the
beginning of line or I mean beginning of
row or end of row or the you know first
row or last row so boundary check that's
the tedious part so that's that is why
we are trying to
find a function that does it already for
you okay disk Matrix uh okay this are
not
we could you know we could use some of
these so let's go back
to let's go back to
the so who which function uses Corner
neighbors let's
see so related guide mathematics
morphology what is
that combining methods from set theory
topology and discrete
mathematics mathematical morphology
provides a powerful approach to
processing images and other discrete
data
okay so it's primarily for processing
images I suppose let's see search
morphology morphology is linguistics so
why I don't understand why do you
have what is mathematical
morphology the wolam language includes
an extensive and efficient
implementation of mathematical
morphology I'm not sure I seen that
before fully integrated with the wam
languages general image and data
processing okay but it seems
mathematical morphology is basically
about image
[Music]
processing and data science maybe oh
this Wikipedia
okay mathematical morphology is a theory
and technique for the analysis and
processing of geometric
structures oh this is new to me based on
set theory lat Theory topology and
random
functions mathematical morphology is
most commonly applied to digital images
but it can be employed as well on graphs
surface measures solids and many other
spatial
structures
okay uh it's a theory and technique okay
for analysis and processing of
geometrical structures okay topological
and geometrical continuous space
Concepts such as size shape convexity
connectivity and geodesic distance were
introduced by mathematical morphology on
both continuous and discrete spaces okay
mathematical morphology is also the
foundation of
morphological image processing h
it's some deep topic which consists of a
set of operations that transform images
according to the above characterizations
okay now let's see what is this a shape
in blue and its morphological dilations
in
green okay uh and uh erosion in yellow
okay by a diamond shaped structural
element
it looks like it's two people
dancing so you know so mathematical
morphology analysis of an image
processing and
uh so I'm
supposing it's trying to find out what
this image is you know it's a seate of
two people dancing so one of the part of
the technique is kind of
just add the outline you know in this
fancy
words dilation morphological dilation
and erosion
okay so
history okay
[Music]
so basic
operations okay it it seems kind of
like
newish kind of thing from the past 20
years maybe kind of new
newish uh field used by mostly I I would
assume image
processing okay so but this is getting
away from
our from what are we doing what we are
doing okay so anyway this is
mathematical morphology a section of
wolam functions related to
that uh and uh does it have anything to
do with our
problem not
really well actually you know that's
what we are trying to do if we look at
our problem from a geome geometric point
of
view you know we consider this as a
geometric shape that's what we are
doing
then that's why we have these questions
about
neighboring elements and that is why
indeed it's some sort of mathematical
morphology issue
so okay I'm just random talking now you
know
to yeah the real I'm just talking so
there's some
video so actually to solve the problem
solve the problem is actually code just
start to code this tediousness I don't
want
to
uh
yeah so the no I'm pretty sure there is
a function okay we just need to find the
function that give
you that extract the neighboring
elements yeah I'm I'm pretty
sure I'm I'm pretty sure in wam language
there is a trivial way okay with a a
trivial
way to such that given a matrix 2D
Matrix and given a index two numbers for
item in the
Matrix so given this you can easily have
it return all the neighboring values of
that entry okay I'm 99% sure that there
is either a buildin function
or it's so trivial to write it yourself
without having to check you know this
boundary conditions like you know
whether you are going beyond the current
row or
whatnot uh which is not actually
difficult to write neither because so
you have to do is just you know but it's
tedious like you have to make four four
checks you have to check if your line is
the beginning I mean the first row of
the Matrix or the last row of The Matrix
matx and you have to check if your
element is the first element in a row or
the last element in a
row neighborhood Matrix thank you so is
that the actual function
name no I don't think uh wait is
that neighborhood okay there's quite a
few
neighborhood
thing neighborhood contraction okay
let's just search for let's get
neighborhood interpreter type natural
language name of a neighborhood
no I think it's just one of those uh
Matrix functions okay I
just it's just here you know I
[Music]
can you know uh uh if I'm not doing this
video I can probably already found it by
now
but you know it's in one of these uh
Matrix constructing
matrices table array Coe coefficient
array construct construct a matrix from
a system of equations okay Spar array
construct a SP Matrix from position and
values that uh no okay noal convert The
Spar Matrix to ordinary form band give
values on any collection of bands or Tri
diagonal matrices okay this is
actually Center array there it is Center
array create a list of length n with the
element create a list of length n with
the elements of a at the center and zero
elsewhere
okay somewhere okay somewhere somewhere
here very uh you know it's one of these
it'll tell you exactly how to do it I'm
pretty sure I'm like 90 90 99 uh% okay
or something trivial like two functions
combined band so what what is band I
haven't okay band
ji represents the sequence of positions
on the diagonal
band that start with IJ in a spar array
okay it basically represent the diagonal
line
so so here okay maybe here so bend I
mean J mean IMAX J
Max right so you
can
okay uh maybe band okay
so spend diagonal okay so there's also
minus maybe extract [ __ ] there it is
extract maybe probably let's look at
extract and let's look at minus
okay uh let's
see extract extract the part of
expression at position specified by
position
okay uh okay so is there a neighborhood
option okay I think I'm going to quit
I'm just
like I'm just going to quit minus gives
a minus of a matrix okay
so minus of a 3X3
Matrix what is it do oh it's it's like
doing this
computation app
so is
it Matrix operations okay that's what I
was looking for Matrix
operations pseudo inverse R reduce new
space Matrix rank no transpose no
conjugate transpose no lower triangular
eyes no upper triangular no symmetric
tries
no diagonal get the list of elements on
the
diagonal we can use that you know once
you get a you know we
can use that
um the thing I'm looking for is to avoid
boundary check myself you
see so diagonal can do that it
automatically avoids bound re
check because it's going to give you the
diagonal elements then you just take you
know one of each side then you get your
diagonal I'm pretty sure there's a
option to give you the other diagonal
right yeah but it's still tedious I I
want like one single function away to
just get all the neighbors okay
so determin nor Fugate minus permanent
quanica product no Matrix power and I
I'm I'm kind of like just wasting time
here
because what
really I need to do is actually actually
just
code uh and it's not that much code
anyway yeah and because I want to
go
adjacency okay let's see there's
adjacency dis
Matrix let's just try adjacent first
adjacency graph adjacency Leist
adjacency tensor adjacency
Matrix ad Jony hypergraph
have delete adjacent duplicate you know
amazing 7,000 functions spill in
adjacency list gives a list of vertices
adjacent to a
Vertex now this is like this is graph
Theory yeah okay
so so this is talking about graph Theory
uh
at least the vertic is adjacent to the
vertex one so yeah that's
uh there it is table highlight graph
okay so maybe this can be applied
to this could I mean that's but that's
something so there is adjacency Matrix
adjacency Matrix gives a Vertex vertex
adjacent y Matrix of a
graph okay it's related to graph
Theory so if you want to if we want to
apply this to our
uh problem we have to do
something so but it's not what we want
for
sure adjacency tensor compu the
adjacency tensor of an arbitrary
hypergraph
okay they are talking about graph Theory
and this is someone wrote this is
a library of a function you know you can
just call and wam language will
dynamically fetch this function in real
time when it's
executed
so this ajason C tensor now who wrote
this who wrote this
Jonathan jard this this is one of the
greatest young physicist Jonathan
gorad you know he's doing the wolfan
physics um research
anyway uh adjacency yeah so but this
adjacency Matrix is doing something
about graph related
so I don't think I so it's you know then
we have to read it uh I think it's
related to what we want to do but it's
not exactly in order to use this you
have to do something you
know uh
so graphs and matrices okay adjacency
tens okay that's it thank you guys for
watching
I'm going I'm going to go offline and by
tomorrow you'll see the shortest
Solution on
Earth
classic
HRI Henrik
says why YouTube doesn't tell me when
you are streaming I check the Bell icon
it simply doesn't tell me when you are
start streaming yeah Google Google is
heavy censorship all kind of nasty dark
things going on so that's why I
recommend Twitter okay bye guys for
today thank you guys for watching uh
meanwhile also I Rec recommend uh
Twitter and I recommend you pay Elam
musk like $8 a month to get a blue check
okay I highly recommend because
Twitter is right now Elam musk is saving
America so America is collapsing kind of
going down a drain uh and there's a good
chance that Elam musk is Reviving you
know it's making America great again
okay thank you guys for watching you
know two hours three close to 3
hours uh it's kind of disappointing I
didn't do it you know I hate to you know
b um yeah but that's how usually I do
things okay bye
guys