Morning, good evening guys. Welcome to
another episode of sound talk show. We
are going to code wam language. Today we
uh this is a coding session. So it's
just going to be me coding technical
stuff. Wam language. Okay. So because uh
you know code you need to code and then
stop coding. Wait, what what's going on
with my Emacs Windows?
Wait, there is something.
Oh yeah. So part of the window is not
showing Emacs. That's what Okay. Coding
session today. Emac bisp. Okay. So not
to do uh let's go to talk show. Today's
talk show. Open it. So uh wuam language
coding session. Uh we're going to write
a custom function to export SVG
graphics. Now we did several talk show
before uh a week or two ago. So the last
one is episode 697.
Uh we explored how to do this and we
abort it because it seems too difficult.
But I decided we're going to persist.
Okay. So we're going to persist to write
this function. Um
this is for exporting graphics. uh
exporting two-dimensional graphics to
SVG.
Now, now if you watch my previous video
uh episode 697 and then another one
episode 687 in July
uh that one is very technical that
discussed why we need to do it and so
on. So um so we uh talked about SVG you
know the technology of X SVG which is uh
XML file and uh lots of issues but
anyway so we're going to just code okay
so if you don't know Wuang language I
have many videos uh so you can download
it here search for Kasali wufam language
tutorial for programmers on kasali.info
info, okay? And you can find the
download link. It's free for personal
use. Uh and uh wam language for
programmers, a comprehensive tutorial
for programmers. If you already know a
programming language and lots of my uh
wraim language packages, I've been
coding wam language for like 30 years.
Hello, I discovered that both of my
physics uh let's see uh let me magnify
the font control plus okay
let's see
so this is boring for you guys for most
of you guys vast maj majority this is
just me coding wuan language um because
you know this is lots of technical
details uh I won't be able to explain
each one of them in detail. So it's just
watching me code wam language. Okay, I
I'll explain something along the way. Um
so if you already know Wuam language,
you started to learn, you know, maybe
for my tutorial, then you know, maybe
you coded wam language for half a year,
then you'll get you'll know what I'm
talking about. But for most of you, it's
probably boring. And if you are watching
this offline, best to play at 1.5 speed,
okay? minimum uh hacksaw discovered that
both of my physics teacher love wam
language. Oh okay. Yeah, physics you
know uh for physist uh basically wam
language is the only choice among a few
handful uh because for physics
you know physics mostly involve ma you
know like the the the heart of physics
is mathematics okay mathematical physics
so it's lots of and mostly they have to
do with the analysis branch or also
known as calculus so calculus
differential equations like turn you
know that that's a majority like uh
theory of relativity and differential
equations the model of the universe and
so on
GPS okay so I'm going to code okay so so
uh again this is going to be boring okay
but I'm just going to uh code it okay so
let's see I need to grab some uh
previous we started pre in previous live
stream we started um
we started to code it okay so there's a
uh AI video summary so let's see what I
want to grab we want to grab the code
okay here
so we're going to we're going to code it
for one hour and uh I will probably not
finish it but I will try to make it a Um
uh wait not eag this so wam language
paste the code and pop it out. So I'll
try to make it like uh at least part of
it is done so it can run so you you know
but on the whole it's not finished. So
let's start to write it. Okay. If you
have questions feel free to ask me. I'm
going to code and talk. Okay. Write a
command to export 2D graphics to SVG. We
want to do this because building export
function creates huge file size.
Uh
that is almost
almost 10 times larger
than
than necessary. Okay, that's a problem
with SVG because you have so many ways
to code the same thing. So it's it's
like HTML. when you use a program like
Adobe or whatever or Microsoft Word to
generate HTML
the result is tends to be like bloated
like 10 times as large
that's a situation typically when you
export from one format to another format
in an automatic way but if you manually
you know convert then it's like 10 times
smaller so I want to do this because I
have like hundreds hundreds of uh
hundreds um of uh graphics uh involving
two-dimensional graphics visualization
of mathematics um that uh let me show it
again. Okay, so
info my website and go down go down go
down below it's mathematics. So you go
to visual dictionary of uh spatial plane
curves for example parabola. Uh so there
are tons of animations and illustrations
about um um mathematics two dimensional.
So all these two-dimensional graphics
they are very suitable for SVG um you
don't want PNG because because they are
not scalable you know anyway so you know
watch my previous video you'll see so
anyway so let's start to write it okay
uh so uh so we going to do uh so for
example this is a primitive graphics so
that's a woofam this is how you do woo
frame um so we don't want axis okay so
let's Tory. So copy. Let's start wam
language.
Okay. New buffer. Paste and uh paste and
shift enter to run it.
And move this here.
And why why is it taking so long? So
let's make it 150. So that's a that's a
the circle is a graphic primitives that
means basic shape. So circle centered at
0 0 with radius one and then then you
wrap graphics around it. Then that
become that that will show us a graphics
and you add a axis true. Okay. So axis
gives you a sense of like what's the
scale of this uh thing.
So by default you can export to SVG like
we showed this before but um so let's
remove the uh axis. Okay. So wait. So
yeah so graphics trim. Yeah. So for
example let let me show this again.
Okay. So do that. Okay. Now it's now
it's saved in documents directory. Go
there and search for circle. Uh wait
what did we save as xx circle? So xx
circle. So you open that. That's a
circle. Then uh show it in HTML mode. So
you can actually see the code. SVG is
actually a uh XML file. So it's all
text. So now you make it to um you make
it to be multiple lines. Uh replace
semicolon by semicolons uh new line. So
So here's the file. Okay. So let's let's
also make this you know. So here is the
entire file. So
now you notice you know it's using the
path uh uh thing. So and uh and uh so
the file size wait
869.
The file size is 869
bytes. But actually the whole thing
should be just one circle. Uh actually
I'm repeating lots of things I talked
about before but let me just do it.
Okay. So if you don't know anything
about SVG you can search for practical
SVG tutorial by by me on si.info. Okay.
So so for a circle you go to you go to
basic shapes for a circle u primitive it
should be a single line. So like that.
Okay. So this is you know that's a
circle. So it should be just like you
know 50 megabytes you know 50 bytes. So
let me close that. So the whole file
should be just like that like that.
Okay. But but instead it creates this
it's using a path it's using a basio
curve. So it's appro it's trying to
approximate
approximate a circle. uh so it's very
inefficient you know so when you have
hundreds of c hundreds of circles like I
have um example like like
when you have hundreds of uh circles
then the file size is like blowing up
100 times so that's that's not that's
not what we want so that's why I'm
trying to write a export to SVG function
custom function by myself that will
convert a circle primitive like that to
just to just this, you know, instead
instead of uh instead of this this this.
Okay, that's what we going to do. So,
let's um
let's cut cut that. Okay, close that.
Don't say uh close that, right? Close uh
kill anyway. Yes. Okay. So, let's go
back. So, let let me post some link
here.
Uh let's that's a circle. Okay.
Actually, let's not do that. Okay. So,
hold on a second.
So, this uh let me
uh Okay. So, go back here. SVG. So let's
copy the link there.
That's plain curves and the SVG shapes
SVG tutorial practical SVG. So paste
that uh actually here.
Okay. Today's talk show. Okay. Special
plane curves and practical SVG tutorial.
So now we uh yeah let's go back to the
code. So let's start to code it. Okay.
So uh so we are writing graphics to
string that turns a graphics like
anything like that to a string to the
SVG string and here is the SVG string.
Okay. So we last time we discovered
there's lots of issues about about
scaling and and about uh scaling the
coordinate because you have to map the
the boundary of the graphics coordinate.
You want to find the maximum and minimum
x coordinate and maximum and minimum of
ycoordinate. Then you want to scale it
to the pixels because the pixel the
width and height will be you know fixed
like 1,00
by 1,000
but this image is you know negative one
to one. So it's just two. So you need to
like scale it. That's why um you need to
use this view box this view box SVG
viewbox to um to scale. So you need to
find the scale factor and the trans and
trans vector you need to also flip the
y-axis because in SVG the yaxis
goes from top to bottom you know the the
higher is negative so lower is positive
so the origin in SVG is the 0 coordinate
is on the upper left corner but in
mathematics the origin is the center you
know So, so you need to flip the y-axis.
So, that's why you need to um do this.
So, if you don't know, you know, you go
to my SVG tutorial.
So, there's a section uh on uh SVG
circle specifying style, shape style,
view port, and viewbox. So, view port
specifies how many pixels, width, and
height. Okay. And the viewbox specifies
a user coordinate
you know
because the actual graph may be one you
know 10 billion uh
um you know the the the coordinate
coordinate value may be a huge number
but you don't have enough pixel so you
need to like rescale it. So anyway, but
that's so so first thing actually the so
the first thing when you ex you know
when to do this you need to find the
maximum and minimum of the um
of the coordinate or Jesus that's
another issue that's another problem
because
God every time you try to do this you
run into another non-trivial problem why
because in this example we are exploding
a circle right so to find the maximum
the max x xcoordinate. One way you can
do is you get the order coordinate and
just find the maximum one you know the
the x you know but in this case we got a
problem because the circle you only
specify the center and radius. So you
you don't actually have a coordinate for
the um
one one and zero you know. So what if
your circle has a radius of 1,00
you know one one,000 or a billion
but you won't find uh so that's another
problem uh god
so every time we do this we um got you
you know we run into lots of issues so
but let's clarify this first okay so so
that is kind of so so now this function
return a string And uh here is like a
sample graphics. Let's remove it.
Okay. And uh and what is this? Um so
first job let's just write it down.
First job uh job is to find the max and
min of
uh x
coord
and and y
coordinate. Okay, that's uh in the
graphics
in the graphics. Okay, that's the first
thing we need to do. Let's do that. So
what is this? Uh so that's a example uh
of a circle. Uh
delete that. Okay. So this is like this
is explorics inline documentation. Let's
forget that for now.
Okay. So yeah, forget that. So right now
we are writing this function. So um so
this is a
sample simple
2D graphics of just a circle. Okay.
Uh
this is
this is built in export to SVG. Okay.
So now we are writing the function. So
graphics to string return a uh string
that is SVG format uh representing
graphics object G. Okay, fantastic.
That's a usage. Now um so right now it
just return this uh template string. So
we need to so first job to find the max
and min of coordinate. So how do you do
that? I you know I don't know. So let's
see.
Let's search for boundary. Okay,
something
let's see if we can find a I think
there's a building function boundary
discrete graphics. Okay. So,
uh
bounding region. Okay. So,
there's a lot. So, bounding region we
can check
uh
so if not we might turn it to a mesh
first. Okay. So, this you know or or dis
discretetized graphics. So, what does
discretetize graphics mean? So for
example when you have a circle this
circle
it you know it just represented by a
circle a center and radius
but let's say you want to distort the
circle you want to apply a function to
all the points on the circle. So for
every point you want to see what you
know what what is the um orientation.
So then then
um
they magnify the circle by the
orientation. So essentially you you you
become it became a spiral. So you see
the the more rotated the point is you
want to multiply that point uh by a
larger value. So basically expand it. So
the more rotated it become more
expanded. So it becomes a spiral.
Suppose you want to apply a function to
a to every point of the circle. Okay.
But you cannot do that to this circle
because this circle you know it's
represented by just one point you know
the origin. So that's when you want to
use discretetized graphics that will
break this circle primitive into many uh
line segments. Okay. So this is part of
computer graphics. Okay. Anyway, I'm I'm
trying to explain then uh I never start
to code. So, you know, I keep explain
explaining I'll never start to code. Uh
so, let me see uh how do you find the
boundary? Okay, so that's the first job.
Boundary uh let's see uh bounding
region. Can we bound region uh points
give the minimal axis align bounding of
box points. Okay, that cannot do because
it takes the uh points.
Okay. So, you know find the max and
minimum of the boundary is actually
necessary. So, we have to do this. We
have to do this. So, so we just have to
first um
do this. Oh god.
Boundary mesh boundary mesh region. Um
okay. So you know
boundary discretetize graphics
discretetize a 2D or 3D graphics G into
a boundary mesh region.
uh you know so
yeah so this this um
this will turn
so given a complicated 2D graphics we it
will turn the boundary
into a discrete graphics. Okay. But um
okay. So
boundary discretetize region.
What is this boundary discretetize
graphics?
Okay. Uh,
okay. So, again,
this is probably boring, so let me just
code it on my own. Okay.
So, so we want to find the minimum and
maximum of the x-axis and the y- axis.
So in wufam language that's called
basically some kind of boundary get the
region boundary. Okay. Uh and uh so you
want to find a command a function that
returns the min and max of the x and y
of a 2D graphics. Okay that's what we
want to do. So right now we are finding
listing all functions that contains the
word bound. Okay. So that should cover
all the possibilities we are we are
looking for I think. So there might be
also max and mean we need to find. Okay.
So let's look at the bounds. Okay. So
there are you know several uh things of
interest. Boundary discretetize
graphics. Boundary discretetize region.
So in wam language graphics means this
you know graphics primitives.
You have 2D version and 3D version. 2D
version is just called graphics. So you
got graphics. Okay. So this boundary
discretetized graphics applies to
graphics.
Now there's another concept in wool
frame language which is region. Uh
region region is not necessarily
graphics but they are like related. A
graphics can have a region. Uh but so
it's kind of it's related. So region is
more like more like a mathematical
concept. So boundary discretetize region
discretetizes the region
into a boundary mesh region. Okay. So
okay so you got that uh we we might look
into so you know so you need to look
into the definition of region I I don't
remember. Okay then another concept is
the mesh. Okay so this is quite
complicated. So mesh is another mesh is
basically a
uh mesh is just like what it sounds you
know like bunch of triangles but it also
include single lines it's like a
generalized mesh.
So for example you can look at the you
know if you look at the
uh
images it becomes somewhat clear. So you
see it's very generalized. So you can
have a mesh. This is not like typically
when we think of a mesh we think of a um
a surface a patch made of made out of
triangles right but in UA language they
you know that's a mesh but you could
also have mesh region and mesh region
can also contain holes and it's not just
for a planer mesh but you you can also
have one-dimensional mesh or
three-dimensional mesh. So a
three-dimensional mesh region is kind of
like a box but might have a holes in it.
So you know so it's like
fairly involved. So right now so there
are several concept that's interesting
to me. So there's uh about boundary
graphics and boundary
you know so several several um
uh concepts. One is discretetized
graphics. Uh the other one is mesh. You
can turn a graphics into a mesh. The
other one is discretetized graphics.
Okay. Then the other concept is region.
Region is like the boundary of a
graphics or or a mesh. Okay.
Then okay. So then um
Okay. So primarily this top few is what
I'm interested I think. Okay. So let's
see what does bounce return bounce
system bounce.
Okay, that's that's
system bounce. Why does it um what does
it do exactly?
There's no documentation for for um
interesting documentation web attribute
protected system bounds. So why is that?
So that's interesting. So you got this
bounce symbol
and that's not documented. Okay, that's
is it because we used it? No, that's
interesting finding. Okay, so then you
got cell bounding box. We don't care.
That's kind of you know uh coordinate
bounds. Okay, so that's that may what we
want. That may be what we want.
Coordinate bounds gives a list min max
of the bounds in each dimension of the
region defined by coordinates. Okay, I
don't know if that will work.
So you know the way to code is we can
start to try out an arrow. You know just
try a coordinate bounce and give a
graphics but that's not going to go well
because you you you're just going to
waste a lot of time. So the the better
approach is actually to um carefully
read each of the documentation. So
coordinate bounds it takes a bunch of
coordinate not graphics. Okay. So that's
not good. That's not what we want. So um
you see it just take a bunch of
coordinates. So coordinate bounding box
mean max region bounds. So let's look at
region bounds.
So region bounds uh region gives a
bounds for the region. Okay. So but how
do you turn a graphics to a region?
Region bounds is also known as bounding
box in bounding volume. Okay. Depending
on 2D or 3D region bounds. So region
bounds returns what kind of thing it
returns? So it returns like uh two um
depending on dimension for one dimension
for one dimension it returns two points
for two dimension two two dimension it
returns um I think four points Right.
So for three dimension it returns six
points I think. So
uh but uh
wait what but why is it uh
gives the bounds for the region. Okay so
you have to think about one region. So
one dimension the bounds is just two
numbers min and max. For two dimension
the bounds is four numbers right? X mean
X max Y mean Y max.
Is that correct though? Uh so let's see
examples. Find the bounds for region.
Let's magnify this. Uh
yeah. So
okay. So let's um
so so let's check find bounds for a
region in R2. Okay. So you are given a
triangle
then bounce and call the function region
bounce and it returns just two numbers y
for a plane two dimensional region it
should return
x mean x max y mean y max right
oh yeah so four numbers that's right
that's right okay so that's Right.
So this is for a plane uh four numbers.
That's right. And visualize. Okay.
That's correct. So it returns uh Oh, so
we can actually use this.
Can can we
So it takes a region, but a graphics is
not necessarily a region. Okay. So we we
need to try this. So region bounds
uh
region bounds. Okay. Is it is this
boring for you guys?
So region bounds then let's just uh try
the graphics. Okay. So the graphics
let's let's put it the graphics like
that. So we even remove the primitive.
Okay.
Okay. So, so you got a graphics. Let's
remove the axis. Okay. So, so that's
your graphics. Now, go back here.
So, we can actually run this. See what
see what it returns.
uh region bounds graphics is not a
correctly specified region. Okay, so
it's telling you a region is a graphics
is not a region. Okay, so that clarifies
that
uh but you so so there's a function that
turns a graphics into a region though.
Okay. So
let's look at bounding region. Okay. So
so now remember region bounds return the
boundary of a region. Now in three
dimension it returns six numbers. That's
correct. Three pairs total of six
numbers.
X mean Xmaxx, Y min YAX and Z mean Zmax.
Okay. Now, now remember this function
region bounds. It returns the boundary
of a region. Okay. Now let's see what
does this function do? Bounding region.
Now bounding region gives a minimal axis
align bounding box.
Uh okay. So bounding region is basically
the same as region bounds except that it
returns the coordinate in a different
order I think. Oh god.
Uh okay. So bound. Okay. So I now I got
it. Okay. So this
this takes a bunch of points and returns
a region. Okay. So
let's go back. Region bounds, right?
Okay. So before we were looking at
region bounds. It takes a region as
input. Now this bounding region takes a
list of points as input and returns a
region.
That's right. So
so if we begin with a list point we can
use this to get a region then feed it to
region bounds to get the max and min.
Okay. So this is bounding region. So
think so remember this is bounding
region takes a list of points. Okay. But
that's not what we want. We want you
know our input is a is a graphics
uh bounding region is not also known as
a an enclosing region or circumscribed
region. Okay. So a bounding region R for
a set of points uh I is a region is such
that
um
so what kind of region? So you have
one-dimensional case, two-dimensional
case,
uh threedimensional case.
So does it always return some kind of
rectangular shape?
bounding box. Yes. So it always return
some kind of rectangular shape never a
triangle for example like that. It
always returns some kind of rectangle.
Okay. Uh and it may be oriented not just
orthogonal to the axis. Okay. So so this
is about bounding region.
Okay. And okay, so you can specify
what kind of return shape it would be.
Okay. So you got minimal disk, minimal
elisp,
minimal convex polygon. Okay. So it's
not just rectangle. You can kind of
specify
uh what kind of region it returns. Okay.
So but but again this thing takes a list
of points which is not what we want or
we must be we should we want to be able
to turn the graphics into a list of
points that that I can do but uh but
that's not optimal.
So okay so let's do
so let so we have to think uh region
within region measure region bounds.
Okay, so you need to turn a graphics
into a region first.
So find a function that turns a graphics
into a region. Then you can just use
region bounds region or region uh you
know region bounds to get the mean and
max. Okay. So find a function that turn
graphics into a region or
find a function that that turn graphics
into all explicit coordinate. For
example, turn this circle into a
discrete you know points on the on the
ring. Okay. So so that's one thing but
the uh but there must I think they are a
direct function that just return the
boundary of a graphics. Okay. I'm pretty
sure.
So we want a function that directly uh
turn you know give the boundary of a uh
either a region of the graphics.
Okay. So let's check again. Okay.
Boundary discrete graphics.
Okay. Let's try that. That's that maybe
that's close. Boundary discretetize
graphics. Okay.
Discretetize a 2D or 3D graphics G into
a boundary mesh region. Fantastic. Okay.
So, what this do is, you know, it takes
any uh graphics like this circle. It
will discretize the graphics so that you
you'll get a graphics that's got lots of
points on a circle. Okay. Then it turns
in into a boundary mesh region. So, it
basically
takes a graphics
make it into a mesh not just the mesh
but the region of the mesh. I mean I
mean the yeah the a mesh of the region.
Okay. So effective effectively
a region then you can use boundary um
you know bounds of region to find the
maxing mean. So that's what we want.
Okay. I I know for I know I know for
sure. Okay. So let's just try it.
So So that's not right. So but that is
what we want. Okay, discretetize
graphics. Okay, so and uh then what is
the graphics? We can just uh paste that
there. So the graphics is that
um you know so let's run it. Okay, let's
see what it returns.
Okay, that's what we want. Fantastic. So
a circle a simple circle becomes this
bunch of points. Okay. Then you see then
this object is a boundary mesh region.
So that means we can now we can use this
uh region bounds to get it. Okay. So let
let's do um
let's let's um
uh let me let me just make it clear.
Okay. So let me code this so that it's
clear.
Um,
okay. That's graphics primitives. Let's
spell it out.
Uh, not it's not okay. So now
region bounds that won't won't work. So
but uh so hold on a second. So let let
me do that. Okay.
Graphics primitives. Let's make it a
list. Okay. you typically it's a list of
circles, lines and lots of other things.
Okay, then you turn that into graphics.
Okay, X graphics
equals to
uh let's name this primitives. Okay, X
primitives. Okay, so now X graphics
equals to X prims. Okay, the result is a
graphics object. Then then what you want
to do is you want uh you uh turn that
into Wait, what's going on? You turn
this into um
boundary. Okay,
boundary equals through that x graphics.
Fantastic. Then you
then you region bounce. Okay,
region bounce into uh equals through x
boundary.
Okay, that is a result. So let's try
that. Okay, so um
Okay, so let's can we run the whole
thing? Um
um
okay let's let's run this in in in wra
language
okay so let's paste that
let's just run it okay we got arrow so
first of all is a circle a list of graph
prim then we got arrow uh okay so what
is the arrow uh x x graphics equals to x
prims
why is that an arrow
graphics box is not a graphics primitive
or directive. Okay, why is that?
Oh, we you know that's that you know you
shouldn't have that graphics there. So
let's fix it. Um
yeah, so let's fix that. Copy that
back to Wam language. Select that. Paste
it. Run it. Okay. Circle. Correct.
That's a graph. That's graphics
primitive.
Then this is a graphics object. Wait,
wait, wait a minute.
Circle. That's a graphics primitive.
Let's output that. Then this circle is a
graphics object. That's that. Okay. Then
the this this
blue kind of thing that's the
discretetized graphics that's a b that's
a region
made out of the boundary of the circle
and discretetized it. So you can see
kind of you know lots of points on the
rim of the circle. Okay. Then finally
you find the boundary. So that is the
boundary. Fantastic.
So that's how you get the minimum and
maximum of the
um
of the graphics. For example, we can now
we now we get it now it works. So we can
kind of try a a lot of other circles.
For example, let's say um
you know another circle big number uh
let's say random coordinate center then
uh uh big big radius you know now we got
two circles one is very big radius so
let's try it
okay two circles then uh you see one
huge circle another circle is very tiny
you can see a little dot over there.
Wait, did I lose my color for for uh for
my uh you know, so you can see a little
dot over there
then.
Okay, so this got this got This
part
boundary discretetized graphics
is not a correctly specified region.
What?
Why is that?
Did I spell it wrong? No. Boundary
discretetize graphics. So that is a
graphics. So why is it not um
region bounds? Oh okay. Region bounds is
incorrect.
Wait. So boundary discretetize graphics.
So that didn't work.
So the problem because it returning
it unevaluated.
So boundary discretetize graphics is not
working. Any comments who who's watching
those who watches here say hi. Okay. So
boundary discretetize graphics is not
working. So let's double check. You got
list of graphics primitives two circles
that's valid. You got
graphics
that should that is valid but xboundary
is incorrect. Let's see xboundary what
is the value?
You see that is incorrect. That didn't
do anything.
So why is it not doing anything? Is it
because spelling error? No.
Let's look at documentation. Boundary
discretetize graphics choice
a 2D or 3D graphics into a boundary v.
Okay. So yeah, that's a graphics.
So
Oh, so it didn't even needs to be a
graphics primitive.
I mean the the argument to this boundary
discretetized graphics needs not to be a
graphics. It can be just
a list of graphics primitives. So
so let's try this. Okay.
So if you um Oh god. So let's copy that.
Do it fresh. So if you just say extremes
not graphics. Okay. So we just do prims
with that.
No.
Okay. Still you see this line is not
doing anything.
So why is that?
So now it becomes a question. So if we
just um
the thing we are interested is just um
does that work?
Yes, that works. So given a single
circle. Now if you um
if you give a uh so so that so that
works. What if you give a uh list of
circles? Does that still work?
Doesn't it?
No. A list of circles fails.
What the
Um,
fail. Okay,
works. Okay, wait. Uh, what
works? So, let's try this again.
Okay, so this is fail. Okay. Yeah. So,
yeah.
Okay. So this works. Now what about
what about if if you say
graphics? Okay.
So now that's a graphics object.
Okay. Run it.
That works.
So when you have a graphics object,
it works. It returns the result. Okay.
So that's good. Um
so let's move that you know. So the
input can be a uh graphics primitive or
it can be a graphics object
but it cannot be a list.
Okay. So, so then why is our original
fails? So, you got the graphics
primitives.
Okay. Then you got the graphics object
spelled out correctly. Yes. Then you try
to discretise
it.
X graphics spelled correctly. Yes. So
why this fail? I don't understand. So
let's go back here. Uh,
it failed because it didn't do anything.
What
graphics
is this graphics and this graphics is
this prim. So,
so it fails if you have two circles in
it. Is that is that right? It fails if
you got two circles in it. Let's try
this again. Okay, let's put another
circle. So,
run it
there. It didn't work.
Oh Jesus.
So this is not um Hello KPTXXZ.
What are you planning on export to XVG?
What are you planning on exporting to
SVG? Well, I talked about it that in my
beginning of the video and two videos
before. So I talked about like one hour
about it. uh basically this okay so
there are like thousands of
illustrations about plane curves that's
I want to export so today's talk show
let me remind you guys um today's talk
show showing browser
uh today's talk show
we have two episode prior each one is
one hour we talked about exporting to SV
SVG why you need to do it what's SVG uh
and so on you know fairly complicated
technical okay so that's why we are
writing a custom function you know we
are not writing you know this here is
the default I mean building function you
can do it but it creates large size
um anyway so now back to
back to this part I don't really
understand okay So, did we talk? How
long have we been talking?
55 minutes already. Okay, maybe uh we
should stop now. Okay, so we we we kind
of made uh some progress, you know, it's
kind of very tiny progress, but it's
solid progress because we we dis we, you
know, now we have a better understanding
of about the different issues. graphics,
discretetized graphics. What is a mesh?
What is a region? And what is a bounding
region? And what's the bounds of a
region?
Okay,
you know, it's a bit complex. So, let me
kind of summarize. Graphics is woof
2D graph graphics or 3D graphics. You
know they they you put the graphics into
it wrap it shows you know graphics all
the graphics you see in Wufam language
uh basically all these are generated in
wam language you know those are you know
all graphics so graphics is made out of
graphics primitives
basically means simple shapes like line
circle uh line circle rectangle and so
on.
So you you got graphics primitives then
you wrap graphics to create a graphics
object. Okay, that's graphics or
graphics 3D for 3D graphics.
Um okay let me let me let me let me talk
about let me go to my tutorial. Let me
show you. Okay so Wuam language not
math. Uh so you go to wam language todo.
No not to do go to tutorial.
Um
so language for programmers
comprehensive tutorial for programmers
from the ground up. You go to string uh
advanced symbol data structure
association pattern matching basics
string comment and print string number
boolean list uh plot and visualization.
So there graphics uh plot and
visualization. So you can see you know
100 plotting functions for services, for
pie chart, for statistics or you know
100 of them. Then you got plotting
options. This is just showing you how to
use Wuam language to create graphics. So
these are 2D and the pie chart is 3D
graphics. The surface is also 3D. So
then you got options such as showing
axis and so on. Okay. So then you got uh
plot 3D options
uh like like uh color lighting very
complex gets it it can get extremely
complex. Then you got kind of the um
glow lighting or ambient lighting or
spectacular specularity lighting
specification and you got also tune
shading. So 3D
coloring of the surface then you got you
know also um
color on the surface you know
interaction with lighting also you got
transparency so very complex okay so
that's about lighting then you you can
have um mesh data type that represent
graphics okay 3D graphics and 2D so
anyway so so so anyway these are about
plotting
how to use the building function to plot
and how do you specify opacity you know
uh transparency of a graphics. So that's
how how to use them. Okay, that's not
about programming. Okay, so so once you
get you know you you know how to use
some of these plotting functions you
start to do uh programming graphics.
Okay, graphics programming that's what
that's that's kind of what we are doing.
So programming graphics you first of all
you need to understand about graphics
primitives. So you got point line
polygon text disk circle rectangle
that's that are basic primitives to
build 2D graphics. Then you got 3D ones
such as also point line polygon sphere
cuboid cube and lots of more. Okay so
graphics primitives you have 2D
primitives and 3D primitives. Okay,
these are called graphics primitives.
Okay, then then you create a graphics
object by wrapping this graphics
function or the graphics 3D function
wrap them around the list of primitives.
So then you get a graphics object. Okay.
Uh so there so so when when you when you
when the out the output of any graphics
object shows up as a graphics like that
like that this is a 3D graphics 3D
graphics 3D okay that's a graphics
object so again primitives then you got
graphics object
uh graphics directive is like specifying
color and like color you know thickness
things like that okay then you got okay
geometric transformation that's that's
like advanced. Okay. Then you got
graphics complex that's also advanced.
Okay. Um then you got um then you got
mesh region. Okay. Mesh region is a
representation of graphics by breaking
the graphics primitive into actually
points. Okay. So that's kind of another
representation of graphics called mesh
mesh region. you know uh it's actually
quite generalized because this woofer
language mesh can be onedimensional or
zero zero dimensional like at least a
points that's also considered a mesh so
it's like very generalized so you got
one-dimensional mesh like just a bunch
of segments on a line then or you got
two dimensional mesh mesh which is what
you think of a mesh like bunch of
triangles making part of a surface or
several of them patch of them not
necessarily connected. Then you got 3D
mesh which is very complex which which
is like um
you know each each mesh element is like
a kind of enclosed volume. Okay. Um
anyway you know so mesh is like another
complex thing. So then you got mesh
region. Okay. Um which represent a
enclosed region. Okay. So
then you got this you know convert
graphics to mesh discretetized graphics
you see a sphere
uh now becomes you know you can kind of
see your triangles on the surface so
that because that's discretetized okay
so so you got discrete dis
discretization
okay so then you got the region concept
that's you know that's beginning to be
what we are talking about um
uh then you got the boundary uh concept
which is the boundary of the graphics or
mesh. Okay. What what what are we doing?
So uh so what so so far how far have we
go? Did we um Yeah. So that's about it.
That's it for today. So today did we
understand why it doesn't work or did we
No, we didn't get it to work. boundary
discretetized graphics but there's some
okay so right now what need we need to
do is just uh study this uh read in
detail of this documentation I think
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching
so boundary discretetized graphics let
let's see how many people are watching
I'm curious three let me let me make a
guess
uh let's
Five people.
Okay. Um that's a crowd. Uh so so we did
not figure out why boundary
discretetized graphics of a given valid
graphics is not working. Okay. So so
right now so the next thing to do is
actually to read this documentation in
detail. Okay. So boundary discretetize
graphics G discretetize a 2D or 3D
graphics G into a boundary mesh region.
Okay. So it returns a boundary mesh
region which is a region that's made of
mesh and that's only the boundary of it.
Okay.
Uh then you can okay give a option to
specify which element to discretetize.
Okay. So deta so uh discretetize full
dimensional graphics primitives into a
boundary representation
consisting of peacewise linear elements
peacewise linear
okay that basically just mean a mesh
so only four dimensional plots area in
2D and volume in 3D will be
discretetized
Okay. The graphics G can be graphics or
graphics 3D or individual graphics
primitives. There it is. Okay. So, we we
give it graphics 2D.
But why is it not working though?
You know, that's that's the thing. So,
you know, this is not working.
Uh this is fail,
right? Wait, it's
fail.
Yeah, it it it return itself. So, it's
fail. So, we give it a graphics
primitive
of a list of circles. That's a graphics
object. So, according to this
documentation, graphics G can be
graphics or graphics 3D
effectively. So boundary discretetized
graphic graphics effectively treats
multiple primitives in graphics and
graphics 3D as a union operation. Okay.
Bounded pie-wise linear primitives in
graphics. This can be uh represent
exactly.
I don't know why is it fail. So let's
try. Is it because our radius is too
large? No, that's not possible. I mean
it would be very silly
if the radius is large. Okay. But let's
just, you know, try small just to be
sure.
You see it's not it's not doing it near
yet.
It should return something like that.
Okay. So
So um
Okay. Unbounded. unbounded peace-wise
linear primitives in graphics graphics
3D only a finite range can be
represented. Okay.
So anyway, so why is it failing? So a
dis parallelogram
uh cone
discretetize a cone discretetize a
prism.
Okay. Then discretetize what is this?
desires a whole 2D graphic scene where
multiple primitives are taken as a
union. Okay. Yeah.
Very quite powerful.
Okay. But um but but but
why is uh
discretetize full dimensional graphics
primitive into a boundary
representation?
So is it because they are not a region
because they are disconnected because we
you know we actually just have two um
you know let's shrink the radius it's
like kind of city
so okay so you know shrink you know
let's not to be too far apart.
So now you see you know two circles.
Uh
yeah. So so
if you
run this Okay, it works.
Wait a minute.
It works.
So when you shrink them,
it works. Wait, this can't be right.
This got to be a major bug, my friend.
This got to be a major bug.
If that's a bug, then I'm very pissed.
You know, Wuam language cannot possibly
have this bug.
You see, when the circle when the second
circle is near the first one or much
smaller in radius, then the whole thing
works. You see it return discretetize.
Then then then uh
then uh x boundary.
Then what is the x boundary?
I did it. Return.
Run it.
Wait. What you see? So that's the that's
the primitives. That's the graphics.
That's discretetized. But there's no
where is my X boundary?
Oh, wait. So, there's another value
Xbounds
region bounds.
So, paste that. You know that works. So,
let let's try this again. Okay. I can't
believe this uh won't work. Okay. So if
you run this, so let's create a new
section. Old four
old four new section. Paste it. Run it.
Doesn't work. Okay. Now all four again
something. Okay. Now
paste it. Now let's shrink the circle.
Okay. Shrink. The radius is just, you
know, 11. Okay. 11. And the center is
six and nine. Okay, do it.
Oh, still doesn't work. Wait.
God, what have I been do? Why is that?
What?
I thought it worked here.
What have I been doing wrong?
Is it because I'm getting tired? And uh
is the circle radius the problem.
So here the radius six that works. So
but 11
let's change it to six. Okay,
do it.
That worked.
Oh god, this is incredible. So if if the
second radius is 11,
then it doesn't work. So this is
a bug.
This is this is not right. So
it is possible I found a
bug in Wuam language but this is not
likely
because how can you possibly have this
bug
you see when the radius of the second
circle is let's say six
then you run it okay then you go down
you can see it create a discretetized
circle and and that one and returns the
boundary. Okay, so this is x min x maxx
y min y max. Okay, when the radius of
the second circle is six. Now if you
change it to 11, you know that's not a
big number. evaluate it.
You see you got this
not not a correctly specified region.
Okay. Okay. So actually so it expect the
input to be a region of some sort.
So why is this overlapping circle not
considered correct region? I mean it
should be a region because we have seen
you know you can you can even have this
this bunch of circles.
Okay that's very interesting finding.
Okay I think that's it for today. That's
very interesting
uh puzzle.
I don't know what's going on, but I
have, you know, now um so I have to look
into more to be sure. So, okay, I think
that's it for today. Bye, guys.
Shutting down in one minute and I'm
going to have uh dinner.
Very interesting. This this we we found
a bug. Um seems like
so clarify the bug. Okay. So, let me
just write down the the the bug, the
nature of a bug.
Okay. Seems like we found a bug.
Need to look into more. Okay.
And what is a bug? The bug is
The bug is Okay. So, hold on a second.
Let me delete this. Delete this. Okay.
The bug is
when
circle
radius
differ by just
five.
It
doesn't work. Okay. What it? So this
bound uh this
this boundary disqueeze graphic doesn't
work. So let let's so so so what works
so what works is this works
this works.
This does not work.
Okay. Okay. So what's the difference? So
the difference here is that uh so let's
see what is the difference. This one
this one the circles are not connected.
So you do so you have um
so they are like they are uh disjointed.
So that works but but then this does not
work.
In this case, the circles are like
overlapping and it didn't work. But it
should because according to this, you
know, you you can even have. So anyway,
bye guys.
So put this back
color the color syntax color it. That's
today's talk show. Fantastic. Uh bye
guys.