Hello, welcome to another episode of son
talk show. We are going to code emac
list. Today is episode let's see what
episode is today. Go to talk show in
browser and go down episode 699. So
we're going to talk about emac list.
This is continuation from yesterday.
Emac Lisp new functions define var key
map and define keymap part two. So we
did an hour yesterday. So today I got
things figured out. If you are here say
hi. If you are watching this offline
play at 1.5 speed. Okay. So Emac 29
which is two years ago has a fantastic
new feature. Okay. So let me show you
what that feature is. So you can see
this is before and this is after. So
before you have you know this a bit more
complicated to define key maps and now
it's much simpler and shorter the code.
So what is that about? This is for
emacisp coders. So okay if you don't
know eacisp this is not interesting to
you. This is of no interest to you.
Okay. But uh so so let me just code. I
need to do this code. Okay. So video
check audio check. Good. So let's uh
stop that. Stop that. Okay. So the pink
window shows all my command
call names on the right and the
corresponding keystroke on the left. So
you can see as I move the cursor
backward forward you can see backward
forward word. Okay. So, uh if you see a
command you can search for it and you'll
find for example this you'll find my
code online for example kas beginning of
line or block. So search in the browser
kasan beginning line or block. So you
can see uh here is my website. Okay. The
other one is you know so here is my
website. Now go back. The other one,
this Wesley guy is a scumbag. He stole
my website. I think he bought my
tutorial like five or 10 years ago and
he put it on his website. So that's, you
know, this waxly
gun. So anyway,
so that's a pink window. Okay. So show
my command uh names and the keystroke on
the left. I'm using a KA flight keys.
The most efficient key binding for
Emacs.
Search for it, you'll find it. It's on
GitHub or watch tens of videos tutorial.
It's the most efficient key binding for
Emacs. More efficient than Vim. And uh
I'm using a Vora keyboard layout. Okay.
So, let's begin today's topic. So, close
that. Close that. So, showing browser.
So, that's what we're going to talk
about. So
let me show so I need to do so let's go
to my packages. Okay. So I have written
many EMAC packages you know supply keys
and all that. So now I need to update
them to use the new um new syntax. Okay.
If you don't know yet, we talked about
yesterday where uh for example, yes. Uh
so Emacs 29 which begin in 2023 two
years ago they added a they overhauled
the key binding functions functions to
create shortcuts. So Emacs has thousands
of commands. Everything you do is a
command you know like the command name.
Okay. Including including when you type
something. Uh for example, let's cancel
new buffer. Type something. Okay. Wait.
Type.
Why does it go to TYP?
Okay. There is a error in my key
binding. Oh, okay. What some
Okay. So s space. So okay there there is
something wrong
uh because I just
made some changes to my emacs. So in
some HTML mod so I probably did
something wrong.
Okay.
So
space. Okay.
Oh okay. Yeah. So this one
uh this one belongs to here.
Okay. Evaluate the buffer. Close it. Now
close it. Reopen it.
So HTML mod
some. No. Now it's fixed. Okay. So I was
saying when you type something
something
even that keystroke is a command that
command is called
um
okay so let me show you describe key
then press a key. So when you type any
letter that actually calls the command
selfinsert command. Okay very
interesting. So in EMAC application
everything you every keystroke you type
invokes a command. So when you type a
normal letter like abc. So every time
you type a that
tries to find the corresponding command.
If there's none then it's selfinsert
command which just insert whatever the
keystroke you type. So this is different
from other editors such as VS Code.
Open VS Code. There's a command open VS
Code I wrote. You can grab it. It's it's
on my website. You see? So in in VS
Code, you know, when you type something,
you know, the characters, you know, you
just insert, it's not a command, but in
EMAC it is. Okay. Although final effect
is the same.
So that's interesting. Okay. So in EMAC
everything is a command. Now
but then so everything is a command but
then you can give a keyboard shortcut to
any command. That's a power of Emacs.
Okay. And so I wrote all these packages.
Um and I need to so let me show you uh
for example CSS mode. uh search for map.
Okay. So this code block shows
where I define the key. So tab space. So
you can see a tap there. Tap space will
call complete symbol. Tap F will call
format buffer and so on. This is how I
define keyboard shortcuts. So let me
demonstrate that. So go to S talk show
today. Showing browser. There it is. Go
back. Now, here's a CSS file. Open it.
So, if I want to say, let's say here,
let's say
font family. I forgot what's the name.
So, tap S completion. So, you got font
face or font family. So, font family.
So, that's completion. So, you can see
correspond to this. You see tab there
space then CSS complete symbol and that
command is defined right here. Okay. See
so search you see. So go back to CSS.
So that's then if you have F let's try
it again. F then tab space. Oh so you
now you have many choices. Let's say
figure
fi guru r. So what does figure return?
Nothing. Figure is a html tag. Yeah,
that's that's for for example here.
Okay. So anyway, that's completion. So
save that, close it.
Save it. Close it. Okay, let's go back
to the
the key binding which is what I'm
talking about. I'm demonstrating how you
define keys for commands. Okay. But now
since Emacs 29 two years ago, there's
some overhaul of the functions to define
keys uh which are simpler. It so which
is better. So the left hand side is a
new one, the right hand side EMAC 28 is
the old one. Okay. So I started to
change for all of my commands
uh all of my packages all these are most
of them are major modes some of them are
minor modes so all almost all of them
has code that defines the key so for
example let's search for key uh let's
say search for um
uh let's search for
let's search for define key. Okay, copy
that. Search in this directory define
key. Just search it. E files. So you can
see all these are occurrences. So if you
open one of them, so you can see you
know each one of them define keys. Now
you can also see this define key is
using the old function
right here. The new one is key map set.
So my job is to update all of them you
know about 201 10 or 15 packages to use
the new
um new function. Okay. So let me just
start to do it. Okay. So let me let me
just show uh let me start to do it. So
let let's search let's search for that.
Okay.
Uh let me just quickly work on it. You
wouldn't understand what I'm doing. So
yeah. So define key. Let's close that.
So let's go to So what is this one? This
one is temp temp file. Delete that. This
one is also temp file.
Delete that. So this PowerShell temp,
delete that. Uh go back here. This temp
delete that. this xx you know those file
starting named with xx in the beginning.
So you can see
uh
you see all these xx those are temporary
files. Whenever I modify something I
create a copy. So so temp files we don't
care. So uh CSS mo mode.
Okay delete that.
Now this woof mode I don't want to
change because the key binding are new
in EMAC 29 which is two years ago. So
there's a question you don't necessarily
want to update because if you update
then for people who are still they still
haven't updated their Emacs from two
years ago then it would wouldn't work
for them. So for some public very public
package packages you don't want to be
aggressive in updating them. So the uh
so the kasawan mode
uh let's you know so do I want to update
them? Uh let's let's compact them first.
Okay.
Uh
do I want to update them two years old
Emacs? Um
maybe.
Okay. So, go back here. Let's close
that.
Let's let's ignore it for now. Okay. LSL
mode. Let's open it. Let's see. Uh now
LSL mode involves
uh menu.
So, I'm not sure I want to update. I
want to update it. But however
I forgot how to define menu. So in Emacs
there's a pecularity.
So remember these are defining keyboard
shortcuts. However, if you want to
create a menu,
you can
but it also involves using the define
key syntax. So in other words in Emacs
the graphical menu they are considered
they are like considered as keys you
know for some reason.
So but I haven't I haven't coded menu
for a long time so I don't remember I
have a tutorial I don't remember. So so
let's leave that for now. Okay. So let's
leave that. Let's go back to uh CSS
mode. Close. Let's go back to
that. Okay. Here. So, S lookup. So, open
that. So, let's update this this one.
Okay.
Yeah. So, copy the code. That's the old
code. Then paste it here. That's a new
code. Now, we just need to So, let me
show you. So, old above and uh here is
new.
Okay.
new code for EMAC 29. So let me show you
how to do it. So define this will be
define
define v key map. Okay.
And uh that will go
here.
And uh
uh
yeah, leave that like that. and here.
Delete. Delete. And delete this line.
And uh cut the whole thing.
Move it inside here.
And uh then
copy that.
Cut that out.
Then for each of these we want it to be.
Let me show you what it to what it we
want it to be like that. Okay. So let's
define a keyboard macro to do that. So
start defining keyboard macro. You can
look at the pink window for the command
I just called. Okay. Start recording
keyboard macro. Delete. Then
delete. Delete. Then search KBD.
Enter. Okay. Now stop recording. So you
can see keyboard macro and macro. Okay.
Now let's call the keyboard macro. So,
so do it. You can see
you know the pink window will show the
repetition of the keyboard marker. Okay.
So then call repeat last command. Do it.
Fantastic. And press the key again. Do
it. Do it. Do do.
Fantastic.
So you see this a text transformation.
Now so you can see so what uh so this
this we
define prefix key map okay so let's see
what I want
uh keyboard lookup map yeah so
wait so copy that this will be the name
where Does that occur? Uh
lookup map search. Okay.
Modify the value. Okay. Search
search. Okay. So here's the old code.
Here's a new code. So we don't need
we don't need this.
Um,
no.
Okay. So,
purify the code.
Okay. So this is the new
and uh this is the old. Can you see how
it is much simpler? Okay, but let's
double check
uh lookup map.
Yeah, I think that's it. Okay, now
select that. Comment it out.
Now
start a you new Emacs. Let's see if I
got any errors. No arrow.
Fantastic.
Magnify. Magnify. Magnify. And change
background color to pink.
So close the Okay. So now let's try
lookup. Okay. Let's say look up uh
Emacs
versus Vim. Okay, now press press.
Okay, I got the key. The key is not
working.
Uh let me try again. Press press press
press.
Okay. So
this is working but there is something
with my personal command I need to
set. Okay. So go to casar key bindings.
This is my personal
modification of keys. Now search for
look up. Okay. So
uh yeah. So this is a map.
So yeah cuz I use a key map edge then
look up map.
Okay. So
I think that's it. Okay. But let me
double check.
Yeah. Okay. So now
kill that. Start Emacs again. Press one
key to start it. Okay. So there's EMAC.
Now make it pink to distinguish from
this EMAC instance. Now increase the
font size.
Okay. Increase increase more. Now press
space
H E. Fantastic.
So you see so it is working. So close
that. Save. Close. Okay. So So you can
see
let's go back to Yeah. So you can see
here's old code
and here's a new code. Much simpler.
Fantastic. One job done. So now go to
now uh now let's
cut that.
Okay. New buffer. Paste it. Paste
previous.
Copy that. Save it. XX temp file. Uh,
wait. Tim file. Then date. Then the map
name.
Save it. So we save it as a new temp
file. So in case I I want to go back, I
can. Okay. Now add X UTF declaration.
Okay. Save it. Close. Close. Now we are
back to this Kasan lookup package.
Okay. Now go all the way to the top. Uh
version date. Add a new version date uh
all digits. Okay. And uh also package
requires EMAC 29 because these new
commands are only available in Emacs 29.
So when people download it and they run
if their Emacs is not 29, it'll
complain. So So this updating this is uh
nice.
Okay. Now make a backup. Go to the
directory by compile the file. Is there
any error? No. Okay. Open the bio byte
compiled file. Delete it. Close. So
that's one thing done. So we updated one
of the package. Fantastic. Now close it.
key binding. Let's put my personal key
binding. Close it. Okay. So, this is
done. Let's go to next.
Okay. So, JavaScript mod this this is
going to be a big job because wait uh
oh, there's only few. Okay. So,
okay. So, copy it. New buffer.
Save it. XX today state the key map
name.
This is our temp file. X UTF declaration
and lexical binding. Okay. And uh cut
that paste it here. So we're going to
create a new one. So the new code is
going to be define v key map. Correct.
Okay. So
delete that and uh uh wait.
So cut that
the doc the new documentation
and uh this you don't need anymore.
Let's highlight that make sparse key
map. You don't need anymore because this
will do it. The new function that's why
it's very good. So define a leader map
you don't need to do it. Okay. So remove
that and uh this okay so this this we
will do it like that. Okay. So let me
show you in a moment. Let me explain in
a moment. Okay. So here we select that
EMAC rectangle command to remove it. And
now delete this KBD KBD. Okay. Co last
keyboard macro be recorded. Do it. And
now repeat. Do it.
Do it. Do it. Do it. Fantastic. Yes.
Okay. Now programming. We don't need it.
Okay. Now
um cut
paste it here.
Uh wait. Actually this you will be
define key map. Okay.
So cut that.
Cut that. Put it here. Pify the code.
There it is. That's our new code. So
compare.
Old code is like that complicated.
New code. Simple. Now, what does this
mean? Let me explain this a little bit.
So, oh wait, I forgot. This needs to be
um
what's the key map name? Oh, yeah. Cuz
JavaScript mode map.
Yep. Okay. So, so let me explain. Okay.
So,
so when so, so normally let's ignore
that one and ignore that one. You know,
normally the value of the define v key
map is just pairs key command name key
command name key command name. But in my
case, I want the leader key. So my
convention is that every major modes key
start with the tab key.
Okay. So you would say
so you would normally uh let me let me
let me do let me Okay. So let me uh
cut let me do a new version. Okay let me
show you how that would be. So normally
it would be like that. Okay. Uh
okay. So this is one way to do it. You
see I'm defining a key map. So when you
press tab space you call this command.
When you press uh press tab F you call
this command and so on. Okay. But now I
want the tab to be customizable.
The tab is the leader key for each major
mode. So, so how do you do that? You
know, this this tab needs to be a
variable. You know, you you can have a
variable in a stream. So,
so, so what you can do is like
complicated. You can like if so, for
example, let me show you. Uh, this is
getting tedious. Okay. So let me show
you. Okay. So if if this variable s
major leader key that is a variable that
allows you to define your custom leader
key for each major mode. Okay. So if if
people have that defined
then
then you just use the value. Okay. So
whatever
that variable's value otherwise
otherwise you say
that
you see so this you know so if you know
otherwise that then okay so then what
you have to do is you you remove this
and you say conc
that that join string okay so the first
part of the string is that the second
part of the string is that okay so you
conc
then then this goes there you see so the
it's slightly complicated then you have
to do this for each one of them
you know remove the tab here you know
and so on
okay so
let me do something okay so let me do
something let me show you. Okay. So,
undo, undo, undo, undo, undo. The power
of undo, undo, undo, undo, undo. Okay.
So, paste that here. Okay. So, we got
several forms.
We got this form
then, but if you want the leader key to
be customizable, you can do this.
Uh
so for each of the beginning you
basically say that
that
that so this is so this is another way
to do it. Not good. Okay. So instead we
go to the final form which is this one.
So you define the customizable
uh leader key over here. So if the major
leader key is defined then you use that
otherwise you just use tab.
Okay.
So after tap that needs to be like
normally each one needs to be a command
but however you can put a key map
which will mean you know after user
press tab then whatever
they press will be um corresponding to
this key map. Okay. So this this is how
you do it. Okay. So now finally we are
done. Okay. So one more thing, let's
change the tab here to be this syntax.
That's another new thing in Emacs 29.
This syntax
uh god it's too much too too many things
to explain. But anyway, this syntax
supposed it allows you to distinguish
tab when you use the tab key. you know,
when you press the tab to distinguish
distinguish the tab key when you press
it in a GUI interface versus when you
press it on a EMAC terminal interface.
Do you guys know what I mean? So, for
example, EMAC terminal
uh no
uh no init file, no Windows system. So,
this is how you run Emacs in a terminal.
It used to be before Emacs 29 you know
in terminal it cannot distinguish tab
key from the tab character you know so
so basically you cannot define your own
tab keys something like that it's a bit
more comp complicated but in EMAC 29
they kind of they they fixed it so
instead instead of the capital TAB
letter you use this you know this angle
bracket Actually that should be angle
bracket not the French quote. So it
should be that. Okay. Um
yeah.
So when you use this syntax then you
will you will just mean tab key and and
the terminal will also be able to to
distinguish the tab key
versus the tab as key character. So do
you guys know what I mean? Hello. A a uh
ACI. So I'm talking about you know uh
lots of
complicated thing.
So ASKI if you are a programmer as
characters is the all important thing
you need to know. Okay. ASI ID
code point and hexadimal representation
abbreviation unic code symbol
uh correct notation. So these are ASKI
characters. So if you are a programmer
and you have been coding for several
years then usually you have some
understanding it's like essential. Okay
especially especially if you are a C C++
kind of coder the bit ders
now if you are JavaScript or Python
coder then usually you don't know uh
well you still need to know some of it
but less. Okay, that's about as key
characters. Okay, so copy that URL,
close it, go to talk show today.
Uh, is that this page? Yes. Now, let's
paste the link because that's the things
we talked about.
Okay. So, let's paste the link here.
There it is. Asky characters.
Okay. Now, let's go back to the code. So
let's go back here. Uh let's go back to
the code. Uh is it what? Uh here. Okay.
So wait. So uh close that.
Okay. Ctrl C. Control Xtrl C to exit
Emacs.
Okay. So this is the code. Now double
check is it correct? So you can compare
this is old and this is new.
Now let's double check if there's error.
Okay. So now backup and uh make bite
compile. Let's see what error duplicate
definition. Okay, that's fine.
Okay, I don't care about that. So delete
the delete the ELC
uh
CSS mode ELC. Okay. So, what are we
doing?
Yeah. See?
Okay. JavaScript mode.
Okay. So,
let's double check.
Is that correct? I think so. So, cut it.
Now, go back to JavaScript mode. Okay.
So, now paste the code. Now, the old
code remove.
Okay. The old code remove. But let's
color it first.
Okay. The old code remove.
Remove. Okay. Now make a backup. Go to a
directory. Bite compile it. Is there
error? No. Open it. Delete it. Close.
Fantastic.
Another package update. Done. Now go to
the top. You need to uh update the
version number.
Okay. and say Emacs 29
and uh version 29.1. Save. Fantastic.
Done. Okay. And this we don't need. So
let's delete the, you know, this sample
code I just showed. Delete it. We don't
need it. Save it. And also delete the
new part. Save it. Close it. Okay. Close
it. Close it. Close it. Close it. Close.
Close. Okay. Now this is wine mode.
Close. We don't want to do. So that is
um now let's let's Okay. So this is done
cuz our go let's do one more. Okay. So
now this is go language mode.
Let's do one more. Okay. And maybe
that's it. So, let's see. ACP says,
"Are you refactoring due to a new
feature in the latest Emacs version?"
Yes, not the latest, but Emacs 29,
version 29, two years ago. Hello, simple
postman ACP says, "But in the new form,
it doesn't look like you do anything
when checking if the leader key va is
bound." It does.
It does.
You see? So, so let's reopen the
JavaScript mode. The JavaScript mode.
Okay. So, let's just let's go here.
JavaScript mode. There it is. Search for
map.
Uh in JavaScript, there's a lot word for
map. So, search for uh key map. Okay. So
you see here is a new code. So first of
all here we check if this major mode
leader key is defined.
Now if you are using my packages if you
are using kasar emacs pack you know
system distro then you have a file emac
keys here. Open it. Then one of the one
of the definition is
major mode leader key. Okay. So that
allows you to customize what is the you
know starting key for all your major
mode commands.
all my all my major mode commands such
as HTML, Goland, Python, uh Emac, this
CSS, autoarchy,
uh JavaScript, you know.
So that's so that's that.
Okay. So it it's checking if that's
defined. Now it may not define because
someone else you know he bought my
packages but he's not using he's not
using Emacs you know he's not using the
whole thing so you check if that is
defined if so just use the value
otherwise return the you know the string
tab so that is the leader key and and
what what follows the leader key is a
key app which means you know the leader
key will start a key then whatever key
correspond to the corresponding command.
Okay. So that does that is that what
you're asking.
You see when it's bound when it's bound
it just return the leader keys value
itself.
Uh yes. Yes.
So the code is a bit you know
kind of you know it's it's not exactly
complicated. It's just the way they are
you know.
Um okay so that's JavaScript mode. Close
that.
Let's do one more. Let's now let's now
we explain the whole thing. We can do
this quickly. Okay. Copy new buffer.
Paste. Copy the name. Save it. XX
today's date the map name.
Okay. Go to the top X UTF to declare key
binding. Okay. Then uh copy the hole.
Paste a new here and let's start to
define define v key map. Okay. Uh then
the the variable will be named that
that's a template.
Okay. Then delete delete that. Then the
documentation will be that. Okay. For go
mode. Okay. Then you don't need this
part. Then this program delete. You
don't need that. This go this make key
map you don't need anymore because that
defines it the key map. and make the
leader key map. Okay, we you know we are
not doing that. Let's delete that. And
uh this part okay gets complicated. You
don't need that. Just say that. Okay.
And change the syntax to the new EMAC 29
tab syntax. Okay. Remove that. And here
this this this this
rectangle
cut. Okay. Now transform the key KBD.
You don't need that. So call the macro
we did before. Do it. Do it. Okay. And
now this three
children needs to be define key map.
Okay. Paste it. And uh there. Okay. Pify
it. Fantastic. Okay.
Pify it. And uh then uh let's see.
Then move this inside. That's a key.
Then what is the value? The value is
this map. Prefy the code. Go to the top.
Fantastic. So compare before
after.
One more check. Is it correct?
Let's highlight this word just to make
sure. You see this? This highlighting
you know highlight symbol a point is
very useful
visual clarity
you know so press one key you can see
where the variables are or whether you
have a typo okay double check this does
this looks right to you yes okay cut go
back to the goland mode paste it there
code make a backup go to the directory
Press B2 by compile. Yes. Is there an
error? No. Open it. Delete it. Close.
Fantastic.
Close GL. Okay. Wait. Reopen Goland
mode. Go to the top. You need to say
package requires now 29.1.
Okay. And update the version date all
digits. And increase this to eight.
Fantastic and beautiful.
Okay. So, we talked for 45 54 minutes.
Okay. So, but this is done. Close.
Close. Okay. So, this goland mode is
done. Close.
Uh let's see.
Simple postman says sorry for off topic.
What keys do you have on the thumb
cluster?
The last update I found on your site was
done in 2023. I'm thinking about binding
apps switching for the upper thumb
cluster row. So, are you using are you
using a glove 80? So, by the way, this
is glove 80 keyboard for those of you
don't know. So, I think that's it for
today. So, I'm just going to talk about
keyboard a bit. Um, yeah. So, yeah. So,
hold on a second. Let me check if
there's anything I want to talk about.
Uh, not really. Okay. So, we covered
basically we covered we completed the
task of these two thing. Oh, there's one
more thing. So, I have a tutorial for
writing
for you Emac this coders if you want to
write a major mode. So, there you know
you go to uh create a major mode.
There's an entire set of tutorials about
creating a major major mode for you know
for a new programming language or for a
new shell or for a new interaction with
chat GPT or AI whatever. So this is how
you do it but I focus on just creating a
major mode for uh programming languages
like when you have a new programming
language and one of the section is
creating key binding here and on this
page I'm still using the old way so you
can see it's using the old way so I need
to update it. It's it's trivial you know
now I know how to do so I can you know
update this in five minutes but you you
also know if you have watched today's
show you also know how to update this
okay so but that's that's it uh let's
see kasan talk show today yeah that's it
for today today's uh thumbnail is
brought to you by the 4chan people
uh okay and uh Yeah, that's it.
And here is the Python example of old
tbinding functions with versus the new.
Yeah. So that's it. So you so you are
saying so wait. So you Okay. So you are
using uh gravity. So yeah. So for those
you don't know, I haven't done
Wait, why is this so small?
Are you guys seeing my full screen of my
like desk right
so this keyboard is glove 80 fantastic I
have video reviews this is ultimate
hacking too this is nia track ball
uh okay so and and uh I haven't a lot of
people ask me for this but I haven't
used it so this is really fantastic SW
board SV A L B O A R D. Okay. So you are
so let me answer your question. So you
are saying that
what keys do you have on the thumb
cluster? Okay. The last update I found
on your website is 2023. I'm thinking
about binding app switching for the
upper thumb cluster.
Okay. So this is about
you know so I'm assuming you are also
using SFY keys right answer that well
because that's important you know uh so
okay so let's go let's go to softly keys
okay go to the top go to the URL open it
so that's keys and uh there is a section
on Batman keyboard layout So this is for
people who have these like me special
keyboards
and they want an optimal
uh key binding for them. So that's why
so you have glove at keyboard. I also
have Kinesis keyboardis
advantage keyboard like that.
Uh I also have you know early you know
like 10 years ago I was using this truly
ergonomic keyboard. So I also have my
opinions and detail detailed analysis on
what is the best key mapping you know to
uh for this keyboard and another one is
you know the ultimate hacking keyboard
this one. Okay. So but and and there's
also this one uh Google keyboard. Okay.
So the question you know so about the
about the you know what key map should
you use? So basically I have so let me
tell you okay so I have my customization
right now is the left hand side is
unchanged. Okay everything is the same.
The right hand side
this key. Okay. So let let me let me
this key the top right is escape
and this one the middle top is
tab. Okay. And that's it. That's that's
it. That's the change I've made. But
yeah, usually well I I I made this
change only like few weeks ago, but
before that the tab is on the right. So
the upper right is tab, the the top
middle is escape.
Okay, that's all I have. Um,
so does that match with what I have?
Yes, exactly. It match it matches what I
have, you know, here.
Uh so to me so I think
this is not a very critical
change for me critical key map. Well so
it really depends on you. So uh yeah. So
I think it really depends on you. Just
just the only thing I think uh you
should remember is that don't don't move
your thumb like that too much. Okay?
Like move your whole hand instead
instead of just moving your thumb. For
some reason I started to have thumb
pain. That's that's another new thing.
Okay. I have my knuckle uh right here.
started two months ago for some reason.
I do not know exactly why.
I don't know if it's because of the
typing or because I was like um
uh you know fighting with my wife. I I
don't know exactly. So, but I started to
have a pain here.
Uh that's too bad. And and also I type
so much like right now here and here
both hands are sore
even with all this setup
and also because I'm getting old. So so
anyway so
so just don't move your thumb too much.
Okay then then otherwise it's up to you.
As for switching up key for me I press
this key. So let me show you. You see
this key? So if I put my screen back
here now watch me press this key. So if
I go here press that key. So you see
switch the last tab I mean the last app
just like
old tab. Okay. You see?
Okay. So that's what I do.
So the question about
whether you use whether you know two
options use softly keys or use softly
keys and follow everything else
what I'm doing. Okay. I would recommend
just use softly keys. Okay. If you use
Emacs then absolutely it is my highest
recommendation
you should use anyone should use softly
keys does not matter what keyboard you
have may be a normal keyboard that's
fine use softly keys that will save your
hand pen tremendously
even better than evil mod or nim or or
vim or neoim. Okay.
But if you are use, you know, if you are
a VI user, Vim, Neo Vim, you know,
that's fine. You know, if you are Evo
Mod user, it's not too bad. Okay.
Uh but other than that, I think it's
really up to each person. Okay? So, you
don't have to follow like,
you know, my you know, everything I do.
So I mean one of the thing I really
think is great is this hoover to
activate feature. So I never basically I
never press mouse mouse buttons. You
know the mouse button is another
hand pain inducer. You know either
either with a physical mouse like you
click click click click or with the
thumb thumb is worse because you
actually have to exert pressure.
Normally on the mouse
you the buttons are top on the top. So
you you can use gravity. You don't have
to like actual move your finger you
know. Let me show you. You don't
actually have to
uh like move your finger. When you move
your finger, you you have to exert
muscle force from there. But instead you
can just
um
make your finger stiff and just press
like that. So you so you are not
actually using your muscle. Okay. So
that's when the buttons are on top those
are good. But when the buttons on the
side you cannot do that you know. So you
actually have to press but
but if you turn on the hoover hoover to
activate like I do like here here here
now you you watch my hand there's no uh
pressing of any mouse buttons hoover to
activate okay fantastic so that I highly
recommend but again each person is
different okay that that also depends on
how how how many hours you sit in front
of computer for me I'm kind of a world
record holder literally no kidding okay
so I for for like 10 years I sit in
front of a computer more than like more
than anyone kind of the top top 1000 in
USA for 10 years
I don't have proof of that but you know
it is my guess it's so severe you guys
you know I don't think anyone would you
know you guys wouldn't understand. Okay,
so depending on how much you sit in
front of computer and all that
so I recommend so hoover to activate is
very good and also you must thing is
that every hour you must get up and walk
about or whatever move for five minutes
every hour. Okay. Every hour
get up, move for 3 minutes or every two
hours get up for you know and move for 5
minutes or 10. That's is it that is
essential if you sit in front of the
computer all day.
Can the pen be of the palm rest on the
keyboard? No, I actually don't use palm
rest much.
Oh, I forgot I even have it on. Um
uh why not to use a trackpad instead of
mouse? Trackpad is no good. Okay. I
don't like a trackpad at all.
Track track ball is much better because
trackpad you have to rub your fingers on
the pad all the time. Also trackpad is
flat. You know my RSI is so severe. I
don't think you guys understand. You see
on a trackpad your hand is flat because
trackpad is not tilted. Normally you can
tilt you you can tilt it if you want to.
You know you have to put something under
but normally it's like that. Okay. For
example on the MacBook I use all day. So
I use the computer so much that even
just put my hand on the table do nothing
just put there for 10 hours 10 hours a
day or something you can feel you you
you you can feel this going to there is
a problem okay I can feel it because I
if I twist my hand all the way back this
this way now I feel so much comfortable
I can feel it you know then this Okay,
because I you know
you know it's like it's like a torture
you know you force someone to sit and
put your hands like that you know fat on
the table for 12 hours a day for a year
for several years
that's going to pro that's going to be a
problem even if you don't do anything we
are not talking about moving fingers to
type at all you know just put just you
know in that position for too Oh, it's a
problem. So that so what I'm describing
is the degree of severity
of the hand issues I'm talking about. So
for most of you guys it may not apply
because nobody you know you are not
going to be like me sitting in front of
a computer for like 12 hours a day. I'm
talking about like literally 12 hours a
day. Not you think it's 12 hours but
anyway
so I don't like trackpad. So first of
all it's flat then you have to rub your
fingers on it like rope rope is it's not
feeling good and also it's not precise
you know it's not it's less it's much
less precise than a mouse or a track
track ball. And also all the gestures is
actually no good. they they create hand
problems. Okay. So you what you actually
want is physical buttons, physical
buttons, physical you know movement and
you don't you know and the other thing
is rubbing your fingers on the thing you
know so many years ago the Apple fixed
it you know Apple's new trackpad they
have this surface that when you when you
slide your finger on it it feels okay.
But before that and most trackpad you
don't feel good you know you like it's
it is not natural for human to rub
fingers on on a slab all the time for
hours.
Okay, that's my opinion about trackpad.
Okay, that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching. Bye guys.
If you enjoyed my show, if you learned
something, donate to me, okay? Go to
PayPal,
go to kasadi.info, my homepage, and all
the way at the bottom, Patreon me,
Amazon gift card me, and PayPal me.
Okay,
that's it for today. Thank you.
So, fly keys. Fantastic. Close. So we
shut down in 2 minutes. Kasa flag keys.
Fantastic. Uh Kasa talk show today is
done. Fantastic.