good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show today is noon
2019 November December 4th noon
Wednesday San Francisco time we have 10
people watching in hello guys and so
what is the topic today I don't have a
topic and so we're gonna pick a topic
social justice okay what in particular
of social justice
so no topic today and let's do perhaps
random then social justice what's
specifically anything you have in mind
hey groaning Jason new to my channel
great
so what wait what country you came from
and are you a programmer so I get you
know like what so what what topics how
did you find me
so I have some idea how what kind of
things you are interested so today we
don't have a topic and let me just go
random ok and Nybo says social justice
but what what in particular because
social justice is a big giant topic we
go there and it's gonna be like in this
and it's going to be politics and you
know I'm going I'm going to feel nervous
about Google is gonna censor me Wow so
so topic okay so topic and let's go to
now by the way this look at this picture
this is hope or in Naruto Naruto is a
place in Japan and you know I learned
about
there's this interesting excuse me
there's this interesting thing about
Naruto okay
I mean Naruto because I'm gonna tell you
how I found some of the interesting
things and jason says Northern Ireland
oh my god I'm a programmer from Northern
Ireland I came across your website by
accident and I'm glad I did fantastic
fantastic so I have a friend from
Northern Ireland now now where is I
Ireland now excuse me I'm American I
don't know where is Ireland Ireland is
above wait oh wait
Ireland is part of England right so na
Bo na vi's you're hiking money knobby so
knobby is anime are you talking about
Naruto so let me tell you about this
okay so let's go to Unicode Unicode
actually let's go to right here saw the
Unicode in fact we haven't done Unicode
for a while so you go to Unicode the
most popular page of my website that is
the Unicode you know interestingly this
is the most popular web page on my
website all the 6000 Arcos and we
haven't talked about Unicode for several
for two months at least
so Bart says you are another proof of
Americans being ignorant of anything
that is not American that is not me no
that's other Americans okay not this one
I know everything Island I can tell you
where is Ireland of course
Ireland is part of UK United Kingdom
okay let's go to shall we go to Google
Maps or Bing Maps okay let's go to
Google
Maps okay and actually I'm going to tell
you about this Naruto swore so let's
write down when you get confused let's
write down the topics our talk show
so today's top talk show it's empty we
go back here we talk about Naruto okay
Naruto swore and unicode fish cake
fantastic from Japan from Japan the land
of Japan Ning home nicknamed Punk Lisbon
okay so fish cake and and fish balls
okay from fish cake to Naruto to
Naruto's war those are fascinating
topics and to the anime nerd anime
character so Jason says the Unicode page
was actually how I found you oh my god
that's how you found me fantastic so
Jason is from Northern Ireland I came
across okay so I have to remember that
because I it's great to know and and
Nybo is from no way nibel is from Norway
and neighbor says social justice
unnecessary Evo how is that necessary
evil I don't think it's necessary evil I
think it's a necessary evil social
justice
so neighbor says okay so neighbor is
talking to party and party is talking to
Saudi parse a sniper do you want me to
spoil your your read o or do you rather
investigate further in to find out where
of course I know where it is it's part
of United Kingdom but you silly let's
look at Ireland
now speaking of United Kingdom I have
one thought that is Emily that is true
okay and she will not be here today
because she's got other things to attend
to
she's got a guest something like that so
here we have United States the greatest
country on Earth
the one with the most number of nuclear
power nuclear bombs so let's go through
fly fly fly fly to fly to the northern
Europe then then there it is Ireland you
know then I'm thinking the history of
England the history of United Kingdom
which I don't know much about but it has
came across my mind they don't agree
much which is actually true for most
part of places on earth
so Ireland so well there it is Ireland
okay so but oh wait mm is taken wait
Ireland this actually is not is it part
of UK okay I'm showing my ignorance here
Ireland is is it's not part of UK right
I mean not as a country yeah not so
northern so you see it's a little bit
complicated so Northern Ireland is part
of United Kingdom but but Ireland is a
country by itself am I correct
how do you spell that Ireland Oh Island
okay so Ireland is actually a country by
itself I'm pretty sure but Northern
Ireland is part of UK so it's you know
complicated if you are not from there
you're to me at least so on Oh so only
Northern Ireland is part of UK oh yeah
so okay so you you are from
Northern Ireland so you are part of UK
so you are British citizen right I mean
that's officially so Ireland so it says
according to Wikipedia he says the
Wikipedia the most abusive today
okay do not donate do not ever donate to
Wikipedia okay
so sorry Wikipedia donation I donate it
to Wikipedia about around 2005 so 15
years ago I donated $2 when they just
begin and they have server problems
because you go to Wikipedia and they you
know the website doesn't come up because
you know they are a great website and
they have problems so they need donation
so I donate $2 back then but today they
are just a money grabber they just they
take your money
you don't know where how how how they
spend it they all the money you Peedee
millions of dollars they go to your
money go to the pocket of one Jimmy
Wales okay Jimbo you know he is not he's
a bad guy okay he he used to run a pawn
website but he tries to hide it you know
he tried to hush don't talk about it and
now he's just taking all this money
that's my opinion okay this is not
disclaimer this is just my opinion may
not be true in case he's going to sue me
so you know do not donate to Wikipedia
okay this is one of my article and you
know and recently on this code people
are talking about it there is a place
okay
so join discord if you have not already
okay join this code my discord page is
let's see my discord page so actually we
have a lot of topics we just wondered
about so my discord page is on my talk
show
or Mike Saudi website you can see this
code right there okay and but you should
join me in June you know join join
discord so we can chat we can talk about
things you know you yeah you should join
enjoy enjoying joining this code so what
are the topics we are talking about so
let's just read the comments okay
melodious scream no rage do you want me
to spoil your you're right melodious
scream no rage so Nybo jason says only
okay services must be framed hey good
morning Matt so Matt we don't have a
topic the Republic of the Republic of
Ireland is not part of UK okay so so we
already touched pushed upon several
subjects but I don't remember what is we
gonna talk about so Ireland you know
Wikipedia don't donate so let's copy
that
copy that and paste it here and okay and
close that in Ireland
okay Ireland so what about Ireland
Ireland is here and Northern Ireland is
part of UK Belfast
so Northern Ireland yeah so okay so let
me show you the Unicode in the Unicode
so we have a this food so you go to this
food item okay so you go to this food
and you will see Japanese food so there
it is Japanese food let's turn on
JavaScript
turn it on
and magnify so here we have Japanese
food now one of them is this one called
fish cake with swar design that so what
is fish cake now do you guys know what
is a fish cake now if you are not from
Asia Japan or China you may not know but
we do eat fish cakes fish cakes so let
me show you okay fish ball and that
there it is fish ball in fact I was just
having it yesterday the two days ago so
this is what it looks like and it is
made made a fish paste it's interesting
so it's it looks like that those are
fish balls now let me show you my I was
eating hotpot today okay no no no no
second no no retails for Hope ooh and I
was eating so discord be your life now
that's my breakfast that's what you have
seen in today's video but and and that
is my food okay I was eating that
yesterday two days ago yesterday with my
roommates and you know this is hot pot
you you boil your water then you throw
in meat veggies crammed into it Oh stir
then you know it boy you're saying you
take it out and you eat on a spot very
popular in traditional food in China
China Chinese people so this is this
pole this pole is mine and you see those
white things these two and also this one
those are fish balls okay those are fish
balls now what is fish for that that is
that okay so it's made of it's actually
made of fish paste now I never read
about this until you know until like few
years ago I started I was wondering what
are those made up you know you know
because they don't it you know when you
eat them they seems like official
artificial you might say our life common
guys so when you eat them they taste I
mean they they have a qualities like it
doesn't it's not meat okay and and it's
not exactly fish it's like some kind of
artificial thing so one day I want a few
years ago what is it made of made of so
it turns out it's made up I mean it's
made of a fish paste and what what is
fish paste fish paste is basically you
kill a fish then you chop them up they
are meat you take out their meat you
chop them until until they are all mushy
okay they until they become a paste kind
of so that's what it made of so it is
made of made out of fish I will I've got
two too much smoking so I started to
have cough so anyway that's fish paste
oh look at this woman
cutting this fish look doesn't look like
sanity is not but for most of humanity
that's what it looks like you know then
when you like today we are concerned
about sanity and all the health
inspections or that but you know in the
past thousands of years that's what we
do you know these like that
so okay hold on a second let me cough
Koff I'm gonna cuff myself to death so
fish paste so fish balls let me explain
okay fish balls
fish balls like that is made out of fish
paste and you make fish paste by
chopping off white meat fish as opposed
to some fish has red meat something like
that so you chop them up and make them
into a paste
that's what fish balls are made up and
the and let me show you another popular
thing in in Taiwan and in China okay I
mean in Taiwan in China and in Japan so
Japan and this is very popular in Japan
they have this thing and I'm not sure
you can buy this in American supermarket
can you okay so so guys tell me can you
bite have you guys seen this in your
supermarket can you buy it so anyway
this is Japanese style of fish bowl I
mean basically they are just fish bowl
you know they made of fish paste so
Japan do these kind of things Japan and
they call this fish cake in English this
is called fish cake and as you can see
in my photo where's my photo
so those these white things are fish
cake or fish ball and so also this one
so all these three are fish ball now
that that white thing over there is some
kind of some kind of potato or yam I I
don't know I don't know exactly what's
the name but they are delicious you know
it's like kind of like play-doh
YUM but these are the these three things
are visual and they are made of fish
paste they so that's the food okay so
typically you have these varieties or
this these are all very common there
there it is you see fish balls very
common in Taiwan in
I'm not sure about Felicio China in
Taiwan China and Japan and they are
delicious
okay that's odd so that's fish force now
however there is this thing about Japan
let me show you fish cake Japan oh my
god I need to turn javascript man every
time I Creole cache I need to turn on
JavaScript again copy
I want images I don't want those thing I
want images so actually I was talking to
Emily this morning yeah this morning
about so there it is you see this is
okay this picture is too small but
anyway you see the squirrel there so
Japan they do lots of that Japan you
know D so these are fish cake made of
fish paste so Japan has that thing what
is this yeah so this is this is more
popular this is kind of very popular in
Taiwan in China too but we don't we
don't have this I mean we don't do this
much for example in this picture on the
left and on the right I eat often well
it is in Taiwan okay but so anyway those
are so anyway so you see Japan has this
kind of thing they let's which search
for fish cakes for okay so they make
food of that pattern force force on some
reason oh God oh this Unicode but
anyway this this is this is be of food
okay so it looks like that actually I've
never seen that before
so that is fish cake now let's go back
and let's let me tell you about the
story I found about reading Wikipedia
you know Wikipedia as tons of
information fish balls
now how did I find how did I find us
whoa let me tell you okay how did I find
us whoa
so we have to go to fishcake you see one
thing leads to another when you have a
queue you're smart you dig into things
and it's gonna be endless and pretty
soon you're gonna cover the entire
history of humanity and geography and
you know everything else so this one
looks delicious of apparently fried deep
fried or something oh yeah that looks
good
Korea and whatnot and whatnot and
whatnot okay so how okay there is a
connection I want to make because I was
looking I was reading somewhere on this
page or the fish boy and fish cake and
fish paste thing then I discovered the
place called Naruto okay hold on a
second let me just copy copy or this
into my talk show page so you see image
source
fish cake okay let me just write it down
fish ball okay I already said it here so
fish ball from Japan and fish balls and
so let's read about fish paste fish
paste is a fish which has been
chemically broken down by a fermentation
process until it reaches the consistency
of a soft creamy puree or paste
alternatively it refers to cooked fish
which has been physically broken down by
pounding grinding and pressing mincing
and blending and or sieving and here
which is the consistency of a paste the
term can be applied also to shellfish
pastes such as shrimp paste or crab
paste so anyway they have different
countries style of fish paste made
things so I think it's this article
let's see so apparently in Japan the
fish bowl they call it kamaboko
something like that cure the surimi okay
so
there it is so so there it is you see so
let's let me read it okay kama Boko is a
type of 2 or the Surya Swami why do they
what do they use this slimy okay slimy
is just the fish paste cured fish paste
a processed seafood product common in
Japan cuisine Japanese cuisine so it's
made by forming various pureed deboned
white fish with either natural or
man-made addictive and flavorings into
distinctive gloves which are then
steamed until fully cooked and fun these
are sliced and either served unheated
with various dippings dipping sauces or
added to various hot soups rice or
noodle dishes kamaboko is often sold in
semi cylindrical loaves some featuring
artistic patterns such as the pink
spiral on each slice of Naruto Maki
Naruto Maki named after the well-known
title hope o near the Japanese city of
Naruto okay that is the key that is a
key key sentence so actually one of them
so they you know they they put artistic
touch to this thing so they have a
spiral squad just like Twinkies you know
you have in America you have the food
Twinkies right you guys know Twinkies so
you have a swore so and actually in
Japan they named that they named that
particular one Naruto Maki something
like that okay and why do they named it
that that because there is a city
there's a city perfecto a city called
Naruto and that city is famous for for
the swore it has okay where is the
picture so this is the swore this is the
swore
the whole pool in Naruto so so so that's
interesting because so so there is a
city in Japan Naruto famous for this
whirlpool so they have named so they
named one of their fish cake with the
hope for Naruto Maki and so so so then I
went to the page about Naruto I and I
started to read a little bit so okay I
already closed the page so let me go
back to the Naruto page Naruto Maki and
Naruto okay where is it I think this one
so there it is this is the city Naruto
Naruto Tokushima chop Japanese city and
UK so it's it's around here so it's
basically a bit lower than lower left to
Tokyo and then you started to see you
know interesting things for example this
one this one is what the city looks like
in Japan I mean like few hundred years
ago maybe so why when you look at this
exactly that's a fish cake unicode so I
look at this picture it reminds me of
Japanese samurai movies you know like 50
years old they have movies about samurai
and the houses looks like that so this
is Naruto okay and and I also remember
there is an American cartoon adopting a
Japanese style called Naruto I looked
like there's a character who wears a
headband
you know like karate you know the
headband and with a school on it do you
guys so is that what you refer to Nabi
so you know so so that and also look at
the city they have a CEO you know the
logo representing the city
they also ever swore so that so because
reading
this page you know that we you know then
I realized that's that is why you know
there's a character okay Naruto limit
let's show him okay like anime character
some kind of a kung-fu there it is yeah
so there is this guy now I've never seen
this I have never watched this anime
before but I think it's actually made in
America I think wait until I close it
bad news taker
what so so you guys seen that movie
Naruto I mean the anime so there is this
character I think that's a main
character so he's got the headband with
a spoiler on it so I'm thinking that's
so ancient because of the city and the
character's name is also Naruto is all
right
he's a right guys right right
am i right or incorrect correct or
incorrect and have you guys seen this
anime I have not but you know so this
anime so noob the anime is Japanese I
believe it's quite popular oh okay I
thought I read it and it turns out to be
okay
I thought it's American made in in in a
style of so let's read
okay so Naruto is a Japanese Magna manga
which means cartoon
it's a Japanese manga series written and
illustrated by masked
Masashi Kishimoto it tells the story of
Naruto Uzumaki a young ninja who seeks
to gain recognition from his peers and
also dreams of becoming the hawk Hodge
the leader of his village
the story is in two parts the first set
in Naruto's preteen years okay well okay
so it's a Japanese anime okay so anyway
so Naruto and so I'm thinking I guess
that's that's where the swar came from
okay let me read the comments okay Oh
Naruto run yes I run into that mean
before cuz I was wondering what the
is that
Naruto run let me demonstrate okay like
when you run you run like that you you
run like your hands are made of paper
you know belong belong bye bye wind so
you are you are like a jet hey hey so
did you find a job no why did you say
that the interview they think you can
create loops 8 because when doing a
interview or when talking to people in
general well ok let's doing an interview
I sound like idiot you know I the
impression I give people is like I just
came out of high school and I'm trying
to prove I know how to code that that is
the impression but in fact but you know
to be to tell you the truth you know
some of these interview they are there
you know let me just say they are idiot
so they are common people you know they
well so there are two reasons okay you
know I I I do came out like a high
school student you know because it's
just because the way I am you know just
like the way you actually mean see me
talking and doing things right now
so to know more people you know they
only have one hour to interview you they
don't know you know they they are not
going to look at your website you know
most of them don't because they are busy
they are you know they
okay Google whatever they you know they
are assigned oh there's the interview
you have to do today you have to you
know participate so they just oh you
know is is like it's not something they
are interested so they just you know
most most of them yeah I mean some some
of the interview to preparations that's
good
but anyway so they they don't know
to begin to begin with they are just
like you and me okay they are just
happens to be you know company or
happens to be the manager you know they
you know they are not great computer
scientists or anything oh great oh you
know great programmers they are just
like you so they are just doing a job so
they don't know you so it's your job
when you are doing interview it's your
job to present yourself you have to you
know of course if you have social skills
and you you you have to kind of learn
pick up on those things okay so but for
nerds like me somewhat extreme okay so
we have to put special effort into it
and also it you know it differs from
people from person to person
so so for me if I in the right mood I
can do well but when I'm not in the
right mood especially when I'm like I
need to you know when you are not you
know not in the right situation you
don't do well so in any way you have to
put special effort
so anyway the summary is that I often
came out you know the impression like I
gave people it's just that I just I just
came out of high school and no nothing
so that is why okay and that leads to
sponsorship okay so if you guys like my
stuff
pay you go through my website my son
tree any of my website there is a PayPal
button some way okay so there it is
patreon button patreon button and
you go to my homepage there's PayPal
there's Bitcoin and stuff so put your
money in that bucket okay if you like my
stuff
so let's actually so let's go back to
read comments so yeah let me go read
comments and how long have I been
talking let's see you're 15 people a lot
of people today Wow
yesterday's guy so let me you know so I
have been doing videos every day now for
at least six months now so I have quite
a lot videos you know for example I
don't want that okay so for example
let's go to I'm going to read the
comments seeing a bit okay so post
questions or comments post just post it
so if you go to my talk show what what I
was I going to say I was you know I've
been doing videos for half a year now
more than half a year everyday almost
basically every day so half a year
that's six months and every month is 30
days so 6 times 30 I have 180 videos
each one is about one hour or more in
fact more than 100 you know so I have
like 200 videos and I have talked quite
a lot of things and sometimes you know
like yesterday I got a question
sometimes I don't I missed some comments
like you have a question especially if
you are new sometimes I you know it's
because there are so many comments I
missed your comments so yesterday
someone asked me about my opinion on
modern JavaScript frameworks such as
react web pack angular and you know a
bunch of others so actually I did I did
two or three videos on that so you know
you can always you you could try to
watch my old videos you know you could
try because they are they you know they
are Co me they are still my opinions
just because they are done
yesterday is you know you can try to
watch them yeah so that's about that so
you know there's some so many videos and
I've done now there are 200 of them so
many topics you know so let's see where
we are
so I've been talking for 40 minutes and
let's see what subject we've been talked
about and it's just like kind of
summarize the things
okay now root of anime close that
fishcake swore because that fish cakes
war is related to the Naruto city okay
it came from Naruto city
famous for its whirlpool now hope or is
a fascinating thing for pool now you see
cool pool you know I haven't read this
article yet but I'm going to read it in
detail you know by the way on Wikipedia
you can read about pools they have
they have huge amount of pictures on
pours because I remember I read
that five years ago so fascinating ho
pause so you can see this is a stupid
small picture you know they are hopefuls
over the earth and some of them are like
comma for pools so you know you see here
and of course Wikipedia will tell you
why it occurs things like that
let's see so yeah so there is okay this
is a man-made one okay out of a sink but
but I remember seeing quite a lot
fantastic photos it's not here okay but
yeah it's not here I don't remember what
page I was reading but some a few years
ago I remember seeing quite a lot
collection of hope all photos so hope or
clothes that go back to Emacs pace it
here and I'm going to read comments okay
so close that so post your comments now
this is my master done close that so
this is a Unicode Unicode fish cake
that's the ancient of it all close that
and Ireland and Northern Ireland is it's
quite interesting so Northern Ireland is
part of the United Kingdom but not
Ireland why is that so what is the
history
of that I don't know so let's write it
down
nothing Ireland
okay Northern Ireland versus Ireland so
I might read it offline you know I might
go wander and read it offline so we were
talking about fish cake fish ball yeah
so close that fish cake fantastic close
that close that close that close that
Colson and this is my photo of hotpot
and those are fish balls and fish cake
okay so what so comments okay let me
read the comments from the top so a
command pong that is delicious stuff
I've had it in Chengdu China Ackman pong
are you Chinese Oh 10 now Oh 10 is a
Japanese word I think it refers to I'm
not sure exactly what I mean it refers
to a stick oh then let's see
so oh 10 is a type of number Mon no one
part dishes consists consisting of
several ingredients such as spoiled eggs
daikon konjac I don't know what they are
when processed fish cakes stood in a
light something something okay I don't
know exactly what that not familiar with
this okay let's see what's the Chinese
term for it because sometimes if I read
Chinese
I understand it okay Quan don't you okay
so
so it seems like it's a hot pot but just
for one person something okay I don't
know what you saw then so now be young
is from Navi young is from well you Pony
USA or Korea but I know you were when
you were small you live in Korea but
Nabi
Nabi is a you know mixed race anyway I'm
not sure I should talk too much about
you guys personal details I mean your
and is the public info that you guys
told me about anyway so Dan that's scary
the hopeful yeah looks like faster
actually what faster Mota I've only seen
crap sticks in my supermarket yeah
there's crab sticks from no way okay
crab sticks are you we yeah okay so new
guys I don't know who you guys saw so
the anime is Japanese I believe okay
quite popular okay so now B says my
coworker talked about that anime
sometimes I'm never seeing it okay
the Naruto now he says he's see only
Naruto I've heard of they talk about
some Naruto run okay yeah so am i anime
says hey so did you find a job okay we
talked about that
Jason says you've been practicing that I
think yes about my about articulation
skills social skills it's not you know
each person has problems okay you me
anyway it's a complicated story social
skills that's something I can slot a
chip for a MRI says seem legit for me
most people can see beneath the surface
yeah
so Campbell says I saw you didn't like
any of the Emax and do we do rappers I
found they were all perky buggy - you
know it's not like so my opinion on that
changed over the past you know 15 years
so okay let me let me give you a short
history of my take on the Emax and do we
do packages okay so I began to use emacs
in 2000 in 1998 okay let me write it
down my opinion on Emacs and to redo
okay so I begin to use Emacs in 1998 by
I live in Emacs everything I do is
inside the Emacs okay that's 1999 so 20
years ago in the 6th in the first six or
seven years okay up to 2006 I just use
Emacs and do okay I don't you know just
I just use the default it just I don't
worry about it I mean it's it just works
okay but since about 2007 or so 2007 to
2012 something like that I find you know
I that's when I started to get into
Emacs Lisp I started to Cody Magnus and
you know I started to dig into lots of
the Emacs things why it should be that
way
why you know which interface is better
is is is the Emacs and do better or the
common conventional and do better things
like that I studied quite a lot of that
in fact let me show you a series of
articles a article collection so you go
to casali Emacs websites such as such
folk sorry
Emacs so you will see my website then
you go to Emacs modernization
so there is a collection of 40 articles
here 40 okay that's not all they are
quite a lot others in some of the
indexes so I have a collection of
articles which is about so-called
research you know you can call them
research you know I don't like that word
okay just it's just my study okay my
study of the of the Emax of the many
details many details on do out on GUI on
user interface on which way is better on
so many issues okay so so anyway
beginning beginning around 2006 I
started to code learn eMac list and I
also started to dive into many of these
issues and I read I write articles about
them so if you don't know already that
Emacs and do is very different from the
typical conventional and do that you
guys are used to you know our typical
software Photoshop or other editors
anywhere anywhere else outside of Emacs
you can undo and do and do and you can
redo okay there's a key to redo okay and
do and do and do we do but remember once
you redo once you do what we do what
once you yeah once you do what we do you
lost whatever and do you had before so
for example you and do so you know you
begin here so let me show you okay so
you begin here you do something to do do
something something something okay then
you and do and do and do okay now you
try to redo okay you redo then you start
to okay you say this is good then you
start to type okay now once you start to
type whatever before that and do is all
good this is the conventional way
you can do and we do once you redo and
start to start from there
you lost or your previous induce this is
so for basically all software now Emacs
is a bit different the Emacs phonetics
they like to say Emacs is superior
because Emacs Emacs do not have a redo
command so there's no redo so what you
have is just undo everything you do is
saved as an undo log so you you can undo
and do and do
there's no redo okay if you want to redo
you type something first you type
something then you then you undo that
then it start to go in this direction
okay it's very complex okay that's the
thing Emacs and do in some technical
sense is superior because you never lose
any historical and do you can always
undo to to the arrangement to to the
arrangement okay but but it's very
counterintuitive it's hard to it's a
it's like a roller coaster so you you
and do and do and do there is no redo
command if you want to redo you type
something you then you and do that
basically the needle goes backwards
until there's no more and do then it
goes backward again so it's it's rather
it's even hard to explain but if you
want to know the details of that I have
a arco here the first arc of simple
modernization of Emacs simple changes
Emacs should adopt okay there is a
section or undo this frequently asked
questions where I I fight with this
Emacs idiots this you know I've
been fighting with the Emacs people for
20 years that's why they call me at row
they are idiots they are the
people who do harm to Emacs they are the
people who prevent Emacs from becoming
popular they
the okay and it's exaggerating
a little bit
but that's essentially what I you know
they are not okay but they are
they are this they are this kind of nerd
this you know very niche not a hacker
you know the hacker typically like UNIX
philosophy you know Linux open-source
chanting UNIX philosophy these type of
people they anyway they are this group
they are responsible for keeping Emacs
in a niche forever this that's their
opinion their behavior their perception
of the world in my opinion they are this
group of people that's why Emacs is
forever in this niche forever it's going
to be that like like that forever you
will not become popular okay and and
many of their beliefs and opinions are
blatantly just wrong just incorrect
factually scientifically incorrect okay
that's this Emacs phonetics that's by
the way that's my opinion okay if you
are watching a talk show you probably
already know that okay I'm a bit
different they call me a troll I've been
fighting with them for twenty years
basically but by the way in anyway let
me just mention they are I'm not saying
they're bad people they are good people
okay just that I'm talking about the
this you know like like like VI versus
Emacs or which language is the best you
know they are nerds fighting among notes
the flame wars
okay so in this in this perspective I
mean this context I'm saying they are
heads because I don't I do not
agree with their opinions I do not agree
with their opinions about Lisp about
basically about coding format style they
I think they are idiots to the extreme
okay and I stand I stand to my opinions
to this day you ask any computer
scientists
or any any statistical scientific you
check the facts you know I I will say
you will find that their opinions are
idiots they are incorrect so anyway back
to the Emacs undo so around 2006 I
started to you know dig into all the
details about Emacs then then it is my
opinion that Emacs and do in some
technical sense is superior but it's
actually no good it's no good okay it's
no good the better system is the
conventional and do and we do and do and
we do yeah when you want you to and we
do you lost history but that's ok
because in real life in practice all
things consider this is a better system
because you never like you don't need to
undo like like in some tech nerd sense I
I need to have a undo record from the
day I was pong you don't need that ok
you are doing do and and and to the
point you that's the point you want you
start to do things we do and and that's
you know you don't need a history so in
my opinion the conventional and do redo
system is better
Emacs should change ok Emacs should
change uses the change it
the Emacs developers you know they
should change it ok that is my opinion
from 2006 to 2012 ok it's a bit
complicated but let me let me continue
that ok then then so there are many
packages you know this in this nerds
they self conflict with their theories
because if Emacs and do is better than
why you have so many packages trying to
do trying to make Emacs and do to be the
conventional yeah there's so many
conflicting you know things of this nuts
hacker type of thing anyway they're over
the past 20 years there are several
there are several packages that try
- makes Emax induce behavior to be
similar you know to the conventional and
do system so so you have undo and you
have redo so I that so I've been using
that for 10 years studying around 2007
or so
but it turns out they all have problems
they have a serious problem major
problem that is undo corruption that is
for example if you are working on
something okay and you try to do
something and and you and do and do you
try to undo and whoops it says there's
no and do record no more and do but
actually you know there's and dude you
just did something you want to and do it
but Emacs cannot undo it because it says
no there's no one do that's a bug okay
that's a that's a corruption of the do
log so when that happens that's a
serious problem because you are relying
on you know you in your mind you know
this undo so you want you made a big
change and use you think oh that
actually I don't want this I want to go
back and you press then do key but but
but you can't undo this is the
think and and do anymore so that's a
major bug so you don't want that when
this happens it's a major thing so it
turns out all these packages over the
years there's quite a few okay so let's
go to you know the maybe show you okay
sorry Emacs and do just search for that
you'll find my heart goes okay so so
there it is so this is written like this
is written in 2011 seven eight years ago
so this article I say this and do we do
mod okay so anyway there are this we do
that year by Kyle Jones which is old you
know he's you know since 1997 and this
we do plus 30 L originally by Cal and
updated by s si Ryoga in 2008
there is undo tree that yeah by tobiko
'but he he is a mathematician in 2009 ok
so you see this and do packages they
they all try to do the same thing
they are all trying to add a redo
command to Emacs so that and in business
so that you know so the Emacs and do
behaves like a conventional and do it's
more intuitive and it turns out they all
have this problem and do corruption like
I'm Pradeep unpredictably like this bug
is usually it's not pretty predictable
like you cannot be producing it's hard
so you you are working with your stuff
and and pen one day there is no and do
yeah and this is emits a major problem
so this is a issue ok so I realized you
know it happens to all of them
it doesn't happen very often but every
every few months or maybe maybe every
few months but when it happens it's a
big big thing because you do need to go
back to and do you don't have a you know
a backup or something you know yeah you
have kids you know you have kid but but
the kid state is like it's not the state
you want you know basically so this is a
major problem ok so once I discover this
in in you know in in I forgot what date
in 2015 or something they all have this
problem when it happens it's stun his
things you so I stopped using any any of
them I stopped using any of them I just
use the Emacs default and do system it
it works you know
it's it's not and it's not intuitive but
once you can get used to it any works
and so that is my that is my experience
with the Emacs and ooh ok so actually
that's a big rant and I think that's it
for
so my ultimate opinion about whether
Emacs and do should be the Emacs and do
or should be conventional I you know now
I'm now I'm getting used to the Emacs
and do it's not a big problem but here's
okay here's what I say okay if you want
Emacs to be popular go with the
conventional and do that is not these
packages okay because this ndu
is a fundamental feature you cannot fix
it by creating a package that is why all
these packages have problems it cannot
be fixed
you need the Emacs the developers you
know you guys you know maybe some of you
guys you need the developers to change
at the call to change the Emacs and do
throw it out and do the conventional and
do that is what you need to do if you
want to fix this problem so if you have
the conventional and do Emacs is one of
the things that we all makes Emacs more
popular okay yeah that's what I say
so anyway that that is my opinion and
experience about Emacs and do and I
think that concludes today's random talk
I have 17 people Wow every time I do a
rant this more people staying sane for
my swearing and stuff so let's see so
yeah that is my opinion can bear Barton
Way from are you free from Sohn Abby
says I see them every time I use the
restroom it's different actually the
live stream is blurry but I think you
are looking of Japanese Odin I was
smelling USA nolo I lived in Korea after
I graduate college oh okay so I was
referring
so how do you like Korea so how long you
lived there and how do you like it some
essays I was referring to that fish face
you showed earlier okay now I don't know
what you are referring to what comment I
was commenting about your comments okay
anyway Mota okay I think Mota I was
referring to the fish face you showed
earlier against oh yeah the the fish
paste the in my paw I think in my this
one I think so I think that's it for
today so thank you guys for coming and
yeah one hour and do we do thing is like
graft versus array yeah kind of yeah
so Campbell Barton says yes I've been
using Emacs and do for quite some time
it's okay but we do can be added into it
without losing this advanced
functionality that is what I've done
yeah but you know these oldest we do
packages they they have a problem of
corrupting go and do log so the
annoyances with not having redo is that
it's useful to hold down way we do key
to get the ladies to the state no you
can do that you know in the Emax and do
system you just base actually you just
press ctrl-g you know then then you can
hold down and do it actually where do we
do you know so it's confusing that's all
they are not that many packages and do
treat and do it this street so that's
not fairly separate well that's that's
that's many enough we got three of them
so yes corrupting undo date data is
insanely bad and unacceptable that's
right
so I ran into this with we do process
and and do
tree yeah exactly because when I
discovered and do tree my reaction is Oh
finally there is this you know
well-written package by this
mathematician which is also dedicated
you know I think you know he you know I
think he knows what he's doing you know
he's a you know and I've you know so you
not only you have the Emacs system of
and do of the whole record but also you
have the conventional power of we do so
I thought it was great but it also have
this corruption problem problem
the the he makes people you
know because he you know why am i angry
because I'm angry I'm angry at these
nerds this not nuts
the hacker types about UNIX
philosophy chanting you used to be /
okay chanting about open source until
each and every day so why am i angry for
example this undo issue now after 10
years I spent 10 years hourly
you know not hourly I spend whole day
mad basically for each problem it's it
you you don't just know it right away it
come with the high cost you know like
for example me I digging into Emacs for
now 20 years this is a problem you know
and dude tree and do tree itself has
this corruption problem if you know at
first I realized so I thought maybe I
did something wrong because I also code
it eMac B's because maybe I did
something that something I don't know
so you have to go ask or something but
then after a few years thing you see
people post on reddit okay then when
people post they don't know either they
don't know the answer but they say okay
I got this problem what what is problem
so I you know because I'm also Emacs not
like that makes many of us we read you
know we spend hours you know to read all
this reddit community Emacs news in you
know so we saw that oh a new trick on a
problem oh oh
then people start to talk can you give
detail or some people say there's no
problem you know nobody actually know so
it's like discussion discussion then no
conclusion can no conclusion then next
year two years later some somebody
posted more reddit you know then
eventually we know yeah it's a got a
problem with a new tree it cuz
there's a cost to that and meanwhile all
this well every time every time this
come up this is one of the sensitive
issues of Emacs you know controversial
because every time this come up then you
have this a bunch of Emacs fanatics they
will you know they will become a flame
flame war it's like oh yeah max is the
superior Emacs ndu is a superior
superior system because you can do the
logs of idiots these heads
so that you know you are seeing me
that's why they call me a troll you know
I I have disagreement with these people
for 20 years so why I am angry you know
actually I'm not angry okay it's not
like I mean you know it's not like I
cannot help it you know it's not like
you know reactionary or something I'm
and I'm not you know I'm I'm expressing
anger because I'm I'm a nerd you know
I'm a I'm a more than you are
then they know this Emacs people are
they spend hours hours you know doing
living in max they think they know stuff
I spent 10 times more than them
and more nerds than them I sit in this
chair more than you know like I
mentioned this before if you measure by
statistic see statistically who sits on
the chair on average more than anyone I
would rank like I'm kind of very weird
top 1000 in USA something like that then
I just read all day you know I read
Wikipedia all day for the past you know
I I have like 7,000
to Wikipedia for my website I've showed
that many times you know so so they so
they so what I'm at my point is that
yeah so I was saying why am I like that
because I'm a nerd that's that's why you
know I mean to arguing just for the
argument's sake I want you know what if
something is correct I mean if one plus
one is is two and someone is saying or
thinking that one plus one is three I
have to correct it okay that is my
that's that's what we are no it's okay
we have to do this we just have to
because some somewhere else on the
internet is wrong okay but I happens to
be more severe than you you
know those who I disagree they ads
and they are just they just don't by any
means anyway so that that is why okay
that's that is why you see you know
because a lot other people they wonder
why are you like that or something like
that you know because I'm not that's
that's not that's that is my nature
okay I'm about to close and close out in
two minutes okay so if you testing our
state of documents so comeback was
sometimes you can and we do and if you
saved you can get to the recent state
yeah so if you testing on old state of
the document for for example yeah so
jason says mean does a good job with
undo redo in my opinion but just a
simple you to and do and control to redo
problem with them is they many
manipulator internal and do data so now
he says eMac says cui key that could
change you and do to know the okay Nabby
the cui key is one of the most
in eMac so they okay is a cui key
that you know the Emacs people that's
another grand okay that's another rant
for another day and and the see the the
Emacs P that's actually the first thing
Emacs people want to change okay so let
me let me just some
it's okay you read this article simple
changes in acts should adopt okay I own
I give like five items only five and
they are trivial to change most of them
you know you can change them in we think
you know they are easy to change if you
change them in emacs step not-not-not
buy a package
okay change them in Akko of Emax
change the call from the miracle of
Emacs you change them I will I guarantee
that
Emacs will turbo its users within within
one year okay I can guarantee that yeah
and and this article is oh this article
is written in 2006 you know so it's 15
years old I know it's not going anywhere
it's not going to happen it's just the
reason you know you know that's another
statement okay in one of the change in
fact the most important change of all
things consider if I can just say one
thing
Emacs you change that is change it's
key bindings make control x2 do
cut ctrl C should be copy okay just make
that change in in corvy max not see you
I see you i packaging see
you I see you a package has its has many
problems just like the new packages it
it doesn't walk often it it creates
complexities this doesn't walk so any
anyway that's that's the you know cui
key that should change that's a number
one thing ok so Australia so Campbell
Campbell is from Australia so I lived
there for two years I liked it
oh ok Korea ok so great you know X even
says we do in the mini buffer you assume
undo package must corrupt data I found a
way to have unduly to without messing
with the internals I linked it to above
where's your link you know YouTube
has a problem that they often prevent
you from posting links so I cannot see
your link so if you want to post it
coach Joe enjoin this code okay join
this code and post here you know joining
my disco channel okay so let me go to
shut up and let's get the discord okay
that's it for today thank you guys for
coming and see you next time so Campbell
says I spent more time writing we do and
have been using it it works nicely
didn't mean to start your rant just
saying it can walk without buggy baggage
okay so you think it can walk maybe I
don't know for sure because there are
three people three good Emacs hackers I
cannot say their well I can say these
two of them I know I trust their code
okay they they've tried to do it and
they both they failed you know we have
like you know these three people Kyle
Jones is old eMac this hacker you know
he's been using Emacs since before
ninety you know he wrote and do packet
b2 package in 1997 he's been using Emacs
before that anyway so but but you are
saying you know your new package package
may work right you know it's possible
because it's possible yeah so maybe in
fact it might be trivia because maybe
because all these packages they try to
kind of try to like have fancy features
for example the intrude and do tree you
know he's trying to make a fancy feature
so you actually have a tree you're
nuts
you know the year so you haven't do you
have like on do tree this
idiot hacker nerds types they think they
think the more feature the more is more
is better they thinking that way you
know these nuts hacker types okay thank
you guys for watching and bye that's it
for today okay so yeah so join this code
and paste your link okay I'm not going
to use it for sure because I'm too old
you know I am too old for you know I
don't pick up yeah I told you you'd
YouTube hide your link so you have to
it's not yeah person on this code so
shutting down bye guys 1 hour and 18
minutes