good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of s talk show we are going to
code wolam language Mathematica today
so so this is so this is what we are
going to code this is a package I wrote
uh about 30 years ago this is uh par
plot
uh
enhanced uh functions for plotting
parametric equations for Mathematica so
let me show you some graphics so um for
example you can plot this is called
costic basically array reflected around
a uh reflected U from a curve so this is
a parabola so this is a typical lamp
situation so costic so you can see many
of the properties that's what this
package do it just generates these
Graphics allows allows you to plot these
graphics for visualization of geometry
and uh and for educational purposes so I
wrote this like around 1994 to
1997 and uh so it's been 30 years
basically or 25
and uh I've been the last time I updated
this package is about 2004
so so I'm revisit you know revisiting
this package it's been 30 years there's
a lot of changes in wfam language and uh
but most of them vast Maj I mean it
still works you see
so so that's some of the graphics let me
so and let me show you okay
so
so if you want to see you know this is
one of my most popular uh website visual
dictionary of special plan curves it's
been linked from University math
departments like from a thousands of
websites back in back in 1990 from 1997
to from 1998 to
2008 but basically Wikipedia took over
and other websit
since 2010 or so so so all these
Graphics are done mostly in
1997 and uh you know it it was cutting
edge technology um and and today I'm
going to update them you know so a lot
code you know wolam language has been
evolving for 30 years and uh uh
so so there are some impr improvements I
can make to the package so uh for
example here is the source code okay so
here's a source code uh so this is a
file
p.m you open it this is a wolam language
code or also known as
Mathematica okay
so and uh you know so here's a source
code source code here's a inline
documentation and let's go down so here
is the
code the this is a code for drawing
normal lines and this is and uh and then
here's a code for doing drawing tangent
lines uh this is a parallel curve and uh
this is CICS we have just shown here is
kind of the code for drawing costic
lines costic meaning reflection of rays
like
this so I'm going to update the code
okay so this is just going to be me
coding it's probably boring for you guys
um yeah am I am I uh live yeah I think
so okay so I'm just going to code it uh
yeah so about wam language Mathematica
if you don't know yet you know just
search
forar Wan language or
Mathematica and you can find find uh my
tutorials you go there W from language
Mathematica tutorials and you can
download wam language for free uh it
will it began to be free about four
years ago or five so you can download
there and some information I tell you
what they are what it is about and from
this tutorial you can learn the
complete tutorial for programmers if you
are familiar with JavaScript python see
C C++ Java any of the language if you
are already a programmer then you can
learn from my tutorial from the
groundup uh and mostly I teach
you understand how wam language works
because wolam language is a term
rewriting system it's a function of
programming language and term rewriting
system you likely have never seen in any
other language not in hascal not in lisp
um uh in a way it's kind of like list
maral so imagine every function you
write is list maros it's kind of like
that okay so except the list maros is
far more advanced it's symbolic pattern
matching so imagine if you are coding
lisp every function is defined by a
marro and you have very Advanced pattern
matching symbolic matching for Marco
that is what kind of it's like in wfam
language okay so that's a introduction
you can read the tutorial to learn it so
I'm and download it uh and I'm going to
start
to code it okay so this is mostly just
for
myself oh we have six concurrent viewers
so if you are here say hi if you have
some questions about wam language or
Mathematica ask me okay hello
reu okay so let's code so let me tell
you what I'm going to do okay
so
um so here is a source code you can view
the source code in wolam language so you
know so here is how it looks like in
wolam
language uh let's magnify okay so here's
a documentation copyright
uh okay and here is the inline
documentation let's go down go down go
down go down go down go down go down go
down go down go down go down so here is
starting to have code this begin is to
declare a name space so you are starting
you know I'm starting my own name space
you know basically this is this is like
writing a library in python or Java
so anyway documentation so here's code
so you can see here's
code um okay so this file is par plot. M
okay so that's this
file and uh let me just let me just
start to code uh let me focus on what I
need to do then maybe I explain what I'm
doing
okay so anyway so this package has been
almost like 15 years I haven't touched
it
so you know this so there is quite a few
changes in wfam language has added about
a thousand more functions so you know
actually wam language has added 5,000
something around 5,000 functions since
20 years ago uh so there is quite a lot
to do and uh also so in the past 30
years there's a lot changes in Computing
in in you know in in Hardware CPU GPU
and uh the style of documentation the
wording you know the the word is
different from 20 years ago because 20
years ago you don't even have Wikipedia
and you barely have the internet so when
you need to know mathematics you know B
basically you read textbooks so it's not
like today today you have cell phones
and everything so this
um wam language has also added a lot of
additions and some incompatible changes
there's some so this a lot to change
reward the documentation and so
on so let me let me let me get to what I
want to do okay
so okay so this file is M MB okay so
this is my original source code
um let's see what I how I want to do
this what I want to
do if I just started to do what I need
to do then you you won't understand
anything uh this is a description of
this video I mean this is what this is
the purpose of today's live stream I'm
just going to code my stuff you won't
understand the thing it's just like in a
real life programming project at at at a
job you know it even takes an hour to
explain to let any Outsider to
understand what you are doing uh because
you know so it's like real life coding
but however I'm going to
try to explain some part of it so at
least you get some sense of what I'm
doing what I need to do
um okay let's let's focus let's
let me show you let's start to load
wolam language from the ground up okay
so I there's some bug I need to fix for
example let me show you some bugs okay
so you can see all these are
fine you can you can see all these are
fine but however you see this got a pink
background that means there's a there's
some error so if you click on that you
can see coordinate in the coordinate in
determinate in terminate should be a
real uh pair of numbers or a scale of
offset form basically you
got basically division by zero so when
you compute this
curve uh this curve is interesting okay
it's called
cycloid it's this curve anyways this so
there's quite a lot things to
explain so this curve is called cycloid
okay so let's let let me just demo then
so you go to visual dictionary of
special CL plane curves then you go to
cycloid
um okay there it is Cy cycloid so this
curve is what happens if you roll a
circle on a line and you trace out the a
point on a wheel on a circle so this is
a cycle cycle
and it's one of the very famous curve
about 200 years ago because this curve
is a solution to you know imagine if you
have a
ball and you have a slope you drop the
ball the ball will roll down right so
obviously the higher the angle of
inclination the ball will reach to the
ground faster
but however if you make the slope curved
will it reach the ground faster than a
straight slope or even if you you know
so what what is the shape of the curve
such that if you drop the drop the ball
it will roll down the fastest Accord by
the laws of physics so it turns out the
solution of that slope is this this
curve called cycloid and you can
generate this Cur by Rolling a circle so
lots of calculus this is this problem
belongs to the calculus of variation so
this is uh interesting part of
calculus typically you don't learn that
you know they don't tell you these
interesting things in school so anyway
so this
curve but then you can generate what's
called a
um
oh this is the this is the evolute yeah
okay so you can generate the evolute of
the curve and the evolute of a cycloid
is itself so anyway that's that's that's
um that's a lot math I won't go into if
you want to read it you can click here
and understand what evolute is about so
there's a visual animation you can
understand what's the evolute so this
animation is showing the evolute of an
elisp so this this red dots traced out
is the evolute of a
elisp okay so then the evolute of a
cycloid is itself so for example this
blue curve the evolute is this red one
is is it itself then the evolute of that
is again you know itself so that's why
you know so that's what this codee is
trying to do is is is trying to
illustrate the evolute of a
cycloid okay but now it's got error so
you see we got some somewhere in a
computation we got
a uh basically division by zero like
one/ zero so in the in determinant so
that's a bug you know it wasn't this I
don't have this bug like 20 years ago
but somehow you know the current version
of wolf language I have that bug so we I
need to fix that okay so that's one of
the things I need to fix let's
see let's focus on that let's see if I
can fix this bug today uh that would be
the focus of this video you see the bug
happened here
again uh and uh and there are some other
bugs so for example this this
expression you are supposed to the
result should be like this okay this
should be the result it shows
the it shows the
um inversion of a hyperbola okay it
should this should be the result but
however if you plot it now you get this
instead so something is wrong so
basically this two bugs I believe this
two bugs is um is what I need to fix
okay so let's just focus on doing
that okay
so close that don't
save and let's start wam language close
that don't save start from the
beginning okay launch
it so do you think it's possible to make
a game using wolf and math plots yes of
course now there are two separate
questions is it possible to create a
game
using uh the ideas of geometry in
particular plating curves or more
specifically surfaces when you have
surfaces oh my God it's pure it's
amazing
okay uh let me talk about that
so it is not just possible it would be
amazing it would be one of the best
seller if you create a 3D game because I
I have been wanting to do that for for a
long time for like 20 years ago I was
thinking about that but I don't know how
to write again despite I try to learn it
it's very complex the open G stuff but
so if you create a game with idea of
either curves or more specifically I
have in mind uh 3D surfaces you are
going to have a
spectacular uh 3D game okay like the you
know like today's 3D game you can walk
inside it you can move
around it would be spectacular I'm going
to show you a few of that uh of the idea
okay so yeah but we just need someone to
write it but some games they already
employ some of the idea for example in
Zelda back in 1999 Zelda
64 okay you have this character link
that goes through a t a tunel okay so
Zelda
64 game
play uh H this Brave search is no
good so let's go to
Google
so let me keep focused I want to talk
about something okay so it is certainly
fantastic if you create a game with ma
mathematical
ideas now however you are talking about
wolam language can you use wolam
language to create search again yeah you
can but like it's not good okay you can
use wolam language in the notebook you
can create a game like
like Tetris that sort of thing but if
you want to create a 3D game like the
you know the type of games you are
familiar with no you cannot do that with
wam language and you don't want to do
that with wam language okay so wolam
language is not for that you know for
that you go to C++ things like that so
in Zelda you have you know so you have
this link character and in this game you
have link go through a tunnel so you go
inside the tunnel then the tunnel become
twist twisted it's like you know upside
down twisting then you come out from the
tunnel to some other side so that is a
incredible idea using the idea of
threedimensional
uh curves and surfaces three dimensional
surfaces okay so let me show you let me
finish talking about that and let's get
back to the wolfen language code um so
for example here are some of some of the
surfaces and for example I want to show
you
um minimal surfaces minimal surfaces is
most spectacular okay so for example
this uh let me show you this
one okay so for for example this one now
this this is a minimal surface so it's a
three-dimensional surface so as you can
see it's kind of symmetric and you got
this holse in it so now imagine imagine
the Zelda game or whatever shooter game
or whatever so you your your character
works inside this hole that's an
interesting interesting thing about
these surfaces because this surface
divides the 3D space into several
sections now some of the surface so you
have to imagine this surface extends all
over so it's this is just showing part
of
it now some of it is uh periodic okay so
let me show you an example here's
another example again this is this
expands to all all the space so you got
this hole so you see you got this hole
this hole gets you into this like a
second store
store you know story then you go around
then you drop into that hole gets to to
get you to the next floor so this this
surface you know it's like a
screw it fills the space so you can go
around different um floors kind
of it partitions the 3D space
into in fact it's it doesn't partition
because uh wait does it yes it does I I
think it does it partition the space
into
two spaces separate from each other you
can never go from one space to the other
you see because this
hole Yeah so you can look at this hole
actually drops you to this
floor but on this floor dropped you to
the so basically you have even floors
and odd
floors you can go from any even floor to
another even floor but you can never
reach the odd floors so this is why it
is interesting so imagine now imagine if
you are the you
know uh a character in the 3D game you
can you cannot get to the other side you
see unless unless maybe there's a hole
there so that's you know that makes it a
puzzle uh By the way when you when you
move like a human you know you walk
around buildings
without without getting a over a bird's
eyes view of the whole map you know in
game usually you have a little map
that's kind of like cheating right
because in reality you don't get a map
like that unless today you you know you
have iPhone you know you you use a
uh you know you have Google
Maps but in real life you you know
without this smap technology you don't
have that so you don't know which room
goes where like in a
puzzle
uh so let me just show you some pictures
to illustrate the idea so like a
labyrinth right without a overview from
above you don't know where you are so
when in that situation you have to rely
on your senses like when did you turn or
leave a thread so that's called dead
reckoning okay that kind of navigation
is called called uh dead reckoning okay
very interesting so now imagine now you
know
you you know we are familiar with these
Labyrinth kind of 2D puzzles but now
imagine in a 3D case 3D case you have
this you know so it's very it it it kind
of makes the interesting level to the
next level so you have to realize you
have to kind of relying on your senses
to
determine whether you can get to the
other side or how many different sides
are there things like that so that's
another example there quite a few uh let
me show you for example this
one this one you know this is called uh
Casher J saddle Tower Casher is a German
geometer it's a one of the top geometer
specializing in minimal surfaces he
taught me a lot mathematics you know so
in this so for example there's also that
one so this kind of surfaces partition
the space into weird you know
compartments so I think it makes it very
interesting and you have things like
that it's hard to imagine how exactly
this expands but you know that's one of
the and you you have G gyroid and today
you know with Wikipedia you have lots of
better uh images you see so this is
another minimal surface so you have so
many holes so that's very interesting
okay so that's one of the thing I've
been thinking of doing but I don't think
think I'll ever do it because I'm
getting old so we need someone to you
know get expert to to work on this idea
okay yeah so back to the question if
you're going to yeah you can do that but
if if can you do that with Mathematica
no you want no you you need to use a
game engine
okay or you even need to um anyway so uh
I'm going to stop there because
otherwise I'll it'll be nonstop so
that's about that
um so by the way all these all these
Graphics you see here are generated uh
by wolam
language uh I did them like long time
ago 20 years
ago uh except some of them are generated
by my professor my friend and Mentor
Professor Richard palet you know many of
these uh
his uh you know his his uh 3D explore
math that's his software okay so anyway
so that's about that's some interesting
things about
um you know differential geometry
threedimensional
surfaces uh idea in games okay let's get
back uh and we talked about Deb
Reckoning Labyrinth
gyroid geometry okay
Zelda uh let's get back to what I I need
to do okay
so uh okay so yeah let's start wolam
language let's begin to Let's load it
okay so it's started now close it don't
save now let's go to the
directory and uh let's open my package
open it
okay so here is my package now select
all
rning okay so here's all the
code and it's done okay now open the
examples open
it okay
documentation now let's
so so for example let's delete that and
run it do you want to automatically
evaluate all initialization cells no
because we already loaded so this is
what this package does it can draw a
parametric curve
but using the color variation to show
where does the curve begin so normally
if you do this in wam language
um I'm not sure it can do it today but I
don't think
so uh parametric
plot okay so if you use wolam language
you get this you don't get you don't
know where where's the beginning of the
curve where's the end
so my package add adds that enhancement
okay
so so it works let's let's just run
another example okay delete that do it
okay
uh delete
that do it
okay
uh now this is also let's run it okay so
each time it generates a different
color
okay so but I want
to yeah let's get to one of the error
problems so for example
here delete
that run it okay you got error
click
indetermined coordinate okay so let's
fix this let's
see H evolute is kind of difficult
so yeah I think so how long have I been
30 minutes I think I'm just going to
start to
code
um so evolute so let's look at my
package search for
evolute now I I wrote this long time ago
so some of the ideas I don't remember
off hand
uh
okay now where is aute defined
what okay I don't
want yeah okay
so so anyway let me see the comments Sam
Hammer
hey okay so what I want to do
[Music]
so let's
see so all these error so let's see you
know so all this error error is about
indeterminate basically one divided by
zero somewhere
and uh it
happens when you plot
evolute okay so what is evolute let me
let me let me try to explain what is
evolute okay
so the evolute
is okay so let's go
to
PL curves go down go
down uh you have a page explaining
evolute okay there evolute is
basically the center
of osculating circle okay so you can see
the blue curve is
elisp and
uh so let me let me see if I can expand
this okay
so
so if you have a curve like that you
know you know the concept of a tangent
right so if you have a point on the
curve the line
closest to that curve approximate that
curve at that point is called tangent so
for example here the tangent line would
be here here the tangent line would be
like that okay so that's called the
tangent of a point on a curve now
there's another concept similar to that
you see when you have a curve you see
some points on a curve at that point the
curve is more curved for example if you
have a point here the point there is not
too much of a curve it's rather you know
there's no curve but over here it's very
highly
curved so if you have a curve with a
sharp turn you know then then another
sharp turn you see this point this point
is very tight on the other hand this
point is not so tight you
know something like that okay
tight so so this a concept of curvature
so the more tight curvature is basically
at any point on the curve it measures
how tight is the curve how sharp a turn
is at that point okay so that's called
curvature curvature of a curve and uh
and then you
can you can use a circle to approximate
that coverture to illustrate for example
you know so here the this illustration
shows
that
now so at any point on a curve you can
have a circle this circle is called
ulating Circle ulate means kiss so it's
a kissing Circle in other in in other
words it's a circle that
kisses the point on the
curve you know so if the turning point
point is very tight then your ulating
circle is very small when the
the the the point is not very tight then
the circle is very
large so this is osculating circle so on
any point on the curve you have a
osculating circle at that point then
once you have a Circle you have a center
of that Circle so the trace of the
center of the circle is called the
evolute of the of the given curve okay
so again let me repeat given a
curve on any point on the curve you have
a circle called oscillating Circle
Associated at that point and this circle
has a
center so
of all the centers of the oing Circle
forms another curve and this new curve
is called the the evolute of the orinal
curve okay that's
idea
so uh God so we need to dive into the
code
uh I need
to yeah so let's start to dive into the
code shall
we so the the here so in order so to do
that it's best
[Music]
to now I know why this happen
because because if you add
0.1 then you don't have the error you
see this one got
error but this one no error you got a
error because you are starting at zero
when when you start at zero you got this
kind of kind of division by zero
thing so how do you fix that so this is
about
evolute this is about evolute so I don't
even remember my code
evolutes
okay so let's see so that's a
documentation then PL evolute is
false so here you are getting
the the optional value for the evolute
okay so let's
see
okay so far so good yes so the value the
variable is this one p evolute okay now
let's search for
that
so what is this part
doing
so we have a if expression here so let's
highlight the P
evolute okay so all values of P evolute
becomes
yellow now here's the if
statement okay and uh if if this this
and this are
true P equals to that equals to that so
if they are all
Force so plot evolute so we can look
at
for example here's a documentation for
this
option PL
evolute okay
so so evolute of a curve is a low focus
of its Center of curvature
exactly so given a point on a curve we
need to
compute we need to find the point that
is the center of the curvature okay so
that's what we have to do in order for
this code to
work
so the p
here is actually just true or false okay
so that's not exactly what we
want so
if so if it's false then oh there it
is so we are we are trying to compute
velocity Vector list and acceleration
vector list the velocity Vector list is
is
basically
derivatives then the acceleration vector
this is basically second derivatives so
this is
about you know parametric
plot so if you don't know what
parametric plot is let me show
you okay so for example
you say
t let's
magnify let's say uh t t^ s
okay that basically give you a parabola
so now you
say t from 0 to
2 okay so you can kind of see a parabola
Parabola so this is parametric curve so
basically parametric curve is a is
defined by two
functions the first function is over
here the second function is there so x
equals to a function y equals to another
function then the function's value goes
from -2 to two so for
example what if uh what if the second
part is
sign s t then you got a S curve now the
interesting so this normally this is how
a a plot of a function works so you have
the first part is just X they don't
change then the second part is y a
function that's a normal plot now what's
interesting about parametric plot is
that you can make the first function
change so for example let's say
t^2 and s t let's see what we get
okay um uh let's let's make a copy of
that let's do it you see you got this
kind of interesting thing let's see what
happens if negative -2 to 20 okay so it
basically becomes a straight line I mean
kind
u-shaped uh okay very interesting to 10
wow wow very
interesting yeah so you can
see let's say now let's times this by T
what
happens okay so let's say -10 to
10 okay because the square um let's
let's make
it third
power okay so that's the fun thing about
mathematics so you can see it gives you
all kind of Curves
[Laughter]
okay
so so that's about parametric plot so
when you want a so now if you take the
derivative of the first function and
take the derivative of the second
function and so you got two new
functions then you evaluate at many
values T = to -2 -1 and so on that gives
you the
the velocity at that point at the time
T and if you take the second derivative
you get the acceleration value at that
point okay so that's what those means so
what I'm doing here is that you know if
if the user does not request any of
these evolute or whatever then you just
set them
to empty list meaning that you don't
have to compute them because you don't
need it you know the purpose is to plot
the curve so if the user
doesn't doesn't request to plot
evolute uh you know you don't need
so but the user request that then you
need to compute so you can see it's over
here so you got velocity Vector
list okay so
so velocity then acceleration okay so
let's see so velocity let's color it
okay pink then acceleration color it
green okay so you can see velocity is
the first
derivative
okay then the acceleration is so if
these features are requested by user
then you compute the acceler
acceleration list okay so you take the
second derivative okay so we got that
now we understand okay so so this
indetermined
indeterminate error came
from basically came from these two
lines when you
have
so let's see so the evolute
so yeah okay so when you have this curve
you know this cycloid curve at this curp
point you know at this sharp Turning
Point there's no
derivative
so in fact it's either no derivative or
the Der
if is infinite something like that
that's that's why we get this error so
let's
see can you do some fire fire cells no I
don't know what that that is
okay okay so we uh almost got it so so
we can see where this Arrow likely came
from I'm pretty sure it came from one
one of these okay the derivative and
second
derivative but okay so let's think about
this
so you see you avoid the error if you
just increment the t a little bit you
avoid you know Computing at these sharp
turning
points
so
so this this error is actually
inevitable because this error came from
mathematics I mean this you know the the
derivative at that point is not defined
basically you see the you see the
function is this
so if you compute this function starting
at zero what you
get
t0 okay so you got Z 0 right now let's
try it again let's do the derivative
okay
uh okay I haven't done calculus for a
long time for like 20 years
so derivative of a function okay let's
see how we do
this okay so that's that's a
documentation now let's read up about
the I believe that's what you
want okay so give the partial derivative
of a function with respect to X okay
this is what we
want gives a multiple derivative of
that okay
so derivative of this thing two
functions with respect to T what you get
you get that then if you okay so
then if you replace
T by zero you get 0
02 okay uh and but why does
our error come up where does it come
up second
derivative
uh
okay so let's do the second
derivative oh
wait you need to say
yeah
T first
derivative second derivative okay
exactly
uh yeah so the derivative just becomes s
cosine the derivative of a constant is
zero that's right I forgot my calculus
Okay
so okay so back to the code
so so you compute the first dtive
here you got z z Okay then if you
compute a second derivative you
also got z0 for if you start at zero
okay so the problem is not here
because yeah because here we simply have
a list you know this velocity Vector
list or acceleration vector list that
some of their points is zero zero okay
so that doesn't give you problem it
start you you start to have a problem
when you when you divide that by zero or
something divided that by by that okay
so let's
check go to the next occurrence of
velocity Vector list
okay okay
velocity
Vector
Leist
curvature okay curvature is
actually one of the more complex thing
okay that's it
here so now you need to find this
coverture GP GP stand for Graphics
primitive this function is is calling it
I think that's where the problem is so
let's search for this
function cure
[Music]
GP yeah so the function is
here coverture GP now where is
this okay
so now I I need to look at my
documentation so this code is a bit
complex you can
see God this is more one of the more
complex
part so let's see where is this
function let's see the documentation I
have yeah so here's a
code find previous find next cature GPS
oh I don't have documentation for it
that's
rare okay so curvature GPS basically
this function returns a list of Graphics
Primitives like lines and
circles and so it takes these arguments
so at least a points on the curve at
least the velocity vectors of those
points and the acceler acceleration
vectors okay
then Circle evolute radius
okay
uh yeah some some there there it is so
square root first last velocity Vector
so
so here is a problem because this part
may become
zero so when this part become zero you
got divide by
zero yeah so there there it is so let's
let me change okay I think I found a
problem if you just change this instead
of three equal sign change it to two
equal sign it
work okay I think
so if you do that
then this
error let me show you indetermined
indeterminant indetermined will go away
okay let's just try
that so now we okay so where do we
change it
yeah let's just change it
here actually we shouldn't uh make a
backup and let's just do
it
okay change triple equal to double
equal okay and change this to a
approximate zero
okay
yeah okay now
we now we just evaluate this block of
code go back
here
make a copy of this part and run it
let's
see steel
Arrow
God
uh let's make
sure
okay maybe we need to restart
because do we need to restart yeah
probably okay let's restart
okay this is a change we made close
it save close it don't
save okay uh and here uh let's just do
create
kernel okay
now open it
again okay select all shift return Rand
name
fantastic okay close
it open the
example then go
to where
that
uh there okay
now make a copy
it run
it no don't re
evaluate ah we still got
error Okay so
let's try this okay so this is kind of
the key
here so if we
have uh z z what it equal equals to
true
triple
equal
C that's Force so this is this is
uh this is a problem
in a field called numerical
analysis because it's kind of
tricky I believe this is where the eror
came from because if you can determine
you know some number is zero if we know
for sure we got a zero Vector then we
simply
return Z 0 we don't do anything but
otherwise we are trying trying to
compute the normal okay so wait so here
is a no uh normal unit Vector yeah we
need
that
uh okay maybe the problem is here so
here is you are Computing the curvature
k k is a traditional function name for
curvature and the our function for
curvature is here oh they are there so
we forgot to change
yeah the two places we need to change
okay so maybe that that we'll fix
it so we need to open this again let's
just change here
okay yeah so uh so what
um
okay make a backup first just to be sure
so you need to change
that here and here so you see the triple
triple equal
means whether the structures are
symbolically the
same while the double equal in wam
language means they
are approximately the same okay so
there's a
difference uh you know the equality sign
there's always big complexity in any
language for example in Python in Java
if you have
a a value that's a list then when you
compare one list is equal to another you
have have the issue of whether if you
are comparing their reference address
they are equal or whether they actual
component value are equal so it gets
very
complex the determination of equality
that is why that is why in iMac lisp you
have like five different equality tests
depending on the type of the value and
similarly for hascal and type Theory you
know the identity equality is extremely
complex okay so those of you are
trolling not recommended
okay uh Return of the loan something is
when you drink something for $3 and
something okay those you guys are
trolling go away
okay so let's see what how do we fix
this let's just change that
okay okay let's do
that
okay
now we're going to create kernel
again create local yes then we're going
to open
this open
it
then select all
evaluated okay
then close it back here try this
again do
it
no
yeah Ste
error
so this arrow is
indeterminant I believe you get that if
you do that one divided by zero okay
complex
Infinity uh what if you
have
okay let me try something
else let's see the documentation for
if so if can take a third
argument
now okay so first argument second
can take a fourth argument okay I
believe that's
new so you can see first argument second
argument third argument so let's give a
fourth argument zero
okay and here let's do the
same first argument second argument
third
argument uh wait
one test
true
false actor list okay test true
Force Vector list okay let's try
that quit Kel
again
quit close
that open
this
select
all
evaluate go back
here minut
it
no and same
errow it should be just here map
thread is there somewh where this happen
again if that then
that it test true
false
oh okay so yeah so here
so okay let's try
again save
it uh permission denied okay
okay okay close this now save it open
it start again create the
Kel okay select all evaluated
back here run this
no
yeah okay that's that's Uh something's
wrong
now where does this
occur
now uh last
negative you
reverse yeah so you can see here they
are reversing the order
so you are given X and Y now it
becomes negative Y and
X so X becomes negative Y and Y becomes
X you are doing that because you you you
are getting a perpendicular Vector of
the
oral and then you divide it by the
square root and first SLS that's you
know
so that
is that is Computing the length of a
vector
so so in wam language now they have a
function to do that it wasn't available
20 years
ago uh normalized form no uh yeah
so unit Vector no you uh you want the
norm so Norm computes the length of a
vector okay so for example
Norm
one one one okay so the the vector one
one the length is square root of two
that's correct so instead of doing that
here now we can just say Norm
okay yeah
so
nor okay that should be the same that
should do it
now
uh okay
so let's search for square root so this
happened in quite a few
places
also happens here so you can just say
no
okay so then search
again
nor
okay
happens one more
place
uh so this is Computing the tangent line
so you also run into this
issue so this
issue this issue let's Okay so let's
start to drill
down so the problem is just this
function
okay so let's put it
here put it here so this function is
giving you
this
indeterminant errow
okay and we can make
it we can try to simplify it
okay
we still got the problem you know so now
in fact let's just say 2 one I believe
it still get the
problem yep so now instead of 1260 one
12 just 10 of them you see much
simpler now let's say
025 let's just say four of them you see
we still got this
eror but now it's much simpler now let's
remove the old aspect R let's remove the
line
style okay we still got the problem now
remove the aspect ratio so simplify
it okay so
so if you don't plot the evolute will
the error still be there let's try
it and it no okay so it's only when you
plot the
evolute this bug
happens so yeah so the problem is with
the Evol
somewhere yeah so this
evolute and this evolute basically the
problem is in somewhere in the velocity
Vector list and acceleration vector
list okay so but when you compute the
derivative will the problem
occur
no
because um you simply get
zero you see when you compute the
derivative
of does it give you divide by zero
no I don't think
so yeah so so
this is not the source of our
problem but the source of our problem is
when
you is when you try
to
do this coverture yeah I'm pretty sure
it's when you try to do the curvature
okay so here is a curvature
core oh okay so the curvature function
the last argument is a list of true or
false okay now let's go to the
definition of curvature
GP okay so there it
is and uh here are the
parameters okay and uh so this the last
three elements are each one of them is
true or false true means plot it plot
the circle
the the oscillating
Circle
uh and this is the center of the circle
and this is radius the line of this to
the
center okay so then we back to
here
in determinant true or false false true
that if it's false then you get
that
um so why don't we just say that
okay
so this K is a cure
function oh God the coverage of function
let's just do this
again so if that if it's
true then zero
otherwise
that
zero test true
false if it's in
indeterminant also zero so when
curvature returns zero what
happens oh there it
is yeah so here is a problem
so one over least okay so there is a
problem radius
list I find the problem I found the
problem so you see one divided by this
Cal function this Cal function here
returns zero
sometimes
so so what you're going to do so what is
this radius list
used Center vectors okay normal unit is
times radius
least yeah that's a problem you see
divide by
zero
um yeah so the problem is
here
the problem is here so 1 divided by
zero you get that
sometimes so what can you do you cannot
simply so you see this curvature part is
a list of values okay it's a list of
values and some of them is zero maybe
zero so what can you do to avoid so when
you one divided by this list you get get
a least of one divided by that okay
so so how can you fix that you cannot
simply
remove those values elements that are
zero because if you do that then you
changed the length of this
list and that's not good because because
this the length of this list needs to be
used
you know because if you change the
length of the radius list
then that list has a different length
than the normal unit Vector list so then
that means you cannot multiply them
together you know element by
element
so and same thing for the center points
so Center points is the center of the
ulating
circle okay so and why what what are we
using this for we are using this for to
compute to draw the circle basically
yeah so you see we draw the circle and
we draw the the center of the circle and
then we draw the radius line
from the point on the curve to the
center of the oscillating Circle okay
so so in order to draw that we have
these variables Center vectors Center
points okay Center Vector Center points
okay so yeah I kind of know what to
do uh
uh almost almost done fixing the problem
so the problem
is some of these elements in this list
is zero you cannot simply delete delete
them if you want to delete them you have
to delete
also the same elements
in the normal unit Vector list and
uh
yeah and uh Center Vector yeah so you
have to delete all of them in one
shot the corresponding elements
okay
so yeah I kind of know what to do so for
example so for example you have a list
of
something okay some of them are zero uh
and you have another list let's
say uh let's say
x
x0
X2
X3
X4 you know let's say you have another
list of several
values now and then you have another
list the important thing thing is that
all these List have the same number of
items so if you delete the zeros in the
first list you also need to delete the
corresponding elements okay so what we
can do here
is oh okay so actually uh the problem is
here you see the problem
is
one divided by zero so the problem is
that okay God I I know what is the
problem you see the curvature so for
example this would
[Music]
be that would be the
that that would correspond to this okay
so now if you have one divided
by that you got that that is the
problem uh
yeah
so
okay you need you need to
CL oh
God okay I need to think about
this okay I've been sitting for 1990
minutes I need a
break how many people are watching one
two
three
okay
uh fantastic someone is watching okay
thank you so so yeah I'm going to take a
break for 4 minutes and uh let's come
back we know the problem
now um yeah so okay be right
back
one Mega ton of
[Music]
coffee let me describe the problem
Let's uh let's just go
slowly now in my normal coding of course
I wouldn't be talking actually I talk to
myself a lot because when you talk WR
things down
you it help you clarify the
thoughts
the K
is the K is a function that
computes uh how do you spell
compute
so
like this okay so let me
just do it so
it people can
understand
so K is a function that computes cure
then
um something like
this where some items are
zero so so when
you one over that then you get div
division by zero that is your problem
you know you get a value of complex
infinite complex Infinity okay when you
when one divide by zero you get complex
Infinity uh and then so our code but our
code continues to you know to
multiply so when you have a unit Vector
times
zero uh then you get a z 0o you get a
zero vector and then so which is okay
centered um which is okay but actually
wrong because it's no longer
Center center of the uh articulating
Circle Center of the C uh you know the
circle of curvature but anyway basically
when you get a zero that means at that
point on the Curve you do not have a
curvature defined so you cannot have a
osculating circle
so so that
means so whenever at those points you
you don't want to compute anything at
those points ah God so what you going to
do
so so what you going to do here
so this curvature function you know so
this curvature
function
um this cure function if we change it
you you see the thing is we don't want
to change the length of the
list okay
[Music]
so
yeah I think I have to do this offlines
so you
know because this
is not so easy to
fix one of the easy way is simply to
turn off the warning
messages n that wouldn't work actually I
already turned it off I
think because you can
see uh
okay let's
see search for
off you see we already so this
line this line already turns
of infinity turns of Errors of infinity
let's close
that you know this this
thing turns of infinity in
determinant
uh yeah but what how do you not solve
this
oh
God go back to go back go back to our
problem so the
problem CU cuz
yeah go to
it let's just comment here so you can
see and uh here let's just make it one
line single line wam
language okay so yeah
so the problem is this
line how do you solve the
problem you got a list of values some of
them are
zero the best solution is just to delete
those zero elements okay but if you want
to do that you also have to delete the
corresponding points of this and that
okay and can you do that yes so yeah
easy okay
so velocity Vector list
so so you compute the radius list first
I mean well you compute this thing
first so actually we can start to fix it
so for example curvature list is a
value we declare it here as
another variable let's say here okay
there okay so curvature list then you
can Define curvature
list here okay
so
there equals to that okay so you got a
cure list then
then some of the value will be zero okay
then but now you
know now you
know which elements are
problematic so once you know that you
can you can shorten
the let's see you can shorten the
velocity Vector
list Therefore your normal Vector list
will be corresponded will be correct
length
right that's
right okay and then so similarly
your okay let's let's move the radius
list here okay
so so similarly your radius list okay so
I can put it here so you so the then the
center
vectors will also be correspondent you
know correct length then Center points
will be
also uh where does the T Point list come
from okay they will not be the correct
length you need to also change the Le
the length of T Point list okay so
anyway that's the but okay so you can
you can you can properly delete some of
the zero elements but however you when
you if you do that then this
curvature Graphics primitive function
will return a
list where the length of the list will
not be necessarily the same is the input
list of points on the
curve that's not so good because use you
know you expect the lengths to always be
the same uh let's look at where cure GPS
is called okay so
cature okay so basically you got you see
this is how you generate
the
the lines of radius
um this is how you generate you draw you
know you generate the
lines of radial lines and uh and the
point the red these red
dots so in order to generate those
Graphics you rely on the curvature
Graphics primitive
Okay so
so now let's look at where are these
variable
used
okay oh then delete
cases
what oh we already have delete
what
delete cases by what
criteria
okay
what
did you finish your Advent of code
already have You' been watching the
videos if you have you know the answer
what is your intention of asking that
question oh God so this
problem do I want to continue yeah let's
continue because let's just I mean
that's what that's the point of this
video
so it's you know it's going to be
boring from the beginning so anyway so
what how do you fix this problem you got
um yeah so here is your radial lines
here is radius radial point the center
points Center of circle
points so this coverage
thing
H coverture is the problematic thing
because you you run into
the undefined
situation where you have a
cusp or in catastroph catastrophe Theory
they are called
Singularity you know like today we are
approaching Singularity those points are
called Singularity okay just for fun
let's chat
random catastrophe Theory okay there it
is catastrophe
Theory actually I don't know the sub
subject too much but
basically okay so you have what fold
catastrophe okay I don't know what that
is but you can see here they are trying
to
show cusp cat catastrophe that's what we
got you see this this cusp this pointed
sharp points that's that's the cusp
catastrophe in fact we just plotted a
graph of it uh today I mean two days ago
I
was yeah you see those all those points
are cusps
sharp
points why are they C I mean so why are
they catastrophe because at those points
things goes wrong you know s things goes
out of the ordinary it's like into the
black
hole because every point on a curve you
know they have properties they have
velocity they have curvature they have
tangent they you know they have normal
it's well defined but when when you
reach one of these curp Point everything
breaks you know you got one divided by
zero you you you don't you don't have
velocity velocity becom zero Cur
curvature is
undefined uh you know things like that
so that's catastrophe so at those points
that's what
the yeah oh oh this is what I'm going to
show I'm going to show it okay so anyway
that's that's what this catastrophe
theory is about you know I don't know
much about it but that's that's a basic
idea they
study when the situations when you know
in what circumstances this CPS
happen Okay so let's read it cusp
catastrophe so you are you have this
equation you know we can plot it let's
ramble you know let's ramble a bit and
uh
um okay uh X4 ax2
BX what is it a x s okay so
ax² that's equals to zero I suppose and
uh okay so
and uh I believe implicit
PL
uh cont to
plot
x-3
23 let's
say what is a and b yeah stupid
A and
B
let's
[Music]
see I'm not even sure that works uh
let's
see
where where is the
Y
whats
yeah X4 power ax s +
BX oh a = to z a less than z Oh a is a
variable so a
changes okay so you got that kind of
situation yeah anyway yeah I'm not going
to app PL it I'm not going to app PL it
so anyway that's a
digression so how do we how do I solve
this problem I have to okay I cannot do
it online I mean I have to think about
it I
cannot just talk
and
stuff and I'm getting tired okay
so so what what what are you doing now
count to
plot
[Music]
um
for
oh syntax error that's
why there it
is so what are they saying a = to
so what is the Wikipedia
saying the Wikipedia is
saying a less than zero let's
see so a less than Zer
-2 you don't get any
Contours uh why is
that
what what is this we Wikipedia
thing oh DVD DX what they taking a
derivative okay so they have to take the
derivative the curp geometry is very
common when one explores what happens to
a fold by
fication if a second parameter B is
added to the control
space okay varying the parameters one
finds that there is now curve
blue of points in AB space where
stability is
lost where a stable solution we suddenly
jump to an alternative outcome okay
that's catastrophe
Theory uh and
uh
so hyperbolic umbilic
catastrophe elliptic umbilic
catastrophe parabolic umbilic
catastrophe Arnold
notation Chaos Theory okay
uh yeah they don't say much
Singularity Theory let's
see what is singularity
Theory this article has problems in math
Singularity Theory studies spaces that
are almost manif folds but not quite a
string can serve as an example of a
one-dimensional manifold if one neglects
its thickness a singularity can be made
by boiling it up dropping it on the
floor and flattening it in some places
the flat string will cross itself in an
approximate X shape the point on the
floor where does this are one kind of
Singularity
yeah yeah again cusps cusps and double
points and
stuff okay uh so but
they they really have nothing to do
with with with debugging our
program our program our
problem is we got this
our problem
is is this we got this
list so here is our problem okay we got
a list of
points and uh some of them are
zero when that
happens you know we need to shorten the
the list we need to remove those
elements but if we do that then
um you see the Cure so if we do that
then oh okay so we actually we just
directly yeah okay so we can shorten
them within this function no
problem
right let's do that okay let's just do
that
okay so let's do that so here is a
function
definition and uh it's not it's not it's
actually quite long but you know you you
you guys probably cannot read this but
but I
can okay but okay so so it's not too
long though but
um so for example let me shorten and so
you can kind of
see what is
this oh this is normal so we are
actually just defining so that's so we
are defining the curvature list we are
defining the radius list we are defining
the normal unit list okay then we are
defining the center vectors list
then we are defining the center point
list okay it's also close and
then and then what's this
um Let me let me shorten the code so you
can see what's going
on yeah then we are actually generating
the graph Graphics so you see these
three
parts you
see we are
returning this list this list is a list
of three things
okay
uh okay so this we are just returning
this three a list of three
things each of those thing is a graphics
primitive it's basically a bunch of
circles that represents the oscillating
circles or a bunch of lines that
represents the point on the curve to the
center of the circle then a bunch
of uh lines that's the radius okay so
what is this Evol
evolute
center point so T point so
okay yeah I can I I know what to do but
um I'm kind of tired here so
again again the main problem is is this
okay so you
can you can get the positions
okay let me show you what that is
position index that Returns the
indexes where
some some criteria occur so we want to
know a list of all indexes where zero
occur yeah so give an association
between a unique elements okay that's
not that's what not position is what we
want yeah position so so for
example so this curvature list we want
to know all the indexes where zero occur
so we can just say
position okay cature list then zero okay
so it tells us do it happens at index 2
and index six
correct okay so once we got the index we
can use this index to remove element by
index so that would be
delete
um okay I forgot what is that let's go
to w tutorial okay uh list
so you got you go to the list then you
want to delete element by position so
let's go to list operations you see in
wam language you have many ways to
delete elements of a list you can delete
by using an
index or you can delete by using a
function criteria if the function
returns true delete those you know or
you can delete Elements by by using
pattern matching now this this this way
is not available in in most
languages so anyway so we want uh so now
but our problem we got a list of indexes
we want to delete them okay so here
delete element in list delete by index
range that's not what we want we don't
want the range we want delete by
position that's what we want okay delete
expression
n uh then you can have a list of
positions that's what we want okay so
for example let's go back to our code
let me show you how this
works okay so for
example so for example let's define
this uh let's define so for example this
is a
corresponding uh T Point list okay for
example you know they have the same
number of
elements now you get the position of the
zero in curvature list then you just
say
delete uh what was the function just
delete
okay then you delete the T
points then you delete by the position
of the indexes you know that okay run it
you see you see the
corresponding elements are removed so we
can use this methodology
to to fix our problem to fix our this
okay
yeah
so so we so now we know the curvature
list okay then so now we need to know
the
position zero
indexes
uh zero positions okay zero let's
say
okay
so there okay there that's good now we
created a new variable let's add it here
okay uh module is like lisps let okay
it's like JavaScript let it just declare
local variables okay so cure list okay
then zero position list okay
fantastic
then then um then you need to delete
that's
right
delete new coverture list equals
to delete coverture list
by the zero position
okay fantastic okay we are coding
blindly because I know what you know is
in my head I have the
structure so we don't have to trial and
error okay so we got the new curvature
this that's what we
want uh then then uh
oh God this is not perfect this is not
good code uh but I'm just doing it for
the live stream because so that we can
get somewhere
because in real life you don't want you
know you need to check if there's a zero
first if there's no zero you don't want
to go all through this if there's no
zero then your code is good as is you
know so you you need to have a check on
zero first there so anyway let's push on
okay so so so find all the zeros then
new so actually it's better if we do
check for
zero
um so how do you check if something if a
list has zero you do member Q okay
member Q uh curvature list zero okay
true that means there is zero in
it
yeah yeah so so much problem so much
tediousness so member
Q curvature
list zero if this true then then problem
okay if it's not true then everything is
simple if so if it's not true then then
we just do all
this okay then then we just do all
this okay but if it's
true we got a problem my
friend let's let's just
um let's just return a empty list okay
let's just return empties and and move
this to here okay so actually
now this solves our
problem because this code solves this
problem but actually it doesn't draw
anything we can try
it okay so
evaluate quit
kernel quit local kernel quit Okay then
open this
file
H where is
it I don't understand why is it taking
so long okay select all evaluated good
close it back to
here copy the
code and uh put it here paste it if we
if we run it it's going to be no error
but however it won't it won't
draw it won't draw the
thing oh
actually oh we got some Arrow here
somewhere okay I I think that's it I'm
going to walk offline I need to uh take
a break and so that's it for today thank
you guys for watching it's like 2 hours
2 hours and 20 minutes bye
guys
and yeah yeah I
gotta so what is the error why is it
private arcing Circle
uh see you later later
Tommy yeah actually I don't I know I
know what is a
problem because cuz you don't yeah you
need to
return actually so let's
return because you are expected to
return three things okay so now let's
try it again quit kernel local
quit Okay then open this
file
it takes why is it taking a
while okay select or B it close it go
back here B it and okay that's it
bye