good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa's
show today's 2020 may 8th Friday 5
o'clock p.m. San Francisco time so what
are we going to talk about we are going
to talk about some keyboard stuff
keyboards and let me show you okay
keyboards several things about keyboards
then you ask me questions if you got a
question for me type it in the chat
YouTube chat okay then we are going to
answer some questions on this code and
first of all look at this fantastic art
this is bad
death washing hands you need to wash
hands wash your hands until you got skin
cancer and I got a poem for it where is
my poem it's somewhere it's on my
website one of my website I'm not sure I
want to show and it's it's not sure
let's talk about keywords hello my
mansion Chico Chico name mentioned sicko
Chico Chico is from Hong Kong and he
helped me resolve one of the questions
about keyboards recently and let me show
you some of the other interesting things
okay about art here look at this shoe
this is very weird shoe you see pretty
weird it's it's got a hinge there and
this one is from Michael Cornelius this
photo he took it in I believe he's in
Spain a few years ago 2012 oh wow it's
five years ago and he's a Emacs user so
he took this photo very strange shoot
hinge there
okay so let's do let's do let's talk
about stuff it's talk talk show talk
show is mean to talk stuff oh and this
one I must show this one this fantastic
starry starry eyed owl
okay this hour is fantastic this this is
actually a blind hour so these are my
song arts website so okay let's let's
talk about today so let's see in ECM
system key keyboards I'm going to
introduce you guys about the Japanese
economic keyboards they are quite a few
as you can see my photos here quite a
lot of them and you can see the photos
here okay there is the M system and M
system there are about five or six
variations over the over you know attain
the span of ten years of their design
they are tamed about five or six
variations it's called M system then you
have trunk on the Japanese strong
keyboard which is truly a fantastic
keyboard and all these are from 1980s to
1990s and also you have the most famous
thump keyboard now you see we mentioned
several keyboards but however they are
not compatible you see trunk is one
thing trunk keyboard then you have the M
system keyboards that's another thing so
this one is M system this one is the
first one and this one and this one and
this one they are all from M systems I'm
going to tell you what they are about
and then so M system is one thing Trung
is one thing wrong is from the trunk
operating system at one time it's the
most used operating system in a world
okay more used than Microsoft
supposedly because they are using all
devices in Japan but there's a anyway so
trunk then you have M systems then you
have the thumb shift some shift shift is
another system they okay so all these
three systems they are not the same they
are not compatible the way you type
Japanese or English is different for
each one of them so they are competing
and they but they are all you know they
share one thing that is they are all
kind of more economic so I'm gonna show
you so actually I'm gonna show so for
example this one this one is a modern
trunk
okay this one many great nerds covered
such as Emily our Emily and
unfortunately this one is not it went
out of business they could they shut
down in 2007 seventeen so two years ago
they should have shut down so you cannot
it's no longer in production and it's
very hard to find you you know you it's
hard to find on eBay and this is very
high-quality keyboard this is one of the
trunk you know so let me tell you the
history but anyway this one is one you
know they the very high quality you see
the key caps what plastic are they PBS
PPD or something and anyway so the you
see you got this label I mean you got
this brand name logo there and it's made
of metal and it's not just metal its
colorful metal embedded on a keyboard
that means that means this is a very
expensive keyboard okay high high
quality highest quality so when it was
around in 2017 2015 I I discovered this
keyboard muchang okay this is called
micro trunk that is symbol for Michael
Michael draw what I discovered when I
discovered this keyboard in 2011 you can
buy it in Japan
it costs something about $550 US Dollars
and you have to go to Japan to buy it so
yeah but they don't Nene they no longer
makes it by the way let me give you a
let me tell you a bit story short
history also interesting thing about
this micro Tron keyboard is that you
know in comparison to the happy hacking
keyboard a man Emily's favorite keyboard
and many nerds favorite keyboards so you
see that micro Tron keyboard is actually
smaller let's see yeah the keys are
actually smaller than the happy hacking
keyboard in Japan you know Japan
Japanese people they are in general they
have smaller body frame than American or
white people and so their keyboard tends
to be smaller I mean they have they have
particular smaller size for the in you
know keyboards made in Japan by Japanese
companies so you see you can compare
with happy hacking keyboard they are
actually smaller and this is
particularly good for females
you know like in USA the standard
keyboard is usually you know one size
fits all you know there's just one
single size of keyboards but actually if
you compare man's hand and females hand
you know let's say you are white white
guy or and and white girl they differ
significantly that you know the hand
size so so that's the thing now now on
the other hand the extreme is that if
you compare a black man a blacksmith a
black man's hand with a asian girl hand
and you know that's gonna be in sharp
contrast so so chip so let me tell you a
little interesting thing about this
strong keyboard okay and also it's using
topher switch top topper capacitor
electro capacitance switch and that's
one of the reason a lot people love this
one
let me let me check my status okay I'm
alive and talking and people are here
good morning jaqen good morning Alan and
namsun named Shin has actually told me
quite a lot info yesterday about all
these Japanese keyboards keyboards but I
didn't have time to update them today
yeah so mutrah so another interesting
thing about mood Trung is that let me
tell you okay there's a video you can go
watch just search for saudi keyboard
you'll find my keyboard blog and you'll
find these all these keyboards and by
the way there's also do-it-yourself
micro Tron so in Japan people started to
make it micro Tron and you can you can
build it yourself
here is Japanese words you know with
some Chinese words you know what it
means so Alan would know because Alan is
a is a multi linguist so this you know
this so you see this so it says he says
in Chinese basically hand sword
okay sword you know the sword of the
Knights hand sword and there is the
Japanese Japanese ninja dot there so
anyway so this is micro Tron do it
yourself
I believe you can buy the kit I don't
have the link you you know you have to
go to you know my sources here image
resource and ask ask the Japanese I
believe you can buy the kit and build it
yourself so back to muchang so that this
micro Tron came out in 2007 2007 and
they stopped in 2017 you know but let me
tell you an interesting story about this
keyboard because you must have okay we
are digressing a lot because I wanted to
talk about I want to tell you about the
stories of all these various Japanese
keyboard but we'll get back to that but
let me tell you something interesting
about this micro trunk okay so you go -
oh go keyboards section and you scroll
down
and you you see this keyboard IO we
talked about this quite a few times this
keyboard came out in about three years
ago 2017 it was in the plan in 2015 but
after three years you know they didn't
come out but eventually it came out
finally
so this keyboard the person who created
this is a Perl program you know back in
1980s 1990s is one of the somewhat
popular program well-known samat and he
his name is what was his name I forgot
his name but anyway he let's see where
is he
so this is a keyboard I all right so
what's his the designers name I have it
somewhere but I I do not always remember
people's names I forgot I could I could
remember it if I think about it but
I'm not going to take the time let's see
so who created this what's that mean
what what is his name I forgot
he's a programmer anyway so so if you
have a question type it with my name
there okay so anyway this guy I forgot
his name at the moment yeah I need to I
should remember I should tell I should
say since I'm doing a video is it anyone
remembered this guy anyways you know we
are all keyboard fans so many of us have
cross-pollination we talked to each
other and we know each other at least
other acquaintances I forgot his name I
have written it somewhere here okay but
I can't find it
anyway so the the the keyboard IO guy
you know he has actually a keyboard
collection like tens of them he you know
he you know back then you know back in
seven years ago the Ergo Ducks came out
and all the nerds are excited you know
everyone is starting to do itself you
know oh go dogs go dogs is based on the
it's based on the Kinesis advantage okay
let me actually there is another thing I
want to show I have a photo of myself
today I took yesterday so let me show
you that photo okay
and other people's photos interesting
pictures of champagne wine and Emily's
flowers and Emily's aboard very
beautiful in UK and we have squatting
this is this is a rerun okay so we have
a squatting competition Begay Ellen so
that's Alan so I did one there it is
squatting with my Kinesis advantage to
keyboard so so this guy who created
keyboard IO he you know since since the
ergo Ducks came out
ergo ducks is a copy kind of a copy of
the Canisius keyboard so ago Ducks came
out Do It Yourself
everyone you know we we you know people
started to do do-it-yourself keyboards
basically oh go suck Google Docs is the
you can say it's the milestone that's a
beginning time when people started to do
lots of do-it-yourself keyboards in
especially the ergonomic ones so so this
guy Jesus what's what's his name anyone
remember type it
Allen squat warrior keyboard Micro Micro
Micro Tron looks very traditional no
it's not traditional chicken this Renee
masu install to install yeah the
Japanese ninja throwing stars trunk
dominated embedded OS okay so so nation
nation reads Japanese so he know he
knows a lot about keyboard stuff as you
know keyboard stuff in Japan in history
and also Chinese input systems anyway
let me finish the story so this guy so
he wanted to build a designer keyboard
for himself you know ergonomic one the
erga dogs began it and he wanted to
improve it you know to something better
and then it took him three or four years
to actually came up with the keyboard
i/o through the design design process
you know several revisions several
revisions of design process they
manufacturing you know he goes to China
and talked to people and you have to
this has to be made out of wood and
these problems then you know we actually
start a business there's all sort of
things you have to solve which most of
us nerds
we wouldn't know you know you have to
start a company to to to know to know
about that so anyway he but before in
his design process he collect he
collected tens of keyboards you can see
he has photo collections on Flickr okay
so let's see Flickr Fei ck
well you see I don't have it here it's
somewhere on my website okay see he has
a collection of his photos of his
keyboard collection and one of his
collection is you you guess it is this
micron and and of course he also owns a
go ducks he also owns Kinesis advantage
so out of all keyboards he's in his
opinion his most favorite keyboard is
this Megatron this is what he think is
the closest to his ideal of the best
keyboard yeah so you know so that's
that's my quote wrong and he went on to
design his keyboard IO so anyway let's
go back to the Japanese Kibo let me tell
you the story okay it's picking by I
want to talk about the trunk key but
that yeah about let's talk about wrong
okay since we started to talk about
trunk so trauma trunk keyboard came out
in so here's what it looks like it's a
it's kind of huge includes these I
believe this is a digital graphics pad
back then so this is back in 1987 ok
trunk trunk a Mardi Gras is a operating
system and come with this trauma a
strong OS project and come with this
keyboard and this keyboard is quite
interesting because
let me show you so it's ergonomic right
but it's got two special shift keys you
see the red shift key on the left and
the right shift key the green and the
blue one on the right the red shift key
on the left and the blue shift key on
the right these two shift key are
different I mean they are not just the
same shift key for both hands for you
know on both sides they are actually
different keys different modifiers so
you have to shift keys to shift keys and
you also have a standard you know us
normal shift keys I believe that's here
here and there but let's let's see you
know that so anyway you got red shift
key and blue shift key so that means for
each letter key you have three
possibilities
pressing the key itself or press it with
the red shift key or press it with the
blue shift key so each key letter key
has becomes three possible possibilities
so you can see the key labels on this
let me show you a bigger picture okay so
you can see the key labels on that you
can see the red let's see you can see
the red you know the black is normal the
black is normal okay let's focus the
black one is normal then you have the if
you hold down the red shift key then you
type that and if you hold down the blue
shift key you you add you will have a
character that's with the X accent
character
added you know that's Japanese reading
systems basically for each of the
Japanese letter they can come with the
accent mark or without so anyway
each key you have three basically three
purposes with the red and left shift but
also notice the number roll notice the
number roll here so you have here you
can see curly single quotes then you
have double curly quotes then you have
Asian quotes those are a.cian brackets
single and double and you can also see
the color that's how you type them then
you have the ASEAN angular brackets then
you have the normal parentheses then you
have the normal braces you know American
cause call these braces the in UK they
co-ed curly brackets and then you have
the square brackets in America you just
call it brackets in UK UK is square
brackets and parentheses in America you
call that but in UK you call round
brackets so the UK system is actually
the linguistics aspect the UK system is
a better one it's because it's a it's
consistent and uniform
you see round brackets curly brackets
square brackets there are all brackets
but on your hand the American Fahrenheit
the imperial system foot feet they
have this you know the parentheses then
you have these braces then you have this
brackets okay
so anyway that's the Japanese this is a
Tron keyboard and another thing
interesting is that I never figure out
is that you see you see this art column
that's this this column is
you know you see okay so you got this
art column and you also have got kind of
a column here now this one is actually
your pinky so your pinky column is this
one this and and here is your ring
finger column and here is your middle
middle finger column and this the this
one is your index finger column so when
you put your hands there is
I cannot imagine it's kind of odd so
it's almost like that okay you put your
head that you you position your hands
like that on this keyboard I don't know
how how how that that you know how how
can that be how is that ergonomic you
actually have to put your hands on it to
know I got a video here but it doesn't
show much I mean video people typing on
a keyboard so anyway this is the trans
system so for reasons Tron died you know
Minnie good designer and I then people
created this mood trunk micro Tron
keyboard you know in 2007 so anyway
that's the transistor now let me tell
you another system that is the EM system
so M system the first one is this one in
now remember 1983 the PC you know
personal computers just began to come
out you know I suppose that's around IBM
PC around a year or something maybe and
in Japan they have these keyboards this
is this is called MGM system
Oh M type type kind of means model you
know it's the the best translation is M
system because it means it's a system of
inputting Japanese words okay so this
system is M system and this is this is
the first model for for the computer
pc-8801 made by NEC NEC is a big company
but back then they also it's also used
for word processors so anyway actually
we talked about this one yesterday so
someone you know modified it so that to
use the Cherry MX
key switches so anyway anyway this is
the first one then you have variations
like this one
let me show you so am I still doing okay
so muchas micro-trauma was launched by
personal media same maker of drunk tk1
oh they are they haha thank you
thank you naman that's that's fantastic
information because I thought someone
else created it so you know when you you
know why why I try to do research when I
try to write these pages it's kind of
difficult you spend hours you know I've
spent days days over the years to to try
to find out what exactly what's this
keyboard who made it why how do you use
it you know what's new why is it
different yet but I don't I don't read
Japanese so so you have to find a page
then you have to translate you know it's
really um you know almost impossible
very difficult but nine nine shinned
speaks Japanese so he knows a lot so
okay so that's a new information micro
Tron was actually launched by personal
media same maker of the trunk TK one
that's amazing so that means that
company you know this strong thing is
you know still around but why do they
cure it I you know what where do they
carry in 2017 as far as I know you know
I read that they because there's not
many buyers something like that
okay okay so so so M system let's go
back to n system then you have this
variation
okay so let's magnify M system so you
have this variation and then you have
then you have this variation which is
rather very different now I don't know
exactly the reason why they change to
these you know flat but I suppose it's I
suppose it's because flat is kind of
more familiar to most people because
this one happened in 1992 you know by
1992 personal computers are very popular
you know and especially in America so
and most of it is using you know
American keyboards you know the there's
you know so this form is more familiar
with people so I suppose that is why the
Japanese created this variation but
still they know all these are M systems
that means you use the you know that
specific way to type Japanese but also
noticed in M systems not notice the
arrangements of the letters you see on
our left hand home row you have e u I a
oh now notice that's all vowels
you know English vowels so it's it's
efficient it for typing English but they
also arrange the Japanese phonetics
differently then as compared to Truong
for example all these all these are
basically efficiency based their design
is based on efficiency so so you have
this variation M system then you have so
this is 1992 then you have then you have
this master this beautiful one you know
they went back to the ergonomic form and
but and they are all symmetric you know
Japanese all these are great I mean even
this one look at this
fantastic ergonomic you know you split
your hands you know apart but actually
the the arrow keys in the middle that's
very bad arrangement and also it's not
so good to put in the middle anyway
after that then they created this one
this one M system and this one this one
is called NEC PK k B 0 1 5 and but
there's a nickname for it this one is
called oh go fit so look let's look at
this you know oh go fit so this is
fantastic
EUI a o then you have the thumb keys
then you have the arrow keys now down in
the middle now that's much better but
still this arrangement of arrow keys is
not so good actually
it's good okay the the arrangement of of
the arrow keys that's another topic to
talk about because over the past thirty
years forty years there are many
different arrangements and actually
there is a study that shows that the
current arrangement you know we are
familiar with the inverted T that is
actually the most efficient because when
you study the hand movements the finger
movements and also the combination of
the arrow keys you need to press the
inverted T turns out to be the most
efficient I have a article that on that
that's half written it's not complete
but but anyway the you can find it on my
website you know if you just go to
keyboard design and click on arrow keys
there's articles someone else will it's
that details why you know remember Apple
keyboard so many keyboards are all the
VI the idiotic VI you know you have the
arrow keys on the same row okay sorry
right sorry vim fans and Evo fans you
have the arrow keys on the same row and
also Apple keyboards has led that let me
show you okay those are no good okay
those are easier idiotic idiocy
those are English actually I have have
quite a few articles on that I have
actually a JavaScript that you can
measure which one is what arrow Q
arrangement is more efficient actually
we did a talk show on that before
several months ago so anyway so this
least one this model M system oh go fit
let's see let's let's see what else to
say about this
you know I saw these are fantastic and
also they are using mechanical keys now
this is a Alves switch
I don't know I don't know much about
elves elves switch but anyways you know
it's mechanical keyboard and and in this
photo you can see one two three four
five you know five variations of the M
system keyboards created by NEC over the
you know over ten span of ten ten or
twenty years so that concludes my
talking about the M system so you can
see Japanese books history of keyboards
something like that they talk about you
know the M system and also this I think
this is a word processor and you see one
huh yeah this is a word processor you
know back in 1980s
you know also using M system and also in
1980s you know before the personal
computer became popular before that you
have the word processors you know a
machine a device that with a screen
that's dedicated for writing you know
what your processor machines so in Japan
you have these you know in USA you have
that too but once once the the personal
computer became popular it just wiped
out the word processor machines because
first on a computer you can do what
processing you can also play games and
other things so there it is the M system
okay so we talked about we talked about
trunk then we talked about M systems or
these these
this one okay anyway so we talked about
several M system keywords then before
before all these there is one this one
okay some shift now this is entirely
different system from trunk and from M
systems this is Japan's thumb shift
keyboards and this is very interesting
as well you see all these all these
keyboards are some shift keyboards it is
it is a particular way to improve
Japanese you know it's like you can call
it thumb shift system in fact trunk and
M system I believe they borrowed ideas
from the thumb shift keyboard because
Trung also remember trunk also have two
thumb shifts you know red and blue they
borrowed that idea from thumb shift I'm
pretty sure so anyway some shift
they began in thumb shift is also known
as Nikolas system it's why is it called
nickel nickel our system because it's
somewhat complicated because the thumb
shift design
what originally was invented by Fujitsu
then they were passed to some consortium
okay Ning honk oh hi or Raikou
consortium meaning Japanese input
consortium then they changed the name to
officially to be Nicola layout because
from the words Ning honk Oh nyah ruku
consortium layout
you know acronym Nicola layout some
shift so you can see some shifts
keyboards on word processors from 1980
and we can see an ad you know 1980s ad
of it
Oasis what processor so I collected some
pictures here you know to do these
pictures takes tremendous time you know
because why you know suppose I found
this picture on Twitter yeah I found it
on Twitter it's Japanese I don't
understand but I can press translate but
usually when you translate you know
first of all it may not make sense
because translate is not 100% accurate
but but mostly when people on Twitter
post something they don't you know they
don't say exactly what this is you know
they say oh this is fantastic you know
that's what they say the audio I love
I've been wanting a keyboard like this
for 10 years you know they say that so
you have no idea you so you can I got a
picture so but I have no idea what what
what it what is it what year who makes
it you know what's the name what's the
model you know I have no idea why why is
it popular white people want it so much
you know I don't know so research and
also so for example if I got this
picture on Twitter I cut the name Oasis
don't you know it's names like three
hours four hours then you you cannot
find you know you have to start to read
Japanese keyboard history oh you have to
have ask people you know that's the
easiest you ask Japanese people can you
tell me the name wise is you know what's
the model things like
you know and by now I learned a little
bit so you know Japanese in the 1980s
they with the help of you know friend
you know Japanese they're you know you
have your processors in Japan so anyway
let's let's go back Mitsuki I wanted to
show you okay so this one is another
thumb shift keyboard made by Fujitsu in
2001 I think you can still buy it
thumb shift oh and this one you know
this one you can buy in 2010 Fujitsu
some shift so here I explain how it
works
some shift you know just like the trunk
okay you have to shift keys and they are
positioned for your thumb now these two
shift Keys they are different you know
they are not just for right hand left
hand they are actually different so two
shifts keys shift keys that makes every
letter key to have three purposes that's
basically what it is for input in
Japanese you know very useful fantastic
very efficient for input in Japanese so
we have we have looked at we have looked
at some shift system then the Truong
system and also the M system remember
they are all different so there is a
question so which one is the most
efficient that's the interesting
question so I now that's a very
difficult difficult question to answer
ok that's actually quite difficult
question to answer
now remember in english-speaking
community we have you know we have court
versus for a quote versus colemak versus
Walkman versus no Norman versus whatever
you know the people
they keep the Nerds you know that they
keep creating different layouts let me
show you
ergonomic keyboards layout so you saw
you we have QWERTY so ms/ms your life
talking let's see how long have been
talking 41 minutes am I good any
questions if you have a questions put my
name to it okay holding down buttons
okay so Chinese people why is Google
banned why does Google ban the the
phrase Chinese people Jesus
you know they you know the American the
typical Americans they'll say who took a
China since the ship since now look at
America you know the you know in China
they have all sort of things going on
you know you type into their forum
you'll see car accidents where the you
see blood you know people got run down
in this blood you know you see also the
things ax accidents right rights on
right right on Chinese forums you know
everywhere videos and everywhere all
kind of accidents and kind of very some
of them are you know kind sick to see
you know like that like this it's so
many okay it's even hard to describe you
know but in USA technically speaking we
are free speech okay that's a
fundamental principle you know it's kind
of the thing of America free speech but
however on YouTube now this is even
before 2010 YouTube Twitter Facebook or
whatever these commercial websites if
you post a car accident let's see I went
out and I was recording something in
over sudden the car come by and in RAM
you know there's accident and someone
died I got I captured on my video by
accident okay I don't go out
intentionally trying to capture some
blood okay buddy
so I have that footage you know you can
you are not allowed to put on a US
website because you know these
commercial organizations they have like
they have like news you know the like
user agreements they don't allow it so
you know so there's a question no no
wait okay you don't allow it so does
that means the censorship you know
American people like you know the
American white people they say oh we
don't have sensitive since the shape
look at China but actually how do you
define it you know in China you have
thousands okay every day every day every
day you have thousands of all sort of
things
you will never ever possible to see it
in America in USA's websites now if you
compare these two which one's got
censorship okay this is even before 2010
before the rise of the social justice
now today you cannot even say or
since in other words they censor it you
know anyway that's a digression into
into the topic of censorship the meaning
of censorship what does it mean exactly
an education for white American people
because they don't know they you know
they have no idea
Reaper are you still here talk okay if
you disagree say it okay I'll address it
so let's go back to keywords what were
we saying so we were talking about the
the the keyboard layouts right so in USA
you know in english-speaking countries
you have a quality you have work you
have program above all rank you know
which improves efficiency for
programmers then you have mini Mac
Cooper asset Norman Commack you know all
these variations now this is for English
letters now in Japan for Japan that
becomes far more complex you know even
for the English language you know just
got 26 letters
you know people compile this study which
one is more sufficient and even that the
the conclusion is inconclusive you know
people people will debate oh comat is is
better than your vorak nova rock is
better no actually you know actually you
need programmers for work actually no
the Walkman is the best one because you
know the comic got problems with with
the index lateral movement you know that
they debate endless
but you see but now for the Japanese the
question becomes even more complex so so
the question about which let's let's go
to look at Japanese keyboard layouts
okay the question becomes more more
complex for many good reasons because
first of all Japanese the Japanese
language is you know the Japanese
languages writing system is quite more
complex than English so in a Japanese
writing system you got 48 letters okay
48 phonetics letters okay the red one
then you got a different set of another
48 letters the blue ones those are
considered it's like a capital letters
okay so 48 of them then you have another
48 the capital case version and they
don't look the same okay unlike English
for example C and capital C looks the
same okay and capped okay looks almost
the same okay
but in Japan you have the capital
version which is very different from the
lowercase version and 48 of them each
then then you have Chinese characters
the Chinese characters come in
so if you see here is a typical let me
show you here's a typical Japanese text
you know this this is a this is Japanese
text from Wikipedia so you you have
those Japanese phonetics hiragana and
katakana then you have Chinese
characters called kanji they call it
kanji okay these Chinese characters you
have to type them in fact the the more
formal is your writing
the more Chinese you're gonna have
you're gonna need it's necessary you
know that's a tradition if you want to
write where and publish it especially
especially in legal documentation IndyGo
documentation so all
scholar documentation writings it's
almost like all Chinese especially a few
years you know a few decades ago anyway
so you got Chinese characters so you
have to type them and they are like
three thousands of them every student
every Japanese has to learn three
thousand Chinese characters then but you
then you also have actually the English
alphabets you know ABCD efg and digits
those are all part of Japanese writing
system officially so Japanese system is
kind of weird also you have you know the
Japanese phonetics first Chinese
characters first the English letters so
it's fairly complex to type them you
know it's the but then then you have to
think about what is the most efficient
way to create a layout or input system
to type Japanese so I have a kind of a
documentation an introduction to all
these different Japanese input systems
how they work and how they look like so
like we mentioned before so so first of
all there's a quote EJ is layout now
this is just like American keyboard okay
then we have the niccola layout which is
the thumb shift we talked about nicol
nicola layout thumb shift then we have
okay so you know I kind of explain how
they work I don't really know Japanese
but you know you can figure out how they
work then you have the M system layout
okay so then you have the JIS x 6004
layout now that's another layout and
it's efficient okay I
then you have the trunk Connally out
okay the trunk jean-louis then you have
you have new Stickney layout so anyway
so I think that's it for my introduction
to the Japanese keyboards the Japanese
economic keyboard stuff just in scarf I
hi Justine how how have you been doing
what else should we go back and talk
about the logo Google bans Chinese
people should we talk about what else to
talk about now let's see let me check
the comments and type your questions
okay I put my name to it I've been
talking for
I've been talking for 51 minutes so I
think let's talk something about the
discord questions so I'm going to do you
know I'm going to update my website from
the name mission the information
omission Chico Chico gave me Michael
Chang I hope to soon and again once
Vicki what Oprah oh yeah oh yeah oh yeah
we haven't done with keyboards yet
because there's a lot update I did today
so let me get let me show you okay let
me talk about some normal keyboards and
first of all we have this one keyboard
with censored okay this word
yeah it's censored if you say it Google
YouTube is going to bang you or the
monetization these scumbags is
anyway so suppression of speech
you know they what will happening is
gonna it's you know it's going to
up society they think these people
social justice type of people you know
they think they are doing good but
actually if you look at if you look
throughout history all those evil
empires all those evil empires like the
end you know in World War two you know
all those evil empires they they all
think they are doing good they actually
all think they are doing good
censorship okay so how anyway so so this
photo let me show you something else
okay so so we got this keyboard
which has key caps for Photoshop now
this is you know it's pretty with
Photoshop key caps and we have let me
show you this one this one this girl
this this keyboard is so sweet
she has to lick it now this keyboard is
very expensive okay this this is
Richman's keyboard this is luxury fc9 a
TC from leo port now Leo port is a
company in Korea I learned South Korea
they make high grade keyboards each one
you know this course cost like $300 each
and they are not economic you know I I
don't like them you know you give it to
me I wouldn't use it but you know if you
are if you like happy hacking you like
it you would like you know a lot nerds
like love these keyboards it's got
Topher switch you know highest quality
so a lot of people love it
in the airport night eight zero see
and by the way there is the there is a
similar version without the number
numeric keypad
this is Leopold FC 6 6 0 C and then then
there is another model that is also Leo
pod which is what this one FC 6 6 0 M M
instead of C now they look the same
ok they look identical they look exactly
the same as the FC 6 6 0 C but however
they are entirely different keyboards
the the in version is actually it's not
mechanical keys I believe you know they
just happen to I mean it's not proper
switch yeah ok the C version is TOEFL
switch the M version is Cherry MX
switch and their keyboard profile is
also different keyboard profiles ok and
actually key size yeah they did differ
in quite a few ways so anyway that
that's a that's the thing let's go back
let's see what else is interesting
Topher's switch okay so why why where
does the name came from Chopra you know
what oops I spelled it wrong he's tio PR
e not GOP not T oper so anyway Thomas
which you know it it came from the
company table her table her cooperation
but why does why is cooperation topic
cooperation aimed so it's because the
company was was called Tokyo press keo
keo company limited but in 1985 October
they changed their name to topher
cooperation why tapa so so tofa is
actually abbreviation for tokyo press I
mean not abbreviation where he came from
the words Tokyo press so that's Topher
okay so I think that's it about
keyboards today should I shut down or
talk something else
let's see comments oh now there's a lot
questions
talking team targeting me wait easier
where did it go oh there so let me
let me answer them I love your keyboard
works your website is great thank you
maths maths cubes let's hold in down
button say so how much time did it took
sure Russian standard keyboard key map
ok Alan Alan has a particular interest
about Russian layout let me show you ok
this is Alan's thing layouts ok we go to
layouts and we go to Russian layouts
Russian so you know he is Russian you
don't know what they are saying
because you don't know Russian no do I
but you have to study you know you when
you study layout you're actually above
the English country you know for example
I'm interested in efficiency of layout
so I look you know I want to know is is
Russian layout efficient or not but in
order to do that you actually you know
if you don't know the language you have
to know you kind of you know so I have
to find out what other Russian are
alphabets then you have to find out you
know the frequency of the Russian
alphabets
if you don't know Russian that's Russian
that's a lot work because when you see a
letter you you don't quite recognize it
you know you know we we don't think too
much of about that when we read ABC you
know because we've been dealing with it
for tens of years but when you look at
Russian like you don't know you are not
familiar so sometimes you get mixed up
and and all that so yeah actually it's
quite a lot work
so anyway Russian layout heat heat map
so it turns out on the Russian you know
the normal Russian layout from Microsoft
Windows you can switch to Russian you
know the the it so happens that the most
frequent frequency used letters are like
near the center like centralized system
just like communism central central
control they have a Central Committee in
in an Allen for some reason loves
lovelies Russian layout because it is
corty theory right ok I used to welcome
a layout I love it ok math cubes ok math
cubes join discord if you haven't been
already you know say who you are because
on discord we can talk and know each
other and lots of talk which we a lot of
people are talking about all sort of
things very interesting stuff you know
on this code beautiful stuff beautiful
people and all sort of things people
talk about
fujitsu Nikola was loved by professional
typists simply so-so named Jean can you
say so can you tell me you know which
which Li which of the Japanese input
systems are supposed to be the most
efficient I mean I understand that back
in 1980s there are there were a lot
competitions
you know typing competitions to see who
can type the fastest and I understand
that the thumb shift system many time
became the champion you know they they
they are the best but that was 1980s do
you know do you have a do you know any
updates I'm I'm guessing today they
still have such competitions right at
least unofficial like on some Japanese
websites they have something similar to
you know typeracer right like the
website you compete to see who can type
the fastest so so do you know what you
know which one is the most efficient
like any such studies or websites or
competitions you know actually I asked
this question to Japanese people on
Twitter you know what one of the
interesting thing is that all these
Japanese layouts the trunk the thumb
shift the M system you know they are
actually not used by anyone like
nobodies are using them the vast
majority like 99.99% of Japanese people
they are just using the the core tjs
input system and layout which is very
inefficient extremely inefficient
that's a situation you know because
habit you know habit you know it's such
a strong influence ripple good morning
Reba so math cube say so someone that is
trained as a firefighter you
you can post car accidents cause it's
these you cannot you cannot post car
accidents okay math cube says someone
that is trained as a firefighter you
cannot post car accidents because it is
disrespect and an invasion of privacy
for the persons involved they may not
want it to be shown yeah exactly I
understand you see that's American
that's American concern the American
culture nothing wrong with that okay but
but you have to understand that's my
point
other coke culture they do not share
that mentality okay you have to
understand this aspect this is what I'm
trying to say important now for a
typical American you know we grew up you
know we educated we you know we grew up
here I didn't grew up here but most
white people right you would think yeah
obviously how can you possibly post a
car accident picture on the web because
you that's that's you know invasion of
privacy you know what if it's your you
know family who got killed and somewhere
else post a picture everyone else see it
make you know maybe they make fun of it
you know you would think that but my
point is that that's that's American
culture you know very narrow that's just
America anyway everywhere else around
the world they don't share they don't
they don't share that mentality that's
the thing other places around the world
they also respect you know they do they
do good they forbid stealing they have
lost mostly okay however they don't
share the similar attitude with
the American that's just one way that's
my that's my point
therefore in Russia in China okay now I
don't know about Japan okay
but I know for sure in Russia in china
in Taiwan you will see call you know car
accidents not just car in industry you
know you in heavy industry where they
have machinery you've never seen before
people get you know cut you know head
chopped chopped off or arms eaten things
like that you will see all people
suicide okay you'll see people suicide a
video of it you know someone jumped from
tenth floor you will see a video of it
right away the next day and everyone
sees it you have pictures like that
videos like that
almost every day every day okay
no so are you saying yo oh that's
because all Chinese are heads they
don't respect human life he said what
you think Oh all Russians are
you know no they don't share the coat
that's that's my point
you know in America was especially the
social justice you know they
say Oh multiculturalism
we must respect black people African
people other country other cultures
them they they are the people who
least respect other other cultures they
what they are they want the
multiculturalism in America is just
respecting other people with different
skin color funny hats you know Chinese
funny funny eyes you respect that funny
hats you know whatever the robes you
know the the India India or the Middle
East or whatever they wear that's that
you don't you detect respect nothing the
actual culture you know the the
mentalities you know these white people
they don't they don't share and in
fact they they go out of their way to
forbid it that's the social justice
people so remember my point is that
other countries they don't they don't
share you know their that's why they are
they are called different cultures
culture that's the thing America culture
Chinese culture Russian culture Japanese
culture they are different okay
so he said that that is why in Japan in
Russia you can see all these different
things you mean while you cannot and
wing meanwhile back to my point before
you know American they are thinking you
know this an educated you know the other
country they censor but depending on
what you mean you know that is not
simple as simple as that
you know in China they say they do
sensor they censor one thing that is
when you attacked attacked the
government which is the Communist Party
you attack the leadership you create
situations that create creates
instability for the country
that thing you cannot talk about any
other thing you can talk about the kind
of like that so it's not necessarily
good okay so I'm not saying it's that
that way is good it's just different
Cauchy theory rising okay so if you show
it it's got very popular size day and
probably would negative no I don't think
so mad okay here okay here here is where
I put my personal opinions on a
situation about showing let's say car
accidents on a web now as a typical
American Way of thinking you know you
don't do that because you know there's
the invasion of privacy or that or you
know things like that but in my opinion
okay if I were to create law I don't
think so no that's okay you can do that
you know you you you I would allow
people to post pictures of death not
okay remember I'm not talking about
malicious ones you don't you don't go
out and and and and like profit you know
try to be be some kind of professional
that you owe you to is trying to capture
you know this in America there's a word
you know these kind of photos this
there's what you know like the things on
fortune the fortune and other
chance you know America meanwhile
they're obsessed about privacy meanwhile
you have this 4chan and other other
channels you know do things cause
you know it's like anyway so so my
opinion is that this is nothing this
actually there is nothing much wrong to
allow in a normal way naturally you know
photos or videos of accidents okay
you know that's my opinion
okay I think I'm gonna shut down Chinese
characters are engineer engineering
articles in scale abroad so even their
health insurance finds out that me screw
them over okay so because opposed Allen
says okay my roommates they are cooking
dinner I'm hot and I think I've been
sitting here for too long I gotta go
so how long I been talking 1 hour and 10
minutes
let's finish five moments or something
Jesus
Allen downloaded me I thinking so what
algorithm things maybe like reddit where
this generates controversy because I
post our Japanese keyboard efficiency
analysis Just Jeans cafe what's a cha
cha Truman such a shame so Holly
oh just in scaffolding Scavo says he's
resting at home not going out and
reading novels at home and also drawing
comics well
okay how come there aren't any uh go
keyboards with topaz switches they are
what they are that micro trunk
that's topaz reach okay and not many
though and I know I know there's more I
can't remember had moments I I'm pretty
sure there's another one I think anyway
the the micro Chong is Topher switch
okay and you know I don't like Topher
switch myself I actually I don't like it
at all
okay I'm thirsty and I'm hot anga Rocco
one more one last question okay guys one
last Jesus
almost done ok so let's see asking
compatible assume lease walks in put us
without extra keyboard you know one
thing about the Russian layout is that
they are you know Russian Russian they
got their alphabet is too many too many
alphabets 33 letters 33 letters so in
order to fit their put their alphabets
on the you know normal US keyboards they
have to remove lots of punctuation for
example all these characters
you cannot type all these characters on
the Russian layout the square brackets
the curly brackets the angle brackets
the you know vertical line the end and
percent the carrot the dollar sign the
pound sign the head sign the tiered sign
you cannot type those characters on the
Russian layout so if you are a
programmer you are fact so you know I
have Russian programmers telling me so
the way they do is that when a program
they have to constantly switch in and
out of the Russian layout so when you
program you use the quality layout but
if you want to write Russian in comments
for example you have to switch to the
Russian way up so they I have are gone
that is quite painful
uh okay so that's about that Russian
layout so an IKE Japanese key was stuff
okay so Jay gun says do you have a
first-time buyers guide hmm yeah I do
well if you want organ ami keyboard just
go to my website okay now time to peddle
my website go to my economics my
keyboard website you'll find all sort of
advices those are all updated okay don't
you just go and read them best
ergonomic keyboard sauce pic okay I'll
show you several and you know so you can
go and check them out unless you have
specific question math cube says what
are your thoughts on an Ergo keyboard
tray okay so you are talking about the
keyboard tray so you know no mori so we
have the concept of keyboard trays you
know keep so this is your table and
keyboard traces like lower level a tray
that you pull it out I don't use that
okay I I don't I don't think I like it
I don't I don't like that it's too
complex you know then you have the
mechanism of something underneath you
have to pull it out also I don't like
you know there are some desk some desks
instead of a tray they cut a hole you
know in your area and then they lower
the level you know like the deck on a
aircraft carrier it's like you can move
you know they cut out a square then you
can move that part down then you put
your keyboards there I don't like that
neither I want my desk to be flat like
just one giant piece of flat flatness
so what would you know so because so
it's simpler
you know normally people like the desk
tray because you know because that's
supposed to supposedly to be more
ergonomic because you know you are
supposed to your hands let me show you
okay you see your hands is supposed to
be like 90 degrees when you when you sit
and type you know not not like that or
not like that like you know you want
your hands to be like 90 degrees for me
typically when I see it my hands are not
like 90 degree are like that okay I've
been doing you know these for like for
30 years so by in theory I should be
like this but actually for me is like
that because yeah I don't I don't like
those I can I cannot say you should do
it this way or that way so I just don't
like that myself and I don't think I
have any hand pain issues related to
that not because of that
so I Alan says Alan says centralized
layout on Russian keyboard means less
kinking pinky finger used and more
pointer and middle finger use that's
true yeah but however I don't think it's
a Bonomi
exactly you know science Alan you have
to put your quarry theory you have to go
you have to push your quarry theory
through science to see if science drops
your quarry theory
so the first step you have to use is to
be precise what exactly mean by quarry
theory and can it be falsifiable so once
you have a definite you know you have
the exact definition science you know
the Western science which got us nuclear
nuclear bomb and we end by science we go
to space we go to the moon so do you
want your coded theory to be scientific
if if if if not then you cannot go to
the moon okay so if you wanted to be
scientific you have to be precise what
exactly is your Cori theory what are you
trying to say and then cuz you measure
it by statistics you know you can
there's so many ways you know you can do
statistics you can do survey you can
measure key counts you know just like
you know those layout comparisons you
know makes your finger travel or
whatever so Cory theory first of all
what define it precisely they measure it
validated see if it works then you have
a theory well Allen says Allen says the
Corey theory is not exactly falsifiable
therefore it's actually not a theory but
it's kind of like a way of life right
the way of life the e and young yeah
well yeah that's great
so that means it just can be anything
anything you want is anything you like
can be quite a theory okay I think
that's it for today so Alan says Alan
says for Japanese keyboards if you use
the manche input you don't have to press
as many modifiers
this is preferable really oh yeah okay
well that's yeah that's that's yeah but
that's just one aspect of it they are
quite a lot other aspects for example
yeah it is true okay so so we are
talking about details of the Japanese
input system remember we are talking
about the several different Japanese
input system which one is the best but I
didn't go into detail because the in the
Japanese input system you have two
primary categories of differences one is
Roman G based system or English letter
based system meaning that you type
English English letters like ABC
ABCD efg and so on then that gets
converted to the Japanese phonetics
alphabet you know so there's a
conversion process you type the English
letters just like on the QWERTY keyboard
then you convert that to the Japanese
letter that's one way one system this
this system is called Roman G command G
input system Roman G means woman Roman
letters womp-womp
okay just English alphabets so that's
one system now the other I mean one
category of the Japanese simple system
the other category is the kana kana
based system meet that that which means
you type the Japanese letters themselves
directly like when you press a key
it becomes a Japanese letter okay that's
the that's the kana based systems okay
so you have two two categories of them
so Alan is saying other than saying the
the English alphabet best based system
is is is preferable because for at least
one reason that reason is you don't have
to you don't have to press so many
modifier keys
why because remember in Japanese you
have 48 kana then you have another 48 of
them cap capital version you know
katakana so you have like these 100
letters you have to type so and then you
have to you have variations with the
that out and you know of variation
with the accent mark so you have about
like hundred 200 letters you have to
type so if you use the direct Japanese
kana system then that means you also
have to type a lot modifiers you know
like the left shift right shift to
create variations you know capital case
or with the accent you know accent mark
but with the with an English letter
system you don't you you don't have to
because you are typing the pronunciation
yeah yeah but then but then the problem
is here's a problem so that's one
advantage of the alphabet system you
don't have to you don't need so many
modifiers but one of the problem is if
you use the alphabet system that means
for each one Japanese phonetics phonetic
symbol you have to type more than one
character like two keystrokes so you
save you save typing modifiers but then
you double your keystrokes so that's a
thing okay I think I think that's it for
today thank you guys for watching
so Farzin says to you do I use foot
pedals no I don't use foot pedals I
haven't I have them I have one of them
Kinesis corporation gave it to me and I
did a review of it you can see my
textual review and in fact I did a
review of this foot pedal on video you
can you can search YouTube you might
find it but basically I personally do
not use foot pedal and I also do not
recommend
foot panel not really okay yeah I think
there are much more better ways to to to
to for input efficiency anyway so that's
that's that's what I'm saying so go read
my articles bye guys that's a long one
today so we don't we didn't have time to
talk about discord questions you know
discord questions we have one bunch of
questions on discord but they are kind
of you know those are like committee
questions they are not actually
questions for me where is it
so I scanned
I only partially scanned some of it
because I was doing other things you
know one bunch of we have to do that
next time bye guys have a good day
shut down shut down time
and stream