hello welcome everyone welcome to
another episode of sant talk show today
we are going to do three things the
first thing is uh demonstration of uh
Karly keys for emac users cly Keys okay
that's the first thing it will be maybe
maybe 20 minutes then I'm going to talk
about mathema matics bog gospel uh bog
gospel mathematics and Conway scheme of
life that's cellular automata so if you
are a programmer you will be very much
interested and uh some mathematics
okay uh B gosper is a well-known
mathematician and he is a he's a hacker
he's the first the you know he's the he
is a guy who kind of brought up the
original hacker community commity hacker
at
Massachusetts uh Institute of Technology
MIT so bper and Richard storman they are
kind of in the same uh group in AI
research department at MIT in the 70s or
80s okay so we're going to talk about
that guy so first of all let's do s like
Keys okay I'm going to do demo of stuff
like this okay first of all this is my
keyboard this is glove 0
keyboard uh you can visit my website
search for S glove 0 I have a
review
uh gra8 keyboard okay fantastic and over
there it's automat hacking keyboard I
also have a video review it's also great
uh you can find ons.info okay so that's
about my keyboard let's switch
screen uh and let's talk about safly
keys in emx okay and also I have a
Discord if you guys don't know so join
Discord you can find a Discord link
atar
doino okay so here is my homepage Kar
code and the Discord you can find the
Discord link there okay it's updated
every month uh if you are here say hi
okay so now let's do let's demo cly Keys
okay so cly Keys it's for emac
users so if you don't I mean emac is a
text editor very powerful one like VI
Vim uh or VSS code so if you are you
know I no need introduction so I
recommend emac now but however emac has
got a major problem is that the key
binding so if you want to move a word
forward or backward move the CER you you
have to do contrl B to wait contrl B
yeah is move backward contrl f is move
forward then if you want to move by word
it's old F okay I disabled the key but
old F so basically the keys are very
comp very complex for example if you
want to open a file that's crl X control
F you know that asks you to open the
file so the keys are very convoluted and
uh if you are a programmer you are going
to have develop RSI it's going to hurt
your hands now lucky for me I have this
fancy Batman keyboard glove 80 so it's
helps a lot but still it's very
conversome so Sly Keys is the idea
that you know do away with this
complicated key binding it's a model
it's a key binding system so in emac for
example right now I'm using Sly keys and
in the pink window you can see as I move
as I press any key you can see the
command shows up on the pink window can
you see that yeah the command shows up
there and the keystroke I pressed to do
that command is also shows I'm using a v
keyboard layout so for example I want to
move up two paragraph I press that I
press that press that press that it just
you know move up paragraph So so the
command isar beginning of line or block
Ora end of line or block so you you you
can see look at my look at my right hand
you know it's one single key press I
don't have to control something if I
want to move cluer by word for example
to the right or left I can just do that
you know right or left left right and
the command is forward word and backward
word by a single key there's no control
F or alt F
something okay and if I want to say
delete this paragraph I again just press
a key you see it's gone now I want to
undo press a key it's undone you see
those commands are called delete current
text block and undo you see let's try
again delete now let's say say I want to
delete multiple paragraphs so I just
hold this key you see then undo Undo You
Know undo all the
way undo yeah okay there so the idea is
that you don't have to hold control meta
so it's a model like VI or Vim key
binding now so why don't I just use Vim
emulation like the Evo mod well the
problem with Vim is that Vim you know
the the way the the Vim V key binding is
historical so
it's not someone sit down and decide and
design it and saying that okay so to
delete the paragraph let's say to delete
the current line you know the most
efficient key would be this finger
because this is the most powerful finger
so they design all the key binding
according to that no it's not like that
VI is through history you know it's it's
complicated and uh so it's not uh
optimal it's not optimal so therefore in
sof FL keys
you the key binding is more optimal
hello guys hello great to see you guys
do you think emac C binding will cause
isi even with an ergonomic keyboard okay
that's one question uh man you change
display what
display uh good evening good evening so
if you are using a ergonomic a very you
know uh bad main keyboard uh very very
radical designed ergonomic keyboard and
expensive 300
400 that helps a lot so the question is
will you develop RSI if you use
ergonomic key keyboard with the default
emac that depends you know depends on
how much you type how what's your typing
habit you know uh and also also that
depends on whether you turn on sticky
key sticky key is one of the best thing
okay that for example two press contrl F
if you have sticky key on that means you
press control first release it then you
press F you don't have to hold control
then press F release F and then unhold
control so sticky keys I highly
recommend it okay it's available on Mac
on Windows on uh Linux but let's go back
to uh talk about Sly Keys okay so s keys
let me show you the source code so
here's a source code so there are about
4,000 lines of code now and it's
available on G Alpa so the homepage you
can just search for S FL Keys you'll
find it and it's also on GitHub and it's
on G Alpa repository so it's part of the
free software Foundation SC repository
okay so so that's a basic concept about
sofly Keys here's a homepage so you can
see uh here's a friend who sent me this
photo you know he's learning s like his
this this is like seven years ago uh and
with cheat sheet so this is basically s
like keys and here is a cheat sheet of
the key binding so it's available for
quity keyboard for V keyboard for comat
you you can click to switch for comat DH
or for Workman so it's available for
many for about 10 layouts including
German layouts and and so so
on so the idea is that you don't have to
press control Oma anymore hello Fant
Alan thank you Alan economic
stimulus thank you Alan Alan Allan is a
great guy Allan i i i i Allan sent me
$2,000 donation okay uh so that is a
huge sponsor forar talk show huge $2,000
and also Dion also Dion has sponsored me
uh
$2,000 so those are uh thank you Alan
thank you a
lot uh okay so back to soft keys so the
idea is like Vim it's a model mod the
idea is that you don't have to press
control or meta uh that will create you
know give you RI you know so I've been
I'm a touch typer since 1980 8 I type on
mechanical typewriter back then I love
typing that was actually data entry was
my job I did that for two years in my
job as a secretary so a Salesman they
will dictate you know dear something
client you know uh if you want to
someone something something salesman you
know so they speak I type in real time
so I did that so I'm a touch typist I
never had a problem until 2005 2005 is a
year
I started to have RSI like I like
tingling um and eventually I discovered
that's before uh wait that that was um
that's the the cause is because I was
using a laptop keyboard for over one two
years exclusively on a Mac iPad you know
Mac laptop so that was the cost then you
know anyway that's my history of Ri so
and back then even up to that time 2005
I'm not I'm I'm using the default emac
keys so to open a file is like control X
control F you know to open the
file uh and to undo is well undo is a
lot keys but you know one of the keys is
control shift uncore you know any
anyway um so sof like Keys okay now let
me
Demo
now let me let me Demo um install it
okay so I'm using sofl keys it's
fantastic let me go over a little bit
about the design of the keys okay so in
general the right hand side you know
this three finger you see this this
um let's see can you see it yeah so you
see these three fingers that control the
arrow so inverted T arrow on on your
right hand side then above those two
fingers uh you and O is the left go to
left by word or go to right by word so
that's that so for example arrow keys
okay so Arrow up down left right let's
magnify right so let's so right left up
down then if you want to go by what it's
that
that and if you want to go move by
paragraph So I we demonstrate it before
so you see I can hold it down and it's
like you don't even have to go to press
page up or page down you know you can
just move by paragraph
fantastic and so that's all left that's
all right hand CER movement and also
some selection for example if I want to
select the whole paragraph I press six
if I want to select again press six six
you see if I want to
cut it's a left hand uh X unquote 40
okay cut you see undo is right hand
again so in general the right hand is
moving
cises they you know and the left hand is
for
deleting uh deleting and modifying uh
text for example let's say I want to
delete this paragraph the left hand you
know the left hand quy G delete again
press again okay undo is right hand undo
undo so you kind of alternate so
basically on the left hand so if you
want to delete by word to the left that
that that okay if you want to delete by
right that that that you see so now Ando
and do Ando and do and do and do you see
so kind of in general the left hand is
modifying deleting any text right hand
is moving cses okay so that's a basic so
now let's install let's start a new emac
okay let's go to
Powershell and let's install a new emac
I mean yeah let's install uh sof Keys
starting from scratch okay so let's go
to my uh.
emac so let's start emac so you can see
GCM which
means this is
Powershell G GCM means finding command
so it's equivalent to Unix which okay uh
the the command the full name for G GCM
is get command I
think yeah that's a full name by the way
Allan when I was learning poers shell
Alan was the one telling telling me you
know I was asking what's the powers
shell command for for the Unix switch
and Allan told me that so anyway GCM
emac you can see I have emac installed
and let's launch emac but this time Dash
q that means do not start with any init
file so we can do that you see so we got
a you know plain go Emax up there okay
now to quit is control X control C okay
let's quit that so start emx again now
this time L is for load dasl so I want
to load my own unit file so so let's
create it here so open new file let's
see let's say
um save it
init.el X init.el okay overwrite uh I
don't want to overwrite so there's
already oh there's already X in it okay
because I tried to do that okay
so so this this file is at this file
path so we want to start emx emx
DQ don't load any in it then-
l-h out means load in it okay at this
location
okay uh we can use Tia for homepage okay
so this is a command you want to launch
and let's
say let's commment those
out okay so let's launch
emex paste do it there it is okay now
quit contrl x contrl c okay now let's
modify the init so that first of all we
want to load oh wait let's install Sly
keys from scratch remember okay let's do
that so right now the unit is empty
because it's all Comon out so first of
all start emac this is like when you you
know when you begin
emac let's do this quickly because we're
going to talk about other fun things and
I'm going to read you guys comments oh
uh what
happened I magnified by mistake so large
but no I have a hard time to magnify oh
okay
yeah
cancel how do
you
magnify this idiotic Google let's just
do it
here what the chat is now
G top chat chat live chat
okay uh pop out
chat okay so back the chat is
back okay back to
[Music]
emac yeah so we are trying to start emac
there it is
now so when you start emac you want to
install s FL Keys okay so you call the
command meta X oh God this so small tiny
so you say list
packages meta X list packages okay there
it is there is your packages now in emx
29 you can press control alt and scroll
up to magnify the font for All Purpose
system wide okay so that's Control Alt
scroll up okay so anyway here it is this
package Pages Now search forar flly Keys
control
xar there it
is so there it is from n okay so you
press enter to hit to open that uh
uh then you just go to this
window tab click
install
uh yes okay so it's going to install
it now actually where is it installed it
actually installed in my emx I think uh
let's look Alpa yeah there it is it
installed there anyway so let's we can
so let's open it so here's a file open
it copy the file path close close close
close close now let's put the file path
here okay so we're going to so in so in
your init file all you have to do is say
load file
uh load
file uh and uh here is
your file path okay load file the that
file
path okay you load sofly keys actually
you can say require anyway let me just
go on so and uh yeah actually you can
just say require and then all you have
to do is you have to say a layout s like
he set layout if you are a normal person
you just say quy then you have to put
this sign softly Keys one that means
turn it on okay so load the file
actually you don't need it because
requireed we do it anyway so here is our
new in file okay now let's go back to
emac now close that emac let's
restart and with that init file do
it now let's see if sof FL key is
working now I don't have to press any
control I just press the right hand
let's see if it moves closer there it is
fantastic now I can
magnify uh wait yeah magnify let's
control
control old scroll
up you see now sof key is installed I
don't have to press any control or meta
so you I can select the whole paragraph
I can copy the whole buffer open a new
uh open open a new paste it you see we
pasted that paragraph
actually
uh close it so copy all new buffer
paste there it is anyway so now I can
delete the left word to the left or
delete word to the right or I can move
curer actually let
magnify uh one more time where is the
emx let's Control Alt
let's make it bigger so I can uh
what control G2 quit Okay so yeah so I
can delete the line from the cruiser to
the
end there it is there's no so I don't
have to press any control any any of
that so there it is we just install it
okay so I think that's so let's close
emac so that I think that that concludes
a demo of sof like keys so there is
tutorial you can go through there is a
short intro if you just read the
homepage what does the command mod do
what does the insert mod do and uh how
do you call some of the frequently used
commands such as switch buffer find file
open
file split pens you know some of the
simple things everyone needs to do you
know intr ction then there is tutorial
there is
customization there is um and there is
key binding if you are using one of
these fancy
keyboard let see yeah you can see you
know I have some uh specialized key
binding you can use I mean as a choice
then there's a history why do I create
when did I create it why and so on okay
that's it for flly Keys 25 minutes not
too bad let's see what you guys are
saying when is the last Danielle Daniel
W Daniel W which Danielle are you when
is the last time you watched star check
oh that must be long
ago well I mean I don't have a TV since
year 2000 so I watch YouTube so Star
Trek so usually I just watch
Clips um but but I haven't watched Star
Trek for a long time and you know since
2010 the whole classic sci-fi movies
they got they became rotten because the
Zuma generation you know they started to
do their things so know especially that
include Star Wars oh hey hello Daniel
Wood uh d Danielle Wood from Canada Alan
from
California and uh uh chista and uh Hank
hello Hank from United States Midwest I
believe be a gosper okay let's move on
to the next topic unless you guys let's
move on to the next topic
mathematics fantastic okay SOA is yeah
we done uh this is you know the whole
thing for like is is for Kim pum Kim
Pome a programmer he's writing he's
creating a new lisp
language so anyway let's so I'm done
with this uh any file close close close
close close close and uh yeah this is
SES go back
close likees source code and what is
this saw emx blog uh we did I did a lot
of things you can check out
and back to S Talk Show let's talk about
mathematics bog gospel now bog gospel is
a fantastic mathematician he's a hacker
okay so be a gospel so first of all for
example you can look at Wikipedia here
there's a
entry you know he this is a guy he's
pretty old now age 80 now so that's be a
gospel he's a hacker he's a nerd okay
he's one of the Prototype of nerd nerd
he you know he's at you know he's
Richard strowman generation at MIT an
artificial researcher he's a
mathematician but but he's into
programming and Computing and in
particular he's into
hacking you know a type of programming
activity you guys you know many of the C
type of people love you know like little
little trick little bit manipulation so
you can multiply faster you know bit did
didling you know the the bit operators
you know that spread like a virus to all
other languages like bit shift you know
bit shifting
yet you know we have a few people loves
that you know I I I uh the the the wit
guy comes to mind and several others and
hot dog and and mover you know they they
like that you know anyway he's a hacker
he's he's one of the best one he's a
original hacker
that founded the hacker community that
basically created the word hacker okay
Bill gosper and he's not just a hacker
he's not he also worked with Donald G
you know so you know so that's that's
this generation of hacker real hacker
the original hacker and he made many
contributions uh in many ways that's
very interesting to us okay he uh for
example let me show you a few gospel
algorithms SC hash life you know this
this algorithm you know so he many of
the things that's named after him you
know so he's
accomplished uh computer scientist and
mathematician so you have gospel curve
gospel algorithm and hash life hash life
and gospel glider gun that's amazing
okay that's about Game of Life so anyway
that's a
guy uh and I'm going to show you let's
see uh some of the math math so the
thing he has done you can kind of divide
it to two categories okay I don't really
know the biography of this the guy very
well so I might made me some mistakes
forgive me so but I'm just going through
what I know about this guy B gosp yeah
great um mathematician okay so he so
what he has do he has done can be
divided into two kind of of sections one
is mathematics okay so let me first of
all show you the the traditional
mathematics part okay look at this
page okay so
that's that's what you know that's some
of the identities he found uh and let's
page down okay so there's so many page
down page down very complicated
identities okay
so you you don't even you know you even
I I I don't understand half of it you
know understanding like of course I
understand what does this formula mean
but but how does it work or is it true I
have no idea okay that requires a
specialized mathematician in analysis in
number Theory to actually
know so all so many of these or all of
them is unknown it's new you cannot
solve it by Mathematica for example you
know let's start Mathematica because we
are going to do it you know you type
this in Mathematica Mathematica doesn't
know the answer but you you but I can
tell I did the first one this is true
because if you try numerical values it
comes comes out closer and closer so
this one for example it says limit n to
Infinity then you have this product pi/
2 RCT 10 n
time pi/ 2 Octan n + 1 times and so on
so on until pi over 2 Octan 2 N okay so
you multiply all this together to
Infinity okay as n approaches Infinity
the result
is is is is the the the py root of
four so that means 4 rais to the power
of one over Pi okay so this is you know
this is just incredible incredible okay
and I type this in Mathematica yesterday
it doesn't it doesn't know the answer so
he has lots of the point is that he has
lots of
these um let me show you a few let's go
down so Octan you know
summation
tangent and here is a hyperbolic a
tangent
Arc you know a
TN A T A and H that's hyperbolic tangent
uh arc tangent function okay which is
defined by you know e plus e ided by two
something like that you can look up
hyperbolic AR tangent so you know some
of the these equations is amazing okay
it so this these are his discoveries and
uh many of them are not
known to other mathematicians you know
so they are not they are not known to
humanity so I'm trying to work out you
know I'm trying to document some of
these okay so this so incredible okay so
these are some of the some this is this
page is just some of them like 20 of
them he's got lots of more um and he
he's a
Pioneer in computer algebra system like
wfam language okay let so anyway so let
me show you wam language and show you
some some of these okay
so so so this part is what he has done
as part of traditional mathematics his
accomplishments you know we could say
you know all this or this extremely
complicated
formula it takes even sometime to even
type them up up you
know so there are pages of them pages
and and these are done by Maxima I think
I'm not sure so you can see this syntax
because he's a Pioneer in computer AR
system so he also write you know the
code in this he's he's a master he's
he's one of the founder he's one of the
biggest lisper okay comparable to to
Paul grham I mean even before Paul grham
he's like almost like previous
generation Paul grham is a guy who you
know who who created Hacker News who
created the hacker Funding Company you
know he wrote a program a Yahoo online e
sto back in year 2000s and sold to Yahoo
for million or billions of dollars
that's how he become very rich po gram
and he's a big lisp fan
and uh so bog gosper is another you know
one of the greatest Giant in lisp
Community is you know so these are
written in MA lisp I think in the 1970s
or or uh
80s so anyway so you you go through
these formulas just amazing amazing you
know of them so I'm kind of going
through them one by one and document
what they
are uh so let me let's try try the first
one I tried this you know first one let
let me show you the first one okay
um in wam language okay so let's see
where is my wam language okay so there
it is open a new document it's evaluate
three shift enter okay let's magnify so
you can see so now let's type the first
one okay we're going to do that then let
me talk about so so that's the part of
mathematics bog gospel is known for you
can read in W Wikipedia Wikipedia will
say
um we'll mention some of these now the
other interesting too many of you know
this this mathematics is very hard if
you are not a professional mathematician
this doesn't mean much to you you cannot
appreciate it you know and you know so
you have to be you have to know calculus
then you kind of like are dazzled by it
but you have to be a professional uh
analysis to actually know what is
actually their significance so anyway
that's esoteric but but B goel has done
lots of other that's more interesting
hacker or Computing things to us okay
for example this this curve this curve
you know you might call it a fractal but
it's a it's you know the technical is
it's called space fing curve okay this
is one of the most beautiful gosper
snowflake okay one of the most beautiful
and you can it it is stun recursively
essentially you replace each line by
this you replace each segment of line by
this figure then you get that am I right
something like that okay I I drew this
like 20 years ago you know for example
you can search
for Aro
make math
art so you know I also am very
interested in these kind of things so I
drew one of B gospers
curve here okay I you know actually I
saw this from a book was it from a book
from an i yeah and I uh I think I Cod it
in wam language or I did some yeah I
think I called it in wam language
so so and uh I
think you know anyway so that's that's
that's this this is the B gopas curve
okay
um this one called gospel curve or flow
snake that's the name I know by flow
snake why is it called flow snake
because it's a pun on the on another
very famous curve this this one Kos
snowflake you know so this this one it's
a factor
curve uh with non integer Dimension you
know very interesting so when you if you
study calculus and limit you know one of
the issue is that you want to study how
long is this
curve you know this this curve is
infinitely uh cringed you know so you
want
to use the technique of calculus to find
out how long is the curve that's one
problem the other thing you want to find
out is what is the area of the co of the
thing you know kach snowflake very uh
famous uh and if you are a programmer
you know one of the most interesting to
thing to do is to draw this you know you
can use python or whatever to actually
draw it so I recommend you guys do it
okay
so let's see uh so K so say something
say something uh guys let me
know so Co snowflake is very popular so
that's why this one gospers curve is
called uh gosper flow snake it's a it's
a pun so lots of so this is this is kind
of the what the hacker Community do like
the Unix you have lots of puns you know
unix commands so anyway this is very
interesting interesting so that this is
one of the Gospel
um creation you know and uh and lots of
more lots of more so let's talk
about uh Game of Life okay I let's talk
about Game of Life for a bit you know
game of life I don't know if you guys
know but if you have not know it before
I highly recommend that you look at it
now in the 199 you know it's a crazy
hackers or nerds or computer programmers
or
mathematicians around late 80s and 1990s
I spent several years every every day
several
hours play kind of play this you know
so so B
gosper found many
um you know made many discover
discoveries in this thing cellular
automata
okay so let's see cellular automation
gam live so here is the article you
search for Conway scam of Life on
Wikipedia and you'll find this okay
so I'm going to so let's go over that a
bit then you know that's for today's
video let's go over Game of Life a
bit and then I'm going to
type
this SP gospel identities in wolam
language just to show so let's do the
let's do the wolam language first
okay so in fact you have to understand
what this equation means you have to do
kind of a bit trans translation okay so
this is
actually actually I did it yesterday so
let's let's save
time instead of me just thinking about
it it takes it takes you have to think
about it so here it is I typed it up
okay so let's just type it
quickly uh bogers identity the first one
okay
uh wam language
okay so let's see if you can see
it uh
okay so I have to move this to the
left okay let's do
it product okay first of all
product
so the product of two things product
takes two arguments the second arguments
is the the first argument is
expression the second argument is the
range so let's say from 100 to 200 x
goes from 100 to two let's say 1,000 to
2,000 and the expression
is the expression is pi/ 2 Octan
okay Pi ided by 2 * Octan Octan is O AR
tangent okay then inside it is
X okay so that is
the let's paste that let evaluate
it so you can see it's a uh it's a
number
uh yeah too many too much so many terms
now you know there are 2,000 actually so
let's just reduce the term let's
say 10 10 to 20
okay
not that shift control okay so let's do
it
again now this time let's make it type
set so in order to do type set control
shift n yeah there it is
now shift enter to evaluate it okay now
copy
the copy the output
actually we can just control shift n to
make it
anyway okay let's do it again and uh
copy the input now let's output let's
force it to numerical results
okay
so if it go if x goes to 10 to 20 the
the answer is 1.6 1.64 something okay
but bog gosper is saying that bper is
saying let's pop this
out okay B gosper is saying this this
this time together is
pi you know 4 rais to the power of one
over Pi so
let's so basa is saying four to the
power of 1 over
pi
uh shift enter okay so you
can copy that and control shift control
shift n to make
it
um to make a type set now we want the
traditional form the traditional form
involves radical
so so if you want to type set in a
traditional form control shift
t h it doesn't do
that uh there's a way to type
that but
um I don't know off hand
so but anyway
so you can evaluate
this so the result you know the py root
of
four is 1.55 okay so you can see this
number is
close so if
you increase let's say
10,000 x goes from 10,000 to
2,000 you know and time them
together
uh you see now the result is 1.55 five
so it's getting closer to this to this
what B gosper claims so this so this is
amazing
so so but if you asked wam language to
actually compute it won't tell you okay
so because for example let's type it
out if you actually ask wam language to
compute
the
uh let me do that here
okay
so it should be
limit okay so limit of this
thing of this product and uh the N the X
should go from n
to to n okay
then X goes to Infinity okay so this is
how you type it this okay so let's
pacing wam
language
okay
evaluated
evaluated you see it came out
unchanged because it doesn't know the
answer okay so for example we can copy
again control shift n to make it typ set
and uh you know uh and uh shift shift
enter to evaluate it came out that way
because it doesn't know the
answer so but we have tried numerical
tried we have tried to evaluate it
numerically we can see you know it seems
correct so that's a amazing thing
about about all these spus identity okay
we are doing the first
one okay so uh you guys still here say
something
guys so that's one of the
thing uh be you know very interesting
now I like to ask you guys th those of
you you know who are into math or
programmers if you are a student or if
you are interested in wolam language
this is a great opportunity to learn
wolam language and some
mathematics hands on so the task I want
you guys to do is to go over this page
this t d this this is sp gospel's
website okay you can see it from my talk
show I have a link and uh type this out
type this B gospel identities in wufan
language
so do
that uh that would be great and then of
course you can try to use you know try
try to see if W language actually know
about these identities and you can then
also try to evaluate these identities
numerically so you can kind of check
whether they are likely true or not you
know it's likely I mean this is you know
from a math from this great
mathematician so this is this this I
don't know but I think this you know
these are I'm pretty sure they are not
known in math communities it's just
something that's just he
found so okay okay type them out okay
and you can uh Twitter on Twitter you
can tweet to me or you can um you know
post it to
Discord I'm trying to collect them all
so you know and maybe comment on you
know and if you are a mathematician
profession professional mathematician
you could tell
me uh what are the significance you know
like B gosper you know he's a he has
contributed a lot to continued factions
okay that's another topic and I don't I
don't really know much about them
continued factions it's amazing so
anyway that's SP gospel
okay yay uh homework
yeah do the equations have a physical
meaning or is it just uh what it goes
towards and is series it's it's these
equations are not no they are not they
are just identities okay so let's go
back to his equations these equations
are many many of these math identities I
mean b gopel have discovered many of
them they are just crazy identities the
the most famous
guy that reminded me you know because go
gosper when I see this that reminded me
is that very famous Indian genius one of
the greatest mathematician okay uh Rama
German you know his name is hard to
pronounce but you can just search for
Indian mathematician so this guy this
some people might consider the greatest
top top 10 mathematicians ever okay he
created you know and this is back then
you know like
1887 to 1920 there's no computers
there's no even pocket
calculators he created
thousands
of
identities kind of you know so to me to
me someone who don't know about this
reminds me you know looks like that so
it's just like extremely complex for
example you have this sum so this you
know when you see this sum this these
are infinite sums so this one for
example this one d244 is saying that if
you add this you know K from zero to
Infinity so you have to add infinite
number of them so so what do you add so
this you know log squared and k + 1 / 2
you know over something k + 1 / 2 minus
log s k + 1/ k + 1 so suppose K so K
begin with zero so you replace K by zero
so you got one term then you then you do
another with k equal to 1 okay then you
do another with k equal to 2 then you
add all of them together now K has to go
to Infinity okay not just 1,000 million
or one billion that's not enough okay
you have to add them to Infinity okay
infinite number you so in a sense you
cannot even do even if you have the most
powerful calculator you know like you
can do it
numerically so this is mathematics so
you have to find theories
to you know so this is part of uh
calculus or analysis so once you so you
so you can then maybe prove this thing
if you add to Infinity it equals to this
thing which is pi/ pi s * log 2 / 6 -
4 um uh this one is um Epson uh Zeta
Zeta or
Epsilon uh and uh Epsilon that's a
special function okay I believe so let's
see gamma function wait is it what is it
yeah so this is part of why this is
interesting because you have to figure
out what
this uh Zeta I think is what is that
Zeta or Epsilon or what is it Zeta
okay uh I believe that character is
Greek
Zeta yeah Greek small letter Zeta
okay
this character
okay so and so you have this zeta
function you take the derivative twice
then you evaluate at zero then Times log
two then minus this complicated thing
and then you see this gamma those are I
believe those are gamma functions yeah
gamma so gamma functions and Zeta this
they are special functions for example
this equation is just amazing like
incredible you know so what does this I
mean it's like
even difficult to
comprehend so here you have the gamma
function so let me show you gamma
function uh gamma function is a special
function okay so even if you studied
calculus usually you don't know this
until you you you know you do master
degree in mathematics focus on analysis
then you learn so here is a gamma
function okay it's a generalization of
the factorial
okay so anyway
so so that's one of the example of the
bog gospel thing you know incredible you
know it's just
incredible so B gosper so when I see
this I don't know so it reminds me of
you know this this Indian mathematician
he's known for creating this whole bunch
of incomprehensible
equations that even the best
mathematicians don't understand it like
you know find it impossible to
understand for example here is one of
the identity this uh Ramon found you
know it's nested radicals so you have
infinite nesting okay so this is
infinite
nesting you know he just like he's like
some people say he's connected to God
you know he just know infinite you know
this is not
just involves infinite
radicals you know so things like that
and this guy created a ton of them here
it is another one example this
integral so you here for example you
have a
integral that involves a product of
infinite product infinite number of
terms you know this times that times
that goes to
Infinity so you have the infinite number
of product then you integrate
them then it's supposed to be equal to
this
thing and on the right side you see
those are gamma functions okay so this
is just amazing
so I don't know nothing about this uh
analysis this this I'm not you know I'm
not sure what kind of um area I think
they are analysis and number Theory okay
involving infinite infinite sequences
and series and and and continued
fractions like infinite nesting
stuff so how did he find that using
Compu
or maybe he's a bit crazy in the
brain both I would say so you know
similar question is how did this guy
ramenu Jan made all these you know
impossible
discoveries so on this topic stepan
wolam has wrote an
article you can um in fact it's
reference it in Wikipedia I
believe yeah there it is it is so wufan
wrote a kind of
analysis of this ramanu Jang
Guai you know talking about how is it
possible why why is he able to do this
these Amazing Discoveries so there's a
movie made out of it you know um you
know there's a movie made out of this so
I highly recommend you read this Stefan
wolam out
and basically we are ex and and this is
one of the most weird amazed Discovery
okay he says 1 + 2 + 3 + 4+ six 5 six to
Infinity is equals to ne1
over2 amazing okay on the surface
obviously it's Force because you add a
bunch of numbers you know how can it
become negative fraction it's like Ed
some not job you know but actually this
has the what the most deep significance
in
mathematics okay I I cannot you know I
cannot even explain it so you have to
you know you you go read Wikipedia
you'll find this equation you know on
the
Reno article you you know just read it
carefully
so so this amazing so you know it has to
do with you know I cannot explain it
really so so wolf fam's
article tries in part to answer how is
it possible this guy you know first of
all he give a biography you know he dig
out where was he born you know like
General biog biography
but takes research you know wol you know
stepan wam did so General biography
about this guy what kind of guy he is
what is he like like uh and then explore
into the question everyone is asking how
is it possible that this guy created
these crazy
equations so to know that read uh U's
article okay so I think May that's it
for today it's been an hour so thank you
guys for watching yeah uh next day you
know next next video we are going to
do uh let's do cellular automat okay
this amazing thing let me show you a few
actually blog
okay let me just uh give you a
taste
of of the cellular aoma okay uh where do
we go so let's go to so there's a book
new book came
out b b gosper told me there's a new
book Conway Game of Life okay you can
buy it and it's also free online but I
want to tell you guys you should you
must try it okay so you just start by
start by reading the Wikipedia article
Game of
Life okay start by reading Wikipedia
then you'll understand what's it about
then I'm going to show
you
uh so where do we
uh go yeah then I'm going to show you
some of
the amazing
things okay so there's a program written
in JavaScript you can try so this is
what B uh game of life is like okay it's
a cellular
autom if you have not heard of it you
should okay that's it for the
um what will the answer be in
Mathematica no it will it won't return
that you know the one over the negative
1 over 12 requires special
interpretation
okay um it requires special
interpretation but you know I I I can't
really
explain it because it's like Beyond me
okay
so and I don't you know I I I so I'm not
the guy to ask so you have to
ask you can actually you can search you
know first read Wikipedia on this guy to
find there's a name to that equation
okay then once you find the name you can
search the web there's quite a few
YouTube I Believe now be careful okay
because when you watch YouTube you know
first of all you'll see lots of you know
screenshots oh my God 1 plus 2 plus
equals to negative you know one over 12
inoss with a funny face you know they
like
clickbait many of the YouTubers they
they don't know they know they just
so you if you are watch YouTube
you have to be very very careful who is
talking so I recommend you watch those
professors video on
these so anyway that's it that's it for
today thank you guys for
watching
bye
guys uh let's see we could we shut down
in in a minute or two so let's see what
I did here
okay so yeah go to the site and try to
type it in Wolf language okay and you
can do that
by you know you just search for so go to
you know just search for k wfam
language you will find my tutorial and
click on the download free so here are
the
instructions uh so you go to their
website so you can download it and uh
let's let me show you wam script okay in
fact yeah I want to show you that so
once you so you can download for free
okay it like it's like 2 gigabyte one
gigabyte download then or you can just
buy a copy okay I
recommend then what you do is for
example let's type this uh in wolam
script okay let's copy that so wolam
script Works in terminal just like bash
python okay
there it
is so we started and uh
paste so there is a result now in wolam
script you don't get the nice fancy type
setting but you can let's see for
example let's type this
one for to the one over P
power okay Enter
so you got this kind of asky type
setting okay and similarly
here okay so now let's say you want the
numerical result of this one so we can
for example type that slash slash n
slash slash is a postfix notation just
like Unix pipe okay n capital N means
give us a numerical result okay so copy
that and here's a great feature so you
can select by increasingly select
syntactical unit you expand okay
copy paste it here control uh did we
copy contrl c contrl
v
what oh okay so you need to copy us
text uh well in in terminal in power
shell so control shift V I guess wait
what is the paste okay right click to
paste enter so you can see there's the
answer now if we
modify 1,00 to
2,000 okay so now it's 1.55 okay so you
can do this
in in the wolarm
script live long and
prosper bye guys