Hello guys, good morning, good evening
everyone. Welcome to another episode of
Star Talk Show. We are going to code
JavaScript today. Advanced JavaScript.
Fantastic.
And have some wine and relax. Just
JavaScript coding. Okay. Meanwhile, I'm
going to tell you something about
JavaScript and maybe you can learn
something from it. This is red wine
about 200 ml
for soothing my soul. This is my
ultimate hacking keyboard UHK80.
There's a review on my YouTube. I
recommend it.
Okay, let's switch my screen to the real
screen and have a zip wine. Let's see.
Okay, fantastic.
So, if you are watching this offline,
play at 1.5 speed. If you are watching
here, say hi.
So, let's pop out this window,
this chat window, so I can be notified
of your comments.
Okay. So what I want to do today's talk
show let's go to JavaScript in depth
search for it you will find it in-depth
tutorial of the best tutorial on
JavaScript everything you want to know
on sardi.info x ah hl.info info. That's
my website. Uh if you got security
error, ignore it because my website do
not ask you for credit card. So you
don't have to worry about oh security.
So uh what I want to do so I'm just
going to code uh some JavaScript. Okay.
So first step is uh JavaScript. Go to um
JavaScript blog. So search for webdev
blog. You'll find it. Tremendous update
on JavaScript. Okay. Now I want to go to
the sort um
array sort. Okay. Array prototype sort.
Now here that's a method to sort array.
Okay. What I want to do is just add a
example of sorting
uh sorting um
objects. Okay. Now so where do I want
it? Uh so this is actually so okay. So
let's expand the window because this is
I have huge font. Um
so let's expand the window so you can
see more. Okay. So this is a sort
method. I want to add a example of
sorting array because I mean sorting um
objects because that's uh often needed.
Now so there's a custom sort order
function. Okay. So let's add there.
Okay. Now again
uh pre okay uh custom okay so let's add
a example here okay so
okay uh all the all the um objects okay
okay so let's just write a uh like just
an example okay so let's Say first of
all you need uh several uh objects
comments there. Okay. So uh let's say so
first of all my
x array. Okay. So uh constants
x array equals to uh array and inside
this array you got several objects named
John
something. Okay. and the edge age uh
let's say
83 that's uh that's too old. Okay. So
let's pick a number 40. Okay. So name
John age 40. Okay. Let's let's have
that. Okay. Copy that. And here is let's
say Mary age uh let's say 12. Well 12 is
not good. And then you know you know
because uh people think about something
let's say 19. Okay.
Well okay. Okay. Anyway so we got a
object of two things name. Let's you
know make the name string you know. Um
yeah you have to so so you got uh
array of objects. You want to sort them.
Okay. Uh so you want to uh sort object
uh
sort objects
in array. Okay. So that's that's what
you want to do. That's the declaration
of your intention.
Am I going video check? Audio check. Am
I alive? Yes. Say hi guys. Okay. We're
doing random JavaScript doodling. Okay,
JavaScript coding. If you have questions
about JavaScript, you can ask me. I can
tell you all about it. Okay, so now
we're going to sort. So you see, we need
to write a custom function. You know,
sort in JavaScript is very lousy. You
know, if you don't know, let me show
you. Okay, sort sorted in JavaScript is
idiotic to the extreme.
If you don't know, let me show you.
Okay, let's say three four uh let's say
uh
eight. Okay, that's array and you want
to sort it, right? So you want console
uh log array. So let's let's uh move it
to the top. Okay, so
the idiocy of sort in JavaScript, that's
what I'm demonstrating. Okay. The ed
idiocy of sort.
So
you know so you got you know you you you
got array 834. You want to sort it
right? Sort is a method. So you get you
know a par. Okay. Run it. You got three
uh 348.
What the [ __ ] is going on? Okay. Well,
that is correct. But what I really what
I meant is that
okay uh wait
what I meant is um
let's say 30 and 40. Okay. 8 30 and 40.
You want to sort it. What do you get?
You get 30 40 then 8. That's idiotic.
Okay. Do you do you guys see what I
mean? Do you do do you do you guys see
this idiocy of the sword in JavaScript?
Now why does it do that? It's because
JavaScript if you don't give a function
your custom function to
to specify the ordering of things. By
default it turns every element in your
array into a string. Then they compare
the string using um
you know dictionary order. actually no
they compare the string using the uh
the um code unit which means the 16
bits. So they take a character they take
the first 16 bits of the UTF16
encoding then they order by the 16 bits.
Okay, do you guys understand? Probably
not because it's fairly complicated.
Okay. So that's why you get this 3048.
Okay. The idiocy of sword in JavaScript.
Okay. Let's um Okay. So let's put this
back. Uh let's copy that. Let's go to
today's talk show. Uh what is this? Go
to today's today's talk show. Showing
browser. Go back and uh section. Go to
the last end section. add the new
section and uh paste uh in wait what and
make it JavaScript. Okay. And uh
[clears throat]
syntax code show in browser. So we show
the idiocy of sort in JavaScript.
Now why is it doing that? Well, it's
fully explained in here. Okay. Sort
array in place. Okay. Um
and the default function okay sort you
know sort element by convert each
element to string and compare their code
unit order. Okay that's what it's doing.
So copy that go back and paste the link
in the showing browser so people who
watch my show can can check it out. Okay
that's the side demo of the idiocy of
the JavaScript sort. JavaScript has
1,000 idiosc. Okay. So, close that.
Wait, what did we close? Uh, okay.
Uh, X2 close talk show index page.
Close. Back to Emacs. Close. And this is
today's talk show. Fantastic. Go back to
Emacs. Switch uh panel. This is dev
webdev. Fantastic webdev. Okay. It's
fantastic blog. You should read it.
Let's linkify it there. Fantastic. Okay.
And by the way, those links are my
keyboards. Ultimate hacking keyboard.
Okay. Fantastic. Full detailed uh
photos and video reviews and unboxing.
Okay, that's my keyboard. And go back.
And then there there it is my trackboard
right there. Okay. And go back. And
there is my
drawing tablet. Okay. Cheers.
So these are great. You can go there and
buy them. Boom. My links on my website.
And what I'm using is Emacs, the most
advanced powerful editing system using
softly keys.
The most advanced more advanced than Vim
or Neo Vim. Okay, by key strokes
less keystrokes. Okay, now let's go back
to Emacs and let's go back to do what we
were doing. So we were doing actually
yeah we was writing a example of sort
object in array. Okay so so you need a
function here. So here so if you don't
know what I'm doing um let me show you.
Okay.
Uh this JavaScript idiac. Okay. So let
me put that there.
So sort here you need a paren then you
need to say a function. Okay. You need
to give a function and uh you know so we
are doing kind of like functional
programming. Okay. So but no so to make
it easier to understand we can just
define the function here. So, um,
sort
uh let's say
predicate.
Okay, wait. Let's let's do this. Sort
predicateut. That's a classic name. Uh,
classic style of naming because
predicate is what people say when you,
you know, when you when you pass a
function that returns true or false, you
call it predicate. Okay. But today with
Zuma generation you guys don't know you
know you guys don't know what the [ __ ]
what what the [ __ ] is you know
[laughter]
Zuma Zuma idiots they they would say uh
you know what the Zuma generate okay let
me explain the Zuma idiots would say
sort call back okay that's what they
call that's what they say call back
function
>> [laughter]
>> the Zuma idiots. The [ __ ] extreme
idiots like oh Jesus I so despise them
so much.
Okay, so anyway, so let's just let's
leave that comment there. Okay, so
anyway, the the classic way the classic
way to name sort function
is predicate. Okay,
predicate came from logic, you know,
came from logic. Predicate means any
function that returns either true or
false. Okay, so so to make it easier to
understand, so you can define a function
like that, we are doing functional
programming. Okay. So you want to say so
x is a object. So you want you know
given an object you you know so and here
we can just say sort predicate you know
we pass the function name
okay and uh and here we we uh let's
rename this array of objects okay let's
make it make it more uh understandable
so not so here is just array of objects
you see we want to sort
this array of objects by this sort
predicate. Fantastic. Okay, now we just
need to write this sort predicate. So
what are you guys saying? Good morning,
good evening. Hey, great. JavaScript is
basically a lisp. Yes, kind of. It's
based on scheme list. Fantastic. Well, I
mean, well, I I think it's it's wrong to
say JavaScript is basically a list
because if you say that basically what
you mean is that JavaScript is you know
basically what you effectively means is
that JavaScript is a functional
programming language but not pure is
like mostly functional programming
language. Okay. So that
that is what people mean when when
people say JavaScript is basically a
lisp. People have been saying that for
people actually said that for Python and
for Ruby, you know, like Python is just
a better lisp. Ruby is just a better
lisp, you know, back then. Actually the
people they even said that for Pearl. So
so this is going back to history. Okay?
If you actually go back to history, if
you lived in the 1990s, in the 2000s,
you know, people actually say that
because when Pearl became super popular,
there's nothing like it. It's just and
it's super convenient. Just like lisp,
you have lists, you know, you can add
elements to a list. It's so convenient
unlike C where where you can move a [ __ ]
without spending an hour you know like C
or C++ first. So, so technically it is
incorrect to say JavaScript is basically
a lisp because people actually said that
about pearl and and about Python and
about Ruby and Python actually from
people uh expert top expert of lisp
common lisp uh that guy is Peter Novik
he's a big promoter of Python back in
2002 around there for for five years you
know 2002 is when Google was you know
Python people don't know Python back
then Google was using it Peter Novik is
a well-known very well-known common dis
expert uh and also in the AI field okay
Peter Novik okay so he's 69 years old
today so back in 200 uh so in 2001 he
won A ai fellow okay small awards anyway
so he works at Google so in 2001 2002
he's promoting Python he's he's he's
well known in lisp
AI field common lisp okay so but in 2001
2002 he's promoting Python he's saying
python is just just a lisp okay python
is like the lisp you know because on the
other hand lisp is kind have already
dying at that time because you you you
know like people don't know what is this
you know like oh this advanced fancy
thing I don't know what is you know too
complicated seems too advanced so anyway
in 2002 this guy is promoting lisp okay
and he's promoting I mean promoting
python he's like saying like he actually
said it python is like a lisp
um you can find the blog okay so can can
we find the blog. Yeah, I I think so. Uh
so if you have to, you know, so I'm
talking about some coding history here.
Uh Peter Novik, Python is a lisp.
Okay, let's see if we can find some uh
Peter Novik. Okay, it's a AI slob. Now
AI is going to say something about it.
Okay, hacker news. Peter Novik a serious
listener calls Python something. This is
2018. This by Zoomer idiots. Okay, we
are talking about the year 2001 2002.
Okay, so Peter Novik here I came to
Python not this is 2010. Okay. Okay. So
yeah in the 2000s okay so anyway let's
see what Peter uh AI says. Fionovic, a
prominent computer scientist and former
Visp advocate has described Python as an
acceptable lisp. That's right, that's
the word he used. Uh sentiment he has
expressed both in public talks and
online discussions. His view stem from
uh Python's steep alignment with core
list principles such as everything being
an object, first class functions,
dynamic typing and blah blah blah d.
Okay, in my opinion, he's incorrect.
Anyway, so I want, you know, I wanted to
tell you guys some history. Hello, Solar
and hello the Informaticist.
Okay, so I digress into some history
about Peter Novik, a big huge famous guy
in AI community and this and uh you know
a history a snippet of history how he
promoted Python. Okay. But lisp is not
but Python is not a lisp. Okay. Python,
Ruby, they are like totally not a lisp.
In order to be like at least to even be
like lisp,
you need a few uh characteristics.
First of all, you need a par. Okay, you
need to have lots of
uh
parents. Okay, so here's a list code. Uh
so let's go let's go to some uh here's
list code. Okay, you need uh you need to
have parents like heavy nesting. That's
the characteristics of this good or for
good or bad. You need to have this.
Okay, you need symbols. You know, every
of your function name of your variable
name, they are actually symbols. Okay,
that means they can be held unevaluated.
Okay, so you need parenthesis syntax.
You need symbols. Every every name is
symbols not like JavaScript
you know that like what the [ __ ] is this
const you know it's it's a keyword it's
not a symbol you can't you know you need
to have symbols okay you need to have
par nesting parent you need to have
symbols and then you need to have mostly
functional programming okay that
JavaScript qualifies but Python does not
qualify okay you need to have the
language must be mostly predominantly
functional programming JavaScript
qualifies because JavaScript is a
derivative of scheme lisp by design
JavaScript by Brenda Ike
specifically he wanted to create a lisp
scheme dispect
that's JavaScript okay qualifies Python
no because the GO van idiots he hates
functional programming he hates lisp he
hates scheme his the lambda in Python is
even broken. You can't have like full
function in lambda you know python it's
a long story I have lots of articles on
that but anyway so python does not
qualify it's not predominant functional
programming python is actually py if you
code python they want you to do like uh
objectoriented programming so if you are
a functional guy you run into lots of
frustrations in python okay so pi so so
so Peter novik you know saying that
python is like accept acceptable list in
my opinion that's like a home homework
you get a fail okay you get a fail I
mean well I mean tech you know
technically this is not a like a
scientific publish you know publication
if you if he published this as a
scientific scientific paper in computer
science saying that Python is an
acceptable at least he won't he won't
get qualified. you know, he won't get um
uh uh you know what they how how they
say um
um
what's the word you know the scientific
publication so you guys are quiet are
you guys are still hearing what I'm
saying so you know the among the science
scientific publication they have a peer
review system you know if if Peter Novik
actually
trying to publish this as a paper. I'm
not sure it's going to go well. But
actually, he's going to fly because his
big name usually you see scientific
papers in the past 20 years has kind of
collapsed a lot along with the general
USA politics. So they become, you know,
they become like collapsed. Anyway, so
that's a side note about Peter Novik.
Okay. So now remember characteristics of
lisp. Let me write this down. I actually
I did a live stream about this like
three four years ago. So let me write
this down. Okay, this is critical. In
order to for a programming language to
be like list you have to have these
characteristics. Okay. So uh
characterist
uh characteristics
um well that's
charact
I got a shortcut characteristics
of this
you must have
symbols
nested syntax. Okay. Wuam language also
qualify. Wuam language, common lisp,
scheme list, emac lisp, auto listp,
closure lisp. They all qualify. Okay.
Then you got to have symbols.
Same thing with closure list. You got
symbols. Okay. Then you need to have uh
maros. Okay. That's a feature. The dear
to the lispus. Okay. dear to the heart
of Lisbus but I despise it okay but but
still it seem maros okay maros is like
fundamental so there are two maros
actually um this maros and there is the
uh reader maros reader marquos is kind
of esoteric but this maros more people
understand okay I got to shut down my
alarm.
Okay. Characteristics of lisp.
Okay. I think how long have I been
talking? So, yes guys, thank you guys.
Yeah. Cheers. Um,
is this digression interesting?
So, you guys have to give me some
feedback, you know, like sometimes, you
know, I have, you know, because I talk
random, my character, my personality, my
live stream. So, I have all kind of all
sort of people watching me, you know,
like
a lot of you guys are young people. Uh,
and a lot of you guys into lisp. A lot
of you guys into crazy like you think
I'm a nut job like the the the the you
know the the the the god operating
system you know that guy what's his name
and and some of you are you know
mathematicians you know professors so
because I go over so
anyway so we were coding JavaScript and
we uh digress into this. So the
characteristics of this you have uh
let's see what else you need. Oh yeah
predominantly functional programming. So
um
okay so that's important characteristics
in fact that should be here. Okay so
this is kind of older in their um in
their importance. So in lisp for for a
programming language to be uh
characterized as like lisp you have to
have nested syntax well to to be to be a
lisp you must have nested syntax symbols
predominantly functional programming
which is not python python failed here
this macros and reader mark macros and
um that's about it okay if you want to
claim your lisp your programming
language is a lisp you must have is
okay. Now if you want to claim your
program is like lisp, you know, like the
Peter Novik would say acceptable lisp.
Well, what does it mean acceptable? It's
not a list. Okay.
And you got some you you need some other
things like less less important but but
uh but it's um implicitly
required such as
auto memory
management. Okay, that's like or also
known as aa garbage collection by the C
and C++ idiots. The industrial
programming idiots when they hear the
word garbage collection they get excited
you know. Oh, garbage collection. No
way. Memory like, you know, [ __ ] them.
[ __ ] C, C C++
this type of and rust bitless. Okay, I
despise them.
You know, if you say automatic memory
management, you know, they they don't,
you know, they don't feel nothing. You
know, these people so funny means the
same thing. But but you have to say
garbage collection. they they they get
excited, you know, they're going to tell
you why you need it, why you not, you
know, you shouldn't need it. You know,
most of them they hate it. Okay? Like
the C idiots.
Okay? So anyway, so to be to be like
Lisp, you must have auto automemory
management. Okay?
Uh
okay that that's you know and and of
course and of course you you must have
built in list or array uh uh data type
otherwise you can say you can say your
language is like lisp. Okay. So, so some
other implicit
require
requirements are okay now showing
browser. So you can see so this is the
meaning of lisp. Okay.
Hello man. What are we learning? We are
learning talking about computer science
um computer scientist history. Peter
Novik uh and Python programming language
history and lisp. Okay. And JavaScript.
Okay. Anyway, I I think I talked too
long. Now, let's just go back and finish
my JavaScript program. So, I was talking
about the terminology predicate. Uh
okay. So, let's finish the program.
Okay. So, we digress. So, let's write
this function. So, this here you need
two variables a and bb. the predicate
sort for sort they need to compare.
Okay. So for the JavaScript it's funny
because in JavaScript you know the
JavaScript sort you need to return
uh negative one or zero or one that's
how uh that's how it determines you know
your predicate function needs to return
these three possible values. Okay, funny
in JavaScript that by the way this
feature came from Pearl. So Brenda Ike
the creator of JavaScript they borrow he
borrowed you know this from Pearl. This
is how Pearl's
uh sort function works. You know you
need you if you want a custom sort you
need to pass a function and your
function must return negative one or
zero or one to indicate which you know
element is is preceding or su succeeding
okay that's the math jargon for order
okay so anyway so so so uh so uh what we
are doing yeah so we want to so aa so if
if uh let's say this is what we want to
do if aa dot name. Okay, so uh is uh
less than
bb.name will actually age not name.
Okay, because we want to sort this
object remember. So, so if that is that
then return that okay something like
that. Copy paste paste. Okay, so we can
like
uh do that and that. Okay. So if that
equals to uh equals to BBH then that
okay if then it's the greater wait.
Yeah. So this is what you have to do.
Okay. This is the sort predicate.
What the Zoomer idiots would say. This
is the uh uh sort for uh call back
function. Okay.
So you got a object array of objects
then you got the pair cut function then
you want to sort them
so sort it okay that's the output and
this part is uh from previous we don't
need it okay now double check one more
time is the whole code correct
uh check yeah I'm pretty sure sort
bracket yeah array of objects okay so
let's run
Press, press. Okay, wait. Press, press,
press. Let's see. Uh, we got this result
now. Is this result correct?
Mary, age 19. John, age 40. Is it
correct? Correct. It actually reverse
them. You see? So, we can actually uh
add another thing. Uh, Mary John Joe.
Okay. Joe age. How how old is Joe? Uh uh
let's say
you know let's say okay 15 well yeah
okay Joe but then let's say David uh
David age uh that's random number okay
David what d a vid okay
let's just say Dave Joe Mary John. Okay.
John, John, Mary, Joe, Dave. Okay.
Something like that. So, did you see?
So, yeah. So, we run it. So, you got
that. You got that.
Copy and paste it
here.
Fantastic. Did we did do well? Yes, we
did do well. Fantastic. And beautiful.
So, we succeeded. Put it back. syntax
color the whole page show in browser. So
we completed today's task
of updating adding a example to my
JavaScript indepth tutorial on
array.prototype.sort
by adding a example of a frequently
needed example of how do you sort
uh objects array of objects. Okay. So we
added the example. Now previously I mean
I had other examples. So this example
for example this one is more complex.
You see you have a array of strings and
in each string you got you know some
letters then followed by a number. So to
sort these strings you want to extract
the number after the first character. So
that's u you know so that's a you know
little example of custom function.
Then we explain other things. The
default order function which is the you
know we have in this example to showcase
the default sort order which is by the
uh the
code unit idiocy which is the first 16
bits of a character's
character UTF16 encoding. So what
JavaScript do JavaS what JavaScript does
is first of all it converts the elements
in your array into a string. Then for
each character I mean index in the
string it takes I mean for each element
the first character it turns into the 16
bits of UTF16 encoding and compare that.
So that's extreme idiocy
and uh that's a default sort order
that's illustrated here. Okay. Anyway,
so that's it for today. So if you guys
uh like my stuff, okay. Hey.
Okay. Is that is that good? Is that you
know reasonable? Is that you know? So
you go to like go to kasali.info.
Uh you know pay me $100 if you have a
job.
uh kasad.info
http no s and all the way down then you
can just pay patreon or amazon gift card
or pay paypal me. Okay. Okay. That's it
guys. Uh I think that's it. Bye. Uh no
questions anyone.
Okay. We shut down in a minute. So, we
did this sort fantastic
order objects example order objects.
Yeah, the classic way. Oh, wait. No, you
see, let's copy this to my tutorial
because here is my official, you know,
here is my JavaScript um wait where is
it object reference. Yeah. So, so this
is my JavaScript in-depth tutorial,
right?
You don't want you know in in this in
this JavaScript tutorial array class
then you go to array prototype then you
go down you go you you know so many
methods you go to sort you don't want
you don't want to say uh zoomer idiots
here
so actually uh let's copy that actually
copy that go to my talk show put that
into my talk show. Okay. Okay. Then
but in my but in my um here don't don't
don't say this thing. Okay. Uh and let's
let's clarify for the right audience.
Okay.
So let's say example of sold objects in
array. Okay. So don't say that people
don't need to know that and in fact we
don't need this um
this uh well you can you can kind of you
know like you can put this so this is a
function functional programming you can
just put that here you don't need it to
be separate so typically
for real life functional programming you
know you if you are familiar usually
usually you Don't you don't create it in
a separate function. You just put it
there part of it. Okay. So now you can
see the code is more compact. This is
more like real you know production code
of sorting. Okay. So you can see you run
it same result. Okay. So now put it back
syntax
show in browser and uh today's date. Did
we update today's date? 2000 February 6.
Okay. Showing browser. Fantastic.
Fantastic.
Older object. Fantastic. Okay. Now go
back. Close that. Close that. Uh flag
keys most advanced key binding. Let's go
back to talk show. Show show in browser.
Uh did we syntax color? Yes. And here we
mention this funny things. Okay. Bye.