of talk show. We are going to code F. We
are going to explore F. I don't know F
so I'm learning it. We are going to
write a find and replace script and
we're going to ask AI for help. Okay,
this is Kasar Discord join. Uh we have
all kind of people there and here is
Kasar uh Twitter. So let's go to guac.
So we're going to use AI a lot. So today
you guys are lucky. So because you have
AI to help you learn a programming
language. Uh 10 years ago you got Stack
Overflow. So you go there ask questions
and you have to deal with people. Then
20 years ago you don't have that. You
have like lousy tutorials official
documentation. They are incredibly hard
to read to understand because these are
you know they they are all elite coders
they don't really write good tutorials
they but rather they use lots of jargon
they think they are doing computer
science and so on. So today you guys are
lucky you young people you got guac to
help you uh you can ask it to write a
entire tutorial for F. So anyway we're
going to learn F. Okay. How to um write
a um
find and replace script, you know. So I
started my own notes.
I still have some cough. So bear with
me. So I started to write my long uh
notes install uh and so on. So find and
replace script. Okay. I have written
that in uh find replace
find replace I have written that script
in wam language in goland in in lots of
okay so here is a woofam language
example in fact we did this uh live
hold on a second if you are watching
this offline play at 1.5 speed or twice
as fast
uh if you are watching here say hi love
to see your comments hello lemon leaf
Stack Overflow rip. That's right. AI
killed it like overnight. Like almost
literally. Nobody visited anymore
because you can just ask AI and AI grab
all the you know millions pages of stock
in uh overflow information. So they
killed it. Then they are suing the AI uh
AI also
grabbed all my websites.
you know like I have article on that if
you search for um let's say um okay let
me quickly go show you okay so go go go
go go go so I I want to talk about
today's topic but let me digress okay
wan language and uh kasali info search
uh AI
you know so this article AI site in
Google G in Google C4 data set for AI
training 2023 three. So, Google got a
website that lists all the websites that
their AI bots grabbed. It's called
Google's C4 data set. Then you search
it. Then you found my website rank
56,000 rank uh this uh 1 million so
info, you know, it's in Google. So, they
just grabbed your info without pay.
Stack Overflow, Reddit, they sue them,
but I don't have the power. I'm not in
the mainstream power, uh, you know,
relation
family or whatever. So, I don't have so
they just grab my website. But well, so
but so all the AI bots knows about me
because I've been blogging for like 30
years. Um, well, that's what it is.
Okay, so we're going to do so let me
show you. So today's talk show is about
writing a find and replace script. Okay.
Uh let me just post the link here.
And I have written that in multiple
languages. So first of all there is
woofam language find replace. We did
this live sometimes in 2022 uh 22. Yes.
Okay. Find replace woofam language.
And
you got find replace in golan.
Click find text in directory grab. So
implementing GP the Unix Linux GP in
Golan. Okay, that's just GP. Uh then you
know it's why so many lines because it
got lots of features. Let's see what
features you can grab. Uh let's see.
Find strings in your directory can be a
list of strings. So you can get have
multiple pairs you know uh golan is
verballs. So then you have goland
regular expression find replace text in
a directory recursively. Okay. Then you
got goland then you got python. So this
find replace is what I do when I learn a
new language. So today we're going to do
f. So, Python
find replace regular expression find
replace in a directory recursively or
not. You can like you can set what file
name extension like you can set uh many
parameters or directory level this you
do not see often like [snorts] can grab
can Unix grab do it? No. Unix grab my
ass.
I'm a Unix hater if you don't know
already. You know, I've been doing a lot
live stream Unix Linux hater. I'm a Unix
Linux C hater. Okay, not so much Linux
because Linux is like kind of derived
from Unix. But anyway, the the Unix
philosophy, the way Unix and C I
consider them the the greatest
responsible damage to computing industry
in programming languages, in programming
practice and so on and on. I talked
about that a lot. Okay. So in this
Python script for example regular
expression find replace text in a
directory
you can specify level of directory. Why
is that important? It's useful when you
have HTML because when you have HTML for
example here's a link uh and this link
goes to up one directory. So but you
know that's my CSS file cascading
stylesheet. Okay. Close it. Now if you
in the current directory talk your
current directory go back. Now you go to
the add emac feature diode. So now hide
the hide the Unix
permission. You know this is example of
the Unix dash RW-RW-RWA
or mod. You know they got uh octag
octagon
uh wait octo
number base you know you you use that to
change the mod you know. Anyway, the and
the username um and the group and wheel
you know and root anyway that's a Unix
complexity. Okay, the the the most
brainless
idiots created them. They are not idiots
exactly but they are like the type of
people they just they we just want to
get things done. We don't care about
design. We don't care about elegance. We
don't care about beautiful. We don't
care about extensibility. Oh, we can
only care about architecture. Let's you
know you worry about that later. So it's
like a virus system. So they just do it.
But we are the most we are the fastest.
That's a Unix and C Okay.
Greatest damage to computing indust
industry. Okay. Even today even today we
have so many other languages but you got
the C and C++ camp. They are saying oh
we are the best C. And
anyway, so
[clears throat] okay, so I already
sweared a lot. So this video is like
degrading. Okay, people left. Okay, so
so back to what we were doing. So yeah,
so we are I'm showing you this
directory. So I'm telling you guys why
it is
useful very useful to have a GB or set
find replace command or script that take
consideration of directory level because
in this directory if you want um because
the the relative links in a HTML
structure they depends on they work only
if you are at certain level.
Does that make sense? Uh okay, I'm not
going to explain and let let's let's
move on. Let let's get to the F. Okay.
So, we got the find replace in Python.
So, there are also find replace text in
a directory. So, what's this difference?
Uh find replace text in a directory.
Regular expression find replace text in
a directory. Find replace text in a
directory. Oh, that's pearl. Okay. So
Pearl is my earliest one. [snorts] This
is written in 2000, year 2000. Okay.
Pearl uh Pearl is dead today. Okay. So
Pearl then you got Emacis
one of the most uh powerful tech for
text editing. So So you got all these uh
scripts
you know. So let's copy that and let's
open it. Okay. Show the pink window.
Okay. So search for topic. Okay. So here
are all the links are not here. So go
down. So the first part of the topic
link. So this is Emacs. Find replace
text in a directory. So you go all the
way down. The first topic box, this
navigation box is all about find replace
in Emacs. So if you are using the Emacs,
the greatest most powerful text editor,
you want to check out all these
articles, you know, search text, find
replace, find replace by regular
expression, find replace and change
letter case. That's a bit complicated.
You you find something you want to
change the letter case. Okay. Then
highlight current highlight words in in
a file. Uh for example, I can I can do
that. So let's highlight all words EMAC.
You see that's kind of like find it
because it has to do that. So regular
expression then complete tutorial on
EMAC regular expression. Emacs in it I
search whites space regular expression
that means for example if you want to
search for EMAC rejects that word. So
that's underscore EMAC lowline rejects.
Okay. But I can type emac space ex that
will still find it. You see even though
this is a that's called unic code in in
uni code this character is called low
line. So let's see. So you see name low
line but traditionally we say it's uh we
call underscore in English. Okay. And
what is the ethmology the history of the
word underscore? Why is it like
underscore? What score? Well, that's
because back then 100 or something 500
years ago, you have a stick like from a
tree, you cut it to tally to to how they
call it um to keep mark, you know, to to
count. So that you cut it. So that that
is a score. So this this character low
line is like underscore that's
ethmology. Okay.
Worthy blog. You can find that article
in my wordy blog. Disorder of a man of
letters. Kasabel letters. Search
underscore uh understanding underscore
ethmology of underscore
1771 to draw a line under from under
score. The figurative sense to emphasize
is attested from 1891.
Noun. Noun meaning a line drawn below
something is recorded in 1901. Okay. 7
uh so beginning in 1771 underscore. So
that's how we got this this character.
Let's magn uh let's magnify.
Let's see the glory of the font. Oh
okay. God, this is like
close that. Okay, we don't want that.
That's too big. Okay.
Okay.
So,
underscore. So, let's copy that. So, we
digressed over ethmology of of
underscore. Close that. Close that.
Let's go to talk show. Uh
what is this? Yeah, this today's talk
show. So go to let's paste the link
here.
Okay, show in browser we talked about
underscore and then I wanted to show
you. Yeah, that um so Emacs. Okay, find
replace script in Emacs. Everything you
want to know. So at the bottom, that's
everything you want to know about that
in Emacs. Then the next topics box is
uh find replace in all these different
languages. That's what we want. So we go
here.
See this this box.
Okay. Now you just press a key. You
extract all the links. Close that. Now
we are back in talk show page. Insert.
Insert blank line. paste them
linkify all make a list show in browser
fantastic
all the programming languages
exploration on their design how they do
that so so so that's that okay so I'm
using Emacs of course and I'm using keys
the most efficient key binding system in
the universe this is the source code
4,000 lines of code go to the directory
this is you can see kafly keys Open it.
Go to the top. Go to the link the
homepage. Open it. Showing browser
safely keys. I did like a 100 videos
about this. And there's a a video you
can watch most of. Okay, it's on GitHub.
Just go there, download it. If you are
using Emacs,
I have planned to implement that in uh
VS code
because VS code is very popular. I don't
use it though. So if I can do you know
make it also working in VS code that
will
add my credibility when I'm dead I'll be
remembered oh he created the universal
keybinding system
likely keys you know but if I don't do a
VS code nobody knows because nobody
knows uh Emacs Emacs is dying Emacs is a
dying dinosaur okay stuff like this copy
the file path close it and on the ping
window you can see all the commands
course and keystroke as I type so for
example I move the cursor you can see
end of line or block four times you know
next window frame you see next window so
that's how I do it okay go to the top
and uh copy that close that close that
fly keys so let's paste the link here
linkify I don't want the full HTML,
HTTP. So,
press press
turn that into a local file path, then
link it. Then you got the title. Okay,
so what's the difference? Let me show
you. Okay, let me delete the Okay, let's
delete. Okay, so here um
uh wait, undo, undo, undo, undo, undo.
Okay, so copy that. So here is the full
URL. If you link it, you got the full
link, you see? And uh you got the full
link. But if you want it to be local,
you know, like a local link. So I turn
this URL
not that press
that becomes a full file path local. So
you can see the command cassite URL to
file path. That's a command I call and
that's a keystroke. I'm using a Vora
keyboard layout. Okay. and some flag
keys. Okay, so you got this local file,
you know, file path and press a key, it
becomes a link. So you can see now it's
a title there. Now if I
uh compact the two lines, make a list
show in browser, then you can see the
difference. Go down, you see one is like
the any arbitrary link format the the
other one is more local like this is
website. So, okay. Now,
we don't want that. We don't want that.
So, go back here. There. Refresh. So,
there we have it.
Okay. We already talked for 20 minutes.
Now, let's get on to uh work on the
F, shall we? Any comments? No comments.
Okay. So, let's just ask how to get file
content the string. Okay.
Um
how to get file content
string in appar
okay AI is going to answer and uh
meanwhile let's uh let's say
in F
let's add that prefix Now go back to AI
and uh let's magnify.
We want it larger.
Okay.
So F's most convenient common way to
read entire file content. So string is
use that. Okay. So let's copy that.
Okay. So,
okay. So, let's start just to uh
wait
paste the code. Let's see
how do I run this. Okay. So let file
path equals to uh so you need a file
path to copy wait. So copy this file
path and uh
select all paste. So I got talk show
use add verbaten string. Okay content
equal string file read. Uh,
okay. Let me just do some renaming.
Uh,
let's run it. Let's see what it does.
Does
fantastic and beautiful. Okay. So, it
printes it prints out entire file
content. Fantastic. So,
read file into a string.
Fantastic
syntax color everything show in browser.
Fantastic. How to read file into a
string. So that got solved
with encoding recommended for the UTF8
files. Okay, that's more complicated. I
will digest this detail later when I'm
offline. So this part a synchronous
version. Wow. It's got a synchronous
version unblocking.
Interesting. Let read file a sync. So
how does it do? Oh, okay. It's got a
sync keyword
comments guys five concurrent users.
Okay. Again we are exploring F asking AI
manual approach with stream reader more
control. Okay. Got a little bit
detailed. Okay. So okay we don't care
about that. So for now how to read a
file that's already covered. How to
write to a file that we want to know.
Okay.
So, Guac, please help me. Guac, I need
help in F. How to write to a file
in File IO uses net system.io namespace.
Here are the most common way to write to
a text file. Simple. Write a single
string to file. Okay, use that. Okay,
very simple. Fantastic
and powerful
functional programming.
F. Paste it. Pop it out.
Okay. Now, hello world. Hello F word.
it. You know that's idiocy. The you
know the hello world convention came
from C the brandness. You know the the
best first programming language code
should be 1 + 1 simple universal
mathematics but the C introduced this
hello hello world that's like from there
on it's downhill you know because this
affect your mentality about coding about
programming so I don't want hello world
okay
so uh write to file so
so instead Instead of let's say hi
there.
Hi there. Beautiful. Okay.
Okay. We don't want line two. So let's
just that. Let's see if this works.
Output. So
okay. Comment date.
Write a string to a file.
Run it. Does it work?
Process finished. Okay. Go to the
directory.
Search for output right there. Open it.
Fantastic. And beautiful. Correct. It
worked.
Okay. So, open that. Delete uh delete
this that file. We don't want it. Okay.
So, but that's a code.
Fantastic. So, you just do content. You
know, that's a string. Uh that's a
constant. So you just say write
file.rite all text. Oh and content. Oh
fantastic and beautiful and simple
syntax color demo.
Fantastic. Write the string to file. So
this is how I learn programming language
logical one task at a time you know.
Then when you want to do find replace of
all files in your directory, you can
synthesize or compose them together. You
know how to do one thing at a time.
Okay, so uh how to write to a file, how
to replace string. Okay, that is a
simple one. That is a really simple one.
That's just a string function. But I
don't know. So walk help me. work help
Joey practice space says I recently had
a project in my undergrad about F how do
you like it and uh
in context what other programming
language your school teaches you like
what do you already know and how do you
feel about F okay so in F# how to
replace string F# strings are immutable
able net system string values. Immutable
means you cannot change them. So
replacement always return a new string
without modifying the original simple
substring or character replacement.
Okay. Use the building replace method
directly on the string. It replaces all
occurrences and is case sensitive.
Okay. You can chain call for multiple
replacement. Fantastic. Copy that.
Exploration of F. Okay.
Okay. So, a new one. F. Paste it. Pop it
out.
Replace string example.
So, let's see. Hello. What?
Back. Hello. What? Hi there. Beautiful.
Uh replace original uh
hi
um let's see
something in the water some something
abstract okay so replace water by fire
replace substring okay of course obvious
shut
result hello world. Hi. Okay, remove
that.
Uh,
replace single character.
Okay, so hold on a second. Let's try
that. Run it.
Oh, yeah. How do you print then?
Okay. How do you print? Let's see. In F.
Uh, let's see. Do I have my F learning
notes
install file name extension comment and
uh how do you print in F okay I don't
have that that's all important the
actually that's the most first most
important thing so
okay so start a new
guac. How to print in shop.
Copy that. That's one of the new things
we need to do. Um,
my wife is home, I think.
How to print in F. Okay. So, wait. Let's
clean this up. Okay. So, actually
I want to make them all into F2.
Actually, uh make them all into F3.
Um so, completion H3
and uh so
too tedious. Okay. So, we can actually
do a macro by start recording the macro.
You can look at the pink window how I do
it. That's there are command names
there. Okay. Start the marwell
completion H3 enter then end mark. Okay.
You see? Okay. Marco end mar. Okay. Now
apply the previous mark. Do it. Then
call repeat last command.
Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Fantastic.
And beautiful.
Can you see that? Okay. So now,
now we actually just uh so so that way
it's more um organized. Okay. So let's
uh let me just cook. Let me cook. So
what is this? This is uh how to read
file. Okay,
there it is. And this is this is
uh write string to a file. Okay.
Right. String to a file. And uh and uh
what are we doing?
And this is find replace string. Okay.
Hold on a second. Put it back. Cut. Find
replace string. And uh how do you print?
So this is more fundamental. We need to
know how to print. Okay. So let's uh
create a new F. How to print? Print fn.
Print fn is what you do. Okay. Copy it.
Pop it up. Just run it. Okay. I'll leave
the hello world. Very annoying. So print
uh wait.
Oh, so there's two different characters.
There's I mean two different functions.
Print f and print fn. Print fn will add
a new line at the end
while print f does not. Okay. Put it
back. Fantastic. Okay. Syntax color show
in browser. So we are starting to get
organized. So I can grab this and uh
then put into my F learning notes and
create pages. Okay.
Is it good?
Okay. Nobody is here. Okay. So let's see
what's next. Uh next next. Let's see
next next. We know how to print uh print
fn. Then how to replace string. So let's
work on the replace string. We need to
print
P. Oh, I got a template. By the way, I'm
using F mode. Okay, let me show you. Uh,
describe function
F mode. I just cooked it up when I
started to learn F.
I started to learn F month ago, but I
didn't continue. So, but anyway, I
started to write a F mode because I know
Emac Lisp very well. Been coding it for
20 years beginning in 2006.
So, it's 19 years. Been coding Emac Lisp
for 19 years. So, I'm very familiar. So,
I as I learn a new programming language,
I
cook up the programming language mode in
Emacs on the fly. So as I learn more
about um then about F the language I add
more templates more keyword symbols and
so on or syntax. Okay so that is
that is SC mode. Close it. Okay. So you
can see you can tell you know because
you see print f is not colored but print
fn is. Why is that? That's because I
didn't realize this print of f. So I
need to you know modify add as I learn.
So now we can uh print it. So replace
okay let's see
print it.
Fantastic. So this is the output. Okay.
So I want to change my var variable
names to begin with x.
so that they are not normal English
words. So I have better completion and
so on.
Now what about the replace character? So
uh replace a single character. Let's try
this. Okay. So replace O by
uh
let's say
A would that work? Result delete.
So run it. It won't do it because you
have to print it. So you have to say
print
it.
Same thing in the water. Funny. Okay.
Fantastic. It works. Okay, so we learned
two things. One is the replace method.
H interesting. This is a functional
programming, but you got a method
or a string. Okay, so you got kind of
like OP feature in this almost pure
functional programming language F.
Fantastic. I think I love F F so far.
Everything is so simple. Uh unlike
Python for example Python the Python
idiots when you read a file they talk
about file object you have to like then
then mode read write mode you know the
string stupid Python one of the worst
programming language okay
[clears throat]
uh hold on a second let me check what's
going on okay so this works right do it
Great. Okay. Uh, great.
Replace a char. Okay. I'll put it back.
Syntax collage show in browser.
How to read a file? Um,
so
read
that is part of this uh
Okay,
next.
How to list the content? Okay, this is
getting more complex.
New one.
How to list the content?
Do it.
In F you can list the contents of a
directory using functions from the
system.io name space. The most common
approach
or with directory
static method returning strings or
directory info instance method returning
reacher file info directory info
objects. Okay.
Okay. So, h
first open open the name space open,
right?
Okay. Let's just try that.
So this only files and this only
subdirectories.
Okay. So this both files and
subdirectories. Okay. There's quite a
few.
[clears throat]
So let's get the file path. For example,
we want the file path to be
that. Okay. Then cut that. Okay. So, or
dot for current directory. Okay. Uh
interesting. So, you use it supports
it supports the Unix shortcut.
directory.get files. Okay. Return the
string.
Okay. So, let's change the variable
name.
Oh, lazy. Uh, so what is this lazy?
Better for large directories. Oh,
return sequence. Interesting. Print
them.
file sequence. Uh then uh what is that
operator?
Sequence eater. Wow.
So this is starting to get interesting
in the functional programming realm.
Uh then with a pattern only text files.
Okay, this is important.
So enumerate files take a second
argument of a pattern. Okay, that's
that's want that. So, let's run it and
see what
uh Okay, the value name space typo
module directory is not defined. Well,
that's because it says you need to do
this uh
open system.io.
Why why is it open? Is it not like
required or import?
Okay. So it works. It works.
So all the uh wait what it do? So it
listed
all kind of files. Okay. First of all
kind of files HTML and text. Then it
list all text files. So it repeated
twice.
So
So separate them.
Okay. So I need to
uh this is very interesting. I need to
look into them list content
several varieties of ways. Fantastic so
far. Love it.
Okay.
Um then last one in F how to list the
content and all subdirectories. Okay. So
does it show
Recursive version. So this both files
and directories or entries using
directory info for more detail. File
size creation time that is very useful.
Now recursive listing. Okay.
Okay. Fantastic.
So let let's try this one. Recursive
listing. Fantastic. So be you know
fantastic. The AI is just fantastic.
Okay. So
F paste it. Pop it out. And you need
that open system IO.
Now I have a question. Why is it open?
Why is it not import or require
something? Anyway, let's try this first.
Okay. So you need to copy a directory.
So this is the directory we want.
Okay. Then cut it then. Okay. So uh now
you can say path equals to oh you have
to say let. So I'm starting to learn f
let. Okay. Let x path
equals to that. Okay. Then
change to X path. Okay. Then list file
recursively. Then you
kind of pipe it I suppose to the
sequence
name space then dot iterator
that will that is a function I suppose
that's a function that goes you know it
will
enumerate it will I mean it will iterate
through this result of enumeration so
let's see file path anything without
anything search options or directories.
Oh, that's interesting. You see
as opposed to the Unix like you say
recursive
the
you know which is CD because what you
want is all subdirectories
and their subdirectories.
So the proper English description is
just all sub all directories and subd
directories. But when you say recursive
that is not
totally fitting because recursive
applies a implementation
but the recursion but the going into
subdirectories is not necessarily
recursion. they they they might uh they
actually might be implemented as uh
loop. Okay. But anyway,
so let's try to run this. Okay. So what
is going on here? So,
so this enumerate files and uh search
option or directories
and what is a dis. Okay, all files
recursively or with directory info.
Okay, so let's comment that out for now.
Let's just run this.
Fantastics. Fantastic.
Okay, I think this is great.
I think that's it for today. The
exploration
of F via the help great help of
artificial intelligence.
So far everything is perfect and uh I
like the language the F. I've been
wanting to learn another functional
programming language. I know lisp and I
know wolfam language.
That's the two primary functional
programming languages I know especially
with wuam language I have 30 years of
experience
but I don't know any of the meta
language family
ML or camel camel F
uh or the Haskell family
uh so uh it's very interesting Um,
fantastic. So, I've been wanting to do
this for a long time. So, now we know
how to do these things, you know,
replace string, get file content, how to
write the file, how to write to a file,
how to print, how to uh replace string.
We can implement a find replace script
by putting this together, but uh I'm not
going to do it today. So, that's it for
today.
those uh bellum expertise.
Hello. So, I think that's it for today.
Thank you guys for watching.
So, it's now the holidays. So, I hope
you guys have fun with your friends or
your family. Uh let's welcome a new year
2026.
Who knows what will happen?
um you know today with AI technology is
truly
kind of a pinnacle of human technology
achievement
or or you can say it's a turning point
you know like in each generation
or each 100 years people say this is the
most important era but
but not really because
then next 100 years people will say that
is the most important critical era for
example when we reached internet age 20
years ago there's something or when we
reached TV
uh 100 years ago people say something
and people envision a future but today
AI is really
phenomenal AI and you know and
associated technologies such as robotics
and all sort of science and technology.
Um, so that's incredible. So that's
we'll see what happens. I hope there's
not much
big huge misery created by a hand of
handful of people like war. Um anyway,
so
happy holidays and by
bye for now. We shut down in one minute.
Okay, so today's talk show
uh if you like my stuff, pay me. Okay,
go to kxali.info http nos. Okay, so this
is my homepage kasali.info info and go
all the way down and you can support me,
sponsor me, PayPal me, PayPal me, Amazon
gift card me or Patreon me. Okay,
sorry.in info. Thank you. Bye.
Fantastic.