Hello guys, good evening guys. Good
evening guys. Welcome to another episode
of Kas talk show. We are going to do
some F learning coding programming
language F supreme functional
programming. Okay, here's my keyboard.
Ultimate hacking keyboard UHK80.
This is my Julian
HP640.
uh drawing tablet. Fantastic. This is my
newly track ball. I have re review on
them on YouTube for each one of them.
Just search for it. You'll find it. And
this I had a introduction. This is Suave
board. SV A L B O A R D. SV A L B O A R
D. Suave board. Fantastic.
I haven't used it yet, but I want to
give a shout shout out. So, look at my
YouTube and other people also have
reviews. Okay, so let's switch to my
screen
uh because we are going to do code
coding. Okay, so my keyboards I have
YouTube reviews. Okay, check it out. If
you are here, say hi. Hello. The
informaticist.
If you are not here, watch at 1.5 speed.
Now, this is this video is probably not
useful to you, okay? For those of you
who have if you want to learn F, the
supreme functional programming language,
there are lots of tutorials out there
focused
and they do much better job.
Uh, meanwhile,
I'm just writing my learning notes and
meanwhile have a little bit fun with
this drink. Okay.
The quality of a good life. What is
this? Kalúa.
Rich people's drink. Oh,
okay. I'm just have some fun. Okay.
is one shot. This is this this kalúa is
rum coffee liquor.
Have you ever had it informat
informat informaticist?
Okay, let's let's start to code F. Okay,
I wanted to do Oh, I forgot to do this.
Okay, so hold on a second. Let me hide
my screen and show display capture.
Okay, hold on a second. Let's go to my
todo pictures in case I have some
personal information. If not, that's
good. Okay, I don't think I do. Okay, so
let's see. Yeah, the personal
information. Um, well, let's go back.
Let's go back. Uh, close that. Let's go.
Uh, okay. Hold on a second.
Do you know what I'm doing? No, you
don't. But I will show you in a bit.
Okay. Move that there.
Okay. Did we move it?
Yes. Okay. Open it. That's good. Okay.
So, close, close, close, close, close.
And uh let's turn back on my screen
so you can see me again. So today's talk
show I'm going to code my uh my F
learning notes. Okay. Now I got my hands
sticky because of the drink. So I need
to uh clean my hands.
Okay. So we are going to write a section
on how to do loops. Very basic loop.
Loops is the fundamental programming
languages of all programming languages.
One of the most important is loops. Uh
it's even more important than variables.
Okay.
Okay. I think we can have another shot
then. I need to like clean my hands.
Not much.
Okay, you need to uh
do something. We can just like drink.
Okay, let's start to code. It's
delicious. Fantastic. Where you from?
So, where where are you based? Okay, so
let's do So, let me show you. Let's go
to desktop. So I have some of these
notes I have prepared.
Uh open it.
So uh notes I have prepared. Now you can
see open it. So you can see it here. Now
it's too small.
Uh yeah it's kind of too small for you
to see
but um
anyway. So that's the notes I have to
do. Okay. So that's basically just the
basic F doing a how how to do a loop.
Okay. And what I want to do is just to
write my tutorial.
Okay. So let's go to uh you know note.
So first of all create a new section
here. So string number types. So you
need a loop and you need
so you need a section for loop. And let
me tell you where these tutorials are
from. That's the best tutorial. You can
find it on Microsoft website. This is
the website. Okay, remember this is the
best F documentation tutorial.
This is the one you want to read if you
are the nononsense type. You don't want
to read stories. Oh, like oh once upon a
time there's this programming and it's
beautiful and uh uh let me tell you how
wonderful it is. Uh you can make a lot
of money and first of all you need to
download and let me tell you what to do
you know like a stupid storytelling
style. Meanwhile, this F documentation
tutorial is to the point. Okay, no
nonsense. That's what I like. And that's
what my tutorials are like.
So, um, okay. So, let's go. Okay. So,
let's let's let's let's Okay. So, so
first of all, go to my tutorial. Open
it. And the pink window shows all my
command course and the keystrokes. You
can see on the pink window. Okay. Uh,
let's go search for panel. And I want to
create a new section for uh loop and uh
there's something else
loop and okay this is about JavaScript.
This is about JavaScript.
Yeah, this is about wam language. Okay,
so I just want some
uh
Oh, so you need to do two things, right?
loop and conditional both are the most
critical. Okay, so let me just show you
how to do that. Okay, variables. Um so
uh let's just say if then
okay if then
and uh loop. Okay, loop
if uh
if then. Okay, if then is known as
conditional. Okay. So, capitalize them
and capitalize it. And uh those should
go should they go before variables or
after?
Uh let's see.
Let's put them after. Okay. So I believe
so because look at my Python tutorial.
Let's see what I did. So here's my
Python tutorial. String unic code
operators, arithmetic operators,
assignment, boolean, conditional, then
loop, conditional, and loop and data
structure. So you have variables before.
Uh yeah, I think so. So wait,
so this is a Python tutorial. Actually
there's no dedicated section for
variable. Okay. So you can see data
structure. Then before that it's loop
and iteration. Before that is
conditional. Conditional and loop. These
are the essence
structure of programming language and
boolean. Okay. And boolean. Then before
that arithmetics like 1 + 1. How do you
do that? And string also the
foundational data stroke uh type and
number. Okay. then comment. Okay. So, so
that's uh the Python tutorial. Then you
go to EMAC this tutorial. So you can see
string number boolean variable. Okay. So
string number boolean they come before
variable then I tell you then you know
you tell people how to define variable.
Okay. Then you have conditionals
conditionals and loop. Yeah that's the
way I want to go. Okay. So you can go
also double check go back um
uh double check go to my programming
languages uh let's see JavaScript
let's see uh it's pretty much uh so
boolean test equality conditional and
loop that's right so assignment and
variable so variables is in the
assignment section so in JavaScript
that's also the case variables
assignment then boolean and
conditional and loop. Okay. Cheers.
Fantastic.
So F back to F. So uh close Python. So
if then yeah. So let's create those
page. So first of all, so copy.
So wherever you see those pages, find
those string.
Wherever you see that,
okay, start with string then replace by
that. Okay,
string number type variable. Do it. And
now string number type variable if then
loop. Okay, change everything in this
directory. So those are changes you can
see. Change change.
Close it. Show in browser. Now you can
navigate. Okay. You see string. Go to
string section. Go to number section. Go
to type section. Go to variable section
and go to if then section which is
empty. Which now we will create. Okay.
Just copy the variable and open the if
then paste it. Save. Close. Save. Close.
What?
Save.
Close. Okay. Open the loop. Empty. Paste
it. Save. Close. Now open if then modify
the title. You can see my command name
there. It's HTML update title. So I just
press press.
Then if then
conditional. Okay, that's the title show
in browser. There it is. Then you don't
want the you don't want the variable. So
make the date correct. Okay.
Delete variable. Delete. Uh delete.
Delete. Delete mutable variables named
literal. Okay. Delete. Receive the let
line by tip. Okay. show in browser empty
fantastic that's what I want so copy the
whole content close it go to the loop
section open it select all paste and uh
rename the title so this would be loop
loop
uh mismatched bracket
no paired closing bracket okay I don't
care so why would I care so showing
browser fantastic so we got the loop
age done string number type variable if
then and loop there it is okay so how do
you do
if then okay so let's go to the
documentation the F tutorial will
explain
we are copying their content because we
are learning
so far so
tool of F functional programming it's a
supreme
uh so we want to know so what's new F
tools uh where are we language reference
language guide okay so values strings
let bindings functions loop and
conditional so we want to learn about
conditional if then okay
so what you can do is uh if then else.
So let's show.
Okay. So let's just start to the first
thing important when you write a
tutorial is the actual code. So you want
to be able to show I mean you want to be
be able to run the code to make sure
that runs then you know what is going
on. Okay. So if boolean expression let's
say three then uh
okay. So you see when we run into a
problem you see I don't know F. So how
do you do this? So uh can you do print
uh
let's say yes then yes okay
can you actually print that uh let's say
print you know is this valid run it
no
okay because you cannot do if three you
know because three is not a valid
boolean type so how do you convert it
can you like do boolean I'm guessing
okay B O L or E N because I don't know
F# so this is like the art of learning a
new language if you know the language
you typically like you are like you you
know like you can you know but the the
like it's very intuitive but usually
when you don't know the language that
becomes
uh
when you don't know the language And
then then things become very
interesting. It it because it throws
away your expectations
you know. So for example here we want to
know can you so first of all if is a
expression
that which is very different from the if
statements in JavaScript in C in Python.
Okay. And the other thing so that's my
guess. Okay. I don't know for sure but
this is my guess. Okay. So that's why we
put the if here it's an expression. Then
the other thing expression means it
returns a value. Okay. The other thing
about if is that so now we want to know
how do you soal
cast but the C idiots they call it cast
cast this type to boolean. So uh can you
do that?
Run it. No. Okay. So uh the value of
constructor boolean is not qualified. So
I'm living on negro island Philippines.
I'm a quiz small talk programmer. Oh
small talk programmer primarily I know
what's a small talk but what is quiz
small talk? Is that a particular
implementation
of small talk? That's interesting.
See
what what is quiz small talk.
Oh,
okay. Quiz maybe quiz small talk is an
open-source multi- multi-platform small
talk 80 system designed with a focus on
simplicity, cleanness,
cleanliness.
Interesting. You see they don't they
don't say cleanness
but they say cleanliness
and maintain maintainability. Okay. It
aims to preserve the original values of
small talk as as envisioned as Xerox
Park [snorts] emphasizing a dynike
environment for learning experimentation
and knowledge expression. Okay.
quiz. Now, how do you what is the
significance of the word quiz? CUIS is
that like what does it mean CUIS?
Quiz actively resists unbounded
complexity growth. It prioritizes a
small comprehensible codebase where
every component has clear purpose. Okay.
Okay. I don't know small talk but uh the
guy I think is a bit of a crackpot Allan
you know the Allen guy.
Okay so anyway that's interesting. Thank
you for the answer. Um
and quiz quiz. Okay. So, that's like
this is their website. Let's open it and
see.
Is that a logo? No. What logo is that?
Is that a dog or what is it?
Interesting logo
now. So, what does CUIS mean? Quiz like
like you got gui. Is this does this like
means cui something s
I don't know. Okay.
Anyway, let's go back to uh F.
Okay. So F you cannot do this. Uh so
what is so let's look so this is a time
when you can look at literal types and
maybe learn something about it. Is there
a boolean type? You know, I just wrote
this like a week ago, a week ago in my
process of learning F#. So these are the
literal types, the most fundamental
basic types, literal types. Okay, type
literal.
Uh well,
so anyway, so is there a true false
boolean decimal char string by string or
by? No, there is no boolean type. Jesus.
Oh, interesting.
There's no like h there's no boolean uh
true and false. So, you don't even see
that.
So, you see the most basic thing we
don't even know how to do if statement.
Uh so, but if you can say can you say
true?
No. Even if that is false, can you like
capital true? No. Okay. So, what is
this? Um
error the value of constructor true is
not defined. Okay. So, let's say true
run that
uh standing error. This expression was
expected to have type unit but it has
type string.
Okay. So this you know I know that the
if expression type should be unit
basically means unique means like
nothing like void. Uh but we have string
so what does it mean? So I no I don't
know so you know we stuck with the most
basic thing we stuck
[ __ ]
Uh so let's go back to the
documentation. And they have some
examples here. Okay. So if you say let's
say
uh three less than four that's true,
right? Run it.
No. So it's a unit unit problem.
Uh so how do they how do they do it?
We got a unit type incompatibility
problem.
Okay. Let's put it back. Let's um put
their code here. And uh so their code
example is a bit complicated because
they try to show if then
and al if and else all together in one
thing which I don't want. You want it
when you write a tutorial, you want to
it to be as simple as possible. So you
want to only show the example of if
then. Then a separate example for if
then else.
Then another separate example for if
then and L iff. Okay. L if as far as I
know is a is a a shortcut for then else.
I mean then for for else if. Okay. So,
so anyway, they have all everything in
one shot. Okay, so let's let's run it.
Okay, this won't run. Okay, so what's
your name? Because I you know because I
I'm not running this in terminal. So it
doesn't get it.
Uh so complicated complicated example.
You see they are trying to show multiple
things about the if expression but also
they meanwhile also demonstrate the
reading user input. So this is a very
complex example
I don't want. So this would not be in my
tutorial. So but but um but their their
example is working. So let's we can
separate it and see see if we can make
sense of the parts.
Okay.
So let's remove the whatever. So if then
equals. So you see another thing
complicated is that they are defining a
function
making things way more complicated.
No good. Okay. So I just want to show
a simple example of if else. Okay. If 3
equals to 4 then say that uh like can
you even how do you do that?
Let's say something
run it.
Okay, that runs. But is this like can
you do this? Run it. That also runs now.
Does that mean I can print it? Uh, so
this is the expression, right? Print
that.
Okay. Can you
do this.
Yes, it does. Okay. So, let's So, let's
say yes. And and this part, let's say
no. Okay. Delete that. Run it.
Fantastic. This is what I want.
So, this this is the most simple example
of showing if then else. But actually,
we don't want else. We just want um Can
you even reduce it with just that run
it?
No.
Yeah. So that's the problems you see.
You see this is the interesting thing
when you learn a new language that you
are not familiar with. So this is about
you know when you don't have the else
part then it returns a unit
um the type of the whole expression must
be a unit but however I have it a string
so how do I like fix it I don't know so
that's an interesting thing okay so
that's um but if you do have the else
part And then then this expression
returns a string type. Okay. And that
works. Okay. So put it back. And uh
Okay.
Is it is this fun? Okay. I think this
I'm not doing good because
I shouldn't I shouldn't drink because
now
the brain becomes slower.
So this is not you know I'm not doing a
good job of
writing this tutorial.
you know this tutorial about if then
else statement in F actually it's quite
interesting to learn because
you see if you are not familiar if you
if you don't have
experience from Haskell or or camel
then this would be totally new even if
you are a functional programmer you see
I'm a functional programmer for like 30
years
uh I have tense you tens of years of
experience in Wuan language and lisp.
Okay. But I'm not familiar with the
strong typed
functional programming languages such as
Okamo, FS ascal.
So in this example, you run into if
expression which I'm very familiar with,
but they require you to have like the
type unit. If you don't have the then
part. So I don't quite understand. You
see?
So if a boolean then something it must
have it must return the type unit.
Okay. The unit type as far as I know is
some kind of new like void. It does just
like no type.
So um
okay so so yeah so so that's um so this
this is in fact interesting if you don't
have background with F or related
languages. Okay.
But uh you see that's it about this if
then else statement. That's just this
page.
You know they they told you about the
unit type. Then you they told you if
chaining if then else expressions
together you can use the keyword L if
instead of else if they are equivalent.
So the lf keyword is just the shortcut
syntactical shortcut for else if. Okay.
So
so there's not much to it. That's the
only example they gave for the entire
section of conditionals.
You see very simple. But
but do I understand it? No. I cannot
even write a simple function of if then
without else.
You see? So does that mean their
tutorial actually failed?
Actually that kind of actually it kind
of mean that it's not very
let's say not very full. Okay. because I
do have experience in functional
programming and you and and I don't so
so you know if you read carefully you
have to read carefully
boolean expression evaluates to true
otherwise expression two runs okay
like other languages if then else
construct can be used to conditionally
execute code in F in F if if then else
is an expression and produces a value by
the branch that executes. Okay. The type
of the expressions in each branch must
match.
Okay. So if then the then expression and
the else expression they must match
type.
Okay. Now if there is no explicit else
branch the overall type is unit and the
type of the lane branch must also be
unit. Okay.
Um,
okay. Yeah, I understand.
I understand. What are you saying, but
but
how do I make a if then without else?
And I want it to print yes.
Do you know what I'm saying? How do I
make this work?
Okay, we can ask AI
by the opus of the AI bot. Let's ask AI.
C UIS is the name of a South American
rodent. Oh, that's interesting. The name
distinguishes it from squeak small talk.
Oh, okay.
>> [laughter]
>> That's interesting. Thank you. So, C UIS
is a rodent. Let's see what uh that's
why the logo.
Okay. So, okay. C UIS. Okay. It looks
like um it's very
niche animal. You see when you search
CUIS they don't even show it except one
like video
like there's no Wikipedia. Typically you
would see when you search for animal
name that's like there would be
Wikipedias and lots of photos but you
don't even see it.
So, CUIS rodent
H
conversational user interface design.
So, let's let's look for pictures. I
want to know what kind of
Oh, so this is CUI. So, this is like uh
what what are they called? Gina pics
something.
Oh, what's the other name? Uh, yeah. So,
H interesting.
Okay.
So, Okay. So, you see how do you do
this? Uh, so let's ask guac
guac. Um, okay. Our question is
fix this code
F code. Okay.
Okay. Control scroll to magnify.
Okay. Good enough.
Here's
your fixed F code with several correct
versions. Pick the one that matches what
you actually want. Okay. Print string if
three equals 4 then yes and else no.
Okay. This one I understand because the
return value the return type is a
string. They they in they are in
agreement. Okay. Now this one, if you
really want unit, ignore the else
clause.
Okay. Well, you also return well you you
are using an else, you see. So that's
not what we want. We want if then
without else. How to do it? But print
yes, you know, but without else. But
they are just adding a else with a empty
string. So it's still using a else.
Okay. So the third alternate alternative
style using pattern matching. Okay.
So you are doing
it's not using if statement at all. So
it's using patterns match three= 4 with
if it's true then return yes or no.
Okay. But that's something else. That's
not if statement. That's not if
conditional that's not what we looking
for because pattern matching
is entirely different thing. Okay,
that's in many ways it can emulate I
mean it serves as a purpose of
conditional but and much more uh
conditional yeah branching and uh
well effect effective effectively it's
branching conditional okay panda
matching is conditional
but without if statement like if
statement is one of the way of a
conditional.
Others others are like switch or which
or cases they are similar but
padmatching is another way of
conditional
kind of more powerful.
Okay. But still panda matching
ultimately is a conditional
you know it's a like the conditional
um you know part of the program language
where where have you have to branching
you know branching conditionals okay you
where you have to make a decision then
run certain code depending on the
situation okay so that is the pattern
matching okay but that's not if
statement okay so Then then you say um
very short version using boolean to
string conversion. Okay. So here you
have boolean to string. Let's see if 3
equals to 4 then yes.
Uh else
string force. Okay.
So you are forcing
the force value into a string.
That's still I mean so that's still with
a clause
you know. So
okay
so looks like we got the answer but the
answer is
you know it's not what we thought.
So that means so from this answer from
guac
even though it's not what we what what
we really wanted but we can infer from
the answer from gu that
in fact what we wanted it wanted to do
is not is not like valid. Okay,
you see why your original code doesn't
compile. That's because without else
return unit. Okay, but print s expect a
string. Unit is not string. So, am I
making sense or do you guys know whether
Allan Key is a crackpot or a visionary
depends entirely on whether you
uh value pure engineering efficiency or
conceptual paradigm shifts. Okay. I'm
guessing you are a fan of Allen key.
Okay.
That is my guess.
Okay. I
I don't I don't know too much detail
about Alan Key to to really say. Okay.
So anyway, yeah. So, you know, to really
know what he's talking about because
I've been looking, you know, I have
somewhat look into small talk because
Alan Key or Alen K, however you
pronounce it, I think he's still alive,
right? I think he's still alive. you
know he made a dramat dramatic claim
about op you know like op is wide you
know it's very popular today right
because of Java C++
not because small talk but rather
because C++ and Java and Python Ruby
JavaScript you know like but mo mostly
Java and C++ mostly C++ okay Java they
made the this style of OP widely popular
but then Alan key came up he claims oh
those are not my ideal I I invented the
word OP but that's not you know the op
in C++ in Java that's not the op you
know of you know I actually created the
word okay so he's like making a dramatic
claim
about OP and he you know he you know I
created it but that's not what you know
that what But what you are doing in C++
and Java is wrong. Okay. So, so that
that made people look into into it uh
look into you know programming language
history and the history of object
oriented programming. Okay. Now it is
true
it is true that his vision I mean it is
true for one thing he I think he created
the jargon OP
like what um you know um I mean I I
think it's reasonable to say he's the
one okay I mean other people I think
there might be you know someone used
before him but basically he's the
effectively the guy who promoted the
jargon. Okay. Who made the jargon
popular? Oop. But then it is also true
that his idea of op is not what the op
um actually wait actually he this this
is uh
uh this is the controversy. Okay. He
claims that his op is different from the
op in Java or C++. But actually
[laughter]
actually that's not true. Okay. Uh
well uh we digressed. Okay. So we um
well actually I'm not doing much of
anything. I'm not doing
um
uh not doing much with F anyway. So
let's you know so let's uh origin of op.
Okay. So um origin of object. Okay. So I
watched this video. This is fantastic.
Okay. Not this one. Inheritance was
invented as a performance hack. This is
about similar
the programming language. Similar which
is another like the history of the OP.
Okay. Objectoriented programming or
engine of inheritance. Okay. But the one
the the one I'm looking for is um this
one. Okay. History of objectoriented
programming by Casey Muratori. Okay, I I
I learned about this video a month ago.
Fantastic video. He dive into deep deep
dive into the history of OP and the
examination
of Alan Keith's claim. I invented OP the
jargon but that's not what you think.
Okay. But in fact, you look at the
history according to him and other
sources I believe. So I trust this guy
is correct. Alan Key is [ __ ] Okay.
Alan Key promoted the same OP that the
Bjang stroke that C++
promoted. Okay, they promoted the same
thing.
Uh but anyway, Small Talk OP they may be
different. I mean they that I think is
true anyway. So I don't so I don't know
much so I don't know too much detail to
make further comments because to
to make further comments you really need
to understand uh small talk. So I need
to start to learn small talk. I'm not
that interested. Okay. Uh for example I
have far more interest. I need I need to
learn about F. I need to get really
proficient with F# that far more
important to me F or Julia. Okay. Or and
uh and also the most important is for
the proof systems. Okay. The uh ling
programming language. Okay. For proof
so-called proof assistant that F or
Julia is really what I need to master.
small talk
you know
not you know it's interesting as a
programming language history research
but uh is not interesting to me at all
like at all there are you know I would
learn pock which I don't know
more than you know before small talk and
uh um
and also Erland I would want to learn
about Erland or its new modern versions
like Elixir then small talk. So small
talk, you know, so I don't really care
that much. But to really make claims
about the history of OP and what Alan
Key is talking about, uh, you need
really need to dive into, uh, small
talk. And also I learned, you know,
because I was talking about these
things, someone on Twitter, was it you,
who told me about I don't think it's you
because they he never mentioned CUI
small talk Twitter. Another small talk
fan told me about apparently small talk
they diversified. So today's small talk
is actually the CPP C++ small talk. You
know they they changed their idea of
object to follow the mainstream CP C++
ones. [laughter]
So silly. So you have the so now you
have the original small talk kind of
like
Yeah. Okay. And also small talk you got
kind kind of got a little quote. I
really truly hate codes because I'm
interested in programming languages,
right? So, you know, people follow me
and we talk about we debate about
programming languages. Like today, we
were debating about jarens on um array
versus list versus map versus hasht
versus um dictionary. We were talking
about that. So anyway, so then there are
people would tell me about small talk. S
have you learned small talk yet? You
know, small talk like there's like kind
of code uh followers of small talk.
Okay, so that's interesting. Uh
so uh KPTXX says Alan K's definition of
op includes lisp
preing
emacisp is closest to what he meant.
It really I don't I don't think so.
Okay. Anyway yeah so anyway you have to
learn small talk you know. So I don't
know some more talk. Okay, I think
that's it. Bye guys.
Yeah, bye guys. Yeah, I think that's it.
So we were I was trying to learn uh F
uh conditional if statement. Then we
were trying to learn how to do loop in
uh F. appar you know we didn't get into
that but just for if then else it's very
simple but
but I don't really I don't fully
understand it you see it's so simple
there's only like two screen
documentation about it
but
do I really understand it no because
like can I comfort comfortably write a
if then else
anywhere in in F# no because first of
all I know it's a expression but how do
you like how do you embed this in
expression like you know another
complexity is that F began to follow the
Python indentation [ __ ] okay that I in
my opinion that crippled F significantly
and there's nothing you can do you you
cannot like I mean they also support
that um the other you know traditional
syntax but but basically they [ __ ] it
up. Okay, because you cannot turn this
off. So
So anyway, do I understand if then else
in F? No, because it's a expression,
right? That means you can embed that
expression into you know somewhere like
like here. But this is not an example
because they they made it into a
function.
So anyway, so I don't know how to do it
and I don't fully understand you know
what if then else if you don't have else
it the return type must be unit. So what
does that mean exactly?
I mean yeah I understand the return type
must be unique. So effectively,
you know, effectively that that just
means you
you never write if then without else
because you ask walk or they tried to do
is they they just added an else or they
switched to the pattern matching,
right? So So what does it mean? If you
want to just have if then and have it
return unit type like what what does it
in practice means? I don't know. So very
simple thing it turns out we haven't uh
learned
uh which is very interesting. This is
about programming languages.
So for languages you are familiar with
let's say if you are learning Ruby from
Python or Pearl or Python from Ruby from
Pearl you know similar or from Java to C
or C++ they are all similar
then you you don't have a problem you
can like right away oh you know but when
you are learning a language that's
totally new like you know for me F is
like barely new uh or if you are
learning like Erland or um or small talk
maybe or you know then you don't get
like very e even very simple things uh
seems confusing. Okay.
Okay. That's it. Bye guys. Bye.