good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of sound talk
show
today we are going to do emacs
and emac list coding and tutorial
uh it's more or less random okay
random talk and so it's going to be pure
emacs or emacs related stuff maybe some
keyboards
so if you have questions ask post in the
chat
chat okay and uh if you
feel it's proper put money in my pocket
chi-ching
okay so and this is my keyboard i'm
showing you my keyboard this
is kinesis advantage to
uh linear okay linear red silent red
switches fantastic this is my favorite
and this is my ultimate hacking keyboard
i use it for as a marker keypad
so anyway we're gonna talk about emac
stuff okay
uh so emacs what we're gonna do i'm not
sure i'm just going to look around
uh the my uh notes on topics and see
maybe some
live coding of emac this
plus tutorial so my video check my audio
check
good okay let's begin
okay good morning keep keep it do you
use emacs for eating as well yes indeed
hello everyone i eat every meal in front
of
my computer and 90 80 of time ninety
percent of time
you know maybe 60 technically on average
would be
in e-max the other half of the time
would be in browser
for the past uh at least for the past 10
years but
you know almost for the past 30 years
okay emacs okay so uh what are we going
to do
today i'm thinking okay first of all let
me tell you about my emacs
pink window this emily's very favorite
color
so on this pink window or purple window
you can see
all my emacs command cores for example
moving cursor by word
or moving cursor by character moving
cursor up and down or moving cursor by
a paragraph up and down beginning a
buffer in a buffer and i'm using
starfly keys okay so for example let me
show you some typing
so i'm using a real-time demo because i
fly keys
okay so that is my
emacs package and you can see all my key
strokes on the left of the pink window
okay delete that and if you find
some commands uh you are interested just
search for the web your
you'll find it on my website and the
source code
okay soft like keys and i'm using a vera
keyboard so okay what is today's topic
let's see
uh do you want me uh do you guys like me
to see
live coding uh emac list
or some just random chat about some
tutorials or demo
of emacs okay so any questions you have
about emacs asked me okay
so let me look at uh topics and uh
hello seed uh is
is any of this dialect used in real
world other than
closure of course okay you're probably
young from from the look of your
question
this is still used okay skim this is
used mostly
in academia skin this or racket okay
and commonly is still used in industry
like 10 years ago
google bought this airplane ticket you
know uh
selling website for big money billions
or what whatever millions
uh probably millions uh you know google
about it so
and it's that website is written in
commonly commonly
you know it's uh industrial it's still
used but not
you know it's less and less it's like
pearl well pearl is even more used
so enclosure is of course used in many
uh many startups
uh you know will you be doing
an episode on keyboards soon if you have
some
questions about keyboard you can ask me
you know because you know emacs people
will probably
be interested in keyboards
uh yeah so because we i you know i talk
about keyboards
all the time so anyway so let's see
what are we going to do uh add html
youtube linkify to emacs blog okay
update that okay i'm going to
[Music]
i think i'm just going to pick random
and start doing it instead of talking
do you suggest me to learn closure or
ragged can you tell the main difference
okay you haven't been watching my videos
i talked about that topic
for like 10 million times okay just go
to my
uh um i talked about emac this okay
go to or go to okay okay let me show you
quickly okay
uh xarley programming blog
okay go to my programming blog
not my patreon of course but you can pay
me go to my patreon and
pay me this article what's ontology or
programming languages i have
you know a thousand articles on that
anyway so
you go to uh let me show you okay you go
to
sardi code you go to my programming blog
you go to then this section complain
perving okay now and then you
can see two videos actually i have more
than two there
it's all about this okay so what's your
question do you suggest okay
learn closure okay closure is much more
um you have jobs with closure possible
jobs okay but
uh much less if you do racket or
scheme anyway i talked about this one
ten thousand times each video is one
hour okay uh watch them
uh okay uh we let's go back to images
okay
no problem no problem sam uh no problem
this is uh
talk show free free speech
free speech and in a chaotic way
okay so you know and you know random
issue so okay so let's see
i need my pain i need my pain to spin
uh this is a habit okay so anyway so
let's
see what we want to do today uh
emac this are you a emac list user okay
i try to use emac this
what is this not enough
video to smooth stream what the
okay um
okay so okay let me read actually let me
let me
let me do some uh let's see what we're
gonna do today
update because i add period to line and
okay
so yeah i talked about that before okay
so let me show you
okay so for example for example uh let
me copy that okay
uh okay let's let's do that okay so so
let me so let me show you so there's a
command
for example if you are on twitter or on
if you are on discord
you know we have lots of chat some you
know sometimes you want to
for example uh square root this guy
wrote a lot of things
you know usually on discord you don't uh
you don't use
comma okay for example this
you know suppose you you wrote something
on discord and you want to put it on
your blog
now there is no comma at the end of the
sentence because
you know it's easier to type on discord
you you know
you know it's not necessary to type
comma or on twitter i mean not not comma
period okay
so but if you for example this you add a
paragraph
and you show in browser and what you see
you know then you see this one long
sentence that doesn't make sense
so you want what you want to do is to
actually
add comma okay to each for example let
me show you
so what do you want is something like
that comma
i mean i mean not comma period period
okay
uh for all each line so there's a easy
so that's why i wrote at uh i wrote a
command for it add period to end line
okay enter you see
it adds the period you know let's do it
again
paste paste okay let's do it here so you
see
compare this paragraph to the above you
know
you have all the periods so now
suppose i compare let's add a paragraph
okay shrink go to the browser
magnify you can compare these two
paragraph
the the one with the period now makes
sense now
let's go back and besides that
let me do another thing that's
interesting because you see it's all
lower case
maybe and search
you know it's all lowercase so
so after you add a period it would
look it will be easier to read if you
make
each beginning of a sentence capital
case so i have a command for it
press the key you see it highlight all
the changes part
now if you go back to browser okay hold
on a second undo
cut paste paste and this and make this
one so we have now
three versions the original version
the one with the period and the one with
the period and capital letter
okay now if you show in browser magnify
you can compare the three paragraphs so
it's much easier to read
you know with the period and capital
letters
so that's two related commands
uh you can see i call them
uh you know you can find the command i
called down on the left
uh except except if i'm doing meta x but
anyway anyway so
so that is the background for the
command
add period okay now but what is i what
what is my problem what is it that i
want to do
i want uh for example let's see
okay let's look at the command okay the
source code okay
magnify okay let's not magnify uh let's
shrink a little bit okay
so let's call you see meta x star add
period to
line end now
ctrl h f that will look
that will show the documentation for
this command
then tab go to it then here's the source
code for this
command okay it's magnified so
the source code so okay so
you see so usually
when i have some useful command i add it
to my emacs blog
so so for example and i i
i will say a ui out here
but apparently i don't have it so that's
what i'm that's what i need to do so
let's go to my emacs blog
using a bookmark so this is my emacs
blog showing browser
okay so now i want to see if i
ever added that command here so i don't
remember
you know sometimes i don't remember
because i anyway
so let's search for period in this
buffer
see what do we find it
uh so there are several
currencies let's let's look at this one
okay so here is the source code
emacs list add period to long end okay
so apparently i do not have a dedicated
page for it
so that's what i'm going to do now
yeah let's look at this one it
what does this say yeah to do okay okay
so let me show you okay so shrink
show in browser wait show in browser
then search for p-e-r-i-o-d
you see to do 2021
february add to emac this tutorial
add period to line end and xr word
uh words etymology link anyway so that's
one of the to do let's search
for period again okay and here is you
know
my blog aside blog sometimes i don't
have time to create a web
you know page for this so let's do that
okay so
now i'm in my blog so this is my blog
file so you can see
uh my emacs blog so showing browser
you know you can see that now i just i
need to so what i need to do i need to
create a new page
uh containing the add period command so
so other people can search for it and
find it and
so create a new page
and also i needed to add it
add that page to one of the
index uh page here table of contents for
example here's a emacs tutorial
uh um uh wait
uh you know firefox does not remember
the font size if it's local file
anyway so you see there are different
topics you know emacs setup emacs keys
so i need to after i create a new page
for that command i need it
i need to add it to some you know one of
these page
probably in this examples okay probably
so copy the url
one single key press this is the
ultimate hacking keyboard my macro
keypad
toggle okay then go to my emacs plot
again create a new entry paste the link
we just copied
and make it make it into a link make it
a paragraph
show in browser and you can see
you can see emac these examples this is
the index
we want to add that page to so okay
so so now we want to
create a page uh that the file name
should be something like add
uh period to line
end okay now i i have written a command
that automate this
process otherwise you know normally i
have what i have to do is
new buffer uh go to
site html mod magnify
then type html h abbrev
wait html uh wait html
oh wait let's switch to html mod okay
html then type html h that creates a
template
then change the you know title the title
then change add you know google tracker
google ads what
there's no google ad in on my emacs page
but you know i have to
add a author add a date you know tedious
so close that i have written a command
so
look look at the command okay so look at
uh i just call
meter x x and p okay
xmp is a edius to start new page
so let's say let me show you okay
control
h f x and p so what is it
so it expands here uh you know
it's alias for site new
page right okay so let's just call it
oh wait uh okay
so put a cursor on this line called
xmp or
site
site new page okay enter
there it is it becomes a link now if you
move the cursor to the link
enter you can see it created a file
now shrink showing browser magnify so
you can see it's a html file everything
all the templates and footers and
navigation buttons are all there already
so all i have to do is just add the
content
so i created new page now let's see uh
you know i start to write the page so
this is a useful command
to add
uh wait
these commands add a
period to current to
each end of line
in current
text block okay this is useful
when you copy text from
discord or twitter
to your blog okay showing browser
that's it that that's what we want
okay and actually i also need the the
navigation bar okay let's do that later
but anyway so
close it now we are back in the um
make a paragraph we are back in my emacs
blog
this file needs to be added to this
index file so
but first of all let's add the code so
let's search for period okay
list matching lines or i want to show
all occurrences
of lines that contains period okay so
you can see here is a section i did
uh you know emac discord let's let's
let's
uh you see it's unreadable but
press a button
now it you can see the lisp code
uh if you are using oak mod babble you
might be familiar with this feature
so anyway so so copy copy cut
okay so we basically cut this
all that okay now to go to the beginning
now shrink now go to the beginning of
buffer search for section
so this is where we were before so
go open the file show in browser that's
the empty file go back
then uh paste it here okay
show in browser now you can see we are
almost done
you know i this is my code okay now
uh close that i mean i mean go back to
emacs then
then press a key to syntax highlight
let's do it again okay
you see it's not syntax highlighted so i
press a key now back to browser
refresh you can see so this all
is part of html mod it's
free online you can use it now okay so
so that's that okay actually
actually there is something i want to do
okay so so hold on a second let me
yeah let's let's do it you know in a
proper order okay so
close that now the file name
i need to follow my tradition of title
of files
so first of all make it capitalize
um title you know let's undo let let me
show you okay so copy that
paste it here so i'm going to call the
command i want to title this line
by sentence case by by title case
meaning capitalize
all words of each word first letter of
each word except
things like two and is you know those
those
uh those those are called um
uh what's uh what's the name for those
words
in grammar i forgot but anyway watch
okay
do it okay you see the two is not
capitalized but the others are so copy
that
we don't need that okay copy that
open the file again now you need to
update in this title tag
and also in this h1 tag
so you have to you know update both
places and
and by my own commit convention the
title
and the first h1 must always be exactly
the same
okay so i have a command to do that uh
just press
let me show you okay so look at the pink
window
i press two keys you know delete n
not end but you know because i have a
brief so it becomes end but delete
the key is like you know there
so let's see how am i doing am i doing
good
uh obs uh yeah check healthy
i'm healthy okay so i'm gonna read the
comments in a bit okay so
so so wait let's continue so i
yeah update the title so
the title now go back to browser you can
look at the title and the first heading
refresh you know it's done
yeah the title well the title is in the
in the tab but anyway this is the
h1 okay and this line is no longer
needed so okay so let's let's
edit it's uh so this is uh the
process of creating a blog of writing a
blog
my my you know my pr my own process
so written on the spot so this is my
blog before it says written on the site
this is useful because when
in online chat often you don't type the
ending period
but when but when you copy and paste to
a blog and reformat it to
html you want the ending period okay so
let's compare
which which description is better for
this page
okay let's see this is useful when you
copy text from discord or twitter to
your blog
yeah okay so so let's worry about the
editing you know so-called editing
you know the uh make them you know make
the text uh you know
more conformant to to grammar or
ease of reading things like that but
let's worry about that later
okay so anyway so here is the uh
basically here's a page okay let's
shrink
show in browser one more time showing
browser
refresh yeah so essentially that's
it for this page so people you know
search it they might find it and
you know here's the code they can put in
in their emacs in it
and then they have it there's no
dependencies
okay okay but okay
there's more things i need to tidy up
for these
uh before i you know before i sync to my
server so
let me show you but before we do that
let's read the comments a little bit
pancreas no learn closure if you want a
job
learn racket if you want to learn about
programming language itself yes
exactly that's a good description thank
you
qpp do you have a video on emacs native
compilation no no i don't have that
uh yeah yeah you know those kind of
things are not
uh you know i know the nerds are always
interested in
those i'm not too interested in those
i'm more interested
in you know the actual useful
the actual usefulness or application uh
you know
i'm less about i'm less interested in
tricking memories
in you know creating a more uh cached
version or
maybe a bit faster uh this way or that
way but you have to spend a lot of time
but anyway but i know it's a great
feature
native compilation you know i'll wait
for emacs 28 when it's released i'll
just download it
i don't have to you know i'm not going
to i'm getting old
i don't have much too much time to to
toy
uh you know windows managers which one
is the best things like that
okay pretty slick add period to each
line yes
and uh what are your thoughts on lost
programming language
is that a troll i talked about that a
million times
okay okay so so now you can see
now this page is almost done but i want
to update for example this command
this command this version on my blog is
2020. november okay
but i have updated how do i know because
if you do
um you know describe function then go to
the social gateway
describe function go to the source code
you can see the latest version is
actually 2021
april you know i update it so i want to
and also i need to add a url here
remember before i don't have it now i
have okay
so back to emacs copy file path
again let me do it again okay watch the
pink window you can see
press three keys copy the file path
go back to previous uh go back to
previous go back to here
then paste this and
okay let me do this so you can see
actually uh let's let's um
you see here is the file path full path
on my local file system now i want to
turn that into a url so i have a command
i've written so i press three keys then
it becomes that you know with a full url
okay
now i don't need a title deleted and
and then i want to make it so that when
people do describe function on this
command it will this link will actually
become clickable so people can click it
let me show you how to do that
okay let me show demonstrate okay for
for example
so now we evaluate this
function done now we call describe
function
add period to n line you can see
so here is the function inline doc
so it has the url but it's not clickable
you know you cannot do nothing to it i
want it to be clickable so how do you do
that
let me show you okay so this url so you
all you have to do is add a format like
that okay let me do this again okay
let's make it clear copy okay so what
you want
is
this okay this is when you have
a line of this format capital url
then with with a you know
you know that backtick
character followed by a straight single
quote then emax will auto automatically
make
that url clickable so let me show you
okay let me demo
so if uh eval the buffer
describe function do it again so you can
see
magnify you can see some add period to
line is something something defined in
this file it's bound to this comma
this key and and there it is
url you can click it
you know it says 404 error because i
just created the page but i have not
uploaded to my website yet but
you know that's good that's what we want
so close this so back to
let's tidy this up and tidy this up
okay that's what we want so copy this
file
i mean copy the code now i want to go
back to
that my blog you know
so what you know and i have written
another command i just
press three keys i can jump to the file
even though
even though if it's url for example
right now this url does not exist
on my website however it exists
on my local uh file system because we
just created
it so i want to jump to it
so i wrote a command which is called um
here excel open file at cursor so when
when that command sees this url is a url
and if this url is my own website you
know uh
by checking whether it matches or go
emacs or
sardi.info.org then we'll just open it
instead of
you know launching to a browser so
do it i'm in the file and show in
browser
okay so let's go back okay close that
let's do it again copy copy the code
copy go to it
then you see here's the disk this code i
need to basically delete this
uh whole thing and paste
over the new one okay
so there are quite a few ways to do it
so let me show you one way okay
okay so paste it here
then go back to here then put my cursor
on the last uh parent
just press the key then the whole thing
is deleted let me show you again
okay you see put the cursor because it
will delete all the content
of the matching parents you see you see
the parents here
you see from here to here so i just put
a cursor here
press the key and you know it's good
so now we have the new code you see this
is a
new version date now i just press the
key again
it becomes syntax highlighted showing
browser
there it is with the url and with uh
today's date so that's how i create a
blog and
update my code so some of the you know
that's a demo of what i do
and this you know let me show you
another feature i you know if you want
to edit this code you can just
press the key so it removes
the code from the html and create a new
buffer
here and you can edit it
you know and once you are done editing
you know
something you delete that
paste it back here okay so you can see
then
then you highlight it again okay shrink
show in browser okay that's what we want
now there is one more thing
we need the navigation bar on the left
so
to do that you click on that oh wait
this is
okay this navigation bar is incorrect it
shouldn't go back to e-max fun
it should go back to um
you know it should go back to here so
anyway we need this navigation bar here
so
and we need to add that page to
somewhere here let's see where do we
want to add it
let's do it one one thing at a time so
copy the url
shrink the browser go back to emacs
okay then
close this close this now we are back
in my emacs blog okay
uh yeah okay so actually the url is
already here
you know the the uh
so what we want so open open emac these
examples showing browser that's that
back
to here search for panel
so the panel correspond the navigation
panel is
near the bottom okay i can do it fast
because
you know i've been working on this for
years so
basically copy the panel copy it close
it
go back to the this file open it
go to the near the end after the main
okay paste the panel now show in browser
so you can see it's starting to look
good
now i need to add this page to one of
the
index table of content here so where
should it be let's see
so this one is emax period two line okay
i need to change
um okay the name is actually incorrect
so let's fix that
uh emax actually this should be e-lisp
okay add
add period to
line ends okay
uh okay show in browser that's good back
to emacs
um okay now the title is correct now
let's fix
the navigation bar for the top okay
which is
this line okay
so how do you do that close that back to
the emacs
the easiest way is okay so let's go to
emac this example and go to one of the
go to one of the you know emac these
examples so
this on this page you have command to
escape quotes
okay copy the url shrink back to emacs
paste it here open it and go down
you can see here is the
navigation bar you know this this
this snap correspond to
that okay copy it close it
delete that line go back to this line go
here
paste it here so this is the new what we
want
we don't need the old one anymore so
show in browser
there it is back to emacs correct
okay uh
okay so so so now we add need to add it
to
uh here so let's see add period to line
ends
so this is one of uh page that
is a emac list example so
add period to long end we need to add it
to
somewhere you know that's similar
period to lines okay let's
add it to bracket cap words
okay let's add it to
text transform under cursor yeah so this
belongs to the category
text transformation under cursor
so let's add it after escape quotes
okay
wait let's add it um
bracket cap words after the bracket cap
words
okay
so that's a little bit involved so
let's see let's so here is a panel
search for bracket so here is a
line that says bracket cap words okay
let me show you what i'm going to do
so i basically i want to
[Music]
change every file that contains these
two lines
okay actually let's let's say change
every file that contains these lines
let me show you okay new buffer
let me show you okay back copy the file
path
back paste it
magnify so we i need to change
every file of this text
by by something okay wait
wait bye by something here
uh something here is in addition to
uh these so here's the file path i need
to make it
into a list you know item
this item so i press the key
let me show you the pink window so uh
so i press the key you see i
here file path press the key that
command is
html aligns to this okay then delete
this url we don't need
so and also let me magnify also modify
this we don't want the
word elise there this
part came from the title of the file so
but in the index page we don't want it
it is there because otherwise every
every
item will say it is believes it is you
know so it's annoying
so anyway so we want to change text like
that
into into a text
ad here with this additional line okay
to all files so two to you know
potentially thousands of files
uh actually it's probably more likely uh
700 files so this is a directory
so so what do you do okay so what do you
let me show you
what i do okay copy this i call
uh i call let me show you okay
uh you know usually i can
you know um
okay let me just do it okay so i i call
this command which is
find replace text and paste
the text i want to find okay
enter then i need to paste the replace
string
so how do i what's the replace string
basically this part okay
copy it okay paste
okay this is the replacement text okay
enter
now in which directory okay
emacs or emax yes now
uh what file path regular expression
uh it should be dot html okay
write changes to file yes fixed case
in search yes fixed case in replacement
yes make backup yes
okay okay so
you can see these are the changes
so this command is one of the package
uh find okay it's on mailpad and
uh the command is called something
replace text
and this is the input directory html
files right to file true backup true
search string uh is this
okay then here is a here are the results
you have you know this this this this
this
you you know you have literally a few
hundred
okay so close it it's done
and as for this file we don't need
anymore close it
do you want to save no okay now shrink
show in browser there you have it
you see add period to line ends
and you see shows there so you can
click on that and you can click on that
you can go around
let's shrink click
click click click click good
okay shrink you know
so it's done okay that's it that's it
for that
and maybe that's it for today let's see
how long have i been talking 44 minutes
40 minutes
and i'm gonna answer some questions okay
what are your thoughts on what's okay
orlan elixir
opinions okay uh you know like i said
before i
i you know i did a thousand videos on
which programming to learn
what is their characteristics
you know and let me show you again
you can find those
in this uh this url okay
complain perving so here's two
of my videos talking about programming
languages
each one is one hour long and
it's more than that you know and here's
another
video one hour long talking about
syntax you know syntax
issues related to programming languages
and if you click on that semantic noodle
here is another
video i've done the sound talk show and
this one is about
programming languages and their culture
okay
pearl python ruby uh so
as to what about rust what about erlang
what about elixir
okay i talked about that those a million
times
but in particular i don't know online
and elite elixir that much
okay but i talked about kind of
uh relevant topics you know okay
okay so that's about emac
yeah that's i think that's you know
that's
uh that's it for these okay let's let's
wrap up okay so
let's double check one more time so i we
created this file today with this
command and all i have to do now is to
upload it to my
server okay
daniel langlois haven't seen you for a
long time
okay so i actually i think that's it for
today let me drink
my drink this is a fresh fruit
juice plus energy drink
and let me turn on let me turn on this
so you can see me
my glorious face
take a break
doing a talk show is not easy
well you know after a while it becomes
rather easy but it's kind of tedious
because if i were
to do this myself it will be done in you
know
five minutes ten minutes to create this
page
uh but if you do a video or talk show
you need to explain right
because you just otherwise you you
you'll see
you know your co-workers they just blah
blah blah typing on the keyboard and
it's
that but you don't get to know what's
going on
so you have to uh kind of explain
for each step so if you uh if you like
my things you know
go buy my tutorial
you know uh my emac list tutorials okay
so emacs and emac list
uh thank you for paypal and patreon me
okay what what what is it now what uh
what are we so i'm gonna read
some anything else anything else guys
so i'm not so alpha beta has a question
how does uh language
compare is that is are you
asking that question in earnest or are
you like trolling me
because i talked about that quite a few
times
in the past two weeks mathematica is the
greatest
language of them all
uh in fact you know maybe that you know
we can
i can do like you know i wanted to you
know i can i can start to do some
mathematica okay let me show you
okay uh wait no i'm not being
wu from language okay because i
want you know i'm in armored you know i
love mathematica i've been coding it for
15 years
from 1993 to
about 2005 but i stopped since 2005.
for reasons okay because i need to
for reasons okay because so and uh
so i'm back on mathematica so one of the
things
i already did you know if you go to my
youtube i
okay so let me show you okay you go to
my xrd
programming okay so open hacker hacker
code go to xrd dot info
okay kassadi.info then you go to uh
programming or you or you just go down
you see this mathematica
so here is my collection of my articles
and related things about
mathematica the language beginning about
last month
i started to do videos and tutorials and
demo
and philosophical discussion about
mathematica the language so so far i
have about
five i think five videos so this is the
first one
this one is you should watch it okay
uh star talk show 2021
february 6th this is my first one
okay characteristics of haskell python
lisp mathematica and stefan
wufran so this is one hour video and i
tell you
this video is not technical so you won't
see any code but
however i tell you the nature the
characteristics of
many different languages for example
what what's
you know how does python different from
lisp philosophically
how does haskell you know how does
haskar approach
has gauss model of computation things
like that you know so
this video then then this one is my
first demo of woofing
uh you know mathematic mathematica the
language you can
this one so how do you get it to okay so
and after that i have i've i've done
three more videos
like yesterday also
so like sometimes i don't know you guys
are trolling me
you know what because i'm gonna tell you
things you know okay so back to the
question you know
oh by the way i want to mention this so
you know the closure the inventor of
closure
okay by the way by the way i have a
tutorial on closure okay
so you click on that you know you see
programming language tutorials index
you know these are uh tutorials
tutorials i've written for different
programming languages and i can tell you
that uh which one i'm very good at
master
of a master of
i would say i'm not okay
let's say expert okay let's not say
master i m i master
you know in some of them as well but a
massive of
uh imaglist wufang language and pearl
okay
these three and also html and and css
but you may not consider them as
a programming language i mean they are
technically but
anyway
so let me just say i'm an expert of
fairly okay
okay let me actually let me try the
precise version okay i'm a master
i was a master the world's top
master of wolf and language and pearl
what mean what do you mean by top i
would say
within one the the words top 1000
yeah 1000 okay
expert i was of wufang language
and pearl back in year around year 2000
okay
now i'm also an expert of emac this but
i would not put myself
you know within you know within what 100
you know 1000
top because well actually maybe that too
because there's not many emac list
coders
but i would say compared to other emac
this coders i'm not
that that good okay i mean i mean there
are a lot
emac based coders who are who are
um you know who really knows language
inside out
okay i wouldn't i wouldn't claim you
know
you know you know when you talk about
who is expert you know how how much you
know it's kind of like a
sensitive topic you know and how do you
compare you know
but you know but it's it's uh
you know it's uh it's it's not incorrect
to say i've coded
you know i've coded uh emac this for 15
years
since 2005. okay wufang language for 15
pearl for pearl is actually for five
years but that was in
industry you know coding every day with
pressure and you have to
code you you know so again let me talk
about let me tell you this
so coding if you are just you know
suppose you are haskell
you are fanatic has got phonetic i know
a lot of people you know
you guys many of you guys haskell
phonetics or
racket phonetics but if you haven't
worked in an industry
where you need to code that language
every day for for let's say two years
and lots of pressure and it's not like
you just sit here and choose what you
want to code no it's not like
it's like there are thousand things you
need to get done
and you know from 1000 libraries you
never
touched you don't know how it works but
you just have to get it done okay
you forget about you know learning it
slowly and
to know exactly what they forget about
that there's deadlines that's a
that's how coding industries like so you
so so your the result your code
your final code you you you know you
give it to your boss
usually it's not good but however you
have to do lots of coding
and get lots of things done and often
times half
in fact most of the time at least half
of the time you don't even know what you
are doing
you just all you know is that just do
you know put this code
it works it works and send it to the
the qa team let them know you let them
you know send it to the
creating that then let them uh you know
kick it back to you
you know but you have done your job
money changing
you know ten thousand dollars a year a
month
lots of money so that kind of coding in
industry is is is a bit uh different
from
like what i am now you know i haven't
been coding industry really for
uh for for for 20 years almost
yeah that's kind of you know i've done
some contract okay but anyway
for 15 you know 15 years but i've done
some contract in between
so i'm kind of mixed case so so anyway
my point here is that coding
you know a lot of people you see online
like you don't know who they are they
they they talk about haskell or lisp
or racket you know or elixir
especially like one of the fancy
languages elixir
or you know um uh
what the erlang you know it seems oh my
god they know
so much but it's not necessarily so okay
it's very different when you just study
your language
um and you know and master it
uh you know it's it also it's not
necessarily that one is better than the
other
you know for someone who has for example
industrial coding
experience let's say with python
compared to another person who who
is a computer scientist who who's
you know who is a computer scientist or
mathematic mathematician background
who also coded path python for two years
for five years let's say so one is a
computer science
scientist working in academia research
you know coding python for ai or
whatever
the other guy is you know joined a
startup
coding for python you know in a startup
both of them have five years
five years of experience of coding
python
their you know their understanding of
the language and they're
you know it would be very different okay
the academic guy
we all know depends also depends on the
person depends on what he's doing okay
so
anyway this the the academic guy tends
to know
many details you know technical details
or technicalities about python language
how it works
what's what's the meaning of an object
you know in a very precise manner
on the other hand the industrial coders
they
he may not know that you know that much
technical detail but
but he will be but but the industrial
guy is more likely to be able to
get a job done whatever new project
he'll be able to do
do it in you know in a day well the
academic guy will
it we will be uh much slower so anyway
i'm talking about some of the
differences so
anyway i have a good you know lots of
expertise
in wufang language in perl in
um svg html css i i grew up with them
you know i watched their birth
uh in linux i've been using unix since
uh
uh 20 22 years ago emac this
uh and python i'm okay with python and
golan
i'm also okay so
anyways let me tell you what i do not
know that well okay closure i don't
know that well i did i coded closure for
half a year
uh java i do not know that well i don't
like java
and i code it for half a year you know
more or less
php i i also code it for half a year
or a year you know uh like that was 15
years ago
and but however php i've read their
entirety of documentation
so so so did i uh foreclosure
entirety of the closures documentation
because i
reading documentation word by word
from the first page to the last of all
official
uh entire official existing
documentation is my thing
that's one that is one of my obsessions
you know so i've read you know all this
i've read the entire documentation some
of them 1000 pages
of mathematica closure
php uh
pearl multiple times many many in many
cases modded
multiple times and also several uh five
books
you know i have a book if you search for
saudi pearl sub you know
anyway i'm not going to go into
it's okay okay where am i going i forgot
and also javascript let me mention
javascript i started
i studied in depth so of all my
tutorials if you can pick one
that is the most in-depth you know
technicality of the language take
the of the languages technicality of the
languages
according to its official documentation
despite
you know despite my ex my different
experiences
or expertise javascript is actually the
one
okay of my all my tutorials my
javascript tutorial is actually the most
the most in-depth and technically
correct
uh and and so detailed and and is also
the most
you know i have like few hundred pages
the the most
voluminous then than my other
tutorials okay so
so that's how that's my description of
kind of my programming language
experiences
which language i know better in what
aspect
and their documentation which one i read
most you know for example i haven't read
python's documentation yeah i i
i wouldn't say i read them all you know
like word by word
you know usually i that's what i i
that's what i do but i don't like python
a golan is fantastic okay goal line is
very simple very
easy to learn fast and the documentation
is superb
okay i'm going to do another video about
documentation some other day because
uh because i have a entire collection
of essays about documentation in
programming languages and programming
industry
and you can find it by go to saudi
programming blog
and tweet this one okay jargons of
software industry
when programmers use math jargons such
as
git directed a cyclic graph
haska monad http
idiom potency or lisp
homie iconicity they don't know which
side is mouth which
side is ass okay that is my description
of
the documentation of the software
industry
uh so i have like uh you know i over the
past 20 years i've quite i've
written uh tens of articles about
different aspects you know i give you
examples aspect about about them
uh okay so let's see what what else uh
let's see
so i rambled so you know today's was
supposed to be just
emac this then due to thank you guys for
the questions
that got you know got me started to talk
about
programming languages which you know
which
is my obsession which is my uh
love you know even though if you ask me
you know is study of programming
language design is that what i really
want to do in my life
no what i really want to do is
mathematics
uh you know that's that's another
subject i truly
love okay i i talked about this uh
in the past few weeks you know many of
these things
many times mathematics
because why so why do i prefer math
over programming language design
so let me let me tell you okay so
because mathematics
you know it's deep it's far deeper than
programming languages now when we talk
about usually you know we
you you people you know industrial
programmers those who work at google
facebook microsoft or whoever
on twitter you know you see them every
day they talk they debate about
languages these people are
you know these people what they are
talking about on hacker news you know
hacker news
reddit you know you see them often right
so what are they talking about they are
usually this this has like almost zero
nothing to do with computer science so
first of all make a distinction
the vast majority the you know the what
programmers
the industrial programmers what they
talk about every day online
their content the subject matter usually
like has nothing to do with computer
science okay computer science as a
academic subject
first of all know that okay then so
when you when most people talk about
programming languages
design you know what do you think of
elixir what do you think of rust
what do i think you know
regardless what i think or what do you
think the subject matter of what you
think about some certain language has
nothing you know you have zero to do
with computer science
you know and so you know in other words
it isn't you know it's like it's not
you know it's just chat it's like you
know which which bikini is beautiful
like girls you know they talk about
bikini or bags or shoes
it's just dramatic it's it's like not
it's
crap it's a chit chat okay but that's
what programmers love you know that's
that's you guys you you
i i love it too you heard so it has
nothing to do with computer science
whatsoever okay first
first of all now secondly
between computer science i mean okay
computer science or maybe some
programming uh
you know what programmers talk about
between that and mathematics
you know mathematics is far deeper far
deeper and
uh far deeper and uh um
and this is absolute okay there's uh
there's one correct answer
due to this definition you know so
there's if you define something this way
there's one
correct answer there's no other okay
there's no in between
you know it's possible there's in
between but that
in that case that in between is well
defined they also define okay
for example um in logic there's fuzzy
logic okay
you know you don't you don't say oh you
know like
like pretend you know if you didn't have
my programmer talking about math
you know some some some other
programmers say logic and i say i
i i i counter you you are you
know there's no such i
i mean there's also a first logic but
but you have to understand it's like
even the name says fuzzy logic but
in math as part of math that's not fuzzy
at all that's
well defined versus you know it's
mathematical
it's still math so in math in general so
it's like
not in general i mean absolutely if it's
not
you know this if there's no one correct
answer that's not math
basically because math there are so many
ways to define math what is math i mean
that you know there's
tons of books written about what is
mathematics but basically
one you know one way to put it is that
when it's
when it's very precise and well
understood that's math okay
anyway so math is very deep in fact you
can consider the entire
uh computer science as a just one branch
of math okay
and math as you know you know as in
jokes physicist
chemistry they all admire adore
mathematics because
math is like almost one level above them
they all need math so it's like math is
god
only so on the other hand when you talk
when
programmers talk about things you know
there are things
it's like you know functional
programming versus
object oriented programming you know
that's one of the hard topic right
and also um uh you know the which
programming language is better
you know uh you know this is like this
it's not well defined
it's it's not well defined you know you
or what which methodology is better for
example
you know you have the voodoo
okay i started to ramble non-stop okay
i'm gonna
yeah i'm starting to ramble non-stop i'm
gonna close down in one minute actually
uh okay david conan mentioned into it
into mystic math
i forgot what's the context but
intrinsic math is very
great mathematics okay and also very
precise
in fact it requires it you know
that get us into homotropy type theory
and uh you know and type systems like
the haskell people talk about all the
time
that's fantastic and you know into an
intuitive math that's also the
fun you know that has to do with
the foundation of mathematics okay
anyway so so
i started to ramble so we're gonna shut
down okay so
so back to you know why do i like math
much more than
the programming kind of talk because
when you come to programming
then you have lots of crap you know then
you have like uh
software engineering you know they tell
you about software engineering like
agile
or extreme programming you know the
programmers
industrial programmers talk about them
all the time like oh would you you know
you uh
oh you should do extreme programming or
you should do programming or you should
do
more uh testing you know you know
you unit testing you know crap or you
should talk about you know
oh you should do patterns oh this is a
pattern this is a factory pattern this
antipattern pattern there
s that's what you know that's what
programmers
oh when then then it comes to the unix
philosophy
you know the linux and unix idiots they
talk about unix philosophy everything
should be small
small is beautiful or dry principle you
know do it once you know
crap crap they don't know they don't
even know what they are talking about
they don't even know they you know what
they are you know the context
they are talking about they like this
industrial programmers have no idea
so that is the character's
characteristics
of what programmers you know these
industrial programmers
are talking about you see them every day
on reddit
on hacker news emacs versus vim you know
which language versus
c versus c plus first which is better
they don't know nothing they don't even
know they
they don't know okay that's that's uh so
therefore so that's you know but i'm
also interested because it you know it's
kind of
it's just you know it's
it's incorrect to say it's wrong okay
it's not wrong it's not like
it's stupid okay it's nothing like that
like for example some people like to
dance
some you know people like to do shopping
or or guys like you know we we like
keyboards and mouse we talk about them
all the time
you know it's not like you have to be
correct or you know
it's fun okay but however that's the
characteristics of what programmers talk
about
uh and if you compare to math
to the mathematics it's it's like entire
entirely different thing math is is very
deep
and you know it has
you know it has um
some kind of significance okay while the
programmers
uh typical programmers chat there's
little very little significance
unless you really start to talk about
the actual
uh computer science you know but most
programmers
they don't talk about computer science
computer science you know like they
just use the jargons they don't even
understand
what the jargon means like directed
graph you know the git people then
you know git tutorials sometimes we'll
claim oh good is just a directed graph
you should learn math these people don't
know nothing about math directly graph
my ass you know not no mathematician
will ever say that you know this like
this is you know this like a kid who
learned about car
then the kid will say oh this is my
dad's transportation system
like what what the you just say
this is your dad's car
oh this is your mom's car but the kid
just learned the idea oh
transportation system then he's gonna
tell his friend look
my dad has this transportation system
this is the same way when programmers
you know use math jargons like they
they'll say you know they'll tell you uh
you know
git is a directed graph or or
or at least you know this syntax is i i
can homonyosity
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching okay bye my tutorials
uh bye guys
[Music]
oh alpha beta so so
you know i've been doing videos for the
past you know starting in 2009
and i'm getting better at it so um
if you like you know you might watch my
recent
videos like the videos in the past one
or two months
you know check to start to check them
out because i because
uh programming language is the main
thing almost the main thing i talk about
mostly
emacs emac these programming languages
uh javascript this a lot of lisp
and keyboards you know keyboard and uh
mouse
okay so that's it for today let's see
thank you guys for watching
hmm
okay bye guys copy that
okay bye guys