good morning everyone
dear or beloved my compatriots my
supporters and sponsors today's 2019
December 20th Friday 1 o'clock p.m. San
Francisco time and welcome oh this is
our talk show and good morning Emily
Nabby the magpie and Pablo Pablo from
Spain Spain and United Kingdom and
Nicaragua and California so we don't
have a topic today what we gonna do well
I do have a I'm gonna let's begin shall
we begin with Emacs these because I have
something I want to command I knew I
want to modify and you guys chat ok type
in the chat keep flood the chat spam the
chat with your opinions and commentaries
ok how are you how have you been doing
Emily and Erika good morning
am i good morning I am I is from Emma is
from oh my god I'm eyes from from where
from from having a chat he has indeed a
mais from from Egypt am I correct
oh did I got it wrong so Emily is still
y-yeah a little bit young a little bit
she has to get needles needles in her
skin needles you know modern medicine
needle poked into your skin and draw
blood that is what it is so ok so
actually I'm getting hot
flash so am I am I is from Tunisia
North Africa oh okay North Africa
Tunisia I don't even know where that is
but North Africa okay so so I think
we're gonna do some eMac B's okay so you
guys comments and we're gonna do stuff I
had to wake up early for blood tests
that's right so okay so we're gonna do
it okay just in a minute give me a
minute okay I need to prepare and this
video is a problem this OBS software by
the way it's Linux compatible you have
this OBS software so if you are planning
to do a stream you see how easy it is
I'm doing my stream how smooth it is
then you think you might do a stream the
OBS software might be the one you want
to try which is what I'm using right now
okay so it's pretty easy okay so let's
let's begin with eMac beasts okay so
start up show and go to today's topic
you go there and open and we so eMac
this modify excite-ation male convert
P&G to JPEG so let me show you what that
is so we go to SAR keyboard blocks okay
so you see these wonderful colors what
is this oh and what what is is oh those
are onions by the way so there's they
are quite a few interesting things here
okay so this is you know I'm getting
something from Amazon that people bought
this is mono modular patch cables now is
this cable used for the keyboard Google
Docs is it is it
Nabby is this
those ago docks use you know you go
ducks keyboard you have two parts and
you need a cable that connects them and
is this the cable so can you tell me
Nabby or any one of you and today I
discovered this thing okay this thing is
called heat press you know this heat
press this is this is just I on you know
steam iron but sort of modern technology
so you see with steam iron you have
issues I suppose because you have you
need to put in put water into it then it
steams you it becomes hard and it burn a
steam and the temperature distribution
is not even but apparently according to
this marketing probe of these device so
you have this device where you have you
guys seen this have you guys seen this
so you have this device where you you
see they show the typical iron the
temperature is uneven
whereas this thing it's even so I
suppose it's a modern technology or
something something I never have have
not seen on steam iron for like 20 years
what what's on your Akira BD bookshelf
I'm not sure that is IKEA PD but it's
just not much you know like I got 20
books or something yeah I showed a few
times I can show you my books but no I'm
kind of lazy too it's not you know
because you guys have not seen it but
you see this bookshelf every day so you
are curious but I have some books maths
books mostly okay like 20 20 maths books
in fact
let me show you math books okay so go to
go to the math books reach information
on sabe infamy information website so
you see free math textbooks I talked
about this before a few times okay so
you have let me show you my books okay
some books and most of these books I had
them for 20 years also so some of the
math books that's just that's a picture
of my math books okay so I'm not sure
should I talk about math you know I
could talk about this for one hour so so
anyway you have a lot of math history
history of mathematics how it is
developed how it evolved when you know
how it becomes so many branches what
what are they what they do what they
study you know math is interesting in a
sense is is that it's abstract and
opaque for example if you have not
studied math you would never know what
it's about as opposed to physics or
cosmology or astrology I mean astronomy
astronomy for example everyone know what
it's about you look at the sky you see
the moon you see the sauce that's
astronomy astronomy you study what they
are where how far are they what are they
made up what you know why why it's there
that's astronomy physics physics for
instance you drop a ball it falls down
and physics study that then today you
have quantum physics you have atomic
physics your particle physics you study
you break down this ball you chop it
into pieces into billions of pieces you
discover the internal structures atoms
and protons and neutrons in particles
and then you have you have molecules
atoms then then quacks then quacks top
beauty submissive dominant you get you
got into BDSM that is the name of the
game okay
atomic quantum mechanics you know
physics so even if you have never
studied physics you kind of get some
idea you know you're okay
what is Adam Adam is the thing you break
it down you you have Tiny's things that
make up materials that's physics you can
explain to your children but however
when it comes to mathematics you know
nothing
okay you don't you don't know nothing
well you if you are you know if you are
programmer you you might know there's
calculus trigonometry about hacker is
about how you calculate areas and stuff
but that's elementary mathematics so you
know the question is you want to for
example the question the way to phrase
it is that what does mathematician study
I mean the Graduate math what you know
what are these for example let me show
you okay so you got history of math
books graph theory which is discrete
mathematics which is fringe fringe
mathematics considered by mathematicians
it's Fringe you programmers love it okay
but it's fringe that's not what
mathematicians do then you have you see
real projective thin geometric
constructions that is a deep topic man
okay you know geometric constructions
the real projective plane then conic
sections and connects and cubics those
are algebraic geometry okay and that's
elementary elementary geo geometry of
differential curves elementary geometry
of algebraic curves
okay math well I did talk about
mathematics like two videos actually so
if you are interested in math look back
okay so I give you a overview of what
are
branches of math and so on and then you
have regular polytopes okay then you
have plain algebraic curves and some of
these are Asian ode books for example
those books pounded like that those are
very old
those are like two hundred years old or
something night I mean 40 years or
something like that so this what is this
I cannot even read it synthetic
synthetic something geometry and this is
geometry of playing curves okay okay
anyway that's math books okay so Mike
the question is what do math curve
mathematicians study topology and
algebra abstract algebra and yeah but
you knows but if you have not looked
into you don't know what they mean what
you don't know you have no idea what
they mean so that's math that's which is
a bit different from physics and
chemistry and biology and you know those
things you can have some idea what are
they talking about biology biology is
about for example that your body your
cells so a man says so actually I'm kind
of sorry to ramble on these without go
so maybe I should go back to Emacs Lisp
because I was trying to I was going to
so this you have more math books
abstract analysis okay this one abstract
analysis now that's a beginning lesson
of analysis so Allen says kurwa kurwa
point creo yes those are great
mathematicians so let's check the
comments Tanzania is a country south of
France Italy north of Madi Chad okay
what's on your bookshelf yeah
those are these books and some others in
pong okay
I have pawned DVDs like 10 of them from
like 20 years ago and math okay Aven say
smith Emily say Emily says I put some
washing in the washing machine and come
back 250 yes you know that that is what
quantum mechanics they named their stuff
of let's quacks okay let's let's see the
origin of BDSM quacks you know the in
physics and math as well physics and
mathematics both of them they name you
know you have to come up with a name to
name of the things so [ __ ] [ __ ]
Wikipedia do not ever donate to
Wikipedia okay I did a video few days
ago about that don't donate to Wikipedia
let it die
then we will have richer and more
information overnight okay because right
now you donate to Wikipedia the money
just go to the gym Jimbo where's pocket
he's a man you know millionaire you just
go to his pocket if each time he does a
talk he get six six figures so that's
like ten thousand or something a hundred
thousand each time he give a talk like
one hour talk
what is this comes and he by the way
this is just my opinion okay in case
he's you me this is my opinion only so
and and all the people we who wrote
Wikipedia we get nothing Wikipedia is
basically a massive infringement of
copyright
you know copyright is the question is
kind of a questionable concept you know
because information most for example I
read my tutorials I spent years so the
study JavaScript and read it out then
someone else on web they can just once
they see the answer you know JavaScript
Intel
the esoteric details how ray or our
checkbooks you know they can't mostly
read it they can once I have it written
as people read it they can just copy it
and rephrase it that's that that is
Wikipedia okay
they just rephrase everything and and
technically they are not violating
copyright because copyright you know
because information cannot be
copyrighted by this you know nerds this
open source phonetics
this you know they say oh the
information cannot be copyrighted you
can copy I not save the idiotic idea so
this hackers I despise them UNIX
philosophy you know that so you know but
but basically basically what they do is
like when something is favorable to them
to their opinion to their livelihood
whatever they say one thing and if it's
not they say something else and then
there's pirate pirating massive pirating
website you know videos of movies then
there's also pirating of journals books
then the argument becomes then it gets
more complex because some of these
corporations they are really evil you
know but basically each person you just
do whatever that's favorable to you so
so what I'm so so so these open source
you know phonetics they think they think
that they themselves are the good guys
they think of themselves are the
fighters of freedom or something no they
are just for themselves okay so anyway
so so we that's about so we were talking
about copying stuff you know information
you know so technically they are not
violating copyright but the way you know
they just copy things copy so anyway we
and then you get a bunch of people who
hock Wikipedia or they they become the
other admins of Wikipedia nameless okay
irresponsible nameless [ __ ] they did
they just they they have nothing to do
every day they just live you know every
time there's a change they pick up you
know they like these things happen on
Stack Overflow as well I'm basically
unrated many of these site it's a
phenomenon
modern the the the modern the
corporatism of creating websites such as
Facebook and Twitter you know you create
this bunch of people everyone is
anonymous they never want to disclose
their names in their excuses oh you know
they excuse his privacy privacy [ __ ] so
this so anyway you create these people
like on Reddit okay
you create all these anonymous people
who just go there
talk random or something then the next
day they did a account they do whatever
they want responsibility and meanwhile
the idea do you not meanwhile they say
oh oh because the privacy okay because
you know you must respect privacy and on
the other hand then they say oh because
what anyway that's our thing is about
the information so in anyway so so so we
were talking we were looking at the
Cork's okay so quacks which is
elementary particles so let's look at
composition so proton let's look at
proton they have a naming okay the
naming of the quotes for town let's see
I don't want to go to proton so by the
way I don't know physics and you don't
know physics likely okay you know yeah
and uh you know be to know something is
to really know it not just you think you
know
okay so physics so you have these quacks
so you can see how they hunt you have up
down charm
this one is charm and this one is top
this one is partum this is my strange
you know so and in in the BDSM community
you have top and bottom top means
dominant the dominatrix
okay the dominant guys
the who are into citizen and bottom is
the submissive slave okay he who are
into citizen you know that like the
Eurythmics song what is the zone anyone
so guys name the song you rhythmic song
I crossed the seven seas and watched all
the people
someone wants somebody wants to abuse
you someone somebody wants to be abused
and someone someone wants to use you
someone wants to be used that is a
Lampoon or characteristics of it's
actually real life that is a situation
someone wants you know son you have
people who wants to lead you want you
have people who wants to follow you have
also people so that's people and that
can be likened to or analogous to games
you know you guys who play Nabi you guys
play who play fantasy games fantasy
games or massive online multi-player
massive multiplayer online fantasy Oh
online adventure games so in the sweet
sweet dreams thank you Emily and Nabi
sweet sweet dreams are made of these so
in these fantastic games you have all
sort of creatures and races okay you
have you have warriors which you know
warriors with the giant hammer or or
some beautiful elf with their arrows you
know beautiful guys then you have the
trough which is well some people are
like that you know they are short and
stodgy and the that that that the trough
race they identify with because that's
them then you have you know magicians
then you have social sorcerers then you
have beautiful goddesses you know women
often you know which would like that
yeah so that you you pick someone you
identify with and in dragons and and and
and so on so anyway so the stats the
standard model of elementary
particle so you have top in bottom you
have charm
this one is charm Oh God so attractive
charm and strange okay this this one
strange man strange and this one is
uppity up uppity down up up and down he
he's up and you are down down down in
dark and then you have boss and
embossing and you have then then then
then then then then then you have got
particles the white people's fascinate
obsession God God particles you bring
get the you you are playing God skin
you're gonna [ __ ] up and we're gonna
extinction human animals go extinct God
God God particles Scotty's got that okay
so that's about quantum mechanics that
which I don't know much Sucker Punch
themed song what do you sucker punch
thing song oh the sucker punch is a
movie and it bombed I think I mean it's
it didn't sell so well or something
sucker punch I have not seen it
chareth parlayed mister yamen so what
are we doing today so I guess today's
just random too many abstractions to
watch and interact but I'm watching it
start to finish once I get time what
so Ammon says how come you did some math
in the past did you study in a math
degree or just general interest well I
talked about my history a little bit
before well basically I am wonderful
that is my nature
that is my personality I do not I tend
not to finish ok nice guys always don't
finish ok nice guy so it's just
beginning things and so I want about I I
don't have a degree
I studied two years in Community College
well my beginning interesting math is
because recreational in mathematics
actually yes so yesterday or the day
before we did a video on mathematics on
you know part of it is mathematics on
combinatorial combinatorics which is
another recreational mathematics or
considered fringe by the mainstream
mathematicians combinatoric s-- okay and
yesterday on a video we showed several
combinatorial unsolved combinatorial
problems and many elementary problems in
combinatorics is about counting that for
example how many ways to have something
how many ways which is called
enumeration okay that's elementary
combinatorics problems for example what
is this a example of change meaning with
six pairs one of the earliest
non-trivial results in graph theory okay
I don't know what that is changed
meaning change meaning is [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ]
Vidia change meaning is the art of
reading a set of tuned bells in a
lightly in a tightly controlled manner
to produce precise variations in their
successive striking sequences known as
changes okay I guess in the old in the
old times like 200 years ago we have
giant church and cathedrals then you
have these giant bells and you have to
like choose which sequence to strike
them something like that change meaning
okay so these are examples of
combinatorial stuff combinatorics can
you subscribe can you subscribe to what
how many years have I studied in
university I studied two years in
community college okay
which is equivalent to the first two
years of university but I never
graduated or got any degree everything I
learned I learned on my own so watch
watch yesterday's video okay so because
we talked about that
so what is the next topic should we go
back to Emacs because I was planning to
you know so we are doing random random
talk in Hamiltonian cycles very
interesting hamiltonians hammered hammer
Hamiltonian cycles okay
and he Hamiltonian cycles Hamiltonian is
named after the guy Hamato hammered
what's his name Hamilton a Scottish guy
and he's most famous for
quaternions he created quaternions by
the way quaternions is another thing
that hands in the mouth of programmers
who do not know nothing about
mathematics but however when it comes to
math they know quaternions you know they
hang it around their mouth all day every
day quaternions anyway so you know so
quadrant quaternions is invented by this
Scottish guy William Rowan Hamilton who
okay he looks like that doesn't look
very attractive Sir William Rowan
Hamilton and the law of math one of the
law of math is that one day he was
walking on the bridge in somewhere in
Scotland or what what bridge okay guys
what bridge we need to get interaction
going what bridge you guys know so one
day he's walking on this bridge and the
idea come to him that oh we can just do
this this this and we got quaternions
and supposedly he carved that on the
bridge but however nobody can find it so
it's a it's a law it's not verified but
later on because this means you become
so popular the the UK government or
whatever the city government government
or whatever they carved a plaque onto
the bridge that says you know that says
Sir William Hamilton thought of
quaternions while why are walking on
this bridge so let's search for so you
no you guys no PR idge okay so we want
to search for bridge let's see bridge
there it is
broom bridge quaternion plag oak
quaternion plague on the broom bridge
pray go back hug how you guys pronounce
it plaque which means a plate basically
a metal plate so this is room bridge
where is it located is a bridge along
Broome Bridge Road which causes the Royo
kanno in cabra Dublin Ireland oh it's
not even in UK it's in Ireland okay in
Ireland I wish not Scott Scottish Irish
excuse me I don't know nothing so he
carved this thing on this bridge oh I
forgot I missed I missed the comments
damn I missed the comment so we got we
got a rat rates coming in so this broom
bridge okay so let's look at the flag
here as we hear us be walked by on the
10th of October 1843
Sir William Rowan Hamilton in a flash of
genius discovered discovered what the
something model or something immortal
something formula for quaternion muta
location okay then there is a formula
quaternion multiplication okay so what
do you guys know what is for quaternion
I can give you a account and the when I
give a account of mathematics you will
get the gist of it okay as opposed to
other sources
quaternion in order to understand
quaternion you have to understand
complex numbers the complex number
system okay so I have to explain that
do I see should we should we should I
should I give you the fundament the gist
why is quaternion important why you know
they put this flag why is this discovery
important in quotes okay it's not you
are it's important but it's not you know
one of the most important things in math
so okay so today we talk about math I
guess okay so since people are
responding is fractal always seems
fascinating to me yeah practice in
fractals when you do factors it's all
about complex numbers because that's the
that's the home of fractals well depends
on what do you mean by fractals now now
in programmers might and while I'm
talking about the general programmer so
excuse me for claiming the program was
the hacker types you know so in
programmers mind factor is one of the
most popular thing in programmers mind
when it comes to math because why well
because it's easy to understand you know
so basically when it comes to
mathematics you know the typical
programmers what they think about math
what they are thinking all the things
they are talking about is basically the
most trivial mathematics factor for
example factors or factors factors every
programmer is talking about factors
practice graph theory and combinatorics
you know and discrete mathematics and
maybe Katona's not not you know most
programmers don't really understand
quaternions but they but it's a jargon
they heard of it's for rotations you
know every every one to say side o is
when you know when you do computer
graphics you need quaternions okay so
why am i you know that's not be you know
to me
so what way am i talking about that way
flame you know programmers yeah because
the reason is because I don't I I like
knowledge okay I like I I don't like so
so here's a reason why I'd always keep
flaming the programmers you know call
them idiots or the UNIX philosophy you
know because because I like I don't want
fat okay I I like math and I like
knowledge I respect you I respect those
people who spent tremendous of time to
study something okay so I respect
running but on the other hand I do not
like fat fashion joggins you know that I
mean that this kind of buzzwords these
are these are not learning but they
pretend to be you know and and that's
what I despise I hate I despise them
truly greatly so so when it comes to you
know these math jargons mentioned by
programmers often for example
programmers will say oh get get what is
kit kit is a directed graph my ass okay
and promise will say you know they
buzzwords jargon they will say oh this
syntax you know that this programming
syntax is is I can't know like I can of
morphic okay it's it something I can't
no I can't I cannot watch guys what is
the word I can't know something okay I
have to I don't remember exactly but
that's crap okay because when
programmers mentioned these words to
them they are like oh they like it's
like oh by the way you know like oh this
okay like I can't know what what is the
word I can't know
okay I got a search my own website I
can't know okay so is this just search
for icon oh I can't know actually I can
remember if I think about it the so Oh
guys you guys pace it okay pace the word
I can't hook a snappy no not I cannot
cast my you know you yeah I know
no so least okay it's fundamental
problems of release
okay so the I got a bunch of like our
goes on these fundamental problems of
this and we want to go to oh let's see
okay it's fundamental problems of
beliefs so source transformation oh that
not a icon of God I got it wrong who me
or iconicity guys homie iconicity what
the idiocy
anyways my point is that you know when
programmers mission math joggins is
somehow you know once you have a jargon
somehow it's like validating you know
it's like validating you know it's like
it showcases that you know math but in
reality many you know so-called math
dragons used by programmers it's it's
nothing it's meaningless okay it's like
entirely ot real okay is unnecessary and
actually meaningless it's idiotic
when programmers use math jargons such
as saying that kit is a directed graph
it's it's idiocy okay and programmers
this per se
oh this language the syntax has the
properties of homie Akane City it's pure
complete idiocy
why did because once you have studied
math let's just say undergraduate you
studied analysis in algebra abstract
algebra you know it does you know did
doesn't
you are using jargons is like told you
you are like as three years old
and you know talking of you know jog
inspiring sharpens to say something if
you have studied math you know
undergraduate so and then so program us
you know so so yeah so I'm talking about
why am I so attacking framing
programmers all the time because I don't
I really love knowledge and study you
know respect knowledge you have to spend
time to learn you I want to reward those
people who really have spent so much
time into something then you know I I
want them to be popular famous for
whatever you know because they they have
given time to it they have done the work
but me but I don't want I don't like
this fad fashion crap like a Haskell
people they with their category fact you
know the Haskell people they are they
are driveling about monad category
everyday and dispersed about homeo akane
city everyday the fans you know these
are fans phonetic so quote there they
are the phenomenon of code so and and
then then the other programmers you know
the the the you know other community how
shall we say you know this you have lots
of jargons in programming buzzwords you
know like you know object oriented
oriented programming or patterns for I
mean patterns then you have the agile
which is from corporate world they have
so many jargons stand-up meetings and so
on and unit testing unit testing our God
is so I so I don't like them I despite
despise them I hate them so much I don't
want to I want to demolish okay I want
to destruct I want to destroy I want to
be be a destructive force against them
this first words jargons these people
who have not spent the time into
something but they want to talk you know
they want to pretend or they they know
stuff you know and also these come to
the 4chan type of people you're on earth
nerds on reddit on Hacker News you
through our jargons you printed pretend
you know so much oh oh oh I know this
because this should be that that I
should be that way so I I don't like
them so I that's why this despise him
you know I that's why I attack them all
the time
this UNIX philosophy UNIX philosophy
thing you know these hackers so-called
hackers you know it's it's you know in
some way in some way you could say I'm a
bit nutcase or extreme you know because
it doesn't warrant that much flaming
against them they are just they are just
a subculture you know hackers you know
programmers some programmers nerdy types
they have certain preferences and they
think they you know they they develop a
community they have something certain
jargons they like they yeah in something
in some sense is true but on the other
hand they are just coat they are they
did you see the thing the harmful thing
is about that is that yeah it's no big
deal but not really it does have
significant impact on industry on the
whole thing because they are when it
goes when it becomes the extreme it they
are crackpots they are creating force
force information they are spreading
force information such as let me give
you examples such as the UNIX you know
how UNIX is secure or you know you they
hate Microsoft right you guys so you
guys hate Microsoft how UNIX is secure
how Linux is the best operating system
and then then you have open source
you know phonetics that's a different
thing you know the then you have the
license phonetics G GPRO no GPL you know
this is a big controversy so it's
alright what so back to the technical
part of programming you know for me you
have lots of jargons like kiss keep it
simple stupid try you know try not to
repeat yourself you know they want
information in one place try you know
they have these jargons keep it simple
try
kiss you know keep it simple and UNIX
philosophy small is beautiful and and
then though so then you have Opie you
know then you have patterns ok factory
patterns okay in this case you need
factory pattern in that case you need
some some some other patterns you know
that they have lots of jargons then you
have the actual people saying you should
you should always have unit testing you
have usually you should have the you
know so this this kind of thing in my
opinion so you you know let me give you
example this kind of thing they they are
most of the time baseless okay they are
not they are not factual they are not
great you know solid information they
are like force force like lies okay so
so so what's wrong with lies well they
they damage society they create force
information what should be good becomes
bad what becomes bad becomes good bad
people get rewarded good people don't
get to be awarded that's what happens
okay so that is why I don't like this
anything that's like code like with
purse words jargons you know and this
kind of thing they do damage to society
so actually that turns out to be a big
grant
I just rambled to myself a monologue
silent monologue for like 20 what 20
minutes or 10 minutes and I did that
often I did that a lot in my stream but
I haven't done that for the past month I
think so I don't know where are we going
so mister Yemen hey good morning Alan so
mister yeah Yemen so you guys chatting
Arabic I don't understand are you
chatting or is it something questionable
okay I don't know because that happens
sometimes so anyway so let's look at the
comment
okay so what do you guys say some person
says a lot of programmers are just
people who memorized syntax and create
more bloated buggy software yeah that's
true
so in some person says I think you need
to ban mr. Yemen he is repeating already
sent messages okay mr. Yemen stopped
that okay so so actually
Nabby says quantum wudu I'm still
waiting for these magical computers
content it's coming it's real it's
coming
they have quantum computers you know
it's real and it's gonna be it's a big
thing it's really it's very significant
okay I think it's very significant
content the quantum computing and then
Google is kind of a leader you know as
at least in us a Google it's pretty
significant content computing so I don't
understand though big you know I don't
understand quantum computing they are
quite a lot tutorials you guys can go
read about quantum computing I don't
understand it
what's my thoughts on Earl and I think
it's great you know Allen is one of the
earliest functional programming language
I'm talking about I mean today you have
people you know young younger generation
they talk about all functional
programming oh you should or should not
you know Allen when I was you know you
know 20 years ago 1999 you know I'm
interested in functional programming
that is when Olin is around you know a
line is the function of programming
language and a practical one used by you
know Ericsson and successful I mean it's
a it's an actor it's a big one and it's
not by the way it's not open source back
then they released it you know to become
open source impetus you know when the
open source became popular but bad thing
it was not open source so it's one of
the early successful and practical
functional programming language as
opposed to has cow cream Miranda and
several others oh man this okay this
miso sauce is a successful one so a line
is one of the early one and then you
know so I'd learned I heard you know I
read fa Q's you know back then so it's
about
it has this unique kind of property or
context where it it you know it has
these you know we can capture adding a
slogan where you run it you you know
this system can die any times you know
you can have a bunch of them you know
thousands of them process is running a
hot hot swappable hot swappable that's a
jargon okay so a system that runs urlan
is hot swappable swappable you can just
you know the the processes are expected
to die random be it doesn't matter to it
the whole system you know you can just
randomly kill like you kill moss okay
you have a hammer then you have bunch of
moss coming up you just killed in the
system system keeps running no problem
so it's suitable it's running for the
phone network phone they're working
systems or something like that
I don't really understand the tech
details so that's that's what that's my
that's what I heard that's my impression
of all that and then that's so this is
back in 1991 time goes on exponential
growth sciences you know math every
small nation goes toot and so after 20
years today each of us becomes nothing
we don't know nothing because the
exponent was that's what it means and
then well and so well is now open source
and you know it's interesting you it had
it it didn't happen so that a line
becomes the you know very popular
dominant functional programming that
that didn't happen as you know as we
know you know so today you have Haskell
is kind of a niche then you have closure
this kind of niche you know this family
closure then you have lots of others you
know the you have you have then you have
new versions of Haskell you have you
know then JavaScript you know and then
you have okay mo you know this so each
one occupying a niche kind of and and I
happened I
just I never had never learned overland
myself you know but this one interesting
thing about Ellen that I want to there's
a one interesting thing about Ellen that
I want to understand is that by the way
what so what is the Yemen guy say what
does he say have any one of you
translated you know one thing
interesting about a line is that I want
to understand it from the the property
of Ellen where you can have you know so
many processes you don't care if it dies
something like that how do you expand
that from a I mean okay so Allah has
this property hot-swappable but I want
to find the context in sudden let's say
math okay well that math is probably not
the right word but I want to find the
context where this property fit in so we
can say okay so in this context we have
you know like you know if you have you
know you have okay Olin is hot swappable
but what are the other alternatives
that's what I'm saying
in other words what I'm saying is that I
want to understand what what does it
mean exactly about this property where
processes are can you expect to die I
mean can you can you capture it in some
sort of you know the greater context I
don't know if I'm commit come by
conveying what I mean well or not but
Emory do you understand what I mean like
I want to you know for example when we
say functional programming functional
programming Oh in a function of who I
mean style when we have a function
that has no side effects then we can say
that function that or the whole style
programming is functional for me and
what it what does it mean no side effect
well it just means a function the output
of a function always depends on the
input and so it's of is like a math
function now when it comes to math
function is very well defined you know
it's it's it's defined by logic very
precisely but it was okay so so you see
so you so functional programming it's
very well defined well I mean in
practice many languages cannot actually
have function that has no side effect
but anyway but but the basic basic idea
is very clear precise where you have a
programming language where most
subroutines they are functions they you
know input and output they depends on
solely on coding functions and get their
output to achieve what you want to do
the result that's function of
programming
okay the idea is pretty clear and
precise so as opposed to now here's the
important so what is the what is the
context well the context is that in most
languages in practice they are not
functions you know for example you call
them subroutines basically so you have a
you know a block of code that's a unit
by itself you code a subroutine it does
something so you can call this
subroutine somewhere else to help you
program much your programming you know
but they are not functions meaning that
you know like the word subroutine is
just a group of several a group of
different things into one code related
you know a unit then you know
programming language you can use you can
use this elsewhere that's subroutine
which is different from function
programming function in a foreign
language so that is a context so you see
a subroutine can you know can just be a
subroutine or it could be you you can
make it a function or alternatively you
could also
have class-based programming where a
class is okay we're getting complicated
but anyway your class is kind of like
it's a kind of like a mix of it's kind
of a like functional programming but
they don't have they have internal
states okay it's anyway so but what I'm
saying is that you have these contexts
basically what we are talking about is
that you have a unit of block of code a
unit where it has certain different kind
of properties when it has certain
certain properties you say it's a
function when sudden sudden something
you say it's a class or object when
something something else you say it's a
most general general you know subroutine
so that is the context of the functional
programming came from you know we could
say so that is the context so back to LA
back to LA so I'm saying you know so
Allah has this property of hot-swappable
or processes processes can be cured but
you see but but I don't so I don't
understand you know because well because
I haven't really studied Orland but also
but my question is I want to know so
what what is the the context or the
overall context you can put this into
you know a land fit fit it so do I do I
make sense okay so I think I remember
too much and maybe we shut down 55
minutes we rambled all over and got to
know where it's my rent rent about
programmers we began with emag base then
we started to show talk about math books
because somebody's asking me about my
bookshelf then we remembered about some
mathematics then I began a rant about we
haven't talked about this through three
maths books we but I did a video you
know a math okay so watch go watch my
video so I did a few focus on math
math alone a couple of them for one hour
and more so we we talked about maths in
math books about a bit then we talked
about the math in programmers mind you
know what program was thinking this by
the way this is some of these book are
great books okay I haven't even start to
talk about it this standard analysis and
the this tiding and you know anyway I
did again I talked about Tydings in
patterns for one hour twice in the past
video so you can watch go watch him
another book on graph theory and shape
of space that's about the topology of
space then the real projective plane
anyway so many interesting things so may
I talked about math then I talked about
the the force ideas programmers have
about math or the ignorant programmers
they're they're idolization of
mathematics they are abuse of math
joggins to promote whatever you know
form or their whatever then I talked you
know that that became a rant then I
talked about Hamilton this law of
mathematics about this mathematician
about quaternion
so I talk about all these things without
getting into anything substantial no
substance okay it's this is a talk show
why you are watching a talk show of no
substance if you want substance you go
to youtube there they are tutorials
about quaternions they are respected
people who have thousands million of
followers you know who talked about
quaternions who talk about neural
networks they teach you actually they
try to be brief and they talk about
quantum mechanics and content computing
there are videos you can go watch they
talk about you know introduction and but
here you are talking we are talking
random random of no substance so let me
read the comments and I think that will
be it today and join this course
okay discord the wonderful discord of
you people you people made it let's see
what else here so C + C sharp so wait
let me get down to the beginning we
begin from the beginning okay so let me
read the comments and now be it for
today okay so so guys stop posting baby
ray Biggs okay so because I don't
understand we don't understand so we
don't know if you are talking about [ __ ]
okay so stop posting or a big stuff
because also it's actually kind of
sensitive sensitive thing right now it's
because it's a sensitive thing you know
because it gets to yeah it's sensitive
thing content computers okay so fractals
okay so then what's my thought about all
that yeah so and what are your thoughts
about
erland okay mr. Yeaman and then some
person says i think you need to ban
yemen okay that's i think so far so good
what's up nabi okay so okay he seems no
more now okay mister yemen so mister
yemen join discord okay you can find the
link in my youtube on my website saudi
down info join this code and say hello
to people and i think we
I at least would love to learn arrey vyx
the basics at least you know the Arabic
writing system and we don't know what
language it is is it rabbits or Persian
so I thinks it's fundamental for me on a
multiplication ok a plus B o4
fundamental formula that that is the ok
yeah so that that Hamiltonian the law of
mathematics this Hamiltonian guy who is
a Irish man Irish mathematician he went
onto this bridge and he carved he
discovered quaternion multiplication how
it works on this bridge so I should you
know I should explain quaternion but you
know I but I you know I don't know the
technical depth in depth but I can give
you I can explain what it is I mean let
me try to do it in one minute ok so
first of all you have to understand
complex numbers I'm gonna now I'm not
going to go in depth but just hand wave
a little bit ok first of all you must
understand complex numbers which is
basically a pair of numbers that
represent a plane ok
now you might have actually I did a
video on complex numbers yeah you can
watch ok
but anyway complex numbers is a pair of
numbers well you might think you know
complex numbers as an imaginary number
whose square root is negative 1 yeah
that's correct but that's not the way to
understand it ok so the way to
understand complex numbers is geometry
complex numbers is a system a number
system where a number is actually a pair
of numbers you know just a pair a B just
like just like when you plot you know XY
in a plane so you think of it it's a
it's a plane ok it's a geometry so
complex numbers is just a point in the
plane it's a pair of numbers one the
first part is the x-axis the second part
is the y-axis
that is a complex number that's not not
not that's not all okay so so we have a
pointer pain but so it's a number with
two you know it's a number with two
numbers you know it's a pair of numbers
so so what this number mean you know a
number with two components so then you
defy+ addition with this number you know
a pair complex number you define
addition by just adding the components X
the X component add with the expert
component Y adds with y so that's
addition very easy to understand so you
have addition you define addition and
you also define subtraction okay you
just - the each cup component to get a
new number so for example you have a
complex number which is a pair of
numbers then you have another complex
number let's say which is a pair of a
number so the first one is a 1 a 2 ok
let's say the two parts the second one
is B 1 B 2 so we we got two complex
numbers
now you define an operation called
addition you can add them the way you
add them is so the first so the new
number will be the first part will be a1
plus b1 that's the first part the second
part is p1 plus I mean a2 plus p2 so
that you got a new number new complex
number so you this way you define
audition but you also define another
thing called multiplication ok
now I'm not going to get into the
formula but basically what happens is
that you have if you have one complex
number which is a point in the plane and
you have another complex number when you
multiply them the you got a new complex
number the new number is equivalent ok
it's equivalent to to how you rotate you
multiply the two numbers angles
basically you you you you you add not
multiply you add the two complex numbers
angle
that's how you get the third the new
number that's multiplication now you can
go to online you can go to my website
okay such folks re complex number you
will find a written tutorial which is
pretty good okay then then you
understand what complex number
multiplication means so that is the
essence okay remember guys that is the
essence of a complex numbers let me try
to summarize again a complex number is a
just number with two components and it's
a number in the plane then you define
addition addition is just like vectors
you you know you can define addition by
just adding their components then the
important thing is about the
multiplication where okay I got
distracted so I think I should stop so
anyway so the important thing about
complex numbers is the definition of
multiplication because it has a very
clear and intuitive geometric meaning
okay so that's a definition of complex
numbers that's the thing okay guys so
wait wait let me get to the gist the
gist of complex numbers so why is this
important because it allows here's
here's the important thing about complex
numbers it allows the rotation of a
point in a plane around our engine okay
so you have x-axis y-axis does middle
the center is our engine then given any
point often often times you want to
rotate it around our engine over some
degrees okay and the way you do it is
that you have to the formula is like
sine cosine something to get a new point
the the important the critical the most
important thing about complex numbers
why why is it so important is that is
that you define a multiplication so that
you can explain the rotation in terms of
the components the arithmetics by just
doing arithmetics with our components
out using tsiyon cosine that is a gist
okay okay I don't know if I'm doing a
good job I guess you guys are chatting
random so anyway that's that's the gist
of complex numbers it allows you to do
rotation without involving sine cosine
it asks you to do rotations by simply
manipulating the components of two
complex numbers I mean to you know two
points that is the that is the heart
okay that is the most important thing
about complex numbers okay that's what
I'm telling you
rotation you want to express rotation by
by just manipulating the components of
the points now that being us that brings
us to the quaternion
because this guy is thinking because
once you see once we have complex
numbers so we have rotation in the plane
it suddenly becomes so rotation now
becomes so easy you know you have a
system for rotations it becomes so easy
then mathematicians are thinking okay
what about three dimensions because now
because right now we are in the plane
two dimensions rotation okay you can do
with the complex numbers but
mathematicians are thinking so can we
come up with a system for points in
three dimension you know x y&z another
axis so can we come up with a system
that such that we can do rotation in
three-dimensional space without getting
complicated with matrix or sine cosine
you know we can just buy money
manipulating the the components of the
points that's what mathematicians want
you know that's like a huge desire can
we crack can we make complex numbers
extend to three dimensions so that
rotation in 3d becomes magical
that is what Hamiltonian came up okay
that that is what quaternion he he
discovered okay quadrennium that's what
it is so that is why we when you hear
quaternions among programmers everyone
is thinking oh rotations oh you need you
know in computer graphics you need
rotations that is the yeah that's true
you know that that that is why what
quaternion arose but we can get into
mathematics you know cortana cortana is
I is a algebraic system okay it's
another number system okay so so I've
rendered rainbowed too much and I missed
all the comments let's go back again a
little bit so let's just miss I mean
this is one hour and 10 minutes already
okay I don't know when I'm gonna finish
so I'm about to I'm mocking a quote from
Jaden Smith where he says how can
mirrors be real if you if our eyes
aren't real okay how can our numbers be
real if they are parts are imaginary
okay forget about the word imaginary
okay that's kind of a misnomer because
he wants you because yeah that's a
misleading path you know you have
imaginary numbers hmm but complex
numbers is a giant huge chapter in the
history of math because for 400 years or
so 50 years or 100 years mathematicians
don't get it they don't understand they
don't it's a huge chapter of history of
mathematics that is very very very
illuminating because it showed you huge
great histories of mathematics and how
they become how they become so our God
man my god you know I'm starting to if I
get into that topic I'm gonna start
another hour because actually I did I
did of
do on the history of mathematics and I
covered complex number is the one thing
I cover because when you study this kind
of kind of things like we talked about
today when you talk about physics like
biology or physics so chemistry people
understand what it is about or astronomy
you know you you know they can see you
know physic is something you can see but
you know physics biology chemistry is
something tangible you know when people
think about chemistry they think about a
lab you know doctors with white coats
then you have a bunch of bottles with
colored liquids and yet that's the
chemistry alchemy can you see that's
chemistry right you know people say oh
oh you put these following and we become
smoke oh my god magic chemistry but when
it comes to math you see math is
abstract you that you don't get it you
don't get you cannot like it's not like
chemistry or physics or the astronomy
you can see look at the Stars you know
it's it's it's abstract and and when you
go down when you go deep when you type
TV just it touches your soul guys it
touch your soul because it's getting
into the deep the higher dimensions
where the ghost lives no that's that's
why it touches me that's why I love math
okay so a lot for me are just people who
memorize yeah so and I T practice in
immersion are key and and and and and
and Arabic aerobics I cannot I don't
even know how aerobics sounds like or
Persian yeah so I have to learn them
Haskell is not about fat probably purism
okay so dropping in to say hello hello
Aaron Allen so some person says I think
you are antithesis for tribalism yes
do you do you have these tolerance
towards people who don't use your
bindings recommendations of course all
of you all of you oh that all of you
most of you any I mean all the people in
my my followers you guys my followers
you know we share interest you know and
so join discourse all of you yes and
some of you use my you know some of you
follow my advice about keybinding or use
my packages but not not you know most
not all of you you know you know many of
you guys use Linux and you know Obst or
talk about them all day or use jargons
you know which I don't agree that but
that's but you see I am in this
community you know I'm just voicing my
opinions we are in this community and
you have your opinions I have my so I'm
a I'll take any OSS unix-based to make
use of knowledge I already have and but
yeah so probably we need some special
web fonts or something we already have
that funds and so sorry we are chatting
he is not well-versed in English okay
great great
mr. Yemen thank you so yeah so the so
the magpie says yeah be it PSD Mac or
something Linux favor he is so fine they
are fine I just can do windows okay
the magpie I would say Windows okay so
so Freddy Freddy
in Germany says what do you think will
happen when they can finally crack RSS
encryption easy using quantum computers
in order factor factor factorization
based on algorithms okay actually we
talked about that yesterday or the day
before
because we have a mathematician in among
us who is on discord and his name is SID
right now he lives in Japan and he's
doing research and his research is post
quantum cryptanalysis meaning that you
know people I have already seen it
you know people that researchers
mathematicians already you know we know
that computer quantum computer is here
and it's it's it's it's gonna wreak
havoc on crypt analysis right we know
people know you know we already know
Google this big giant companies
Microsoft Facebook Google you know they
are doing it they are studying so they
have you know they have these Swiss
researchers they are studying what's
so-called I forgot what's a term exactly
but post quantum cryptanalysis meaning
that they are studying what happens with
quantum computers then you know what so
they are creating a new system they are
exploration exploring new ways to you
know have you know what you know
cryptanalysis and things like that
systems so I don't know nothing about
that in fact that would be interesting
to look into so but like I said you know
we each of us knows nothing and can hope
to know nothing you gonna know nothing
okay you're gonna know you you are
nothing you know nothing you're gonna
know nothing in your life remember that
okay remember that first then possibly
you might know a little something
because all the you know exponential
growth math in computer science they go
they go beyond what you can beyond each
of each of us what regardless how great
you are mathematicians they go beyond
what you can understand comprehend
that's my that's that's that's my kind
of view okay so so Alan says some person
that is right but if you are the type of
programmers that stays in some ideal
environment this is not this is not
troublesome awful I mean doing
statistics on studio okay so I don't
know
are we talking about her land or
something okay I got shut down
I got us shut down okay and uh Alan says
does good work talking about Microsoft's
pretty objectively good and bad oh great
Alan says I think his things thinks my
opinion are objective okay so I'm gonna
shut down okay you have a second in one
minute because we talked for too long so
Freddie says please answer my question
about quantum yes we did then okay
anything else let's scroll down and
coffee Oh coffee coffee beans are those
coffee beans show coffee beans in
popcorn tomatoes in popco and in
Guatemala so some person says we can
solve these secrets in the universe in
our selfies so hops from subject phone
subject gasps we disable what is like to
be a bat homeless Nico and I think I saw
pot somewhere here but good morning pot
but where are you located but but get on
discord so we can talk if you want to be
okay if you want to so bad greetings you
know so I'm going to visit Germany but
I'm going to visit Germany so you know
if you are around : area possibly we can
set up to meet up or if you go to go
along and meet me up okay and you show
me around okay but so that's a good idea
you show me around Germany you show me
around town but okay you still here
right so let's talk but we don't have a
good way to chat you know we have email
but email is problematic so we you know
apart
so who is calling who a widow Helen what
it's it's it's stuff that a joke joke or
not don't go too far okay so some people
who get asked to be modular what Emily
okay so easy to find so what are you
doing on Christmas yeah so but I'm going
to I'm not I'm doing nothing on
Christmas and but I'm going to visit
Germany and okay so let's get getting
contact okay but say hi or something if
you if there's a possibility we might
meet up okay but you have my email we
have talked in email before yeah so but
you know we I talked I'm gonna be in
Germany for two weeks okay
yeah so do that so let's get you know
email me okay so oh yeah you don't want
to join this call the email me okay Oh
something okay bye guys bye guys and
have a great day
it's gonna be February or March okay
February February or March for two weeks
I have not decided yet
I will you know let's get on let's talk
and I'll let you know so that concludes
today's talk show random random
nothingness nothingness bye guys and
support me by pay you see that dollar
sign that dollar sign is for me and for
you okay put money in my pocket patreon
or whatever Amazon gifts bye guys