Hello guys. Hello guys. Good morning.
Good morning everyone. It's been a long
time. Uh so today we we're going to do
unboxing of the Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard 80. Okay, let me prepare so you
guys can see me. Yeah, so Ultimate
Hacking Keyboard 80. So let me just show
you around what that is. Okay,
the Ultimate Hacking Keyboard 80. I'm 20
I'm 2 minutes early. So this is the
first one, Ultimate Hacking Keyboard
that came out in 2015
and uh and so you go to kasali.info
that's my website. So I got a lot
reviews. So this is the first one 2015
lots of photos and detailed review and
the second version ultimate hacking
keyboard 2 came out in 2020. Okay. So
that is actually uh this one you cannot
see I you know it's in my live stream
video every day. So anyway so this
ultimate hacking keyboard version two
fantastic. Okay so I have detailed
reviews check it out. Uh you are
watching sound talk show. If you are
watching offline play at 1.5 speed
minimum if you are watching live say hi.
Hi. Hi. Nice. So ultimate hacking
keyboard version two. Uh, fantastic. And
you go down, go down. So, you you see
they got all these modules, add-on
modules. You have to buy extra. So, let
me show you. Uh, and backlight, and you
can change the lead to display your
name, for example, or whatever layout.
And, uh, and, uh, the software is
superb. Okay, let me let me show you the
software. Ultimate hacking keyboard. Let
me show it again. But today, we're going
to do the Ultimate Hacking Keyboard 80.
That's a new one. came out a few month
ago. I'm gonna unbox it. So, let me show
you the box. So, this huge heavy box.
They sent me all the accessories. So,
we're going to open it. Okay.
But let me do the intro to auto hacking
keyboard. So, the software is I believe
it's open source. It's it's one of the
the best software, okay, for for
remapping uh keyboards. Okay. So,
ultimate hacking keyboard. Then you got
these add-on modules. You have to pay to
get them. Each one is like $60 US
something. I forgot. Check out their
website. Okay. Add-on modules. So, you
know, you can't see it today, but you
know, you see it every day in my live
stream videos. I haven't done live
stream for like almost a month. So,
anyway, the modules. So you can see you
got the track ball, you got a trackpad,
you got a track point or track stick,
and you also got extra keys and the tiny
uh track ball. So you can buy each one
of them. Uh so that's the module. Then
the the last item, the ultimate hacking
keyboard UHK80.
Now this is a upgrade because it's got
80 keys. Before it's only 60 keys. So
before you don't have function keys. So
let's go to their website
ultimatehackingkeyboard.com.
So uh aat. Okay. So you click on that.
So that's ultimate hacking keyboard 80.
So and that is what we're going to
review.
I mean not not review. We just I'm just
going to do unboxing. Okay. So is that
good? Hello GCS. Long time no see. Hello
PP. Evening. Good evening. Hello. Uh,
Cortez,
Cortez is my supplier of of bread and
butter. Thank you, Cortez.
Uh,
okay. So, auto hanging keyboard. Okay.
So, how much is it? You go to their
website. Check their website. Okay. I
can say that they send me one to review
without payment, but they but I get to
keep the keyboard. Okay. So, so this is
my fair review. Judge for yourself.
Okay. So, now let's So, have you guys
seen enough of it? Yeah. So, let's let's
do the unboxing. The Zuma's tradition.
Okay. Now, unboxing. I need to My desk
My desk is crammed.
Qu cramped. Can you hear me? Yeah. Okay.
So now this this full box that's my
address. I need to hide it. So let's
let's let's let's open the the thing.
Okay. Now I don't I'm not like th those
other nerds who got fantastic cameras
that cost $600
and they got the cutter and whatever
stuff to do the unboxing. You know they
got money anyway. So I use scissors and
do this the same job. Okay.
Scissors. And you got So you see they
got you see this is kind of heavy. Two
boxes.
From my past experience I know one of
them is the ultimate hacking keyboard
with uh now they got the the wrist pad.
I think it's attached to it. I think you
cannot remove. We'll see. Okay. But the
other box is a bunch of accessories like
the those add-on trackpads and track
balls. Okay. So, let's open that sesame
open.
Okay.
Sesame open. My wish is fulfilled.
And uh are there any other
tape I need to remove? Okay, let me do
it on the floor.
Okay. Now I got two boxes. You see this
one of them. Okay. this. I believe
that's a keyboard.
And and the other box, I believe that's
accessories, the the add-on track balls
and trackpad and stuff. So, let's open
this one.
Okay. So, you got
what?
Okay. So, let's study the construction
of the box first. So, the opening the
seal is here.
I believe that's the proper way to say
the seal.
Yeah.
Am I doing good? Am I doing good?
Are you entertained?
Okay. So this
so this you see it opens like that. So
you kind of
let's just break the box.
Okay. So now
I believe it's opened and sealed.
Correct. There you go. There we go.
Am I doing good? Let me check. Okay.
High quality. Yes. The ultimate hacking
keyboard is one of the highest quality.
Can you hear me? Yeah. So this
microphone
highest quality. Okay. So let's So there
it is and that's just empty. Now this
box has fulfilled its purpose.
We can ignore it now. So there it is.
The ultimate hacking keyboard at Can you
guys see it? Beautiful. You know, I know
what I'm going to say. This is I'm just
going to love this keyboard. Okay,
because I have, you know, because I have
like 5 years experience with them. I
know it's the highest quality.
Uh, but you guys need to see it, right?
So, okay. So, another
So, let's find the seal. No, there's no
seal. So, the So, okay. So, this is the
front. So, front of the box and the back
back of the box, they show you the
add-ons.
track ball, track point, trackpad and
the key cluster module.
Module is written. So you flip that
open. Flip that open
and
then sesame me open.
[Music]
Oh god, this is fantastic.
And when you buy it, you can choose you
can opt select your
uh key switch of choice. Oh my god, it's
it's got light there. Can you see?
Fantastic. So, so they include battery.
I know if you go to their website when
you buy it, you can buy it with or
without battery. If you buy it without
battery, then you just going to use it
plugged in. Okay. Uh and but if you can
buy the battery, if you plan to use it
wireless, it's got USB dongle wireless
and Bluetooth wireless. So they give you
the option whether to pay for the
battery because according to them I read
on their website you know the battery
they last you know 3 years four years
then it's kind of dead. Okay so I don't
want to break it. I got to be careful
how you Okay. I'm getting old so I need
to take off my glasses.
Oh,
there it is. Fantastic. So, it's thin
thinner than I expected. Okay. Let me
inspect it closely.
Okay. So, you see it. The nice thing is
about this um extra thumb keys. Now, you
can see they have different
height. You know, I always pronounce it
hate, but since I started to do YouTube,
Allan
told me it's not hate, it's height.
Okay? So, so you see different height.
Um, which which is by the way stupid
English, you know, H EI is not supposed
to be height,
but you know, you live with it. Okay.
And it's thinner than I expected. So
what else you guys want to see? Okay,
comments.
So and now these two can split a
shunder.
Now let's try
split a shunder.
Yes. Fantastic.
So you you can see those supposedly
goldplated
thing um that so you can you know that's
where the add-on modules the key cluster
or the mouse or the track pad track ball
um connects the electric contact and
it's this is magnetic. So anyway, when
you buy it, you can choose, you know,
what kind of key switch you want.
So let's put it back.
So this is today is just unboxing. Okay.
Now, is it good now? Let me So put that
aside.
Jesus, I don't have room. So what is
this?
This is the cable that goes between the
keyboard. If you
and this is uh
snap on feet
snap on, you know, you just insert it,
twist it, and it's on it, you know, so
so you don't need screws and all that.
Uh what about this side?
So this side you got the USB cables, USB
C on one side and the normal USBA I
believe. You know what? Whatever that's
called.
Okay, that's nice. And there's
attachment. Okay, so actually it's two
USBC
USBC.
But with this converter, you can
convert. They got the key puller.
Fantastic for you nerds who wants to
deal with it. Okay, so four feet. So
that's good.
Okay, I think that's the conclusion of
the
unboxing of the men keyboard Ultimate
Hacking Keyboard 80. Now let me try to
type on it. Okay, let me get a feel.
Fantastic.
Um,
you know, so now, so if you can see my
setup, you see this is glove 80.
Fantastic. That's my current main and
that's the ultimate hacking 60, the
version two. That's pre, you know, two
years or three years ago.
So now, so the switcher I have is the
lightest called pink something. Go to
their website, you will see pink. Okay.
So
fantastic. What do you think about this
keyboard? I think it is fantastic. Okay,
so that's that.
And uh let me open the uh the add-on box
add-on modules. So hexan simple postman
says you are getting a whole keyboard
collection don't you? How do you plan to
place that big girl between the glove 80
halves?
Yeah. So you know I probably
will not it will not be like in the
middle. So it will be just either using
that or using that you know one for
other use. Um so I I'll probably use the
ultimate hacking keyboard 80 for a while
uh you know for a change and also to uh
make advertisement for them. Do you
always use a multiple keyboard setup?
Not always. You know, I don't have money
before. So, usually one single keyboard,
but now I'm like I have a lot.
Okay, let's open the other box.
[Music]
Okay, this box is much lighter. So, let
me just open it.
What purpose does that middle keyboard
serve? Okay, this one I talked many
times. This is ultimate hacking keyboard
60 and I use it as a macco keypad. So I
press a key or do copy paste switch
windows whatever you know I demonstrated
many times. watch my old videos because
I have a I have like two or three
uh video reviews of the ultimate hacking
keyboard 2 and also two or three video
reviews of the ultimate hacking the
first version and also I have several
videos for the glove at and many others.
So you got to watch my older keyboard.
By the way, I plan to learn wolf ram
soon. I work in combinatorics. I'm a a
graduate student,
aspiring window compositor says.
Fantastic. Okay, now without further
ado, let me go back to the key to the
ultimate hacking keyboard box. Okay,
so you can see they sent me
the riser.
That's that's when you want to tilt your
keyboard. You don't want you don't want
like that. You know, if you don't type
much like most people, that's fine. You
know, you can hunt and peck. Hunt and
peck. But if you are a touch typer and
you like are a serious hacker, you want
your keyboard to be tented like that.
Okay. The the the the higher the
tenting, the less convenient it is. But
so depends on how much you type. So
that's what this box is. Let's open it
because I think you guys want to see.
So what is the mechanism? Okay, they got
two um they got
okay. So you see you know these days you
know since long ago 10 or 20 years ago
you you when you design the box you need
to have interesting designs so that you
know they they can be reopened and
sealed without
tearing the box apart.
Okay. So there it is. There's quick
start guide. Uh so let's see. So that's
that's a bunch of screws.
A bunch of screws.
Okay. How is this? So this is okay.
There's two pieces.
Uh it's kind a little bit heavy. It's
made of metal. Okay.
Metal. And you got this twist screw.
Thumb twist screw. Very good design. So
that you don't need screwdrivers. You
just flip it up. Then you can twist it.
Now what exactly is the purpose? I don't
know yet.
Uh so I suppose this can open up. Yeah.
So it can open up like that.
Okay. I have to look into
and uh Oh, so this pops up. Okay.
Something something like that.
Oh, okay. So, you move. So, okay. So,
you untwist them. You see this bar is
movable. So, you can adjust. You move it
by
turn it back and twist these two screws
and move it down a few notch. So, this
bar will come down here. Then then this
will
uh
will snap onto that bar. So if you do it
this way, it's going to be like this
degree. That that's the default. Can you
guys hear me?
That's a default. Okay. So this is
I think it's good design. Very good. You
know, I I noticed that the ultimate
hacking keyboard guys, they do good
design. So you don't need schools you
know this elegant design this is design
is the most important you know like
otherwise if you buy something from
China you know China they are massive
prod producers of keyboard today but
usually you know they they go the basic
ways like school or whatever but
ultimate hacking they got the most
elegant design from what I see okay so
so anyway so this is two
uh tenting
props.
Now, what is the proper way to call it?
Do they say
riser? So, they call it riser.
Riser 80 adjustability.
Fantastic. So, you can go maximum of 60°
riser.
Okay.
So, two two more.
They didn't send me the entire thing,
you know, like I thought they're going
to send me one trackpad, one track ball,
one key cluster, and one track stick,
but actually they only sent me two,
which I'm very happy with because they
already sent me the entire add-on
modules before. So anyway, two more box
to go.
I think you need screw it on the
keyboard. Maybe, maybe not. Okay, I
don't know about that. You know, maybe
not. So, um anyway
now, do I have one of those razor
cutters? Actually, I think I do, but we
don't need it. Oh, they actually sent me
the entire thing. So, it's you know this
box got two
little thing.
So, what is this? Okay, so there's more
USB connector. Why do you need this?
I don't know. Let's see. Uh dongo.
So, this one is track point. Can you
read it? Can you read it? Can you read
it? This stupid Logitech cheapo camera
track point.
Oh, this is a stick. Track point stick.
Okay. Now, so this this is for the right
hand. Yeah. So the right hand, this is
like those IBM. It's like a tiny
joystick kind of thing. Okay. Some
people love it.
Two buttons here.
Okay. So that's the track.
What do they call it?
Track point.
Okay. So, let's go quicker. So, this
one,
this one. What is this? What does it
say? Uh trackpad.
Trackpad. This one goes also to the
right hand side. Like the keyboard is
here. You plug it in. uh touchpad. Okay.
So, what about this box?
Yeah.
Okay. I think that's it for this video.
Enjoy your day and I will be setting
this keyboard up and you will be seeing
me using it in about a week, in about 10
days. Okay.
like over my desktop.
Uh so I going to have two like Ultimate
Hacking 80 and Ultimate Hacking 60 over
there. So like the entire the Ultimate
Hacking set because I'm a hacker. I'm an
ultimate hacker.
Okay, so two more boxes got going to do
this quickly. So what is this one? This
one is track ball. This is my favorite.
No doubt.
Also for the right hand side. This is my
favorite. You can see you can see I got
a trackboard
there. You know
I believe they are actually same. You
know the they are compatible with the
earlier versions.
So fantastic. So you got a button here.
You got button here and you can twist
this and move the ball out if you you
know when you need to clean it. I never
stupid Logitech camera.
Anyway,
so any more questions? Any more
questions
before I shut down? So this the last
add-on module is the key cluster.
So this key cluster is for the left hand
side keyboard. You plug it in like that.
Okay. Plug it in. So this for your
thumbs. So you got three keys and you
got a tiny
track ball. Okay. Can you see tiny? It
actually works. works fair, you know,
works well.
So, there's a two buttons. You can you
can see this a button. This a button.
Can you hear it?
Okay. So,
so this is for your thumb. Fantastic.
Okay. Because I have so many keyboards,
so I haven't been using them, you know.
So but but now if you know if you only
have one keyboard then that those are
extremely useful extremely.
Okay. So so many box. Let me So that's
that's it for today.
But let's look at this one more time.
Okay. Now, now they got a display here.
So, they got the display, you know, over
here. Um,
yeah. And the the best thing is uh these
thumb keys.
Oh, they light up. Look. Look.
Fantastic. What about this one also?
About this one? No. Okay. So, yeah.
Anything else? We shut down in two
minutes.
Question. Which switches did you get and
which switches do you recommend in
general? The one I have is the code
pink. Okay. So, let me show you.
Uh, so let's let's go to their keyboard,
the Ottoman hacking keyboard website.
And you can see these modules and you go
down and they tell you how great it is.
You know the
tent in 10 to 60° with riser
shears a little red wine makes you live
longer.
Okay. Then you can see the switch and
key cap mechanism.
highest quality. So this is a double
shot PBT key caps. Double shot means
they the key labels is made in such way
that is actually made of two plastics
one inside it. So they merge kind of
melt you know merge that merge them. So
the key labels will never wear off never
not in 10 years not in 100 years. Okay,
that's called double shot.
Now, what is PBT? PB PBT is a special
plastic. Okay, now the plastic also
matters because if you have a cheap
keyboard after two years, you'll see
they become shiny, you know, very ugly.
The label wears off and shiny, you know,
like fairly ugly. I I have photos.
Search for key caps on si.info. you will
see lots of photos also on the Mac
laptop. So anyway, so so auto hacking
keyboard they use doubleshot PBT key
caps. So can you can can I actually
explain to you? Yes, actually. So look
at my uh website. You go to
uh fun history key switch guide.
Okay, so key switch guide. So you can go
there and lots of but there is a a page
about key caps I want to show you. Okay.
So anyway rubber dome scissor switch uh
keyboard switch mechanisms introduction
lot you know like you can just read my
website and and your question about
what's my favorite my favorite is the
lightest switch. Okay 35 grams. So
actually this
uh this this is a different thing. This
is a thin uh profile. That's actually
bad. That's good. Okay. I I like I love
that. But it needs to be 35 grams
uh activation force. So typically a
cherry
MX
red is at 45. Okay. So the lightest
cherry MX red linear that is even too
heavy for me. So my recommendation is
that if you are a heavy typer and you
plan to type for 20 years, you want to
get used to the lightest switch possible
like right now for you young people.
Okay? So I recommend Cherry MX Red or
similar. Okay? You want linear. You
don't want clicky. You don't want firm.
You don't want feeling the activation.
You know that those Okay? Linear.
Okay? Get linear and light. So, Cherry
MX red or similar because today there's
lots of Chinese ones.
Cherry MX is no longer the standard but
anyway Cherry MX is well known. Okay.
So, you want a linear and uh 45 grams of
activation force or less. So today
I must have like at maximum 35 no more
than 35. So I get so anyway so you can
read a lot about key switches. Okay. So
um you know key switch and what's my
favorite and the details about the the
key uh you know force requirement linear
switch force uh comparison. So you know
I got like 10,000 articles here. Okay.
Can you see it? Yes. So is it is my
answer good? Okay. So let me show you.
So uh we want to go to look at key caps.
Okay. So uh
key switch activation force with uh
versus resistance field. They are
different. Okay. Uh there's lots of
details like technical details. For
example, Cherry MX blue or Cherry MX,
you know, they show you this diagram,
but there's a lot to dig into. Also when
they say the activa activation force is
45g
but on one brand versus another brand
the same number actually are slightly
different. Okay. So you you get you just
have to um have experience. Okay. So
anyway let's go to um
history of keyboard mechanical switches.
Okay. Oh my god. is what
in the past 10 years there's explo
explosion of key switches like you don't
know what the they are like raccoon
kangaroo switch raccoon switch phantom
switch alias switch CJ switch click keys
switch player switch botic switch and
strawberry switch and chocolate switch
you know this in the past 10 years like
you have no idea what they
So anyway, so let's go back uh to uh So
anyway, so there's a lot of articles. So
I wanted to show you the key caps that
we were talking. Uh so which section is
it? Cute key caps. Okay. So there's a
custom artistic key caps you can buy.
But back to key caps section index. So
there it is, the key cap and labeling
technology.
So you got ABS plastic. That's the
cheapest you when you buy Microsoft
or Logitech non- gaming keyboards.
That's what you get. And after a year,
you got this ugly shine. Very ugly and
annoying. Look at the look at this Mac.
On the Mac, you know, very ugly and like
disgusting. Okay, so that's ABS plastic.
You don't want that. Okay. Then you got
PBT key caps. This is high quality. So
you can see them using Kinesis 360.
Okay. Let's m Let me magnify my window.
Okay. Kinesis 360. I have a review video
review of course and also used on uh you
know this quality keyboards. Okay.
And then there's other types like PVC
and palm and gets complex. Okay. Uh
different type of plastic. For example,
this one is using glove 80. Okay. So,
did I answer all the questions? That's
it for today, I think. Thank you guys.
If you love my stuff, go to PayPal Pay
Me. Okay. Go to my website.info.
This is important.
Don't skip this part. This is the most
important part. Where do my food come
from?
If you enjoy my video, okay.
Uh, you know, so then you go down, go
down, go down, go down. Programming
languages, technicality,
mathematics, advanced, nobody
understand. Then you see Patreon, Amazon
gift card, PayPal, everyone understand.
But you just need to pay me. Okay. Thank
you.
So let's go back. So yeah. So let's see
if I answer the question. Study shows
simple postman say study shows that the
cause is that wealthy people have access
to good health care and additionally
sometimes drink red wine but the drink
is not that healthy.
I think that's true. You know, I'm in
California for the past 30 years, they
tell you red wine, if you want to live
forever, you need to drink red wine like
a cup a day because it contains
chemicals and and stuff. So, something
something no, you know. So, so we need
to drink red wine. You need to buy you
need to make America great again. Peg
afteralism.
What switches do you have in your glove
80?
Again, that's called cherry blossom
something. Uh 20 grams of force. Okay.
So, it's the lightest possible.
So you go to talk show today's talk show
go to ultimate hacking keyboard go to
ergonomic keyboard review go to glove 80
then scroll down scroll down my power
station my battle station when I'm I'm
ready on Twitter to do keyboard wars
with with with other coders you know the
C and C++ and rust gun.
So my B battle station beats them. Of
course I press one thing one key. I just
press one key on my system and they are
destroyed.
Uh okay. So my glove 80 keyboard is
using this fantastic new key switch.
They came out uh about last year which
is called key switch there. Okay. So you
go to um
so I got linear 35 uh port red. Okay.
Actually I got lighter than that. They
got a new um new uh switch. So let's
see. I believe they call it cherry
blossom. Okay. You go to glove 80s
keyboard website. It's their own like
like this one. Okay. Pink. You know the
the the the naming is not standardized
because they
because this this switch this chalk
switch made in China
China Kay chalk switch
so they don't they don't make 35 grams
of force but people customize so they
then you have different factories you
know produce so so the label the key
label the name the pink whatever is
different but anyway the one I have is
um I think they call cherry blossom on
glove 80 website. It's like 20 grams I
believe. Okay. Like here on this one.
The white one is not the 20. The white
one is actually heavy. 60 grams. Okay.
Okay. I think that's it. Thank you guys
for watching. Bye guys. I think that's
it. Did Did we cover everything? I think
so. Yeah. So
after about a week then u you know
you'll see me using the glove uh the
ultimate hacking keyboard. Let's let's
switch back to ultimate hacking
keyboard. Okay info.info
keyboard blog then ultimate hacking
keyboard. So that's what we are talking
about. Then I'll start to have lots of
photos detailed photos and review. Okay.
Bye.