Hello, good evening. Welcome to another
episode of Exot Talk Show. We are going
to uh code JavaScript. Okay, we're going
to have fun code JavaScript. We going to
um so JavaScript we're going to write a
command that taste test equality of
array or object.
Uh you know in JavaScript it's a very
lousy language. you you cannot compare
uh array by array content or uh object.
So we're gonna write that in fact it's
already written
but we're going to do some uh we're
going to write so what we're going to
write so the command is already here
okay test equality of array and object
by content okay so the array or object
can be nested so that's what we uh and
you know so but so here's the code uh
and this is written beginning in 2022
uh I think it's earlier than that. But
anyway, so
what we're going to write is actually
we're going to write a benchmark of
using alternative uh method of uh JSON
to uh string gify. Okay. So we can turn
an array to JSON string and compare the
resulting string. That's one of the way
to uh test if arrays are equal or
object. But however, there's lots of
problems. We're going to talk about that
because you know when you use uh when
you turn them into JSON, you got lots of
issues. Uh uh for example, object uh key
order, that's an issue. And uh and also
when you use array, you got issues like
undefined and new values or sparse
array. They will cause problems. Okay,
so that's what we're going to explore.
Uh if you are watching this offline,
play at speed two. If you are here, say
hi. Okay.
So let's start code. Okay. So let me
just uh I I need to do it this for
myself. Uh continue from Yes. So today's
today's talk show. Can you see it? Yes.
Okay. So let me start to do it. Okay.
Uh let's remove remove that showing
browser. So that's what we going to talk
about. And uh that's my keyboard if you
are wondering. So that's my uh ultimate
hacking keyboard. The keyboard you see
here and go here, go here, go here, go
here. Scene two. So the ultimate hacking
keyboard UHK80
NIA trackboard and Logitech trackboard.
And uh let me mention again this is
fantastic device. This is called SWA
board. SV
A L B O A R D S V A L SWboard. Okay.
Magnetic switch. I haven't used it yet.
So, I'm I so so fantastic.
You can uh check out YouTube. I had a
kind of review a year or two ago and
lots of other people has done it. Uh
they have reviews. Okay.
Okay. Now let's let me just let's let's
let me just go back to start to code.
Okay. Uh so demo object. So let's let's
show the code. Okay. If you are here,
say hi. Hello. Hello Andrean. Hello
Isaac. Isaac Fiddler. So we going to
demonstrate the code. Uh show in
browser. My god the the the font is
huge.
You know, one thing you learned when you
do live stream is that you need to make
your font on your screen like twice as
large like and then because of
for for for for those watching the
YouTube that will be much easier but for
you for myself the font becomes so so
huge you know it's hard to get used to
because then you you can only see a tiny
part of your screen.
So anyway, so
so that's a code. So we going to let me
uh first of all demo demo de demonstrate
the code. Okay, so here's a code uh
search for it. So pop it out. So here's
a code. Here's a documentation. Uh is
object equal return true if every
innumerable property keys and values are
equal. Symbol keys are ignored. Nested
object are compared uh in the same way.
Okay.
So you can you the object can be array
or uh or data object and they can be
nested and only innumerable property
keys are compared. Okay. And their value
okay must be equal. All the properties
does not matter.
Okay. So uh excuse me. Hold on a second.
Need to blow my nose.
So here is a so so here is the uh code.
Okay. So here is the code. Not not too
long. It's only uh you know it's only
let's see uh
copy uh copy new paste 20 lines of code.
Okay. 20 lines. Fantastic supreme
functional programming. This is
recursive function. Okay, this function
coites itself
and it is the most efficient
function for this purpose out there. You
know, you can go out and look at the
MPM, you know, there's lots of
libraries,
you know, the popular frameworks that
has this kind of similar feature. And I
would say my is the most correct
and the most the the the fastest as
well. the most so they say performant
okay you can you can test it you know it
go up but actually there's one thing we
need to modify okay there is uh because
I was looking at the code I noticed
there's one thing we need to modify to
improve the speed because here you can
see they they get the keys object if
they are objects okay if they are array
you know if their ref reference is the
same then you just return true you know
by the triple equal because they are
exactly the same array because they have
the same array address okay but
otherwise if they are not object both of
them are not object a a and bb so that's
the argument okay if they are not object
then then you compare them as array by
nest you know you compare each element
you nest into um and you call itself
okay those if if they are both of them
are true arrays okay because in
JavaScript You got this array like
you know very complicated So
if they are if one of them is not array
then you have to compare compare them as
object. So when you compare them as
object you got several issues. You got
keys whether they are innumerable or
not. You also got the issue of symbol
keys because remember a object in
JavaScript is a collection of key and
value pairs. Each key and value is
called a property. Okay, am I too loud
here? So collection of key and value
pairs. That's a definition of object in
JavaScript. And each key and value pair
is called a property. Okay? And they are
identified by the keys name. Okay. And
the key
uh can be two types you know like a
value type. So the key must be a string
or a symbol type.
I'm coughing a bit. So I'm you know so
anyway key must be string or symbol
type. Okay. And also a key a property
can be innumerable. there's a attribute.
So, so you got key and value that's
called property. Key can be a string
type or a symbol type. The symbol type
is new 10 10 years ago in 2015. Okay.
The value of a property can be any type
can be can be string can be number can
be a function can be whatever. Okay. So
key value pairs each key value is called
property. Okay. Now for each property
you can have attributes you know so so
one of the attribute is innumerable
boolean attribute whether that
you know that property is considered
considered innumerable then you got uh
you got two others okay uh like get
getter and setter anyway that's very
complicated and you you know you it's
like so complicated the JavaScript is
crap okay you don't need them. I mean
the reason they have them because they
don't have true arrays. So they you know
they are trying to make it easier but
they got up because this the
whole thing is written and designed in
10 days JavaScript in 1995. So you got
like tons of problems. Okay. So anyway
now remember object by definition is a
collection of key value pairs.
Well actually there's more than that. By
the spec it says key value pairs but in
reality in practice actually
each object may have special behaviors
such as function date and time object
regular expression object
u you know the the reflect object you
know like the specialized objects but
anyway object is key value pairs and
they are it's each key value pairs is
called a property and uh a property can
be innumerable have several attributes
and one of them is innumerable so anyway
so you started to so I'm talking about
there's a inefficiency here I shouldn't
sort there I should sort it later okay
but actually we can fix it but before we
do let's just run it test it okay
compare array compare object compare uh
then compare so then so this is object
this is pure array array, nested array.
This is nested object and here is nested
array and object or array and array
array or or object array you know you
know nested nested any of object array
and here is primitives let's just run
them all so they return nothing because
that means it's success because this
console log uh I mean this console
assert function that's a function I just
learned today actually I never used it
but it's pretty old. I think concert
assert that um basically return if it
returns true it does nothing. It only re
it only prints just like console log
when when the value is not true. So it's
just like console log except
when the value is true it doesn't
doesn't do anything. Okay. So, so all
these are true. Prints nothing. That
means my test function is successful.
Uh
but I needed to add some more. So let me
show you some more. Okay. So compare uh
let's say compare array. So let's add a
new condition
array with undefined and no values.
Okay. So let's say uh three no and uh
here three undefined. Okay, let's see if
they are uh yes or no same or not.
Assertion failed.
Okay, so there you got assertion. Well,
of course, because they are not equal.
Okay, they are not supposed to equal.
Okay, so that's successful. So this
should be equals to um false.
Okay. Now run it. Perfect. So this means
my function is working correctly. Okay.
Unlike possibly some like if you use
string, if you use JSON. So let me show
you the JSON thing. Okay. So if you want
to compare to a object, you can use JSON
uh JSON stringify. Okay, there it is. So
you want JSON stringify that is it
equals to JSON stringify
of
of that. Okay. Now you you can run this.
Let's just run it locally.
No output. Okay. Let's see. Let's try
again. No output. Okay. So that means
it's successful. This assert. Yeah. I'm
not sure I like assert, you know. I just
started to use it
because when you have log they actually
make sense because it prints it. So it's
like it's more intuitive
you know like because most of because
assert is rather more rare used rarely
used. Hello are you guys here? Say hi.
Okay say hi guys. Andrean and Isaac and
train what are you doing? You missed you
missed things. We we coding advanced
JavaScript JavaScript in depth. Okay.
So let's uh let's change the assert back
to log. So I don't want to assert
because assert is less well-known thing
when you have like console log is
universal. So you see now it returned
all true. Okay.
So we we tested special case. So this is
the example of using JSON to compare
string. Okay. Uh and and in this case uh
this returns true. Okay. Let me run it.
You see true which is incorrect. You see
because one array is got the no the
other arrays got a undefined. No new and
undefined are not the same thing. Okay.
So this is a failure the example of a
failure when when you use JSON string.
Okay. So anyway so let's uh we want to
test some more things. Okay. So let's
make another test case. Compare object
uh with
key in different uh
okay let's just say that
two
uh two okay so we need to
Okay. So, let's see if that uh
works or not.
Okay. So, you don't want the extra
comma. You know, it's very annoying that
um you see I have I have a script that
auto format for example. Let me show
you.
The pink window shows all my command
calls and the function names. Okay. So,
do you know what I'm doing now? Trainer.
Okay. Uh a arise. Hello from dev room.
Hello there congaroo.
So, let's make it one line. Okay. Now,
press the key format. Okay. It's still
formatted into one line. But um but if
the line is too long, it will not. Okay.
So, let's see.
So anyway, so let's see for example, for
example, let's say uh let's say else
make it one line. This make it one line.
Let's make it the whole thing one line.
Okay. Now press a key. It's you see it
formats and that command is um that
command is uh describe key. That command
is JS format buffer. Okay. Go to the
source code. You can go to the source
code. Go there. SJS format buffer and it
actually calls deno. Okay. D N O
highlighted. It call it call deno. Okay.
So, but I don't have to go to shell like
for example go to shell
then deno fmt or was it just fmt then
file name you know then completion to
get the file name too too much problem.
I don't want that. Okay. I just want
whatever the file I'm in. For example,
let's make this long line. Okay. I mean
long space in front. Okay. Now, press a
key. You see my cursor can be anywhere.
Press a key.
You see I can I can you know I can
actually So, let's let's try this.
Make a backup first. Okay. So,
so the whole thing make it one line and
run it. It will still run fantastic and
beautiful. Can you see the power of this
functional programming style? Most
industrial coders, they don't know this.
Okay, those people at Google or GitHub
or you know they create the frameworks
and you know oh the sparkling frameworks
and this or that react you know but they
don't know this coding style then
likely they never seen it. Okay.
So now you see one single line run the
code it still works and but now press
key to format it everything nice
automatically one key press. Okay. Now
expand the window so you can see. So you
see now render code still works.
That's the beauty of the automatic
formatting.
Uh it's it this is done by Deno. Okay.
Deno I highly recommend it. Okay. Deno
don't use uh uh NodeJS that's because
it's it got corrupted by this Isaac like
I believe he's in my opinion
only okay by by the mpm you know
whatever he did with it so the I
recommend Deno highly recommend Deno if
you're going to do web dev use deno okay
don't use njs
and also okay so so deno uh and uh what
else what Um
so this superb code okay now put it back
put it back you you can see now show in
browser now this not syntax colored go
back to emac error because every time I
show in browser it will try to validate
you cannot right now because you got you
got this greater equal you know greater
than sign so but now press a key to
syntax color all the code in this page
and show in browser And now you can see
it says HTML valid and in the browser
you can see colorful beautiful code one
line functional programming the power of
functional programming okay it's pure
function it's no imperative you know for
for looping C++
biting thing and bit deleted hack you
know let's let's use bit bit end you
know so we can save one microc second
and nobody can understand your code. The
C C++ fuckets. Okay, I despise them. So
anyway, function functional programming
and test cases. Okay, uh we are not
done. So actually we need to actually I
need to move on because I got actually
things to do because I can talk for
hours. I can talk and tell you things
about JavaScript for hours but but I'm
not doing anything for myself. I need to
actually
So what I want to do is actually write a
benchmark. We so what we want to do is
write a new uh version of the object
comparison equality test function but
but but make it based on the uh JSON
stringify. Okay, we showed before. Make
it based on stringify. We need to fix
part of it and write a benchmark to see
which one is faster. Okay. Okay. Let's
quickly do that. But there's one more
thing we need to uh uh uh check. Okay.
So, compare object. Um okay, this is
this is like nested and readable. See,
now it's better. Okay. Now, I was saying
demo before they they add this
extraneous comma at the end. Finally
they don't they fix that because for
example here you know the reason they
you know you see here is a function call
okay that's a function call but the
thing the the thing with the console
lock is that you can have three four
five you any function call you can have
a ending comma in JavaScript okay that
is by you know that's the syntax that's
valid and some people beginning with
late Malay and gen they think this is a
better syntax you know programming
language should allow you to have a
trading comma because because that way
it's easier to add a new item whenever
you know you can add a new item
uh but it's less logical because then
you know because this is not English
this is not traditional
writing systems you don't have a ending
comma that's goes nowhere you know but
however anyway in JavaScript this
valid
and with a demo format they
automatically add this thing you you
know like whenever you have a function
call uh let's say
uh my function okay my fun something so
when you call demo demo format then boom
they they add a comma at the end of the
argument like what the is that so
that is Why you see this comma here?
Because I was using den also before. So
now if you remove it and you know for
example let me uh make it one line.
Okay. So
wait
did we?
Yeah remove that. Okay. And uh make it
one line. Yeah. Okay. Now format the
whole buffer to it. It doesn't add
extraneous comma again. Okay. So there's
another one. Remove it. Okay. So wait.
So we we need to uh do this quickly. So
what is this? Compare object. Compare
array with undefined and no. Okay. Then
uh what we want to do is compare object.
Yes.
And compare object with diff uh with uh
with uh key in different order. That's
right. So A1 B2 B2 A1 that should return
true still run it. Okay, fantastic. It's
all true. Yes. Okay. So
put it back syntax show in browser.
Okay. Now is there anything we missing?
So far so good everyone.
Oh now you sir I'm 50 something pushing
sir. I'm about to die.
Well, few more, you know, maybe a 10
more years actually. Maybe.
What if you have two ending commas?
That's a good question. Two ending
commas. That's illegal. You got syntax
error. So, let me let me So, actually I
I So, so let me show you that. Okay. So,
you go to JavaScript JavaScript in
depth. That's my tutorial. I you know
there are 600 pages JavaScript in depth
the most concise the most accurate
correct and the most easy to understand
JavaScript and the most in-depth in the
world on earth in English language okay
you can check it out okay so so here you
go to um the comma okay so the trading
comma objects of so there are several
issues there's a trailing comma in
object literal
expression which is here basics value
types variable strings. Uh then you got
properties. Then you got object and
inheritance object object overview. Go
there and go down. Then you got object
type. Uh where where is it? Object
overview.
Uh
object type. You want to go to the
object literal expression. Okay. So
where where is it? Create object. Okay.
Go create object then object literal
expression. That means the that kind
that means the literal the syntax you
use to create object. Okay. So in object
literal expression you have the issue of
ending comma. You see
trailing comma is ignored. That's no
problem. But however, if you have
repeated trading comma, that's a syntax
error. Okay. So, for example, you can
run this for example, let's open that
page. Search pre uh that that that
trading comma repeated trading comma.
Okay. Pop it up. Run it. You see error.
The module source code could not be
passed. Expected something. Okay.
Because you got two comma, but one is
fine. Uh okay. So, let's try it. Remove
it. Run it. Uh, wait. Run it. What?
Uh, wait. One, comma. Save it. Run.
What?
Wait. So, this is um
what's going on?
Trading comma is ignored. So why is it
uh what's going on?
Run it.
One comma should be fine. But why are we
Oh, wait. Is it trying to cash? I
got somewhere.
Wait. Close that. Okay. Now run this.
What?
This is
what uh wait something is going on.
What? It's not.
So, it's it's using the latest code, but
it's not
uh what
am I have I gone crazy? What's going on
here?
Oh, that's right. Oh god, another
problem. You see, here's another watt of
JavaScript. You see
when you have that you know that's a
object literal expression syntax right
no not here you must have like you know
you must in the proper context okay so
here this thing is a object literal
expression okay not here because over
there JavaScript is thinking that you
are writing a block you know like
constant you know constant a = to 3
print x + uh 2 you know so so when you
have this thing without any you know
without a variable in front or whatever
JavaScript is is thinking you you are
doing a you know a block expression that
is why
so that is why when you run the code it
says error you know the module source
code could not be passed you know so But
you do this then remove that this. Okay.
Now run it. Fantastic and beautiful. You
see?
So now we can demonstrate the comma.
Okay. So one single comma. Put it there.
Okay. Now run it. No problem.
Add another comma. Run it. Problem.
Okay. So that is uh what we're going to
demonstrate. So put it back. And let me
fix the code here because I need to fix
code. So this part one single comma you
need to um
uh constant. Okay. So so that way people
can actually kind of see.
Perfect. Okay. Now
put it back. Now this part this part uh
two comma is a error. That's right.
Okay. So put it back. Syntax correct
show in browser. Okay. So we got the so
it's a bad design. Okay. So if you have
one trailing comma it's okay but if you
got two you got a problem. Also you
can't have two comma in the middle
neither. Okay. So so okay I we need to
fix that part too. So pre so we are like
going all over we are not um so is it
entertaining is it informative or is it
entertaining is it uh you know something
let me know okay so let let's run this
run this uh this won't work because you
got two commas there uh so we need um
let's say cannot have
repeated comma
Okay,
it got problems. Okay, put it back now.
Syntax code showing browser. Fantastic.
Okay, so this is about object literal
expression. Now, but
you got the trailing comma issue or
repeated comma issue. But the same thing
applies the same thing applies when you
have array syntax. Okay. So do I have a
did I explain somewhere array repeated
comma?
Uh I might have somewhere. Okay, you got
exactly the same situation in array and
in function call. Okay, so when you when
you go down go down function call. So
where's the function array function
function overview arrow function
function constructor you know so and
also keyword function
uh and function call. So you also got
these issues whether you have one you
know trading comma or or repeated comma
in general repeated comma in all all
these three cases repeated comma is not
good is error okay but trading comma is
good so we were saying that demo
used to like at least a year ago they
they automatically add a trailing comma
at the end a function code very bad and
this trailing comma idea began about
it began with a late Malaysian I believe
like 2010 like people started to think
trading comma is a good thing we should
have it you know in style guides and you
know people started to have that opinion
you know so I think you know the late
Malay chen you know people became more
idiotic
lots of problems
so anyway we digressed we haven't um we
haven't got to talk about actual um
writing a um
we wanted to write a um
right we we we wanted to write okay so
where are we showing browser go back
close that
showing browser we wanted to write a
function
basically we want to write a benchmark
okay let's just you know benchmark of
this function versus uh uh JSON two
string. Okay, let's just write a
benchmark and that's it. Let's forget
about
uh any other extra details. Okay,
so let's see what what are you guys
saying? Uh maybe that's why the correct
way is to not have the trading comma if
you by mistake have two in the code
dice.
Uh yes.
But the you see the reason they think
training comma is convenient is great
because like it it does make sense
sometimes like because
like when you want to add more item in a
array or in a you know object
when you have trading comma it's easy
but then they but then if you have
double trailing comma it's error. I'm
not sure what you know
that you know that makes sense. Either
you allow
Yeah. So I actually I I have to think
about this like maybe you should you
know either allow both you know if you
allow the training comma then you should
allow repeated comma which should you
know assume then just to be one single
comma maybe I you know I have to think
about so this is about
syntax design okay so for example in in
Wuam language and all earlier languages
they don't allow that you know they
don't allow a trading comma but I think
in later languages
um they allow that actually that's
interesting let's ask guac
okay can we ask guac which programming
language has trading comma in uh in list
okay so let's ask a guac a new question
uh
Which part then allow trailing comma in
list or array
items. Okay. So let's just say that the
AI is will understand. You know AI
doesn't care about your grammatical
errors. You know your incorrect English.
AI understand.
So let's magnify
control. It's a big farmed.
Okay. So, how long have we been talking?
So, wait. What are you doing? God.
Uh, I'm thinking maybe I should go 40
minutes. Okay. We've been talking for 40
minutes.
So, what is Guac's answer?
Here are the major programming languages
that allow trailing commas in array list
literal and often in other comma
separated constructs like object
parameters. Yes. Okay. Of course,
JavaScript and Typescript that began it
and Python idiotic Python
indeed. Okay. So, Rust
uh so what is it? Training comma uh
object and dictionary. Okay. So, array
and D. Okay. Rust allow it. Okay. Rust
is new. Golan
also allow it. Okay, that makes sense.
Okay. Yeah, you see they all allow it.
Okay. I didn't know but it begin with
Java.
So it begin with Java I guess. See do
they have C and C++ first? No. You see?
Yeah. So I was correct. not in C, C++
but basically began with Java. Well,
Java began in 1994, 1995.
Ruby began in 1987
like Ruby and Python and uh they began
all about the same year. R Python in
1987 or 88 Python and Pearl. Uh but Ruby
is a bit later like two years later. So
1989 something. So but so it's
interesting the so the who is the first
who began it that would be
okay. So that would be uh Python and and
Ruby. You see the the the the problem
with Python and Ruby as the originator
is that they are not popular until after
year 2000s. Like nobody know what the
is Python. But people do know what
is what the is Java like since
1995. So in in a sense uh Java began and
then C++ pushed it. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Well then well oh there it is Pearl.
Okay.
Okay. So so Pearl.
So there is the answer. Pearl kind of
started Pearl and Java I think.
Interesting question. Okay. So anyway,
we we digressed so much. We haven't uh I
wanted to write a function to I mean we
I want to write a benchmark. So you see
why is this interesting? What we're
going to do is that you know you can you
can use um so let me show you articles.
I already have this you know 10,000
articles written about this. You can you
see test object equality by JSON string.
You you cannot do that. You got older
problem. You got you got because the key
if they are ordered in different way
otherwise exactly the same you still
won't get you know true you know because
the order you when you JSON dot string
the order matters okay so but you
can fix it by first of all by by first
kind of reorder the object like
well actually you know for for the for
the object case it's it's difficult to
to write the equality using JSON
stringify. Okay. But however, for the
array case, if you want to if you want
to test
the equality of two arrays to nested
arrays by their content,
it is then possible to use JSON string
stringify to do it. Okay. But there are
some issues you need to pay attention
to. One is undefined versus new because
in JSON there is no such thing as
undefined. This just new okay or or was
it the other value but anyway so doesn't
matter it's you know when you have
undefined and new both of them become
new in JSON okay so but however in
JavaScript these two are different
values so this is one thing you need to
uh pay attention to. So if you're going
to write a array equality test, you have
to check if um
so can you like so the question is like
can you actually like um
try to use stringify
but still fix this problem? uh because
that would be difficult actually because
because you have to know each element
then
you have to dive into the array nested
array to actually know if if there's an
element that's undefined or new you have
to but if you want to do that then you
don't need stringify any anymore because
you could you just directly compare the
array element values right so it doesn't
save you anything to use stringify. So
that's you see that was what I I was
thinking about doing like because
otherwise let me show you okay so beside
these few issues stringify is rather it
works it works for array okay for pure
array I mean uh true array like array is
array return true not for array like
okay so so you got undefined versus
new then you also got sparse array
issue. Um you know for example these two
arrays one is got repeated comma that's
a actually in array that's that's valid.
Okay but you got
you you you you you
will end up creating a so-called sparse
array which is different from array of
of having a value of undefined. Okay, so
this aa and bb these two array are
actually different. They behave
completely differently like when you map
you know a function to the array the map
will skip those missing indexes. So they
are completely different things these
two. Okay. But but if you say you see
because if you get the key they say they
are not the same force. But if you turn
them into JSON they become equal
because
when you have like a sparse array JSON
will automatically turn all missing
indexes to have a value of undefined. So
they become the same. Okay. So this is a
issue. So but when you actually so in
JavaScript when you want to compare two
arrays and one is sparse do you want to
consider these two equal? No. Right?
Because when you have a sparse array
it's very problematic. Okay. It's very
problematic.
So you don't want this to return true.
Okay. So that's another thing you need
to fix.
Um so how can we fix this? I mean and
still use uh JSON.st stringify. So you
need to detect SP uh sparse array which
means you need to detect
missing keys. So you need to get the
length of the array and you need need to
check it has keys starting from zero to
to length minus one. All keys exist
otherwise you got a sparse array. Okay.
Uh by the way all all this all this I'm
talking about is explained in my
tutorial like for example array overview
then you got you you you know you got a
full page on um on sparse array array
like object and so on and how to convert
them and how to fix them things like
that okay so let's go back
so so let's go back so we were talking
about test array equality by comparison
with JSON string Okay. So we get so
sparse array.
So you need to so if you want to use
stringify to
as a as you know implement the array
comparison how can you do it? You have
to first of all write a function to
check for sparse array and uh that would
be too much work
because again if you're going to do that
you might as well compare the elements.
You don't need stringify, you know,
because stringify is just super
convenient. And you see the reason we
want to we might want to implement array
equality function using string stringify
because it's implemented
building function that means it's
implemented in C you know very low level
language and guaranteed to be correct
otherwise because millions millions of
people using it. So the stringify is
fully specified and guaranteed to be
correct according to the specification
and it is the fastest possible. Okay. No
function you can write that's do
stringify faster than the building.
That's the nature in almost all
languages in in in eac in whatever
language. Okay. You want to use the
building function as much as possible.
So that's why we might want to write a
array comparison function.
and you know using the stringify because
that will make it very fast but then you
know so we got these issues uh I'm not
sure we can actually solve it
okay so other than these two issues um
everything works out okay so array can
be nested it also work out uh test
equality of nested array by converting
to JSON uh JSON cannot be used to test
equality of object right so if your
array contains a element that is object
then you are okay when you have
object uh JSON stringify cannot do it
okay
uh and when you have array likes like
object that's al you also no good okay
because array like object are not array
they are objects so you als it's the
same situation with objects
okay so in the summary So far I think
you you know you simply you cannot use
JSON stringify. Okay
I mean you you you can if your array
doesn't contain define and
if it's not sparse array
and it doesn't contain object objects or
array like objects then JSON works.
Okay, but then there's another issue.
Okay, so even if it works, but let's say
if you have a array of let's say 100,000
items. Ching. Hello, F Hank. Thank you.
Uh did you see the new Jerry Qu uh
jQuery version came out? Jerry uh jQuery
is no good, man. JQuery is good like 15
years ago.
15 years ago before 2015 I mean it's
it's useful like in 2005 okay 20 years
ago 2005 to 2015
so 10 years ago it's still useful very
useful in fact it's not just useful it's
necessary jQuery is not just useful it's
like absolutely necessary if you want to
uh do any web dev jQuery okay it's it's
written by a late Malay Jen who is
pushing for you know kind of pushing for
the for the for the social justice
warriors. Okay.
Hello go J. So jQuery is extremely
useful and necessary 10 years ago but
since 2015 JavaScript has a big change
you know
basically J jQuery you know because
JavaScript went went through the
modernization along with um not NodeJS
you know they became actually a
revolution in computing industry. So you
started to have the idea of the
a sync functions which before before
NodeJS around 2009
it almost doesn't exist in other
programming languages like nobody
thought of I'm pretty sure it exists but
the average you know the the the
mainstream nobody you know it's not a
common idea to think about to to have a
function that that does a sync you know
then do promise and wait or whatever
people don't do that but
beginning in 200 you know since nojs in
2009 2008
that be that that became a thing and to
this day I'm not sure I don't fully
understand it okay so I I don't
understand I I'm not sure whether it's
justified like why is it we don't have a
sync functions in most other languages
before I
So
it's it's a it's a bit complicated issue
because it it has to do with concurrency
programming and parallel programming
which are different. So it has to do
with those but not exactly. Okay, it's
like somewhere there somewhere there
with to do with concurrency but not
exactly because a sync in JavaScript is
still serial. It's not parallel. It's
not concurrent at all. It just delayed.
It's just like a loop check. Okay. So
anyway, so it's very complex. So, so in
summary,
starting in no Node.js 2009, uh,
JavaScript introduced the like a sync
idea kind of to the to the programming
industry and and JavaScript started a
revolution kind of and also you started
to have serverside JavaScript. So the
web the web dev industry is going
through lots of change and also remember
internet explorer
people are trying to kick it out. It's
very hard you know there's still like
you know there's still 6% using it
which is not compatible with all your
JavaScript code. So, so but eventually
so 2015
eventually you know so we have a new
JavaScript version and and uh you know
JavaScript used on servers and internal
internet explorer explorer finally went
away so there's a lot changed so that's
so you know so jQuery
you know by 2015
starting in 2015 it's basically useless
okay it's like useless. The only people
who still use jQuery are those people
who don't know how to code like they
don't they don't know they just follow
you know I I I you know I need a job I
heard working as a programmer can make a
lot of money so oh this jQuery you just
do this and that's only that's basically
the only two there are two two two kind
of people still using jQuery one one is
the new like people who don't know how
to code at all they still use you know
jQuery and the other is like backward is
like legacy code
there's already one million more than a
million lines on the web that's using
jQuery and you don't have you know you
you are not going to hire programmers to
rewrite them
so it's just there it's going to stay
there forever like like forever so
that's you know so you got new
programmers I mean you you you
know gradually remove them or you like
usually they just stays okay this legacy
code they just stay until this you know
you you no longer use the software you
know the company died or whatever so
that's the only reason jQuery is still
around basically you know
okay so we went through all of us the
stuff uh I think that's it
you know we uh we didn't write a
benchmark so
You see we were going to write a
benchmark. You know so far I explained
you know the all the details about you
know JSON and test you know uh array
equality code uh test equality of array
and object by content. We talk about
also we talked about using JSON to do it
and we were talking about benchmark. So
what is it about benchmark? So if you
don't know, you go to JavaScript
at the bottom there's a benchmark. So
you can you can you can uh in demo you
can um you can do benchmark. So it
allows you to test you know many
different to compare different
constructs or implementations
of functions in JavaScript. Very useful.
So this will bring up you know this will
show you lots of like
issues you might be wondering. For
example, we did some others before speed
comparison of generating array. There
are many ways to do it. You can use a
for loop. You can use a you know like
while loop. Here is a while loop of
generating a um
array. Okay. So you want I believe you
want a range function. Yeah. You want an
array with values from 0 1 2 3 and so
on. Okay. So you can use a while loop.
You can use a for loop or you can use a
functional programming style. You see
this one very supreme functional
functional programming you know you
don't have local variables you know so
which one is faster you can compare you
know do it one 10,000 times you know it
came out result
for loop is the fastest okay
there's nothing you can do about it for
loop you know this this uh well you know
if you do it 10,000 times then it's a
you know it's 10 50 microcond faster.
Okay.
So even if you use push you know so can
you see the like the result? Yeah you
can know if you use uh direct assign for
loop or wire loop that's n microscond.
If you use push to generate array you
got 40 microcond. If you use array field
purely functional programming way you
got 60 microsconds. So the difference is
like compared to for loop is like 50
microsconds. Okay, that's like 10,000 of
a second.
But you know what happens if you use
jQuery?
If you use jQuery, it's going to be more
than 100 times slow. Like your entire
thing is like 100 times slow.
Uh
so I think that's it. Okay. So let me
answer a few more questions. You've
called lispcon's logic garbage compared
to Mathematica. That's correct. But
still use Emacs. Is wam perfect syntax
irrelevant if it's proprietary license
kills the open echo economy? Well the
the reason I don't use wuam language for
everything is because it's not suitable.
Okay. It has nothing to do with open
source.
First of all, first of all in Emacs, why
am I using emacisp? Because emacisp is
for the editor. I need to process text.
I for example, I can press a key. Wait.
For example, I can uh for example, let's
scroll down. Okay. So, you see this is
uh syntax color JavaScript code. Press
press. Now, they become, you know, they
remove the syntax tax. You see now I can
press press press press press press
press press press press pop it out now
it's in a dedicated
uh buffer of JavaScript and I can press
press I can run the code and I can
expand the window you can see all my
command calls in the pink window it's
all commands written by myself okay in
eagisp what do you think eagisp okay so
for example HTML toggle syntactical text
uh stuff like HTML pop out source code
you That's what I'm doing. So now press
press. You can you can see pop back
source code. Now press press press. Now
you can see HTML re HTML
pre-code buffer. Okay. Now press. That's
HTML open in browser. You see I can do
all this. Where's the code? Well, let's
show the code. Press press. Okay. Wait.
Um. Okay. describe key press. Okay, so
this you are coding HTML re HTML as uh
pre-code buffer. The source code is here
as well as all the other source code
1,00 lines actually this file is 3,000
lines of code but that's not the only
one you got.
You got uh you know you got so alto
together it's like six almost
9,000 files 9 9,000 lines of code in
this HTML HTML mode okay you see all
these commands you see
where's the code that's here's the code
what is the source code this is emac
this can you do this in wam language
actually you can because
But nobody do it because
so anyway the the reason I don't use
wuam language you know first of all you
can't
it's not suitable okay it's a different
thing uh it's not suitable now in wam
language you can actually
you can actually just program it like
like just like eag this okay I talked
about this before but first first of all
evaluate it
uh you can you can program it just like
emac this you can manipulate because
anyway that's another topic okay I
talked about watch my old videos I'm
pretty sure I I think you know most you
I don't think you are interested you are
just asking because you want things to
be free that's why that's that's your
question that's like that's the heart of
your question because wuan language you
have to pay you don't want to pay you
really like can can it be like open
source so I don't have to pay of course
you don't say you you don't you you
don't say that you don't want to pay you
you say in terms of like open source I
want you know the share but actually
what you really want is that you don't
want to pay okay that's why you are
asking how come you are not using you
know woven you know basically that's
that's the the fundamental source of the
question
so I'm not using it here you know or in
JavaScript in in browser because well
you cannot
use you know JavaScript is the language
for the browser you can use wam language
so you can also you know compare to comp
compile to javascript or web assembly
you can also do that with f or judia or
some other languages but but that's not
the like the core you know that's
that's why okay I I think that's the
that's kind of your question.
Um
so I think that's it. What what what are
the questions? Uh so nothing beats for
um four plus
ifs. Uh
yeah for and if yeah they you know the
imperative code they it's true that they
are the most you know if you uh they are
the fastest if you are really concerned
about that
so this question you know so you are
call this con very silly question
because
this so if you are you know because I'm
in EMAC this you know I code you know I
do this things that's that's why I use
emacisp can I have wam language in emac
emac no emacs is not using wuam language
just just like vim is not using emacisp
if you use vim or neo vim can you why
why don't why are not use why why are
you not using eacisp
to code nim or v or nim or if you are
using vs code.
Open this file in VS code. Okay. Why are
you not using emac this to code VS code?
VS code is written in JavaScript. Okay.
Why why are they all these people
millions of like literally 10 million of
VS code developers? Why are not they are
not using emac this?
Because it's not part of EBS code. Is
you know VS code is written in electron
in JavaScript.
That is why so why why don't you why are
you not using JavaScript to develop wam
notebook you know wufam notebook
because wufam notebook is not written in
JavaScript or this wam notebook is in
written in wuam language okay now now
now
you mention it let me let me let me I
need to run uh some code to demo woof
language
okay So uh in fact I have so many you
know uh wam language uh tutorials and
let's go to there. So uh wam language go
there. Let's just uh repeat one of the
okay so programming language tutorials.
Uh there is wra language uh let's just
copy this code. Okay I want to learn
something 3D. So here's a code we
demonstrated. We coded live about in
2023. So that's two years ago. So copy
the code. You see how concise it is.
Paste it. Uh wait, paste it wrong. Uh
select all. Delete.
Delete. Okay. Paste it. Okay. Here's the
code.
Magnify. Okay. Now shift enter to run
it. There it is. Okay. This this can do
computation, can do uh mathematics, can
do number theory, can do uh differential
equations, can do differential geometry,
can do um black holes physics, you know,
can can solve all these equations, can
do
neural networks, can do machine
learning. one single function like one
single function you can do chart GPT and
so on. Okay. And you can type set like
press press control shift N to type set
it. Okay. So this is Wuan language. You
can format it on the fly as you type.
Okay. You can see even if you have
complicated math expressions like
fractions or nested fractions, it will
format it in a great logical way on the
fly. You don't have to manually insert
tab and return like tab like Python
idiots. Python and F idiots. This you
zoomer idiots.
Okay. So you have to pay.
So why am I not you know why why is
Wuan? Why am I not using JavaScript or
or or or you know emac this or this to
code wan language but because it's not
it's not that it's not written in those
languages.
Okay, that's it. Bye guys.
Did we complete everything? Well,
basically yes. We kind of covered the
topic we want to talk about. Uh so
showing browser. Yes. Close. Okay. So
here's HTML mode. Close. Emac list code.
Okay. Different purpose different place
in different places. Here you are
looking at extreme
functional programming of EMAC listp.
Okay. Extreme functional programming.
And here we are looking at the most
extreme tur supreme
functional programming in wuam language
and in fact more advanced and then
hascar or f okay here here my code
this this this subject is is is called
inversion okay inversion
threedimensional geometry inversive
geometry okay beautiful
and in fact we need to change something
so that when you rotate it, it doesn't
so it like has a fixed center. It
doesn't shrink or enlarge. And you can
actually let's see control uh Oh yeah.
So control. So now you use you need to
use a mouse. It's easier if you use a
mouse. Control that. You see? Can you
see a circle? Can you see kind of like a
sphere inside it? Sublime. This is
sublime. Can you do this in JavaScript?
Actually you can
yeah it would be interesting to code
this in JavaScript. Uh so uh to code
this in JavaScript you have two options.
One is just using um well you can use
SVG
then that's no good because SVG is just
two dimensional. So if you want to code
this in JavaScript you're going to write
a lot code. if you want to do um um
uh SVG. So I have a tutorial on that SVG
clocks. Okay. So you click on that uh
live clock.
So but so another way is you using a
3DJS which still create SVG or use the
uh um uh web uh GL WebGL. Okay. 3D G
WebGL.
So I haven't actually this is what I
really want to learn but I haven't
learned it. Okay. So so so co to code
this in JavaScript you you use webgl and
in fact I have a demo on my website.
Okay. So then here is the typescript. Uh
I mean that's the VS code. Where is my
page? Okay. So let's go
um web. So let's go to CSS.
Go down here. Go here. So actually go
here go hacker code go search uh webgl
do I have there it is uh so
so you got this dynamic thing in in
written webgl so I haven't learned how
to do it yet okay it went off uh so you
see
um so yeah you can do this in but you
In Wufam language, this is like one
single line. Okay? Or if you count
characters, you know, maybe three lines.
But in WebGL, it's like 300 lines. No,
it's going to it's more like
it's more like 1,000 2,000 lines of
code. Okay. To to do this um to uh wait,
if you want to, you know, see. So, if
you want to be able to like rotate it,
you know,
here's a challenge. Okay, for those of
you who think you know stuff, code this,
okay, look up geometric inversion
actually. So, you can code this, okay?
Code this in uh in WebGL. I would be
very interested.
And if you if you showed me, you know,
you can go to Kasar Discord, you know, I
have on my Twitter. I am on Twitter or
Kasar Discord. You can find it on my
website.info
the address. Okay. So if you call this
in WebGL, I will be highly respect
of of your uh you know creation you know
call this in WebGL. This is geometric
inversion of a three-dimensional uh grid
of cubes. Okay, that's it. Simple. Just
look up with geometric inversion. We did
this live, okay? In one of my YouTube
two or three years ago. Okay, you can
you can look up. So, code this in WebGL.
I will be very interested to see that.
You know, this is one of the things I
have to learn. But but you got too many
things to learn. Okay, bye guys. Bye.
That's it. Bye.