Hello guys. Welcome to another episode
of Xah Talk Show.
We are going to code Emacs Lisp, not
coding Emacs Lisp, but I'm going to show
you Xah Fly Keys,
the most efficient key binding for
Emacs. And what is Emacs? Emacs is the
most powerful text editor.
Okay, so this is for you guys, uh
programmers, coders, scientists,
engineers, mathematicians, and writers.
So when you need to manipulate text a
lot,
Xah Fly Key Emacs is the answer. And
when you use Emacs, use Xah Fly Keys.
It's a more efficient than Vim.
Uh and uh
Pravin is using Evil mode. Evil mode is
kind of similar, but inferior. So this
is more efficient than Evil Evil mode is
a mode in Emacs.
A mode for Emacs that makes Emacs using
behave like Vim.
Uh okay, so let me get my coffee. Be
right back in 10 seconds, and let's
begin. Okay, so
Xah Fly Keys, and uh be right back.
Fantastic and beautiful coffee.
And tea. Coffee and tea.
Okay, so we going to demonstrate
Xah Fly Keys, and uh I'm going to do
some Emacs workflow, so you can see
as I code,
uh how do I work on my website. So
every 1 hour or so, I get up and walk.
So I got this bunch of uh screenshots.
I, you know, I walk back and forth with
a notebook, and I write notes. So these
are things I need to change.
So okay, so so what is Xah Fly Keys,
first of all? So Xah Fly Keys close
eyes. So right now I'm using Xah Fly
Keys, if you don't know. You can see all
my command calls on the left. For
example, move cursor
by word, right and left, you see
uh forward word, backward word, and uh
the key stroke
is shown on the left side. I'm using a
Dvorak keyboard layout, so
so Xah Fly Keys, so you can go to this
xahlee.info, search for Xah Fly Keys,
you can find it.
There's a video.
Actually, I've done quite a few videos,
so you can watch
and learn it, and uh you can install it.
It's on GitHub, download on GitHub.
Okay.
So
so let me quickly
tell you uh what is Xah Fly Keys, okay?
Xah Fly Keys is a efficient key binding
for Emacs. First of all, so you use
Emacs as a text editor, the most
powerful and flexible.
Then
uh so for example, if you want to open
file in a traditional text editor, for
example, let's go VS Code. Let's start
VS Code.
Okay, so there you have it, the VS Code
of the same file.
Uh wait, update version. [ __ ] shut up.
So this exact same file, you see, Xah
Talk Show episode 678
in VS Code.
There.
So it's a text editor, okay? So so but
in for example, if you want to open
file, now typically, traditionally in VS
Code or other editors, you press control
O.
You know, then it shows a bunch of files
you want to open.
Okay, so I don't want to open. So but in
Emacs, it has its own keys. That would
be control X control F.
Uh wait, I removed the key, so so I
don't have it that. So basically, in
Emacs, the keys are cumbersome, you
know, so
there that's when Xah Fly Keys come in.
So now if I want to open file, I don't
have to press control press control and
hold down control. I press press press
press.
Wait, this is open previous. So press
press press.
You know, it asked me to open file.
Okay, cancel. So Emacs keys by default
is complicated. Lots of, you know,
control X control something, then alt
something meta.
So Xah Fly Keys is is a model. It's like
Vim.
So you don't have to hold this and press
that.
You don't have to do that. So
all keys are just a single key press.
For example, open is
uh space C
uh
and
the wait, not that. Space C that, you
know, by muscle memory. E, so
I'm using a Dvorak keyboard layout, so
it's different from the one you are
using.
Okay, so if you don't know what is
keyboard layout, search for Xah Lee
keyboard blog. There are 1,000 articles
there. So layout.
So you can see keyboard layout. So you
can see in this picture, you got
you know, you got QWERTY. This is what
you are familiar with.
And Dvorak, this is what I use. So
Dvorak gives more efficient because the
most frequently used keys are in the
home row, the big circles. So you see
QWERTY,
Dvorak.
QWERTY, you have to go over.
Dvorak, and you have you have others
like Colemak and
and Norman and Workman, okay?
So I'm using Dvorak keyboard layout. So
what you see, you see the key stroke on
the on the left side, those are Dvorak.
So anyway, so Xah Fly Keys is a
efficient key key binding system, okay?
Um and uh you can, you know, go watch a
video. So
uh
and
uh there are some changes I made
recently. So now this is for those of
you already using Xah Fly Keys.
You know, Xah Fly Keys has been around
for like uh
for like 15 uh
13 years.
Before that, 5 years before that, it's
Ergo Emacs
key binding, which I created also.
Uh but I created Xah Fly Keys uh
as a replacement.
Okay, so anyway, for those of you using
it, I made some changes, kind of uh you
you might consider it as a kind of minor
upgrade. So it's upgrade. So
uh the changes are
I removed
the keys that uses digit.
So for example, delete other window, for
example, let's say you have many split
windows. You know, in Emacs, you can
split uh in different ways.
Okay.
So
if you want to unsplit, before that, you
press the digit three key.
Now it doesn't work. Now it just insert,
because I changed it. So now if you want
to unsplit, you press this
uh
on Dvorak keyboard, it's a dash. It's
it's your pinky to the right, okay?
You see, unsplit.
So that's some of the key changes. All
the digit keys are removed.
Why? Because the digit key, the digit
row, they are on top. They are hard to
press, and especially for touch typists.
Now if you don't touch type, then
doesn't matter, because you
you know, like normal keyboard, you use
you know,
you move your whole hand to press the
digit key. Usually, you look at the
keyboard like half of the time.
But if you are touch typist, you know,
then your hand is always in this
position. Then you have to like move up,
and that actually created permanent
damage to my fingers.
Uh
because of the one two three keys on the
left side of the keyboard.
Uh one time in 2010,
and another time. So 2010 is the key one
and two.
Then 2016 is the key three.
So you are wondering, so how is it
possible? Well, how you know, why is
pressing those keys damage, you know, uh
your hand, like painful?
In fact, it's permanent. I still suffer
from it.
So the key the so it's a long story. So
here's my uh log of my typing experience
and repetitive strain injury.
So the key one and two happened because
key one two, because back in 2010,
I was using the
uh Microsoft 4000 keyboard, okay? So
this keyboard.
And so one and two are uh you know, on
the left. So I have a habit. So you see,
they are shifted way to the left. So
instead of just moving my hand, you
know, up
like using my pinky and uh uh
and uh ring finger, I tends to like
twist my hand to the side and use my
index finger to press them, one and two.
So, I do that, you know, so for several
years, then that and then started to
have some pain.
Then I realized that's a problem.
Why do I have to press one and two
often? Because one and two is the most
used digit among all, one and zero,
okay?
Uh then two.
Far more than all the rest combined.
And the other
reason is that uh what is one and two? I
forgot. Why do I have to press one and
two, okay?
Uh
Yeah, I have a like complete log about
it, 2010. Programmer hand health, V I
escape key syndrome, okay?
So, the reason why I'm pressing one and
two so much is because um
I forgot why do I have to press Oh,
yeah. So, in Ergo Emacs
Alt one and Alt two are for uh
for expanding pane. So, so that's for
this operation, you know, split split
split pane. Uh
you know, or split vertical
uh you know, and unsplit. You have to do
this often. So, on Ergo Emacs system,
which is a key binding system for Emacs,
that is Alt one and Alt two. So, that is
why I always have to press the one and
two. That
created a damage to my hand, painful.
You know, after like after 5 years.
So, that's one thing.
Then the other thing around So, you
know, this repetitive strain injury,
they occur like every few years. Then in
2016,
I started to have another problem.
You know, once a problem happened after
a while, you discover but oh, that why I
have this pain. Then you avoid it, you
know, so once I discovered in 2010, you
know, this one and two keys create
problem. How do you know? Because every
time you
try to press those keys, you feel the
pain, okay? So,
so usually you sometimes it's easy to
discover what's the cause, sometimes
not.
So, once you discover it,
uh you avoid it, you know, you change
the key binding and stuff. So,
that's one issue, 2010. Then 2000 uh
then there's other incident, okay? But
2016, another thing happened is that I
discovered
I have this mysterio mysterious pain
right here and still so today. Not not
right now because I didn't type too
much, but every time I type too much,
for example, a few months ago, I have
pain here, okay?
Like permanent. So, I usually use a ball
to like hit it or use massager, you
know.
Permanent damage.
So, but in 2016, I discovered that
that's the cause, okay?
And
I don't know what's the cause, you know,
how is it possible? Like why is it hurt
here? Uh I do not know, but after
several months, I eventually discovered
that is because the it's a number three
key, okay? So, you cannot see it. Can
you see it now?
So, the number three key, you know, the
like on this keyboard, you cannot see,
but
I'm not I wasn't using this keyboard,
but anyway, the number three key, okay?
Doesn't matter what keyboard.
So, to in order to press that, you
extend your middle finger all the way
up.
So, that key is doing this unsplit, you
know, this unsplit. So, what like every
time you do something in Emacs, let's
say
uh for example, let's say
diet, then it split the window. So,
usually after you read it, you don't you
know, you want to remove it, so unsplit,
okay? So, that unsplit is was the digit
three.
So, you have to press that every you
know, every minute, every few 10 seconds
or every minute. So, that is why in
2016, I got the pain here. Serious,
okay? So, I got a
I got a full blog about it. Um
So, back then I was using this keyboard
and then
I I was typing so much, you know, I
would I I would I was like the world's
number one
on record who sits in front of the
computer more than anyone, like the top
1000, I would say.
In USA, at least.
So, then then in 2000 uh what
what year? 2016, I switched to this
keyboard again.
The same pain happens on this keyboard,
number three key, okay? The number three
key, even on this keyboard, canices.
So, you know, I have full documentation
about this hand pain. So, that's 2016.
Wait, where did I go?
Okay, so Xahlee typing experience uh
2016.
Okay, so
so um you know, you can read about the
details.
Okay, so that is why
so that is why the you know, I made a
change to Xahlee keys.
Showing browser.
To remove all these digit keys.
Okay?
That's some of the change.
Any questions? Any comments and
questions? Nobody. Nobody is here, okay?
Uh seven people watching. So, any
questions, comments?
So,
GCS says, I'm using PT Nativo.
Now, PT Nativo, let me introduce to
other people.
PT Nativo is a efficient key binding
system for
Portuguese.
So, in Brazil, mostly spoken in Brazil.
So, this is my keyboard review.
Um
This is all the trackballs you ever
wanted to know.
Okay? There are 1000 pages on my
keyboard guide, okay? And uh Xah
keyboard guide. So, you can you know,
you can um
video reviews. There's like So, I had
like hundreds of video reviews in the
past few years.
I haven't done
much about keyboards much in past a year
two or two, but I had so many.
So, ergonomic keyboards, so you got you
know, one of the fantastic one I still
need to learn and show you guys is
is this fantastic device, Svalboard
DataHand, okay? So, I will be showing
you guys again.
You know, I will be learning this. Yeah,
I don't know when, but I will, okay? I
will for sure.
So, DataHand, okay? Svalboard. So,
search the web. Thanks to the guy,
uh you know, check it out.
Uh I consider this ultimate
input system, okay?
But I haven't you know, used it yet.
So, anyway, so we were talking about uh
the
PT Nativo. So, you have many efficient
layout and one of them is PT Nativo for
Portuguese, okay? This one.
So, you can see
right now this is English text. If you
type English, you know, it's much more
efficient than QWERTY because all the
keys you can see on the home row. So,
this is QWERTY on English,
Dvorak on English text, and
and then PT Nativo on English text.
But you can also switch to Spanish. I
don't have Portuguese, but Spanish is
similar, so check
So, if you type Spanish, it looks like
that.
English,
Spanish, Spanish,
German,
French, okay? Anyway, PT Nativo.
So, PT Nativo, let's see if if I have
the detail, okay?
Not
Nativo, PT Nativo, okay? PT Nativo is a
uh
key binding design that looks like that,
created by a Brazilian by this guy, Ari
Caldeira, okay? So, in 2006,
I think he contacted me
or I forgot what, you know,
you know, but I knew it since 2006 and
his website went down. So, this So, I
got a mirror here.
Okay? So, that's PT Nativo
for uh efficient key binding
uh efficient letter layout for
Portuguese.
And Xahlee keys support that, too,
support this layout. So, Xahlee keys
supports like all these uh
all the layouts I showed. Um
Okay? So, let's go back to layout. So,
check out layout.
So, you know, uh Xahlee keys supports
all these
all these layouts.
Okay, so Xahlee keys. Now, any other
question? Now I'm going to So now what
I'm going to do is
so Emacs blog close close Xah Talk Show.
So doing do during my work back and
forth sessions I have these notes. I
need to update my page. So I'm going to
show you I'm just going to work on them
and you're going to see my Emacs
workflow.
So it's a demonstration of how I work on
my website
10,000
HTML pages written tag by tag by me
since like 30 years ago.
Okay, so these are the things I need to
work on.
So switch to it and uh
and switch back, okay?
Let's see the comments.
So I like the window setup the post doc
I work with.
Uh I work under
Oh, you work under a post doc. Also use
Windows, but I wonder if you are using
Emacs, why not go full open source
Linux?
That has been
explained a thousand times, a frequently
asked question. Just search my YouTube
for operating system or search for Linux
like why which operating system is the
best, why you should use this or that.
But basically it's just for practical
reasons, okay?
I don't like Windows. Windows got lots
of problems.
User interface the most lousy, but
better than Linux, okay? Linux is the
worst
user interface, you know.
Microsoft Windows they got lots of
political problems associated with deep
state. So they they gather your
information, you cannot trust it.
Uh so for that aspect Linux is much
better. But then the Linux Unix idiots,
they don't know how to design user
interface. So on Linux you're going to
spend an hour every day to Oh, how do
you do this? How do you change this, you
know? Basically every day you're going
to spend 1 hour to dido. Like I need to
change this to this, you know? Then a
problem, then you go to stack overflow,
then then then, you know, configure and
[ __ ] whatnot.
I've been using Linux since
1998.
The first Linux I installed is MK Linux.
But back then I was mostly Solaris, a
Unix guy, okay? Unix.
Then I used Linux as my desktop from
from
from 2008 to 2005, something like that.
So let me show you the article.
Just search for Linux, okay? So I have
lots of like I have like 100 pages on
Linux, okay? You can see endless.
Uh this So this is 188 results.
So Microsoft Linux Microsoft created an
ad against Linux back in 2000 uh 2000,
okay? 2000 December.
In German.
So you are looking at Linux, you know,
the mutation of the Linux.
So the article Unix Unix pestilence, you
know, I I despise Unix which became
Linux, okay? Unix is the most
[ __ ] insulting [ __ ] Unix and C.
Now if you
follow me, you already know that because
I talk about that all the time in the
past 4 years.
Okay? So but anyway, what are we
So what, you know, is there something?
Yeah, I wanted to show you the Mac OS
uh Mac
about um
how to build Emacs on on Linux and this
stuff and
let's say
Windows. Microsoft Windows is install
Linux tools. So that's a list of
like a list of most common needed
uh Linux tools you need on Windows. But
not today, you know, because PowerShell
and so on.
And here's a relevant article, you know,
Linux versus Mac versus Windows, which
is best for key binding. I also talked
about this
two or three times in my live stream.
You know, as you know, I'm a
you know, expert, you know, in study on
key binding systems so much, you know.
For example, this keyboard page you can
look at
you can look at, you know,
typing habit, touch type, how to what's
the proper pause posture, mousing tips,
how to avoid mouse pain,
ergonomic keyboards of all sorts of, you
know, there are literally 1,000
articles.
Do it yourself keyboards all sorts of
normal keyboards
all sorts of
and then key binding design this is like
this is talking about Emacs Vim, you
know,
you want a keyboard shortcut to do some
command.
What is the most efficient design? You
know, should you have control X for this
command or should it be control Y or
should it be alt X, you know, or should
it be sequential like press alt release
then press something like the Windows
alt space. You can see that, you know,
resize window and stuff. Alt space.
Sequential. So there are many ways. So
this, you know,
this index is uh
full of articles about that
that key binding design issue.
Then you got all sorts of typing related
touch typing, what is touch typing,
gaming, you know, touch typing
competition, what does word per minute
mean, does it matter, what is the
average, who are the fastest typers,
things like that. And
what if you have hand pain, you know,
what kind of toys or exercise tools you
can relieve your hand pain, you know.
So 1,000 articles, okay?
For example, speed typing. So here is
all the article about speed typing. Who
is the world's fastest? What's their
record? Uh and where can you see them
demonstrate, you know? So YouTube links
and, you know,
So anyway, so then laptop keyboards
design intricate, you know, very
you know, and history of it, you know,
lots of details, evolution of a laptop
keys.
And then mouse and joystick and all
sorts of, okay? So
check it out, okay? Just search for Xah
Lee keyboard.
I haven't done live stream. I haven't
talked about this topic for like for the
past 2 years.
Because I've been doing this for, you
know, over 10 years, actually since 1940
1994. Uh and
so
So the question was we were talking
about we can see your screen. Oh, [ __ ]
Uh that's so bad.
Uh [ __ ]
So anyway, so I was showing I was
showing my um
keyboard guides, okay? So they are like
1,000 pages
about ergonomic keyboard and do it
yourself keyboards and normal keyboards,
okay? And uh
then keypads keypads all the things you
want to know about keypads.
Then
kind of miscellaneous esoteric
comical or humorous things about
keyboard or key binding or typing
related. You know, these for example,
the hackers
battle station.
And there's lots of histories of, you
know, this is one of the most famous and
great design this this this type board
called uh ABM Selectric about 40 years
ago.
So history, you know, like for example,
what is the first
who invented the meta key or who who
invented the old key or the command key
or the control key? You know, or it's
all documented somewhere here.
And ergonomic ergonomic keyboard
history, so you got the ergonomic
typewriter back in like back in 1935
ergonomic typewriter.
Okay? Then, you know, then the Japanese
from 1980s
uh then you got
key switch guide. So this is all you
need to know about you keyboard
aficionados
or keyboard fanatics, you know, which
key switch is the best and so on, okay?
And my opinions of it. What how are they
designed? What do they mean? For
example, this is buckling's
spring, one of the most famous and
loved.
Um then there is like magnetic switch,
then this is optical switch optical,
okay? Fantastic.
So then you key switch, then you got
design of keyboard issues. So besides
key switch, there is tenting, you know,
tenting is when tilt your keyboard in
the middle.
Uh
is it important? How important is it,
you know, and so on. So, I discuss all
these issues. And firmware, what about
firmware, you know, like if you buy a
gaming keyboard, you are familiar with
this a gaming keyboard got this fancy
you know, fancy and
scary, ugly interface to to program your
keys and control, you know, set your
keyboard shortcuts and and so on.
And the the RGB lights, colored, you
know, colorful lighting and stuff.
And you know, so and keycaps. So, there
are many beautiful keycaps, okay? So,
for example, this uh paw keycaps, paw
and naw.
Uh many of them are
very beautiful, okay?
So, then the you know, tons of others.
Then special keys, so if you want to
know the history of the control key or
history of the enter key or what are the
variations, you know, different
variations of the enter key size or the
return key or issues like what should it
be named? Some keyboard says enter, some
keyboard says return. Do they mean the
same thing? What about the enter key on
the numerical keypad? Usually there's
also enter. Are they the same or are
they different? And also on the Mac
you know, you have different, you know,
and also besides the naming of the key,
but there's also the label, labeling of
the key. For example, the backspace key.
Uh the space key, why is it so long? Who
who created, you know, who first created
the space key? Was it, you know, that
long? Was it always been this long?
There's history, okay? So, then you
know, then who is the uh you know, the
first topic? So, escape, when is it
invented? Why what does it do? Why is it
called escape?
You know, then uh then the you know,
screen s- system request, uh print
screen, scroll lock, pause break, kind
of obsolete, you know, and uh then you
got the compose key and alt graph key.
Uh so, for example, alt graph and
compose, okay?
Then you got page up and down, you know,
where you know, who which keyboard first
invented, you know, have the page up and
down and okay. So, all these are about
keyboard keys.
And you got keyboard layout issue, which
is familiar familiar to a lot of us, you
know, different keyboard letter layout.
Okay. Then you got uh
so, go back, then you got then you got
key binding design, which is like Vim
and Emacs.
Uh then you got typing or things you
want to know about typing, what is touch
typing? Is it actually good for you?
Like some people will say touch typing
actually creates hand pain, which is
false.
Uh
and there we mentioned, you know, toys
for your hands
if you have hand pain, okay?
Okay, so far so good. Now, we talked for
40 minutes. Um
My man, 1994 is 30 years old ago. Yeah,
I'm I'm I'm close to 60, my friend.
So, 1994, when I was like 23 or
something.
Uh
20, I was like 20 or something.
Okay, so so
yeah, I'm showing, you know, so then
typing, okay, so you got this um
everything related to typing and
repetitive strain injury, then you got
everything related to using the mouse.
How should you hold the mouse to avoid
pain? How can you adjust mouse speed?
Things like that.
Okay. Uh then you know, and mouse drag,
you know,
like Apple created kind of popularized
the idea of using the mouse to drag. For
example, you can select, you know, I
have the mouse here, can you see my
mouse? No. So, you got to switch, you
see?
You can drag with the mouse.
Okay, so who who who created this idea?
So, this user interface, is it good or
bad? Does it
f- create hand pain or not? What is the
alternative design? So, this article
talk about that. Ban mouse drag. In my
opinion, it should be banned, okay?
So, go back. So, this is all about
mouse, using the mouse, and then you got
everything you need to know to configure
your keyboard shortcuts. So, you got
Microsoft Windows, you got PowerToys,
you know, I recommended, okay?
PowerToys. You got a entire tutorial of
AutoHotkey. So, if you are on Windows,
you know, you can uh install AutoHotkey
and read my tutorials. I show you what
it does and how to program it and how
to, for example, insert text. So, you
can press a key, it will insert insert,
you know, say today's date, you know,
which I have in Emacs, for example.
Press press press, you see?
Uh but I'm not using AutoHotkey, but but
I'm I am using AutoHotkey, so AutoHotkey
AutoHotkey for you can see my
configuration for AutoHotkey, which one
of them is this uh
toggle maximize window, okay? For
example, I can press a key, it becomes
full screen, not full screen, but
maximize window. Press it again,
it becomes original, you see? Press
press press press, it toggles.
Without AutoHotkey
by default on Windows, you cannot do
that, okay?
But but instead you have going to full
screen, which is different from maximize
window. Full screen is not good, okay?
So,
so about AutoHotkey so, back to
everything you want to know about
Windows. So, here then here is complete
list of
Windows key binding. I mean, what they
call Windows keyboard shortcuts.
That's what they call it
on Windows.
On Linux, they call it key binding,
okay? This tech techno nerds detail. So,
that's interesting. As a human animal,
what is the proper terminology
for keyboard shortcuts? Should it be key
binding or should it be like keyboard
shortcuts? You know, you can dive into
that. Then the proper proper subject
matter would be in the field of
linguistics.
And uh linguistics and terminology, the
science of terminology analysis and so
on.
Okay. So, keyboard shortcuts, everything
you want to know, and of course there's
not just, you know, then there's uh Win-
uh specific to Windows key, this Windows
logo key.
Uh and several others, screenshot
keyboard shortcuts, you know, and then
file explorer shortcuts, you know,
so this page is all about Windows. Now,
go back. Now, there's Linux. Now,
there's uh Linux is more complex. You
have like 20 pages about it.
LXDE keys.
And Linux keyboard software guide, you
know, like
pretty much complete, okay? But I
haven't worked on this for for four five
or more years.
And how do you swap control and alt on
Linux? That's how you do it. That's one
of the way, okay? And you know, so
everything you want to know
let's go back on Windows, on Linux or on
the Mac. So, on the Mac is actually
turns out the simplest and easiest and
the more more powerful, okay? On the
Mac, all you want to do is just when you
want to create your custom keyboards,
just install
just install uh what is the command?
Swap add create custom keyboard layout
layer, keyboard Mac keyboard software
guide.
Just install
uh this one, Karabiner Karabiner
Elements.
This software got renamed several times,
you know, in back in 2014 it's called
Key Remap for MacBook, okay? Then it got
renamed, then got renamed, you know,
So, I you know, I've been writing this
long ago, you know, for example, this
one is 2011 begin.
Uh so, not so, not just that, Karabiner,
then you got others. Then you got the
Mac's own system. So, anyway, this page
is all about keyboard shortcuts on the
Mac.
Okay, then you can go to Emacs, then
Emacs
this page is the table of contents to
all articles about Emacs key binding.
So, you got, you know, 20 30 pages.
Okay? So, then then next, you know,
everything about typewriters, you know,
this ancient, you see? Look at this
baroque Asian, beautiful design
uh of typewriters. Typewriter is the
granddaddy
of today's keyboard and also the reason
why
today's keyboard is so lousy, extremely,
because they came from mechanical
typewriters. They inherited the design.
It
we inherited the habit, basically.
So, even many of the habit doesn't apply
anymore because our keyboard is not
mechanical typewriters. But the habit
stuck.
Such as the shift key.
You know, on this mechanical keyboard,
you know, on this one, they don't even
have a shift shift key. But this one is
interesting because you see
they don't have a shift key, but you
have capital letters, then you have
lower-case letters. Each one is a key by
itself. You see?
But you can look at, you know, then you
got older designs like that. Then you
can see
shift key. They got a shift key here.
Do they have it? No. No. No, not not
yet.
But this one
I think this No. Okay, so you know, you
got funky designs.
But sometimes, you know, they started to
have a shift key, okay?
So, why shift key? Why do you have to
hold it hold the shift?
Then press the letter key, then release
the letter,
then release the shift. Why is it that
way? Why can't you just press shift and
press the letter?
Well, that's because shift key on
mechanical keyboards back then,
when you you have to hold it down
because you you you press it down, it
shifts the gears. You see, it shift the
gears. Then you press the letter key,
you know, then different hammer jacks
it.
Then you have to release the shift and
then then the all the, you know,
mechanism when goes back. So, that that
is why it's called shift.
So, for for example, on this keyboard,
can you see shift? I think there is
there. Let's see big image.
I think that that's German. Is that
shift?
Um
you know, so that is why shift. That's
why you always like have to hold
something, but that's idiotic because
that applies to mechanical keyboards,
not today.
But you see, habit stuck.
You know, once you have computer
keyboards, you don't have to do that
anymore.
But however, people want to
they they they want to be able to they
they they actually want the, you know,
holding the shift then press the letter
then release the letter and then release
the shift because that's the way things
how things work. I mean, they they you
know, it's just a habit. If you design
something that's press shift and press
letter, they don't like it because God,
what the [ __ ] you created, you know?
It's un so un-intuitive.
You know, a lot of
things we are using today uh are because
of that habit.
Habit from long past. Okay?
So, that is why shift you have to hold
it then same thing with control, alt,
[ __ ] Okay, you shouldn't do that. So,
if we can throw away history,
in fact, we can do it today, you know,
Microsoft or or Apple or Linux, you
know, you you you just
key binding, you know, you don't have to
hold alt, you know, don't hold. Press
alt, press some key, you know, or press
control, press some of the key, you
know, holding is not good. Holding is
one of the
primary problem of creating hand stress,
okay? And also you can turn on sticky
keys, you know, to
sticky keys, okay? It's one of in one of
these articles, special keys, key
binding design, mouse,
programming program keys, you know.
So, I talk about sticky keys here.
Search for s t i c, you know, so I
recommended turn it on on Windows
and on Mac.
You can turn it on and on Linux, okay?
So, you don't have to hold the modifier
keys.
Then
Okay, so we talked about, you know, then
then of course there's a mouse, you
know, full mouse review.
Uh there's a trackball, you know, all
trackballs you
never seen before.
And uh do-it-yourself trackballs
and then trackball history.
Okay, then trackballs then then of
course there there is um
uh pen input, you know, I have right
here a pen input so you can see I can
click and I can open that Microsoft
Surface Book.
This was the notebook I used to walk
around and take notes.
So, close that.
Go to this directory. So, you see,
that's the notes I'm taking. That's the
things I need to work on.
Okay, we digressed so much to about
keyboard stuff as
um
Okay, no comments. No comments?
Pen input device, okay, then
knobs and dials. These are super useful,
in fact, necessary
if you do Photoshop or if you edit
videos a lot, you know, if that's your
profession.
Now, if your profession is a
is a illustrator,
of course, you need the pen input.
It's necessary for your job. And this
one, for example, this one Sony digital
paper, this is ink.
This is what's called digital ink,
e-ink.
Okay, someone showed me, he's a
mathematician.
Uh he's a he's a mathematician.
Thanks to CID.
Very expensive. So,
so if you are artist, of course, it's
necessary to get this one of the pen
devices. This This another one from
Emily. Wait, this this one from Jim
Jim's knee, another friend a friend in
China.
So, you got, you know, you can write on
it, which is what I very useful.
Uh but if you then if you edit videos or
Photoshop is your profession, then you
need these knobs and wheels.
Kind of necessary because they make your
work much more efficient.
You know, adjust select color, adjust
adjust whatever, you know, Photoshop
stuff.
Or video. For video editing, you need
this called shuttle jog wheel and
shuttle ring, okay?
Uh amazing, you know, you see you see.
Then but then
so that's knobs and wheels and of course
then you got joystick. Now, if you are
gamer, then this is necessary.
Uh then there's also eye visual control,
eye tracker, okay, which I never used
myself.
Uh then there's got a bunch of then
there's coding keyboard, so I was
talking about this
which I will use down the road. So, can
you see?
Uh yeah, this is a fantastic, okay?
Fantastic.
Uh
Which So, this came from the design of
this called DataHand.
And this is a precursor to the small
board. Then you got small board.
Then you got then then you got stenotype
machine. How does it work, you know, you
want to know.
Uh
Okay, so you know, so I got lots of
articles about them.
And here is my my keyboards.
Like right now I'm using that.
And here is my previous one. Kinesis 360
and also ultimate hacking keyboard.
And then So, this is my battle station.
Uh using ultimate hacking keyboard as my
main the version two. So, I got two of
them.
One is version one then the
I got version two.
Then before that is Kinesis
Advantage 2 keyboard that that.
So, I have lots of videos about them.
Then this is this are my other
keyboards.
Uh this one is a this one is called
Signum.
I think it's very interesting because
you got these flippers.
So, you see, these flippers
I got a keyboard somewhere, okay? The
flippers lets your thumb so you you can
you know, move your thumb and they
function as a key.
I think that is that is an innovation,
okay? But unfortunately, the guy who
sent me this,
he is expecting me to build it, you
know, like I'm, you know, using the what
is what's the software, you know, that
uh uh
uh you know, the these keyboard hackers,
they have, you know, you have to
configure you have to compile the
software.
I don't have time for that, you know, so
so this is by this guy
Troy Fletcher. He's on YouTube. You can
watch his video.
So, I never had time to
configure it. Uh so so I end up never
used it.
Okay, that's but that's I think this is
very interesting.
Uh
then another great person uh who sent me
this Kinesis
which I used for a year or two. Um very
interesting.
Okay, so lots of keyboards, okay?
But now, let's go back, okay? I want to
do some I I want to do some work.
Uh so go back. So Oh yeah, one this is
one of the article I wanted to show
earlier because someone is asking me
about why don't you use link uh Linux,
okay?
So, in 2009, I switched from Mac to
Windows.
Uh and here is my complete story why,
okay?
Then at the bottom is a brief history,
so 1990
1990 to 1991,
I was using DOS.
1992 to 2009, I was using Mac. So,
that's 17 years using Mac.
1999 to 2003, I was using Windows NT.
Okay, that was uh at work.
And 2009 to 2011, I was using Windows
for 3 years.
So, I wasn't I wasn't a Windows user.
I'm mostly Mac.
For my own home, used mostly Mac.
And you know, 17 years of Mac and 3
years of Windows.
Then from 2011 to 2017,
I was using Linux for 6 years.
Then back to Mac, then to Windows, okay?
So
but for my work, usually I'm on Unix,
you know, Solaris, uh so
so that is, you know
uh
one of the articles. So, this is my old
Mac computer. 20 years ago. 2009.
Okay, so let's see. That's about so you
can, you know, so there's also foot
pedal you can check out.
This is Kinesis foot pedal, very
expensive.
Um
and my other devices, for example, my
camera, this one is extremely lousy,
very popular.
Logitech C920, very bad.
Uh and this is great, fantastic portable
portable drive, Samsung.
And
uh this is my looking into hi-fi
speakers. They are expensive, like
$1,000 or something.
Uh
So, anyway, so that's some of the
things.
So, now I want to work on my I want to
work on this, okay? So, let's, you know,
let's let's go to it. Uh I want to work
on my
Or should I stop? Okay, so I want to
work my So, let's go to talk show.
Um so go to soft light keys. I need to
Now, I'm going to work on my stuff.
So, color all red. So, you see this
this
uh this
this illustration is SVG, okay? So,
let's go ahead make a backup.
Search for SVG. So, that's that part.
So, what I want to do here is I need to
color, you see
some of them are letter keys, some of
them are the commands. So, I want to
com- color the commands section, okay?
So
So, you know, so this is technical
detail. I'm just going to work on this.
So, you look at
my uh Emacs workflow, you know, the
power of Emacs.
Uh actually, I don't want that many
windows, so close this one.
Okay, so
what you're going to do is you So, this
is SVG. Now, if you don't know SVG
search for Kxsa SVG tutorial, so you can
learn from the ground up for beginners.
Basic examples, rectangles, line and uh
circle and how to create a clock.
Uh you know, so the code is here, 50
lines of code. You can have it.
So, that's SVG tutorial. So, but now,
what uh So, I want to make this color,
so okay.
Okay, so showing browser. Now, let's go
to this page tutorial. So, let's open
that. Okay. So, that's the same SVG, so
search for it, okay? Begin here and uh
I want to color them.
Uh so I need to look at how to color
SVG, okay? So, SVG
shape style, specifying style, okay? I
want shapes style.
Stroke, stroke line up,
uh uh
stroke fill. Uh okay, fill capacity.
Fill rule, so what is the color? So,
fill green
stroke blue, stroke width, okay? So
Let's try that.
So, what
How do I begin here? So
Okay, so the commands begin here, so we
can do something like
uh they style.
Uh
Yeah, annoying.
So, they are actually style, something
like that, okay? So
stroke width, we don't I don't want
stroke width.
The stroke default is none, okay? Value
is CSS color or none, so let's
Okay, cut that and and paste it that,
okay?
So, now we got that and let's just do
them all, okay? So
Replace that by
that.
Okay?
Do it. No, yes. Yes. Yes, yes, yes, yes,
yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
text
Wait, is it stroke or fill? Not sure.
Okay, so
showing browser.
Now, you see, okay?
Um
Okay, I don't want that. I want Let's
change something.
Okay, change that to fill.
Is it good? That's better, okay?
So, let's see.
So, color all red. So, um should it be
red or blue? Now, in order to answer
that, I need to double-check on
PowerShell toggle dark theme because
because
So, that's a PowerShell command you can
you can find on my website.
Okay, so it doesn't matter because
whenever you change color, you want to
make sure it works well in
white theme and dark theme. In our case,
it doesn't matter because the SVG is
white background, okay?
So
So, go back here. So, wait. Why don't we
Oh, not here. Okay. So, yeah, we changed
over there.
So,
let's leave it like that, okay?
So, let's see.
Okay. So, this one color or red, it's
done.
Delete it. This one command mode, remove
it. Okay.
So, because the command mode, that's
actually not
you know,
to change something to command mode
is
um
is usually the escape key, but escape
key is usually not there, okay?
So, remove that. That's done.
Delete. Next.
So, escape in GUI, okay? So, now that
that means
uh
so, C-like keys tutorial.
Uh what is that? Activate command. So,
that's not here. So, that's C-like keys.
Copy back to Emacs.
Open it.
Search for GUI entry. This is SVG. Let's
make a backup. Delete the SVG because
we're going to copy from the other.
Now, search for GUI.
Wait. Why is it not showing?
Oh, okay. So, activate. So, search for
activate.
Yeah. So, there's two of them.
So, right now you say activate command
mode.
Now,
dark theme is very annoying, okay? Dark
theme is bad for your eyes.
Okay, I think that's it. Uh activate
command mode insert mode. So, what is
this cursor? So, this is tutorial,
actually.
Yeah. So, search for activate.
Yeah. So, there.
Uh just copy that, paste it here, and uh
delete that, and we need escape.
Uh actually, that
uh-huh
search HTML key.
Tab UK, okay? Tab UK. Yeah, okay.
So, escape.
So, when in GUI Emacs, escape will do
this
command. Wait.
Uh did we
No. Wait.
I don't want to
show
cursor movement uh
activate. So, you have two keys to
activate command mode.
Okay, that's good.
Next.
Escape when in GUI. So,
delete that.
Next.
So, yeah. So, you want to capitalize the
first
uh
letter, okay? So,
so, that is in tutorial.
Search for H3.
Uh so, you need to search for H3, okay?
Search search
search capitalize search capitalize
search capitalize. Now, let's do a
keyboard macro, okay?
So,
keyboard macro search that H3
enter, then move the key, then
capitalize it. Then
then stop the keyboard macro, okay? Now,
let's just call keyboard macro. Do it.
Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it.
Do it.
Okay. So, undo that.
So, switch back. You can see
see where are the other H3.
Anyway, that that is done, okay?
So, capitalize the first letter, okay?
So, wait.
Yeah. So, what about H2?
List matching lines. They are good.
So far, so good. So good, okay.
List matching lines.
Okay. So,
H2.
Yeah.
H3.
That's good, okay.
Delete that.
Yeah.
That.
Go to talk show.
Not that.
Bookmark talk show.
There. Actually, go to XX directory.
Open that.
Uh let's open instead of in Emacs, let's
just open them in this
Oh, it's gone.
Refresh. Now, open them in this
this
um image viewer called iPhone view.
Okay, move by word, okay? So, let's So,
let's delete that. Delete that. To
tutorial. C-like tutorial. Search for
move.
Move by word. So, I need to
What is this? Try them.
Move that
up there, okay? Showing browser.
That's this sentence, okay?
Move by char. So,
then end. Move to begin end buffer,
okay? So, and let me explain this one.
So, you can see there's a header move to
begin end of buffer.
Now, I use a slash. That's a convention
in English. That means begin or end of a
buffer because, you know, you have two
commands. One to move to beginning of a
buffer and the other move to end of a
buffer.
But now,
so, this is about writing linguistics.
I think it's better if you say move to
beginning of a buffer.
Then then repeat move
or end of a buffer or
for example, or
end of buffer. So, you can
you know,
so, this I believe is better than that
even though it's
longer and verbose.
So, but you can just shorten it just to
move
to beginning of a buffer. So,
now I just I'll just use that, okay? So,
back to browser. So, you can see there.
And now, refresh.
Okay. And uh to be consistent, let's
lowercase this. Now, there's another uh
style issue. That is, do you want to
capitalize every word, or do you want to
capitalize
the words that are normally capitalized,
or do you want to simply capitalize only
the beginning of a sentence
when in a title? So, you have different
style guides for that.
So, normally I follow the cap like the
American style where you capitalize not
every word, but
like capitalize every word except words
that are
uh
you know, common like
uh you know, proverbs What what What are
those words? Proverb verbs and you know,
uh
like they are called grammatically
What are the words called for to and of?
Uh
adverbs or something. Anyway, they they
are kind of the English grammar words,
which is not significant. So, in
American convention writing style, they
do not capitalize those.
But another style is more systematic.
You simply capitalize every each and
every word in a title, okay?
And another style, which is more common
in Britain,
is that you you don't capitalize every
word. You only capitalize the first
word, just like a sentence, okay?
So, I kind of started to adopt these,
but
but not much. So, right now I'm using it
a bit for H3.
Uh but usually I cap capitalize all the
important words. But I think this
British way is actually better because
you know, because it's simpler.
Okay, so that's another detail. So,
okay, so what's the next thing you want
to change? Okay, move to beginning of
buffer.
Actually, you know, by convention it's
beginning.
Okay, that's another quirk of English.
You know, instead of beginning of
buffer, you have to say beginning of a
buffer.
Uh exactly why it's
kind of complicated. So, this is uh
grammar grammar and writing and style
issue.
Okay, so
uh close that kill that uh bracket text,
okay? So,
So, this should be changed to delete the
brackets
and
its inner text, okay? That's better.
That's the smart delete, a feature in
fly keys. For example, let me type it.
That is smart delete.
Parentheses,
a
feature of
let's say a nice feature, okay? Now,
move the cursor here. Now, look at the
pink window. If I press a key, it'll
delete the entire bracket tag text,
okay? So, for example,
if there's uh
white space on the left, you press the e
key like right here. You see, it removes
all the white space.
Now, if the character to the left of
cursor is a bracket, you press it, it
deletes the entire bracket.
You know, bracketed text, okay?
So, that is that is this
uh smart delete command. So, you can see
here.
You see, right there.
Okay, so now delete that that. Now, back
to my notes.
Okay, fixed. Next
uh spaces or blank lines, okay? Delete
char delete white space, okay? That
This is about smart shrink white space.
Okay, it's right here. So, this command
should be So, this is original and now
we're going to modify delete white
spaces.
Uh you know, I wanted to say delete
spaces or
blank
lines, okay?
Repeated call deletes
the other type.
Okay, now showing browser.
Search for shrink. So, you can see now
we have two versions of writing. So, one
description is delete white spaces.
Repeated call delete more white spaces,
okay?
That's kind of short.
Uh now, this version, the new version,
delete spaces or blank lines. Repeated
call deletes the other type.
Okay, so I think that is better.
So, let's remove the first version. So,
again, writing style technical writing
and style stuff.
Okay, so this one is done.
Uh yeah, so that then is there uh
redo key, okay? So,
no comment. So, let's go to two. So, is
there a key for redo? So,
in Emacs, redo undo is complicated. It's
different from other edit text editors.
I'm not going to explain. You can find
it on my article.
Uh just search for Emacs undo redo,
well. Then, but
about 5 years ago or so or maybe 10
years ago, Emacs started to have a
command called redo.
Um
So, let's see if there's a key for that.
Do I have it in fly keys? No, I don't
think so.
So, go to fly keys, go there.
These matching lines redo.
Oh, I do have it. So, I added a key. So,
that's a global control Y, okay?
Uh okay, so anyway, this this part I
need to think about because I might add
a key to fly keys, okay? Next text
selection shortcuts, okay? Should not
delete that header.
Uh mark and text selection, okay? Should
just delete that.
Delete uh add switch direction. Oh,
okay. Oh, yeah, okay. So, wait.
Undo undo.
Uh mark and text selection mark and text
selection.
So, that is you know, if you want to
select, you can press a key. Press,
okay? That's begin the mark. Then, move
cursor. You know, you can select to the
right or select to the left or by
paragraph. You know, by paragraph.
Uh so, that's how you select text, okay?
Cancel. Now, but
but what if, you know, let's say begin
here,
then you wait, begin, then you
let's say wait, let's say you begin
here. Begin.
Then, okay, then go down. Let's say then
you want to select
before this.
So, what you can do is you switch the
cursor position, you see? Call this, you
know,
then you can
like extend, okay? Then, you can switch
back and you can extend, you know,
switch back and extend.
So, this is fly keys.
Now, I'm in HTML mode. So, if I want to
select the whole section, actually, I
can just press a key.
Do that does it.
So, it's even more efficient.
But anyway, so this is you know, this
page is a tutorial for fly keys covering
the basics. So, I need to talk about
Yeah, so and then let's add that.
Um
So, this is how you select
and
and this should be select all, okay?
Select all.
And this is a command and that key right
now is uh that, okay?
Uh that's that's space O, okay? Space
O, so
tap UK to mark it to HTML, okay? Space O
what it does is it does this command and
what that command do is
uh
swap
selection
and position.
Something like that. Now, Emacs uses its
own technical jargon. So, describe key
Emacs will say exchange point and mark.
You know, point in Emacs is a technical
jargon to mean cursor position.
Okay, but Emacs call it point. So, for
most other people, like people since 19
1990s, they have no idea what the [ __ ]
is a point.
But Emacs refuse to adopt to modern
jargons, modern terminologies. Emacs
stick with point. You know, instead of
cursor position, Emacs say point.
Okay, so that is part of the reason
makes Emacs hard to use for a lot of
people because you have to learn oh, you
know,
you have to learn new jargons
everywhere. Like
like Emacs doesn't call it copy paste
clipboard.
What Emacs call it copy is
uh yank.
I mean, copy is um
uh is
um
paste is yank. Copy is kill, okay? Copy
is kill, paste is yank and uh
cursor is point, you know? So, it's very
annoying.
Anyway, so let's let's just say that,
okay? So, selection, so there is we
added that.
Uh better wording is swap
cursor
move cursor
to the
other end of selection, okay? That is
easier to understand.
That characterizes my tutorials for
programming languages.
Mark is something in the keyring.
Not keyring, that's called not no
register. Yeah, you are correct, but
mark is mark ring, okay? So
So we when we talking about this, then
you go to um
go to Emacs tutorial,
then go to
practical Emac Lisp, then there's a
section on mark region active region,
you know, Emacs own jargon.
Mark is basically the start of the
selection.
Region
you know, normally we say selection. In
Emacs, they call it region.
And then you have active region because
for histor- historical reas- reasons,
Emacs doesn't have
the region is not always active. So, I
mean, in in modern text editor,
you know, let's say
simple text, you know, uh notepad,
you know, you have a selection, you
know, you just click and select.
But Emacs doesn't have that. So,
so instead because Emacs is like 10
years before you have like selection
before Apple.
So, Emacs, you have mark instead. Mark
to cursor point.
But but but the selection intuitive
beginning in the 1990s with the
Macintosh, you know, Mac Apple.
It it highlight the text.
You see? But Emacs cannot do that. Emacs
don't know what you know, Emacs doesn't
have highlighting until year 2000
something.
But
you see, but people like this highlight,
you know, it makes sense. You want to
highlight something when you select it,
right? So, Emacs later on added it.
And Emacs calls that
uh Emacs called very idiotic name,
transient mark mode, okay? Let's search.
There.
So, so the highlighting, you know, the
when you select something, it highlights
it.
That is beyond Emacs. That that is like
10 years after Emacs have have this
text selection. So, Emacs adds that.
They call it transient mark mode, okay?
Idio- idiotic name.
It began it was introduced in 1994
because by 1994, Apple introduced it.
Then Microsoft copied it in Windows, you
know, 3.0 or something.
So, everyone is used to it.
But the Emacs oh Jesus, we don't have we
don't have it. So, what can we do? Let's
you know, so they instead you know, so
they
retro feed and retro fit and they have
it, you know, they call it transient
mark mode.
So, that means when when you have this
mode on, that means when you make a
selection, it actually highlight.
Otherwise, it doesn't highlight, okay?
So, that's kind of history.
So
So then, you know, then so then you have
the the concept of active region, you
know, so you have region
which is which means selection, but once
you add the color to highlight it, then
you have the new concept of uh called
active region, you know.
Then but Emacs mark is very powerful,
you know, because Emacs is actually you
know, more powerful than most text
editors. So, they So, when you have a
mark, you can have actually a history of
marks just like a history of a copy.
Even today, Apple doesn't have history
of copy. You have to install external uh
applications.
On Windows, you do. You just press uh
Windows key V, then you can copy
previous
or paste previous.
I mean, paste previous.
So, anyway.
So, mark ring, yeah, mark ring. Mark
ring is what you were saying. So, you
can actually So, you can like jump to
previous, for example.
Uh shift Y, jump to previous marked
position, you see?
Now, I'm moving my cursor to to all the
positions I've
I've marked before in this buffer, okay?
Anyway.
So, I think that's it for today. So, I
got a few more things to do. Uh as
switch direction, so I'm you know,
working on my select all.
So, I'm working on updating my tutorial
on copy and do select such text select
all there, okay? Then what's next?
Switch direction, we did that.
Okay, then
add B, okay? So, let's do this one.
Search forward.
So
I want to add
a new command to soft like keys. So,
let's go to the source code.
Let's say search. Let's say
uh s- I search, okay?
I want to create a new key
uh
I wait.
Search
forward, okay?
Yeah, I want to create a new key for
search.
Okay? So, the new key will be
capital B.
And this will be search backward.
Okay, now this will be new, okay?
So, before that, I don't have a search
backward. You know, if you want to
search something backward, let's say,
you know, let's say
let's say search this, okay? You just
search forward, then press right arrow
to go forward next next next next next
next next or press left arrow to go
backward previous previous previous, you
see?
So, but now
so I don't have So, if if you want to
search something before, you just search
you know, then you just search it,
then press the left arrow to go to
previous.
But now, if I add this uh you don't need
the parent. If I add this, that means I
can directly search backward by pressing
capital B, okay? Now, evaluate the
buffer.
It's done. Now, press
shift B.
Uh wait, okay. So, so you is you still
requires you to um
Wait, so what if I have this selected?
Shift B.
Uh okay. So, I don't think I want to add
that.
Because because it doesn't
it doesn't save you keystrokes because
when you you know, if I press shift B,
it prompts you to search backward.
Uh
and it doesn't save you keys.
Not much.
Anyway, let's leave it, okay? So,
now if you go to the directory,
now Eshell start Eshell.
So, this is what I do, you know, I'm
showing you my workflow working on my
packages, okay? So, go to Eshell, then
just say git status.
So, you can see soft like keys has been
changed.
Open it.
Uh call Z VC diff. So, you can see the
difference we did. You see, we added
that.
Now, close it.
Now, if I want to commit, then I just
say uh git add, then git commit, okay?
So, I'm showing you kind of showing my
workflow.
Uh what do I think about modern editors?
VS Code and Zed.
I don't know about Zed. I haven't used
it, but VS Code
is pretty good. I mean, it's easy you
know, it's you don't have to spend much
time to learn.
Uh
Emacs, you have to spend because Emacs,
they they intentionally
make it hard to learn because they are
like, you know, they they are so-called,
you know, gatekeepers, you know, they
are the they are the real guys, you
know, the we are the GNU.
So, they Emacs has
kind of has a lot of elements that's
intentionally hard to learn. You know,
they don't want
they don't want anyone to easy adopt it,
but they refuse to believe that.
Meanwhile, you know, on one hand, they
really want, you know, please use Emacs.
We are the most powerful. Please, you
know, all new people all, you know, if
you don't know computer, you can still
use Emacs because, you know, they they
try to say that. But meanwhile,
when when it comes to Emacs jargon, they
refuse to change. For example, in the
documentation, they refuse to change,
you know, the terminology paste
from yank, you know, they
they can easily change that, you know,
they actually can change that.
So, it becomes easier to learn, but they
refuse.
This [ __ ] Emacs people.
But so, VS Code,
you know, is much much more modern, you
know, it was created 10 years ago, so
you can use
But the problem is you see, but they are
but the problem is my VS code is from
the giant deep state corporation
Microsoft.
You know, if you don't know, you follow
my Twitter, you will see some you know,
like half of the time I talk about
politics. Microsoft is a very deep
state.
They they don't really care about what
you know, what what's good the software.
They they really just care about money
and and heavy censorship, you know, very
deep state.
You know, grab your information whenever
possible, whatever, you know.
So, but anyway
if we go just to back to the technical
issues, you can see here's Visual
Studio.
I got just one file open, you know,
maybe two, you know, because this
release notes is automatic.
Let's close release notes. You know, one
single file.
And it's using
600 641
megabytes of RAM.
Okay? You can see that VS code
one single file
I don't have any extensions. I don't
have nothing installed. One single file.
megabytes.
Now, let's see Emacs, you know, all the
things we've been doing including
including you know
including viewing um
and see where I talk show
talk show XX including let's say you
know, opening image files.
Let's go to let's see Emacs. There it is
Emacs.
God, shift it again.
There.
79 megabytes. Can you see that?
Emacs
80 megabyte memory usage.
VS code one single file.
Now, it's like 430 megabytes. That's the
difference, okay?
VS code easy to use. Yeah, you can you
know, easy to use, fairly powerful. You
can integration with PowerShell and so
on.
Yeah, but this is
10 times
20 that's 20 times more memory use.
That's only one you know, if you
actually if I actually work in VS code
you know, I have to open tens of files,
you know, I can you know Right now in
Emacs I'm running a shell
you know, I'm I'm
you know, I'm running lots of things. I
can run Emacs this you know, lots of
image files.
40 megabyte.
Uh 80 megabyte. But in VS code, you
know, 400 500 megabyte. That's a that's
a difference.
This difference will not go away.
Okay? There are many reasons. Well, but
the the most fundamental reason is that
VS code is for Microsoft from a huge
giant corporation.
They got programmers come and go. The
programmers don't give a [ __ ] The
programmers who work at corporation huge
corporation, they come in they just care
about their pay. Every month they got a
lot money, a lot, you know
each month they get
what they get is like my my 10 years
income.
You know, I was very poor.
One month
what they get like $10,000 is equal to
10 years $10,000. That's what I get.
Okay, so but anyway, so they don't care
about the code, so you know, that's what
that's what this big corporation product
are like. That is why that is the
fundamental reason
VS code is you know, 500 mega megabyte
and lots of others efficiency and
others, okay?
But Emacs is from the dedicated hardcore
coders like me.
We created it
with a passion for coding. So, that's
different.
Now, there are problem with open source
too, you know, with the Emacs. For
example, they refuse to make it easier.
They refuse to change terminology like
they refuse to change the yank
terminology cryptic to paste, you know,
because they are proud. We are yank
because we invented it first before you
have copy in you know
in in in Windows or
Apple. You know, so they they got
problems and they got this extremely
difficult to use key binding that
creates the most
uh repetitive strain injury hand injury
in among programmers, okay? Emacs is the
number one editor that is the most
responsible for creating the most hand
damages around the world.
And they refuse to change it.
You know, because they are like they
think oh we we are the first you know,
you have to learn our way. The [ __ ]
in my opinion, okay?
Anyway, so that's pros and cons, you
know, that's you know, just like just
like when you use Windows Microsoft
Windows or Linux. Kind of similar.
You know, Windows you got deep state
watching behind you. They get your
information and so on. But at least it
you know, I can use it.
On on Linux, oh Jesus, you got to dive
into kernels. If you don't know what a
kernel is, [ __ ] you.
That's a Linux [ __ ]
You know, they they sneer people who
don't know tech technology are smart as
they are. That's what Linux people
[ __ ] are.
And they today also collaborated like
very much integrated with deep state.
It's just that you don't know it. You
know, you think oh Linux is freedom.
It's you know, security privacy. No
government can control. Actually, that's
not true. Linux has been deeply
you know
penetrated by deep state since like 10
years ago.
Okay? You know, sometimes I got like
fanatics, you know, open source fanatics
telling me "Xah, why don't you use
Linux?" These idiots.
Okay, I think that's it. I think I
talked for 2 hours. Is that right?
Today is like 2 hours, right? Is that
right?
1 hour and 40 minutes, okay? That's it.
So, I got lots of other things to do,
okay? So, let's do a few more.
Uh about other questions next time.
About using Copilot
I myself don't use it. Well, I sometimes
do as well, but I don't
I don't like the idea of integrated like
as you code, you know, pop up tips how
you code this, you know, I don't like
that.
And uh
it's it's progressing very rapidly. So,
I don't know where it's going to go.
You know, maybe one day everybody is
every coder
but not today. Today is like they have a
big way to go.
The AI generated code. They be
you know, it's very fast changing thing.
So, you can't say today next month it
will be different. So
you know, we can't
we don't know what to say yet, you know,
the AI powered coding assistant
so-called.
So, anyway, let's go back to tutorial.
So, there's a few more things I want to
write. There's no key.
Okay, so there
so
uh actually we just added
uh search
search text.
Q T N, okay? So, search text search
forward.
And now we have a search backward.
Okay, so that would be capital N.
Uh search
backward, okay?
We just added that.
And then remove this comment about
there's no key beginning search
backward, okay?
Okay, so this part is done. We just
added a new one delete.
And this part is easy. Needs a period
after each of those, okay? So
uh so
actually add the period. So, go to the
beginning, make a backup
do find replace that and uh add the
period, okay? That
do it
Okay, I don't like this cut off, so why
don't we expand it?
Do it
do it
do it do it
do it do it do it. There's a
capitalization inconsistency.
So, I need to fix that.
Do it
do it
All right.
Do it.
Do it. Do it.
Do it. Do it. Do it.
Do it.
Wait.
Yeah.
No.
No. Okay.
Now
Now where is my
Where is Where is my Firefox? Yeah.
So now you can see there's no period
behind you know, right after the red
words. Now refresh.
Refresh. Now you got a period.
Fantastic.
Okay, delete. Okay, that's it. Bye guys.
Close it.
If you like my stuff again, I need to
mention this.
Go to my homepage, xahlee.info.
Uh xahlee.info. You can buy my Emacs
tutorial.
Uh
and you can you know, Patreon me, Amazon
gift card me, PayPal me. If you have a
job, pay me $100, okay?
Bye guys.