hello guys welcome to another episode of
sun talk show today is 2020
august 25th 25th
tuesday 8 o'clock in the morning san
francisco time
and today we are going to talk about
emacs i'm going to give you a live
reaction
of using tree max
and speed bar which is some kind of
directory
uh showing directory tree structure
so today's background image is this one
this
space cadet keyboard now space
connect keyboard is one of the most it
is the most
famous this keyboard partly because
the fantastic name space cadet and it's
from
symbolics very um
memorable name symbolics that's back in
the lisp
when lisp was ruling ruling the word the
computing world in the 1980s late 1980s
well over the whole 1980s
so there are several there are quite
actually several versions of the space
cadet keyword you see
you can see there is this uh lambda
machine
at least from machine very expensive
tens of thousand dollars back then
and this uh you know there's quite a lot
of interesting things about the space
cadet keyboard you can see
many you can see for example the hyper
super
meta control keys and the greek
keys front top you know you got like
six or seven modifier keys then you have
you have the roman numeral sign and you
have the apl symbols on the keycaps
you see the let me show you here apl
symbols
you see apl
is stand for a programming language
and it is a programming language very
interesting
that language is what you call a array
based
what they call array language array
programming
and similar to them in the same category
are mathematica and matlab
see you know those are array languages
those are wonderful
basically what that means is that those
languages
you know typically in perl python java
javascript
you have the map function right you map
a function to a list
so you have to say map you know to a
list in array languages you don't have
to say map you just
when you apply a function to a list it
automatically maps
so it's it's almost all your data
you know normally in pro python ruby and
so on you apply a function to a number
you know to one argument but in these
array languages you
that argument the variable you know the
values are almost always a list or
matrix or a tree or next basically a
nested
so every function works on a list
and it basically applies to every
element in a list
i have a lot articles on that we can
talk about that another day so
anyway so that's a background image the
the the space cadet
keyboard okay let's talk about let's
talk about today's topic today's topic
is gonna be
i'm going to explore
in real time my reaction you're going to
see my reaction of
my you know using these packages tree
so let's magnify let's go to so here is
my talk show page
and that is today's video let's comment
out
showing browser so
we're gonna do
okay so we're gonna do speed bar okay so
speed bar you know you know you know
what is the speed bar so
this is my the ad diet you know you see
this is what i'm used to in in diet i
can copy i can i can mark
i can for example let's see split window
create a new directory hold on a second
i want to show you
again let's not i want to show you the
pink window on the pink window you can
see all the commands i call
on the pink window and their keys okay
so for example i'm
i can mark a directory that's m i can
unmark them all let's say split the
window
and create a new directory xxx let's say
for example so
there it is a new directory and i enter
to go into it and i can mark mark mark
let's say i want to remove these four
files
into that directory so i press capital r
it asks you do you want to do it yes you
see
so i just removed i just created a
new directory and removed four files
there
and i can remove them back i can delete
and so on
so i'm used to you know i'm direct is
uh supremely powerful so for example now
this directory xxx
is now empty i want to delete it just do
it
uh you know then we are back to where we
are
now close that diet showing browser so
this is my talk show page
so diet you know i you know go to search
for xally
uh uh emacs tutorial diet i have a
chapter
as a page on that now but
the one of the problem is that well
another problem
exactly is that you you sometimes you
want to see a tree
you know directory tree for example on
linux you have this tree command
i don't think it's available on the mac
let's see which
tree yeah let's go to my linux
page okay actually not
let's go to linux website showing
browser
so you have this the tree command
so what is it app sudo apt get install
tree yeah
that's the name so you see it shows you
sometimes you want to see the directory
as a tree but in emacs you don't have
that
uh it's not building you have to install
a package
but there's something similar there's
something similar called spacebar
uh okay speed bar not spacebar close
close
hold on second let's see
speed bar let's see if that
we get it right let's see
so describe function speed bar there it
is
so it's there this speed body is built
in let's see
let's see what it says speed body is an
alias for speed by
frame mod okay yeah yeah yeah uh
so probably introduced okay so it says
probably introduced at or before
emacs version 20.3 you know starting in
in the past few years starting in 2015
emacs documentation they began to add
for every command they began to say when
is this command introduced so you see
but but many of these commands are
pretty old speed bar you know speed bar
is pretty old like i think
back in 1999 it was there so
so they now say you know they tried to
find out
when was this command introduced then so
now
it says probably introduced at ob4 emax
version 20.3
so then it says enable disable speed bar
okay
yeah okay okay let's try this it's like
what it is
it's uh meta x speed bar
let's see if i like it okay so there we
have it a bar you know a
speed bar i don't use it okay so i
actually never used it
so let's adjust let's give it some room
to
breath
okay so it uh let's let's magnify so it
let's see what happened if you click on
it
so let's move cruiser to there and
click on it oh it opens that page
okay back to the cursor
open it now
now when i open another one does it
close
the one before let's see intro to cobo
open it okay now
back to the spacebar speed bar
let's see open topic notes okay
now you can see the topic notes becomes
highlighted let's magnify
okay the topic notes becomes highlighted
but i wonder if it when you hit
enter on one of these items in a
directory does it
oh does it close the previous one you
entered
i'm not sure let's find out so back to
the emacs window
let's do this command so what is this
command
that command is i buffer okay i buffer
is
a way to list all buffers
okay so okay so it doesn't close you see
now you can see uh the eye buffer here
is the list of all my buffers
open so i go to the space to the speed
bar again
and open it okay close that
refresh uh let's can we mark
let's see let's try no you cannot mock
so open another one back to sp uh
speed bar open another one
open another one open another one open
okay and it's
open a lot okay so we seems to have
opened
quite a few files now let's go to
ibuffer
refresh
uh did we open okay let's try open
another one
i buffer refresh wait
let's open another one let's open a
bunch more
open open open
now go to i buffer again
yeah they all stay open
so that's speed bar it seems to work
what what else let's see let's click the
plus sign
that's supposed to open the subdirectory
okay what is that
yeah because there is no you see
all these are files these are not
directories so you move the cursor to
the plus sign
you can what
oh you don't want this that's a mac
thing
so you you move the cursor to one of
those
uh plus sign and enter
oh that doesn't work so
okay so at this point we look at speed
but
that you know that seems it that's what
it does
but but now i want to know
what are some other features of speed
bot
you know i'm trying to learn so let's
see if there's any
uh special menu for the speed bar
it doesn't looks like it oh there it is
so there is a
menu for speed bar you know a graphical
menu is one of the quickest way to learn
useful commands so you look at the menu
it says update
auto update okay uh use images
uh no i don't want to use images let's
try it
yeah i don't want stupid images
you see the images they just um
yeah not good
okay not don't use images but the button
doesn't
the but the click okay so now it's
updated
so use images then edit item online
return oh so you can edit
normally a return will open the file so
but you can make it edit instead
show files expand file tags flash cache
expand or descendants okay so we
so we gotta try these expand all
descendants so we we're gonna try to
find a directory that
that has a lot subdirectories then try
expand all descendants
file tag information i'm not sure what
that is
copy file rename or you can also copy
rename okay
displays quick buffer so you have to you
know
so i guess you have to learn how to use
it
so okay let's check
where are we lots of comments good
morning guys good morning to
united kingdom el cook
and good morning to russia green deck
uh good morning to uh dr uh hope
so let's see what's going on uh
anthony's
sofia hi uh i'm in san francisco
yes california time good morning bought
to
germany and how this keyboard looks yes
space cadet
and julie hi there it's jkl
hi there h j k l that's a
veeam user good morning alan to
california
what about vim what about veeam sucks
okay what
is that what you want to ask me green
sucks donkey s
okay so okay so we have tried space
you know that's my that's my reaction to
the speed bar
not not not useful to me just so far i
don't see
any i don't see how i don't find
it's that useful i just go to diet you
know i have the big window showing the
whole thing
i have all i need i don't need another
like frame or window to switch to and
look at
but but one thing i want is to show the
tree directory
uh tree structure
that is when you have uh like typically
npm
json you know npm you know the
javascript when you do dev on javascript
you have a directory with
other structure okay so i need to go to
[Music]
some directory with lots of nesting i
don't think i have such
um let's go to
keyboard okay let's go to the directory
yeah i don't have lots of nesting let's
delete those files you see
another let me show you another
fantastic
usage of emacs so you can see i have
this directory lots of files right
let's try this uh visible let's
what's this what what is visible mod
i don't know what is visible mod so i
just tried
a visible mod let's describe function
and see
oh toggle marking toggle making or
invisible text temporary temporarily
visible yeah
i don't know what that is i don't care
so i want to
direct hide details mod you see in
in diode you can hide all those
permissions that can
those came from unix so you can see so
i'm in a
directory so this is my current
directory you see on keyboards
so i have 800 files
and you can see some of these files are
emacs
backup files you see they by
convention emacs backup files the file
name ends in a tioda
so i want to begin delete them all so
you can press a key
that marks you can see the mini buffer
says 45 backup files
flagged you see all these are flagged
and
now i press x and it shows all these
smart files do i want to delete them yes
fantastic you see you never go to
a shell again so for example if you want
to do this in shell
the command would be remove
and idiotic i guess that
that but you are not sure because you
don't see it visually
you might you might have uh typed
something wrong and that deleted
your entire directory
so anyway so that's tired let's yeah so
there's one more thing we need to find
out
about how do you
can speed bar show the nested structure
okay let's create one on the fly okay
let's create a nested structure on the
fly
okay so what we're gonna do so far so
good
comments we're gonna we're gonna create
a um meta xh
spacebar speed bar
it's showing browser we're gonna create
a nested structure
on the fly and meanwhile that also shows
the power
of emacs okay so go to a directory
well actually you can do it so in so
many ways but let's just do it
the simple way uh okay
uh magnify uh
height i don't want uh what what's the
key for high detail smart
is there a key oh left paren
left paren is high detail smart great
so now i'm going to create a directory
split the buffer
create x1 okay
now there it is the directory go into it
create x one one
okay create directory x12
creator three one x one three
create uh what wait wait what's going on
what did you say
i didn't wait let's try again
create x13 okay
and uh let's say let's create one more
let's say create struct
you know one of those npm thing you know
they have those name
create one named lib
okay just show the directories now let's
go to
lib okay now create another
directory let's say x21
okay create another directory let's say
x22 okay then go into x22
then create the file
open a new buffer same thing okay save
as
save something let's say save as x
2 to underscore one dot
text okay so go back to the directory
again
magnify you can see your file here
so go up a directory go up a directory
go up a directory uh so we got this
bunch of directories go up one more
yeah yeah so we are here we are here x1
open it so that's uh you know the
problem now is that we want to show the
tree structure
so can can speed bar do it now that's
the test
now we're back to uh the speed bar
buffer
how do i how do i
um how do i tell
speed bar to um wait what is this
how do i tell speed bar to open oh you
just press enter oh
okay it's it's showing all my
directories
privacy concerns
uh cancel so what
so how does speed bar automatically
it seems is trying to automatically
show directories i don't know uh
okay so right now we actually need to
read some documentation of speed bar
actually so wait before we do that let's
just go to the speed bar
uh let's go where do we want to go i
don't want to
i want to be careful here
okay can we where is the speed bar menu
you know e-max menu is problematic it
doesn't it's supposed to show the speed
bar menu
we saw it before but now it's not
showing
so far so good so far so good
glad finally get to see live stream okay
i think that's
you know maybe we need to go to the tree
mod
you know that's uh how long have have i
been talking 22 minutes we need to go to
the tree mod because that's actually
anyway let's find out space mod okay so
speed bar okay let's describe function
speed bar
let's let's quickly uh find the
documentation okay so here are the
all commands for speed bar
speed bar frame mod okay let's open that
i want what i want to do is quickly to
find out how
is it possible to use this uh speed bar
to view the structure of a directory
like a tree
so a near speed bar mod will be
displayed okay
only one speed bar is supported at the
time okay so let's go to speed bar
documentation so here is the full
inline documentation so major mod for
managing display of directories
and the tags now what what is the tag i
don't know
so the first line the first time i
represent default directory of this vr
frame
each directory the each uh each
directory segment is a
button which jumps speed bots default
directly to that directory and so on so
each line is starting that so each line
starting with a plus sign represents the
directory uh click on that
to insert a directory listing into the
current tree okay
click on the and click on minus to
retract it okay so
so yes i think it does
so i first of all i want to find out how
do you use
speed bar to open a specific directory
that's the thing that user wants to do
the most
because right now the speed bar is
showing my home directory
i don't want to uh i don't want it to
show my own home directory i wanted to
so where is there a command let's see
speed bar
i don't know i i didn't see it okay so
let's go to my directory
right now this directory let's call
speed bar again let's see
what does does it do speed bar
i guess that turns it off let's call it
again
okay it turns it back on
but the directory didn't change
let's call speed bar again speed bar
speed bar
what why is it uh okay let's show
let's go to i buffer let's go to all my
buffers and
okay so now yeah let me show you some
other thing okay now so i have so many
files opened
you know i don't want this usually i try
to use
my style of using emacs is that i always
try to close files i don't need
i used to most people most people who
use
emacs it's very common to have hundreds
of buffer open
because once you open you don't you
don't close them you know you have
hundreds of them i used to do that too
for 10 plus years so every time
you know it is o there are a few hundred
buffers open but
but now i always do a clean um
so i want to remove those buffers i mean
i mean close them not remove
not delete
so what are these uh make download copy
okay
keo buffer
load dev uh this file always opens by
mistake
wait okay so you open this file oh i see
what it's
okay now
now we bumped into the feature we are we
were looking for
so basically when you open the file
basically when you open the file
then the speed bar will update it so
let's try it
let's open this file there it is
okay so you when you open a file this
the speed bar will update to that file
so so that means let's go up to a
directory up go up
that means let's create a file in this
directory okay so
this is the root of the directory we
want to see the tree so
split the buffer create a new buffer
same thing okay
save it xxx
let's for change yyyy dot txt
okay back to the diet and you can see we
created
a file here so let's open it
there it is look at check out the speed
bar you see
now it shows the um
now it shows okay so i'm not sure
let's see
oh uh oops
so open that again
so how do i expand them all i forgot
let's go back to the speed bar
um describe function
speed bar mod
wait describe function
so we we see the documentation again
now now i want to find a command that
expands
the entire tree okay
refresh next previous speed bar toggle
updates
speed bar power click
d frame any comments questions
cure some buffer and keep one uh
pressing y
for 10 seconds oh that that can work
i don't usually use kill some buffer
that command
so let's see speed bar
expand speedball toggle updates
okay speed bump ma took
so anyone uses speed bar
so i don't see any command to expand all
you see what i what we want is to expand
all the directories so we can see their
structure
okay and we don't see it in this inline
documentation for
speed mod neither so what can we do well
let's there's a command okay this
command
let me show you you can call this
command which is
called there is a command called
a propose command here okay
uh magnify a proposed command so you
call that command
okay let's call it then we type speed
bar what it will do is we'll it will
list
all commands containing that name speed
bar
so there it is here's the result so here
is
all the commands containing the word
speed bar
and now we have to we found it you know
then you just search
expand you see expand line uh
so there are several commands expand
speed bar expand
line speed by expand line descendants
speed bar
is that is that it now let's
this matching lines expand
okay there are only three commands
containing the word expand
okay so let's look at one of them
let's look at this one so speed by
expand line
expand the line under cursor now that's
not
interesting idiotic i want to expand all
you know so so so far i don't see
the command you know i'm just going
around so this is
the typical way i go about learning emac
stuff
now of course the more proper
way is you start to read the manual
of the speed bar so for example
so let's try it let's try it okay so
ctrl
h i gets gets you to the info directory
of all the information docs now let's
just list maximize or just search for
speed bar there it is so there is a
manual
info manual dock for speed bar so you
click on that
okay so here is the documentation for
speed bar
introduction basic navigation file mod
buffer mod miner mods customer
customization
okay introduction basic navigation
summarizing files maybe maybe here
summarizing buffers
so let's go to file mark directory
display
open it
there are three major sections in the
display the first line or two is
is the root directory okay
yeah but just what is the command to
show all
okay so there is a link tag
hierarchy methods tag hierarchy methods
what the heck what the hell is this okay
okay that's customization
but all i want to do now is how do i how
do i
expand does any no does anyone know
anyone all you people say something
anyone
okay go up you know
uh so if you are a emacs user you should
be familiar with info mod
so right now i'm in the info mod info
mod is the
mod to view all the info files from the
the emacs documentation format so you
want to be familiar with the keys to
navigate
up up a level down a level next
next chapter previous chapter
and so on if you search i have a
tutorial on that
of course you just search excel emacs
info
doc so where is the
so let's go up basic navigation base
basic visuals okay let's do this a bit
more then we're gonna look at
the uh tree emacs
package
i don't know maybe let's just try
blindly let's
try to press the plus key
okay maybe i move here press the cross
key
okay
i i want to expand all what what
what's the command
oak mod no i don't think it's like oak
mod so in oak
mod it's uh shift tab so let's try shift
tab
now it doesn't do anything shift shift
no
shift tab doesn't do anything
so
i'm pretty sure it's there you know i'm
pretty sure
so info doc okay so
you see the space bar so we just
discovered
another feature the speed bar is not
just
for visualizing directories but it
also visualizes the info documentation
what does that mean because you know i
know well i know because of
experience you know for example when i
am looking at the info doc so what's the
info doc
info doc is a uh hold on a second
let me show you okay uh
where are we okay info dot let's go to
the info dot directory
so these are info documentations that
comes with emacs
uh you know this is the directory they
are in
and uh so let's do diode hide again
okay so so you see a bunch of info
documentations
now info files so each one of these
is info file and they are zipped by
default
so for example uh we can search for
lisp okay so we have this emacs this
info documentation by the way that is
900 pages
so this is huge but however they you see
they come in one single file
uh they come in one single file so for
example
let me open it okay so
um yeah that's not the way to do it
okay well i open the file so let me show
you okay i'm
i'm viewing the gz gzipped
file of the elise.info.gz
so by default when you open a gz file
emacs automatically unzip it
so that's why you can see you know you
can read it but however i want to put
this
in the info mod because right now it's
not
you know when it's in info mod you have
links you know you have previous chapter
uh next chapter up a directory you know
to the
table of contents and so on but now you
don't see it you are actually
you are actually seeing the raw uh
your file kind of so you know for
example all these are supposed to be
links on the left
so how do you get into an info mod um
you just call i think you just call info
okay meta x info
there it is so okay so
so but what i'm saying is that so this
is one single file info file
but but the speed bar you see
it is actually showing you
uh it it is actually showing you the
chapters
the sections of a you know
of the info file so it can not it can
visualize the
info file as well
okay so let's let's move on to the next
package the tree emacs package now now
speedpad
looks okay uh what i really want to
uh to use it for is to look at the
directory
structure then be able to navigate
easily
but so far we haven't found it i'm
pretty sure you know we've seen the
command before
but you know so you have to read the
dock
okay that's speedback it's called bar
again
to turn it off close the info
close the info we don't care about this
anymore close close
close okay back to our directory
back to our structure directory
i don't like you know so far my
experience i don't think i like speed
but
i i i rather prefer diet i want
the full um
uh i want to i i want for example let me
show you
diet okay actually yeah yeah well that
doesn't you see the one of the problem
with diode is that
it does not show you it doesn't show the
directory
as a tree like you you can show a
subdirectory but it will show
under you know you it will just append
it
under beneath it so it doesn't show them
as a tree
in theory actually i you know i think
it's not
difficult to to write a diet by yourself
you know you just
know emac listen write it and you can
you can make it do what you want
to show the directory structure
anyway let's move on to the tree emacs
okay let's move on to the tree e-max
okay so i'm gonna call the command these
packages
it's taking a while okay
magnify search for
tree e max wait
okay 3 3 max not 3
max 3 max
okay male part lsp lsp3 max wow
why does 3 max needs a lsp i'm not sure
there it is 3 max so so why does that
have so many
variations 3 max uh
now i'm not too clear exactly what tree
max do
i suppose it just show directory tree
so it says uh a tree
style file explorer package yeah okay so
let's
install that tree max okay
uh enter on it let's do it again okay
enter it asked me to install tab
install yes install it
there's a bug in emacs it doesn't
what emacs stuck
the screen became blank what the hell
okay
now it's back
so now it's um
now it's installed how do i know because
normally you would pop a message wait i
don't know what's going on so open a new
buffer
go to the messages buffer
and
so apparently it installed tree macs
and in fact oh my god so tree max is a
huge
package so the do you know why the
screen went blank
because it's doing uh compilation the
imac to this
compilation wow tree max is a
looks like it's a huge
package you see it generated all these
messages
okay that made me curious let's go
close this close this let's go to the
directory of tree max let's see
what the heck so emacs.d
helper go to this directory
magnify search for tree there it is
go into it oh my god
hide hide the details hide the
permissions
so it's got like 30 files
i didn't know 3 3 max is so huge
30 files okay how do i use it
i don't know so let's just let's just
try to call it
meta x 3 max
wait i want to do it at over here okay
so meta x
wait so let's switch the buffer to
to here so meta x 3 x
okay so what is this project root
oh so it's asking you to do a project
route
so tree max
is
okay anyway so let's just say okay just
say
there so what are you doing
open a file oh
oh pretty
tree max how pretty
let's switch directory oh okay
3 max directory 64 files
basically that means 32 files
okay let's try open them
okay tree max so far it's just like
speed
uh just like the speed um bar
okay i want to know who wrote 3 max
that's usually one of my concern i want
to check out who wrote it
so back to the directory uh okay let's
shrink
again let's go to the bottom
open this file and let's
okay there's one thing i don't like
about tree max
now you see it splits window vertically
but now you cannot unsplit it
you see it uh
you see when i try to unsplit it it says
no
no other windows to split so what does
that mean
is that when tree max splits your emax
frame
it's trying to do some kind of magic
it's not using the standard way to split
your window
so those are no good okay so
so you know the the power of emacs
is that you have a basic set of commands
that works everywhere
you know so you can use them any
anywhere but now
uh especially with you know these days
there are more and more packages that
kind of limits you you know
in their opinion because they you know
anyway i don't like this um
thing because now you have to learn a
special way
about how tree max i mean what what the
is this pen
for example let's go here okay let's
show all buffers
it's probably hidden okay in theory we
should
see the tree max pen in my buffer list
but i don't think we are seeing it
you see all these are three max files
but this buffer you know it normally
would show
as a special buffer like the purple one
you see messages
and you see messages and scratch
and shell command and compile log
you open compile log you can see
uh you you can see all the compilations
of the tree mag
that that was done before so anyway you
go back to the
buffer you go back to i buffer this
buffers close that
go back to i buffer so these are the
list of buffers
so you can see by convention
if a buffer name begins and ends with an
asterisk that means that buffer are
emacs generated so we have compile log
messages and scratch and shell command
but but you see now this thing
here on the side the tree max that is a
buffer
but it's not showing there so it's it's
hidden it's it's
doing some kind of magic that's not good
that's not the e-max way
anyway so okay so wait so who wrote
three max
shreemax is written by alexander miller
uh who is that i'm not sure who that is
let's see
magnify
okay and okay so it's using dash
crap i will not use tree max
i will not use any package that uses
dash
why because dash dash and f
and s you know there are a bunch of
these packages
these these are new generations written
by malene
young people you know they they are
trying to rewrite emac lists
basically they are wrappers to the core
emacs these
functions in their mind they think they
are
improving the emac list language
but in my mind in my opinion they are
they are just making things slow okay
you know they they are trying to write a
wrapper with a new name
kind of consistent name so they you know
it's no good okay it uses stash you know
so what is dash let's uh dash is for
let's look at some of the way
let me go to dash okay hold on second go
to dash
go to dash yeah dash is written
by this guy this is a fun guy
you know dash came about around
what 2012 yeah
no good uh
well this guy this guy has created he
you know he's the guy of the emacs rocks
you might have heard
he has written quite a few very useful
packages you know so he's a great
contributor to emacs
uh but i don't like the you know i don't
like
uh the dash i don't like the you know
this kind of thing he has
created but anyway he
he he is you know he has written quite a
few um
emacs useful emacs packages and also
he's
he on youtube he has an account called
emax rocks
and those emacs tutorials are very
excellent okay they are typically five
minutes very
very short and very condensed showing
you
uh power use of emacs
so anyway yeah so dash is dash is what
the uh dash is let's see
you see here here is what it is a
modern this api for emacs modern
this api my ass
you know if you want to improve emac
this not
you know it's not done by writing a
wrapper
where you just change the the you know
the list command you know function name
you change the function name and change
you know
reorder the arguments add uh some more
optional arguments
so that it's better no that's not how
you improve the emac this
language if you want really want to
improve the emacs this
language what you do is you you
you you make the gnu e max people change
emac list
that's the real improvement of emac
these two
in some cases you have to write c code
you know there are pers you know but the
way he does it you know the
this advantage is you know because of
dash
precisely because of a dash you know
because the gnu people they are
they are kind of halty they they don't
they don't they don't progress you know
they don't progress
if nothing happens they they just sit
there and you know they are the
gods you know they you cannot tell them
what to do
but until someone creates an alternative
and when the alternative is become very
popular then
that is when the gnu emacs people
started to oh we need to you know
improve it so that it's better than the
alternative
so one of the effect of dash is that the
dash
becomes hugely popular this modern you
know the
so-called modern lisp api dash becomes
hugely popular
then about five years ago then the gnu
emacs started to
say that oh oh look at dash they have so
many these
functions we don't have you know
sequencing functions
then the emac this group people started
to add them
to the gnu emacs call
uh that that happened about five years
ago
so if you go to my emac this tutorial
you'll see
uh you know just search for xd emax
these sequence functions us you'll find
them
so anyway that's digression about dash
so anyway three three max so tree max
requires um
you see i'm you know
you know all this work is great but
because i've been using
i've been coding emacs and using emacs
you know for 10
20 years so i don't
i mean even if they are great i don't
use them you know if i want something
like i want something i write my own
i can easily write my own
so anyway there is some report about how
saffly keys is not working on tree max
uh are you still here stathak
were you asking that it seems to work
for me
i don't see any commands that's not
working or something
okay i think that's it about that's
that's it today
that concludes today's exam talk show
any questions
type your comments now any questions
you know meanwhile let's try
you know before i was complaining how 3e
max the 3max does not use standard
buffer
because you cannot you know i like
normally you see
the power of the of the core basic
general powerful commands is very
powerful because i can install
any package in emacs i want and i can
just split window
however i want you know i can split
window however i want i can split
and i can close them however i want
you see that's the power of emacs i can
split them in
you know but now let's let me close this
one okay uh wait what's the key
uh yeah so you see but now
with the tree max this tree max
i cannot close that thing you know
i
like i i don't know what that is it
doesn't let me close like this you know
my
generate command to unsplit the window
it doesn't work what the
i have to learn i have to read the three
mag stock
what command to call you know what what
is that thing
so this that's no good okay i i tell you
that's not good
this is my personal opinion i mean
little personal opinion that
in always means you know this
is not a great package this is my
personal opinion about
about programming style about gui what
it should be
so anyway who is alex miller what else
has he written i think
okay so there are quite a few people
named alex
miller so alex miller emacs
so let's see oh so he's um
oh he's a ob wait
well something i don't know
tree max so there's a huge documentation
okay you can manage project easy
navigation
versatile file access understanding of
frames
finding a files and tags okay git
integration okay okay it's
certainly a fairly big
you know 32 file simple mouse interface
session persistence dashing good looks
dashing good looks i don't want dashing
good looks
i want ugly looks
okay yeah yeah yeah yeah
detailed feature list project and okay
so what else what else tree max
alexander miller hey hi hi alex
we should uh we should do a meet up
so company shell
okay so i guess three max
he has written that's the most popular
okay i know i
i don't know i don't know alex miller
okay i think that's it for today thank
you guys for watching
love my tutorials okay you go to
you see fantastic look at this look at
this uh look at this
let's say let's say show calendar okay
then let's say calculator
uh
what
okay so wait yeah that's not right
what's going on with the cac so i have
i have a keyboard of course
i have a
show all the keyboards
space n7
okay there's emacs calculator and
uh let's do tetris
there it is tetris oh
down down down
okay wait what
what key is it too
so let's show snake
so you can play snake and tetris
and wait did i just go into irc no
that's snake scores
thank you guys for watching oh i forgot
to say uh
you need to go to my emacs tutorial
and buy it
bye guys