Hello guys. Welcome everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Talk Show.
Today is 2022 March 3rd and today the
first 30 minutes we are going to code
Emac Lisp, okay?
Video check, audio check, I'm alive.
Emac Lisp coding for the first 30
minutes. Then I'm going to talk
randomish.
Randomish.
Uh so if you have a questions for me,
ask it, okay? So
let's begin.
Uh so let's begin. So you are looking at
my keyboard. This is Kinesis Advantage 2
and this is ultimate hacking fantastic
visual dictionary of special plane
curves and visual CSS, okay?
Let's begin, okay? So let's begin
today's talk show. So so let's go to
talk show. So
I want to code
um
swap.
Okay, so this is what I'm going to code.
Begin
uh yeah, Emac Lisp. Yeah, so this one,
okay? So
copy it. So it you know, we are I'm
going to do uh
Lisp coding Emac Lisp coding right now
and you are also looking at my
Emacs workflow. So this is a great real
life practical real world workflow. So
in a pink window you can see all my
Emacs command calls like every key I
press, you will see the uh command names
in the pink window and you will also see
the keystrokes I use. So I'm using Xah
Fly Keys.
So that means
uh Xah Fly Keys.
So that is a Emacs key binding system.
It's a model system just like Vim but
with much more efficient
uh
command and key bindings. So that's what
I'm using Xah Fly Keys. It's free on
GitHub and uh it's it's and and then
it's um
Xah Fly Keys. Yeah, and I'm I'm using a
Dvorak keyboard. So let's see. So
So let me show you Dvorak keyboard. Uh
this is common topic of my talk show. So
this is you are looking at QWERTY
keyboard layout and you this is Dvorak
keyboard layout. So you see all the
keystrokes showing up there. All those
are uh Dvorak. Okay? And you will not
see
control much. You will not see meta, you
know?
So Kinesis Advantage uh so let me show
it again, okay? So keyboard.
Uh yeah, okay. So wait.
Bookmark.
Open bookmarks keyboard blog. So this is
you can search it, you can find it. Ergo
Emacs keyboard I mean ergonomics
keyboard review. Kinesis Advantage,
okay? And uh Ultimate Hacking keyboard.
I'm using it it. I'm using it as a key
marker system. Fantastic. You go buy it,
okay?
And there's going to be more keyboard
review coming up coming up new
keyboards, okay?
Uh So those of you making keyboards, if
you send me one, I'll do a review for
you. Independent, you know? Doesn't
matter
you know,
you give it to me or not. I'm going to
do independent keyboard review
according to my judgement.
That is what review should be. That's
what's review is all about, okay? So
anyway, so
regardless of you know, sponsorship.
So I'm going to I was going to show you
the
you know, anyway I talked about this
keyboard often not today, okay? So yeah,
I was going to show you this picture. So
this is my uh
you uh
This is my
key binding shortcut layout. You know,
you know, the shortcut system using the
this this and this you know, these two
together. The Ultimate Hacking keyboard.
So let me show you key keypad for
Windows. You see? So this is select all,
copy, paste, new tab, new new window,
new document, new tab,
open last closed, close, reload.
Uh this is close you know, and so on.
So close that, you see one key press
that's Alt F4. But one single key press,
you know, no extra.
Any extra causes pain right now I have
here like I talked about many times
right now. Repetitive strain injury.
So okay, let's focus on keyboard
on Emac Lisp coding. So right away we
are going to start Emac Lisp coding,
okay? So right away. So like right now,
okay? So close close
Xah Fly Keys, okay? Close that. What is
this? Yeah, so So this is um
So I'm using Xah HTML mod. Yeah, let me
mention a few things, you know, since
I'm doing Xah Talk Show not someone
else's talk show. Xah Talk Show, so you
buy my stuff, okay? You pay me. So for
example, uh
Okay, let me show you this.
Xah packages, okay? This is my Emac Lisp
you know, pack Emacs packages. You can
download. They have been for free for
like 15 years but I don't get paid. I
get I get like
$50 a month. So I'm you know, pretty
bad. So anyway, Xah Fly Keys free. The
other ones you have to pay me, okay? And
right now I'm using Xah HTML mod, you
know, I did a video there
talk show. So
Xah HTML mod. So I'm working directly in
HTML. Oh, there is a question on Discord
on Xah D Discord about how
uh let me mention it, okay? Actually we
need to get get into uh coding E this
now. Say you know, say say hi guys,
okay? Central Intelligence Agency. Hello
there.
So Emac Lisp coding. So but let me
quickly mention about this package,
okay? Yeah, this one. So
[ __ ] said is a great guy. [ __ ] said
posted this thing. [ __ ] said is a
He wrote a package for the Zettelkasten
something note taking system.
Okay, he's author of that. He's a big
Emacs
Lisp coder, too. And so anyway, so
So there's this package, you know,
modern org style. You know, I despise
any package that says modern. What the
[ __ ] modern modern.
Uh modern org style. So basically they
replace org mod, you know, the syntax uh
yeah, okay. Let's open it.
Yeah, so you can see big. Can you Can
you magnify? Yeah, you can.
So basically they they change the org
mod
rendering so display. So instead of
using pure ASCII, they introduce Unicode
and you know, basically prettify it. You
see? They draw this line.
You know, this is after. This is before,
you know, before the when you have a
code block, it looks like that. Before,
you know, begin source. Then after it's
you know, all pretty. And look at the
headings using Unicode. Look at the
headings. You see? Before it's like
that. Headings 1 2 3 4. Now it's they
are using Unicode. So
they are trying to prettify it.
Rendering is is so it's kind of a
rendering system. But that this thing
it's good, okay? I mean I'm not I mean I
mean I have my opinions on on
everything, okay? But almost everything
mostly.
Not actually everything. I do have a lot
of opinions but technically speaking not
on everything. Yeah, mostly programming
related and the stuff.
But anyway, so this
I don't think this is good, okay? This
this this is contrary to the spirit of
org mod, okay? Org mod begin about 15
years ago, 2008, okay? Org mod begin
2008 written by this astronomy student
astronomy, you know, in PhD student
something taking notes, you know.
He was using
Okay, I'm starting to digress into the
history of org mod.
You know, Emacs there's a outline mod,
you know, I can show you outline mod.
Yeah, you know, I actually I need to
code. Let's let's focus on coding. You
know, I
I want to code Emac Lisp instead of the
random instead of talking random.
So anyway, so so
the spirit of org mod, you know, it
begin 15 years ago. Was that it's pure
ASCII, okay? Pure ASCII. Everything you
type you you know what they are, you
know,
unlike for example, HTML. You have all
these tag complexities, you know?
You know, the render you know, so so so
the spirit of org mod
one of the fundamental pillar that made
org mod popular, you know, spread all
among the hacker types, programmers,
coders is that it's pure ASCII, okay?
Because the Unix type of people, you
know, the Unix philosophy, you know, the
Linux type of people, they love just
pure ASCII. None of this Unicode pretty
[ __ ] okay? That's what they love.
So
So org mod, you know, just just pure
ASCII and you can read it, you know,
human readable, you know, ASCII. So
that's That is one of the fundamental
reason the the gist
that made org mod popular.
If you have the if if org Mod start with
this, nobody's going to use it, okay? Uh
so,
but but this is
but this but now after 15 years, the
generation changed, you know, the hacker
generation died out. Now this millennial
gen and zoomers,
they don't you know, they have different
ideas because you know, because they
they were just born. So they they start
to use Oak Oak Mod, you know, they don't
know history of Oak Mod. So they just
use it. It's fantastic, you know, tree
you know. Then they thought, "Hey, why
not? Why why don't we just make it
prettier, you know? Why don't we you
know, instead of this ugly headline, you
know, ugly asterisk, now we have
Unicode. Let's let's make it pretty."
There's millennial gen, the zoomers.
So that's the that's the that's the
situation. That's the evolution of the
culture, okay? So that is uh
audio check. Did I check audio? Yes. So
that is the evolution kind of the
culture of the Oak Mod users, you know,
the zoomers. So they introduce this
pretty pretty.
But
so that is why I say this is the this is
kind of the contrary spirit to the you
know, to the contrary to the spirit of
Oak Mod.
Uh but overall, so let's step back.
Overall, is it good? I mean, why not? I
mean, let's disregard
the hacker culture, the previous
generation or the current generation.
Let's disregard that. Is this a good
thing technically? You know,
is it a good thing?
To me,
not so much.
I I I wouldn't say it's a good thing,
okay? So first of all, I give you the
history of Oak Mod a little bit. And I
think this you know, I think this is a
contrary to the spirit of Oak Mod, you
know, using
Basically, then my opinion of it
disregard history, you know, my opinion
of this is not too good because
it introduces a lot of complexity.
So what does that mean? So you see, it
introduces a rendering
kind of rendering process. So because
you have to render, you know.
And
and then it also introduces Unicode, you
know, Unicode.
In order to you know, in order to
display them like that, sometimes it
won't work because when you actually use
it in different computer, you just you
know, on your mom's computer or on a
computer at work, you just got hired,
you know,
it doesn't work because it's using
Unicode because then you are missing
font, you know, you try to use this
you know, then sometime then then
something doesn't work. It doesn't show
as as as it's supposed to be. Then you
started to look at the config.
Why doesn't it work? Unicode. You know,
you know, let's let's
Okay,
I started to ramble a lot. So
okay, Cody Cody's got an opinion, but I
I have opinion on that. That's a
different thing. So um
so Unicode, right? So Unicode Yeah, so
you you start to have a font issues
because there's a lot issues. I mean,
it's really Unicode is pretty good now,
but it's nowhere near at the
universalness
of ASCII, okay? So because you you are
going to have missing fonts. For
example, let me show you some missing
fonts, okay? So let's see hands.
Okay, it's a bit weird. You you can see
there's a you know, I talked about
Unicode in my past videos. I'm not not
going to do it now, but let me just show
you some
tofu characters, okay?
Office.
Okay,
okay, Microsoft is actually pretty good.
If you are doing this on a Mac, try it
now. You Mac phonetics, try it now. Many
of these going to going to become tofu
like blank squares.
You know, it's another history. Apple
used to be the best supporter of
Unicode, but not today
because Apple
decided they they are the king, you
know, they they
they disregard the Unicode standard.
They they created they decided which
character should be
available, which one should you know,
not be available.
Apple is making that decision. So
Apple lots of this you'll see square.
Okay, so here's a example of a square
rifle, okay?
Rifle. Now it comes Now now this becomes
a political situation
because the rifle, you know, nobody you
know, the part of the society in USA,
they say, "Oh, you cannot show a rifle."
It become political. When you come
become political, everything going to be
[ __ ]
So Unicode has these problems, okay?
So that is why I say this mod Okay,
let's go back to the yeah, Oak Moden.
Hey guys, this is modern guys, modern.
Modern Oak style.
No, I don't like it.
And I don't use Oak Mod myself. You
know, this is one of the frequently
asked question because I just asked
again. Kasa,
do you use Oak Mod? Why not? How come
you don't use Oak Mod? Oak Mod is
Well, I use HTML.
Let me give you the reason quickly,
okay?
I code HTML directly, raw, manually
since 1996.
Essentially,
I watched HTML birth of HTML. I watched
it, you know, it boom.
And
I've been working on it, you know,
beginning by typing every
tag
magnify, okay? Typing every character,
every tag
every tag name manually, you know,
character by character beginning with
that and using Microsoft Word 1997,
okay? 1996.
So I begin working with HTML. So now
I've been coding HTML for 25 years.
Jesus, I'm almost dead. 25 years, you
know, so HTML is
So let's let's go to Kasa HTML tutorial.
Check it out, okay? You watch my video,
check it out and pay me, okay? Donate,
Patreon,
PayPal, okay? That's what I'm here for.
So
I have HTML tutorial and recently you
know, and there's also CSS tutorial.
Recently I've been working on it to
Let's let's start the
Recently I've been working on it to make
it
to optimize it on the phone, you know,
so you are looking at the iPhone, you
know, emulation kind of. So I have CSS
tutorial, I have HTML tutorial, I have
JavaScript tutorial. Yeah, this phone
phone screen sucks.
So JavaScript in depth, you know, so all
together this are you know, 500 pages
JavaScript reference and DOM reference
and how do you
color picker and today much of this is
building actually. So you can see color
picker.
Tutorials, okay? All these are about DOM
checkbox and
web cookies, digital clock, okay?
Digital clock is boring.
Then there's analog clock, stopwatch, so
you can have a stopwatch. How do you do
How do you write that in JavaScript? And
fade elements. Let's see, fade
and fade, fade.
Okay, so
so tutorials, you know, and SVG. So
JavaScript. So I've been working with
them since HTML since 1997, CSS since
2002. I was late comer to CSS because
when when CSS was born around 1999,
you know, most people are like, "What
the [ __ ] is that? You know, we are not
going to use it." But new technology
usually is like that like that. New
languages, you know. Most people a lot
of people like,
you know, you are not sure it's going to
be
around.
You are not sure it's going to die
anytime soon because it's just a fad. So
of course a lot of new technology died
and you never heard of such as VRML.
You know, but back then around year
2000, this is this is the biggest thing.
My god, VRML. Everyone knows about.
Everyone is pushing for it. This is like
today's This is the technology
that is for that is supposed to be
today's metaverse, you know, the
Facebook meta, you know, Facebook is
like they are pushing metaverse. This
was supposed to be the thing, the
metaverse that will replace HTML. That
will be like every page you go to is
going be 3D and that's VRML. It's all
over the place in year 2000 in around
year 2000 for several years, for 5 years
or so. Eventually it died. It become So
no nobody use it. So I started to use
CSS.
Um I started to code, you know, as
uh you know, study and code CSS 2003,
something like Yeah, I would say
I'm pretty late. So 2005 maybe.
And then JavaScript Java I I'm even late
later
more late in JavaScript. I begin
JavaScript, you know, I begin a little
in 2005 coding JavaScript, but that's
like I don't know what I'm doing. I'm
just like
you know, to to me back then I already
know lots of several languages, you
know, JavaScript is
JavaScript in a year
19 JavaScript begin in 1995.
So from 1995 to year 2010 for 15 years
about 15 years JavaScript is considered
by all programmers to be the all
professional programmers to be a
crap, you know, it's a language it's
like Visual Basic, you know, basic, you
know,
everyone spits on it spit on it. You
probably have seen many mean memes about
JavaScript, you know, like this is it's
for kids for designers who don't know
who don't know what is a variable what
does a variable mean what does a
function that you know, that's the
attitude among programmers
about JavaScript.
The same attitude towards PHP back then,
you know,
and it's actually it's true because
JavaScript turns out to be the one of
the worst
language because it's created and
designed and implemented in 10 days.
Literally 10 days.
Uh so JavaScript is a very lousy
language, but I begin to
kind of learn a little bit in 2005.
Then
around
um
around 2009 I started I started a deep
dive into JavaScript. So that's why So I
create I wrote this tutorial. I wrote it
full-time for like three three years,
okay? JavaScript in depth.
Why Why Why in depth? Because JavaScript
is a very complex language, you know,
programming languages every programming
language each one of them has a kind of
a computing model. Usually you don't
hear about it and usually it's not
formalized. Basically, you know,
okay, I digress so much, you know, I
should
um
Any Any Okay, let's call Emac
Let Let my thought flow go, okay?
So
So every programming language has a
computational model it's built upon.
For example, Java Java is OOP. You know,
I'll get into it, okay? So
Java, Python
Ruby they are kind of based on OOP.
Anyway, so programming languages they
all compile to
to machine code
eventually, you know, because you need
to work on hardware CPU memory
registers, you know.
So
that's machine code, okay?
So every language eventually compiles to
machine code to assembly first then
machine code. Then then
So you might say, you know, the model of
every language is actually the CPU the
the the instruction set
architecture, you know, that's what
called, you know, CPU
every CPU is different, right? You have
the Intel CPU Intel 486
286 386 then x86, you know,
architecture.
Then you have the, you know, today you
have the Mac M1 chip, you know, Mac with
based on the
You know, every CPU is different, but
however each CPU you can
there's a specification abstracted as
the instruction in
instruction set architecture, okay?
Uh I'm going over over the place. So
let's um
So um
So I want to show you this article,
okay? So semantic noodle so semantic
noodle
Let's go there
and uh
a bunch of essays about programming
language design and uh
you know, about programming language
design. So let me find the article
what I want to talk about.
Yeah, so this section programming
languages and their machine, okay? So
this is a critical section programming
languages and their machine. So let's go
to So why is array access constant time
programming language and its machine,
okay?
And programming languages and their
computational models, okay? That's what
I'm talking about. Programming languages
and their computational models. You go
read that article, okay? So you can base
you know, so So So you have the concept
of you know
for
uh personal computers, you know,
eventually they all um
work on CPU. So let me talk let me um
So programming languages and its
machine, okay? So check out this
article. C is not a low-level language.
That's a great article, okay? By this
guy. C is not a low-level language. C is
a scum.
C C C C is the worst. The C is a
language that caused the most damage to
programming languages
in the past 30 years.
Uh if you disagree, you don't know,
okay? You don't know what the [ __ ]
you're talking about.
Programming languages and its machine.
So here it is instruction set
instruction set architecture. You can go
read about it on Wikipedia. So
So all the CPUS CPUs are different, but
they can be specified captured in an
abstract way by the by this instruction
set architecture.
Basically just um specification of the
CPU essentially. So
Oh god, I'm going anyway I'm going all
over the place. Um
So what I'm saying is that different CPU
can be represented as instruction is
instruction set architecture, okay? Then
then
um
then programming languages um
compiles into that, okay? Programming
languages compile it into the assembly
language for the for that particular
CPU's instruction set instruction set
architecture. Okay? So
you have many different programming
languages. They all compile to assembly
code.
But there are so many assembly
languages, you know,
assembly languages. You know, you
compile to assembly
uh code of a particular assembly
language. Each assembly language is
designed to work with a particular
instruction set architecture which
represent that particular CPU chip,
okay?
So different languages they compile
compile to assembly languages, you know,
which depends on the instruction set
architecture, okay?
So you might say Oh, all the language
are the same because they all compile to
the
to a particular instruction set
architecture. So you might say, okay, so
languages might be different depending
on which instruction set architecture
they compile to. Actually that's not
really
the case. So what I'm trying to say is
that different language programming
languages have a different programming
model, okay? That's not that's higher
level that's much higher level than
instruction set architecture, okay? So
you have a programming model for this
particular language.
And uh
then
So Java has a programming model. Lisp
has a programming model.
Python has a programming model. And this
this programming language model they are
like they don't even have a name like
usually it's not talked about. But when
you learn a language you kind of get a
sense of it. That's what that's what it
is, okay? This is a thing that no
textbook almost like no none no Okay,
I'm making a big claim here. Drama here
comes the drama.
Different programming languages
are based on they have a programming
model they are based on, okay? And this
programming model of a programming
language is almost never talked about.
You read all Python books Python
tutorials. You read all these tutorials.
This you know, Haskell tutorials or
Haskell books. You'll not find it.
You'll not see it. They will not They
They They They almost never will mention
like how Haskell has this model. What is
this model exactly what it is. They will
not mention it.
But But you kind of just get the sense.
For example, Python.
Uh let me give you
Should I give you some concrete
examples, okay? Concrete examples of
what I'm I'm about about these
programming language models. Uh for
example, object, okay? So, what does a
object mean? They mean different things
according to different uh programming
languages.
And that is a good example to illustrate
how programming languages actually have
a different model for each one of them.
So, um
So, let's find my uh article.
Okay. So, for example, you go check out
this article.
Um
the meaning of object in computer
languages, okay? So, Java, if you read
Java documentation or the Java language
spec,
they all they all have the word, you
know,
class and object. Okay? So,
that has a specific very specific
technical meaning in Java, okay? Class
and object. In fact,
class is the programming language's
keyword. So, there's a keyword in the
programming language source code. You
can type class to to do something, okay?
That's
But the object is not, okay?
So, there's a complexities, okay? So,
anyway, I'm what I'm trying to say is
that different languages
have different computational models they
are based upon. And this compu-
computational model of a language is
almost never mentioned. However, you can
kind of see it
from their documentation or the language
spec.
And one of the example to illustrate
that is
is by looking at the meaning of the word
object in different languages. So, in
Java, if you code Java, you know, okay?
If you code Java, you then you know what
I'm talking about. Java has class and
object. Class has a specific specific
Both of them have a very specific
technical meaning in the language.
Now, Python also have a concept of class
and object, but it's very different from
Java. Although, to most programmers, you
know, so to the everyday practical
programming, they're kind of the same,
you know, they are just class and object
of OOP
object-oriented programming, you know,
you create a class,
then you can create a object from that
class, you know.
So, on the surface, they are the same,
but they're very different, okay? Java
and JavaScript. Java and
Okay, wait, hold. Java and Python,
they are both object-oriented
programming languages,
okay? And Java is a pure object-oriented
but Python is not that pure, okay? But
anyway, they both you can you can do
object-oriented programming in both.
But however, here's the, you know, what
I'm talking about the about the model.
So,
Java object and, you know, so what does
the what what it
Does the word class or object has a
technical meaning in the language? Yes.
In Java,
very precise, very technical, okay? In
Python, um
in Python, not
not much, less, okay? But they But they
are very different, okay? These two, you
know, very very different. For example,
in in Java in Java, okay?
An object is a reference type data type,
okay?
Uh
I haven't coded Java for a long time,
but anyway, don't take my word for it.
Okay, so anyway anyway, so then then
comes to Lisp. Lisp also have the word
object, you know?
And the meaning is entirely completely
different from Java and Python, okay?
Lisp object is just a blob, okay? Lisp
the the meaning of object in Lisp is
just a compiled blob, okay? Like if you
have if you have a Lisp function,
you know, so
So, for example, let let's see so
for So, for example, let's go to So, for
example, this this code,
copy rectangle to kill ring, okay?
That's um you know, anyway, this is a
function, okay? In Emacs Lisp.
Uh when you run the when when you run
the Emacs Lisp, it will compile to a
thing, and that thing is called object,
okay? That's what the object in Lisp
means.
And JavaScript object JavaScript And
then comes to JavaScript. Java-
JavaScript object.
JavaScript The the word object in
JavaScript also have a very specific
meaning in JavaScript, okay? And it
means it means a
it means a particular data structure,
but basically like a hash table. Hash
table or dictionary, you know, Python
calls it dictionary, Ruby calls it hash
table, Perl calls it hash table, Java
calls it
Java calls it map map object, okay?
Basically, key-value pairs.
That is that is the meaning of the the
word object in JavaScript, okay? Very
very entirely different again an
entirely different from Java and and
Python, okay?
And and and and Node.js, okay?
It This is funny, okay? So, Node.js is
basically just JavaScript, but however,
then then then in Node.js Node.js
Node.js,
the word object is not
does not mean the same thing as
JavaScript object. In Node.js,
the word object basically just means a
namespace, okay?
Namespace.
[ __ ] idiocy.
And C language also have a has a concept
of object, okay? I don't know C well, so
someone else might This is a great
guy, Nick O'Clock. He's a Emacs user for
30 years, you know, he's he started to
use Emacs in 1980s or something, much
earlier than me. So, he Nick O'Clock,
and he's a he's been coding C for like
30 years.
So, he tells me what object in C means,
okay? So,
So, my point here in in this article,
the meaning of object in computer
languages, so you you have seen
different languages have very different
meaning of the word object. Some Some of
the languages,
the word class or object has a very
specific meaning, while some other
languages,
the meaning is not important. For
example, in Lisp,
the word object is not important. I
mean, you can you can remove every word
of the word object in Emacs Lisp
documentation and it doesn't matter,
because the word object in Lisp is just
compiled thing, you know, again, it
doesn't it doesn't matter, okay? So,
So, you can see different languages have
different sense of, you know, word
object. And what does that mean? So,
that
So, so So, that just means you could
say, "Oh, yeah, that just Yeah, of
course, they are different languages."
But that's shallow. That's a shallow
view. The real The example that What I'm
trying to say in this example is that
they illustrate
that
different languages,
each one of them, have a computational
model, okay? Computational model. So, in
Java,
the computa- computational model is
basically um
So, let me describe it. So, the
computational model of Java is basically
um
procedural, you know?
Yeah. Methods, um
you call a methods You you Okay,
it's basically object-oriented, so So,
let me let me let me capture it in one
nice sentence. So, it's So, the model of
Java is a the computational model of the
Java language is
is that you create objects,
and object
here means it contains data and it
contains functions, methods, okay? Then
you call the methods to modify the data
via the object class system. That is the
computational model of Java, okay? A
pure OOP language.
Okay? Now, Python
is also OOP.
The computational model is a bit loose,
so it's kind it's kind of like Java, but
not exactly.
It's a much looser.
Um
So, you you do that, and then but you
also do um
uh imperative
programming or procedural, yeah.
Procedural, you know, well, both of them
are procedural. So, anyway, we get into
lots of complexities and categorization
of programming languages. So,
Python's programming model is also
kind of OOP, but anyway,
as I like like I said before, when you
read the documentation or language spec,
you will not see a clear,
you know, definition of computational
model, but rather, for example, for
Python, you can see
you can see one of the documentation
start to talk about that, but not
exactly, okay? So, let me show you.
So, let's turn on JavaScript. So, Google
knows what I'm doing, what I'm reading.
Uh then you go to community
documentation. Okay, Java uh Python
website has a new design.
Uh, what the [ __ ] Go to doc. God,
Jesus.
What?
So, we got JavaScript on.
Reload the page.
Click on doc. God,
idiotic JavaScript.
Uh, Python uh
website. [ __ ] Python website has
always been the most idiotic.
Click.
Why Why Why is clicking doesn't work?
Shh. Jesus.
Incredible [ __ ] The Python Python is
the worst
[ __ ] possible.
Okay, let's open a new browser. Let's
paste it here. Python doc.
Oh, we are already Wait.
Yeah, so we are already on the Python
doc page. They redesigned their website.
This This is pretty recent recent.
Must be within
uh this year, last few months I I would
say.
So, Python documentation. So, okay. So,
now you have to click on that. Okay, now
now I'm familiar with this
page.
The most annoying You see, the Python
idiocy the Guido van Rossum van Rossum
Guido van Rossum
idiocy. You see? Look for the word
pillow. There it is.
Keep this under your pillow. Library
reference. [ __ ] the Python.
Uh, this is not nice style, okay? When I
see that, what [ __ ] is this? Keep this
under your pillow.
Irre- irrelevancy.
Ju- juvenile drivel. That's what it is.
Ju- juvenile drivel.
You know, they think you know, they
you know.
So, what does it mean? This it means you
know, the meaning of that is that this
section is kind of important, you know?
So, you you
keep this under your pillow. [ __ ] [ __ ]
the Python idiots.
You know, speak speaking of that, let me
show you.
Speaking of that, let me show you
Xahlee, okay?
Just go to xahlee.info.
Uh, okay, let's turn on JavaScript.
Okay, so today I've been rambling all
over. So, let's let's forget about doing
Emacs Lisp, okay? JavaScript So, you go
to my website, then you go to
then you go to
documentation.
Doc by dummies, okay? Doc by dummies.
This is all the documentation the Unix
man page, Python and Perl, you know,
lots of them. In detail, okay? Some some
of them are in very technical detail.
Some of these articles are about the
programming language programmer's
culture, the hackers, you know, what the
idiocy they
And some of them are very technical
detail about programming language
documentation problems, okay?
There's a lot issues, technical writing,
organization, and so on.
Uh, and formatting, you know, how do you
format a function arguments, you know,
optional arguments, how do you write
that? How do you indicate something is
optional? You know, there are many ways.
Which one is the best and so on. So, all
these
all these
this chapter is about all that. But
then, let's go to a one of a sub
chapter. Python Why Python doc sucks.
Keep this under your pillow.
That's
That's from these Python documentation,
okay?
Let's We digress. Let's go back to the
language reference, okay? Wait. Library
reference.
Uh
No, not library reference. Wait.
God, this You know, Python documentation
is a one of the worst. You know, they
have the Guido van Rossum has a style.
He He's personality, you know, he's he's
got a style of pseudo formality.
You know, he like formal. You know, he
like things formal. You can see it from
his writing style. You know, he like
things formal like PEP, you know, Python
Foundation, Python you know
you know, whatever. The like process,
you know, meetings and whatever. Then
then then the his writings exhibit a
kind of formality,
but it's a pseudo formality. Like he
would use words like
You know, he he is almost artificial,
you know, it doesn't It's not formal in
a real sense of formality of useful
formality. For example, mathematics,
mathematical logic, you know, you go
read a textbook or treatise or
exposition of math or mathematical
logic. It's very formal, you know,
definition. You know, the dry very dry
extremely dry formal and and that style
has a particular practicality usefulness
because
formals no no drivel no no
anything there's nothing irrelevant.
Every word every character is relevant,
okay? It has a significant meaning in
formal kind of style,
especially in mathematics, okay?
But Python, they try to be formal
because the way they write, you know.
For example, let me let let's read the
let me let me show Okay. So,
while the Python, you know, the Python
standard library, okay? Let's read this
section, you know, let's let me do the
exposition of this.
The The Python standard library.
While the Python language reference
describes the exact syntax and semantics
of the Python language, this library
reference manual describes the standard
library that is distributed with Python.
It also describes some of the optional
components that are commonly included in
Python distributions, okay? Let me let
me
deconstruct this paragraph. The
introduction, the most important uh
a paragraph in any documentation, the
first paragraph, okay?
So, this section is about Python
standard library, right? The Python uh
wait. Yeah, the Python standard library,
okay? It says keep this under your
pillow, okay?
Okay, the first paragraph.
So,
normally, just about every other
language, you know, they will just say,
"Okay, this section is about
Python standard libraries, okay? The
documentation for Python for for for
modules or components included with
Python." Okay? Almost every programming
language will just say that. But wait
but but Guido van Rossum the
the the pseudo formality, he's going to
say
What you know, he's going to introduce a
irrelevant uh introduction first, okay?
While while the Python language
reference section, you know, he's going
to talk about tell you about some other
section. While that section is about
syntax and semantics, okay? But this
section is about libraries.
He He has to mention that that that the
other thing.
That that is uh Guido van Rossum style.
He all over the place like you
irrelevant [ __ ]
The Guido van van Rossum idiot, you
know, he's not too
uh he's not too bright, okay? I would
say. Not
Okay.
I began to talk random and it's almost I
talked for 50 minutes. So, I guess I
guess we are not going to do
we are not going to code right uh any
Emacs Lisp
today.
So, I just saw a comment comment from
Gavin Freeborn.
Racket doc are unmatched. That is
correct. Racket, you know, the Racket
programming language.
The full name the proper name for that
language is Scheme.
Racket Scheme Lisp.
Okay.
The proper name of that language,
Racket, should be Racket Scheme Lisp
because you should remember your roots,
okay?
Because Racket is a branch of Scheme
language and Scheme language is branch
of Lisp, okay? Racket Scheme Lisp. They
change They changed their name to Racket
about 10 years ago.
I did I did a few video on, you know, on
Racket and uh
So, anyway, back to Python, okay? So,
Python library reference, you know, in
end documentation, in end.
Uh, and I talk I criticize lots of them,
the Python documentation problems, you
know, like pseudo pseudo formality. What
the [ __ ] is this?
You know, they they they want to pretend
like they they are they are the top they
they are the computer science, you know?
While the Python language reference
describes the syntax and semantics, but
this section this
[ __ ] idiot. Python documentation is
very very bad, okay? What is one of the
worst among programming languages.
Okay, let's go back. So what So I was
going to tell you about
about the object. Remember we were
talking about the you know programming
language computational model. So I was
trying to tell you
example
in Python documentation where they talk
about they kind of
hinted or implied the computational
model.
Okay, so so
uh
God, this you see you see this pseudo
formality is here again, you see.
So let me tell you about the Python
documentation, okay? So that's that will
be today's topic, okay? So you see
Python documentation. So they are they
are this three, okay? If you don't know
Python
then we you if you learn Python. By the
way, I have a Python tutorial, okay?
Just read read mine, okay? Mine is the
best.
In my opinion, but you know I I would
you know so so
So you just go to my website, yeah.
There it is already. So you go to my
website uh xali.info
uh watch this video. This is about
programming languages, you know, I
characterized the
different programming languages and this
is also great on Wolfram language
graphics uh tutorial. No no nonsense. So
you go to my website xali.info, then you
go to Python
there. So I have a Python tutorial. I've
been coding Python since 2005.
Uh so
So this Yeah, so let me go back to the
I'm talking about Python documentation,
okay? So Python documentation, if you
are new to Python the the three most
important section are the these three,
okay? Tutorial library reference and
language you know, actually language
reference nobody reads. You don't need
to read this section at all. So the two
most important is just these two. The
others almost nobody nobody reads. You
know, what one one in one in a one in
10,000, okay? You don't need to read any
of those. Just these two. Tutorial and
library reference, okay? Now Python
tutorial is not good, okay? It's not
very good.
You know, I read it like 15 years ago.
It's not very good. It's the same. It's
pretty much the same
since 15 years ago, yeah.
Uh so
if you like my style, if you like what I
do, check out xali Python by example,
okay? So this Python 3 basics, you know,
I give you the most concrete most
dense introduction to Python. You can
learn it in an hour, okay?
And they are example based. So I don't I
don't talk about philosophy, coding
style, idioms like
like computer science, you know.
You just get a code, you know, this is
your what you type. This is what you
type and what it does exactly, you know.
Uh programming tutorial by example
style.
So that's my example. Uh that's that's
my Python tutorial. So anyway, back to
Python documentation, okay? So Python
documentation, so these two are most
important. Tutorial then a library
reference. Okay, now let now let's
let me let me um
let me talk about the in inanity of this
section, the Python standard library.
Let me let me show you why it is pseudo
formality. Very annoying. This very
annoying like I I've been reading Python
documentation now and then
for 15 years now. Very annoying.
Everywhere you go there's this this
pretentious, you know, pretentious. It's
It tries to tell you things you don't
need to know.
While the things you want wanted to know
it's buried somewhere. It's a [ __ ]
[ __ ] Python tutorial. For example, this
one.
Python standard library, okay? Let me
read it.
The Python standard library.
Oh wait, we did already did this. Uh
let's try the sec this section, the
Python language reference, okay? So this
section is basically basically it's a
specification of the Python language. So
this this part
nobody reads, okay? This this section is
more about
for compiler writers, okay? For for for
someone if you are going to implement
your own Python language.
Am I still still alive? Say say hi. Say
hi, guys.
12 people watching.
Uh
check video check audio check. Good.
So I'm going to read the comments and
that's it for today. So
the Python language reference, so this
reference manual describes the syntax
and core semantics of the language.
You know, notice you know the Let's take
some time to notice this first sentence.
Pseudo formality, pretentious [ __ ]
You know let me let me say say it again.
This reference manual describes the
syntax and quote and quote core
semantics of the language.
What? Why do they need to quote it? You
know, there's a question.
You know, the the the the quote doesn't
just does not magically appears. Like if
you are writer, if you
you know, write documentation, you know
they like every character you have to
put there. You have to make a decision.
So why did they put the quote? You know
this reference manual describes the
syntax and quote core semantics unquote
of the of the language. So what does it
mean? Why do they quote that? Let me
tell you. So they they are trying to
give you they they they want to say what
they are trying to say is that this
documentation is not 100% complete
specification, okay? We are just giving
you a you know, we are just describing
the syntax and core semantics like like
quote and quote core core semantics. So
it's trying to impart the idea that this
is not
complete or that the the the core
semantics is not well defined. So they
they because they are formal, you know,
they are very precise. They are 100%
correct. So if you don't quote the core
semantics, that would be incorrect
because this actually the the the
meaning of core semantics is actually
not well defined. So they have to quote
core semantics.
That's why.
That's That's That's why That's That's
why I say it's a pseudo formality.
Useless, you know, useless.
Then it says it is terse but attempts to
be exact and complete. [ __ ] [ __ ] You
know
he
You know, almost just just about every
other language you know, when you want
to describe aspect of the language, you
just you just begin write it, you know?
This section introduces introduce
this section is a you know, a
a documentation of the
Python language.
Uh I mean I mean specification, okay?
For those interested in
implementing Python.
That's that's to the point. That's what
this this section this chapter is about.
Or just about every language, Go, Lang,
Java, you know, they they just write
that.
But when it comes to Python, you know,
first of all, the reference manual
describe the syntax and core semantics
of the language, then then he has to say
it has to tell you it is terse. By the
way, oh by the way, this section is very
terse, okay? So be careful. If you don't
know, you know
If you don't know computer science too
much, maybe
you know, so we are giving you a warning
first. You know, it is terse but attempt
to be exact and complete, okay? But
however, we are not exactly complete and
we are not exactly exact, but we
attempted, okay? So don't blame us when
something goes wrong because we are just
we are just being very formal and
precise. We tell you exactly what's
going on on this page. [ __ ] Python
idiots. The guy Guido van Rossum, that's
his style. That's
that's his character. That's his
personality, you know, he's like that.
Useless useless, you know, they just it
just wasted two sentence kind of waste
this sentence this sentence is
completely useless.
Then it says then it says it and so on
and on, okay? Okay, this pseudo
formality very
annoying, okay? Then it says the
semantics of the
the semantics of non-essential building
object types and of the building
functions and modules are described in
the Python standard library.
Uh God, complete
You know,
so what what's going on here? This is
this is
confusion and you know, pretentious
confusion like going nowhere.
You know, so suppose I I I want to
implement Python programming language,
okay? I'm interested in reading this
section. So it then it says
"The semantics of non-essential building
object types and of the building
functions and modules are described in
this other documentation."
So, what the [ __ ] what So, what the [ __ ]
is non-essential building object types?
I came here
to read about that because, you know,
I'm trying to understand the Python
language specification. So, you you can
see
object will be defined here. Yeah, this
is what I was looking for, this section.
You see, object values types where they
describe what those kind of things are.
So, this is the This is trying to
describe the model, the computational
model of the Python language, okay?
Which which is what I am talk I was
talking about.
So, this this chapter is about you know,
this this this book is uh
Python language spec.
Okay, even allows you one, but that's
what it is, okay?
But then, in the introduction, they tell
you, you know, they has to mention, "Oh,
by the way, the semantics of the
non-essential building object types and
of the building functions and modules
are described in the other
documentation."
Okay, what but what but what is what is
non-essential building object types?
You don't know. You don't know. You
don't know. You have to read, you know,
you don't know what the introduction is
saying. So, so so
So, for for example, me
suppose I'm reading this for the first
time. So, should I start to read it
this section first? I mean, the the the
Oh god, the standard library. [ __ ]
idiot. [ __ ] extreme idiocy the
Python. Then it says, "For the For an
informal introduction to the language,
see Python tutorial." God. You see, in
this intersection
they have to
they have to sell themselves. They have
to do Oh, by the way, we have a tutorial
over here. By the way, we have the
library section over the here there.
[ __ ] idiocy.
So, in this section, basically, they are
give you kind of giving you a
introduction to the Python documentation
almost.
Okay, so anyway, that's it for today.
So, I'm going to read the comments and
uh
Okay, you're looking at Haskell. I I
haven't coded Haskell, so I don't really
know, okay? So, yeah, so
uh
Haskell for university course on
functional programming, that's good.
That's good for you.
Okay, uh I like SCSS, okay? I don't I
like SCSS. I don't like any of those
layers, you know, they create a layer.
Those are
those are malingering things.
Okay, so you can see
my articles about them. Let me show you.
So, you have Markdown, very
controversial. You have YAML, you have
Haml, you have Sass,
you know? So, SCSS, that's Sass.
Because Sass split, you know, Sass begin
in 2006, okay?
Um
then
then it split, you know, Sass has
original syntax, then it
then CSS become more popular and you
know, basically become because HTML5
come along. So, they decided oh, Sass
is, you know, not suitable anymore. So,
they split, they created a new syntax,
SCSS.
So, for example, this is Sass.
This is SCSS. Basically, SCSS is using
the CSS syntax.
While Sass is using the Python syntax.
And then, here's a regular CSS.
Wait.
Oh, yeah, yeah, this is regular CSS. You
know,
you don't need SCSS. You don't need the
Sass or SCSS anymore because CSS now has
variables.
I So, I wouldn't, you know, I do not
recommend any of these Sass
or Haml
crap or YAML. YAML, Haml, there's a lot
of them. There's Mustache, there's tons
of them.
Like they they function as a layer on
top of HTML.
Uh which includes Oak mod. You know, you
can consider Oak mod as a kind of
simplified layer on top of HTML.
Uh so, I don't use them. I use And
there's Slim,
you know, then there's Slim markup, you
see, using the Python
uh syntax.
Uh so, I don't use them. So, I like
I work directly in HTML.
In Python, it's a synonym for cryptic
syntax with lots of underscores.
In Common Lisp, it has some meaning
though, given it's related to COS. I
don't know what is
Common Lisp object system. That's right.
That's right, okay. I was going to, you
know, that's a bit esoteric, so I didn't
mention it. So, Common Lisp
So, we are talking about objects,
meaning of object in computer languages.
And this object, you know, object is
just a compiled blob, okay? But however,
there's a package called Common Lisp
object system.
So, if you use that package, then
obviously, object means something else,
you know? That is like
that That reminds me I'm going to do
another rant on the
Uh should I Yeah, Common Lisp. I'm going
to flame Common Lisp.
Don't use that, okay? My recommendation
is never. If you code Lisp, never ever
use that Common Lisp object system crap.
That's destroying the language. That's
just like just just like the just like
the Oak mod, you know? That's
Common Lisp object system is destroying
the spirit of Lisp.
Common Lisp object system
is the antithesis of the Lisp functional
programming
way. Okay, so
it's a bastard, you know, in in essence.
Don't use that. I don't recommend it.
You know, they they in in that Common
Lisp object system, you will often hear
dispatch, right? Dispatch.
Okay, I can I, you know, let me let's
just search, okay?
Dispatch
color
water, okay? Let's let's search it.
Set color There it is, polymorphism.
Polymorphism, dispatch, and the tail of
poly-tinting.
Okay, this is my
caricature. This is my
lampoon of the
of the of the Common Lisp object system
and associated things like polymorphism
and dispatch my ass. They are idiocy,
okay? Now, if you Now, the Haskell
coder, if you are Haskell if you are
functional
programming, then you know what I mean.
This polymorphism and dis- idiocy.
Coy.
Uh okay, that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching. Bye, guys.
Pay me, okay? Donate. If you like my
stuff, buy me a drink.
Okay, please do more shows with
commentary on documentation. Yeah, we
you know, usually I talk it's going to
be non-stop because I didn't intend
to talk about documentation, okay? But
but
but, you know, when it comes to
documentation, I'm going to talk for
several hours non-stop because we didn't
even begin
talking about it. For example, let's um
uh
Yeah, doc by dummies. You know, so for
example, there's Unix,
there's
uh there's lots of issues, organization,
syntax, format. Uh
you know, for example, and there's
something other funny things. For
example, the the typos in programming
doc. I, you know, like I I mentioned
before, I'm a I'm obsessive in reading
program
in reading documentations and manuals of
of whatever thing.
You know, TV, you know, back then, TV or
whatever, watch. I read them cover from
cover, you know, Casio watch, you know,
I used to have Casio watch 20 years ago.
There's a little manual. I read every
page, every word, you know?
And of course, for programming language
documentation, I read every word
multiple times, you know.
The Wolfram language manual, I have an
article on that somewhere, okay? You
know, you can see the history
of my
documentation or manual reading habit
and how I go about, you know, I read,
you know, that's one of my obsession,
reading documentation. So, on this page,
for example,
I found the the typos in programming
doc, you know? So, Python doc,
Python 3.3, you know, you have these
constant used to represent the the limit
for an unlimited resource, you know? So,
there's a
repeated
the typo, you know, repeat, you know?
So, I document them.
Yeah, so documentation, so there's a lot
to talk about. So,
um
uh the
I don't recommend Python, okay? That's a
frequently asked question, Dave. Talking
about that so many times, so I'm not,
you know, one of the problem of doing
you doing YouTube is that you have to
repeat lots of things like people going
to ask you again and again.
Like I I'm going to answer, suppose I
spend 20 minutes answering that, what
what language do I recommend? Then
tomorrow, by next week, someone going to
ask again. So, I have a video, I already
talked about that. That's the
That's over here, okay? That I mean,
just
it's in in a prominent place, okay?
Uh let's see, because I need info.
On my homepage, okay? Here.
Okay? Read this watch this one, okay?
This this video
about what programming language I
recommend
and why.
Uh
do I like YouTubers?
Uh that depends on who is the YouTuber.
BLZ,
you are stuck in traffic. Where you
from? I again, I forgot.
I remember you are on Discord, right?
But I forgot. Okay, that's it. Bye,
guys. Pay me, okay? Bye.
Shutting down in 1 minute.
2 minutes, okay? So, close that.
So, I'm just going to So, what is this?
I'm going to
log
the things we talked about into my
website, okay?
Uh
it's too big, so let's go to talk show.
Today's talk show, there it is, okay?
So, I'm going to
So, you are looking at my workflow, so
you can see
HTML tutorial is there, so close that,
close that.
That's my homepage.
Close that. Polymorphism, okay? That's
that's about the class thing.
So, you can see it's there, so it's one
button press, everything, you know,
that's how I operate. So, you are
watching my Emacs workflow of the those
of you Linux tiling window manager
fanatics.
This is for you.
So, you see, mouse, no click, you know?
No click, okay? No mouse click and no no
alt tab crap, okay?
Workflow, okay?
Got that. The the typo, okay? Copy that.
I'm going to here, then show the pink
window, paste that, linkify.
Okay? Go here, close that. Why Python
doc sucks. Yeah, why Python doc sucks.
Uh wait, something wrong with my
Why is it not
Oh, [ __ ]
You know, I don't like the www.
Why did it introduce the W? Okay, let me
fix it. Let me show you guys, okay?
So, copy the all.
So, we got a block of code here. I'm
going to I want to extract all the
links, okay? So, move the cursor here,
press two key, you can see Xah HTML
extract URL in the pink window,
then move the cursor here,
paste. You see? Now I got the
I extract extracted the link from those
that block of text. Now I want to delete
this block, so there's one way to select
all.
Uh yeah, okay. So, now I want to remove
the www, okay? So, now linkify. Now,
that's good. You see, I want relative
URL. Okay, do you see what I'm doing?
You see what's going on? Let me do it
again, okay?
Okay, let's do it again, okay?
Let's just focus on one of them, okay?
So, this one,
Python doc, okay? This is about This is
about open it, you know, this is about
why Python doc sucks, okay? So,
let's make two of them, one with with
www and one without, okay?
Now I'm going to link this one,
link.
So, you see that becomes a full URL, so
you see. And I'm going to link this one
without www.
You see? So, here you see a relative
link, then you see the title of that
page. But if you have the www, you got
the full URL, which is wrong.
Uh
Yeah, that makes sense, anyway. So, I'm
using Xah HTML mode, okay? If you like
it, you have to pay, okay? Search for
Xah HTML mode, you'll find it.
So, anyway, so
So, yeah, I want to So, show in browser,
so we got the links, why Python doc
sucks, repeated, okay? Do it again,
there it is.
Close that.
What is this? String markup, okay?
We talked about string markup
We talked about kind of SAS, okay? Copy
that.
Paste it.
You know, I don't want the
www, okay? Close that. Python
documentation problems, copy that.
Uh I think that's already here.
Oh, no.
Wait,
www again.
Uh I don't want to sub.
Okay.
Why Python sucks.
Python documentation problems. Oh, yeah,
so why Python sucks is the index page,
table of contents, then you have why
documentation why Python documentation
sucks.
Oh, Brazil, yes.
Yes, but you are using a different
nickname, right? Yeah, that's That's why
I don't like nicknames, you know, these
Malenchenko Zumas, you know? On
different places, you have a different I
can't remember. And also, you know, the
bad name, princess, you know, the
cookie, what whatever names.
I can't remember No, no. Nobody can
remember who you are.
Python documentation problems, okay?
Close that.
Yeah,
language idiocy, got it. Python
documentation idiocy.
Pretentious,
pretentious and artificial formality,
HTML, VRML, meaning of object in
programming languages, okay?
Uh Java define a function. Yeah, Java
Java script JavaScript, okay? So, that's
JavaScript JavaScript in depth, let's
copy that.
Unicode search, yeah, we were talking
about tofu characters.
So,
Yeah, copy that, okay?
Close that.
Back to Emacs, show the pink window,
back to browser.
Close that.
Wait, what is this character not
showing? Rifle, yeah. Political
situation, you know, they want
certain class of people
begin beginning around year 2010.
The name of that class is kind of
social justice warrior, okay?
So, they they think that the idea they
are you know, their idea is that
if you have a emoji that shows a gun,
that's that's going to um that's going
going to be bad for society. That is
going to encourage or increase violence
and murder, you know? For example,
you also have this Unicode character,
it's a pistol,
but actually
it is shown as a water pistol toy,
you know? So, that's a that's a
that's the issue, okay? Then the rifle
is not even showing these days. It was
showing before, you know, a few years
ago, but they decided, I guess,
Microsoft and Apple Apple
Apple begin it, basically.
So, these people think that
if you have a gun,
you know, in a emoji,
that's not good. That's going to
encourage violence. That's going to
create, you know, encourage murder and
you know,
that's what they think.
So, these people, they um
Is it true? That's not true. That's not
true at all. You know, so in other
words, what they are trying to do that
what they are doing is some form of
censorship.
You know, people will say America is a
free, you know, the free free free
speech country. It's the most free, you
know, for example,
a lot pro-America I'm American, okay.
A lot
um
the
establishment, let's say, the American
establishment, they they say, you know,
they they think America is the best
country, you know, the we, you know, you
don't get censored or and you don't get
sent to
If you say something wrong, you know,
you don't disappear.
Okay, we are getting further away. So,
anyway, so
So, this is a form of censorship, okay?
Uh
I don't think it's good. First First of
all, it's not true. It's blatant It's
not true that when you have like for
example,
in English language,
you have we have the word gun, okay? We
have the word
gun.
We have the word pistol. We have the
word machine gun. We have the word
automatic rifles. We have the word
assault rifles. Now Now Google is going
to ban me.
Censorship. Oh God. That's uh you know,
that's
I think this is the collapse of USA, my
friends.
All of you Americans out there, you
know, watching my show.
This is the this this this is not good,
you know, this is
You are not doing anything good. You are
actually doing making it things a lot
worse.
So, anyway, so you know, in English
words, we have all these words. We have
the violence, you have we have the word
violence, we have the word punch,
beat, kick, rape, you know, that's
that's one of the most dramatic word
among these type of people.
So, are you going to ban this word the
word words, you know? Are you going to
ban these words in English? Why don't we
ban it, you know?
For example, let's type it out, okay?
So, let's let's see the full glory.
Uh
pretty sad situation, okay?
rape
gun
machine gun
Okay?
That's English words.
Humanity, that's part of humanity.
Are you going to ban those words?
You know, you're going to ban emoji
because you don't code.
Oh, I get it. I get it. Now I get it.
Oh, you the emoji should be banned
because
you know,
you know, they probably think, you know,
but the words
should not be banned because they are
already there. But emoji is for fun, you
know, it's for happy happy meals, happy
color, you know, happy cheerful family,
you know, you know, so
So, for emoji,
you know, we should not introduce, you
know, these violent things. And and bomb
it.
firecracker
For emoji, we should ban them. But for
the for the for the words, the English
word, that's okay. That's what they
think.
Uh yeah, I don't think it's good. I
don't think it's good. It's pretty sad.
Um
You know, so you ban them. Of course,
you guys know, you know, this becomes a
big issue. It you know, America becomes
split. Is Trump on one side, you know,
the Trump
Everyone still needs to talk about
Trump, you know, like or or or right
wing right wing versus the left wing,
okay?
It's pretty bad because on on TV, the
Firefox, CNN,
they are running a show, you know,
fighting each other every day every day.
You know, the politicians left the
conservatives versus the Democratic
Party, you know, on TV every day.
Oh, you are a [ __ ] No, you are the
[ __ ] You are you are unpatriotic,
you know, they are they are doing that
every day.
Uh and uh this is happening here in
America. That's I don't think it's good.
S- and um
You know, so so so when you ban this,
yeah, but the right wingers, they are
not happy. So, you going to create more
problems.
You know, that
You going to create more problems.
That's what's going That's what
happening.
What am I doing? Okay.
So, I'm trying to clean the page, clean
the page, conjoin the list, make them
pretty. So, now we have a good list.
Yes.
Okay, close that. Close that.
Sorry, max packages. We need to mention
it, of course.
It's my bread and butter. You pay me.
And yeah, this package, okay.
This org mode.
Copy that. Back here.
org mode
Okay, close that. xhtml mode
important
Close that. To do, close that. xfy keys
Close that. Yeah, this ultimate hacking
keyboard.
Bye.