good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of SCI talk show
let me get prepared
well I wait for people to come out and
today we're gonna talk about lots of
things so I have the that's some talk
show web page yesterday we did we did a
keyboard session or about keyboards so I
need to do that and today's topic I may
talk about mathematics
well not mathematics but why tech
latekka sucks and math notations on the
history of math notations and its
relation to formal systems and what's an
alternative things like that hey guys Oh
Larry and Isaac so you guys know the
format you ask me questions and I answer
so let me type the type key of questions
here oh when I'm talking just comment
put your opinions you know if you have
question ask me questions and whatever
you know that's that's a current
situation for the south talk show so
what I'm going to do now is to put the
topics here in the YouTube panel first
of all type questions type questions
comments your opinions act you as I talk
so that is the situation so this is our
talk show in today's date and let's go
back to so I get let's get the
title in everything correct so there you
should see the list of topics hiya Larry
ties interesting topics looking forward
to this one cool so let's close that
let's go back to my Emacs and why I mean
Emacs let's do let's turn on let me show
you this so I've showed this many times
but in case anyone is new I think you
guys are new here and you saw start
command lock now if you are Emacs users
this mod is great because because it
records every command call you know on
the Left panel so if you are wondering
what command I just called you can just
see the command there and search the web
you'll find it and meanwhile let me drag
these over here a little bit so that
it's not hidden okay so I think you know
yesterday break the loop asked me a
question about math notations math
notation is you know I have this article
about tech pestilence so lead tech
pestilence or just take sucks you know
search for why tech sucks you know Tech
is a very popular extremely well you
know extremely popular among the hacker
types of programmers like they are gonna
say Tech in that tech you know Tech so
Tech is the package created by Donald
Knuth Knuth this by the way does anyone
know how he pronounces his name is Ruth
or Knuth Donald Knuth anyway he wrote so
if
type it he wrote the you know series of
books on the art of computer programming
was it oughta before I mean the other
programming yeah I think that's a title
you know and it's supposed to be like
nigh bottoms and it's still and finished
I know you're only has like three
volumes came out and fourth volume Knuth
okay Knuth hey break the loop great to
see you so I'm gonna talk about you know
the while our tech sucks and what's an
alternative now if I missed you know if
I didn't you know if you have something
like if I didn't address your question
if you have something you you want to
know just we just remind me I mean you
know I you know I yeah just you know
feel free to type in if anything you
know I I tend to come across like I
noticed my friends you know they I tend
to come across as formal like whenever
people you know like they start to maybe
it's like two extremes a lot of people
you just consider me as a troll
you know whenever like still there are
people whenever they see my name you
know with my without my environment on
the hacker hacker news and elsewhere I
know some of these people you know I
mean I know their names
you know whenever they see someone
mentioned you know my article my name
they are just coming and posting you
know that guy don't know you know
that case crap you know so is one on my
hand is like that then some people like
some people who follow me is on Twitter
you know since like I notice that they
they they start to when they talk to me
they start to be very super polite and
formal it's like thank you very much for
your great work and you know very valid
and you know that this that's that's
great but that's not it's not I guess
the reason it's that way it's just
because my personal personality came
across that way because I tend to be
you know I can't attend to be this
ascetic you know guy who who is you know
concerned about morality and concerned
about the wood of affairs you know
analysis of all the situations but you
know you don't want you don't have to be
that way you know you you you be you
know whoever you are that's the best you
know I you know it's like something you
know I haven't talked to I'm not much a
social person so it's almost like I
haven't talked to people like for twenty
years that's actually not really true
but but I mean but I haven't you know I
haven't working on cooperation so I
haven't you know really talked to you
know you know you know professional
level you know yeah like usually I've
been just staying at home so it's kind
of like a hermit so but anyway so I
started to do this video and that doing
this video is great because you know on
what I mean in some sense I mean on one
hand it helped it that's what I want to
do because it gives me first of all I
mean I like to express my opinions you
know I have opinions about something I
tell people and maybe I hope you know
it's some of the information it's useful
to guys and it's fun you know to have
videos these days you know the geeks
types they tends to be like they don't
want to do video like it's been like
four that way for like thirty years like
in the in the 1990s like nobody okay in
the 1990s we don't really have videos
yet but anyway in the 2000s Facebook
began you know Facebook is actually a
one that began to associate people's
real names with their impossibly photo
but beginning beginning with associating
people's real names with their whatever
they say Facebook in fact we could say
Facebook revolutionized the internet
that way at least you know that's a good
point about Facebook because before
Facebook nobody ever
officially the programmer types in it
you know the geeks they nobody ever
actually put real name there like
everyone is in you know you go to these
talk forums new scoops everyone is a
Batman Joker or something you know you
can still see that you know let me show
you let's see
geek hack this is a typical geek hack
actually the easiest way to find a geek
hacked link is in my keyboard website
because I know where to look
so actually I don't know where to look
actually go to my keyboard blog keyboard
and search for search for geek hack that
directory yes so okay I got a bunch of
articles so this one look at the browser
and oh this is a great keyboard this
this keyboard is from Japan is one of
the best and someone has compared this
keyboard with Trulia gonna make keyboard
which I have and also compared with
hands-on review so compared with oh go
dogs
so between oh go ducks as real and truly
economic he likes this one the most
however this one is very expensive it's
like five hundred dollars something like
that so you know it's you know the
connect Kinesis is just 320 you know so
it's kind of a bit much
you know too expensive so yeah let's go
to geek hack I mean that that's why we
are here so okay this geek hack link
let's copy it
let's go to Bri browser geek hack
now kick hack is a website where all the
keyboard geeks gather I mean they they
are extreme geeks
may I extreme fans about keyboards they
you know they a lot of them they dig
into the electronics the the key caps
the component of a key caps the
technology to create you know the labels
on a key and the plastic the material
you know the chemistry you know and and
the electronics as switches I mean
everything they talk about everything
about keyboard many of them are very
deep
you know like so anyway so so this is a
geek hack so is a website for keyboard
enthusiast
enthusiasts and you can see all these
people you know this disguise Angelics
edition actually oh and actually I know
that guy that guy is on Emacs user
he's already Daz well he posts posts
often location flatland flatland is a a
very famous math book we talked about as
time as many of you guys know mention it
so you know and this guy is cpt badass
okay and this guy is Scotty SC zero t t
y and this guy is a tip for a tissue tip
for tissue yeah so internet before
Facebook is like this okay you got this
bunch of Batman's you know nobody they
don't like to associate you know real
names like whenever that puppy comes up
all the opinions about oh security you
know privacy yeah privacy reasons and Oh
Jack Jack obelus this guy is also very
popular
I mean he's also a nerd he wrote an
article about how can how ago ducks
damaged his thumbs I think it's him I
might get I might be confused with
another guy oh oh maybe he's the other
guy who collects keyboards like hundreds
of them he connects you know really
literally hundreds of the esoteric
keyboards so anyway you got this bad man
you know they don't like to associate
names and they talk about privacy and
but look at today the privacy is like
ten times worse then then then then in
the 2000s
you know because partly because these
key people because on one hand they all
care concerned about privacy but look
look at their mindset and their actions
and where society went we what we got
today we got Google Facebook it you know
they Twitter you know this is all fake
news every day and and if you are using
your phone
I mean modern society you cannot use the
phone I don't have a phone number myself
I actually just got a phone for the
first time like two years ago where I
need to visit a professor but anyway so
we you know everyone needs to have a
phone I mean especially Apple just came
out today with some kind of you know
electronic payment so if I if I don't
have a phone what do I do
you cannot live in the society right so
but once you have a phone the phone you
know I I looked I I so I I got a phone
like two years ago so I looked you know
a little bit on the phone you know
there's no privacy absolutely whatsoever
compared to a laptop if you have a
laptop doesn't matter it's a Linux Mac
OS or Windows you can for example in
browser you can turn off JavaScript you
can run programs you know Wireshark to
see the traffic you know who is sending
what traffic even when you are not
connected to anything you know you can
you know you can look at all the
directories you know you can monitor
monitor things so you have like you have
control on the phone everything is an
app you know they'd like yeah it's a
long story you know and and there's no
way to turn off JavaScript or whatever
and you know so it's it's ten times
worse and each company says you know and
the options are all confusing there's
basically no way you got a phone
your life is is it's an open book known
by Google by Apple you know and you have
to record your voice you know like Siri
you know what's today's where the ends
you know that you know they know your
photos you know there's this thing about
the photos you know when you you know
when you get a phone you know phone has
a camera like when I first got a camera
is like 2 year 2000 you know digital
camera you know they become cheaper and
cheaper every every year so today it's
like basically everyone this you know
every almost everyone in the world
except the very poor countries has a
camera in your pocket what do you do
with the camera when you you know where
a person average person has a camera the
first thing you do is to take photo of
yourself so that's what selfies okay I
got some messages derivative what so
what are you saying is the best
Sebastian car it's not edgy most
relationships are superficial v-space
help okay I think when we got a troll
here so privacy is only a problem when
you start to get punished for being
different
yeah I guess so anyway so yeah so let's
go back you know to the previous topic
so I was saying Facebook was the first
it's an Evo company but at least you
know one thing they did to the Internet
is that it creates you know it began a
phenomenon where people start to
associate their real names on to what
they say which is which is actually you
know most people want I mean before that
the the the the the concept of Internet
is like oh it's dangerous in this stock
you know
you know spread by you no other
programmer you know hacker types so
anyway back to the so I was talking
about Facebook and I was talking about
names and what's the previous topic how
did we get there
yeah take Donald Donald Knuth and
baths hang car who is this guy
so anyway back to Donald knows the
author of programming and yeah why tech
sucks so let's talk about that okay so
let's see what so we cannot talk about
that yeah okay yeah well yeah okay so
Pistons you know so tech was created
because and it's free and you know it
began with math communities and then
he's spread to programmers you know and
it's very bad okay the tech is very bad
yeah I'm kind of you know I actually you
know thought Donald Knuth Donald Knuth I
actually never liked anything almost
anything he wrote you know I I read lots
of his books back in the 1990s
you know I started to read out of
computer programming in 1992 I didn't
understand it you know and you know -
well partly partly because well you know
that this that series of books the other
programming is actually focused on I
mean the way he teaches is that he want
to teach you assembly first assembly
assembly code you know assembly code is
the heart of actual actual programming
hardware you know you have machine
language you know
machine language because when you write
a program you know doesn't matter what
language today Python Java see you it
the compiler converted to the machine
code and machine code is just a bunch of
one in zeros I mean the source code of
machine code is just one zero one zero
and what you know it is a sequence of
the when zero that's the lowest level of
kind of the programming language above
that is a same assembly language
assembly language looks like okay well
I'm getting into that topic but anyway
so so assembly language so why am I
talking about that yeah yeah anyway
going back so the other programming so
that book he's I mean the way he wants
to teach that is that he wants to talk
about he want to give you a concrete
machine to work with so for example if
he is teaching you about sorting you
know algorithms for sorting you know
there are many ways to sort you know a
bunch of numbers or whatever you know I
abstractly abstract Lee you know it's a
mathematical idea we understand what
what it means so you have a bunch of
things and they have a space specific
order in math there's a thing about
order theory I mean that's that's
actually the the real math about it
let's see all the theory yeah you can
read about that other theory and and
miss magnify so order theory is a branch
of math which investigates the intuitive
notion of order using binary relations
yeah so you can so it's a bunch of
things then it relates to yeah math math
is amazing it race yeah Paul said if
when you study your category theory you
also get
to posit partially ordered sets the
others are critical information then
you'll get into lattice lattice theory
so anyway and you know orders you know
that's a math mathematical theory about
odors lattices yeah
bounded posits lattices complete
lattices directed complete partial order
and stuff this is great thing you know I
really love this kind of thing math is
my true love but she's been difficult
and so programming so you want to order
you know you know you want to sorting
algorithms so you you know you can talk
about it in a mathematical sense you
know your order but if you want to talk
about programming well you can discuss
various methods for sorting you know
Wikipedia there's a huge article about
sorting different methods so you can
talk about it you can talk to you you
can teach you the algorithms about
sorting you know like for example baboso
sort you just compare two numbers you
know which one is greater than you swap
him you know you swap the order so this
is a abstract way to teach about you
know one specific sorting algorithms but
Knuth his idea is a he he this doesn't
he doesn't like that he wants you to
actually work with a machine because in
his opinion in a preface or somewhere I
read that to actually really understand
sorting or anything about programming
computing you have to understand the
machine that you know something you are
working with not not the math elements
you know not the math elements but
actual assembly language you know yeah
it's called a machine you know it's just
called a machine so so but different
CPUs you know different yeah let's go
into that topic since you know this is
talk show so it's go random then we then
we go back to
talk about the tech pestilence that's a
lot there too because that that one
easton an hour by itself because it
relates to formal languages it relates
to yes formal languages and formal
languages relates through the heart of
computer science I mean the theoretical
computer science the the most difficult
problems in computer science and it
relates to prove theories prove systems
which is we are trying to invent today
like add idris programming language co q
programming language you know those are
proof systems they are intimately tied
to math notations so these subjects are
all like related you know all related
the meaning of notations the semantics
of notations how it how it relates
through mathematics and the social
consequences of a notation and the
notational systems what are their the
history of notations and computer
systems for notations in you know math
algebra systems like Mathematica and
maple and others they are kind of all
related but anyway so let's get let's
talk about that I was saying about the
Machine CPU and compilers okay maybe a
little bit it's it's they did yeah let
me try to manage the topics and let me
try to be coherent so hold on one second
my roommates
so notations so we put back to the
machine language yeah let's talk about
so let's go to semantic noodle it's
let's go there hey Danielle
let's do okay so notations so what what
I don't know about see you know most you
know I'm into math so my background is
mostly math so my perception about
programming language is mostly math
oriented you know and I like it that way
and I don't actually know much about
low-level languages such as C or it's
3:30 okay whatever languages C or I
never coded assembly languages and I you
know and I don't know about the cpu
architecture the memory stuff those are
you know I like I don't know nothing
about it systems programming you know
that that field you know I don't know
very little or even how to write
compilers I don't know nothing nothing
about it but I'm trying to learn but in
the past few years I started to read
about them and they they are you know
they are quite interesting especially
the CPU design I mean the CPU design
that you know powers or our computers
today you know the Intel CPU chips
whatever chips sparks chips chips they
the design of the CPU is a huge topic I
mean I had realized okay that that's and
it's non-trivial it's it's not and it
involves several things it's it's
extremely mathematical okay for one
aspect and also its engineering you know
the physical engineering of making the
chips the design what is possible you
know even if you have a mathematical
model sometimes you cannot be or you
know chips and also there's a practical
aspect and efficiency aspect you know
you cannot just design you know an ideal
design of a CPU and say let's make it
you know there's lots of constraints
cost and you know efficiency of
computation you know it's not just about
elegance or whatever you want so there's
so many engineering constraint
constraints and and but even few from a
pure mathematical point of view it's
also very interesting so I wrote
something about that they know hey hey
hey info Matic so let's see you know I
got I sometimes I have a hard time to
find where where's my articles so on a
rectification of programming language
spec by formal language ontology okay
math was programming what versus how to
a class of computer languages math
languages yeah that's a great article
brain yeah I I one time I did a
homework phone for someone you know he
paid me to do a homework and that's a
brain brain is you know one of
the language that programmers the hacker
types like to cite all the time because
and actually when you do the brain
it's very you start to get into the
low-level programming and you learn a
lot of things you know I learned a lot
of things because in high-level
programming like Python Ruby late
JavaScript or Lisp you know if you live
in this level you you never get the
exposed to some you know what's actually
going on you know in a low lower level
and some of your concepts of programming
languages or you know programming or
computation it's actually just wrong
yes because yeah you have to have like
exposed to the level for example you
know before you know you might think
there's you know for example Python or
supposed to Perl Python people like to
say you know we try to make things so
that there's only one
way to write it you know an algorithm or
whatever like good you know this is just
one way well on the other hand Perl is
found of you know they are more than one
way to do it that's their slogan you
know because but I actually if you look
at you know if you code low-level
assembly you know such as brain you
know that's a very low-level language
you you realize that there is no it's
impossible to have one way to do it
there are like a million ways you know
for one specific algorithm that solves
one specific goal such as sorting you
know when when we talk about sorting
algorithms we are in for example you go
to Wikipedia there's lots of you know
articles and we but but they are all
talking at a high level you know like yo
you just swap two numbers and that's it
but at the CPU you know when you have to
like yet electronics is going around in
your machine you know the billion speedy
ins make a pinion jig opinion some
electronics they are you know doing
their stuff and for example how you know
for example I display your characters
you know and sewed it here what what is
you what is in in a CPU so you you is a
byte
you know just as eight eight digits of
one and zeros and so so so it's very
complex I mean it's very complex so I
mean so anyway okay so at the low level
when you want to you you you kind of get
get to see that it is impossible you
know it's basically impossible to have
like one algorithm that is you know
suppose the the best okay because there
are million ways to do it you know like
you know if you look at into brain fog
you will see it but anyway that let's
get back to the okay let me just try to
find our article quickly and it's right
okay Kozlov computer language operations
programming languages and this and it's
machine okay this is very interesting
topic so programming languages and it's
machine so you know I'm interested in
programming languages you know I think
you know which is better you know
Haskell : oh you know why it's better in
that way this away no functional
programming oh you know okay but then
you have you know they start to look
into the CPU design and I learned a lot
of things so okay so yeah that's what I
want to try to find instructions set
architecture now what does I mean that
that is basically a mathematical
abstract mathematical idea that captures
a design of a CPU so it's called
instruction set architecture so what
does that mean it's just an instruction
set basically you have a set of things
each thing is an instruction what does
the instruction means instruction means
like you know put this number in this
address oh yeah let me let me read it
it's probably best there so a machine so
instruction set architecture a machine
can be abstracted into instruction set
architecture for example a set of
instructions yeah I mean that is a set
of instructions this makes up a machine
language okay that's a key that machine
language the lowest form of programming
language each instruction to things like
move this storm over there or put this
numbered here add two numbers together
and things like that so each instruction
you know instruction they just do one
very simple things you know add these
two numbers so in a CPU you have like
registers you know a register is like a
storing number which is just a sequence
of zeros and ones you know you have one
two three you know let's say you have 32
register
and instruction comes instruction tells
you take the number register from
register 1 and take the number from
register 2 and add them together and put
it in register 5 for example that's
that's one instruction another
instruction might be you know let's say
remove em you know empty empty register
number number 4 you know something like
that so that's a you so you got a bunch
of instructions and you have the
instruction set architecture ok once you
have that you are given a once you have
a designed one specific instruction
instruction set architecture then you
can then you'll have microarchitecture
which is you know when you actually
implement the is a instruction set
architecture is a when you want to
implement a specific is a by implement I
mean you know you actually have to
design the chip that you know when an
instruction comes certain electronics
you know you you know electricity flow
happens and you know that adds two
registers for example you have to you
know that's you know electrical
engineering you have to get you know
it's a electricity that's doing a walk
so you have to design that chip that the
thing is the chip you have to when you
implement a is a so is a is like a
abstract mathematical thing but you need
to implement it that means design the
chip you know the electronic flowing
around and that is called micro
architecture I mean because there are so
many ways to design the chip that you
know that does the instructional stuff
so you got micro architecture okay so
that's a two thing I want to say back to
the Guth you know so he when he teaches
algorithms
you know let's say sorting he wants you
to have a instruction set architecture
so you know he just you know you know
simply it's just saying you know ok just
swap these two numbers compare compare
them which one is larger then swap them
you know instead of saying that he wants
you to actually get down to the
instruction instruction set architecture
so it's like you have to call
instruction that maybe there's an
instruction that swapped to register the
numbers in into registers he wants you
to deal with that so he so but because
you know in practice every different
machines have different CPUs so they
have different instruction set
architecture
they have different microarchitecture
and they change every year you know
intel has you know pentium then then you
know and what are the others yeah all
these are different chips you know
Science Park em ideas you know so they
change it all the time so what news did
is that he created a abstract
instruction set architecture which is
called MMX I think so let's let's let's
look at the the odd programming
so how is everyone doing so far so good
you know let me know where I'm going you
know if I'm you know not so yeah so this
is his book you know it's still going I
don't think he's gonna finish it he's
very old you know huh
hey hey so he's very old you know I
actually met him when a friend a female
friend interesting she contact contacted
me she says you know hey you want to go
down to the computer museum which is
just down the street over here in
Mountain View we're deep so when they're
when they're and Donald Donald booth
he's there
Knuth is his there so I saw him he's
very old you know he's like 70 70
something and you can see something you
know you can see his videos in the last
couple of years on YouTube you know when
you are very old you know it happens to
everyone
you cannot 81 he's 81 years old you
cannot even talk well you know not even
mentioning you know your coherence or
whatever you don't even talk well so
anyway so he so let's go back to let's
say let's search for MX ok volume 1
fundamental algorithms valuing to semi
numerical algorithms sorting and
searching and stuff you know you know
the entire volume on sorting and
searching volume 3 you know that book is
like this thick syntactic algorithms
compiler techniques here it's planned
you know volume five compiler is the
critical importance
oh and theory of context-free languages
they are of critical I mean you
okay the volume 5 combinatorial rhythms
you know so volume 1 2 3 they are very
basic I mean yeah they are algorithms
they are important in numeric oh yeah
they are the I mean they are essential
you know but then I mean all these are
kind of like all very essential I mean
the heart of the programming computer
science because you see volume 5 then
you have a theory of context-free
languages and volume 7 or money and 6
what if 6 wait volume ok volumes
podium for I mean turn off auto click
volume 4 is combinatorial algorithms
volume 5 is syntactic algorithms volume
6 the theory of context-free languages
volume 7 is compiler techniques
now let's you know look at volume 7 if
you don't have a compiled compiler
nothing happens you know we are back to
the 1960s you know you have to compile
it to actually start to do anything
basic you know you need a C compiler and
so you cannot just code you much I mean
you cannot it's impossible to code in
machine languages so you need a compiler
and before you have a compiler you need
to know about the context-free languages
which is a grammar specification of a
language so that you know a program that
can read actually read your code and
understand what it means then translate
it to the machine language so you know
that we have a compiler you have to have
a theory of context-free languages which
is a topics I love that you know it's
again it has to do with formal languages
parsing regular expressions registration
is a mathematical theory originated from
there but today when we say talk about
regular expression it has nothing to do
with that you know ad evolves and become
say you know to us you know most
programmers regular expression is just a
practical tool you know for pattern
matching strings but originally it was
it was it is also pattern matching
strings but it's used it's using a
theoretical context tu-tu-tu-tu-tu-tu
sub or extra certain certain languages
grammar or to help but anyway so so you
can see that you know many of his works
is not it's just not done it's not you
know it's not like we grab done so one
two three four he got these four volumes
so okay back to the my previous topic so
I was saying you know when he wrote the
book he created the MX why can't night
we can I find it ok let's search for
don't know good news MMX that way you'll
find it in mmm IX okay so that's why I
like I cannot search for it cuz switch
such mmm I X there it is
so he's got a machine you know remember
we were talking about machine CPU design
ISP you know the the I you know I as a
the instruction set architecture you
know then you have microarchitecture
which which is actual implementation of
the ISA as a chip you know hardware
that's microarchitecture so he Donald
Knuth created the end mmm IX okay let's
read it Mme X is a 64-bit reduced
instruction set computing okay so this
designed by Donald Knuth okay so what
that means is that mmm I X
is a instruction set architecture a
specific type called reduced reduced
instruction set okay
but anyway it's just it's just an
instruction set you know it's a
mathematical abstract it's a abstract
idea it's a set of instructions so once
you have a instruction set you know you
basically have a machine even you didn't
build it even you don't have a
microarchitecture even you don't
actually build you know a physical thing
or your chip you know but you got the
instruction set architecture which is
actually precisely define your machine
you know because you have a bunch of
instructions and each instruction is
exactly you know what they do so
Knuth created this MMX instruction set
you know so the purpose of this is so
that so he can use it in his book the
other computer programming to teach
algorithms so when he's teaching you
know for example sorting algorithms he
doesn't want to just say ok episode is
just you know swapping neighboring you
know elements until something happens
that doesn't work for him he has to get
in town into a instruction said you know
so yeah that I think that that kind of
wraps up what I originally was going to
say that's maybe let's go back to tech
peasants so I think I've saw how long
I've been going 4050 minutes okay ma
okay ma my ex Thank You Norman so
interesting talk thank you did you like
the Computer History Museum no not
really it's kind of silly to say because
I you know I went to museums a lot in my
life because you know that's my thing
you know I like those kind of things so
you know science museums laser shows
planetariums you know and
also almost so it is museums usually
they have there are a lot kids go there
you know children you know they have
like toys you know math math toy is the
most but usually it turns out usually I
don't I didn't find them interesting or
these museums because basically once you
went to a few everyone looks the same
you know you have a bunch of I mean and
the things they cover is very pop like
popular you know they have to cover
things like everyone like like none
scientist a peer tutor and and scientist
you know so you know children or you
know they you go their date you know and
laser shows you know but for a nerd you
know for a program for example we are
programmers all most of you are and you
know you go there you don't you know
yeah I didn't find that you know this
museums you know to interesting kind of
boring actually
but anyway you do get to see old
machines you know they they have they
build the not ENIAC but the the famous
calculator by package Oh Babbage what so
what's the name of the machine which is
a kind of like the first computer but
with gears difference engine okay you
guys heard of that right the difference
engine yes you know there's a lag like
between whatever you type until I see it
on on my screen I think there's a
five-second lag yeah different
difference engine nobody is on fire okay
so I went there so I saw this machine
but I didn't see them actually run it
then I also saw one of the earlier
computers you know like they have 60s
computers where you have vector-based
screen that shows you know like you
shoot a game you know but anyway you
know that's a computer computer history
museum which is down here in Mountain
View you can you can you can just search
that word if you're not here and you'll
find it there's their website and also
Wikipedia article I think on Wednesday
or something it's free so babich-design
the second one yeah babby g also is a
interesting character he is a sad fellow
you know he he has great ambitions and
he created he designed all these things
and you know but he never completed
anything and he died very like Peter man
like you know Stefan wolf and he did
research he wrote an alcohol beverage
one time I think I think it's him I
think he did or maybe somewhere else
anyway it's like you cannot find oh yeah
analytical engine right say and you
cannot find a photo of Babbage that's
smiling yeah it's Peter you know in
conveying about other things
he never finished his machine yeah so
complete computer museum Computer
History Museum and this music museums
they are again I suppose nonprofit and
they you know they want your money and
well yeah it's it's good you know I
suppose it's not nothing bad about it
okay so yeah Donald Knuth so he created
mmm IX so yeah I was you know looking
into so I learned this just about you
know last year I you know I looked into
and so this is a instruction set
architecture is was tremendously
interesting because you have to you know
all the computing happens
you have to have the chip you know and
also once I you know read a lot about
this once I studied this subject I
learned a lot of things because so many
things that just you know in the past 20
years you hear it all the day or every
day you know Oh Intel created new chip
Oh Intel as see young you know Oh risk
chip you know I see chips you know or
x86 architecture like when you download
Emacs sometimes sometimes they ask you
you know download x86 something
something so what does it mean you what
do you want you mean x86 oh you know all
these names you start to understand you
know I start to understand you know you
you might have you know well I mean if
you are a C programmer okay if you are a
system programmer or Linux you know you
are interested a lot you know a lot of
programmers are interested in that
especially the hacker types you know
they are interested in low-level stuff
you know assembly you know compute so
then then you already know this stuff
you know I'm kind of ignorant but anyway
so I learned about this last year and
and and it just it's it's it's fantastic
and you know so all these years you know
I've been thinking about programming
language design you know that's oh you
know I'm for math background so it's all
high level but at the bottom these
things also requires tremendous design
in not just abstract design because you
have to actually create a chip to so
that so that your design must satisfy
many constraints constraints cost
constraints and and so on and also it
must be very fast because it's highly
competitive
yeah so so there's a lot of things you
know that non-trivial things I mean
besides the social parts aspects that's
interesting but those also many of these
are deep mathematical questions for it
there's SAT there's a problem about SAT
which is in formal languages a kind of
open problem it's it's the SAT you know
not-not-not
exam SAT but ok let's go to this ambigú
action
okay language and linguistics government
government language organization science
math okay here boolean satisfiability
problem which is one of the major major
chapter of theoretical computer science
so he says in computer science the
boolean satisfiability problem is the
problem of determining if there exists
an interpretation they are satisfied
given boolean formula now that that's a
bad warding but because if you read that
you don't understand what it means
that's not okay in other words it asks
whether the variables of a given boolean
formula can be consistently replaced by
the values true or false in such a way
that the formula evaluates to true yeah
that's a good way to put it so basically
you want you you got a bunch a
collection of equations like a a and B
equals to C then B or a equals to a for
example you got a bunch of them you
won't find the values for any of the
variable ABC you know or more more
variables you you want to replace each
variable by either true or by force such
that all of them becomes true something
like that okay
I think you get idea so I mean I'm sure
they have the examples here so you know
basically each one of the equation is
the boolean expression so you want to
replace the variables x1 x2
you know XA n pi yeah okay this is just
not not a bunch of equation it's just
one one expression of bullying you know
expression so you want to is it possible
so is it is it possible to replace any
of the variable by true or false such
that this whole expression
true so this is not so the the the real
question is about so so that is the
boolean satisfiability problem the real
question is about whether the the
question is about - how can you find the
efficient way to solve this problem of
course you can always do brute force but
that doesn't work because I think
because this number of variables can be
like medians or something yeah anyway I
don't know about this topic much so but
I this is one of the things I learned
when you design CPU you know when you
design I say instruction set
architecture you have to I think this is
one of the essential problems I mean you
have to solve
okay so so gp2 say hi gb g gb - so since
you are talking about low level design
for systems and languages what do you
think of Terry Davis and his creation
temple OS just curious he was
schizophrenic and died tragically last
year yeah someone told me that so I
looked into the guy so this is this guy
Terry Davis you can go to youtube and
find his videos so he's a very extremely
weird guy he's a schizophrenic
schizophrenic
is very different from schizoid okay I'm
a schizoid which is a lone personality
okay but schizophrenic is someone who
has like hallucinations like you see
things that are not there like like you
I mean you see or hear things that
doesn't exist so yeah I watched some of
his videos he's talking about what was
his beef about CIA or
P I you know he's like you know swearing
it does at the FBI or CIA F I forgot
which one but you know all the time and
yeah very weird person but he was yeah I
cut because he's a schizophrenic but
also because he but I mean he's also
extremely smart and capable he he create
he created this our CIA okay he created
this tempo OS which is a extremely small
what a few megabytes like a few oh s I
saw it you know YouTube you know it
actually has a actually has a 3d modeler
like CAD you know like AutoCAD you know
a simplified version like three and the
editor and the compiler you know the
whole it is a operating system and
everything he wrote himself
yeah so that's amazing you know I don't
know nothing about our main systems
right I can see you know it's you know
he's someone out there and he looks like
he died last year you know suppose he he
ran into a train you know it's it's not
certain it's either suicide or just by
mistake you know maybe he's drunk we
don't know but yeah so that guy so
anyway so I let's get back to the okay
let's talk about this original topic
let's talk about that a little bit you
know I'm I'm still learning about doing
videos of course yeah the you know I was
mentioning that because you know I it's
been like half a year almost half a year
now I've been doing videos I started to
do it every day since maybe a month ago
but you know I'm learning things you
know so I learning talking and giving a
presentation and and for example right
now I I'm getting more
better at you know you know like like I
wasn't sure you know something like this
Casa talk shows you know currently I
wasn't sure sometimes you know I want to
teach a you know actually teach
something you know one narrow specific
item sometimes people like that
especially Emacs because a lot of people
following me because of my Emacs stuff
but you know on your hand I'm not sure
because some yeah I mean when you teach
specific subjects sometimes it gets
boring you know but when you are like
doing a talk show you know so caught up
showed I mean there are lots of talk
shows you know the radio talk shows on
the internet they get popular because
people wants to see you just talk about
things you know not supposed to you know
for example if you have a professor or
you teach you know math subject for
example they owe a lot you don't get you
know it's kind of boring but but anyway
let's talk about this tech pesters so
yeah I don't like tech very much and and
it's one of the things you know it's
embraced by all the elite hacker types
of programmers like any opportunity they
tell you like you oh you should use tech
and stuff and tech and I was I was very
disappointed by Donald Knuth because he
he created this thing yeah so before I
was mentioning I I read quite a few of
his books he's found books you know I
tried to read computer art of computer
programming and his other books he has
collected essays and others I didn't
like his stuff I mean they are other you
know computer scientists I do like but
it turns out not much of you know his
style and his of his he's he's kind of
they the nerd he's the typical the nerd
qualifies him in the sense that I'm also
honored but he is the nerd like the he's
the the squarish not funny kind of
you know and he so I don't like his
jokes you know so anyway so so he
created this tech he also created so
cold you know what a literate
programming yeah it despite I
don't despise it but yeah it's stupid
it's City you know all the hacker types
you know they want to like I wanted you
know literate programming it's very
popular in the Emacs oak community and
the back then when Pearl was you know
over the world it's very popular in the
programming community too and usually
these hacker types they don't actually
know what they are doing you know
literate programming is something
specific you know and in you know it's
very silly because literate programming
okay the heart of literate programming
is that you you are a programmer you
actually write for other humans to
understand you don't write to the
machine writing the algorithm I mean for
the machine to understand is only a part
of it it's like the second purpose like
the side effect of your literate
programming you are actually writing an
essay describing the algorithm to other
programmers in other words that is
documentation okay so this relates to
documentation heavily that's that's the
heart of little programming you write
essays community communicating your
algorithms to other human animals okay
all human beings but on so a lot you
know hacker types oh yeah we want to you
know I like literate programming no oh
you know mod you know did you know and
poor people back then you don't hear
them anymore because this this hacker
fat they kind of died away you know then
you have the next new one next next five
years you don't know history you don't
know oh they are this you know poor
people they are so much into it but
anyway so literal programming is about
writing essays for other humans to
understand
but look at you no no you notice all
these people who are a big you know who
talk about literal programming all the
time in Emacs immunity or impro they
don't like write documentation you look
at their stuff they don't know how to
write documentation you know they are
not concerned about technical writing
they are not concerned you know they
have never thought about you know
actually take the time to study
technical writing or documentation it's
like no they don't care about that so
the way the reason they follow you know
they seems to be a fan of literal
programming is purely of the like elite
hacker you know the fad aspect you
because oh this is Knuth created
different programming therefore we're
gonna do literate programming oh yeah
and I'm excited about you know the
terminology of what they have like they
have tell terminology about you know
like like compiling I'm not I forgot the
terms so let's let me read the some
comments so anyone remember what's the
terms for the literate programming like
you have to spit out code like compiling
all much code something like that so
Norman says if you need to write tech
extensions the language is horrible and
as a user you need a lot of time making
small random changes to influence the
layout system direct indirectly yeah
exactly
gp2 says I could never really get into
tech I'm not sure people praise and
swear by it like crazy
it seems really different and too much
effort for simple tasks exactly I mean I
agree with both of these points and and
okay so there was literal programming
but back to the tech so I don't like
tech because okay let me just maybe take
five minutes we can finish this five or
ten minutes so take you know so this
article
you know you can let's see let's talk
JavaScript okay it's already allowed so
let me show you an example okay so it's
suppose you want to write this okay take
the granddaddy of syntax OOP
yeah worse than C sprint you know the
language C created sprint sprint off
sprint F okay I hated that because
that's a like a little language you know
like yesterday we talked about you know
the C you know you my opinion C and UNIX
created everything that's wrong in the
in computing industry so C has this
spring's
f you know you have like you have a
string then you have little you know
percentage sign to do things okay
basic basically you see you know in c +
% and and python they like all these
special syntax sprinkled throughout your
language like if you want to do this
thing you have a special syntax over
here you know if you want to that you
have a special syntax like over there
you have to learn each one of them you
know individually and they are ad hoc
like there is no coherency like like
like there is no simple few principles
that governs everything no it's like
just you know why do you you know I mean
everything is just at heart but anyway
Tech is even worse tech so suppose you
want to create these math expressions so
and this is what it looks like in tech
okay this is what it looks like it's a
it's a crap it's a syntax ooh it's hard
to type and there's no structure now
remember there's no structure okay or
structure you know when you look at math
expressions look at this there is a
structure what do you mean for example
let's look at the first one first of all
this sign greater than greater than
greater than sign okay that's a that's a
specific greater than sign that's I you
can think of it as a function it's a
binary function this sign is it has a
hierarchy higher
hierarchy on the tree then these two so
so this one connects these two okay and
well this one actually connect the left
and right and this one the equal sign
connects the left and right over here
and here okay and for example if we take
this part we can further dissect so this
part the some symbol is at the top then
the K and N equals 1 and the 1 over N is
its arguments basically so this greater
than equal sign the left and right is
its arguments so you can think of it as
functions it has a structure it has a
tree structure similarly for these you
know equal sign has two arguments the
left and right the left left part we
already covered but let's look at the
fraction let's look at this fraction 1
over 3 so fraction is a function it has
two arguments 1 & 3
okay so n plus sign is a also a so
anyway you know it has a tree structure
you know you might know you know
abstract syntax tree it can be converted
to abstraction r3 it has a structure
okay any of these may be any of these
okay so in if you if you use tech you
know to do it it looks like this
basically all structure is lost given
any tech expression you cannot you
cannot recover the original structure of
these of this expression you cannot
recover it now let's look at the
alternative here's the mathematical
syntax now you can see okay let's look
at this one let's magnify okay look look
at this one so you have this okay so
it's a sum then bracket 1 over X okay
sum has two arguments one is one of X
the other one is list of n 1 and K okay
now if you look back ok so
let's still get back the okay I cannot
show both of them at the same time but
you know look at this expression this
one the first one and look at the math
America you can see the mathematical
expression is clear and logical and also
in a simple grammatical way that as a
programming language you can actually
pass it easily
okay so so here are other mathematic
mathematic Wolfram language syntax okay
to represent these math expressions in
fact if you type this in Mathematica you
can press the button and they will be
rendered like these okay math notations
so the first thing about tech is that it
has no let me show you the math America
so this is math America okay you can see
it's rendered you know when you type you
press a button it's rendered into
two-dimensional windowing you know like
like this but what tech does first of
all it it doesn't have structure and it
it basically what the text approach is
that they are like for typesetting so
called typesetting they create you know
little bit map graphics about okay which
number you know to put where you know
maybe you're one pixel up a little bit
or maybe you're a little bit to the
right to pixels you know you you write
these expressions to adjust that you
know like one little fixes over here
that's what tech is the the heart of
tech it's extremely bad you know what
wider hackers types sighted all the time
because first of all the most
fundamental reason is is because it's
free everyone love free things when you
have something free as slow as it's you
know reasonable it does something it
becomes wipes out any competitors
anything that you know you have to pay
it just it's like a virus you know it
wipes out everything like UNIX and Linux
okay you may not agree but I talked
about that it's you know when you have a
free you know you wipe out everything
that's that's one reason that's the most
important reason the second reason is
that oh yeah so the second reason that
elite hacker types you know it's not
suicide the about tech locket every day
is is that is because Donald Knuth you
know he's famous you know he's a
celebrity so in a sense it's like all
the young girls they follow
Kadath ian you know potassium who became
famous because she made a sex tape and
she is now like a billionaire you know
like you know you have like millions ten
millionths hundred minions following
girls for the following her you know her
twitter she posts you know women things
like oh this bikini is $4,000
and other girls you know going to buy it
it's like that so you in programming you
have something similar my eyes gets dry
so in programming you have it's like the
same kind of phenomenon you know Donald
knows created this so all the
programmers go crazy you know not oh you
know the hacker types those types who
think you know they are also hackers
they want to you know follow the hackers
path you know those kind of people so
yeah that's also that's basically why I
don't like take okay the structure in
math expressions I talk about that you
know you can see this simplest
expression is a tree the problem of tech
okay okay so what is alternative you
know actually - I don't really have a
good answer for one thing the one good
alternative is Mathematica but it's from
prior teri and you have to pay so a
hobbyist version is like $200 or
something so that's one way to go
I mean so you have to pay and you buy
man you go to vine research you buy
Mathematica then everything is so it's
wonderful I mean you know you just type
this you know you can do math
complicated math you can program you
know yeah but it's a it's a it's a
commitment you know once you buy
Mathematica well I mean if you are
programmer
you know working your company that's not
too much money for hobbyist version and
you know but I mean you pay you you do
have to pay and once you pay something
you might you know you might do
something with it I mean it's a
commitment if you want to code
Mathematica you actually have to spend
time to learn it to study it to
programming it you know all right pay
your maybe okay maybe you actually have
a need to you know publish math
notebooks all the time you know write
this then it's a good choice
Mathematica which I wrecked I do
recommend you know I I programmed
Mathematica for 10 years every day you
know I'm heavily into it you know I know
it inside out in the 1990s
you know I it's got a book this thick
1000 over 1,000 pages let me show you I
read it from cover to cover three times
in different years in the 1990s fourth
edition is the last printed edition here
so yeah it looks like that this is a
fourth edition this is this one is
stranded around 1999 something like that
oh fifth edition but anyway this they
stopped printing just like every other
companies around you know early 2000s
but anyway this book is like this book
is heavy it is like this thick yeah this
thick
okay so yeah I programmed a lot
Mathematica but I haven't done so for
ten years at least
so yeah what's so what is alternative so
you buy Mathematica that's one
alternative they are they are some other
oh okay let me talk about the other
thing okay math email
now math email is a is a or alternative
it's a XML based technology for the web
so you can you know displace display
math formulas on the web but Google
Chrome kougakyo dead in their browser
like three years ago it's very sad
Google become so evil and and partly
because nobody you know all the geeks
wants to use this you know we love this
but but in reality if you look at the
real world nobody I mean who is true in
mathematics people want YouTube you know
it's not math you know there's no so you
know so Google is not gonna you know get
much out of it you you know they killed
it in their Chrome browser
but anyway math ml is very verbose when
math ml was beginning to be created I
was a wolf and research 1995 you know so
Wolfram research sent representative
representatives to to the w3c you know
committee Oliver to to to help or
participate in the creation of math ml
but anyway it's pretty bad I mean you
got it's extremely verbose I mean look
at this this formula if you want to type
this it's like 100 lines of mathema
email is this one x equals I mean see
yeah this this this one basically
unreadable but anyway math a meow is one
option it's it's not really supported in
Chrome Google Chrome but it's I think
it's your subordinate Firefox but
because of the situation you you could
say it's you know it's not really I
think Wikipedia also supported you have
to go to Wikipedia and log in and turn
go to preferences and turn use you know
logging and say there's a preference you
know you have to say use my math a meow
the otherwise you'll just use a image
like this one you know this one is the
image you know the problem with images
that you cannot copy the advantage of
math email is that you know when you see
a formula like that on a web if it's
using mass email you can just select it
and you get you eat you get sensible you
know copy
you know either mass email itself or
something sensible something like this
okay then you can paste paste it in you
know
I mean language I mean the idea the idea
of math Mao is that it's allowed you
know copy and pasting for example you
can just you see a formula you just copy
it you go to Emacs or whatever
application you just face it and it
becomes a valid you know program and you
can press ENTER and they all run you
know you can just put a value to PC you
know AC and you'll just run so that that
is the that is the advantage that that
is a reason that is part of the reason
okay why this is extremely superior then
then the tech you know the tech you
know when you have tech you you got this
this is nothing you can do it's and it's
very insulting is that it's not
computable you know you the tech you
know and latech is for typesetting you
know oh it does it should generate
pretty pictures it generates bitmaps you
know all vector graphic anyway it's just
generate pictures this you copy is not
computable these things are computable
you know and you can substitute you know
Kate a number and you come out a number
you know we are talking about
programming languages here it's supposed
to be you know Donald glued one of the
premiere you know the the top computer
scientists should should know this you
know you you created this thing it's not
computable it's just for you know pretty
printing things you know what the
and also the way you create the language
the way it's structured you have no
structure so it's pure garbage you know
so yeah so that it's it's great you know
so there are two things you lose
structures and it's not computable I
mean it's not you know it's not actually
you destroyed everything about math you
know this all essentially almost all
math expressions even the abstract
algebra like category theory with arrows
you know you see category Theory diagram
there are arrows they have structures
you know they can they have structures
you know
so essentially oh man
formulas you know you open any physics
book or whatever however complicated
they have structures and there's anyway
so so tech you know you you lose
structures and you you are not
computable you know you and you know and
Guth created he just went into the wrong
path you know you know you cannot play I
mean I cannot blame him because it's not
like I mean I'm because I'm looking at
this from a hint side you know you know
from this point of view you can see oh
they should have you know maybe what
didn't they design it that way in the
beginning but but things that's from
hindsight you know when he designed it
back in 1970s or 1960s late I think
1970s you know he just wanted to create
a digital tap setting system you know
that's for typesetting because back then
there's not even digital typesetting yet
we don't have desktop publishing which
Apple kind of brought you know created
in the 1990s you know so he just want a
computable type typesetting system to
help him print his the other programming
book that's our engine of tech you know
he want to you know he write this book
and he want beautiful fonts and stuff
and there's you know difficulties so
that's why he created tech to do that
but but from today's point of view or
you know even from 1990s you can see
it's really bad in many ways it's a
wrong direction you know it's it's just
not the right direction how you want to
go so Mathematica is alternative math
math a meow is an alternative of course
if you use math America it can export it
can export to tech or math email or
images you know then
okay I think that's about it I think
it's let's see questions yeah Norman
says amusingly you can export latech
from Mathematica
well because Mathematica is a you know
company they want to make money when
when people use Mathematica they want
the future you know otherwise why am i
buying this for because as a matter of
fact you know the scientific community
many of them except you know they
require tech and low tech you know so
Mathematica is a tool you know the U has
that feature so you get your money was
you know you can write Mathematica and
you can export to latech or you know
others but you cannot use so break the
loop says okay let me go to the top okay
break the loop says you cannot use
Mathematica to write and print math
notes so what is the alternative
what do you mean you cannot you can i
mean well you can use Mathematica and to
write and print math notes you can you
can print it out I mean you can you know
you start in Mathematica notebook just
like today's Jupiter
you know today there's a jupiter
notebook very very popular in python
communities you can you can just type it
in it and and print out your printout
with you know formulas or the math
formulas unless you mean something else
okay so then daniel says expensive
proprietary system Mathematica speeding
graphics to are fantastic for
exploratory visualization yes it has
very general purpose graphics yes
okay the gnosis but consider Mathematica
doesn't have a good Emacs interface of a
way of support in Mathematica mod
it was back in 1990s it has you know
many Emacs programmers has view has
written Emacs interface to Mathematica
you know the way Mathematica works is
that it's an application I mean you can
think of it of it as a application or
you can think of it it as a programming
language now for vast majority of people
who use Mathematica just for you know do
any math like they want to find the
integral of something you know
derivative or solving equations you know
they are using it just like an app like
a calculator so there's no actual
programming involved I mean you just
type some equation like solve then type
some equation you press ENTER you'll
give you the solution or differential
equations you know solutions and so on
all matrices or multiplication of
matrices and so on you know you use it
as a calculator or you want to plot you
know 3d stuff or surfaces and so on so
most people scientists you know a lot of
people in in NASA for example they use
Mathematica you know these scientific
organizations so that's one way to use
it but but then sometimes you get more
advanced like you solve some equations
but but you need to combine these two
solutions and maybe you know maybe sort
them you know and then select some part
such that they satisfy some other
equation no constraints then that's your
final thing you want you know like
engineering engineering you know the
scientists or maybe physics you know so
once you get the next step you know
besides using it as a calculator you a
little bit programming is involved but
of course because then you start to
review it as a programming language
because then you can get more and more
involved you know because for example I
wrote many packages in Mathematica to do
things you know to the to the
visualization
and in stuff for example it's nice go to
handcuff notations suck some ass so I
wrote this packing this is back in 1997
visual dictionary of special pain curves
1995 2 to 97 so you have many of these
has animations let's see so all these
are created in Mathematica back then so
let's let's look at this is a
cauliflower interesting fractal and also
they the shape is a equiangular spyro
equiangular because from the center you
shoot out a line called array in any
direction you will contact the curve the
angle is always constant like 80 degrees
here that's why it's called equiangular
spyro of course the degree can be
different so if the do are different you
got different shape of curves
it's called equiangular spyro but also
known more popularly known as a log
spiral
log spiral anyway so let me show you a
animation so let's let's see that you
know so I wrote Mathematica notebook
this packing you know 1995 to create
these animations today you don't need my
package it's much easier because math
mica in the past 20 years they have
added lots of things so it's much more
easier you know it you to create this
just one line you know so back then I
wrote a package that does this you know
so the package is like few hundred lines
but but you just have a function then
you can just one line or just a function
you can create this animation but today
is is kind of like building
so yeah so that one I'm talking about
Mathematica so you you can see it as a
programming language so yeah okay back
then okay
Mathematica so it's an application right
but actually it comes in two parts so it
comes in two components one is called
the kernel one is called the front end
so the kernel is kind of like the engine
that actually does all the computation
the front end is actually what you see
the notebook you can think of it as a
IDE for Mathematica the default editor
in other words so the kernel actually do
the computation so whereby on the in a
notebook when you click Mathematica it
opens a notebook you type and you press
ENTER you know they say solve equation
solve some equations gives you the
answer what actually happens is that
when you press ENTER the the front end
it's called the front end the notebook
okay the front end sends messages to the
kernel in a protocol code you used to be
called math link I'm not sure what's
called today I think they might have
changed the name the protocol was called
math link so anyway the the funnyand
sense that since out the equation to the
kernel the kernel computes and responds
sends response to the front end then the
front end display the result so that's
how it works so it has two parts
now obviously the kernel can be anywhere
it can be young a remote server it can
be you know but even on your desktop
it's it's different you have a kernel
you have a front end so you can have 100
person login to use the kernel so that's
how it works
so people has written Emacs front end to
connect to the mathematical kernel so
you use Emacs you type something you
press Enter it sends it to the Cano and
the colonel since reply then it shows
result in a in emacs so that was one way
to use Mathematica back then but today
you can still find Emacs package for
Mathematica but it's not well developed
because because most people just use
notebook you know because notebook and
display graphics animations sound you
know it's hard to do in Emacs you know
you can kind of but it's it's it's hard
you know so you don't get much you know
and and the person who writes that you
know open source you don't get paid so
you know it it's not very popular so
anyway that's it for today for 100
minutes any any questions I think that's
it for today so we covered we covered
quite a few things about low-level
programming about assembly languages
about instruction architecture
instruction set architecture about Guth
mm IX instruction set about then about
math notations so thank you guys for
coming have a great day bye