Hi everyone.
I'm going to show you unboxing of the
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard.
So, this is the palm rest.
Okay, so they sent it to me free.
And uh
you know, for for my review.
And this is the keyboard. So, I'm going
to
unbox it.
Okay, let's see how it goes.
So, I'm going to put that away.
And uh
open this.
So, power supply Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard.
Okay, the net The nice thing about it is
that they have this new technology.
They have this uh new technology, this
uh track trackball.
Uh trackball and track trackpad,
trackball and thumb thumb um
pointer.
So, but you have to buy them extra and
they attach like that.
You know, that's really nice. Uh it's
not out yet, so uh you have to wait.
Okay, so So, let's see. Let me open
that.
Okay, so you have to peel this off.
Actually, I don't I don't think you'd
have to. It should just slide open.
It doesn't slide.
Yes.
It's like that.
Just the cover.
Okay, so now
No, I don't want to tear the box because
you know, so
cuz this looks like a nice box.
Okay, there it is.
Ta-da!
Cover.
And now I'm trying to see how much how
how much does it weigh.
Okay, there's this
this box which is wire. That's very
nice.
Uh
Okay, that's the wire
with the looks like a mini mini phone
jack.
Like
super mini
phone jack.
Screws, a bunch of screws, tiny screws.
And this is
like attachments.
Like attached to the box or something.
So that's the
wire in between.
And this is the USB wire.
Okay, so one one side is uh standard
USB.
The other side is
mini USB. I think that's mini USB.
So, the keyboard itself, okay, it's very
nice. It's very solid and compact.
Uh it's not too heavy and it's not super
light. Some keyboard is super light.
This is I would say average. Um half a
pound, maybe.
Let's see how it works.
Okay, this is great.
How
are you
doing uh doing uh
today?
I am feeling my
key key
board testing. Very nice. Uh they come
in These are mechanical keys. They come
in in several choices. Like you can
I think you can choose from uh Cherry MX
red or blue or brown and black, I think.
All those are available. And I pick red
because
I want red. Red Red is linear, like the
the least resistance in linear.
Red and black are both linear. Black is
stronger resistance. And and brown is
tactile.
Uh like you can feel a bump. Red,
there's no bump bump.
And blue is tactile, but also with
audible click. Like click click click,
it's loudest.
But
okay, so
So, this is red heavy.
It It feels very compact. It's very big
well built. So So
So this is a front.
And this is the back.
I'm going to Yeah, why don't I plug it
in? And actually I'm going to do more,
you know, typing and trying it out and
probably will do another video review.
But for now let's just plug in and I'm
also going to take it apart because it
can
split into two.
So I'm just going to plug it in right
here.
Without reading any manuals.
But hold on a second. I want to see if I
can, you know, just take it this parts
right now.
Uh actually I should I better read
manuals.
Because I don't want I don't want to
break it.
So but I can probably just plug it in
though.
Where is he?
Okay, it does not go there and does not
go there. So
Yeah, it goes somewhere else. Obviously
these two goes here.
So this I can
pick.
Click.
Okay, but there's no more holes on the
outside.
So, it must be
Oh, there it is. It's right here.
You see?
It's there.
So,
let's just do that.
Let's
So, you can see
here.
I don't know. Let me make sure.
I'm not so sure.
Okay, it's in.
It's actually a bit hard.
See?
Actually, my my Mac just pop popped up a
um
you know, telling me that a new keyboard
is there.
So, now it's it's working. Oh, it's
light.
Oh, well, let's see if I can actually
type.
Uh go to my Emacs.
Okay.
Okay, what's
control
No, I'm uh
Let me open text editor, so
Because I'm using Dvorak, so I want to
make sure I don't know if it's Dvorak or
QWERTY.
Oh, so this is right now it's QWERTY and
uh it's switched to
Dvorak.
There it is. A E O U
Okay, so so so this is unboxing and I'm
going to play with it and I'm going to
show you what's what are the features
and how to take it apart.
See you soon.