good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show good I'm alive
today is 2019 July 18th 3 o clock p.m.
San Francisco time
today's topic is programming and
programming languages ok and we have a
appointment with some of my readers you
know yesterday so we set up a time today
you know I hope they come so today's
topic is gonna be programming kind of
random ish topics you know the
programming related stuff so let's go to
first first of all go to my programming
block ok and ok starting Firefox
programming block let's move it
here so you can see my window that's
good
ok programming so what we gonna talk
about today I don't know actually I just
scramble good morning good morning guys
good money say hi so it's for the date
you know I wait for people to come maybe
so this ad hoc show today's date topic
random ok programming related
programming and programming languages
fascinating subject okay and hey guys
type your thoughts okay tab it here so
that's the topic so what is so what are
we going to talk about okay let's let's
talk about let's see I need to review
this alko why does this this one is very
interesting topic let's talk about that
what does symbolic language mean now if
you code this if you know any Emacs list
scheme this skin this racket skin this
Oh
Crozier or Mathematica also known as
Wolfram language then you notice that
this language is still with symbols you
have I'm gonna show you okay I can't I
can do as some demo symbols okay let me
show you one one obvious example of
symbols
okay this let's start on a second let's
let's do this since I mean Emacs I'm
going to show my Emacs commands for
those of you who are using Emacs okay so
on a second so saw start command lock
mod okay now in this window you can see
every command I call you max you know if
you are Emacs user that's useful
so we let's go back to three people okay
say hi okay say hi here and so we cannot
so what is symbolic programming language
let me show you okay sing symbolic now
if you coding emag miss view we all know
okay hold on a second so oh wait so this
emag be okay so Emacs elise okay now i
show the code let's say magnify let's
say first one two okay I evaluate the
code you can see three at the bottom
maybe you cannot see it but let me show
you then okay so let's open a new window
and let's go to the messages but this is
where all Emax messages come out you
know error messages or whatever so it
here so you see let's do one plus three
okay well now second we need to move it
down so let's let's do one plus three
okay evaluate you can see the result is
four
let's eMac eMac sleaze okay now so let's
sit let's set X equal to three okay
evaluated okay it's done
now let's message you know which means
print X okay evaluated you can see the
result here three you know it's a string
you know because you are printing a
message it so it's like print you can
use also use print right away but we are
not you know this is not a tutorial
about eMac this you know that's some
other day so anyway so so so you can so
we have now set X equal to three now
there's interesting thing about symbolic
languages now this X is symbol the same
thing that you know this six set Q this
message they are all symbols and what
does that mean that means you can get X
without it becoming three so maybe this
is strange to you but let me you know if
I show you a Python example you are
knowing you you will know let's let's
start let's do JavaScript then okay so
let's go open a new buffer and let's see
console.log wait let's say constant x
equals three three okay let's just say
let X equal to three and now let's
console.log print X okay now this is
JavaScript now I'm gonna run it you can
see the output here three you see but
once the variable has a value you know
that you don't have the X anymore I mean
perhaps this is how do I explain this
let's go back to Lisp okay eMac this VC
in Emacs Lisp you can print the value of
x but however you can also print the
symbol itself now look at this okay
let's comment this out and let's call
this evaluate this buffer okay remove
that okay let's keep it so evaluate the
bottle and what we get
let's see message okay so okay yeah
evaluate this line you see you got this
kind of like a string you got a string X
well yeah because this week we so you
got a string and but this thing is
symbol
let's see symbol symbol Q okay
let's see describe function symbol okay
our symbol P you know why is not showing
up not Q min P P okay now sing Bob he
tells you what whether something is a
symbol let's say three let's do this
okay message message then we say we
print symbol three that tells you
whether three whether emac be considered
this thing is a symbol let's evaluate
that let's evaluate that this this
window it's knowing neil okay you see
the result there evaluate you see it
says knio knio means force you know so
this three is not a symbol but however
if we do this again let's say let's say
do let's say let's check if symbol X is
a symbol let's run it it says new okay
now but if we can we can do this then we
run it it says T team is true okay so
you see so the point I'm trying to say
is that in Lisp any any identifier you
know so-called identifier in other
languages in list they are a symbol and
same thing with Mathematica so it's so
that that is why sometimes it's heard
you know it said they are symbolic
languages now in Python or JavaScript
you cannot do that you know like you
have identifier identifier is you know
evaluates to a value or you know whether
it's a name of a function you know it
itself is not something that it exists
you know it's just an identifier so do
you see what I mean so do we have people
five people so say hi okay so where did
those yesterday the path hello Jas sky
where did he go how
you hear okay so anyway so let's see
yeah see okok so anyway so I just
demonstrate a little bit what you know
the symbol that the symbol in Emacs list
and this is a semi in other list for
example scheme racket kosher Common Lisp
they they all basically have you know
they are like this you know they all
have you know you have symbols so the
question so the question I'm asking is
what does symbolic language mean I mean
yeah okay so you know we understand that
instead of identifiers you you have like
the simple concept but what does it do
like what is the utility I mean why do
you have symbols that is the question so
I was you know because this is this is
interesting because I was a mathematical
program for like 15 years from 1992 to
you know to about 2005 I haven't have
encoded Mathematica for like 10 years
but you know I was a heavy mathematical
coder and also I am a lisp coder you
know especially email is so you have
these languages you have symbols but
what does it what is the significance
that's an interesting question you see
sometimes you people you know you wonder
so what's the difference between Lisp
and other languages I can tell you what
what is the difference the number one
the most fundamental primary difference
of these languages and others is that
list has symbols this concept you don't
find basically you you you you don't
find in any languages like not in Perl
Python Ruby well I think ubios you know
not in them not in Perl Python Ruby
JavaScript Java C C++ even Haskell has
Kokomo you
have cymbals anyone any of them although
in Ruby and JavaScript you you you have
something like a simple type but that
but that's that's that's not the same
thing because in Lisp every identifier
like every one every one of them you
know
variable names function name speeding
function names operator names such as
you know and even even the plus sign
it's a symbol okay for example let's see
let's see you know if the plus sign is a
symbol let's run it it says true you see
so in these languages everything is
simple it's called symbolic languages so
what so what is useful what what is the
purpose I mean what what is the
significance the significance is that I
learned you know this article I wrote I
wrote in 2005 wait no I did not write
this in 2005 that's a mistake so right
let's correct that okay so let's correct
this let's go to so I must I wrote this
in 2016 not 2005 and it's update yeah so
2016 so I wrote this I asked the
question so it turns out it seems the
answer is that the significance of
symbols in language like this symbolic
language is that they allow rule-based
transformation rule based programming
you know it's called rule-based trans
programming or also known as firmly
rewriting languages terms rewriting
system you know if you you may not have
heard of that that you can see on
Wikipedia term rewriting and rewriting
systems let's see rewriting okay let's
go through this
Harco so so he says in mathematics ink
and computer science in logic the
writing covers a wide range of
potentially non deterministic methods of
replacing sub terms of a formula with
other terms okay
the objects of focus for this Alko
includes rewriting systems okay in their
most basic form they consist of a set of
objects plus relations on how to
transform those objects okay well but
you know this this article gets a bit
abstract
but basically what happens is that under
direct rewriting system is that you can
transform can read the writing system is
that term rewriting pattern matching
okay yeah you know term rewriting system
that's kind of a technical mathematical
computer science term but in practice
what you have is a basically pattern
matching symbolic pattern matching okay
meaning that you know for example
regular expression now regular
expression is not term is not am
rewriting okay it's not symbolic time
already regular expression is a you know
you know it works on strings basically
you can you know replace a patterns in
strings into some other string so that's
a replace you know that's that that's
kind of like that's a that's that is
actually technically also autumn
rewriting system but anyway in most
languages when you have a regular
expression you work it works on string
datatype now in Lisp in Mathematica in
particular you have
you have you know you have regular
expression but you also have what's
called symbolic pattern matching so what
is what is symbolic Pat imagined it
basically is just like regular
expression except you don't it's not
working on strings it's not you know
refacing part of the string rather you
replace the whole source code for
example this is a pattern now for
example this pattern for example this
pattern I can make it a string for
example in let's see okay so for example
now it's a string then I can use regular
expression to you know maybe you know
find out which you know this part and
this part in the middle and this part
you know I can start to pass it you know
and maybe we place this part by some
other thing but the whole thing must be
a string that's regular expression but
when you have symbolic pattern matching
you know you are not dealing with
strings rather you deal with this this
whole thing whole expression directory
so you can create a pattern in
Mathematica for example you know at
least doesn't have it what what this is
has has is Marcos we'll talk about that
but anyway so this you know the whole
source code is a pattern and you can you
can write a rule like pattern
replacement you know like regular
expression to replace any part of it you
know so that that is what symbolic
pattern matching is now in okay mo in
Haskell those you know functional
languages they also have pattern
matching but their pattern matching is
not symbolic because you know their
language is not symbolic so so what what
they do is that when they have a pattern
matching they match on the values of
expressions
you know any expression like a variable
or more complicated expression for
example at least a structure at least a
hash table you know expression you know
that's an expression you can match you
know you can match the pattern let's say
the first element versus the rest
element you know that's a common pattern
in Haskell or scheme you know these kind
of languages you know you can you can
find out you know the first element
versus the rest element then you can
replace you know the list by the rest
you know or any other elements your last
element or you know the third element
things like that pattern matching they
match on the expressions value typically
the structure you know like a list or a
structure or the type sometimes also
type are part of the pattern matching so
for example if you have a list of many
things you know if you have a list of
elements and each element is also a list
okay let's say but the first element of
that list may be some of them may be a
number some of them may be a string you
know for example but you want to filter
the whole thing you want only lists that
the first element is a number for
example so you can use pattern matching
for that you know you just say the first
element of a list you know this needs a
pattern the first element must have the
type number so that's has cow and Oh
camel you know I don't know this
languages in you know I don't really
know them but that's what I understand
that that is the situation for their
pattern matching system it's based you
know they match a value of expressions
typically by the structure and type you
know especially like you know camel
Hesco they are strongly typed but how is
it different from symbolic pattern
matching symbolic pad imagine because
it's symbols you know it does for
example this whole source file this
whole file is a sequence of care
that's a pattern you know it's almost
like a string but it's not a string so
you you can now match the whole thing
you know the whole thing without you
know not evaluating you know like any of
these not evaluating them you know you
are matching the raw source code that's
symbolic pattern matching now the the
more the most obvious example in Lisp is
called Marcos you know I don't you know
list Marcos is very idiotic because list
Marco is the you can you know it's
actually the the creep horde kind of the
beginning form of symbolic pattern
matching it's like you know very small
subset of it but I'm not going to call
the list Marcos I never cook I don't I
don't I do not ever use this Marcos
speaker because I think it's idiotic you
know so but anyway that's the most
famous example and you know many
languages they think because of lists so
many other languages such such as Julia
I think you know they they say in their
feature least they say oh we we also
have Marcos you know like this that's
not good what you should have is pattern
matching and you know for languages
those for languages that are not
symbolic you know I don't think julia is
a symbolic language so when they try to
do Marco's they are create they are kind
of like I suppose they are kind of
creating some you know idiosyncratic way
you know it's not systematic you see the
the reason this you know you have
symbolic language the whole thing is
symbols is that so that the whole you
know source code can be treated as like
as the data as they say you know as you
know you in earth you can choose to
evaluate it or you can choose not to
evaluate it you know just take the whole
source code or part of the source code
like exhibition unit then you can do
transformation on it that's what this
marquel does but this macro is very you
know very rigid and not is you know it's
very it's kind of a hack what you really
want is symbolic pattern matching
that's the fool you know let's say you
know let's say symbolic pattern matching
feature of Mathematica has you know 100
things you know let's say score 100 then
this Marco is like 5% you know like 1%
of it so that's a that's the gap that's
that's how that's how different they are
you know between these smokers versus
the symbolic a true symbolic Pat imagine
in Mathematica by the way there are
other symbolic pattern matching through
languages so they you know used
sometimes they are called terms
rewriting systems so are you any guys of
you here so say hi okay say come and put
post comments or opinions okay yeah that
way that you know the talk gets better
because I otherwise I don't know where
to go but anyway so let's go back to the
I'm talking about the okay here is an
article for liberation of computer
languages this I wrote in 2008 because
beginning new material story beginning
in 2008 or around there you know 2005 to
2008 okay I would say you start to
notice that there are so many more and
more languages everyday you know that's
the beginning 2008 not before that
basically you know around 2008 or seven
you know
so this that so this this is my
observation you know this is my the
information I want to give out because
when you ask other programmer so the
programming forums later
you know the
News 8 on the you know vast majority of
their opinions are just crass so anyway
into so so what I'm saying I'm telling
you that if you observe you know as a
part of human history you know if you
say if you historians look at computer
languages you know there is a period of
time around 2000 late 2000s that we
started to see a explosion of computer
languages okay that is what I'm saying
you know historians we all have this
item and that is around 2008 and okay so
you know so I started I wrote this
article and some some of my opinions you
know then is a collection of languages
like new languages for example this this
language pure is a pattern matching
language pure is a dynamically typed
functional programming language based on
term rewriting okay it has facilities
for user-defined
operators syntax mark was multiple
precision numbers and compilation to
native code blah blah blah you know
Wikipedia wanted to remove at one time
Wikipedia I wanted to remove this
article pure came from another language
called Q which was like they try to
improve it by the same guy I think I
haven't tried the language by the way so
stable released April 2018 okay so it
looks like still active but I've never
heard anyone else mention it though this
language pure but anyway this is a
pattern and you know this language can
do pattern matching now okay so for me
the next next question is is is this
language symbolic I don't know so that
would be interesting to know because
that's related to our question
because you know I don't know I have
still things to learn so I don't know if
is it true that or some rewriting
systems necessarily require the language
to be symbolic like you know like the
way Lisp or Mathematica is is that true
I do not know for sure so you know pure
would be something you know I have to
look into but anyway this article you
know I list a bunch of new languages you
are pure you have voila Genie you have
factor you have phantom phantom language
I don't have a logo you know
CoffeeScript is kind of bad
you have dot is also kind of dead Google
Google start they are trying to replace
JavaScript by Java that's what that is
that is that is Java in that is
JavaScript in Java syntax and also in
Java semantics basically that is
everything is just like Java okay Google
wants to make JavaScript to become Java
like no good and they fail you know they
didn't nobody is using it but they are
still like alive though they are still
you know doing something with it at one
point they try to they try to tell other
browsers to put dart into into the
browser they they try to tell Microsoft
in Firefox and both refused this is like
you know five words five years ago so
they all refused Apple also refused you
see so there is the article I what do
Microsoft Apple Mozilla say about that
you know they all refused
hey good morning Lynch what
what do you know about SQL corrupting no
I don't know nothing about that what
does that mean
it's SQL corrupting yeah so what does I
mean so anyway this page you know at
least of languages typescript go lost
Judea Oh meta Elm you know there's so
many hacks hack swift elixir cuddling
named Crystal you know name is name
language is very fast
it's like Python you know Python in with
C speed
that's what name is like crystal is like
Ruby with C speed that's crystal is like
pirate is like Lisp in Python syntax
that's what toilet is like pirate is
basically created by this you know the
racket scheme people because scheme you
know this basically failed they you know
so they had to they they started to you
know use the Python like language pirate
Python syntax then you have pure script
you know you have so many there is an
explosion of languages so what so let's
go back to this so what does symbolic
language means so okay let's summarize
Mathematica and Lisp
these are languages that are so-called
symbolic that is every identifier every
name every variable name function name
even operators they are symbols and they
don't you know the it so a symbol has a
value or it may not have a very or it
may may be kept unevaluated so when
symbol is evaluated to a value then
similar to other languages for example
various variables becomes a number or a
string or something a function for such
as message
you know it's it's a value is a function
it does something but every every
identifier in Lisp or Mathematica they
can be hold unevaluated in this
whiskered quote like this okay
or it can also be written like this I'm
gonna show you
oops quote X okay so this quote X this
is exactly exactly the same as that this
and this are exactly the same they are
syntactically equivalent meaning that
when this compiles it these two things
are exactly the same
before you even start to compare the
code you know yeah so in Lisp it's
called quote equating it's called
quoting a symbol meaning it means do not
evaluate this symbol you know like do
not evaluate it instead what you want is
the symbol itself
the symbol itself so that's you know
this Mathematica are symbolic so what is
the purpose of symbolic languages that
is my question and as as far as I
understand as far as I understand the
symbolic language the purpose of
cymatics languages is that they they
allow symbolic pattern matching which in
other words is they allow the feature of
terminal rewriting term rewriting okay
meaning that you can take the whole
source code or the expression of a
source code in a symbolic form you know
basically it just means you can
transform you can do transformation on
the source code okay that is what term
rewriting or pattern new duo based
pattern matching means rule based is
it's also called rule based programming
because a rule is basically like specify
which pattern should become which like a
transformation rule so
you have a bunch of transformation rule
so when an expression is evaluated for
example when this expression is
evaluated the system will try to see if
the pattern matches you know of the some
of the rules if it matches then that
rule will apply so the pattern you know
that your your expression becomes
something else you know it got
transformed so that's rule based
programming or the the the the feature
is called symbolic pattern matching and
the mathematical term for this kind of
system is called term rewriting system
okay so that's a you know that's that's
so so the purpose of symbolic language
it seems to me is so that they can they
can have this root term rewriting they
can front they can
it is a it is a way to achieve the
feature of symbolic pattern matching
yeah that's how you say it but what I do
not know is whether it is a necessary
requirement that is if you are going to
do term rewrite if you if you are going
to create a term rewriting system
language do you require that your
language be symbolic that is a question
you know the way like least well
mathematically that is the question I
don't know okay that kind that that kind
of concludes my discussion about this
but there's one addition let me mention
okay so least you know in Mathematica
they are symbolic and they do you know
they allow pattern matching symbolic
pattern matching or transformation of
code but why why is this useful I mean
what is it useful what I mean what is
the actual use of that
the actual use well in a lisp you have
Marcos you know which allows you to it
has some you know it's useful because it
allows you to hold some expression until
and evaluate them at Adelaide you know
it allows you actually to transform the
code let me talk about let me show one
example then for example if okay let's
see if okay so if if x equals so let's
say if X okay
message okay let's just do that let's
say that you know we have a if
expression if X is true then print yes
otherwise print no now if it's like a
function you know because in this every
basically the beginning of a parenthesis
is a function so if it's a function
typically a function will evaluate the
first argument then I mean the argument
to a function you know we have a if if
it's a function and right now we have
three arguments X and that and and that
you know three arguments now normally
when a function when you call a function
with arguments the arguments itself
themselves will be evaluated so X will
become three for example and this
message will print right away like
evaluate your B that you value so it
will print yes and then here it will
print no and so normally it's okay okay
normally when you call a function all
the arguments will be evaluated but if
you have a function like if this doesn't
work because the
if is that you don't want some of the
you know you only want to evaluate
depending on this condition so you have
a problem here you have a problem how do
you feel so the question here is how do
you write a function how do you write
your own if function you cannot because
well when you call a function all the
arguments get evaluated
you know you so that is the issue but in
list you can do that because mark was so
what does that mean is that you can
define a function called my if okay
let's say my if okay you can let's say
let's copy that my if okay you can
define a function your own my if such
that when it is called the arguments all
the arguments are not evaluated you know
they are rather they are held in in
their symbolic form just like that they
are not evaluated then in the function
in the in Europe in a body of your
function you can you can tell it Lisp to
you know how do you want to transform
these this expressions you know in your
body of the code you can say okay if if
X is true then then you evaluate this
argument okay otherwise then you
evaluate that argument so that's how you
rather if by a chemical you can say if
Marco you know that's how you do it but
I don't use smoker so I'm not very
familiar with the syntax and or and to
show you so I cannot show you I should
get prettier like if I prepare you know
I'll be able to but you know I don't use
Marcos because you know so anyway so
that's what Marco in Lisp is about they
limit this review they allows you to
hold expressions like don't evaluate it
then in the body of the marker you can
tell you know the language how you can
do transformation you like it like you
can do whatever you want you can
manipulate you know the argument you
know then you can tell you know when to
evaluate a certain part of it
that's what Marco does this Marco which
which is a witch so this is the
beginning of pattern matching remember
we talked about pattern matching Solis
Marcos is like a very small part of the
whole symbolic pattern matching because
holding the form and you know
transformation that's what pattern
matching is about that's the whole topic
of pattern matching symbolic pattern
matching
okay so okay so you have Marcos and you
have Panama trees and what else is it
useful I mean so what so the most useful
about symbolic pattern matching is in
computer algebra in computer algebra for
example you have for example X first Y
okay let's say raised to the power of 3
you know something like that
you know 30 okay you want to you want to
expand that for example if you don't
know math if you don't know Matt let me
show you so this expression means for
example this expression means that and
that will become x squared plus 2xy plus
y squared okay
so if you multiply this out will become
that but now what if you have that how
do you gonna do what you're gonna do or
or if you have that for example you want
to factor it how you know you want to
get this form to this form you know you
want to factor polynomials how do you do
it you know so this is this is when
symbolic Padme
rule based programming you know the
transformation of code sequences becomes
critical becomes very useful in computer
algebra and also other examples are you
know derivatives linear algebra you know
linear algebra you have a matrix times a
vector you know to you know 10 by 10
matrix times a vector u and you know you
can do it numerically but sometimes you
want it symbolically you want those you
know symbolically if let me show you an
example so it's also used for example
matrix okay M equals 2 so we have that 2
1 2 1 2 okay so 3 4 so that's the matrix
okay and a vector is for example a B
okay let's replace so so let's say a b c
d okay let's say the vector XY okay now
you want to multiply them out so makes
matrix x alone second let me write it
out
so if you have a matrix and you know a
vector and if you want to multiply them
M times V and the result will be a X
plus B Y okay and C X plus the Y that
that is a symbolic result so if you you
know what if you want a programming
language that can you know you can
define a matrix like that you can define
vector and you want this result notice
that you wanted symbolic you know you
don't want you know in the beginning you
don't have numbers you know you don't
want numbers you want this that is so
that is when that's that's called
computer algebra you can computer
algebra systems that is why you want to
use that is when the rule based
programming the pattern matching
symbolic pattern matching becomes
extremely useful so Lynch no more
questions about that SQL what was the
question SQL corruption corruption so
otherwise I think that's it nobody is
commenting what happened to that methyl
Oh meow jay is my god yesterday he said
he's gonna come up so I think that's it
for today then you know we talked about
yeah forty minutes we spend 15 minutes
talking about symbolic languages that's
a you know good topic so the question is
what does you know what's the
significance
I don't know the hunt the answer 100
percent yet you know because you know
I'm exploring you know they say as long
as you are alive you are learning
there's always something to learn so I'm
still Ronnie so I wanted to know what is
the
so let me let me ask let me talk about
so why is this question important what
does it matter
okay you have some language are symbolic
some are not why I mean is it important
to know why does symbolic language me I
mean it's just a feature I mean you can
say okay some language they just design
like that they have symbols that's it
but but my point is that you see here is
the question that makes this question
interesting okay you see as programmers
we usually think about we often people
talk about a you know perfect ideal
general language you know people are
thinking you know wouldn't it be great
if we have one general-purpose language
and this language is so well designed
that you know you can it can do anything
like it's a general-purpose language but
it's a way of design you can do you know
lots of things so here's the interesting
thing about that now first of all the
question you want to ask is that okay so
you have this idea of generic purpose
language question does your ideal
language does it can it do can it solve
equations like you know can it expand
polynomials like this is a simple
problem you just multiply a polynomial
out or symbolic compute the matrix in
vector you know multiplication product
symbolically so does your
general-purpose language do that so what
do you say I mean what do you say did
your idea of general-purpose do you
think it's good to have that you know
this so in my opinion this are really
significant you know this math symbolic
processing it's it's great to have it
should be ideally okay you know we are
talking about ideal general focus
languages so ideally it should in
rude this kind of capabilities okay it
should you know I do generic generic
purpose language now the next question
is okay so if you if you want your
language to be able to do symbolic you
know this math computer algebra you know
the basic at least the basic ones then
is it required that your language be
symbolic like the way Lisp in
Mathematica ah you know that's a
question that's an interesting question
so if if it is required then we have a
problem so you if it's required then you
can see that all today's or the
general-purpose language Java goal and
pro Python Ruby you know all of them
they are not symbolic
so this oh so to us you know to the us
you know the programmers who want a
generic I do generate programming
language all these are crap you know all
the all those languages failed you know
goal and rust rust : Haskell oh they
they are failures they all failed
because they cannot simply do as such a
simple simple thing as a symbolic matrix
matrix multiplication you know they
cannot even do that so they failed so
that is why this question is interesting
on the other hand if in order to do
symbolic come you know basic symbolic
computation computer algebra if you it
is not required that the language be
symbolic the wait lists are then you
know that's a good answer then that
means okay goal and Haskell or whatever
or something you might think of you know
creating you know it's possible you know
you can do that so that that is about
that today for today's talk
so NIC Nikolas leo says pizza I would
like to learn more about Lisp macros
because there are some interesting uses
of meta programming in julia also
similar to template
metaprogramming is simplest press okay
okay so some some questions let me
answer okay so so Nick close question
about so he likes to learn more about
this macro and he says that because they
are you know applications of meta
programming in Judea and also template
metaprogramming is suppressed first okay
okay so do you have a question or is
that just a comment okay so you know in
C prospers in Judea
so yeah they also have there are few
things to talk about that okay so one so
one of the thing you know interesting
topic is is what is the nature you know
what what is the nature of Marko in
Julia and what is the nature of macro in
C++ you know severs process these
templates
I don't really know see purpose and I
don't know Julia neither so you know in
pursuit about question about somatic
programming it would be nice to know so
it's something to look into
so you have to like you know spend a
month or a week study I would you know I
would have to study C press first you
know you know exactly what's their
template system and study Julia Marco
see how they differ from least you know
things like that and how they compare to
you know the real symbolic pattern
matching off the bat I think they are
you know they are not comparable to
symbolic pattern matching they are just
like little tricks here and there I
don't know yeah that's what I think
because because the Lisp you know Marco
is like that it's like as I mentioned
before if this Marco is a feature then
symbolic pattern matching system in
Mathematica would be like ten times
more powerful it's like 10 times you
know stuff so anyway so so Lynch is
beginning to learn programming so what
you should learn first so if you are
like average I mean if you are normal
you know the primary thing you would be
concerned is you know be able to find a
job with the language so so in that
respect Python is good to learn colon is
good to learn as a first language okay
so yeah so you know like if you ask this
question to different people they they
will give you different answers like
every language you know depending on
which language they are a fan of but in
general has cow is good I mean I'm not
Haskell
okay Python Python is good to go so ruby
is also good Ruby Python JavaScript is
kind of screwed up but yeah it's not
really good for beginner beginning
language you know colon colon is okay
yeah I would say so
: Ruby Python okay so yeah so I haven't
worked with supers first I don't even I
haven't i never coded simplest first
actually so then your ylang-ylang grow
is good morning Mathematica have mark
was my god well you did you just came to
the show because the whole hour we were
talking about that we were talking about
the details of lease markers in
Mathematica let me answer the question
okay actually there are people who ask
that does Mathematica have markers the
answer is Mathematica the programming
language in the whole the entire
language is is based on the symbolic
pattern matching or it's also known as
rule-based programming or in academia
it's known as a term rewriting system
the whole thing how Mathematica computes
is Marcos okay that's what I'm trying to
say for the past 15 minutes the entire
language there are two ways Mathematica
computes one way is just like every
normal language you define a function
you have loops you have you know you do
functional programming you know that's
one way but the other half is symbolic
pattern matching meaning that whenever
you write a function it's not actually a
function it's rather it's a it's a rule
that tells you which pattern becomes
what other pattern that works as a
function so when Mathematica sees our
expression it does you know it tries to
see which rule applies when it applies
it used the rule to do a transformation
of the expression then that we saw that
the whole thing be pedes until there is
no more rule matches you know it's like
a grammar when you write a compiler a
parser
it's you know that's you know it's like
that that's that's called symbolic
pattern matching of Mathematica so I
have been saying least marco is kind of
like that but it's like you know one
percent of this whole thing five percent
of it that's that's that so to do you
know so like you know there i've seen
people on Stack Overflow who asked you
know does math America have markers then
I have seen like the best the best
answer this this oh you say no and blah
blah blah it's like 100 percent idiotic
wrong you know they don't know what they
talking about I know because I have you
know I you know I would claim I'm the
top 100 mathematical coder in 1990s at
least okay well you know okay I'm
bragging a lot of people you know we all
tend to be turned off but anyway that's
and you know that that's what it is the
whole system is a you can co-ed Marcos
but it's Marco is just the wrong word
okay Marco is the stupid word what's the
really core disco called symbolic
pattern matching system
you know it matches expressions it
transforms and all you can call it group
when you do programming like that you
know this called rule-based programming
you know typical mathematical code
source code anywhere you know like 50%
of is is you know using patterns like
Google group based programming
transformation of the patterns so in
other words the whole thing like the
whole thing is Marco it's just a giant
Marco that's running Marco's you know
everything is Marcos so that is why I
despise you know the lispers with their
Marco's concept because when you see
when you actually know Mathematica you
you you don't have to know the whole
thing you just spend you know half a
year to study Mathematica learn the
patent systems you you see you know like
in fact we can like let's show
Mathematica patterns let's show you know
some concrete let's look at what it
exactly looks like what you know what
the patterns what are you talking about
you know it's have a look you know how
you know you can you can see how it is
Marco how it is not a Marco you know you
can you and you can see you can start to
see if you study this you can see how
the list mark was like common list you
know scheme they they are extremely
idiotic they are like and they are
trumpeted by this lispers all day day
and night this this but you don't know
nothing so well Mathematica you know I'm
going I'm not going to go into details
because you know because then you have
to explain the syntax and you have to
explain you know there's a lot to
explain but let's see if I can
yeah there's a lot to you know in order
to kind of expand how it works you know
the basic it'll take some time it'll
take you know have a half an hour but I
have a introduction essay if you are
interested for those of you dispersed
who are interested in looking into what
what this whole pattern matching means
you can read this article this article
will explain okay
intro to Mathematica pattern matching
for these programmers okay this is
written in 2008 I show you some concrete
problem you know a programming problem
where given a list you want the result
to be some you know selection of it or
something and you can see some examples
how to do that by patterns by using you
know patterns and I also show you know
Lisp solution you can so you can compare
you know but however this problem cannot
be done with least macros you know
that's the thing because Lise Marcos is
a puny it's you know you can do nothing
oh it can well oh it does is that oh it
does is that basically what this macro
is said is that when you have a function
then you have a bunch of arguments
what list Marcos allows you to do when
you say diff macro is that it can hold
the arguments not evaluated so you have
these arguments as as as is you know
without the evaluation then in your body
you can say what to do with them that is
you know this macro is about but on the
other hand when you think of the whole
thing as a pattern matching what what
happens in terms of symbolic pattern
matching is that you have a function
call expression that which is an
expression that's a pattern because you
have a function name then the bunch of
arguments as a pattern then you can
define a pattern such that you know each
of your argument is you know for example
in math America is
it's it's this phone it's this form okay
X underscore that that stand for any pad
any expression argument you know and we
call it to be referred to as X okay so
the list Marco if you look at it in
terms of symbolic pattern matching what
it is is that you have a function
expression you know very simple pattern
you know function name a bunch of
arguments you you know each argument
becomes a pattern you can name it X Y Z
or whatever then you can do whatever
with it that's it you know that so the
only pattern we are using is this this
one X underscore you see but Mathematica
has all these others you see blank blank
sequence brand new sequence and lots of
and you can compose them you can combine
them so it'd be so you know it's a you
know that's what it is essentially it's
like a transformation of your code so
you know know you know that's a common
question you know because I happen to be
you know math America happens to be my
first language you know and it so
happens I'm a big fan of math so I spent
ten years more than you know fifteen
years to code Mathematica all day at you
know in the 1990s I don't even know
anything else I don't know the basics of
computer with languages what it means I
don't know nothing
I only know Mathematica because I read
the manual you know that's a 1,000 pages
I read it three times cover to cover in
different years you know because I'm
into math so Mathematica is my first
language and is also the first language
I learned through early mastered it you
know for over ten for ten plus years and
I you know I went to work for Wolfram
research because of that for a while
then so and my case is a bit different
you know because so so I'm so I'm
Mathematica you know
it's my first language then my next
language is you know I started to do
industrial coding I started to learn
Perl and your Nicks
yeah I started to find out they are like
they are just totally different you see
so they are completely different and
they are not comparable to this so so
Mathematica you know so you don't you
know so so what's a wise Mathematica so
different for example because first of
all it's symbolic like Lisp you know
that is already where you know you
accept you know so you have this mean
Mathematica nothing else you know goal
and all the other language are not
symbol symbolic okay so that's why you
know Mathematica is like you know out
there but then you have symbolic pattern
matching you don't find anywhere else
you know in these features have like
tiny mark was that you know so cold
Marco's that's it but Mathematica you
have the whole symbolic pattern matching
I don't see it anywhere in Haskell you
know camo they also have pattern
matching but as I mentioned before they
are pattern matching is not symbolic
it's rather the based on structures in
types you know in Mathematica
Mathematica is not typed so all these
patterns you are actually you are truly
really matching you know the characters
like each you know which character
follows by what you know that that's
what you are matching you are not
matching you know say nested least odd
or type of something that's not like
that so actually I should end the video
so I've been talking for hour so that's
a good talk today anyway about this
topic focused on this thing so let's see
the comments for me have math America in
general what do you mean so Danielle
says I can hash I can bash Mathematica
for example I don't like that sign that
is how you write sign that oh my god
Danielle you asked the right person for
that question because I can talk about
that for one hour
the reason for that okay is actually
because Mathematica is the actually
that's a whole topic about math
notations and how the consistency in or
abuse of traditional notations and also
the question about what is the proper
solution ideal solution for
computational mathematics okay that's a
whole topic and you know I have like
tens of articles about it so the reason
mathematical syntax is like that you
know they use square bracket is because
this so that way each bracket you know
maybe parenthesis square they have one
unique meaning okay that is not a case
for typical math for example typical
math you have for example let's say sine
X okay sine X wait sine X magnify for
example sine X let's say plus five okay
times three okay now notice there are
two parentheses you know there's
parentheses here and there are their
parentheses here now these two instances
of parentheses
they have different semantics they have
different purposes here it's used as a
delimiter for functions argument but
here it's used for grouping for
precedents you know
so that's inconsistent that's a problem
that's a burg okay that's a traditional
math notation that's a that's no good so
Mathematica they they that's that is why
that okay so okay they are allowed to
talk about that so we talked about that
some other day
yeah Mathematica yeah we can talk about
that so thank you guys for oh so if you
want to learn math America oh yeah you
can but it's expensive that's a problem
because Mathematica is not open source
you have to pay like
a thousand or something more than a
thousand but they have a hobbyist
version which is I think I don't know a
few hundred dollars but which is
identical to the professional version
identical okay so but you only pay a few
hundred dollars and there's also a free
version free version is when you go
through bye
let's go let's go to Amazon okay this is
my last last five minutes let's last two
minutes let's go to Amazon and raspberry
raspberry pie okay let's go there and so
raspberry pie includes Mathematica three
so if you buy raspberry pi you can buy
the whole kit okay then it will have you
have Mathematica to play with but of
course as you know Raspberry Pi is very
it's not very powerful so if you really
want to do you know huge computations
you know Mathematica Scott graphics you
know the it's a lot things so well you
know but anyway so if you buy this it's
free oh I don't have let's see
let's pick one let's pick this one okay
this one so what I want to do is
actually I want to post a link I want to
post the link with
okay with my name in it okay so you guys
can go buy it okay so that that's it for
today thank you guys for watching
anything else
type it you have like 10 seconds then
there'll be it bye