good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of our show today's 2019
November 23rd Saturday 5 o'clock p.m.
San Francisco time in sunny California
and we are going to do JavaScript + SVG
scalable scale scalable scalable vector
graphics like coding + tutorial so I'm
going to code it and teach in the same
time like explaining what what is what
is going on so this is gonna be live
script and we are going to JavaScript
and we are going to do a real time
creating a polyhedron platonic solids
and rotated in real time like this we
did this actually two days ago so here
you see a I suckers icosahedron okay and
octahedron and we're gonna write this
from scratch now last week we did one of
these from scratch so consider that as
part one you might go watch it and today
we are going to do it from scratch so
it's gonna be fast and we're gonna so
we're gonna create last time we didn't
finish we only created one face of the
queue
today it should be better because I did
it once and so we're gonna do a you know
this then we gonna then we are going to
hold on a second let me check if I'm
alive my status so I should be okay
right live so six concurrent uses
Watchers so yeah I'm good and so we
gonna continue with this from scratch we
are going to do this and we are going to
you see there is a problem with this one
because it's only doing wireframe
my frame is nice but oftentimes we want
opaque faces so that we oh that means we
need to we're gonna do that today
hopefully we can finish that in 1 hour
maybe more than wow so but we need to
start fast we need to get going in order
to do this now before we begin so
today's talk show so let me show you
some JavaScript in depth I need to
mention this again so this is my
tutorial on complete tutorial on
JavaScript so you can learn from it you
don't need any you don't need it's not
using any framework it's not using any
library which is what we are going to do
today no framework no library no react
no nothing no not even not even the
let's see
not even the jQuery ok known that
libraries from scratch pure JavaScript
technology and so I have my tutorial and
if you like I'm going to refer to it
many times because I use it for my own
as a reference for my own coding so I'm
going to refer it many times and you can
just search for Kesari javascript in
depth you'll find it so it includes for
beginners you just read this section ok
JavaScript basics like that will get you
started but this tutorial this project
is actually in depth it covers many
things you will not sing anywhere in any
other JavaScript books ok especially the
style the treatment ok anyway that's so
you have JavaScript reference as well
object reference then you have Dom
JavaScript and Dom are separate things
they are actually separate entirely
separate technologies so you learn
JavaScript the language then you lot
learn Dom DOM is what enables you to do
these web applications single page web
applications that's the jargon so you
need to learn Dom so I have a beginners
tutorial on Dom here
then you also have SVG technology now
SVG is what allows you to draw graphics
you know circles you know
two-dimensional graphics that's the
technology we are going to use today and
as you can see this is SVG what you are
seeing is SVG this polyhedron platonic
solid eye icosahedron okay and we are
going to begin that but before we begin
let's take one minutes to say hi to
people hello beautiful people
oh you beautiful people here Emily and
hello beautiful people and Kathy and
Matt and zoom way out from Florida and
you guys are from UK and and Czech
Republic and Kathy from UK so zero hi
Xetra so let's begin okay so today we're
gonna focus on JavaScript so if you know
JavaScript you know if that's your job
you know if I stuck somewhere just post
opinions post opinions how you do it how
do you how do you maybe I have an arrow
you know tell me so please - that'll be
great and if you don't know JavaScript
so if you have any questions you know
when I'm doing things please do ask ok
so we're gonna do quickly get to first
of all we're gonna create this thing
quickly repeat what we've done last week
ok so first thing so let's go to let's
begin so far so good
keep the comments coming ok so far so
good so good good good good
oh no good ok so JavaScript maybe maybe
I should shouldn't talk so fast in a
Russian manner we need to be relaxed and
melodious that's good ok so here is the
so we are going to create a a new page
ok so we are going to create poly ok so
we are we are going to create a new page
so let's do
so we created a new buffer save it as
holy okay Poli - let's say dot HTML okay
then we enter Simpson template okay hold
on a second so you can see this is HTML
page we just created so show in browser
it's empty now let's add a title title
so well not title but h1 so h1 live
rotation of hole the he'd run okay
so showing browser that's good and we
also need to change the title here and
make that that okay showing browser live
rotation polyhedron good and we are
going to now hold on a second let me
change my font so it's larger everywhere
so close that hold on a second copy that
path close that save it put a path here
link if I link it showing browser so the
top one is what we have today so before
we do that we we are going to increase
my phone so settings I'm going to
increase my Emacs font for all of us so
now I don't have to enlarge it every
time so here is that's how I do it
that's good that's done so put this here
or just a little bit so the fruit juice
energy drink tea is doing its thing
indeed it is my ritual of drinking
energy drink so we have that and let me
take a sip a small sip one hurt
- sis
that's a goat okay now we got to create
a dive element dive that's what we want
and we want to create an ID something ID
SVG okay
SVG yeah that's the SVG element showing
browser okay now we're gonna add a style
at the top style now if you don't know
any of these HTML remember I have
complete tutorial on HTML CSS you know
from the scratch from beginners so if
you don't know if you are not a web dev
check check it out and you can buy them
for $30 it's the best book anywhere you
can get for JavaScript in my opinion I
consider they are one possibly one or
two other JavaScript book either printed
or online that is possibly better than
me depending on your which style of
tutorial you know writing style and you
prefer so I consider mine to be the top
one in English language so if you like
it suppose I walk by it
okay the PayPal button it up here there
you can buy it so and okay so back to
Lee so we are going to add a style so
what I'm saying okay so CSS so this is
CSS we are going to add now we the ID
that's the JavaScript ID okay then then
for the solid thing gray okay that's
good clothes saved reopen showing
browser now we have a border now it's
empty therefore you see your line so now
we go to now we need to create a
JavaScript now copy the file path
JavaScript Minkoff I so here we created
a link to a JavaScript open it it
doesn't exist created yes okay so here's
our JavaScript file so you can see
console.log three three three okay
close it saving browser showing browser
okay it doesn't do nothing we need to go
to because in Firefox I don't have
JavaScript on so we need to show in
Chrome browser so that's we so we are
going to do that so call the Emacs
command
sorry opening Chrome browser okay that's
what we have and now open the console
log control command on the Mac its
command option I okay we can see the
console RQ c333 that's what we printed
before so that's all good now let's see
my house you know okay you have a
minutes actually we should go faster you
know lets me skip the mundane talk and
stuff so the how about talk about some
advanced deep JavaScript features if you
have time we cannot do it today because
if we do that we don't have time to
finish or even begin these polyhedrons
so we you know so we focus on how to do
this today so we have the JavaScript
code is running you can see there and
first of all so what what we need to do
so we need to create a SVG element so
like before I'm going to show you how to
create to begin with to do this
polyhedron I'm going to create I'm going
to show you how to tell you just rotate
one face okay so let's just write code
fast and cube now if you get if I'm
going too fast just ask questions so I
had a video last week just such Mike
sorry YouTube search for polyhedron that
is slow and that talks about many things
in detail so right now I'm just going to
do it fast to catch up so create a
constant cube face and this is gonna be
a array and array of values so cube face
the corner one face of a
cube corner so it's going to be lets say
so this is X this is y and z is coming
out from the screen XY so you want so
focus on the x-axis one what one face of
a cube so you need four corners okay so
we are going there negative 1 negative 1
then negative 1 1 ok so that's the four
coordinates 3d coordinate coordinates of
a cube now it's back live streaming
offline okay so okay so apparently maybe
I got YouTube problem live ok so it's
still good still good so we're going
into ok so we have a face of a cube I
mean the coordinates now we want to
project okay so we got a point in 3
space we want to we just want to project
into it into a 2d plane plane and the
way we do that is parallel projection by
simply dropping the Z coordinate so
we're gonna write a project project 2
plane ok so that's a function constant
project 2 plane and actually constant
arrow functions so okay
so this function will take a 3d point
XYZ 3d coordinate and return just XY it
just dropped the last one parallel
project okay so let's name it project 3d
point to 2d so now we need to for each
of the 3d point on the corner of the
face we need to project so we need to
apply parallel project to to all the
vertices of cube face okay
so cube face is away then we can say map
map then give a function and we're going
to give that function so the result of
that is going to be cube points okay
cube 2d points I'm not sure it's a good
name but it's just push on okay so now
we have cube cube so we so let's show
the result okay so let's when you code
it's usually nice to show the results
I'll refresh so you can see we got the
answer here we got you see array each
element is is just two points on the
plane so now we can start to draw that
on you know so to draw that we begin to
draw it so to draw it we need SVG
technology so SVG technology you need to
create first of all you need to create
the SVG element create element create
element create new I forgot what's the
function name create element I know what
it is actually create element okay
but for SVG we need create element in s
okay so it's not here I don't have a
brief for it so let's go find out so
let's go to SVG so SVG is let me tell
you what SVG is SVG looks like that okay
so this for example let's look at this
one this rectangle to create this
rectangle this three lines of code is
all you need so you first of all you
have the SVG tag with and hate then you
close it here then you have a rectangle
tag and XY is the XY is a point where
the the rectangle begins the the upper
left corner then you say which and hate
that's within head of the rectangle so
if you put this three lines in HTML file
it will show a rectangle that's how SVG
works so SVG is basically XML it's very
similar to HTML
so what we are going to do is we got we
are going to draw basically a rectangle
but instead of rectangle we need to draw
a polygon because when you rotate you
know a 3d object in 2d it's gonna show
like a polygon like triangles or so this
is what we need so we need to create
this in the HTML so we need to somehow
insert this in so these three lines into
HTML by using javascript okay so let's
do that how do you do that so how do you
how do you create this SVG and polygon
tags in inserted in HTML so the way we
do it is by you go to SVG and and down
here there is a scripting SVG example so
this is a full example so you put this
in your HTML page and that will create
let's go to brave okay so that's because
I have JavaScript oh I don't have
JavaScript on here so on a second so
let's go through well let's go to Chrome
then so you can see there is this
graphics entirely created by JavaScript
and how is that done first of all in
your HTML page you create this type tag
then here is the JavaScript code that
you create a SVG element then you let
let's work on let's let's just do that
okay let me let me grab the code and
we're gonna so this is we're gonna this
is three minutes
intro to SVG so let me explain I'm going
to explain what's going on okay so on a
second so but ultimately what we are
doing is we want to basically create
these three lines by JavaScript and
insert it into the page
so okay so actually we don't need that
so copy it so first of all we create a
SVG element that's how you do it
constant SVG one equals two document
create element NS then the the second
argument is SVG that's just how you do
it that will create a SVG tag element
then you set the attribute hate and wait
with of that thing so let's say 600 600
by 400 with and hate okay so you will
have basically a SVG element or area a
drawing area code it's called viewport
viewport okay then you then you start to
create an element in our case we need to
you see here here it's trying to create
a circle now in our case we need to
create a polygon so what is the element
named polygon so let's go to let's check
SVG basics so am I still doing good am i
doing good night people watching I don't
have any well you know usually I asked
you guys about some questions but I'm
doing this so fast I don't have any
questions so so far so good oh good so
far so great so so we are going to
create a polygon element so what is the
name of polygon the element name okay
it's polygon okay you know because you
cannot be too sure because sometimes
it's pody okay so poly pol ygo n so this
creates a polygon so face let's say face
one okay that create a polygon and what
is the attributes for the polygon so we
can see
the attribute for the polygon is so we
you have points and then you have style
okay so attribute so we need an
attribute face 1 points and here these
are coordinates this of numbers that's
what we need there the the others we
don't need ok so we need to do this
these some numbers so now we need to you
see this cube to 2d 2d points that's are
these some numbers actually that's a
rate remember the cube 2d points that
see this array so we need to turn that
array into into this format into this
format you know number number no
basically your sequence of numbers so
what we can do is that the way to do
that is that dot to string I think your
walk to string ok and copy that TV dad
pays it here so face face start set
attribute points then a list of numbers
in a stream form
okay I hope so far so good but actually
before we do that let's see we can
actually print out console.log and let's
see if this is a format we need
okay let's comment this out we don't
need that for now so we are printing it
out to see we got that's a format what
we need so refresh okay that's good
looks good that's exactly the format we
want a bunch of you know a sequence of
numbers so so okay so this is this is
what we want so we got a face now we're
going to attach this face into the SVG
here face 1 then we need to then we need
to attach the container to document I
mean the SVG we need to attach the the
SVG 1 to the dive element wait this is
not what I mean let me do it here so ok
ok we need to attach our SVG element we
created into the dive element so what is
the dive element name ok so here we get
it open the file again go to the top
let's say constant ok constant SVG e l
equals through document get get element
by ID ok then paste the ID so that so
now the SVG er1 amia the SVG EO is the
is a dive element ok that's that's
annoying name so type 1 let's just name
it I've won ok
dive box okay let's say dive box so go
back to the HTML rename it dive box
okay rename it tie box okay now open the
SVG open the JavaScript so dive box is
the dive element we need that because we
need to attach our SVG to it so dive box
dot append child okay then we append SVG
1 to it okay that should be it let's try
it now we should see some graphics no we
don't see the graphics because I know
the problem because our viewport is 600
pixels by 400 pixels however our cube
face is only you know between negative Y
and Y so it's very tiny you don't see it
that's the problem so there is a
solution of SVG oh my god this is taking
longer than I thought you know going
through what we did last time one hour
this to recreate the whole thing the
explanation is taking much longer than I
thought
so the problem you see so the solution
to do that is we go to SVG there is
called the thing called view box so this
is what you need to do SVG with hate
those are pixels then you specify a view
box which basically means you can
specify you can tell the browser from
the left to the right how many you know
is it is it how many virtual coordinate
how long it is so in our case we have
600 pixels but then we can tell the
browser that is actually from let's say
from negative 2 to 2 so it's actually 4
so that's how you do it so we need to
add this view box thing okay so let's do
it
sit with and hate okay then so this view
box so what what we need to do is set
view box and phone numbers okay phone
numbers will be will be the first two
number is means the the coordinate for
the upper upper left corner so so forth
it will be negative
- and the - okay so negative two and two
and the second two number is width in
hate so with is six and four let's just
say wait let's make a square so because
square is easier to compute so 600 by
600 pixels and the width will be four
and four okay let's go back to browser
refresh it's empty
again it's empty I know why because our
polygon because our polygon does not
have a color like it doesn't have a feel
like like this thing style feel blue and
Stroke blue so we need to create that so
let's do it
so the polygon you know this is so
tedious this is so we are we are going
to say face one dot set attribute and
style style will be okay
style will be that back to browser show
it nothing
why is that nothing feel okay so feel
stroke blue sometimes it's too small
that's why you don't see it feel yellow
negative two
x and y so the upper left corner should
be negative 2 a negative 2 you know this
is important because if you specify the
wrong number for the view box then your
joining is somewhere there but your view
box is showing here so that's why you
see nothing so maybe this will fix it
there we have it so we have a we have a
view box I mean let me get the
terminology correct but hold on a second
so let's let me explain ok let's go back
to the HTML and let's make these hoops
display table ok so this play table
means make a shrink box now that's CSS
detail you know it if you don't
understand so now if we show it you see
this this border is the actual SVG
viewport area so for me so you have 400
pixels
I mean 600 pixels by 600 pixels okay
okay so and and and and and ok so let me
show you the sub turn on the the
JavaScript console and go to the
elements you can see you can see this
part this line is what we created can
you magnify okay magnify let's go
so you see this bunch of lines is what
we created in JavaScript so you can see
SVG width and hate 600 view box negative
2 2 and negative 2 and 4 4 so that means
the upper left corner that coordinate is
considered negative 2 and negative 2 x
and y okay and meanwhile from the left
to right is for unit and top to bottom
is for unit so that's that's basically
the user coordinate that's how we
specify it now
our polygon why is it not a square I
don't know let's now look at our polygon
why is it not square so let's look at
Emacs problem okay so our polygon why is
it not a square why is it showing a
rectangle so stroke blue oh you need to
specify stroke width this is a very
annoying thing in SVG when you if you
have if you have a view box that is user
coordinate then every unit is with
respect to the view box it's not risk
with respect to pixels okay it's with
respect to your view box so you need a
stroke stroke with something like that
so let's go to SVG let's see
shape styles so here is unit stroke
width okay so let's put it here stroke
blue and stroke width
0.2 okay feel yellow let's try it again
show okay so it it is actually just
showing a stroke X yeah that that is the
reason okay now we are seeing we are not
seeing a square because we are seeing
actually the face we created is just
it's actually like that you know like
that so we you know we are looking at it
at it hm so we can we can for example we
if we change your face then you walk if
we change the coordinate and see okay
show it you see now we are showing this
face now let's go into we are going to
rotate this thing so let me check the
comments live stream okay so so far so
good
okay it's good facing okay great welcome
Daniel hey hey Danielle
they Mayo made more comments to suffer
like ease anyways let's keep going and
with the JavaScript
hello looks like some geo JavaScript
today yes we're gonna keep focusing
creating a live rotation of this
polyhedron we we try to do that quickly
so how long I've been talking 30 minutes
my god this is so so this is going to
stop so okay so let's just push on it
was any questions so far let me know
okay if anything unclear so we keep
using our old face and it's so next
thing we are going to do rotate you know
show some rotation first so rotation you
need a code you need the 3d matrix
basically to do rotation so last time I
try to explain how matrix rotation from
works but today we're gonna skip it skip
it and instead today we are just going
to look at existing my existing code
okay just grab grab the rotation code
and we are not going to expand we did
this before so okay but okay so so grab
the code that's that's what we're gonna
do okay so rotation code now we have the
rotation code where do we put it put it
here okay so we have this function not X
that we are given a degree it will
rotate vertices it will rotate a
variable vertices so the rotation is a
bunch of math cosine sine formula so you
can see this code is easy to understand
so basically so if we or what it does is
that you when you call write X give a
degree then it will change this
variables value this vertices variable
is meant to be a list of 3d coordinates
just like our cube face so let's change
our cube face to vertices or actually
let's just change vertices to cube face
okay so find and replace vertices
replaced by a cube face replace okay now
let's rotate let's let's call rot X okay
so let's call rot X
here because we need to rotate it before
we create the polygon so rod X and how
many degrees let's say 30 degrees okay
let's say rot Y rotate with respect to Y
well let's say what Z okay okay let's
get back to the browser this refresh
what is the problem
let's see console.log rot Z type error
assignment to constant variable line 38
assignment to constant variable okay so
line 38 rots Z is some assignment to
constant variables what assignment to
constant variable cubeface is the list
of points in 3d okay then have we have
rotation X rotate Y and rotate Z then it
says okay so yeah because we are trying
to change cubeface but however we
declared cubeface to be a constant so
that's no good it needs to be let okay
refresh
okay so so why is it not rotated I don't
know let's see what's going on
so oh ok so we need to actually we need
to rotate before because we need to
rotate it before we generate the 2d
points
so we first rotate it then project those
3d points into 2d coordinates then we
create the polygons so let's show it
and that's good let's you expect that we
success
so let's organize the code a little bit
so we need to put let's see create SVG
element then we create the polygon so so
let's move this to down here so we
create a SVG element then we rotate our
vertices in 3d around Z then we project
it to the plane drop one coordinate then
we create a polygon that is correct
order okay now let's do a live rotation
let's get this quickly that's going live
rotation so we you need an event to
detect when user press keys so so the
way you do that is you want the dev box
actually body the body of the page HTML
page then add event handler add event
handler okay you need the Dom function
to add event so what is the down
function so go to Dom add remove class
as you add remove event handler so we
have a div event listener add event
listener okay
so input then you need a function key
okay so actually this is not key this is
not info it should be key like you you
when user press okay when user presses
event down arrow it should protei the
thing around the x-axis okay that's what
we want to do so body add event listener
key then what happens when you you want
to call a function when when user
presses okey so
so we are going to cheat okay so we are
going to cheat by by looking at and at
the code we have okay so we cannot cheat
because that will save us time you'll
save a lot save us a lot time okay do
okay so let's do that so key press ok so
we are going to create a function here
to key press so to key press is a
function so if the key is okay so if the
key is arrow up then we do rotate X then
30 okay let's say five rotation
increment that's kind of five degrees
every time you press a key rotate five
to five degrees so if user press left
and right then you rotate around the y
axis five degrees okay then we need to
so when you suppress the key you call do
key press
okay but but then then you need to
render it okay so we need to right now
it won't work because we already created
the face you know we see you see we
rotate it here then we do when we
generate the 2d points then we create a
face all these things must happen after
the rotation so we are going to create a
render function new function okay
constant arrow function render and we're
just going to grab those thing inside
the render function okay and this render
function will take no argument let's put
the rotate there before okay so render
function so rotate 30 degrees then you
need to call render so we need to call
it render function so render function
needs to be called
so we call it here and attach to the SVG
container yes we need to attach it so
move it into here when the render
function so we're gonna call render and
also over here you need to do key press
then you need to render it so let's
write the harrow function so you call to
key press then you call render okay
every time you press a key you call to
key press which rotate the thing then
you call render which is which renders
it so let's try it render arrow a body
is not defined okay so it's body so what
is the body of HTML so body is not
defined yeah okay you need document dot
body refresh good let's try to press the
keys of arrow nothing happens
what why is that anyone know up arrow so
up arrow nothing happens
nothing happens in no error message
let's try of arrow down arrow left arrow
right arrow so debug time debug time so
every time we do key press let's print
something so we know key pressed okay
refresh up arrow it's not even call it's
not even being cold okay so so something
went wrong with our event listener so
let's look at the code how my code
somewhere else let's see did I have it
oh you need to pass an argument to do
key press of course the event for
keepers so this will be key you need to
pass the argument to do key press that's
right okay let's try to get try of arrow
he's not being called Dookie press event
key oh let's look at the code again
let's look at the key down yeah so
idiotic so the reason it's not working
because we are using we are using the
wrong event name so the event name it
should be key down see you know the very
annoying key down yeah okay thank you
and so let's refresh now press up arrow
there it is fantastic this is very
interesting you know why this happens
this happens because when we are
rotating so every time we press the key
it cause rotate right it cause rotate
nakos render you know it cause key press
here then it called every time so the
key press does some rotation then then
we call render but everytime we render
we just everytime we render let's go to
the render code render here it just
creates a new SVG you know the polygon
element then you press a key here
windows again no another polygon element
so it doesn't erase the old one that's
why and by the way
mathematically when you rotate something
like that this shape you see here that
is actually a hyperbola okay there's a
little math stuff math fearing that that
is actually hyperbola when you rotate a
cube do I have a cube I don't have a
cube but let's say you have a dice you
know dice you you spin it on a table
then on the side you or see you know let
me show you okay you spin a dice then on
the side you you have a seed weight and
that is the that is the silhouette is
actually chocolate I mean
that that silhouette is actually
hyperbola okay where is it it's not
showing up here so we have polyhedron
chocalate that's what we're gonna do
today we are okay so do I want to show
it
I can't find it in a minute in one
quickly
so this is well that's math okay we are
not going to talk about that but anyway
the this is what you see that that is
the shape exactly what you see here what
do you see here that that when you
rotate it basically when you rotate a
line you rotate it like you know then it
becomes a hyperbola that's just
interesting thing there it is so you
rotate a dice on table you take a photo
and you'll have a silhouette and those
curves are hyperbola
okay that's just interesting thing now
let's get this fixed every time we want
to remove the old copy so what what did
some well things just got hyperbolic yes
so let's do let's every time we create a
new face we want to erase existing face
so what we do is we we okay so we say
erase existing okay so SVG 1.8 TM l
equals to empty string that's just well
that's one way to do it so back to
browser refresh press up arrow fantastic
press left arrow fantastic now we got a
face okay now we got a face now let's do
actually we can take a break now so the
rest is easy
now we are going to create the rest is
easy because all we need is the you know
the word you know create more faces and
different different vertices for
different polyhedron like octahedron or
we can have cube you know this is just a
matter of adding more 3d points now it's
interesting to you know you think about
for the cube it's very easy
other points are just you know all the
points are easy to find so let's put
this in in a right shape
let's see how this is actually so you
can see for the cube or the corner you
know it's negative 1 or what it's also
very simple if you are doing octahedron
because you can see all the how do you
do this you see all the coordinates are
just 1 and negative 1 very easy to find
but it's in it gets interesting if you
want a aisaka Hedra now how do you find
those vertices coordinates you can go to
Wikipedia it's a bit tedious ok we are
not going to go through it but we I
already have the coordinates so we just
put push put them in so actually that's
great so let me take you know half a set
half a minute break and let's start to
so we we actually caught up almost to
the last time we did for one hour 56
minutes ok so
so far so good guys okay we I'm dropping
viewers like crazy now it's six people
so far so good
so we let's continue let's you know
continue to the interesting you know
starting to get fancy bathroom break
okay pol III let's go through okay so
let me just grab the code I have okay so
I have several versions here we want in
fact you have we have a version here let
me show you this version okay
chrome showing Chrome browser you see
this is the goal but we want to do and
you see this version it's already done
you know we can go wireframe now there's
a very interesting feature of this
version now can you guys see it oh yeah
you can there is a very interesting
feature you can see let me stop rotating
okay you can see the lines crossing each
other you see it shows when it's in
front it will cut over the lines behind
it so that's an interesting feature so
this is not just wireframe it actually
does something interesting
you know and you can say you can also
change patch style okay let's let's try
wireframe and you can change orthogonal
projection perspective projection and
you can change oh you cannot anyway so
that we are going to do this so right
now we are just going to grab a bunch of
codes syslog saw Alan Xbox theme I think
I saw in this code you speak Spanish
Latin oh yeah so okay first person 3d
engine no that's okay so so let's
continue okay so let's let me continue
this and we are going to here's what we
gonna do we're gonna first of all grab
the full code okay so actually let me
show
let me grab the full code so now right
now we only have one face of tube we
want all the coordinates of a cube so
let's do it
so what we're gonna do is going to
create
constants vertices okay actually I don't
want to show that so constant vertices
okay actually so this is actually taking
much longer I'm starting to feel
actually I like like I need to you need
a break so so let's do this
so we are going to create a bunch of
vertices for the cube instead of just
one face okay so so actually
so let's just put a global variable here
ten okay so so we're going to create a
object and hold on a second
yeah we're gonna create a object this
object is going to have Emacs bug save
open so this object is going to have a
cube thing okay and its value is another
object and and that object will have
vertices okay a bunch of data then faces
okay so vertices is the vertices of cube
the faces will be the index to the
vertices of the cube okay
and let's grab that you will see how it
is done in a minute
so actually so it is going to be this
right
okay so wait so we got a cube data so
not vertices holy data okay and here
constant vertices okay we don't know
what they are yet
so the Polie data will contain the
object cube so we can select you know
cube or ice us as a cathedral or others
but let's do a cube first we are racing
against time Alice says the Red Queen
said to Alice if you don't move you know
you are falling behind so we need to
race to it
so Poli data so what am i doing so
poorly data we are creating a database
of all these vertices of all platonic
solids
okay so n cube is done like this very
symmetric
that's the vertices of the tube and V is
10 me has the value of 10 and now and
the faces are just indexed to the
vertices so one of the face is 0 1 2 3
that means the first weight virtus
connected to the second vertex to the
third one and fourth one so that's how
we generate the vertices that that's the
data structure for our cube ok so now we
got that poly data now now once we have
poly date harlots we don't need the cube
face anymore the cube face will be
defined in terms of poly data so we will
say cube face will be we are equals to
poly data
Poli date huh then ok cube
wait that's so our cubeface is actually
just one face okay so this is scanning
this is getting more and more
complicated so some holy data dot cube
is this object right and we want to get
one face so then it will be that
actually let's use this notation
okay cube then dot faces okay then then
you get the first face okay so zero we
use index with 0 that will be the first
face then for each of this index we need
to actually get the coordinate so that
means dot map a function so the function
our function takes a index I and we need
to get God this is more much more code
than I expected so poly data cube dot
vertices okay then
then I okay that's that's the code let
me show you here okay so so basically
that's the code so this line should
actually recreate that you know
so let's print it console.log okay cue
phase two let's just see if we got it
correct cube phase two
undefined undefined undefined it's all
undefined
that means we screwed up somewhere of
course the code still works but however
the way we try to grab the cube face the
new data structure is not working this
is so complicated so cube to face so we
get fully data then cube then faces
let's just print that okay let's see
what we get so face is 0 so this this
line should return 0 1 2 3 let's see
yeah
it's correct so so blind coding is
actually working but not yet not fully
ok so now you got the indexes you need
to map you got these indexes then you
need to get the vertices so index poly
data dot cube that vertices for each
index is one vertex oh yeah so you
didn't return it that's why you need to
say return ok you see what I'm saying
you need to say return when you use our
function like that but actually a better
way to do it is to just simply remove
the curly bracket so this this is good
this is no good so delete that make it
into one line and you don't need return
anymore show it we need to print so
print it show it
yes indeed successful look how beautiful
it is a bad man so like would be proud
so so actually we are not going fast
enough
you know all these hours we just got
this stupid thing we need to see a thing
we need to see this solid man and you
guys need to go to sleep because it's
late in UK and Germany I'm not sure many
people are still here Emily Emily and
Kathy are you guys still here are you
abandoned okay so we didn't it's a lot
work you know JavaScript without
libraries of course so now we got okay
now we got a full face okay now we see
we we can see how this is actually
working now we don't need original face
anymore so back to the browser we are
we're here refresh
no no it's oh yeah because we change it
to tell it's it's like okay we can we
see it yeah we got now it's too big
because the vertices is 1 vertices
should be 1 okay oh we are just the view
box remember this view box let's say 40
and 40 okay back to browsers show it
okay now it's kind of yeah okay so and
now we need to adjust the coordinate at
the top left corner so let's say 20 20
redraw no it's good
but we need to order faith we need to do
all the faces so let's do it quickly
this is it come on
so let's get one face so we need code to
get one face so so this just get one
face we need to get more you know we
need to do this for multiple faces so
let's see cube face cube face map rotate
eggs
we need a lot there's a lot of things to
do I mean it's in principle it's very
simple you just need to add more phases
but you need to do this in a systematic
way so when we rotate X we need to
rotate all the phases not just one but
how do you you see we got this one phase
here so you need to rotate all phases
Emily's is a face to sleep like a lot of
vases okay Tatsumi Tetsu me were you
from back to sleep okay so what oh okay
I need okay I'm getting distracted I
need to get this finished and in fact I
need to go to the bathroom too he's too
much drink live-streaming one hour and
12 minutes okay so let's let's
concentrate and gets let's get this
going this big apple juice okay guys see
big apple juice the giant make our turn
[Music]
let's okay so we have one cube face one
cube face and when we generate the face
the SVG code here it creates SVG element
then it lets we don't need this rotate
anymore then it render when when when
render is called it it projects the
three-dimensional points to cube faces
cube face cube faces we need we need
okay I need I know what to do so let's
go back okay I know what to do now
I don't know I don't know what to do I
know what to do but not yet yeah you
need to concentrate when you do these
things okay so so this render function
it cube face cube face is a nested array
where each element is a 3d coordinate
point in 3d you project it to the plane
so cube face is just one face you need
to do this for multiple cube faces cube
has 1 2 3 4 5 6 6 faces so you need to
do this for 6 faces so you need to
create not just one polygon you need to
create six polygons you see you see this
polygon element SVG so let's change face
one - well let's not rename them because
when you do rename it gets confusing so
we are we so you can see the element we
generate this is a code so there's only
one single polygon now we need to
actually generate 1 2 3 4 5 6 6 polygons
SVG elements ok so we need to generate 6
polygon SVG elements so this is just one
of them but how do you how do how do you
I mean right now the the problem is not
how to do it but like we have to figure
out this the data structure we are using
vertices
so cube has one two so one two three
four five six seven eight one two three
four five six
oh yeah those are vertices so face you
have one two three four five six six
faces eight vertices for cube okay so so
vertices so actually let me cheat a
little bit okay let me look at my old
code
nested array of 3d coordinates no that's
not just nest it's called
you don't value without vertices
I'm kind of I'm stuck because if I go
ahead and do what I'm I think I'm going
to do which will work we will create a
cube however we will not be able to
quickly do the I suck as Isaac ahed run
and octahedron in others because if I
just go ahead and do what I am thinking
right now
then my code the data structure will be
incompatible with what what I've already
written that's the thing so I can
quickly do it now but then it's then we
we start to do icicle Heatran then we
have a problem because it's because I
can no longer simply copy and paste the
existing code to help we move along so I
that's that so that is why I have to
think about what what is my code is
actually doing so we can follow it that
way okay so actually this indicates a
documentation problem because normally
when you have things like this you
should be able to just read you know
just read off what these vertices are
but here it is incorrect because all it
says is vertices is just a nested array
of 3d coordinates
so that doesn't make sense because you
have if you have a polygon if you have
yeah so I think it's actually nested
like to never to level nesting okay I'm
getting this is getting bad we we are
stuck here and we haven't we need to we
need to get the whole thing in place
because otherwise today's video is just
like last week no difference vertices
god I need to get this holy data so what
are the comments come here to typescript
in writing more general interface next
great that's a lot work and also when
you do typescript then a lot of people
don't understand it don't understand it
oh yeah and also Alan you know created
live rotation with the mouse which I
haven't actually had time to grab that
code - yeah I haven't been working on
this this this this all these new
features is by the way by a professor he
he did it you know he you know he is
yeah so anyway I you know let's this I
need to get on with this so at least
today we have some polyhedron to look at
so let me let me just think about this
to get this right okay so so by the way
Alan's code you know you can you guys
can see ours code and I need a because
you know the Alan's cold where's you
Alan Alan Scott I don't have it handy so
Alan posted or something you know if you
can post to YouTube
so okay so let me focus on these sub
vertices for he trod on policeman dot
value dot vertices so it actually gives
you vertices okay so Welles's vertices
is a
okay I don't like these structure
actually what is this he just complete
these the vertices okay I know I know
what it I know what it is now so what is
this it's just a complete list of
vertices okay so okay so I know what
what's what is going on so let's let's
go back to our cube so poly data
vertices is just a complete set of
vertices and it depends on the faces to
tell you you know which vertices connect
to which to create a face yeah
so with it vertices is just rather
randomly ordered list of 3d points so
once you have a vertices so the it is
the face that matters okay it is a face
that matters okay so when you rotate you
actually just rotate the order vertices
so it is a face that matters okay
so face can we put it down below let's
try it okay
okay it's working
and go back to okay so we so now I know
what phases are vertices okay so now I
need to
okay so cubeface so now we're gonna do
something okay so we're gonna do this so
we are going to change the cube face and
into vertices okay and this is gonna be
so cube face the structure of cube face
will be changed so it's not it's no
longer that like that so instead the
cube face will be all faces so in fact I
mean all the vertices right now it's
just so cute face will be actually cube
vertices that's that's what I mean so
you have more than four points so that
is what the vertices will be so let's
remove cube cube face let's remove it
coming out so vertices will be the list
of all vertices for the cube so we can
do that by let's use this syntax okay
so it's not zero anymore so so you get
polyhedra you get cube then you get
is also much work we need to do so much
work
okay I know what to do so here is what's
that
that's simple cube that's that polyhedra
cube not faces just vertices okay that
gets you the vertices now faces let's
define faces let faces equals true the
face will be a nested array each element
will be one face okay this Scott this is
getting very complicated to get this
going
faces okay face index so face index
holy Hydra cube and faces okay so
vertices and face so you got the
vertices and you got face index and we
need actual face of a cube
okay let's just copy the code because we
are running late so gate phase phase is
a I think this is no no I don't think
I'm doing good
this is stuck for too long during the
child jeff bezos I think his code is on
github yeah but yeah yeah yeah so you
can you know you can go to our Aaron's
CODIS Aaron's code is on github
I don't know if I this well if I don't
finish this it's kind of a failure
because okay let me just do it let's we
must finish this at least we this we
must have a polyhedron up there so face
index gives you the index of faces then
get face I don't like the way this is
written country because it's not you
know it's not really how to hunt how to
describe anyway so your face your face
one of the face okay girl face face face
face indexes okay so that's the face
indexes let's just follow the code okay
face indexes so you get one face then
you map and the map and get focuses so
okay so get face returns one face so now
we can say cube face here's how we back
to the original let cube face equals to
get face let's say the second face of a
cube okay
okay that's how we get cube face okay
just like before however though oh this
data is changed they might they need to
be changed to vertices
change that change that change that
change that I changed I change that okay
and one more
so cubeface this line of code generate a
data like that that's just one phase
okay
and so you need so you need to get phase
and where is the part where we generate
the SVG element so create a polygon so
we're gonna create more than one here so
create a polygon constant so you need to
project the points so instead of a cube
face you're gonna project all the
vertices of the object into two deep 2d
plane and here you start to create one
face cube face so you're gonna start by
so we have the faces face indexes so we
start with the indexes of the face then
we for each for each of the face we're
gonna call function have a function okay
for each index of the cube face so this
is one index of a face we're going to
create a SVG element for that okay
so for each index of a face that's so
that's that that okay so let's call
these indexes
face indexes what we're gonna do is so
for each one of these we're going to get
face ok map function I so the eyes face
so face indexes I get face I so get face
returns the actual coordinates for the
faces indexes so that so here we is a
bunch of vertices then we that's right
so we create a SVG here and we need to
get phase one so we create for each face
we create an SVG then we the points will
be we're gonna finish this soon okay
with almost done so the point will be
you see here is when you need to
concentrate because this is getting this
is rather getting quite advanced so if
you haven't paid attention you know I
don't know you don't know what I'm doing
I don't even know what I'm doing I have
to really just focus on this get 2d
points so here it is so
yeah that's that's what I think
okay so I think we have it here I think
it's too much code here too so here here
is we are creating a polygon for each of
the cubes face so we begin with we
create a face element polygon element
there
so let's rename this face one - poly
poly G okay so so we create a polygon
element and we add attribute not that
okay we add at the attribute the second
animal you see basically a string of
numbers so how do we get the string of
numbers so remember we are creating a
polygon so we each vertex is a to needs
to be a two-dimensional point so what we
do is we
so what we do is we get the face so we
get the face what
so face index face indexes
so we get the fail this is going bad so
we get the face the vertices of the face
then one of the face you see I here then
we mapped for each one point in that
face with a 3d point in that face we met
we parallel project to the plane so it
becomes 2d point then we just to string
it becomes a string i I think that
should work I hope there's no errors so
polygons setattribute then we create if
this works please then that is almost
done we are almost done one moment
refresh peace Oh fantastic ok there's
some minor issues you see this we can
fix that because you see it's it's it's
it's weird here because this we got
something after 90 minutes now it's easy
to add aisaka Heatran and all the other
fancy ones now we got this problem
because right now we don't know which
one is in front which one is behind we
can't fix that ok you know we can fix
that
but so what do we do now so first of all
let's fix this annoying thing so instead
of feel yellow let's say Fionan so it
doesn't actually do that ok so now we
rotate ok that's good now let's add
let's just add the eye socket
I saw isoka he'd run ok the code essica
he'd run it's just that it is just a
bunch of data points so we're gonna grab
this whole thing ok so we're gonna grab
this whole
code I'm gonna show you what that is
okay copy it close it I'm gonna show it
here so in fact I'm going to show it
like that okay so I'm gonna compact the
code so you can see
so we have Dan toca he'd run icosahedron
these are platonic solids you see so you
see we have a innate vertices so this
function will take one argument and this
argument will be a polyhedron name such
as tetrahedron such as tetrahedron cube
octahedron and so on okay and it will
wait there is I did something wrong here
okay so yeah so you can see this
structure so this function we are
basically all this function do is it it
will it will just feel the variable
vertices and face indexes that's all it
does so we're gonna copy this code cut
it and use using our code so now instead
of this polyhedra we just defined to
find a function here define it
okay and we just say in it vertices
polyhedra
we don't need that okay Poli data so
where is our Poli data so
what
oh yeah pony data so we don't need Polly
data anymore we delete Polly data and we
delete vertices here
we delete our constant we delete
cubeface so the so that then we move the
variables to the top so vertices is list
of vertices 3d points and face indexes
are the index to the vertices to how
they connect into faces so we have
innate vertices that we'll just
initialize it so we do it by let's say
default is cube okay so we need to call
innate vertices okay that just feel the
two good as the virtus variables I hope
that or walk because this is getting
more and more well
it's reasonably getting yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah moneymoney
now let's just hope let's replace cube
by ice at isoka Hedra okay this way
let's do that okay he drew we face cube
by darka he drew yes yes yes yes yes oh
good good I can I can call it a day now
again you know this is good how long how
long have I been talking one hour and 40
minutes I think which I should stop
wireframe view solid view okay should
wait should we do solid view it will
take five to ten minutes they may take
ten minutes because when you actually
code lots of things
come up you know so so we begin I mean
we did from scratch this and now we have
this okay then we can create the menu
should we do it like are you guys
interested okay let me ask you guys
should we go on to create to show how do
you actually create solid face so you
you know instead of wireframe solid
phase so that sure is what
oh we continue to create the menu so you
can select you know base you can select
what what polyhedra to show like cube as
like icosahedron which one should be Oh
should I be good for today
yeah because today is already too long
so you know we might can be done for
today
what is that UFO to Dec heat drawn to
tech he jiong Oh Danica he'd run right
we have that so career today
okay go co-ed a day finish up the menu
super quick okay so let's do menu yeah
so okay so that's too many okay yeah so
this finish menu so so finish me this
this is you know help help help me
cheating this you know I intended to do
actually the solid and actually more
stuff but you know it really takes our
time to do to to to get them so okay so
what we need to do is just add a menu so
add menu you go through my Dom tutorial
then you go to
what menu should we want pop-up menu
yeah okay pop-up menu so you select this
code that's what you need
select this code I'm gonna show you what
they mean what they do okay so you go
back here you open the HTML file and on
us you open the HTML file you paste it
here okay so you so here is the code for
the menu okay so you say select ID
select polyhedrons select solids okay
then you give a ID name same name size 1
size y means you can only select one at
a time so they then you say actually
should we use menu or radio box I think
I prefer radio box ok well let's stick
with menu ok so anyway so so you select
so that's what you do and value 1 is is
cube ok cube the value 2 is octahedron
so I need to spare it correctly so I
don't remember how I experienced so so
here are the names so tetrahedron
tetrahedron comes first then cube then
after he'd run okay then I eyes
icosahedron I always got it confused
sometimes I say isoka he'd run but it's
icosahedron not icicle he'd run okay we
got a menu we're gonna menu now next is
the JavaScript code we don't need these
okay then
the next part is in the JavaScript code
you need to add so here is a menu so you
go to the browser
show him browser we got a menu add bada
it's like cube it doesn't do anything
because we don't have JavaScript event
so let's open the event so open the
JavaScript here then we need to add a
event so first of all so how do you
event so let's paste the code and see so
first of all you need
select solids okay create that select
solids okay cut that go to the top paste
it we put on top so that we know all the
requirement from the HTML so we need we
are selecting this menu and that we
order M and is called select select
solids okay then we need to know which
item is currently selected and you do
that by selects a light dot value then
you get you know you get one of the
string tetrahedron cube octahedron I cuz
he drew are we missing one we are
missing octahedron
oh yeah no we have me missing Pataca
Heatran okay yeah so okay we got that
then to find out what's the current
selection all you need is this fine so
we don't need the rest of here all you
need is right line so now we expand go
to the initialization we instead of
saying that we type that so that is
actually the proper value okay let's
make it work
tetrahedron that's correct because in
HTML the by default we have tetrahedron
selected okay so now you can rotate and
now you can select cube well cube okay
wait that's not cube okay so we get in
the menu is covered by video screen okay
yeah I thought so
finally too late okay but let's fix it
now my video is big it's
yeah no no it's it's
okay when we select octahedron that's
not working
it's like Tariq he drew no it's not
working because we don't have we don't
have event listener yet so we add event
business for our menu so select solids
go to the button select select dot add
event listener so listen to input yes so
when when input when the menu is changed
we call a function let's let's just say
change solid okay function okay so when
we say change solid so change solid
needs to be a function so constant arrow
function change solid and takes no
arguments and the result will be the
result will be okay so we need this one
second so the result will be we need to
call in eight vertices and give it a
name so that will feel that will feel
the variables vertices and face indexes
so so make it one line so you need
vertices change solid start value okay
okay so that is the function but
actually when you so when when you sir
change the menu you also need to render
it so we actually need to have we need
to call change solids and we also need
to call render okay yeah so let's hope
so refresh move arrow arrow key change
to cube that's good
rotate that's good change to octahedron
whoops cannot read poverty vertices of
undefined so did ask did I spell it
wrong let's go to the oh yeah I spelled
it wrong
up Hedra not octahedron refresh select
octahedron select octahedron good let's
try to rotate it that's good select
Nautica Heatran rotate it good and we
are doing unit testing select as I could
suck he'd run that's good okay that's it
for today
the menu is cover okay so thank you guys
for watching that's too long two hours
very slow progress so tomorrow me I mean
next time we're gonna just next day next
time we do this we are going to ask
people to watch the part one something
like that okay thank you guys bye we I'm
gonna shut down in 30 seconds 30 seconds
one minute does 30 seconds something so
here is the HTML
and okay so here's HTML you can you can
just search my website Saudi polyhedron
you might on github
you know there's but anyway the the my
code on github is changing all the time
so and also Alan has a copy
you know you search for Alan's website
hey Kathy you are still here Kathy is
the lawyer I want you so thank you guys
yeah so if you want a code you know go
did you know just you you can probably
find it or go to the go to my go to the
discord my discord you know ask you know
you got the link yeah if you like my
stuff by my JavaScript tutorial okay
javascript SVG and all that so good
thank you guys bye