Hello. Good morning, guys. I'm alive.
Welcome to another episode of Kasan Talk
Show. Chocolate Goiva. This is what I'm
going to
eat. God diva chocolate. So, we are
going to code Emac Lisp today and do a
massive text processing on 1,000 files.
We're going to create a hasht. Okay.
Text processing. That's the task. It is
called the field. A field of task. So if
you are watching this offline, play at
1.5 speed because I ramble. 1.5 speed is
perfect. If you are here, say hi. Love
to see your comments. Okay. Comments
here. Okay. So let's begin quickly. I'm
going to call 40 minutes then I got to
go. Okay. So we going to finish whatever
you know. Um so what is the what is the
job? Okay. So the task
is so if you go to my JavaScript
tutorial or JavaScript in depth for
example then use JavaScript in depth
then you see let's say quote string okay
uh then you can see okay let me magnify
my screen actually so the Firefox needs
to be much larger
font 150 mega big font
Okay. So actually wow um
uh you know so
this 150 is too
large
but so let me show you what we going to
do today. Okay. So do we have any people
watching? Six people. Six is double
crowds.
KPXXZ good morning. So you see my
JavaScript. You go to JavaScript and
Okay. So go to type of class. So you see
this this page is about type of class.
Let's go
up and you go down. You see there is
this topic box. So copy it back to
Emacs. Open that page. Showing browser
type of class. Go back to Emacs. Then
you go down. Right now I'm describing
what I'm doing. Okay. So I mean what is
the problem? Okay. So you see this type
of class. Oh god this is all too
big. So this
this JavaScript constructors and class
section. So they are like related pages
related to this type of class page. If
you go down, you see these are all about
constructors and class in JavaScript.
So, how do I make this panel? Let's say
if I want to add a new page, you know,
if you want to add a new page to this uh
topic box, you need to update every
every one of these page. So, let's say
let's go to constructor and class. Go
all the way down. You can see then this
binding go all the way down. You can see
the same topic box. Okay. Now in this
case they are all all these files are in
the same directory you know. So for
example open that go to the directory
you see those all these are in the same
directory. Okay close open. So now, so
if I want to add a new page, let's say
let's go to Emacs blog. Copy the file
path. Now all my command course are
shown in the pink window and my
keystrokes on the left. I'm using Kafly
keys. Kafly keys. Okay. And I'm I'm
using a Vora keyboard layout. So here is
Kafly keys. Fantastic. the most
efficient key binding system and you can
watch a v YouTube video too for
Emacs okay keys and va keyboard layout
so the commands are shown here and my
keystrokes no control no meta no you
know so it's a model system more
efficient than vim okay now so Emacs
blog so copy the file path close it so I
want to so open the type of class again
all the way bottom Um, I want to add,
for example, the Emac Emacs block to
this page as well. Now, hold on a
second. I don't I don't like this. You
see I
um I have this set up so that Okay. So
So you see I'm using a efficient Hoover
to activate window system. So for every
window I need to have like kind of a
corner of exposure so I can easily
uh switch to it without clicking because
clicking is actually one of the muscle
intensive activity. So if you work on
the computer for eight hours a day for
10 years for me 30 years you're going to
have problems with your hands.
So back to the topic. Uh so I want to
add a Emacs page. Let's say a new page
here. Uh so actually yeah. Okay. So
let's so let's say where do you want to
add it? Let's say here. Okay. So paste
link make a link make a list. Remove
that URL and uh remove the blank line.
Okay. So now show in browser. Now go to
the bottom. You can see we got a Emacs
block there. Click on that. Okay. But
but but this page doesn't have the topic
box. And this page is too long. So let's
use some something shorter.
Okay. Am I good? Say hi. Say good
morning. Acquire. Okay. So let's say I
want to let's say uh let's say uh uh uh
command line options. Okay. Let's just
say this page. This page is not too
long. You see this page also got its
topic box related to launching Emacs.
Emacs start exit init file and stuff. So
copy the file path. Go back to my Emacs.
So let's paste that link. Linkify list.
Remove the URL. And this one remove it.
You see I forgot to show my pink window.
Okay. So undo, undo, undo, undo. Okay,
let's redo uh link this. Make a list.
Remove the
URL. And this one, delete. You see, you
can see all the commands on the pink
window. Now, remove the blank lines.
Okay. Now, showing browser. Okay. Type
of class. Go all the way to the bottom.
So, you can see you got a new page. But
if you go there, you don't have the
JavaScript. So whenever you update this
topic box, you need to update all of
them. And I have a command. Okay, let me
show you. Press, press, press,
press. Okay, it's update updating all
the pages. It's actually searching
through my entire website, 100 files.
Okay, now you go to show list of
buffers. So all these files are opened.
So open any one of them. So this one is
JavaScript define a class without the
class
keyword advanced rocket science. Okay.
So if you do web
dev check out my tutorial because they
are fantastic. So you can define class
without any of class no new nor this nor
even the function keyword. That's how
you do it. So anyway, go to the bottom.
So you can
see there it is. Emacs command line
options. Click that. Okay. Now you go to
the
bottom Emacs topic box. Then run emac
this script in terminal rel topic box.
Then you got the JavaScript topic box.
So fantastic. Now you can navigate all
these coherent topics. You see? So that
command I just called is um HTML update
topic box. Okay, but it's got a
problem. Okay, at this rate we going to
not going to start to code because just
to explain the problem, it's going to
take 10
hours. Okay, anyway, let's try, you
know, let's just do what we can then I
gotta go. Okay. So you got this to box.
So the So how does the program work? So
let me show you. Uh press press describe
key. Then uh press press. Wait, not that
key. Describe key. Press press. Uh not
that key. Describe key. Press
press. Uh what is Oh yeah. So describe
key again. Press, press, press,
press. Sequential key system. No
control, no old, no meta
crap. So that prevents your hands to
become a when you get
older. Right now you are young. You are
uh you know on a row but you it's coming
to you. Okay. So you see this command
site HTML update topic box. Now tap tap
to go to the source code. Expand the
window. There it is. So the way it works
is that it will search. Okay. This part
this part is actually shouldn't be there
anyway. So it will search. Uh so let me
show you. Okay. Uh so it will search. So
I was actually working on this command
like I was updating it.
Uh, so how do I Oh god, I'm going to
explain this. Uh, it's going to take an
hour. So there it is. Search for word.
And what word it search? It searches the
search text. So what is the search text?
Highlight it and go back. So the search
text, you can see you
insert Oh god. You insert the entire
buffer's text into a temp buffer. Okay?
Then you insert the text. Then you go to
the point beginning of the buffer. Then
you search for word for this word for
the for this thing. Okay. So what is
that thing? That thing is let me show
you close
close. That part is basically this. So
you search 10,000 files for anything of
the dive class topic excel then with
this specific title with H4. Okay,
that's what you
search. Okay. So so this title and that
serves as a ID identifier.
Okay.
So so this is the approach. So once you
find a file with this then you just then
you just like go to you know you know
basically delete the entire uh dive
section then you replace it with a new
one. Okay that's how it works but
there's complexities. So the first
complexity is that if I happen to have
you know if I have happen to have a
topic box of the same
name then but but but it's actually
different topic for example let's say
this topic box may be
named list
operations so list operations ex exist
in different languages in eac list in
Python, in Goland, in JavaScript, you
know, but they are actually different
topic boxes. So, so that is the problem
of this command
uh you
know, so what I want to do is I want to
add ID. Okay. So something like
this ID
uh and with a unique ID. So instead of
using the title as a
identifier uh use ID. So the task is go
through 10,00 files, find all existing
topic
box and uh classify them. So you know so
then for each one of them you want to
add ID. For example, in this case, I
want to add I want to
modify any of that text to this text for
each of the files listed in the box.
Okay. So again, so the the task
is go
through the web. I don't think I can
start to write it because I got to go
soon. Go to the
web 10,000 HTML files.
Open each.
Find find that.
Then add in an ID
attribute such
as like
that for
each of the page in the topic
box. Okay, that's what you want to do.
Okay, now let's put this into my talk
show. So maybe we can um work on this
tomorrow. So cut it. Go to the talk
show. Now where's talk show? Okay, so
you see all these are different pages.
Now where's my talk show? So this
openers talk. There it is. So this is a
task task. Okay. Press press press. And
uh this topic box that's uh HTML code.
So you put that into a Chinese corner
brackets.
Okay. Then you turn it into code with
the amperand the greater than sign less
than equal sign turned into amperand
property because otherwise it's going to
screw up your HTML. So now make it into
a list show in browser that is the
task. Okay, since this task is
sequential and ordered let's change this
URL to ordered list. So you can just
press press
press o yes showing browser. Fantastic.
So that is a
task. Okay. Am I doing good? Is it
interesting? No comment. Uh that means
it's boring. Okay.
So I have 30 minutes to go. Let's start
to write this. Okay. Let's start to code
this. Okay. So
uh okay. What is this? Web de block
close. Okay. So and uh so this is a
command this update topic uh boxes
that's another command close so show my
buffers okay let's go through them
and close
close each one of them are like one of
the pages here okay so go back I want to
So, uh, yeah. So, remove that. That's
what we did. Save.
Close. Close. Okay. So,
close. Close. Close. Clo close. Clo
close. By the way, the command leave
each buffer open
intentionally.
Um, you know, because sometimes there's
a mistake.
So, close. C close.
close. Uh I can close them all one shot.
Okay. What is
this? Oh, yeah. So, this is You see this
is interesting. This is Emacs command
options. So, you also got this box. Oh,
actually I need to redo them. Okay. So,
let's do it again. Okay. So, this we
don't, you know, this we don't need
anymore. So, go here. press one key or
press a key to select the semantic unit
in
HTML you know so it doesn't matter where
you are press a key that's a semantic
unit press again that's a semantic unit
press again that's another semantic unit
in HTML press again the semantic unit
okay delete the whole or just press
press okay showing browser Emacs command
and line
options. So the JavaScript part is
removed. Fantastic. Close. Now I
actually Okay. JavaScript constructors
and class. I need to update this page to
remove this Emacs link. Okay. Easy. Just
delete that. Okay. So that's what you
want. Yes. Now press
press. So again you'll search 10,000
files written over the past 30 years. So
I calculated you know right now I have
10,000
files in my
uh on my
website written about 29 since
1997 29 years that's about three
articles I mean one article every three
days. Okay, it's done. Showing browser.
So you can
see the Emacs uh page is done. Okay, so
let's write. Okay, let's start to write
a command. So actually so let's Okay, so
hold on. So how do you close this uh all
this? Just do it or just search a reg u
use a regress regular expression. But I
don't need to but let's just delete it.
Okay. Now, start talk show. Okay. Let's
start to code it. Let's see how far we
can
go. Okay.
Start. Okay. Uh the task. Okay. So, do
that. Cut. Undo.
Undo. Go to the uh Emacs again. Paste.
Go here. Select all. Comment out.
Fantastic. Okay. Okay. And uh comment
out that. So default
defund casar work. Okay. Date date.
Okay. So we're going to start to code
this thing. Okay. So uh so first of
all do one file. So let's name this do
one file. Okay. So you need a file path.
Okay. Something like that.
Okay.
So, so first job is open that file. God,
I need to go faster. I need to go
faster. I have 30 minutes. 30 more
minutes. Okay.
Uh, open file. So, what is the EDM to
open file? Is it fine file? No, because
that is super slow. I talked about this
a thousand times. So I have by the way
few hundred Emac this coding YouTube
live streams. You can go check them out.
In fact there's a collection Emacs
search for Emacs tutorial. Then you just
go to Emacs and Emac list video
tutorials. So you can watch my past
videos. These are the best ones I
collected here. Okay. on EMAC this
coding for beginners. There's a beginner
one. Uh then
okay, that's my alarm
clock. You see you see my nice phone
cats. So
cute. So cute.
And now enjoy the richness of midclass
American life. Go diva. Wait, what
camera is this? This lousy camera. Pay
me money. Okay, guys. Go
to.info. Go to the bottom. You'll see my
PayPal.
Put, you know, $100. If you work at
Google or some corporation, put $1,000.
Okay. Make me make me a happy man. Now,
chocolate. Okay, we got 30 minutes to do
this. So, yeah, go watch my videos,
okay? If you like my stuff, I hope it's
useful. Now, how do you open a file?
Okay, that would be in the topics of
EMAC
list. Okay, that's just uh user input,
text processing. Everything I do today
is all covered, you know, in my
tutorial. Writing a command, text
processing,
um get user input, file and buffer,
that's what we want. Read file, that's
what we want. Process file. Oh, copy.
It's already done. Copy.
Close. Copy and cut coding. The best
coding. Okay. Delete
that. Delete that. Delete
that.
Okay. Put that
there. Um. Yeah. So, and this name needs
to be that.
Okay, that is the most efficient way. If
you want to open 10,000
files extremely fast, you can open
10,000 files within a few seconds. So,
you just with temp buffer that creates a
temporary buffer and insert it.
Okay, then do something. Now, what is
something we need to do? We need to
search for this. Okay. So, first of all,
go to
uh go to character point mean. Let's go
to the beginning of buffer. Okay. Then
search for word. Search for this. Okay.
Research for word. That's what we need.
And now we need regular expression for
this thing. Okay.
So, so
yeah, escape quotes. Do it.
Fantastic. And both of them in quote.
Fantastic. And this part is going to be
regular
expression. Can you do it?
Yes. So what regular expression would
that be? Now look at this magic
trick. RG
a fantastic autocoding.
Now this part will be correct. That
means
not the less equal sign less than sign.
Okay. And uh wait undo redo.
Okay. Now because we are in um yeah
wait. So okay. So this capture the
pattern for this for this for this part.
Okay. So now because we are in EMAC list
which got the most lousy regular
expression
possible. So you need back tick and back
tick the back quotes you know the slash
double slash to
uh toothpick syndrome. Okay cut it put
it here. That is our regular expression.
Okay. So cut
it. Go back here. Go back here. Paste
and delete that. Okay. Now prettyify the
code. Pretty fantastic. Beautiful. Is it
beautiful?
Yes. Now remove these options. Option
bound. Bound uh bound Neo uh bound Neo.
No arrow true because some page doesn't
have you know the topic box.
If you don't say uh you know if you
don't say no error then if it cannot
find it it'll like stop. Okay. So no
error true count we don't
care. And here we have a literal new
line. Now let's replace it by just make
it that so the code is easier kind of.
Okay. You search for that. Okay. We
cannot finish this today because there's
a lot to do. So once once you found it,
you need to uh you need to put it into a
hash table. So for each of these topic
box, we need to put in a hash table. So
let's declare a
hasht x table. Okay. Now, how do you do
hasht? Oh. Oh, that's interesting
question. I forgot. But first of all,
copy that. Go to the talk show.
pedal my tutorial there. Okay. Now, but
how do you do hasht? Well, that would be
lisp basics. So, this section covers
everything in the lisp language common
to all lisp languages such as string,
number, boolean, variable,
conditionals, loop, data structure,
hasht. That's what we want.
Oh, make hasht. That's what you do.
Okay. Copy and paste
code. The fantastic methodology. Better
than OOP. Just copy and
paste. The most
practical. Okay. So, you got uh Yeah.
So, create a hasht. Yes, of course.
Let's put put it here. So, this will be
named X table. Make hasht test equal.
Yes.
And by default we can add like the
number of keys you want estimated
because for efficiency reasons that's
that's of a concern to the bit dlers but
let's ignore it for
now you know doesn't matter much it'll
save you you know few
microsconds well the thing is you know
when you have a hash table you see hash
table is kind of the bit diddling
computer science. Okay. Uh very
fundamental part you know list array
hash table those are very fundamental
and fairly complicated because you need
to implement it on this you know this
these digital abacus. So when you have a
hash table you usually in lower level
languages you need to declare how many
items you're going to have. You know,
ideally, who cares? You know, just
watch. If I add one, do it. If I add 10
items, do it. You know, don't ask me how
many item I'm going to have, you know,
but but in in
reality, in practice, you know, you need
to you need to you need to specify, you
know, it needs to begin like declare
memory, you know, how many items you're
going to have.
Then if it's beyond that many items then
behind the scenes it will like recreate
um yeah literally yeah kind of so the
implementation is actually a entirely
diff thing it's a different you know
that that's when you need to read Guth
Donald Gunn's the other programming book
okay that's a low-level implementation
issue but for Most people like Python
coders, Ruby coders, JavaScript coders,
they don't know you. And for
mathematician coders and scient
scientists who study the advanced rocket
science, they don't know neither you
know like which is in my case my first
like 20 years of computing like I don't
know what hasht actually do underneath.
But all I care as a mathematician, I
just want the key value pairs. Okay, you
you figure out the you know the I
figure out the advanced mathematics. You
figure out the bit did ddling
Okay, that that is that is a job of
programming
language unless you are the bit diddler
then you are into C and Rust. So anyway,
that's a side side story about the hash
table. But anyway, that's how we want to
do it. Okay. Uh, so table declare hasht.
Yes. Then every time you found it. Okay.
Every time you found this item, then you
need
to comments. Are you Chinese? Yes
sir. I'm Chinese
blood of of US citizen. Okay. Shiao
Xiaoang.
Xiaoang. Oh,
KPTXX. Okay. I haven't read I haven't
checked my email for for for a few days.
So, I remember that. Thank you. Make let
make a screenshot of it. I'll make sure
to send it to you. Okay. S HTML mod
powerful. Thank you.
Uh so okay so once you found this uh I
gotta go in 20 minutes. Okay. Uh once
you found this am I am I doing good?
Video check and video check live check
audio.
Okay. So once you found the hasht uh
once you found this you go need to go to
um okay. So you need a beginning and
end. Okay. So let me do
that.
Okay. Begin and end local variable. Then
set x begin. Uh okay. Uh
actually put it here. Uh then you want
to set it to we want to find we want to
save the beginning position of the dive.
Okay. position is the you know the
beginning of buffer is one. So it goes
by characters basically counting
characters. So beginning position would
be
uh match beginning. Okay the whole
match. Okay that returns the
position of this.
Okay. Then uh then what you want to do,
you want to then go to X begin. Go to
there. Then jump to the end of tag. So
what you want to do is
uh let me open a JavaScript page so you
can
see. Okay, let's uh let's use that.
Define a class without class. Okay. Then
constructor in class and uh you want to
know
uh where's the hasht one there.
Okay. Copy copy copy. Do that. Do that.
Do that. Do that. Do that. Show in
browser. Okay. That's today's topics.
Okay. So, so back to the code. What we
want to uh Oh yeah. So what we doing is
that you see once your cruiser position
is here you want to jump to the um to
the bottom. Okay. So you can do that by
what is my
[Music]
key. Wait what? What is my Wait, what?
Oh, I don't want that.
basically uh
what? Okay. So, you you kind of want to
uh you
see jump. So, what is my key for uh
uh I forgot what is the key. Okay, let's
look.
Forward.
What? Tag. Insert tag. Remove join. Go
to matching tag. Oh, yeah. Tab down. Oh,
that's
right. Yeah. Okay. So, tap down. Yeah,
that's right. I forgot the key. So, tap
down or tap up. Go to the matching tag.
So, for example, tap up. You know, for
example, like I put that like that. You
see it? Jump to the matching tag. Okay.
So, so what is the command? That command
would be that. Okay. So, go back here.
Save. Close. Go back to my code. Go back
to my code. Then do that. Okay. Look at
the documentation. Describe function.
Then you can
see the source code
here. You know, actually I'm just using
um actually I'm using the uh let me show
you. I should use that. I need to
implement my own
uh there. Okay, that is actually the
command I'm using. SGML
skip tag forward one that is
uh bundled with emacs. Okay, so if you
are going to code your own, you can use
this command. Fairly fairly complex. I
need to implement my own though. Okay.
But anyway, close. Close. Copy that.
Copy that. Close. Close. Okay. Actually
do
that. Uh go to char that
uh actually move forward one character.
Okay. Then then jump to the end. Then
set x
end point. Okay. So that's a beginning
position and end position
of of this this kind of block. Okay. So
purify the code. So okay. So so far so
good. Yeah. Let's clean
up. Okay. So we got the beginning
position and just copy it. But for
substring no properties okay that is
that and uh let's say the
text. Okay then just say set text
uh set text that. Okay. So we got we got
this text. We got this kind of this text
captured. Okay. Now let's just make a
hash table. So we we want to add that to
a hash table. What should the key be?
The key should
be let's say the key should be the
entire text. Okay. So, uh, put hash, I
believe, is the function put hash.
That's right. The key is going to be
this huge text and value is going to be
the current file path.
Okay. Okay. And what table? table is
this uh x table. Okay. So, that will add
to the hash. Actually you need to
check check if exist if not
add.
Okay.
Uh but if
exist
push path to value. So the value should
be a list of path. Okay. So first of all
check if it exist. So h go back to
hasht. Go to
hasht. Uh wait not that
hasht hasht check exist.
Um okay it's get hash. Okay get hash
table. Yeah.
So get
hash that in X
table. Okay. So
if is in the hash
table then do something
otherwise if it's not in hash table just
add it. And uh we need to add to us a
list. Okay. So, so this would
be
okay. So, but if it's already there,
then
[Music]
you then uh if it's already there,
you you want to update the value. Okay.
So that would
be okay. That would be put hash too.
So if already exist
then then okay get hash. So
okay.
Uh okay. So actually we run into
efficiency issue. So we already got
hash. So hold on a second. So it's a bit
confusing here, but let me
do let me add
uh
current key. Okay, something like that.
Current
key set current
key that.
Okay. So if current key already
exist, if it doesn't exist, then just
add it. If it already exist, then you
need to
uh then you need to put
hash current key.
Then
uh you need to push the new value to
existing
list.
Uh okay. So you need to
um go there must be better way to do it.
Okay. I got nine minutes to go. I need
to go. Uh
Okay. Nobody nobody is watching. No
comments. 11 people.
Okay.
[Music]
Uh. Okay. So, what we need to do?
Um, hi. Hi. He commit. Lots of new
people today. Uh, because Oh, because
I'm doing it at a different time frame.
Usually,
usually I don't do it this
early.
Chocolate. Yeah. Hi guys.
Hi. Put
hash current
key.
Okay. Am I doing good? Okay. I I
Yeah. Okay, back to the code. So, put
hash current
key. Put hash in that key and the value
would be
Oh god, how do you do
this? You need to push this path to the
value.
Okay,
so that is a key. Wait
uh wait that that is not a current key.
That's a key value.
So there's a semantic issue. Get hash
this text. Okay. So that's not a key
current. That should be
value. Something like that.
Okay. Okay. key value get hash
text
then if the value exist. Yeah.
So wait. So wait. So this this is wrong.
So this should be
text right that's a key. Then the value
is that's right now I
know. Okay. You just do push this file
path into the
list.
Fantastic. Uh, wait. What does it
return? What does push
return?
Push. This place thing is really
annoying. This this this you know this
the problem here the complexity is due
to imperative programming mutability of
things that's why it gets complex so
right now right now I want to know what
does push return or does it
actually does this actually work you see
you need to
whenever it's already there you need to
push the current file path into this
list and put it into the hash table.
Okay. So,
uh let's say
let xx Okay.
So, let's do some little experiment
here. One, two, three. So, we got a list
here. And uh now
push
for
xx. What does it um but what does push
return? So you need to
message.
Okay. Push result. Okay. Let's run this
code and then we'll
know. Show. Okay. Push result is a
list. Okay. So it returns a list. You
know stupid
um describe function. the documentation
doesn't
say yeah this you know this this very
lousy part of the
documentation you know it doesn't tell
you directly what it returns but
indirectly it says it's like equivalent
to that set set f okay now the set f say
explicitly what it returns.
Check the return value is the last vow
in the list.
What that's not that's not what I want.
You see, so it's actually so this is the
push documentation is actually
incorrect, you know. So it says it's
this is morally equivalent to that. But
actually you know the return value is
entirely different you know let's try to
run this
code you know run this code you see the
result is that that means it returns the
entire list so it is not morally
equivalent to
that stupid documentation I mean this is
a bad part I mean So if for you guys
those of you Emacs list coders, okay,
now you guys are more friendly and
social people. So you need to go tell
the GNU Emacs dev mailing list. You you
need you need to go tell them this
documentation this inline documentation
for the push function. Let's look at
it. Define malware. This inline
documentation is not real well written.
It needs to be changed. It needs to
specify what is the return value
explicitly. Okay. And it also to remove
this morality
you know, it says this is morally
equivalent to this. So what does what
does morally equivalent mean?
So it's kind of like you know morally
equivalent is not a good phrase to use
when you do technical writing. Okay. So
you know you don't you in technical
writing you don't go you don't you know
use
flowid analogies like that morally
equivalent you know is you should say in
this case if you want to say this way
this is similar okay or uh almost
equivalent okay not morally
equivalent and also okay so you need a
return you need to say what it returns
and change this phrase morally
equivalent. And
also also you see this is trying to
explain what this push does by
using by comparing to another
construct. That's not good.
simply directly describe what this push
do without if possible without trying to
like doing analogy to some other
construct because then people need to
know what does a set F do what what is
set F especially set F set F is rarely
used almost never used in IMAG this so
this and and also added to the
injury is that this this thing is like
generalized variable that's like
completely
So this documentation, this part,
the documentation for this push um
function is the worst of all inline
documentation of all eag functions in
the entire eacisp programming language.
Okay, that is what I'm telling you for
my experience of coding
eag since
2006. So by now it's like 20
years. 20 years. The old man says this
inline documentation push is the worst
in the entire eagleline documentation.
Okay. So you guys for you young people
still you know nice persons. So you go
tell go to the Emacs GNU Emacs dev
mailing list and kindly don't mention my
name. Okay just like
uh just tell them like you know oh I
think you know there's a problem with
this documentation. Can we possibly
improve it? Okay, just tell them to add
a
return explicit what is a return and
tell them to like um you know try it try
to write these rephrases without
comparing to some other construct.
Okay? And uh
don't don't tell them what I said about
the generalized variable because that's
But if you tell them they they're
going to not going to listen. But just
tell them to add a return statement. If
you can do that, if by next release of
Emacs 20, you know, next one gonna be
Emacs 31. If in next release this
documentation is changed, then I'm
happy. That means I actually did
something useful for you
guys. Okay. So, you know, actually I got
to go. So, I gotta go. So that's it for
today. We haven't finished this, but let
let's put it back. Um to do okay,
actually to do to be
continued. C N T and U D. Okay. Then
then this part test what push returns.
Okay.
Uh then this is like this is the
description. Okay. So put it back syntax
color the whole show in browser that is
today's talk show to be continued. Hello
Oliviver I got to go to understand
generalized variables you basically need
to read the language standard for common
list. No actually I talked about
generalized variables maybe half a year
ago or a year ago.
generalized variable is the worst
in lisp. Okay, that like the worst
possible. So, uh you know if
you you know Olivivera you probably know
already you know what it what it is but
generalized variable that's another
topic. So in my opinion that should be
banned. That should be like
removed in
eacis. I don't want it. Nobody wants it.
generalized variable that should be
banned because it's simulating the
imperative programming
languages x equals to some uh you know x
x bracket index like if you want to
update a index element of a array in
python or javascript or golan or any
other language you know you say array
square bracket three you want to update
the you know the third
um you know third index equals to
something that is what generalized
variable mean. It's not generalized
generalized my ass. It's just it just it
just
illogical syntax and semantics created
so that because it reflects
the the traditional mathematical
notation. Okay. But it is in fact
illogical and bad in a programming
language. Okay? Because it conf
conflates as as the people say it
confuses the
uh confus confuses
the the evaluation strategy. Okay. So
like when when does a variable
uh become evaluated? Okay. So anyway
that's what generalized variable is. I I
think it's very bad.
Okay. Yeah, Emacs documentation. Great
guy. You'll leave
a Okay. Bye, guys. I gotta go. I really
got to go.