oh I'm live I'm live hello guys test
test hello Juan Hello Alan good morning
good morning again so today is random so
if you got questions ask it now because
once I started to talk on something
thing it's going to be
nonstop now look at my cute hat this is
China red God hat all I need to do is
just put a red star
here audio check video check I am alive
it is
true okay so I can't think of a good
name oh I can't think of a good name
okay good morning I can't think of a
good name okay so what we going to do
nothing to to talk about wait what are
you guys seeing you you guys are seeing
my okay my keyboard This is glove 8s
keyboard glove 80 search for my website
I got a video video review this is
Ultimate hacking keyboard too both are
fantastic okay now let's switch to So
Random okay I don't have a topic
today you are the director of my talk
show okay today so let's see you know
usually when I have nothing to no topic
usually I just talk about
emac which many of of you will find
boring because you don't use
emac okay
so the point here is that you talk okay
you gotta talk because you don't talk
there's nothing you're going to hear
hello Mo and very welcome back to Kar
Discord you know the kar Discord we have
upheaval every every half a
year and and mo have you have you taken
your PE today hello immortality a lot
people hello oh my God so many people
today so again let me repeat if you have
a questions mention it okay so because
we don't have a topic today it's
randomish uh I wanted to be um I can
talk about emac then it's going to be
nonstop emac lots of update just check
emx blog or I can um so of course there
is you know the machine learning which
I'm in need to talk about like
artificial intelligence and machine
learning because I have strong opinions
and mo is the expert in machine learning
okay mo mo is a real expert in machine
learning here Mo has been actually
taught me machine
learning uh the other day in in chat so
and so I started to learn machine
learning a lot you know but you know if
I started to talk machine learning you
know I'm just started to learn but um
you know so I can give my opinions about
you know about it and also related is is
the how it relates to artificial
intelligence it's becoming
amazing uh you know so recently you know
the Microsoft are beloved Microsoft they
started to show wait you can see my
screen right oh you can
okay you know frany our memb started to
show the belove our beloved
Microsoft bypass membership okay this
you know because it doesn't you know it
we Microsoft thing they started to have
um you know to let you generate images
uh but
however they know understand n English
okay so if you post in English like show
me a show me a naked
women it's going to say I'm sorry you
know you you know that is not available
but if you type in Dutch then it's going
to be show something okay so anyway so
here is some
images involving Microsoft
and I love the hot ones I always love
the hot ones okay so what is the topic
topic guys okay if you have mostly for
those of you many of you here watch me a
lot you know know my know my know my
problems and my
problems then then if you have a
questions this is the right time to ask
okay so we have lots of people here
friend and ewit you know each one have
individual style and the way they chat
and also the type of content they chat
about so I came to know many of you guys
frany ewit and uh and George of course
George is obsessed with in the past
three days is obsessed posting about
this n okay we shall just call it n
King
and uh and oh of course there's a hot
dog with his usual
characteristics uh and uh and oh my God
this image you know this image is not
allowed typically but you get to see it
via fres
trickery oh and this one is
hot now I wonder if I'm going to be
censored you know YouTube going to say
you know after today is going to say
warning notice you know you are getting
a
strike uh we'll see how smart you know
Google AI is you know whether you know
we don't talk about it but whether
you'll see and it will say this is not
allowed [ __ ]
Google okay and this this is my this
lovely okay so what
uh What uh
uh stream band okay so what so what is
uh what is the topic we talking about
Andrew okay Mo Andrew wait so many
things and I'm getting old so I need to
magnify okay hi okay
minky powers minky powers says H can you
talk about defund a little and maybe
walk through the principles of creating
a procedure with it okay let's talk
about that for five minutes uh that's a
EAC stuff do you uh Juan says Do You
Believe In traditional
medicine uh in general no okay by that I
think you mean Chinese traditional
medicine you know most foreigners so if
you are a white people you probably have
no idea what Chinese medicine Len I mean
you have vague idea like but for Chinese
who grew up in China or Taiwan I I came
from Taiwan we know what it is you know
the uh basically plant-based medicine
okay and there's I mean it's more than
it's there's a lot um it's building into
our minds okay there's a lot things
about it but do I believe it not really
okay I mean some of them are good I
mean um it it's it's like it's like home
medicine okay for example you got a code
so by traditional way not just China but
some other you know around the globe you
have like
traditional uh established kind of via
verbal uh tradition you for example if
you are cold you should drink hot water
maybe put some Gans on it maybe honey uh
those kind of things so that's kind of
traditional medicine but Chinese
traditional medicine is like more
involved in that
they and there's huge amount of
superstitions too so in general I don't
you know uh I don't believe it just like
you know the white people they believe
in West medicine they have to take a PE
every day in order to sleep otherwise
they cannot
sleep do you believe in Western
medicine like you you did you guys take
your P today like go to you know get
your vitamin C vitamin D Vitamin B you
know you got to have lots of those reer
is Ripper here you know
that's I imagine you know
so I don't usually take any um
PS okay so msk's question about emac you
know what you should do is actually um
so if we go to talk show you will see I
have done a lot of course emac like half
more than half this so there's over 100
or 200 videos about emac coding so
actually your question about defend uh
you should um okay so for example let's
search forar emac blog so you go to my
emac blog this scum back let me let me
talk about this comeb back this Wesley
okay he still
he steal my website you know I maybe he
bought my tutorial 10 years ago you know
but I I I don't know if he bought it or
not but he steals my uh website content
and put it on his website we weekly.org
this
scum I emailed him about a few months
ago he I didn't get any reply you know
this uh this [ __ ] this kind of people
so anyway here is my
uh Le website okay uhar info okay Brave
search is kind of not so up to date so
anyway you go toar emac
blog okay then you know so this is my
emac tutorial I'm talking to you Minsky
pose so emac tutorial then there is emac
disp disp basics okay then over here
okay then you'll
find there's a link talk show
20122 September
7th okay emac list for beginner okay so
you you uh you probably want to watch
that so that's emac list tutorial from
the ground
up
then then you go back to S Emax tutorial
then you go to emac L practical emac L
chapter there's another video this is s
talk show
2022 May 21st okay so that's also a
groundup so you know and there's
actually a lot more videos so I think
you just watch those okay and uh as far
as your specific question about emac
this defend that is also covered uh you
know just function define function how
do you define function what they do uh
you know what do you need to you know
very simple it's always just like that
so I hope that answered your
question so let's see what's the
questions okay
uh so let me just read one by
one
uh eonis says I'll throw a bone for a
topic brand computer interface okay you
know you shouldn't throw a b you know
don't don't throw a random topic like
something you really have for me because
you know I talked about this you know
I'm not looking for General suggestions
please suggest me a topic I have but
literally I have a million topics like
right now I can talk about emac emac
this programming language design which
language is the best one which one
should you learn CU have you looked into
rust or I can talk about politics you
know politics is you know the collapse
of USA that's big thing that's going on
you know the the so many you know uh and
to do to talk about politics I should
dedicate I should not stream it on
YouTube because because it's sure thing
to get banned so instead we'll use uh
you know so there is
my Odyssey you know on Odyssey so one
day I hope you know I talked about this
before but never do it that's like my
typical way but I should so I should go
to Odyssey and let's live
stream a session about politics so then
we can talk
about or or you know the the the the the
[ __ ] Google the
[ __ ] collapse of USA say it's pretty bad
in San Francisco okay we shall not
mention any specifics right now
because so okay so uh so but brand
computer interface I don't know much
about that actually that is something
Elam musk is trying to do okay let me
talk about that brand computer interface
so uh we have currently we have the
issue of artificial intelligence threat
you know it's omness because every day
it's generating all these photos you
know this
almost you know for for example this one
we can easily tell it's fake you know
it's not real but it can generate you
know Millions realistic photos
that you know we average you know it's
very hard to tell you know you can
generate millions millions of it in fact
right now on Twitter for example there
are lots of photo you don't know it's
fake you know if you like we are you
know every day we see hundred thousands
of photos every day you know this
[ __ ] Meenan Zuma Fox they they they
like to post this violent you know [ __ ]
and memes so they get more views this m
look at look at this this icon this [ __ ]
a non [ __ ] okay that's why I despise
this kind of and we have half of it on
our server is like
that so anyway so so we we see thousands
of photos but you don't know which one
is real actually if you don't stop and
actually spend five minutes to look into
you just see photos that you know you
think it's real right right now I think
it's already happening so anyway so
there is the threat of AI you know we
are concerned about and Al also
especially CH gbt which can write essays
better than you can you know it can
write 10,000 essays in in one minute
and and you take a year to write your
PhD thesis you know in a year or two
Char generates it on the spot you
know and the thing is you cannot tell
it's real or not I mean getting very
very more and more difficult that's a
thing that's a critical thing so there's
a threat of AI so that is just the
current situation it can generate all
these photos and essays or text or
carry out a
conversation and uh it's kind of
difficult so far for for us to tell it's
real is from a human or not that's a
current state of things of artificial
intelligence and uh we don't know what's
going to happen tomorrow and you know
next year two years after you know and
also combined with robotics there's also
already self-driving cars you know so
there is definitely a threat because you
don't know who are you dealing with
every day especially most you know most
of us spend time online right I mean
there are still people who don't spend
that much time online but it's actually
few you know it's just it's technology
it's like yeah you can you can live a
life without driving a car or without
ever using a cell phone yeah you can but
that's not practical you know so don't
don't don't don't say that oh yeah but
you know I refuse I don't I don't leave
on Twitter blah blah blah blah blah [ __ ]
okay yeah you don't leave Twitter but
everything you see is already is from
Twitter okay so you cannot avoid so
there's a threat of AI That's a thing so
people are talking about how do we avoid
it you know how do we fight it how what
can we do and you know then then then
then there's diverse opinions like I
don't think you are right you know
disagreement but one of the thing that
the brand computer interface that's what
Elm must
proposes he think that's the best um way
to fight AI
so oh FY is generated one one bunch more
oh I love okay I love I love I love
chicks I love hot
chicks I don't love trans [ __ ] okay I
love hot chicks
yes uh by the way you go to Twitter type
stable diffusion or aiy Fe there's a lot
okay but I'm not going to show
it but so there's a threat so one of the
thing L must think is good is Brin
computer interface so so so he thinks
that we just uh pay me
okay I thrive by money no money no
talk CU why always so negative
why not so you you do you like me to be
hi my name is googgle I'm here to help
the world to to help
Humanity better place to create
information for everyone so everyone can
access all the information they need to
help you decide for a wife is that what
you
want why always so negative how many
positive things do you need this this
this malen and white people they they
are positive you know go watch their
show they they are like Google like
Google you know Google YouTube they have
like kind beautiful white people they
kindly all black people you know they'll
tell you nice things about the world you
know this those are
good why negative so we talking about so
Elam musk is is um is into the brain
computer interface so that chin thank
you flam
uh so Elam musk is trying to so to fight
AI he think one of the solution is to
build chips to embed chips in our brain
or have some kind of interface so that
we our brain the way we think can be
enhanced just like AI so when AI becomes
big and powerful actually nobody knows
how which you know which way you go
but but our brain is like no less
powerful you know we can because we can
connect with chips so that's what adamus
idea uh the any details I don't
know and by the way when it comes to
that topic Brin computer interface or
artificial intelligence the the not just
technical detail but the the future you
know what will become nobody knows okay
you're online you have lots of experts
you know some of them you know of course
some many of them have lots of phds or
they are the they are the member they
are the president or they are the you
know the the CEO of artificial in
intelligence ethics conference or
something okay lots of Google Microsoft
they have that they know [ __ ] okay
that's if if you watch my video I can
tell you they know [ __ ] you know don't
when when when it comes to topics about
AI ethic you know about what AI can or
cannot do about you know you know they
know [ __ ] okay there are some you know
some of them I agree with some of them
you know but mostly they no [ __ ] that's
my opinion this stepan wolfan his
opinion I respect very much okay let me
give you a few of the people who knows
AI that I respect their opinion okay
stepan
Wan Elam musk okay
uh I don't I don't you know I don't read
much of their you know all these
especially the popular type of people
like the for example let me give you a
example the chat GPT guy what what's his
name okay he's a scum okay he's a scum
he's a no nothing scum the chat GPT the
guy who led the company who created chat
gbt okay he's a [ __ ] in my
opinion and he don't know nothing about
AI you know actual you know the science
you know that's my
opinion so anyway so let's read on so uh
Andrew
ask more oh Andrew uh where where is
Andrew Andrew ask can you talk about
your script that generates the back
links to your website oh yeah Andrew
where are you come on to are you uh
talking on
Discord
uh yeah se you know SE takes money and
it's trivial like uh anyway so yeah
about how do I create a link so okay so
for example um you know for example
right now I'm on my S Talk Show page
right so if I want to link to for for
example suppose this is a block okay
let's let's go to my comp L blog okay my
program programming blog
you know it's not cleaned up it's just
piled up a bunch of my notes my
programming
blog syntactic Obsession imperative
dispo Unicode
love and hacker hate [ __ ] the
hackers you know what what what does
hacker mean that's a Unix and C type
Fanatics [ __ ]
them okay so so anyway my Pro
programming blog is like very messy lots
of basically my notes and I stopped RSS
feed uh but anyway so let's so let's say
I'm
here so machine learning uh so you know
it's just one of my notes about one of
the task to try for machine learning
learning by creating lots of random Pol
Pol nomials and see how far can solve
you know pols we know exact we know the
solution exactly but so this would be I
think you know it would be a good test
or good thing to do to learn machine
learning so you can make a machine you
because you can easily generate lots of
examples equation and their solution
like feed the machine millions of it
billions of it then see how good it goes
or you can then you can try you know try
the neural network try
to different methods different
architecture you know maybe that's you
know that's um that's a good thing
exercise you know that's so that's one
of my notes so anyway so suppose I want
to create a new blog so showing browser
you can see today's date so I want to
let's say link to my Python tutorial so
let's see if I have a
um uh U python uh you Goan okay so let's
look at my aeve anyway no more I I just
do this okay I use my bookmark to go to
goland page there it is showing browser
goand tutorial back to emx then press a
key copy the file path you can see the
command line command name in the pink
window so I got the file
path okay and now close that paste the
link P paste the fire path here you see
there it is press a key it's linki and
press the key make it paragraph showing
browser so I have a link about to my
goine
tutorial so that's basically what I do
so but I also have a BRI I forgot like I
if I need this Goan tutorial often I
make a brief so that I Type U for
example you go then enter it becomes
that file path then I just link it you
know so for example this is useful
very useful when I was
writing uh this my major
project uh a visual dictionary of
special plan curves so this is one of my
biggest project back in 1997 it began so
often in each one of these curve equal
angular spiral for example I often needs
to link
to uh links to uh for example let's see
do I discuss here yeah there for example
involute how it relates to involute so
you can click on that so you have lots
of inter inter links for example on this
involute you have a link to Roulette by
the way what's the involute it's like
this okay so you have a curve let's say
a circle you take a
string string like a needle thread you
know then you like shoel shoelace then
you wrap around the circle then you try
to unwrap it and keep the string tight
and that curve at the end of the string
Trac out is called the involute of the
circle okay so that curve at the end is
the involute of the circle you can do
the same thing for the sign curve so you
can see the
animation so that's you know very
interesting math things in the
loot so anyway so for for example in
this project I need to create a lot of
links for example here's conic sections
you know I did this 20 25 years ago so
it's long ago I was I was a math fan so
anyways you know it's still good still
good but today most of these this is one
of my most linked website but today
people go to Wikipedia you know in the
beginning like
2005 Wikipedia contains lots of
information for my website and the
bottom at the bottom you'll say
reference you know you know for example
hyperbola whatever when Wikipedia began
in 2003 then gradually all those are gun
removed and you know they just that's
what that's the nature of Wikipedia they
essentially have of it they just copy it
from other websites you know they see
some info they rephrase it you know they
rephrase it put on
Wikipedia and first maybe a link
reference source then after year2 that
source is gone that's the nature of
Wikipedia then it becomes fake news in
the past five five years any Pol
political things on Wikipedia is just
fake news okay that's about how I create
a link uh
okay so let's see what uh I found some
money thank you flamio so let's see how
long I've been talking 30
minutes uh does Psychotherapy actually
work uh I know you flamio you have
a uh what what how do I say you are anti
Psychotherapy right you are anti
psychology and uh if you ask me the
question does psycho therapy actually
work
uh in my opinion no not really uh well I
guess it's also depends on some people
but if you are strong willed if you
are intelligent and uh you know that's a
forbidden word today intelligent what do
you mean intelligent anyway if you are
strong will and intelligent and you are
you you read a lot I don't think
Psychotherapy works but on the other
hand for most people you know they you
know they don't know for example
we we NS we can study you know we can
read about psychology psycho the therapy
what they are about but most people
don't you know they have a life to run
you know Mom and Pop maybe uh and they
and many of them you know some of them
have a lot of money right the
businessmen
salesman uh they don't they are not into
study academic study read about
psychology or whatever so for them when
they have a issue you know maybe some
you know mental health or psycho
psychology related you know they go see
a
psychotherapist and or or a c counselor
you know that becomes extremely bad
today but anyway that's what these
people do c counselor counselor of
psychotherapy so they so
this therapist you know say so they can
s you know they talk to you and they
maybe helps so at least it's a form
of talking to someone you know you get
you talk to someone have someone listen
to your problems right like like we do
on Discord you know each of us have
opinions on this or that you know so we
we need to go to on Discord to tell to
talk about our opin ions why I believe
in this or that this is a need you know
so
similarly we why not those average
people they go and pay a psycho the
therapist right you know so they have
someone to listen to them and it's
comforting that's a human need so in
that sense I think it's it maybe help it
I think depends on the situation
uh did you forget to take your
PS yeah uh well yeah I you know I I have
like a bunch of vitamins like I
usually I you know I I I I maybe I
should take it every day but um anyway
what the [ __ ] is this hello Reaper hello
John Hammer hey dude nice cat y y I'm
not going to bother to go to wesy cheap
knockoff what what is what this chip KN
off I don't know being a huge fan of
your site went through your entire
tutorial oh I was just curious if you
could just talk about defund a bit more
just for uh okay okay let's do
that okay so
defend uh
well so we we are in emac now so we are
in iMac list mod you can see at the
bottom then you just defund okay
I mean uh what I mean what else you need
to know so defund you can define a
function so function name here is a form
and here is the parameters let's say XY
and here's a dark stream this adds X and
Y okay so let's say that's what we want
okay then then this interactive thing is
a bit tricky you so you just put that if
you put that that means you can call
this command FF or whatever it's
whatever you named it you when you have
this interactive
line then that means you can call this
command by meta X so for example meta X
diod okay so that's a command so I can
just diet the command diet let me drop
into a directory right so so you have
you know in emx you have all these
commands like thousand thousands of them
you know right so if you want your
function to be call colable by meta
X that's called interactive use so if
you want that you add this this
interactive thing right after the dark
string okay then then whatever then
that's it so then whatever after that is
the body of your function so in our case
we we can delete the Le let is Define
local variables we don't need it so we
can just say x we can just say plus X Y
the last expression is a return value so
in this you don't have a return
statement okay everything is a
expression the last expression is the is
the thing that returns so this is our
whole function now pedify it you know so
that's it so we now evaluate it
so we can see I just called eval six so
now emac know about this command about
this function so now we can call it
let's say FF
ff34 okay now eval so you can see in the
mini buffer seven so let's show the mini
buffer seven right that's a result
correct now because we have the
interactive there we can also call this
function by command by meta X by name
okay so let me do it so meta
X then FF okay there it is emac knows
because of because we have the
interactive thing there okay Enter wrong
number of arguments Lambda XY you know
be
well well because when you call
interactively you know emac doesn't know
what argument they are so in this case
you need to uh you need to add like this
okay so you need to add
uh read number okay first
number
okay clean up clean up okay so you can
see
now this is how interactive becomes more
useful because now it will prompt the
user to for the input argument because
when you call interactively there it's
not like you know in a program you just
do that so okay so let's evaluate this
okay now do it again meta X FF enter so
look at the mini buffer it says first
number let's say 99 okay Enter second
number let's say one
enter it's
done now where is the results okay it
doesn't show so so you have to do one
more thing so if you want to make this
useful interactive so you just say
message uh let's just say that
okay so that way it will actually print
the result let's do it again MX FF enter
first number five second number nine
enter so you can see 14 show you see so
that's that's it that's about
that uh the resting the West is calling
why is chat GPD so bad in math oh that's
a good question uh chat GPD is so bad in
in math is
because uh because it goes by neural
network because okay here's a
fundamental thing because it's machine
learning okay so machine learning is to
get the machine to learn
something and basically the way you do
it is you just feed it a lot of examples
so here's a example input and what is
the expected
result you
know for example for chbt the input is a
question the result is maybe an essay or
answer to that question that's a typical
so all you have to do is just you you
you have to give give the machine the
program billions upon billions of such
examples typically you know so this is
called machine learning okay so you need
I mean one of the one you know machine
learning is huge so but essentially you
are teaching a computer program to learn
something okay that's basically machine
learning okay and the neural network is
one technique of machine learning so
machine learning is there's a lot of
techniques how how do you get machine to
learn something to play video games to
drive a car to recognize
images you know this is a cat this is a
dog this is computer or to recognize
human face you know to memorize human
face you know we can see you know show
10 pictures you know five pictur is the
same guy the computer can say okay this
five is actually the same guy or not you
know so computer that's machine learning
or this is machine learning okay so you
are teaching you are trying to write a
program an algorithm such that the
program can
learn based on your input based on you
know you have to give it a lot examples
that's one way there's also ways where
you don't give it examples but anyway so
anyway so machine learning is to try to
get a program to write a program so it
actually learn things okay
and and there's a lot a lot
techniques okay uh mo mo would know a
lot more you know mo teach me you know
mo is a expert you know professional
actually working the field I just
started to learn it okay so I just
started to learn it a few months ago so
anyway but I think I can give you the
general
um you know the general overview what's
going on so so that's some that's about
machine learning you write a program
an algorithm such that it can learn
things based on like example like
statistical example it can learn things
okay and there are a lot techniques you
know for example there is uh I learned
from Mo there
is one thing called uh random
Forest okay I learned that fantastic you
know what so and there's I think the
other one is decision tree what is it uh
Mo uh random Forest okay Wiki so this
one of the way one of the technique in
machine learning you know this so this
is one of the technique uh but I also
learned for more about last month about
um decision trees which is simpler so so
if you are into machine learning you
have to learn this then you then you
find some issues about this method you
know each method has like strong points
pros and cons so so then you you use
random fares to solve that problem it's
better so there are many ways okay so
machine learning you know you can see
this huge amount of like for you can do
a PhD on this right so then then so then
one of the so these are two example
techniques of getting machine to learn
something okay and and one of the method
is neural network uh which is kind of
more advanced so this picture you are
seeing that's a kind of trying to show
you neural network okay so neural
network is one of the kind of more
advanced method in machine learning okay
so but the essence of all this is that
they you are trying to get the machine
to learn something okay to to to learn
as opposed to actually writing writing a
program telling it how to solve the
problem you know for example you can
write a program how to solve how to
recognize objects you know
you but typically very hard you know so
instead you write a program using these
methods you know random forest or neural
networks so that machine can
automatically like like tell you the
answers so that's machine learning okay
so the but the essence here is that
that's a I think that's that's my
opinion okay so why is chat GPT so bad
about math so the essence you know
especially I got this Insight from
Reading Stefan wol F's article which I
think is great Stefan wolam you know so
you know if you just search for Stefan
wolam why chat GPT Works how does chat
GPT GPT work okay that's a long article
I've been reading it for the past four
month and I'm still not finished you
know so there's a Insight so seven so
the Insight is that all these machine
learning algorithms you know especially
today like with chat GB so powerful you
know magically it can like write an
essay it can write a poem describing us
you know actually this poem CH he wrote
about me because he know my website
so it's magical but so it can solve all
the problems that's what we think you
know but the but the thing is it's so
bad at math you know it when you ask
chbd for for you know simple math
questions like find a derivative you'll
just get wrong
answer it'll be very elaborate like like
it'll tell you because this theorem you
know therefore you know so we plug in
this side each side we swap them
therefore the answer is that but that
answer is wrong but it has elaborate way
you know telling you it sounds very
convincing convincing but it's just
wrong so so the reason is that is
that
uh the machine learning so hold on a
second let me close my
door so the reason is that machine
learning
they so they so Essen actually it's a
algorithm right it's algorithm that
that you know algorithm is a stepbystep
instruction which it tries to figure
things out itself so that in the end you
give it the input will come out an
output that you think is correct you
know based on existing examples so you
give it so in essence what it does all
the machine learning is eventually a
function a math function in math in math
terms you give it input it will come out
output and the the function is basically
what we want you know we want a function
that that does that a specific function
and what the machine learning does is
that it will come out with with with a
function that is very close to the
function you want you know a function
that gives the correct
answer so and this is done by training
you know by training but eventually it
gives you a function that is approximate
to the function you want so so so in in
in essence it cannot actually do any
computation so if you ask it to multiply
two big numbers it cannot do it you know
we can try chat gbt okay so let let's do
a demo okay so chat GPT hi chat GPT okay
okay it says how can I assist you
today please tell me why you are
wrong okay let's let's
see let's not wolam language okay let's
demo how idiot how what idiocy chb is at
math okay let's see if we can show
it uh okay new
document Okay so let's just say two big
numbers
okay so uh okay let's now now let's
multi technology now let's go to emac
now because I want a big number okay now
it's just give me a random number
okay times okay so this number times
that number please tell me the answer
enter oh uh shift
enter okay that's the answer
multiplication of two
numbers okay now let's chat GPT
please show me how stupid you
are wait wait
okay
check
what look the last three digit is
136 now the chat gbt the last three
digit is
036 so it's
incorrect you see so but the you see
that's the thing about chbt it's so
smart it can write essays it can write
poems but it fails in the most most
basic arithmetics
multiplication so that's a thing so this
is machine learning so but but you see
because machine learning is
algorithm that is trained to come out
with a
function so but it cannot do basic
computation that's the thing okay I
think yeah that that's a that's kind of
thing so if you like you know I can re
you know I just recommend stepan Wolf's
article
okay uh you but you takes like you
really have to be really DC at uh to to
learn
about okay so uh so you know for his
article is here I have a
link so if you are really interested in
getting to know not necessarily the
technical details I mean I'm which I'm
trying to do to learn but if you just
want to overview what is I mean the from
a scientific point of view what is going
on I can Rec highly recommend I really
like you know this guy's way of thinking
so I learned this it's like a
realization you know because I've been
thinking about how AI will or will not
be a threat you know will become
conscious will it become this or that so
one of the thing he wrote that I
realized he put it simply you know so
chat GPT or whatever machine learning it
cannot compute that's basically what you
know that's the shortest
saying artificial intelligence it cannot
compute unless you know chat gbd for
example it
recognized oh actually I'm trying to do
a computation then it it costs you know
interface it cost plugin Wan language or
whatever python then have the python do
the computation get a result and show
you but but then that's not you know you
know really machine learning that's let
that's not machine learning by itself
you know but machine can become smarter
enough that it recognize you are you are
needing you are asking to do some
computation then it asks some other
program to do it then get a result so
otherwise it's machine learning machine
learning cannot do computation so
that's that's kind of my
insight so okay so 50 minutes maybe
that's it for today uh
uh does emx do a multiplication
correctly of course if the digit is not
large enough uh if the digit is not
large enough so but is it large enough
let's
see uh so in in in emac of course it uh
so we just
do uh times yeah times okay yeah so emx
is this way so evaluate it let's see the
result here it is copy the result paste
it here
magnify emac gives the correct answer
just like w
find uh language 965 44 965 44 blah blah
blah 136 there it is chbd gives the
wrong
answer okay maybe that's it for today uh
Andrew is unable to log to my YouTube
okay can I speak still speak
Chinese uh so that's a question do I
speak
Chinese okay
so yeah you can come to Discord there's
a Chinese
room Temple o OS and David and Terry
Davis okay that's a frequently Asked
question why people ask that because
because Terry Davis is a another job
he's got a um severe you know he's got
this psycho What's
um I was going to say psycho
kesis he's got
the what's what's the word SK
schizophrenia okay that's a severe
biological brain problem you know you
you have you see Illusions you hear
things that's not there you you know
that's a
serious not that's not just a
psychological problem that's a eon
that's a brain problem okay that's what
he kind of have so and he killed he he
he he he he he died you know because he
ran into a train train ran into him or
he ran into the train we don't know
which one exactly so he's a crazy guy
and he's talking
about he's talking about you know in his
video he's talking
about uh where is
it he's he he talks about
this this thing a lot you know this end
thing so it so he's got fans like you
guys forchan people you get Zuma no
nothing us oh Terry Davis oh God Temple
o oh Drama Oh I love it oh look at this
crazy guy he's gonna die yeah so you
like you watch him just like you watch
me so you have like what do you think of
him uh well he's very smart but uh a sad
story so that's know that's about it you
know he's very bright uh he wrote Temple
OS which is very non trivial task you
know not many people can do that uh I
myself don't know much about OS okay
that's not my interest I don't I'm not
interested in C or C++ that type of
languages I'm interested in mathematics
proof Theory machine learning AI you
know I'm not interested in high level
stuff I'm not interested in C rust [ __ ]
CPU GPU [ __ ] okay that's a lot this
industrial programs are interesting
those like memory memory uh whatever the
[ __ ] you know rust rust C C++ those
people you know so anyway I don't you
know so but I can see he's you know
great
very talented but he's
got uh brain problems so that's
unfortunate that's so that's why
I uh say that's you
know okay 1 hour so that's it for today
thank you guys for watching
uh I have to thank you about your why
tiing window sucks thank
you uh potential Ultra
repan some I don't know what that
means now I hope that's not something
sensible Ultra
riparian noting or pertaining to a
person who crize judges or gives advice
outside their area of expertise okay oh
interesting new world I didn't know that
I didn't know
that
uh I can't think of a good name I think
you should think of a good name because
I can think of a good name is not a good
name yeah okay good correct good
suggestion okay um okay thank you guys
for watching that's it
that's
it I pretend to what buy it oh it's
great okay so I love this gra 0 so you
haven't read much my you know I talked
about it too
much uh so yeah you know buy a gra 80
that's I recommend so that's it thank
you guys thank you thank you so much
thank you Mo um you know in s Forum we
have lots of uh qual sometimes and
actually half of a time or often you
know I make trouble you know so sorry
about that
Mo uh and uh I mean and but it's not
just me right I mean we argue a lot so
uh thank you guys for joining and uh
let's have fun uh and I hope to let's do
a you know uh voice chat again
soon you know then then
uh thank you bye
guys yeah I think that's it for today so
great talk so we talked about let's put
them into we're going to shut down in 1
minute and let's put them kind of put
whatever we talked about into the uh
um Talk Show uh
page what I want to do so emac this yeah
I want to insert
that thank you Mo so uh yeah so here is
a result from emac so
fantastic uh what
else okay so let's put this also there
we talk about emac this defund
okay color it s HTML mod if you like it
buy it okay if you work with HTML a lot
so that's what we did today let's see
what else programming blog okay this go
back delete close uh save
close uh what else emx okay okay
bye