good morning guys welcome to another
episode of Santos show today is
September 20th Friday
2019 8 o clock a.m. San Francisco time
morning mr. spring splendid good morning
male cat
so mr. splendid says hello cos I like I
like when you talk about shortcut
optimization like key sequences what do
you think about mini 8 layout
ok let me answer that and mr. splendid
says I found recently that ago docks
easy and many other popular Do It
Yourself keyboards has not enough
standard sized keys for Russian alphabet
on the right side that is true
many of these do-it-yourself keyboards
they let me show you the keyboards so
many of them they have many data they
have too few keys so for example Do It
Yourself keyboards so I have collected a
bunch here and many of them you know it
became a fashion that they only have
like 60 keys or even 50 for example
oh go dogs oh go dogs is 70 76 keys now
for reference the piece the normal PC
keyboard for example like you know the
full size they usually have hundred one
hundred and five keys or 100 keys
something like that so a full-size
keyboard head has a hundred keys and
typically the the compact keyboard such
as such as this one they got for example
this one got 1890s so night he kissed
it's let's look at another one let's
look at this one
Keystone keyboard okay so anyway tonight
so nightly kiss of 80 keys how many keys
jeez I need to find out how many keys so
guys what other topics type it okay type
it we need topics to talk about
so vortex this one is God wait why
didn't I list number of keys
this one is vortex race this this one's
got a tribal s programming that means to
program the keys or you know for example
set caps lock to control you don't have
to launch any software you just press
keys to to set a key or remap or swap
keys so let me find out what about this
one okay so this is a full-size keyboard
about 105 keys I want I need to find out
what's the compact so look let's look at
wooden now booting is very interesting
one because they've got analog analog
keystroke it's actually I think it's
actually digital digital but how about
by analog they mean that that how much
you press down is measured so you can so
so you can the process of pressing your
key down is kind of a control it's not
just on and off so you have different
levels of control for example you can
you can use one key as a gas pedal in
some driving game for example so they
called analog mechanical switch the
actual mechanism may not be analog they
just use that word so it makes sense to
people
so let's look at oh yeah so wait so why
can't I find compact keywords okay happy
hacking for example it's only God
something like 60 60 keys not not enough
okay
anything that's in 60s parity minimum
it's actually not good god when I need
to know number of keys I don't have it
usually I'm meticulous about making sure
I have the number of keys information
because it usually it's hard to count so
this one is a compact keyboard I have it
I did a review video review this
ultimate hacking keyboard this one's got
64 keys okay that's not enough
64 keys nice that's not enough when you
have when you like a keyboard that does
not have enough keys then what you want
to do is you want to buy a programmable
keypad such as any one of these this one
is got this pray on each key and there
and by the way this is these days these
are not very expensive for example this
one is only 100 hundred dollars one
hundred fifty hundred fifty dollars you
know and this one is similar so when you
like a keyboard that does not have
enough keys you want to buy one of these
programmable keypads there are many
varieties here I have it on my website
so let me post my website so you guys
can check it out you know buy it on my
website so you support me let me paste
it and I will get to the question
wait am i talking yes I'm talking in am
i alive yes I'm alive okay good
so mr. splendid says what about what do
I think of mini 8 mini Mac 8 layout I
don't think it's good I'm going to let
me talk about that okay so so first of
all yes it's true you know so it's a
fashion it's it's kind it became a
fashionable today that many of these
keyboards does not have mini keys for
example this one is only got 54 keys now
oh go dogs Scout 70 76 keys 76 is barely
enough okay I would still I mean for me
it's not still not enough I would need
for example I showed this many times I
would need to get and see I need to
would I would need to get a program book
or keypad like that okay so so yeah so
one solution you can do is just to buy a
programmable keypad now there are many
solutions like by the way if you have
questions ask okay I mean this is a good
time to ask all your keyboard questions
like when I talk you have a question
just ask so we can talk about it so what
so when I talk about programmable
keypads there are many you can buy one
of these the oh these are programmable
keypads now here's a thing now if you
don't want to spend that much money on a
programmable chip hat usually these are
anywhere from $80 to 150 okay these are
programmable keypads now so if you want
to save money so what you can do is you
buy a you buy a numeric keypad such as
this
these are not programmable they are just
like number pads so you buy one of these
then then you can use your operating
system
maybe Linux Mac or Windows you can
program it of course this is this is not
this is a programmable keypad is much
better but if you don't really want to
spend that much money then you can go
with this numerical keypads and use your
operating system to program it and I
have a article that teaches that that
teaches you how to program number keypad
as function keys so you know for Windows
basically for Windows you use auto
hotkey for Mac you use you basically use
this carabiner ok and on Linux you know
there are solutions I show here morning
green deck
ok so let me finish talking about the
topic so let me say hi to green deck
thanks for advice in previous show for
not swapping contrarian caps thank you
thank you yeah you had a swapped for
three months now switched back oh yeah
yeah that's a good thing so so splendid
as asked about the mini Mac eight key
layout okay let me tell you what that is
so you go through my keyboard blog then
you go to layout this section okay and
you go to alternative layout so you have
Corti you have Iraq you have
programmable rack you have mini Mac
copper asset Norman Commack and and
quite a few others ok so there is one of
them is mini Mac so let me talk about
mini Mac so many of these keyboard
layouts
they are designed so that they are
designed so that if you already know how
to touch type on quote II then
supposedly you
easier to learn this new layout okay
oh these for example or this normal
layout Asset layout Walkman well mostly
in particular Cormac Commack is designed
so that it changes 17 keys from quote e
for example all the red keys you see
here they are different from Cody but
all the white keys are the same as Cody
so that the idea is that when you
already know how to touch type on Cody
and if you want to switch to a efficient
layout then you can switch to Commack
because supposedly it's easier to learn
because you don't have to learn every
key you just learn some some of the keys
are changed 17 of them that's idea and
but but in my opinion that's not a good
idea because when you want to learn
because first of all it's not
necessarily easier fewer keys does not
necessarily mean it's easier to learn
okay in fact I have people I mean
somewhere on my blog I've shown the
people other people's Park they tried to
learn Commack and they he also tried to
learn more AK and for him Warrick is
easier to learn Commack is harder to
learn so anyway I don't like the idea
you know they I don't think he's good I
don't like Commack okay so this is my
biased opinion but anyway so now let's
talk about mini Mac so mini Mac is the
same idea you know mini Mac the idea of
mini Mac is that actually the mini Mac
layer
they have several versions the first
version only changed four keys from
Corti okay so this is extremely easy to
learn this is easy to learn for sure
you know you're only swap to two pair of
keys so in total four keys are changed
okay
then they have a different version okay
they have like similar versions like
progressively more change in a changed
number of keys so the first one is
changing for keys the second one is
changing 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 8 keys then
let's see another one is 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
9 10 11 12 then another one 12 keys so
you have these three different versions
the idea is is that you start with the
easiest version you know assuming that
you already know how to touch type on
Cody so you switch to this version you
know you just learn change your muscle
memory for four keys so after a week
maybe after week you will be okay then
if you want to get if you want to be
more efficient then you use a 12-8 key a
key change version then used later on
switch to twelve keys changed version
that's idea and to me I don't I don't I
don't think is this is a great idea okay
if you really want to be proficient in
you know if you want a proficient layout
you want a efficient layout just go go
through a layout of your choice my
choice is for whack so you pick a layout
you like and just just just spend one
month one hour a day just you know learn
that layout I mean so the the mini Mac
you know the idea of switching gradually
yeah I suppose that works but you know I
don't think it's it's it's that I mean
the by the design I mean I don't think
it's a practical okay I mean the idea is
that you have a busy person you have to
type everyday you know other you know
your your income depends you on you
typing every day so you cannot have one
month vacation you know being unable to
type or type slowly the
for they created this minimax so you can
just change a few keys then you when you
are good then you switch to more keys
it's a it's you know it's kind of a
fancy idea but it's it's not I don't
think it's realistic I mean you work for
sure but I don't think it's necessary
just just pick a layout you like and
yeah and spend one month do it okay so
that's my opinion opinion about the mini
Mac layout yeah some splendid says by
the way over Docs has a a nice online
layout configurator it's not good okay
because for example I have article on
that let me show you the best thing okay
you see this subject matter is about
once you have a programmable keyboard
what is the method to program the keys
now there are several methods one method
is let me let me talk about them okay so
but let me be the comments first let's
see what else are the topics by the way
if you want to learn Russian layout why
don't you use all Russian yeah Russian
is a problem yeah the ocean you know
typing Russian noise have problems
because you have you have to constantly
switch between corty you know English
layout and Russian layout is that true I
mean is that what you do so green deck
says I actually had a swamp green deck
says why even switch from Cody is that
bad oh yeah Cody is bad that yeah that's
the first thing you learn when you study
about keyboard efficiency you know that
Cody is pretty bad you know so I talked
about this topic about few months you
know the last week or something so let's
go to let me let me show you okay
because that's a I because I talked on
that be
deal I talked about twenty or thirty
minutes on on whether you should switch
to switch your layout and what layout
should you switch and whether you should
learn touch typing so that's one our
talk about that
so let me show you what search for
colemak okay so this this this one okay
wait so let's show it so this is 2019
August 21st
okay go to youtube and watch this one
green deck if you are interested okay so
because this this video talks about or
this layout and touch typing issues yeah
yeah just so check out that video okay
so let me answer the question about
online configurator yeah so so this is
about so let's go back to keyboard close
that okay so wait yeah close that yeah
let's go back to keyboard okay back to
my keyboard block and we want to go to
key binding is it key binding or layout
let's see they are no it's actually in
design okay
so on this page it's an index of
articles related to keyboard design the
physical keyboard design the key switch
issues the Enki rollover issues which is
electronics the key cap technology key
labo technology I mean there are many
details like when you actually study the
keyboard like you you get deeper and
deeper like over the past you know 20 30
years I you know I learned every time I
learned the new thing about keyboard and
didn't
before and you know I I was surprised so
anyway and one of the topic about
keyboard is firmware now a firmware is a
piece of software that usually it's
embedded in a chip inside a keyboard
because when you press a key you know
there's a there needs to be a small chip
that processes the information and send
it to your computer so that that piece
of software on a chip is called firmware
now for programmable keyboards from
where is all important because this is
because it is a firmware that does the
reprogram reprogramming of keys now
and each programmable keyboard they are
they have different capabilities okay
this is important now if you don't study
keyboards you may not know because for
example today you have lots of gaming
keyboards you can like program across
then you also have lots of you know
programmable keyboards for example let
me show you
programmable keyboards with amp onboard
memory all these ok now when you buy a
program of programmable keyboard you
have to make sure they have onboard
memory because there are some gaming
keyboards such as those made by Razer
they suck okay they sometimes they don't
have onboard memory or they have
software on a keyboard that prevents you
to actually store things in the memory
they want you to connect to the internet
the crowd you know they want to register
they want you to register account
otherwise you know and install their
software otherwise you cannot reprogram
your keys things like that you know
those are bad you want a keyboard
programmable keyboard when you buy a
programmable keyboard make sure they
have onboard memory like I've you know
so I studied this issue I give you the
conclusions you know you can see on this
page you can read about it just go to my
website
so these are the programmable
programmable keyboards with onboard
memory oh these are good okay
the the goal of this thing is that
basically you don't you don't want you
don't need internet okay you don't want
them to depend on internet so you don't
have internet you can just program your
keyboard bring to work plug in and your
work you know all your custom keys your
work you know you bring it to your
friends house your walk you walk
anywhere you know because it's
programmed inside the keyboard that's
what you want so all these are
programmable keyboards okay and now
let's go back to the firmware now
different programmable keyboards they
have different capabilities okay this is
another important thing for example many
keyboards allows you to swap keys remap
keys for example you want you want f2 to
do some other thing a macro or something
okay you can do that but they are not
the same okay so they have different
capabilities for example modifier keys
okay what if you want to be map modifier
keys for example you want to swap caps
lock with ctrl or alt or Windows key
things like that so that's another thing
so some some programmable keyboard can
do that some cannot okay so this is this
is important once you get into detail
for example gaming keyboards typically
keyboards you know market marketed to
gamers you know they are programmable
but they but they are they are not
designed when you want to do something
they cannot do for example typically
suppose you want f11 and f12 to be
volume down and volume up sound level up
sound level down okay every level have
job on gaming keyboards typically you
may not be able to do it
that to do that depends on the model
didn't you know depending on who who is
making it so so so these are some of the
issues you might be concerned now if you
are a programmer or Emacs user your need
are typically different from those
schemas for example if you are a Russian
you you know you from Russia and you use
Russian layout you want a key tool for
example to swap layer between English
and Russia you know you want to do
suppose you want f11 to set it to
English layout f12 to rush your layout
now for gaming keyboards you cannot do
that it's so more so you know usually
older gaming keyboards
however fancy like programmable and
lights and so that that's usually they
don't have that capability in so in this
case you want you want a programmable
keyboard such as such as Oh
most of these wheel can do that you know
you can press a key to to swap the
entire layout for your keyboard so there
are these different capabilities you
might be of interest you know depending
on what you want your keyboard to do you
know whether you are programmer or a
gamer or you want both you know so
basically the more powerful they can do
everything you know so the one with the
most program ability is this one okay
the ultimate hacking keyboard I did a
video review this one is got the best
program ability the power the power of
how you know what things you can program
okay and but however this keyboard do
not have driverless it's not driverless
programmable meaning that every time you
want to change some keys you need to
launch the software okay so you need to
like start the software then it's very
easy you know change keys and press set
okay then closes you know you can create
the software then it's set in
keyboard then you can bring to work and
so on but it's not driverless
programmable meaning that you have to
launch the software to program it so
that's one way to program the keyboard
driver driverless programmable is the
best okay so anyway we talked about
firmware capabilities you know what kind
of changing Keys they can do that you
know you can read it for detail then
let's talk about up okay another issue
is we talked about this you know
firmware programmable keyboard so you
might be thinking you know maybe you are
using Linux or maybe you are using
Windows with the autohotkey or Mac with
carabiner you know you can already
program the keys via the operating
system why do you need to buy a
programmable keyboard because you can
already for example I have the carabiner
here carabiner which is yeah this this
software you know you know it changed
some keys so you might so so why do you
need a program programmable keyboard now
programmable keyboard is the better it's
better okay because programming by the
operating system always have they always
have glitches issues like sometimes it
doesn't work like the Devaney on average
system also depends on you know which
software you used to program it so but
typically they always have little
sometimes glitches for example on
Windows for example if you use
autohotkey but sometimes when you launch
your register edit okay when you launch
that with a privilege you know admin
privilege then all your autohotkey does
not work so when you when you wrote
launch for example read register edit
then your your autohotkey keep key
bindings stop walking stops working
because
because you need to launch autohotkey as
a privileged user in order to do so so
you know that's an example of a glitch
but however if you have your own
programmable keyboard it's always work
always work because the signal sent to
the computer is always the key you want
so that's an example same thing on Linux
you have issues for example typically on
Linux you program the keys in x11
but then every time you switch to the
virtual console or in the boot screen or
single user mod then all your keys
doesn't work so if you are Russian
programmer for example you want you have
a key that switch between English and
Russia but then when you are in a
virtual console you all your keys
doesn't work so you have to you know
then then it gets more complex to
program you know so things like that on
a Mac is it's less of an impact but
anyway you have this issue okay so the
best thing is to get you on the
programmable keyboard okay with with
onboard memory so by it
okay buy it buy it from my website ok
let me show the let me paste you the
link ok and ok so that's about that now
the next thing we're going to talk about
is the next thing we're going to talk
about is where is the where did my page
ok the next thing about firmware is what
is the method what what is the method to
program the keys you see once you have a
programmable keyboard how do you program
the keyboard what's the method ok one of
the best feature best method is
driverless programming I already talked
about that meaning that if you want to
even if you want to change for example
f2 to be
saucy control C for copy for example f2
you press f2 it does control C if you
want that you don't have to launch any
software you just you just press you
know press some keep on comment
you know like start programming key
combination typically and then press f2
then press the key you want you know the
combination
then press stop programming then that
set then now you when you press f2 that
does control C now that is the case with
my keyboard Canisius ok I can do it
right now but I don't want to because
you know this camera sucks ok this
camera is Logitech 920 and 922 ok he
sucks he cannot focus so so anyway so I
you know on this my Canisius advantage I
can just press keys to program it I
don't have to launch any software they
all that they do
allows you to have software way too so
anyway so tribalist programming is a
great feature to have it's not necessary
you know because typically you program
it once and you know it's not something
you have to do all the time unless you
are designing shortcut layouts you know
or you you if you are using Photoshop
you constantly you are you you are
trying to design your system of you know
shortcut layout for Photoshop for
example and you are not decided you know
what shortcut you want to be yet so
every day or every few days you have to
constantly constantly change anyway so
travelers programming is great feature
ok travel less programming and then you
have graphical software graphical
software is typically like gaming
keyboard like this one I showed you know
this this this gaming keyboard this one
is Logitech 9 9 10 actually all our gtex
gaming keyboard they have the same
same programming software the you know
the drivers you know on Windows you call
them drivers so the interface is the
same so and it's very good Logitech I
trust logitech ok if you want them if
you want to buy a commercial gain gaming
keyboard
I recommend Logitech I have many
logitech on my website for example PC
keyboards I have some reviews of them
somewhere here Logitech this classic
night hand and logitech 5:13 Logitech
810 you know they are pretty good
I do not never by Razer ok never by
Razer and I would I do not recommend cos
a needle I trust Logitech so logitech
gaming keyboards oh huh so we are back
to the topic of how do you program the
keys so graphical software is very
popular okay and and very good because
they give you an overview of all your
keys you know in one shot this in this
aspect is better than tribalist
because travelers you know once you
program in case you forgot which key
does what and that's a headache you know
usually that's a headache to figure out
so you usually they they also feature a
graphical user interface so that you can
see all your keys you know so so you
want graphical software and if you have
travelers programming that's better now
the worst case is updating firmware okay
now that is an example of the logo Docs
as far as I know so what does obtain
from where mean like they like this okay
this is one of the oviducts website this
one is from oh go Doc's infinity okay so
you go to a website you know it's kind
of tedious you go to their website then
you drag the keys you know you
create a layout okay then you click Save
then you it will create a file you
download that file then then then you
follow some instructions you how is it
done yeah
can you explain I mean you got a go Docs
right mr. splendid so basically so you
download the file that's your layout
then you start up the firmware updater
some kind of software you know you have
to download a firmware updater then you
launch that then you say change layout
then you select the layout you just
created then it updates it it updates
the firmware then you can quit quit or
the software then it's now now it's
programmed the way you like so this this
is the worst this this way
so mr. splendid says I have think
keyless master Keys Pro by Cooler Master
yeah okay so cooler master is I also
kind of trust but actually I don't have
any cooler master keyboard but cooler
master so you have the 10 keyless master
key okay master key ok so that's a you
know gaming that's designed for gaming
yeah 10 keyless this one now so they
also feature you see they say change
your settings on the fly no need to
first with proprietary software or
adjust all of your preferences right on
your keyboard that means they have
driverless programming yeah so it's very
good so any any other questions posted
ok let me let me check out the comments
Green Tech so Pablo says hey good
morning Pablo Pablo is from hey Pablo
you are from South America is I right
like what country I think it's South
America
what would you do if you didn't touch
type and you want to learn I mean where
I quote you okay max efficiency
reasonable learning time okay yeah like
you know like I mentioned you should
check out you know check out the check
out this talk show okay
I mean if you have time you know if you
have extra time check out this August
twenty one twenty two thousand eleven
two thousand nineteen August 21st my
video that talks about a lot about that
but let me tell you so to learn touch
typing there is no shortcuts okay it's
like there is no shortcut to good things
you have to spend one hour a day and
four months then you'll be good yeah one
hour a day for Oh half a house let's say
1/2 hour a day okay and and do it for a
month
Oh Pablo is from Spain Europe okay great
so you if I have any question about
Spain I'm gonna ask you okay so anyway
so to learn touch typing you let me show
you okay let's go back to keyboard I
have so on this page is all about touch
typing so you just you have to spend 30
minutes practice you know 30 minutes a
day for at least one month then you'll
be you will be faster then then then
before you were touch typing okay so I
have like how to touch type basically
and I also give you so this is the
basics of how to touch type okay let me
let me talk about this for one minute
basically the prints that the only thing
that principle is the only if you can if
you if there is one sentence you can
remember about touch typing it is this
okay always use the correct finger for
each key
okay in touch-typing every key is
supposed to be typed by a specific
finger so the the fundamental principle
about touch typing is always use the
correct key to press a party correct
finger to press a particular key you can
forget about all tutorials everything
else just remember this one every time
you press key any key you press always
use the correct finger you can just
remember this one thing if you are in
your island no books no nothing this
principle you buy this principle you
will learn touch typing okay but anyway
so that's the principle and I talked
about here but but I also have some
websites web typing typing tutorial
website you know these three are good
ones and there's also typing speed
websites so these four are good ones so
just go there and check it out you know
this yeah it's better it's good to
follow you know they have like you know
sequential lessons you know you just go
there practice for half hour a day so
let me type that
so whether to choose work or not it's
it's a bit complicated okay so it's
really depends on you for example I
would tell you to go for AK because I
use for AK since 1994 and it's very
efficient but they are trade offs for
example once once you learn more AK you
will forget you will forget usually come
you know you don't remember touch-typing
quality anymore
so every time you go to library or use
your friend's computer you cannot touch
type that you have you have problems
like that you know you know company you
cannot use other people's computer
because you don't touch type there well
you can still hunt and pick you know so
you got little problems like these so
ultimately what it's worth it or not
it's up to you now if you mostly just
you know mostly if you are just a
programmer by yourself you don't use any
other keyboards you you know then Dania
and and and and also if you prefer
efficiency then yeah you know work
Oh mr. splendid says see a masters CMS
turkey Marco sucks okay that's good to
know yeah yeah so so you know the
programmable you know although they are
all programmable keyboards but they they
do have differences like once you get
once you start to use it you know you
know this this one doesn't do can really
do what you need to do so that's why I
said you know the best if you know if we
consider the programmable
programmability of a keyboard this one
is the best the automat hacking keyboard
their you know their programming ability
is just fantastic I have the you know so
I did a video review of it you know you
guys can watch go to go to my website
then that the video will show so George
good morning George and George is from
Sacramento am I correct
Church says Mac OS version of Commack
dozen we map caps lock so haven't tried
it oh okay oh really
yeah so that's a it's another issue with
Commack so yeah I didn't know so I'm
surprised okay so yeah they didn't
remaps lock
so mr. splendid says I just use it
because it's mechanical and ten key
keyless but I do not use its macro
functions okay so but you are do you
have a go dogs or are you thinking of
buying one
so Malka Malka says today's topic is
Richard Stallman's parrot does he have a
parrot so did they really engage in okay
you know anyways let's talk about
keyboard for today
Oh George is from Perth Australia oh
sorry about that
jeez I forgot the
so who's the other guy on yes so I was
going to say Australia but I thought its
Sacramento Rica play by training key
okay so Rica played does I'd considered
also time like if faced with the same
speed as you press it yeah yeah yeah so
I guess that's not so good yeah but okay
so that's about all the keyboards I
guess that's about the keyboards so is
there any questions anything else
interesting Richard Stallman let's talk
about that another day you know it's
it's kind of very touchy yeah let's talk
about him the another day so male cat
are you using
are you using a mechanical keyboard or
so dingo Oh dingo dingo dingo rule says
if you didn't type Chinese would you
consider Commack as an option no because
it has little to do with Chinese oh okay
so no I wouldn't consider Commack well
because you know I already typed for Ag
since 1994 so you know I've been typing
work for 20-25 years there's no reason
for me to switch to Commack now let's
but suppose suppose in 1994 Commack is
already invented you know Commack was
invented around 2005 okay I don't like I
don't like Commack you know because you
know so partly because I'm biased you
know because I already used for AK so
Commack to me is kind of this deviant
you know they are trying to this guy he
is trying to you know create a
for himself you know there's already
vorak which is good but he created one
and he says oh this is more efficient
than the more active so what he created
so what happens is there's a fork so now
and and since Commack there's many folks
that's why there are so many but but the
problem is you know you see one of the
important things is is that you want
people to bind together you know if you
want to go efficiency there's one
prorack if you know if that's okay
that's good because you have more and
more people using ball rack and possibly
quarry will be obsolete
you know people every key board maker
you just create wall rack and that's
good for everyone okay so in my eyes the
VOC the Commack is not good guy you know
he just created oh this is my this is my
own Commack you know this is even better
than boric actually that's not true
you know I thought that I talked about
that in in the other video I mentioned
you know for for our it's not true you
know I have article here you can see I
don't want to click it you know because
every time I click a link it takes you
know a minute or two anyway so so so I
so it's kind of biased opinion so I
don't like black because he just created
you know he just created his own you
know he wants of course he become more
famous you know instead of just you know
joining the vorak user it's episode my
opinion of Commack is a little bit
biased but I do have good reasons you
know like I analyzing one of the
articles in if you go to keyboard layout
you will see it anyway so so but what if
Co Mac is invented in 1994 before I even
learned Barack would I choose it
possibly yeah
you know it's hard to say it could it's
possible because then because I I did a
nova rack then I have to chop to toe
you know vorak and Cormac then I
probably will hear you know the Comex
marketing you know talk they will say Oh
Commack is Martin Martin you know
because the computer era we can analyze
keystrokes and so while Dvorak is like
fifty hundred years old you know back
then you know you don't have much Anna
you know such it's statistics computer
statistics stuff so you know that's a
leo
that's a lieu of Commack you know so so
yeah so if I you know if I didn't know
where Ike possibly I choose Cormac okay
so you you use Commack with pinging
that's fine okay so George George used
Commack okay so mr. splendid dinga dinga
where where are you from what country so
mr. splendid and mr. stranded where are
you from again sale again so mr.
splendid says I plan to buy oh go ducks
toi found about Russ they are problem
what is the roast layout problem a
Russian oh oh yeah so so actually I
don't recommend a go ducks okay if you
want to go that route now first of all
you can buy one of these you know what
yeah so for example kinases so that's
what I use I also recommend this one
kinase is free-style H this Oconee is
free-style edge these are easy choices
you can buy it on Amazon you know Oh
ultimate hacking is pretty good but
against too few keys okay okay so to
view keys also it's not it's not Otto
leaner so in other words the layout is
not a grid you know rectangular grid
it uses the traditional kind of slanted
you know layout so two major problems is
the you know slanted layout and and too
few keys you know it's only got 64 keys
so too few keys you can solve that
problem you can solve it by just buying
a programmable keypad so you know get a
combination with you know get get get
this or or that you know then solve the
problem all for your all for all of your
one key packing needs like copy paste
you know copy or you know soleko copy
paste like like like what do for example
I'm gonna show you okay look look at
what I do so let me show you that okay
so you can see and you can see my screen
okay so you can see you see my screen I
press this key select all copy switch to
last window okay that's not what I want
I want to switch to Emacs okay now open
a new buffer paste you see it's like or
copy/paste it's all one thing one finger
key press never do code like I never do
control something like like you can see
my Emacs saw start command log mod okay
so go to the top up buffer you see the
my keys will show up on the left window
so you can delete this section go down
or go up go down you can delete this
section go up enter paste that section
paste paste previous for example and now
I want to cross the buffer okay again
one key look at my finger okay i yeah i
i i'm i don't i'm not going to move the
cam
but anyway one key okay close the buffer
okay he asked me do I want to save then
no on the left you see that you see that
means super W I mean that means command
W but actually I'm pressing one key
because it's a programmed via my
operating system because the because
this keyboard this keypad is a numerical
keypad
it's not a programmable keypad so I have
to use Mac OS to program it
okay that is why when I press a key that
does closed window so when I press the
key that actually does command W on a
Mac so that that is why you see this
this thing here but actually it's just
one key but on the meanwhile but if you
look at on my Emacs you can see it's all
single key like showing browser again
the key to show in browser is also a
single key but it because it's
programmed so that's why it shows two
keys so okay but German but German says
Commack you can do copy-paste same as
corty so it is nice no it is not nice
actually that is a flaw of Commack I
talked about that in this article okay
in detail that actually gives you
repetitive strain injury you know so I
talked about this in my articles many of
these layout designs let me show you
that so let's go to keyboard layouts
which is here and you go to alternative
layouts and you go to go down go down
you go to the colemak okay so let me
read it okay
layouts such as mini Mac copper acid
norman komak have one thing in common
they all keep many quality keys in same
position so it's supposed to be easier
to learn if you already touch type korte
also they keep the z XC v keys in the
same position as quality so that the
undo cut copy paste keys don't change
which actually induces repetitive strain
injury can you believe that if you don't
believe that you have to read this
article see why undo cut shortcut key
are bad so ever story here I tell you so
you see to so many of these layout you
know by design they think you know they
want to keep the control cut you know
copy paste keys as the same you know
don't change don't change the X X v XC v
and z keys you know they think it's a
good design but actually it's not
because because when you can see you see
you see let's let's look at undo you
know typically undo let's go back you
see undo is this key right Z now which
fit which your which one of your finger
presses see if you touch type that's
going to be this finger okay wait so
this is my right hand this is my left
hand why do I see we reversed so this is
my left hand on a second
I'm getting confused this is my left
hand
is it we reversed guys can it this is my
left hand is it reversed like do you see
this anyway so anyway so when you press
the Z key you use your pinky it's fine
okay so when you press the Z key you use
your pinky right and undo is one of the
most frequently and do good morning
Cathy great to see you and do is one of
the most frequently used shortcuts so
imagine they wherever you press and do
they want you to use pinky you think
that's good that's no good that you know
that's not economic you know on one hand
is this is this is supposed to be a
economic layout but then they try to
keep the shortcuts to be an ergonomic
what's what our idea see anyway anyway
so it is a flaw you know this so I think
these people they they didn't think
about that they didn't look into too
much in depth you know they you know
just because they are designing a letter
layout they you know so they are just
concerned about later layout and they
you know then then they think that oh
let's just keep keep the Z Z xcw in the
same place so that you know the
shortcuts works the same that's not
that's not right because the shortcut is
also pressed by your fingers so that's
also you know there's economic issues so
this problem actually happened to me so
back so let me tell you about the story
away where you know because I was using
I was using this keyboard yeah I
explained in detail I back then so this
is around this is 2012
okay in 2012 I was using this keyboard
this is the robot Dom keyboard and and
back then I was using you know I'm a
Emacs user and I was using the ogon ago
Emacs mod ok and it has a feature such
that let me show you that such that when
you want to cut you don't have to make a
selection like normally in Emacs you
have to make selection then you cut you
know then you cut okay but but I have a
function you don't need to do that let
me show you okay so so look at my
command course on the left window so I
want to cut I just press one key no no
need to selection okay undo I want to
cut this line press one key no selection
and what if I want to cut multiple lines
for example I go here cut cut cut cut
cut cut you see look at the left side
its oh I'm I'm using borax oh it's so
cute key you see six times so I can
continue to cut cut cut cut again I can
hold down cut you know you'll cut the
whole buffer okay you see it's all cut
now I open a new buffer paste it you see
everything is together all the things I
could you know is here okay now close
this code the close these don't save
reopen yeah we are back okay so so we
saw in Emacs in Ocoee max mod I created
a a command such that you can cut
without needing to selected also you can
hold it down and you cut model multiple
lines so I find this so convenient I
stopped you know suppose I want to
delete this paragraph I stopped making a
selection you know I stopped making a
selection then DV that I stopped doing
that I just you know I just started to
cut cooker I just do this you know hold
it down you know I started to do that
so that means I started to press this
key a lot you know this this X key I
started to press that a lot with this
finger you know with this you see the
this ring finger and one day I started
to have pain okay what is the what is my
you know I thought I detailed them here
so in 2012 using ergonomic economic
keyboard but with a row bottom keyboard
so the Microsoft natural economic 4000 I
actually developed RSI syndrome my hand
ting ting goes yeah so my hand tingles
so actually I have I have a detailed
reason here this you know this is
serious because back then it was panic
like you don't know you don't know you
don't know what caused it you know oh I
know is that I started to have this
tingling I know it's going to be pain if
I don't care because you know I I know
about this I so the story is here okay
so the story the complete story is this
one so return in 2012 and this the cause
of this problem is with the X and s Keys
the reason I started to press X a lot is
because that cut you know that cut thing
no good so it let me describe the horror
okay
you know I want to find a section that
way I I was panicking because you know
because you are programmer you need to
breathe you need to type to eat okay to
to tube to make money what he wants you
can all type you got a problem so back
then okay I don't remember where do I
say it but I have to read it you know
it's a long article but anyway let me
just tell you so I started to have this
tingling I mean is it serious because
you don't know you don't know what you
did wrong
you don't know maybe the keyboard is
wrong or maybe you didn't eat well or
you know or something you didn't sleep
well or something you don't know but you
just have this pain you know and it's
everyday like maybe today but you think
Oh tomorrow you'll be fine but tomorrow
it's again so so when this happens to
you it could happen to any of you okay
or when you get older after 10 years or
five years you will come okay it happens
to you and you don't know you know
typically it's very hard to find out
exactly what you know what is causing it
you don't know so one day this happened
eventually after a month okay here here
here here is a paragraph okay you know
this is my blog I wrote it at the at the
time you know my left hand is
Emacs wasn't sure what's causing it now
I know it's a key that require using
fourth and fifth fingers while hand is
in standard touch typing position
actually mostly the undo cut keys and
the standard save and select all keys
yeah that that that was causing it okay
I did I did not describe the panic much
it's just you know the first sentence my
left hand is you know at that
time I remember you know it's it's
pretty bad because you panic because
then you have to see a doctor right I
don't have I don't have money to see a
doctor you know
so you and I know a lot of people like
the email me you know they've seen
doctor so horror stories so so so anyway
back to the topic so that is why I'm
telling you that this should cut Z has
xcw that's no good okay you don't want
that you see this happened to me in
particularly because I was using this
keyboard now normally this is an
ergonomic keyboard and it's all good
however it's rubber dome that's a
problem no bottom is no good you want my
mechanical keys if you if I have no
mechanical keys then back then I may not
have that problem yeah so this I think
after this I you know so after this I
stopped I think after year in 2003 or so
I stopped using these keys I started to
use mechanical keys the truly urban arm
a keyboard I have a review here I know I
know where to find it but let's keep
that let's go back to read the comments
so so let me warn you guys okay don't do
you know when you you know the photos
copy cut paste be careful the best thing
is actually to make f1 f2 f3 f4 to be to
be sick or soleko cut copy paste like
like I just showed you know with my
keypad one key you know you never press
control something things like that so
let's read the comments and that that
will be it for today so maybe let's talk
for five more minutes
yeah oh if you have any more key
keyboard questions key binding questions
pace it okay
so he has some advanced programmable
behaviors so dingo says i find so many
of the keys being in the same position
on Commack a little confusing
compared to iraq when switching from
corty ok ok so so mrs. Brenda says by
the way I find it copy and paste on
extra mouse keys yeah that's good too
because my mouse right now you know it's
it's it's this one I cannot show it my
mouse is this one Logitech Logitech
you know it's it's got this great thing
it's this spins forever like it's it can
spin up to 30 seconds no this is
fantastic
so I can show you for example if I go to
browser if I go to this open a new
window new go to blog I can just spin it
you see it's still spinning you know you
need to go to a really long page and you
know just keep spinning
let's go through let's go through my
keyboard blog I mean my programming blog
ok
so you see using my hands is here you
know so I can stop it anytime against I
can quickly go to places I want and stop
it you're just spinning and when I want
to stop I just you know put my hand on
the wheel so you guys spy it let me show
you the mouse okay how to choose a mouse
you know all the other things you ever
wanted to know about mass it's all here
so the that one is actually here and I
do have a video showing a spin
okay so you need to you guys need to buy
it buy it and I make a dollar also yeah
half a dollar and fifty cents okay so
anything else
so yeah I was saying I have that mouse
but this mouse 2 does not have as many
key as I wish
so let me demo okay so let me show you
what you know you need to look at my so
there is my mouse and if I go here my
browser so you see these two buttons
they are previous tab next tab you see
so I don't I don't have to leave my hand
and you know I don't have to go back to
keyboard to switch tab you know previous
tab previous tab previous tab and and
this button on the thump here it's close
tab okay I don't have any way so this
button is close tab let me show it again
close okay reopen it oh wait I need to
reopen reopen reopen reopen reopen okay
so and and these two buttons thumb
buttons are back backward and forward
for example I go to Unicode I can scroll
down and backward back previous forward
backward forward you know it just go to
previous link page so this mouse does
not have that many buttons you know 1 2
3 4 5 5 extra buttons so you have
previous tab next tab close tab backward
forward so it's you know but I have
another mouse that has like 20 buttons
so I have so I have those and I also
have copy paste select oh and and other
things volume up volume down things like
that so that's so that's why I also
recommend a it's close this you know I
recommend a
Mortimer's I mean if you are a gamer if
you are PG gamer then you know you know
you know how useful it is but if you are
a programmer this is how useful it is
because for programmers you need to
browse web all the time you know reading
documentation or you need to especially
if you work in Windows visual Microsoft
Visual Studio things like that you can
press a key to compile and stuff and
things like that you know so that's
about Mouse that's about you know extra
buttons on Mouse
how about remapping map caps allowed to
escape if you are using VI are you using
VI Kathy so if you are using VI
that's that's an excellent thing to do
yes
so mr. splendid says I have map caps to
layout switch en Russia okay great the
yeah I think that's a great thing to do
so George George say it's not sure about
mapping caps to escape but my philosophy
is use pinky fingers video as possible
yeah that makes sense too you know one
technique about pinky is that you don't
want to move the finger you want to like
just use a whole hand so you so when you
want to press the caps lock you just
move it over there and just let means
try to do just move it there and just
push the entire palm down don't don't
like move your finger
ok I think that's it for today
in in USA yeah you do have you need
money to see a doctor unless you are in
Canada or Northern Europe where you have
like universal healthcare things like
that Benjamin Benjamin where are you
from you know even today I have I have a
repetitive strain injury like this is
strange like it's over here okay I can
show you it's here it's just is some
area here you know it's like here I had
this kind of pen it's not really really
a pen but it's kind of pen and it's not
tingling so usually I do this you know
this is metal I mean the stone paw you
know so I do this it feels good so I you
know this I had this like for a year and
I cannot find out exactly what is the
problem
you know usually yeah usually when you
have a repetitive strain injury usually
it's hard to pin that pin down so so
this time I have this issue I don't I
don't know what's causing it I I cannot
you know I cannot figure out why
Oh Benjamin is from Scotland so they
have a free universal healthcare or
something like that you can see doctors
for free so green deck says my friend
has palm has pain in left hand what
advice can I give him he's unlikely to
switch layout or something as far as I
know he uses many freaky shortcut tell
him tell him don't do that that's worse
you know switching layout like like
there are two things about layout one is
them what people think of that is later
layout for example warrick corty you
know that's about the arrangement of
letter letter keys okay so when people
talk about layout they are thinking of
that now this is actually less important
than shortcut layout now shortcut layout
in Unix Linux Emacs it's usually called
key binding but on Windows or Photoshop
you call them shortcuts shortcut is also
a layer for example on Photoshop you
have you have control C control ctrl C
to switch to some to control a for the
tool I mean not control a but you know
then control option something to change
other to or things like that in
Photoshop and this is true for video
editing for 3d software like like render
what's a blender for example 3d software
you know a lot computer workers they you
know artists or digital media you know
they work with Photoshop so you have you
know especially in those programs video
editing Photoshop you have lots of you
know keep shortcuts so shortcuts are
actually a layout and same thing in
Emacs you know if you are using
traditional Emacs keybinding it's all
about control something control X
control C control XT you know you know
those shortcuts now if you lock your
keystroke you all know that most
programmers you press shortcuts more
often than you type okay I have a static
statistics you know it's on my website
you know I don't I don't want to go to
link I don't want to go to you know open
that because they know take another two
minutes anyway you know just read my
website just such folks Rd Emacs
keybinding statistics you'll find it
sorry
Emacs keybinding statistics so anyway I
found that you know by statistics and I
learned that for at most programmers the
the the keystrokes you press that are
for shortcuts is actually more than then
you type in letters okay
so therefore shortcut shortcut layout is
actually more important so you know
because you use that more often so you
want to be concerned about shortcut
layout design so all all the articles
here all the articles on this page are
related to shortcut design like watch
what choice you know which key binding
is the best for copy which key binding
is the best for paste you know if you
are using Photoshop you know how do you
design shortcuts for Photoshop you know
so this this page articles about that so
I would recommend you tell your friend
okay you tell you a fan just just by a
keypad
by one of these you know programmable
depending on what he is doing you know
she Photoshop or what whatever I mean
depending on how many keys he need so
you know you you either have 20 keys or
you have like you know 60 keys so tell
him to buy a programmable keypad and
tell him to stop using control something
control odd you know something just
never do that
like I don't do that I haven't been
doing that for like five years for four
or five years you know in emacs with
stuff like this I you know I almost
never I never type you know control
something for example cut paste you know
paste paste and if you look at the left
window it's all single key there's no
for example close this buffer okay so
it's closed
CRO this buffer you know I don't do
control me toss something combo I think
that's it so let's see two more
let me read two more comments as far as
I know they use mini 3d key shockers
yeah tell your friend don't stop doing
that off-topic so George says have you
heard of Symphony OS and really cry not
Symphony OS it's called serenity OS no I
have not I may I don't remember
serenity operating system so do they
have a Wikipedia I guess not yet so
let's go to github and
so serene serenity OS so what is about
about I always wonder what we what it
would be like to ride my own operating
system but I never took it seriously
until now serenity is the love letter
tonight his user interface with the
custom unix-like core it flatters with
sincerity by steaming beautiful idea for
millions of the operating systems ok so
I guess it's a personal project my take
is nah I mean okay here's here's the
thing first of all I let's assume okay
this is a great program okay he's
capable he's one of the best programmer
in the world and he he knows the
operating system well he knows computer
science you know well so he can create
this beautiful most useful and practical
popular system but however it's not
going to fly okay
because in practice you know Mac Windows
Linux that that is dominant you when you
use a computer you need operating system
but you also need lots of applications
that is the main thing I mean as a user
you actually don't care about operating
systems you need a lot huge amount of
applications you need Photoshop and
Microsoft Word you know for business
people you know spreadsheet and the song
in Emacs and these companies they are
not going to port it to your operating
system okay unless you are you know
unless you are cuckoo so this is like
this is the dead end
okay that's my opinion but you know
possibly in 20 years you will be your
main stream it will be fantastic yeah
but I'm not even sure I'll be around in
20 years so for the future it's good
thing but you know so for me I see it
kind it's kind of well it's a hobby you
know so if you enjoy how
you know it's good so that's it for
today thank you guys for watching so
today's topic is all about keyboards and
key binding and layout so if that's very
good thank you guys if you like my stuff
you know do my patreon I have my patreon
link over my pages like most of my pages
at the bottom patreon or Pay Pal if you
like my stuff bye guys