good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of s talk show today we are
going to code emac disp lots of emac
this probably probably an hour 40
minutes or so so this is my keyboard
kesis 360 and this is Ultimate hacking
keyboard and this is Logitech mouse with
spin wheel fantastic it can spin for 20
seconds so I recommend it uh so let's
show my screen and uh let's start
talking about emac this stuff and okay
today's talk show is this page so let's
see can you see it everything is good
good morning everyone say hi uh okay so
s talk
show uh let's say S Talk Show episode
530 showing browser okay first stop
press one key now let me Dem demonstrate
that again so see my see this finger
press one key to close that now I want
to open poers shell or terminal move
finger here can you see it uh okay so
you cannot see the keyboard there uh you
know but anyway press that key there it
is power shell magnify so you can see so
let's put powers shell here so uh right
yeah so let's
Callo CLE Dark theme do it
fantastic you see that's a Powershell
command now okay so Powershell let's go
to Powershell Powell
tutorial uh so you have three sections
how to in depth and power out scripts so
you go to scripts so you can see po
tarle Dark theme click on that that's a
code
copy it and you'll have it let's do it
again
fantastic fantastic Dark theme okay Dark
theme is no good hurts your eyes because
in nature humans you know you see things
in a white background sunlight you know
you don't live in the darkness and see
glowes you know that's what Dark theme
is let me poke a hole into those you you
know this is this computer nerds oh Dark
theme dark theme dark theme is no good
hurts your eyes I used it for like three
months so dark theme and I have an
article on that just search for Dark
theme you'll see the details let's see
if I have a link here so you go to Power
do them and no I don't have a link here
so you should I should have a link so
anyway let's put this here power
tutorial uh talk show today's talk show
yeah we're going to do several things so
let's
begin uh so there is the do theme and po
doc theme and you click on search and
search for
do theme okay so you have CSS Dark theme
that tells you how you know my website
how do I make it dark theme you know so
that's CSS stock theme and uh we did
somewhat talk show about that and then
here article user interface design
window Dark theme problem or
Windows Windows got lots of problems
Windows dark them you can see what's
where you know because they they don't
have borders so every window is becomes
like you don't know which one is a panel
which one is window idiotic extreme
Windows become extreme circuit since
since since Windows uh 10
also uh you know so any anyway so user
interface design window Dark theme
problems let's copy that paste that I'm
going to not I'm not going to I'm not
going to talk about that today today's
EAC LP and here is for your web dev
monkeys you know you want how to use CSS
stock theme media you know
the what's the word the the the the
flexible you know flex and all that you
know the anyway so here is how do you do
that with
CSS and uh okay and some some comments
about issues you need to watch out if
you want to make your blog or your
website Dark theme because there's
there's several issues for example this
image becomes very
ugly background becomes you know
invisible when you have dark them like
that so anyway so copy back here so
paste here make a list combine the list
combine the list showing browser and
there it is three articles and I'm using
emac the Fantastic the most Supreme
powerful
emac and uh I'm using HTML mod I'm using
CA keys and uh okay let me show you
quickly SOA Keys is a key binding system
this is a source code about 4,000 lines
of code go to the top and here is the
URL the homepage so you can uh use it
sof like ke copy the link back to emac
close close and uh let's paste the link
here and uh and I'm using SI HTML mod so
let's
see
okay done here it is the source code
about about 6,000 lines of of code
because there are two other files HTML
engine HTML mod so go to the top and uh
go to uh go to here the link open it sh
browser HTML mod pay me and get it for
15 years everything is free but I was
dying of hunger so now I'm not take your
I'm not your tech support you know when
you put your package on GitHub every
everyone is asking how do you do this
then you create the system so no nobody
pays you open source uh okay s HTML mod
okay let's copy that so let's get back
to emac okay uh yeah wow this are
related to emac topic so HTML mod so you
see my cruiser is here now watch my
screen carefully you see I want to
delete this this list item right so one
single key press you see that key is E
on V keyboard I'm using a vout that key
is e so I press e then it call Smart
delete okay let me Demo a few
more okay let's say I have empty spaces
one single key press remove all those
empty spaces another key press remove
that list item another key press remove
empty space another key press remove
that Ur an order list okay press again
REM remove
empty wi space press again the entire
section is
G okay you see that's a power of you see
so you know smart delete that's part of
SAR flag keys but when you are in
HTML that's part of CA HTML mod so you
can download flag keys for free and uh
if you install HTML mod you'll have
something similar so okay undo undo undo
undo undo undo okay we are back can you
undo more yes okay doesn't matter to
showing browser S Talk Show episode
5:30 so we have our links here okay now
let's see let's get on to what we I need
to do so I'm I'm doing I'm not doing
today's talk show because usually in my
day life I have a lot Works to do
running my website so I need to you know
a lot commands miscellaneous I need to
fix this command or do something in pow
shell or you know things like that okay
so this is what I have to do and
meanwhile I'm just go over it so I can
share it you know like the nice people's
way of saying it I'm going to share it
I'm going to share this tip with you
with you guys and hope you guys find it
useful thank you thank you so
much okay ching ching looks like we got
money Allan Allan is a fantastic great
guy you don't leave in the darkness and
see glories CHR Christ is born glorify
Christ okay thank you Alan so let's see
what what you guys are saying uh any
comments worth reading if you want me to
answer questions related to emx today uh
uh uh uh tag my name
okay
uh uh Luke Smith Lucas Smith says I
remember I think I remember your name I
love your unical explanations kind of
new to emac though just curious how do
you handle code
Snippets like typing a command man to
print a bunch of boiler plates instead
instead of AI pilot oh Snippets uh I use
a brief okay I I did a video a few on
emac a brief okay let me just talk about
that for one minute a brief okay all you
need is a brief the most powerful okay
emac a brief so you have emac this a
brief template for major mod that is
writing a major mod to support templates
you know for example in
HTML uh well I'm not well let's skip
that okay so anyway what you want is
this this article
okay emac a bre mod by Leist code okay
so read this article a believe is the
most powerful thing in emac because
I H okay I okay
let's uh not talk about that today
because we got so many other things to
do so but basically read this article
okay so also I did kind of a video on on
this like two years ago so it's pretty
old so anyway here is
a a Remar by this Cod so after I done
this video I'll upload it you'll see uh
these links
okay so okay let's let's start to code
emac Le so let me show you what a few
things I want to do okay resize image
make the result okay so so for example I
have a image uh let's Okay show in
browser so let's go to the top so you
see this live stream block I don't need
it anymore so press through key and it's
G back to browser refresh you see
fantastic okay first St let's show you
this command HTML resize image
so let's go to a directory and let's
let's get some images okay
so uh Alien wack fantastic this
is I think this is drawn by Allan or
based on some of the mem you know so I
have a image copy the file path you can
see the command in the Ping window so
close it you see ultimate hacking
keyboard the best micro keyboard close
it one single key press you don't want
control meta shift up your
fingers okay so every you know if you
can get a mro key keypad okay uh and uh
so okay so there's a here's the image
path uh I can press a key there are
several ways but I press the key so it
becomes undo redo okay it becomes that
showing browser so you see I got that
that now so that command is you know H
HTML opening browser uh no it's
um that command is uh this s HTML any to
link so that can link a image embed a
image or or Amazon link or other link or
or css link you know there are so many
different type of link for example if
you have a CSS file you don't want to
link it like a normal link but you in
said you want this link reference
stylesheet you know you know so so that
command any link anyway so let me let me
let me concentrate on this today's work
okay so here's the image close it now I
want to make a icon of this image okay
so I press a
key okay it says width how large you
want the icon okay 250 that's a default
yes there it is so you got the file path
here
open it you see a smaller version close
it now press a key to make it HTML to
make a embedded image go to the browser
okay go to the browser refresh there it
is fantastic so it automatically called
a image processing command to shrink it
and so we can open it go to diet which
is the directory so you can see here's
original image and here is the width
width
250 smaller icon okay so open it you can
see I don't know if you can
see uh yeah you can okay so you see so
that is a command so that command we
just called is let's
[Music]
see
uh it it you know there's so many where
is
it there it is HTML resize image you see
that's a command we just did let's do it
again okay open it press the key to
delete that image so that command is s
delete current file make backup okay so
remove that tag as well show in browser
so that is done now let's re redo okay
so press the key width 250 yes there it
is okay so that command is HTML resize
image now I want to modify the image so
that when it's done it doesn't you know
instead of just pasting the file path
but it should make a link like that okay
let's do
that okay so first of all open this
delete it again remove that so now let's
go to the source code of this image of
this command HTML resize image open it
okay so we are in the source code and
again fantastic CH Ching giant money
thank you
Alan okay so so here's a
command uh let's copy it let's make a
new buffer paste it save it uh let's
save it let's see where am I okay copy
okay
so save it X X today's State file name.
okay so here is the command let's see
what we want to do with it yeah we want
to modify it so that um oh God this
command is pretty
long oh my God we already like 15
minutes okay we got several things to
do uh so what what am I going to do so
I'm going to do I like Okay so here's a
command we want to make a
modification so that when it's done it
creates a link okay which is very easy
so basically near the
end so you see it cause image magic to
shrink it
then okay so then you go to tag begin
then insert the file
path okay insert the file
path
okay thank you Reaper fantastic thank
you
Reaper I don't want to hear all your
word descriptions of words words words
you made up all winter man I want to be
enlightened by actions okay so do you
mean the emac this well you are not a
emac user
so what what do you
mean
so we got to do this quickly so we got
because we got a several other commands
to do
so
so okay I don't I can't I can't you know
keep reading the comments because now
there's so many today oh we are busy
today so anyway so here is the command
here is the function that insert the
file
path so after we insert it we need to
make it image link so how do we do that
let me show you
okay so for example here's a image so I
do describe key so this this this is a
command I call S tml image to image tag
okay
so so let me show you okay so here's a
file path open it you see now call Meta
X image HTML image to image tag so you
see so this basically these two lines
are identical so anyway I don't need it
undo so that is a command so uh yeah so
now we back to the
code we just add we call this and let's
see the documentation for this
command uh the documentation is optional
begin with end okay we don't care begin
end with h
begin end with height I learned from
Allan that this English
word height is not pronounced
hate two years ago I always pronounce it
width and height but now it's width and
height stupid English you know
H
hide you know okay okay so so so this is
so here's the syntax so let's see begin
end with uh what are the what are the
arguments okay
so okay I'm going to worry about the
details SL later because in the live
stream you you know you just show you
just show show drama people can see it
works and stuff so okay so that's it now
evaluate the buffer so now emac news
know the new command oh but we we need
to uh version so put today's statee here
and uh remove some of the old dates too
many dates so this is sequence of dates
I modified this command so okay evaluate
the buffer now back to let's see I think
we are done so
now now okay now
watch do it
make a icon version okay 250 width
yes
okay close but wrong okay I know what's
wrong okay
undo uh wait
undo okay so you see it inserted I know
what's wrong so let's fix it first of
all open it delete that delete that
delete that okay now back to the
code
okay back to the code we don't want this
new line okay
so okay insert the file path then make
it a image tag then you insert a new
line okay eval the buffer back to here
now try it
again width 250
yes
fantastic now showing browser
fantastic you see okay job number one
done okay now I don't need this I don't
need this smaller image anymore so
anyway we done this
one we have completed task number
one now task number two let me show you
this one this is also very interesting
by the way all these are HTML mod so if
you want it buy it of course for Alan
and repper if you guys want it you can
get it free Allan is a emac
user repper is VSS
code okay so this one now you know can
can vs code do
that no okay now this one is very
interesting too so you see this now this
image let's try some other image are you
are you guys tired of this image image
let's try another one let's see oh this
is every run okay let's see
oh oh this one is nice this is this nice
okay copy file path close shrink close
Okay paste it here make link show in
browser
beautiful China China stuff China China
girls okay now what we want to do so we
got a file name here here bey bey okay
this Bey b is CH China's YouTube okay
bey bey
multiculturalism oh
fantastic okay so we what we want to do
we want to Reen rename this image okay
so normally what you do is that for
example let me show you you you you you
go to the diet here is a here is a file
you jump to it you can see all my
commands on the pink window so you want
to rename it so in diet so let's magnify
so in diet you call this command now you
can change it let's say let's say add
one
okay okay done okay so you
see here is a new name okay now close it
but
now your you embedded image no longer
works because you see file no exists
because you just changed the name so you
need to change your name here to again
you know open it now you see it so and
refresh you see it's
cumbersome okay it's cumbersome I want
to just press the command press the key
so I can rename it right here then emac
will automatically rename the file and
update the link too so let's do that
okay so let me show you let me demo that
command so D so that command is called s
HTML rename source
file uh here okay
so let's uh okay press press press and
the new name to okay yes okay it's done
so you you know it says old path is this
new path is this a report okay now
showing browser you see it still
works but the
file you see now it's named
uh named two so this allows you to
rename without going to the diet or even
going to like VI users or vs code you
have to go to Powershell or fash or you
have to something something tedious or
you or or worse
was is that you have to go to the you
know the
windows Windows File Manager you know
then you you rename it like that so
tedious okay but okay so but what what
do you do I want to do okay here's what
I want to do this command can rename
okay but it can also change directory
okay so for example I can change it to
I2 you know like you can so it does two
things rename or
move you know like the Unix
idiocy you know in Unix you have the
command MV okay m stand for move one of
the Unix Linux command but it's also
rename because according to these neres
rename and move actually are the same
thing as far as their code Works how how
their code Works rename and move are the
same thing to them that's no good okay
because rename and move are completely
different concepts okay you move is move
something to another location like you
are moving to another country or
something rename is rename okay change
change
identity like change your profile name
you know change your name to a
Batman
Zuma thing they
change anyway
so
so that's one of the thing I want to say
you know Unix idiocy they combine move
and rename into the same thing now in
poers Shell they are named differently
okay in pow shell let me show you so you
have rename item that's one thing okay
then you
have move item that's another command
okay so let me show
you okay so move item you have Adas
shortcut so you can also type Mi or MV
like Unix or move move came from dos
okay and what about rename item okay
rename item
is so you have the shortcut r n or rni
okay they are distinct Concepts in
Powershell proper design okay so that's
just something I want to mention so
let's do a screenshot of
this so we
can have a record in our talk
show
fantastic okay so what I want to do so
what I want to do is I want
to restructure my command so that this
so that this
command HTML rename source file path
will be two different commands Okay one
is rename one is move okay let's do
quickly are you guys still following
well
okay let me read the comments quickly
uh okay so do I have it expanded here so
yeah HTML rename make it two commands
Okay let's do
it okay first of all let's grab the code
copy make a new buffer paste it here
copy the file name save it
XX today's State the command
name. okay so now make a backup okay
show in the Ping window okay so this is
a command and how many lines of
code uh
43 43 lines of code okay so I want to
make it into two commands one is just
rename one is for move so they are
separate you know you might think why
bother you know because why bother you
know it it it it actually make it more
convenient because for example if I
going to rename this
file you see it also shows the directory
path so sometimes you know like
sometimes if I want to rename something
quickly
then then you have to worry about you
know you have to make sure you don't
touch the directory otherwise it went
somewhere else like by mistake you know
maybe you paste it in something then the
file disappeared it went to some
directory so that's
a so that's one thing the other thing is
that when you actually want to move the
file you see let's say I want to move
this file okay so let's see so I can
move it by removing the
directory so you see now now you open it
it's inoo directory it's no longer in
this image directory you see you moved
it to the to the S directory so when you
want to move a file let's say I want to
do it okay uh let's do it so you see
there is no way to do directory
completion so I cannot press tab to know
what you know or go up a directory I
cannot do that but if you actually have
two two separate
commands then it's much easier to do
that okay so let's just um start to code
okay let's quickly let me finish this in
two in two three minutes then let me
read the comments okay so let's uh yeah
so the command so that's one command
uh okay so where is the command so here
rename source so first of all copy all
paste so re so uh rename this to move
okay so one is move and one is rename so
first of all let's go to the
rename so the rename one will just
rename it will not prompt directories
okay uh rename H so let me do it this
command is used for for rename local
image file directory
okay
okay modify the uh documentation a bit
the file name is renamed and the current
link is also updated space comma
apostrophe okay warning if you have
links to the file elsewhere you need to
change them right okay put today's State
and remove that those States okay so
this will be just for
rename
H okay
God okay God there's a lot to do I
think H there's a lot to do uh are you
guys interested seeing me doing this
because I'm thinking of doing this
offline uh let's see okay let me read
the comment for now
so there's a question so do you use
Windows terminal or pow shell both
okay so you install Windows terminal
which which is what I'm using so you can
see uh settings you know so this is
Windows terminal Windows terminal is a
new terminal for Microsoft that came out
about five years ago about
544 so it's a better terminal much
better you know uh one of the primary
reason it's better is because it
supports unic code because you can for
example let's see
uh CD web
[Music]
s
info uh comp okay let's go to the that
directory show uh
and
Cat
Unicode it's show some unical alchemical
alchemical symbols okay so you can see
uh there's no Emoji oh there's some okay
so you can see so this is one of the
primary feature
of the new Microsoft terminal in the old
system which is command
exe you know you can't do that okay you
you you're going to get giberish so
that's I I recommend that okay okay okay
so let's uh let's see what we already
talked for
[Music]
50 40 minutes I think so what else oh
God so you know we actually we got
so uh several other things to go
through oh okay so actually we we for
doing this one
okay yeah several things okay so let's
read the comment because I want to make
the live stream interesting to you guys
not just me
coding okay offline okay I see that so
let's see let me go through the
comments know in
China
uh I think you are losing if you don't
vs code vs code I write emails and you
code for
me
uh
AI Bing AI into notepad
really I hat adds in my voice okay so
talking about files identifying as HTML
changing to
text
what uh let's canonically and
unironically
use SL mod on
Discord do I let's see Discord yes light
mod let there be light yes
indeed uh EU say something something
something okay maybe that's it for today
actually we got several other things emx
any
questions
Kola
offline do you have a favorite fun for
programming oh yeah I'm I'm a I'm
obsessive about
fonts in fact I have like so many videos
live stream of our fonts fonts font
Obsession the mo is the most idiotic
thing okay but but but but but I have my
recommendations
okay just search for font and you have
51 results okay so
um you know and uh you
uh so what's the best font for
programmers this one
okay uh let's just add programmers P
there it is sp unit code found for
programmer so here I I recommend about
three of
them uh actually my best recommendation
for Farm is just stick with whatever
your platform's default okay that is
actually the
best you know so on on Microsoft Windows
you want to stick with
consoler just stick with it okay forget
about your yeah but I like I like this C
I like you know this this that you know
the best the most efficient and the
most PR practical and the the most
elegant and the most
Supreme is on Microsoft Windows is the
Microsoft consolas and if you are on the
Mac it's a Mac OS Apple menow okay and
on Linux that's that's when you need to
D like which one is best that's when you
need to spend 100 hours okay but in
General on Linux stick with Deja Vu okay
deju is the best period you know I
talked about this many times uh but
that's it quy Theory that's right
Alan you know so let let me let me let
me spend another minute on this so what
is my criteria how do I judge which is
the best fund okay the best fund is the
fund besides the the basic issues for
example you need to distinguish all
zero capital O and you know lowercase o
you need to distinguish one the digit
one with L with I capital I you know
besides that that's common you know
everyone needs that b and and and and
every every monop space f does that okay
distinguish that so you it's not even a
concern you know since like 40 30 years
ago but my criteria for the best font is
is that it must contain math
symbols
okay you you C++ Java python crap it
okay I don't care about asky you know
the English you know you know every time
you know Hacker News you'll see
programmers driil about found every day
every three years there's a new font oh
we need to this is the best design this
this got the cing this got the you know
the
the you know the the
um what what's that what's the word they
call the um Bon and and
the what what's the word that's some uh
you know one of
[Music]
the you know basically they combine two
characters like fi okay you know I
talked about this so many times like fi
character they they they need to combine
them idiot idiot but anyway so the my
criteria for the best found is that it
contains the the most numerous useful
symbols may it be mathematics mostly
mathematics and Technical symbols such
as you know mathematics such as logic
symbols uh Pi Infinity for all not and
or exist there exist
implies because therefore and appr proof
empty
Set uh element of a set not element of a
set subset super set and so on
mathematics errors you know then then
you know you need arrrow arrow is the
most important then computer keyboards
option key control key you know up Arrow
enter symbol that that that symbol is
the enter key for the for the numerical
keypad enter okay that's a unic code ESO
esoteria so back delete forward delete
and the Escape that's a escape and eject
sign so I want these symbols okay then
arrows return several versions of return
Tab and then you have uh you know this
this this is on ABM ThinkPad keyboard
they have this symbol for page up and
page down and uh I forgot what they use
it for
so you have print screen clear screen
then you have watch sign and you have
cppo cppo
sign the universal sign but
today they don't use that sign anymore
because they think it's differently
enabled okay they don't use that sign
anymore which is idiotic because you
don't you no longer understand what it
mean you know like for example you know
see now this is called ease access okay
you know now now they have like you know
this symbol instead you can't use a
wheel
wheelchair so anyway undo redo and uh
you know refresh and mail and circle one
two three and
Christianity and Hinduism and uh you
know Israel Stars taii you know
technical symbols and chemistry so I I
want a font that has this included as
part of the F that's almost the one
fundamental idea but the most
programming idiots the Jesus I
always have a problem with them you know
these lenux Fanatics Unix Fanatics
python priests they tell you what to do
they tell you how your code formatting
should be they tell you what's the best
ediom you know the what's the best
pythonic way you know these idiots
when they talk about fonts they they are
very obsessive about fun about font
every year there's like new font I hack
a new in
already you look at them they don't
contain any of these symbols they just
asky 26 characters first about it but
this looks a little thinner that's
better I prefer that one idiots
okay that's that's it I think that's it
for today
coffee anything
else you know my recommendation that's
not a joke okay
actually you know I I don't just
recommend oh you just should use the
default no after careful obsessive
research years after after you know in
the past 10 years I'm obsessed about
font since since 1990s because I read uh
many of the G books about typography you
know in the 1990s that's uh anyway so my
obsessive digging into font and the
conclusion today is that on Microsoft
you just want consola okay on on the Mac
you want meno okay on Linux I
recommend Deja Vu Sans mono okay Deja Vu
is a set of FS so they have monospace
they also have serif and and uh s serif
okay that's basically I recommend and
then you have fancy ones like you know
today you have lots of fancy ones like
the Julia mono they try to combine uh
symbols so that a character is it's it's
like this you know what's uh what's
what is this uh word I must know it now
okay let me think
about conning so um so what what what
they call it you know the combining two
two characters combining two characters
basically into one single
GL
uh
what's what's the word can't
remember it
now uh you guys must have ligature
that's right hang thank you
hang ju is the master master of making
Kar
memes
lature the most idiotic Western
lature and it turns out in the surprise
surprisingly or maybe not
surprisingly all the all the
Unix Fanatics this geek this
programming had they are obsessed about
that lature the most idiotic on
Earth lature
okay uh okay so that's it for today so
uh but you know for for example let me
show you an article about
lature okay so in Unicode you actually
have characters that's called lature
okay but actually you know here's a
funny thing here is a rarely known
information you will you you will not
see on other YouTubers those got 1
million followers okay let me tell you
this Unicode has lature okay you only
get this from
Kar Kar talk show okay Unicode has
lature you see these are characters okay
let let me show you a example a lure
character Okay so so um there it is okay
let's copy
that uh where's
the so let's magnify it more so let's
let's just copy that okay so let me show
you okay so here okay so you see this is
one single character okay so what is the
name of this character describe function
so you can see search for name Latin
small lature fi that's the name of the
character okay and the you know here's a
code point you know
okay so this is a
lature it's a single character in unic
code
okay however in unic
code this character by the Unicode
specification is not required to be
combined like a traditional
ligature okay
so so in this case uh what font am I
using it happens to be
combined
uh console as regular okay
so let's try to let's try to see it
somewhere else okay so let's paste it oh
there it is okay so you can
see you you you can see over here this
single one character can you see that
there is not
combined although by Unix you know but
but this is a unical lature character
but but in here I I'm not sure which
font it is using it's not
combined so
the intuitively you think that's wrong
you know somebody May created the wrong
font for it because this character is
called lature so therefore it must be
you know you must when you design a font
for this character it must be like lure
combined but actually that's not true
okay that's not true you know the UN
unicor lure character does not require
them to be combined okay uh did I
explain here so ironically the dicated
FI Latin small lature fi is less of a
lature in some fonts then ask key fi
okay so meaning that even if you type fi
in ask key it's um
okay well in here because I'm using
monop space so let's see if I can switch
to yeah so there it is so now I'm using
a serif font okay not mono space so this
the first one is a lure is one single
character the second one is two
character s you see so but you can see
they are not combined you can you see
magnify you see it's not combined into
one
character okay
so and according to spec that is correct
I mean there's nothing wrong to it okay
it is not required to be stylistically
merged fi okay just just b f and I in a
single graph for legacy support so
that's a
interesting information about this
lature okay I think that's it for
today so one question about my emac
theme yes all you have to do is just K
search okay uh
theme okay type theme emac how to create
your own theme emac set color themes how
to emac how to set a theme depending on
mod emac theme Gallery okay so I have
1,000 articles on themes so or you guys
instead of just asking random you can
just search sad. info
okay so here is uh best Unicode found uh
how to create your own theme and uh
Emax how do you set a
theme how how to set a theme in emx and
here is how to set the theme depending
on mod which actually you cannot do it
uh and this article theme Gallery okay
so you have you know this is a color
themes is a melen James theme okay I'm
not into it I don't want themes I don't
want themes nothing okay I don't want
any color themes okay I just want the
simplest default is fine except I set
the background color Okay I I I'm not
into themes so anyway here's our themes
okay in fact I despise
themes okay that's it for today's talk
show and uh thank you so much
Alan for the donation big money Alan
also actually you know Allan donated
$1,000 before uh and thank you Raper and
I think that's it for
today final do does anyone do you have
your final
[Music]
words any final words we shut down in
two minutes okay close close close so
let me just make it
uh okay so we are about done showing
browser fantastic today's talk is
multiculturalism lovely
China and the stuff and the
stuff okay we shut down in 1
minute uh and I'm just going to code
offline oh if you want them HTML mod of
course you pay me and get it
okay uh and
stuff you know Microsoft Windows sucks
very much you know
so maybe in my next change you know it's
painful to change because you have to
switch your machine you have to go over
your setup you know when you switch
operating system uh I don't want you
know I don't like Windows of course uh
but however I do have a apple apple is
the best apple is the best
thing
okay bye
guys