hello guys good morning good morning
welcome to another episode of s talk
show we are going to code wolam language
today uh yeah so if you are here say hi
love to see your comments if you are not
here play at 1.5 speed and Skip around
because I ramble all over if you do not
skip around you'll just hear me ramble
rambling okay so wolam language coding
today so um let's begin
so yeah my keyboards glove 0 ultimate
hacking keyboard n trackable and then
there is SW board okay s v a l b o a r d
s v a l b o a r d I have a video review
on YouTube on each one of them ultimate
hacking keyboard in the
middle okay so I'm using V keyboard
layout and I'm using Sly Keys okay uh
here's a source code Sly Keys the most
efficient key binding system for emac so
you can watch a video introduction okay
more efficient than
Vim okay so let's start to
code wam language
uh the pink window shows all my command
Calles and key strokes for example I
move up previous line move down next
line move forward by word move backward
by word or go here delete delete a tag
undo you can see and the keystroke on
the left V keyboard layout close Okay so
open that copy close paste a link make a
link make a list showing browser today's
S Talk Show so I want let's do
Mathematica so if you don't know already
watch my past videos I have 100 videos
on wfam language just search for Wam
language you can download it okay so
there's a lot introduction I did in the
past uh today we just going to do
continue updating
my visual dictionary of special plan
curves Okay so last time we walked on
Parabola uh last week so let's see what
I need to do
[Music]
um hello e
EU hi sprinkle
night sprinkled nights High take bra
Jupiter are you
married yes do you how do you think
about the emac release 30 1 is that
released
yet uh let's
see so hello based science based science
has been following me on my Twitter but
I don't know who you are you a non
guys uh without knowing who you are you
know so it's hard to uh really actually
know you guys so emac blog go to emac
tutorial go to tables of contents go to
practical emac tutorial go to start at
download okay let's go to G let's see
emac 30 oh emac 30 is
released I'm going to install it today
later
fantastic yeah this is uh good exciting
news yeah I'm going to install it so go
back copy the URL back to
emac uh and what is this close emac
block talk show yes paste link there
fantastic thank
you so emac 30 and then it's going to be
few days of work or one week of work on
digging in what's new and uh then update
my website my emx tutorial uh update my
packages things like that so so it's
great so now let's go back to wam
language let's see Parabola
okay uh let's see I want to
do there is something
okay go to the page go to the top
search. MB
uh make a backup
open wolam language notebook wolam
language the most advanced programming
language by a
magnitude I get donation from them
okay uh so last time we've been uh
working on this this is 30 years old uh
so my goal is to delete all these and
update them and uh put down put the code
on my website like this so because time
changed you know this is 30 years ago
today you know usually you don't like
download stuff and you know you just
like go back
web uh okay so there is some you see
this so many interesting properties this
one for example is not on my
website uh this is showing the tangent
properties we did did last week
also
live okay and and there's that one very
interesting
uh you see this this uh type set in wam
language you know one one of the just
for this
feature you you should get wam language
just for this feature because you don't
have to you
see
because for example
uh okay I'm digressing for example you
you know you paste that paste again
control shift control shift I okay so
normally your source code looks like
that in any normal programming
language right your source code looks
like that but now you press a key
control shift in it automatically became
math mathematically typ set
and you can they
reformat on the Fly you see
how how the expression reformat on the
fly so you don't have to worry about
indentation you know this like
programmer programmer idiots the
cc++
Java rust these idiots for the past 30
years this feature has been in wufan
language since 1996 six version
three okay so let's go back so that's
that's a little little digression let's
go back uh what I want to do yeah so
that image that's about the optical
properties um I also need to update
that and uh this animation I
did there it is we did it last week
um evolute of Parabola so this evolutes
uh let's
see
search okay let's update let's just
update this uh this this one okay make a
backup close that search for evolute
Okay so there it is that correspond to
this section so uh so you can see this
is a image from 30 years
ago go to the directory four kilobytes
you know
tiny uh so let's update this one okay
so
copy
cut paste it here we're going to work on
this
one
copy copy so we're going to put the code
here W from language code paste it uh
and pop it out so we can code in
emac uh this is I'm using San mod search
for the web you'll find it it's free on
GI hook wolan
mod okay mod there so go to the source
code it's 3,000 lines of code go to the
website open it showing browser there
and uh it's on GitHub
okay so uh close that so we want to work
this work on this okay so let me go to I
need to some packages planker plot copy
that okay so
evolute okay Parabola so so we going to
um this is the formula we want we don't
want so formula is
that and
uh and the new name is plank C plot not
par plot okay actually I want to
make you see this par plot U okay let
let me just show you a few things
okay okay parametric plot is a building
function so you can plot that
by uh let me show you so remove that
remove that remove that remove that
okay so this is building okay so let's
draw
that uh AIS okay okay so you see that's
a result now a is true shift enter you
see that's what the curve looks like but
what we want to do is we want to draw
the
normals to the parabola so what is a
normal to a curve so given a curve any
curve pick any one point on a curve you
got the
tangent you know so tangent is the close
is fitting
line you know you you know
tangent I should not need to explain
because it's the simplest
concept so given a curve like that so if
if this point P there is a tangent so
the tangent would be um yeah
undo the tangent would be a line like
that so the tangent is a line that's
closest to a to the point to the given
point okay so if you want to say what is
a tangent here P that would be a line
like that okay so a tangent here would
be a line like that okay so that's a
tangent the most fundamental idea in
calculus now what is a normal normal the
normal of a
given point on a curve is a line that's
perpendicular to the tangent so so this
is a normal okay at that point and over
here what it's got confused
uh so over here it's like that so over
here it's like that so tangent is the
normal is the
line that is perpendicular to the
tangent okay so give a parabola like
that so close
that
save so you see here's a parabola and
all those lines are tangent now instead
of drawing the tangent you draw the
normal then you got these red lines you
see so once you have a bunch of lines
you can see they form a new curve you
see this this bunch of lines they kind
of form a new curve and this new curve
happens to be semic cubic Parabola okay
that's another curve that's that's this
one uh very interest interesting so it
looks like a v-shaped curve
okay uh and the formula is T3 power and
T2 power you know
that's semi cubic
Parabola all these are historical curves
they have many properties that
discovered by
mathematicians uh same you know so
anyway let's go back so normal okay so
you draw all the normals so our goal is
just to uh programming Graphics computer
Graphics we want to draw these lines by
default you cannot do that because wam
language doesn't you know so I wrote a
package
package now this package 30 years ago is
called parlot but how however I rename
it I renamed it to be to be called PL
curve plot so that's more um sensible
people can understand oh PL curve plot
you know before it was named parlot like
kind of a shorter name for par for
enhanced parametric
plot but I think now it's better to have
a adus so that it became Backward
Compatible okay so let's try to do that
so we go to the package directory plan
curve plot so here's the source
code moam language source code 700 lines
go to the directory so here is the
directory get remove the backup delete
yes okay uh now open the package again
now let's make an Adas okay so what we
do is
just uh plank plot uh and
uh par plot so par plot we just equals
to how do I type a equal there
so that's how you define an alias in wam
language uh basically wam language is a
term rewriting system symbolic turn re
writing system so this symbolic makes it
different from the pattern matching in
hascal in F in okam or even in link
proof system I started to learn that so
so this is how you basically so this
symbolic term re writing system which is
different
from like link or
FSH so anyway so once you declare you
know you you create this areas you also
need to kind of go to the top and
declare the symbol okay so let me do
that
uh because this is within a package so
that means you have to be concerned
about uh name
space okay so let's go okay begin PR
there okay
so clear PL cve plot and uh let's
[Music]
see okay copy
that par PL
usage same as pler plot okay
so that's a inline documentation I think
it will
work I think that's
it so make a backup and save it and copy
to copy to the wolam applications in it
directory okay so that's done I have a
emac command to do
that so all I have to do is make some
update then press a key it automatically
copy that file to that directory okay so
so now it's
done okay now close that now go back to
our code
here so we can
say we need to so we will running this
now we need to use the enhanced version
so this one okay so let's delete
that uh delete that okay I think that's
it remove
that uh
okay that's what you
need paste it please make it work shift
enter one shot coding no trial any eror
because I know what I'm
doing beautiful is that beautiful what
do you guys think so now copy
it okay
fantastic delete that and
uh d that okay put a code back
and and okay and and showing browser
okay then go down go down go down go
down go down you need to go to the
evolute
part there is the code okay now
uh syntax
C refresh beautiful you see Power plot
now
works now you need to get the image okay
this this image we just
did so now go to the talk
show showing browser yeah so go here go
here move the image here showing browser
fantastic that's what we were
explaining the tangent and normals okay
this is a so bad a drawing let's delete
it I don't want
it delete remove show refresh okay now
go back to
Parabola move the screenshot
here close that
refresh
beautiful okay so beautiful so this old
curve this old
one open it delete
it and remove the Tex and here's
annotation
cut Put The annotation here Parabola and
it's
normals okay
uh uh wait
so so let's this a new rename it I can
rename directly in
HTML okay so
yeah lower case okay now you see this
old annotation we need to refresh it so
rename I mean relink you refresh so prob
and it's normals okay so let's see go
back here refresh fantastic we've done
our
job
today the evolute of a parabola is the
semic cubic Parabola okay evolute is the
curve formed by these normal lines the
red lines so you got this v-shaped
thing okay remove this redundant
sentence
just
okay that's I think maybe that's it for
today you know make it short one Topic
at a time any comments I'll answer so we
talked
about uh we only talked about less than
30 minutes so
let's see
comments the new completion preview mod
is very cool okay that's emac 30 I'll
try that that's going to be a lot of
interesting things uh I'm going to be
busy I'm I'm going to be so busy because
I do a lot I need to do a lot um
it is the you know link proof system
that's what I really want to know let's
you know maybe talk about
it so this is my list of to-do like
usually they pile up like hundreds and
then thousands you
know like to do math emx wam language
Javas script python goand CSS Microsoft
Windows Powershell to read to watch
videos uh review like my articles old
articles I have to like now they are you
know I've been writing blogs for 30
years so you have to review especially
Tech blogs and to-do keyboard unic code
you know and research you know so lots
of Tod do and uh one of the
thing so I've been starting to learn
link programming language I talked about
it in the past few videos so link
programming language is a proof system
so it actually do mathematical proofs
which is a new field kind of kind of new
uh era okay uh in
fact this is the future of
mathematics because
traditionally Ma you know you got
mathematicians to do proofs
um manually so by human but now we got
super super computers why can't we use
computers to help us that is a goal you
know the ideal is since computers can be
can do calculation why don't we just let
the computer run and and uh and find all
the new theories like we don't need
Einstein anymore we don't need
Einstein's you know relativity or
whatever you know new you know we got
the super computers the computer just
Chun out new theories that never seen
before and today also with the AI you
know AI Bots neural networks artificial
intelligence machine
learning so but turns out it turns out
it's it's a problem you can't do that
first of all you So eventually over the
past 100 years we learned
oh yeah you know let's just use the
computer prove everything oh but we got
problems you know we got so many
problems the the logic system doesn't
work if you use that logic system you
got that problem if you fix that problem
then you got that problem so you see
step by step just like the history of AI
we learned a lot of things and today we
don't have we still don't have any you
know like automatic proof systems at
all but we but we learned a lot it's
like all the past efforts is not is not
waste is not uh is good we are learning
things just like machine learning and
artificial intelligence we are learning
we learned for example in artificial
intelligence that
writing
poetry is actually not intelligent you
know like today's AI Bots they can write
poetries like
10,000 fairly okay poems in a
second so we learned
that you know like before we were
thinking oh writing poetry that must be
you got to be a human because it
requires emotion it requires the emotion
to understand you know the feelings of
humanity but not
really the machine can CH out thousand
10,000 poems but do the AI BS you know
do they actually understand a thing no
you know as if you have used AI Bots you
know they just still they are not
intelligent at
all so anyway let's go back to math okay
so proof you know logic Foundation we
learned so many things so you you know
you got set theory then you got type
Theory type Theory turns out is a way to
go for computers so we
got so that's a lot progress okay
uh so I'm learning link okay that's what
I want to learn because when you learn a
link programming you know I there are
several of them you know I I have old
articles you know but anyway there are
several uh proof systems they are
so-called proof
assistants uh they are actually also
programming
languages so link is one of the newer
modern one starting about 10 years ago
okay I decided I'm going to start to
learn link okay uh okay so let me talk
about so you go to my math
blog so you can
search so there is category
Theory okay uh I you know my notes is
not good so but I want to uh
so the one of the latest math Foundation
is this homotopy type Theory which is
meant basically to
replace set theory which is the the
mainstream foundation for mathematics
for the past few hundred years okay set
theory but set theory as we learned in
the past 00 years set theory turns out
you can't use it on a computer it's hard
to work with so you need homotopy type
Theory okay which
is part type theory part of the homotopy
theory which is Advanced topology very
very Advanced you know but it it it's
it's it's like quite amazing that these
two connects anyway that's another
another history Okay so
so H homotopy type Theory and that's not
the only one so right now you know there
are several approaches you know we are
the
mathematicians uh
um you know the computational
mathematicians are trying to uh explore
so one of the popular you know so anyway
I'm learning so link programming
language okay so it is good because you
can read this book homotopy type theory
is free you know it's a PDF you know I
have some notes here um you know there's
a PDF you can download you can read it
okay but reading only gets you so far
reading is
actually That's a classic way to learn
things but now with the programming
languages it's much better if you
actually hands on
learn the link programming language
because if if your code doesn't work
then you understand nothing okay when
you read a book type Theory or category
Theory you think you understand but
nobody can check you but if you try to
write a code the computer will tell you
you are a idiot you know you you think
you know you actually don't know because
your code needs to work you know so so
I'm very excited because this this is
different from reading this you know
type Theory textbooks because you
actually have
to get your understanding provable by
computer okay that's a digression that's
it for today okay so
um first time catching me doing wolam
language okay uh I'm not using used to
knowing about math in English and I'm
far from knowing this math okay that's
uh yeah well this is basic calculus this
is kind of basic calculus so uh you see
most programmers you know they don't
know nothing about math except except in
the past 10 years because in the past 10
years or 15 years starting around
2010 you started to have this situation
of Big Data you know like 10 years ago
it was a jargon uh Big Data you know one
Tetra pet Petra pet you know Google you
know they're talking about big data and
then machine learning oh you know it's a
new it's actually a new era it's it's a
new chapter in human history okay it's a
new chapter in human history so you got
machine learning you got big data you
got then you got SOC called On The Rise
the dat data science you know now I'm a
data
scientist then then you got neural
networks then you got all of a sudden
two years ago you got the chat GPT
that's kind of like that's a turning
point in human history okay chat
GPT by the way there are a lot idiotic
rumors and you know like like oh we
going to have AGI you know like whenever
people talk
about AGI or arcial general intelligence
or you know or or the BS taking over
ignore it okay they are totally idiots
whenever you hear someone on Twitter you
know some of some of them are actually
like professionals like working at AI
companies but when they talk about how
AI is going to rule the world or Rob
jobs or the the ethics of AI you like
basically any of those topics they don't
know they are just bullshitting you okay
they they are grifting you know it
depends like some of them genuinely
believe you know they have opinions but
is
just that's my opinion okay I'm telling
you my opinion so whenever you hear
someone AI this or that AI you know this
all crap like total crap
okay the question about what what what
will the a future of AI become will it
become sentient will it become actually
like General int nobody knows okay
nobody knows if someone claims they I
know you know this going to happen next
year in five years we're GNA you know
this like this Sam Oldman a
criminal he's a extreme bad person okay
this is my op
opinion they are all scams
okay
so we were talking about what so what
um yeah so that's
uh so this the things so yeah I was
going to say so these
things
are basically calculus okay kind of
basic calculus okay in you if you are
you know calculus if you are a math
major undergraduate calculus so you and
you need to know this okay you see like
today you have types you know people
talk about crypto uh
cryptocurrency bit money uh they talk
about uh blockchain uh machine learning
neuron networks uh uh AI you
know uh you know to know all that you
need to know this okay this is like this
is not drama but but the this drama
things you actually in order to do all
those things especially rocket science
like elements is doing you need to know
all of these okay you see so I was
saying programmers in the past they
don't know math you know because
programming the typical programming
programming Linux kernel operating
system
programming
uh it's web da you know most programming
they not they got nothing to do with
math okay a little a little you know
like discret mathematics okay uh and
then in game programming you also this
little mathematics except the game
engine when you're talking about
computer graphics 3D Graphics that's
linear algebra and only linear algebra
you only need to know like like 5% of
linear algebra like matrix
multiplication projection you know so in
general
programming is separate from mathematics
mathematics okay uh but um but but not
in the past 10 years so because of the
AI so in the past 10 years the this big
data machine learning That's Heavy
mathematics okay the neural networks
that's a lot of
these heavy mathematics and also
crypto analysis you see cryptocurrency
okay
swab board okay I don't know yet so
sorry about that it's long
delay ebonic for Uncle you know why is
that people like kept saying
ebonics you know that like I I have on
my Twitter someone asked me about do you
know ebonics like that's that's just I
don't like that term you know just like
just just say black English just like
black American English what the is
ionics and the Ben who are you driving
now uh you already know who is that I
can't type but I'm
listening uh what's up Uncle I don't
know who you are
okay uh okay that's it for today thank
you guys for watching uh if you like my
stuff pay me okay. info go all the way
to the bottom pay me Amazon gift card
click the link use this copy paste this
email address pay me 100 bucks or PayPal
okay pay
uh the real deal of free trade that will
get get you a prosperous Society you
know like free trade you like my
stuff you pay
me bye