hello guys good morning welcome to
another episode of EX talk show we are
going to code wfam language Advent of
code 2024 day five this is take two so
last time about a week or two ago we I
did it but didn't but it turns out my
algorithm is incorrect so sound talk
show 2024
uh you know Advent of code 2024 day five
last time my algorithm for sorting is
incorrect so let's do it again you know
time goes fast now it's
17th now I'm 10 you know 10 problems
late but anyway let's do it okay Advent
of code day uh 2024 day five so let's
start coding okay so let's just begin
coding I'm using wam language and and uh
and uhan mod okay so what is the problem
okay so let's just start coding V code
day five uh we got a problem here if you
are here say hi love to see your comment
hello Dan
V uh if you are watching offline skip
around and play at speed two speed 1.5
or2 okay and here is all the commands of
my emac
core okay and this window got to move
here so
that okay
so okay so day five what what what was
the problem day five day five is given a
list of pairs like that each line
specify an order so the the the first
element comes before the second element
so at least a PIR they specify on order
then you got a list of lines each line
you want to determine if the line is
already ordered according to this list
okay according to the list of pairs you
want to know if it's already ordered
then what you want to do if
um let's see
so when they are ordered so if the line
is already ordered then you want to take
the middle number the middle of the
list okay and then you want to add them
up okay so that is a problem
so um let's do uh from scratch okay so
last time I did the problem here uh
let's see mini problem generate the
Leist correct answer part two to
actually that's not
correct okay
so we got to do this again okay so let's
just copy
it paste okay uh okay
so uh code logic is wrong okay so anyway
so we got the input the total input like
that then we got um then input is read
string um read string is yeah so this is
my personal input okay we don't want use
that yet uh then you got the pairs and
lines okay so Pairs and lines okay then
you want to turn you you pass the text
so they
become then you assign to pairs pair is
a list of pairs of numbers okay and
lines is just a a list of list each list
is a list of numbers
okay so if that is correct then you can
just say um let's just make sure that
um that is what we got okay can we run
it no okay so you need to uh print or
intermediate
Expressions yeah it's still new so so
you actually so you got to say so what I
want to do is I want to see Pairs and
lines to see if we uh actually pass it
correctly okay so you got that tab
a okay so here is the result uh so let's
see the pairs looks like that sounds
good and the lines looks like that
sound good sounds good
yeah okay
uh okay so we got the pairs and we got
the lines okay this of pairs and this of
lines then what we want to do is you got
list of pairs so you want to determine
if the each line is already ordered so
so you want to first turn these
pairs list of pairs into uh kind of
ordering specification so you can right
away know which number comes before
which number given any random two number
you see this list of payers they they
they kind of chain up to form order okay
so you got the list of orders so what
what so you know there are many ways to
do this and what I want to do is what I
want to
do uh is to
create let's hold on a second let's
see okay this is incorrect
what what I want to do is to build a
list of numbers of all elements in the
pairs list okay build the list of
ordered sequence such that items are
from all the pairs and all elements in
proper order okay that's what I want to
do so I call this variable order the
sequence uh let's let's stop this
um Can Can
we
uh okay seven people watching okay so so
uh what's going
on what
there is
some window issue okay
so
um okay so we we we want to build this
old sequence okay so how so how do you
do that so
uh I worked on it a little bit last time
so I know what to do now so um yeah so
you first of all take all the numbers
here x pairs okay uh what you want to do
is you take the pairs such that you
flatten
it so they became just a flat list okay
then you want to say delete
duplicate is that right yeah
[Music]
delete
duplicate okay delete duplicate and uh
then flat and pairs okay so that will
get
you let me show you in wam language here
so you got the code here uh so let's
let's evaluate it so you see 47 53
so yeah that's basically that's the um
let's check 47 you know that's the
numbers here all the all the possible
numbers yeah
okay so let's
say you numbers okay so that that's
basically the set of the
universe and uh then what you want to do
is you want to
uh order this list okay using this these
pairs
uh okay
uh yeah how do you do that well last
time we did it with this this thing but
uh the algorithm is
incorrect because oh yeah we I remember
what's going on because we need to
actually repeat it okay so it's a
slightly complicated so let's see what I
want to do so you you go through each
pair you go through each pair
numbers and uh you know then you
check you know
basically if the two numbers are in the
wrong order in your list then you swap
them okay you go through this this each
pair if the numbers in your list is
incorrect you swap them okay after you
done you repeat this
until there's no two numbers that's in
incorrect order okay okay so let's see
let's let's let's uh
let's um uh
what where are
we unique numbers
okay uh this should be called Universe
set let's say unique numbers because
that's more concrete okay
so go through each pair
if they are in the wrong order
in in unique number
list swap their position
okay do this again
until none are in wrong order okay so
let's do that so go through each pair
okay
so map map is a very standard way to go
through each pair so what we want to go
through is
you know map a function to these unique
numbers okay and what is the function
the function will actually wait actually
we need to go through the pairs okay not
not okay so
actually you need to map to
the pairs okay now you want to map a
function to the pairs of course so what
the function do it will do something
with the unique pairs
so what the function will do is
uh let's say given one pair
um let's say this function takes two
numbers okay A and
B A A and BB that's suppose that's two
items in a pair that's an argument so
the function takes two arguments a a BB
okay now what does the function Do It
[Music]
um okay
so you know basically you want to swap
the items um but okay I now we run into
efficiency
issue
um hello
Diego hey new to our lives uh thank you
welcome uh this is probably boring
that's why that's why I stopped you
know ideally it would be nice if I
quickly solve the problem in 30 minutes
so people get a nice nice understanding
of the problem how do you use roof
language to solve it but in
[Music]
reality you you often Stuck in the
Middle for five minutes or
10 uh and uh yeah
so I feel bad every time that happens
but anyway so the the function takes two
arguments okay
so so that's you know takes two argument
and here's a function function and what
the function what do you want to do you
want to see if the two numbers
given in the unique numbers list if they
are in the right order so yeah how do
you do that
well you
know what you can easily do is that you
check um you know but that's very
inefficient so uh
uh for example let's just do the simple
way okay
remember Q
um remember Q returns true if the item
is in it yeah we know it's always always
in it so we want the position so uh to
get the position you use First Position
what what you can do is use um this
function first
position uh it will take a list
okay and an expression so for example
this will return the position the index
of a A in the list okay and you do the
same for BB and all you have to do is
you
check you know check if if
if that is less less or equals to um
that yeah but this
is this is not efficient because you
every time you do first position you are
basically searching through a list then
you search it again not efficient well
so what we can do is this
[Music]
um so we uh we can do
positions okay this will return so
position so what you do is uh like this
okay so give a list numbers and you want
to know the position of both AA and BB
in one shot yeah so both AA and BB in
one shot so
um so let's magnify this so you can
see give the list of position say Which
object matching pattern appears in
expression yes that's what we
want uh what is the default level
spec uh okay we need to change this to
one yeah so it's so it doesn't search
Nest at least so you want here is a
pattern and here is you just want what
means depth one only so you don't dive
into sub list because wolam language the
wolam every wam expression is nested
just like lisp so this position will not
just search a flat
list but it will search any list down to
any nested element so by default it's
every element you know you can see from
zero to
Infinity you don't want that because
because all you got is a flat list um
you know these unique numbers uh can we
show can we get the unique numbers here
yeah so let's copy that
copy this is a example of the unique
numbers okay
so so our list is flat anyway so this
this last parameter shouldn't matter but
let's just put one okay so the pattern
will be apparently a a uh
o so what is the O BB so I believe
that's what will do so let's try Okay so
let's try one
two 2 three 4 five that's a least and uh
this is let's say
405 and we can run this
line you know so that returns 4 five
that's correct both of them so you see
the pattern matches here okay so that's
a toy example uh kind of the toy example
there
showing how position works okay
um you know so so let's go back to our
problem here so you want uh from this
this and that okay so you given that
then you want to
see uh they return nested list okay so
you want to see
uh uh
uh you can flatten it okay
[Music]
so
flatten of this thing so then you got a
list of two numbers then you want to see
if they are
ordered
uh let's check
so all the returns either zero one or
negative one so you can see if they are
in order it returns one if they are in
not in order it returns negative one
otherwise if they are equal equal uh
returns zero
okay so that's what the order does so
for example order 3
three it returns zero see so for example
order the uh
34 evolve the current
line it returns one okay so that's
another toy example let's put the toy
examples there um
okay so so now back to our problem we we
flatten this okay then you just want to
apply ordered to it you know apply this
order function okay so let's do
that um you know we can uh in fact
actually we want that that okay so that
just means okay well that's a shortcut
for
let me explain what what this does okay
so whenever you have some symbol FF add
some some something okay this syntax is
a is exactly the
same
as it's just a shortcut it's exactly the
as um
yeah okay it's exactly the same as that
uh because you know we can actually try
it evaluate the
line that returns true so you know this
this is just syntactical shortcut so you
can just say
old then that okay and that will
zero or one or negative 1 so when it's
one or zero that means they are already
in order so if this thing is negative
one then you need to swap them oh
God you know so so much tedious
coding
uh so if it's zero then um
yeah you can do
that so for example if statement
if if the argument is
zero uh if it's negative one that means
you need to swap
it otherwise do
nothing so what how do you swap it well
to swap it you can just
say this process is enjoyable too uh
it's more realistic than having all
perfectly planned yeah thank
you uh yeah um okay yeah but it takes
long
time uh yeah
okay so so
um so we so we got uh hello Dam dam sick
so we we
um okay so so let's push on let's stick
with this algorithm okay I mean usually
I find it lots of tedious coding and I
don't want to do that but let's stick
with one algorithm that you know that
kind of the things I learned during live
stream you know once you have algorithm
stick with it don't like try to make it
more efficient because then you go into
other
holes okay let's stick with this so if
it's negative one you want to swap the
elements how do you
swap so
um what is the efficient way to swap to
El
well you can just say you know something
like this okay something like uh plus
one equals
to
um BB right wait so
position plus a
a equals to BB something like that and
position of the BB equals
to uh AA that's how you
swap uh oh actually it's better let me
show you a better way
okay that's how you swap two elements
let's
see yeah position AA position BB and
swap it okay so that's how you
get yeah but this is not functional
programming so once you swap you have to
return that then in fact you have to
assign you have to assign this to a new
you know something like assign that
to
uh okay let's think about functional way
so so basically you given a list given a
list you do you you determine you find a
condition to determine whether you want
to swap it swap two elements
okay and uh you want to
return a result of the new list
okay
so so let's let's look at um so you
know so that's our function here okay
basically
um you know this we don't want
so basically
if this
thing okay is negative one then
then swap it then just return that
okay otherwise no no means do
nothing yeah that will do
it are you sure yes I'm pretty sure for
example let's try
okay so what is our unique numbers Let's
uh let's try do we have it yeah here
here okay for example let's try it
um uh where is it yeah so let's put the
so so here's our function so now let's
try the function on real data okay so
here is the real
data
um well I
mean so the AA and BB needs to be a a
pair so for example let's pick one that
um for example
7553 uh let's look at you know we want
to pick one that needs to be
swapped
53 comes before
75 wait 75 should come before 53 okay so
75 and 53 is a good pair because that
needs to be swapped
okay copy that go back down
here uh go back down here so this AB is
actually that okay I mean that
you
7553 right yeah
okay
uh okay so back here and
uh so this function okay so here is a
function so this
function this will work I'm pretty sure
so yeah but um okay so let's let's you
know let's try it out
unique number equals to that then I want
to make this a pure function though I
don't want it to rely on a variable but
anyway so this function takes two
arguments and the argument is a pair
here and uh then the A and BB are the
inputs um so um
yeah but you don't know where what is
the position X and Y okay
so so you actually this more complicated
thing you have to do
so
uh you know
so you need to assign variables you know
position a a and BB okay let's do
it this is a tedious tedious things I'm
trying to
avoid but now you need let's do this
first okay so you need two local
variables that is a position so module
is how you do local variable module is
like JavaScript let or lisps let or
hascar
let so so here's your variables local
variables two two of them then then you
just inside then you just
um then you just yeah put this if
statement inside that's what you want to
do okay so the function two local
variables and uh what the what is the
value of the local variables well the
values
are you assign them okay so
yeah so the
value there okay so that's how you get
the two local
variables they position uh is that right
A or B
wait okay this is not good
[Music]
because uh because it may turn so you
don't know which order they actually
came that's a
problem uh okay another
problem because you are using a pattern
A or B so you don't know what exactly
which one it found
first okay let's look at
position position can you take a
list no
you see the problem is let me try to
explain the problem is when you use
position you see let's say now let's say
four and five are in different order
okay now if if you evaluate it the
result is going to be the same as that
wait yeah you see it you know because
they tell you the things you want which
is 405 occurs in two positions position
four and position
five but in both case it doesn't tell
you which one is which so that's not
good
so so instead we can you know we want to
map the position map each number to map
the position you know
yeah you want to map the position to the
pairs
um well that means it's more slow um you
know so our code is becoming bigger and
bigger I don't want that you know
because the whole thing can be do can be
done in a functional way uh more
easy uh what
so yeah so there is that issue so that's
not good um okay so
now let's go back here so now what you
going to do
[Music]
well you can go back to the the
inefficient
way
yeah okay let's let's just code that
okay remember don't first about
efficiency and stuff just get it
done okay so position um let's just do
this position AA equals to just AA okay
no first about in fact since now we just
you can you can just say first position
okay uh because we know it only occur
once we
you know this this is simple okay so
first position because we know the item
only occur once so once you found it
stop
searching that's what you know this does
First Position expression pattern okay
so so so um expression and pattern so
this is expression and pattern and we
don't need uh that
uh okay it also takes a level spec what
is the default level
spec okay defa level spec again is zero
to Infinity that means onest it your
search go through or nesting so we don't
want hesting so we need to say one but
then you need uh this intermediate
default uh default is no okay it
shouldn't happen because we know the
pirs any item in the pirs always exist
in these unique
numbers okay so what what what does the
default return return
um I'm curious Now
default Oh by default it returns missing
no found okay I don't care but I do want
the level spec okay
and no no inam language is just like
like uh like
nothing yeah absence of expression or
result okay so so that is what we want
then we don't need this anymore that
gives you the position of a and then
yeah then you
just okay okay BB and
that okay so now it become the code
becomes simpler okay to read uh and in
fact do you want flatten
so let's see uh we don't want no so
let's check some
examples uh it returns a list okay so it
always returns a list
right so this this first position always
return a
list so in fact you can uh
first so that makes it a number you
don't want the Leist okay so so that is
done you got a position then this part
so so then you can just now just say
order position
AA position
BB okay if that is equals to negative 1
if so that means you need to
swap
then then what is efficient way to swap
you see we can do this but however this
is not
functional uh because then um well then
you just return numbers
yeah I mean you just return that thing
it should work though so let's not worry
about efficiency and functional style
let's just get this to work for now uh
module so there it is that's our
function so if we evaluate
this this we should get a new list such
that such that the 75 and 53 is swapped
okay you see so we we so we evaluate
this do
it uh invalid syntax in or before 4 73
okay we got a problem oh this needs to
be moved here because otherwise
yeah do
it beautiful did you see that it worked
one shot coding No
Nonsense you see here's the result 75
and 50 3 has been swapped so this is
like a you know toy example so we don't
need the previous
um no more so here is a total example of
sorting
um example
of swapping a
list swapping two items in a list of
coding to a given pair okay so that's so
he you know so this block of code is
just another toy
example okay we solve that um what what
what's the next step we can move on or
we can try to refine this so that it's
more functional and more
efficient uh let's move on you know the
problem with not concern about
efficiency
or functional style of coding is that is
that basically once you get the
answer you you are not interested in
like fixing it you know change the style
anymore because you just done it you
know yeah so so anyway so this works
anyway but that's not you know this is
not uh efficient okay so let me think
about it a little bit and let's see
what's the next
step uh this about ordering issue okay
so okay
so wam language let's go to my wam
Language tutorial let's go to um
list uh because there's a lot functions
that works on ordering stuff
ordering is part of the order Theory I
mean there's a whole uh kind of entire
branch of mathematics about ordering
Theory so wolam language has a lot
function that deal deals uh deals with
order so let's see this operation sort
reverse order okay so you got older by
so let me think you know so we need
so right now we
need we need to create this old
list via a list of
pairs so once we so now we have this
function what we need to do is we need
to apply this function let's give this
function a name swap to items
okay um
equal equal okay
so this is f f means a function okay
this function swap two items given a
pair so swap pair so swap
pair actually better name is reorder
pair okay so this function will reorder
a
pair um and now what you want to do is
you want to apply
this okay let's push on uh so you want
to apply this map reorder pair
to um to all pairs okay okay
uh wait not here okay X pairs you want
to map this to all pairs that's
right uh in fact you want to use map
thread
instead because if you use map that
means your function takes one argument
but your function our function takes two
argument A and B so what you can do is
you just say map
thread with the same function but
here you transpose the pairs so you got
instead of a list of
lists a least of two lists now you
transpose so you it's still a list of
two list but instead of each list being
a pair now it's a a list of all the
first part then a list of all the second
part that's what the transpose payers to
okay then uh you don't care about that
so you so that's what you want okay so
you want do that so let's we can
actually do that okay so map thread and
let's see what it returns okay
so let's combine okay so so let's
evaluate so make a backup EV evaluate
this
region uh map thread okay something
error least expected okay something uh
something something something oh okay so
we don't want that there so here is a
function
yeah
function this is a function okay then
you can test the function on that thing
then okay so then you map this function
to that okay so delete that delete that
yeah let's try
again this region of code okay evaluate
it uh map thread some still problem okay
so
uh still some
problem okay let's see what is the
problem
so let's just evaluate
this okay we got we got this new
um this
okay
[Music]
actually
let's modify this reorder pair so
that so that instead of taking two
arguments you'll just take a single
argument of the pair as a
least you see right now it's taking two
arguments
yeah okay
so okay let's let's let's work on this
okay so let's create a new section let's
work on
this so this will be just
pair and uh let's just say well pair
okay uh let's just say xx and uh here
you will
be uh yeah so then we want to so then we
add more variables a a and BB okay two
more variables and a a and BB will
[Music]
be a a BB equals to
XX you see uh let's rename
uh okay so the function takes one
argument a pair in fact you don't need
that so it takes a pair then the then we
declare local some local variables then
the first thing we do is assign the pair
a name the first element a a the second
part is BB okay then you got you know
then you got your AA and BB um
yeah okay so let's just um yeah so
that so yeah so now we can try for
example we apply this function to this
pair okay and actually we need um we
need this this thing okay
so there there there there there there
there evaluate the region let's see what
we get
finished this is
incorrect what do you mean
finished oh oh wait if uh
what oh okay you change the
variable too much changing of of
variables you made a mistake you forgot
to do that okay so this function if it's
in order return that if it's not in
order you just return that list itself
you need to do that
okay yeah okay so so you do this
again evaluate the
region there it is
so is 75 and 53
[Music]
reversed no it is
not now which is
incorrect for variety let's try it here
53 no the the okay so it's not
right God what is going
on DS says I can officially
say uh that I've Master sof flag Keys
now fantastic using
corac fan key binding layout fantastic
so great because
it has so many features other of other
packages yes started adding my key
binding under S command map fantastic
thank you uh that's Sly Keys that's uh
efficient key binding system for emac
you can get it on GitHub okay so back to
this problem this is
wrong 75 should come before 53
however the result uh
evaluation is this okay and
uh and this is just not
right
God you know the coding is just tedious
little problems what's going
on did we you know we just try to
change something but uh then you
got oh
oh God we just need to change we
you know we are not done yet and it's
already 1
hour how did these people you know this
Advent of code finish in 2
minutes okay concentrate okay so you got
so this is a pair that's right because
you know the yeah so you
know
you a list of two items is the argument
okay then the first thing you do is you
assign
them a pair right did we yeah so you got
you know you assign them to the pair
then the oh God this variable you like I
try to rename variable I forgot
something too again you know that's my
bad okay so now try again it should work
okay so eval the region
75 comes first that's right so we got
this result
fantastic okay finally our code is
good okay and now we can remove the
previous toy code okay so we can just
remove uh
remove okay so
there okay so now this
function we reorder a p here now
actually we don't want now we can you
know we no longer want map
thread um we want to actually Nest it
reduce okay so reduce in wolam language
is called fold
okay uh let me show you okay so wait
fold uh what takes two arguments okay
the
first part is reorder okay reorder the
pairs
then you got
um you want to F to this list of pairs
beginning with the first pair okay so
yeah so I think that's it that's that
that so let's look up forward
documentation uh yeah okay so you see
there in Python in in JavaScript this is
called
reduce uh in some language it's called
fold in some others it's called reduce
so why you want fold instead of map
because every time you swap two items
you want that to be the new input
okay so you fold it so so after this
fold you should get a older least okay
that's what we want okay so let's let's
now evaluate this
part make a backup
and now evaluate this
region okay something wrong
okay nonatomic nonatomic expression
expected okay
so
nonatomic
expression okay you got something let's
see what the
this is how you debug wolam
language
so you know so it's not
very uh intuitive
because wam language works by term
rewriting so if you code lisp you
understand it's like every function in
wolam language is doing a mark a list
Mark okay that's how wam language does
computation so imagine in thisp emag
lisp or common lisp every single one of
your function is written using list
Mark that is essenti ually the hard of
wolam language that's what we are doing
so so um so so unlike typical procedural
languages using values your
error it's going to be quite
different so it's saying that fold
normal so it's this error is about fold
and the message is about normal it's
something about normal the fold function
normal okay nonatomic expression
expected so nonatomic so basically it
want it doesn't want a number it or a
symbol it want a list or something so in
this expression fold function that you
got a nonatomic you know
so usually when you see some error
language you just look at your code and
you know re-exam your code then you can
find what's a problem instead of like
dive deep into trying to understand what
the message error message is saying so
anyway
so so we it got the list of numbers and
this fold pair takes a pair
right take oh oh we are oh the pair is
undefined that's why okay you gotta you
got to Define your pairs
okay there is our our pairs
okay that's why of course it's not
working that's why of course non Atomic
expression expected because your pairs
is not defined so let's define the pairs
here uh because we are making a
standalone example you see so here is a
numbers here's a pairs
okay okay and
then this function actually requires
that and that okay then what you do is
then you fold there it is let's try
again eval the
region okay uh see wrong
okay wait is that the pairs yeah that's
that's the pairs
[Music]
so so why am I
getting oh
okay set shape list and that are not the
same
oh so somewhere I set it in
correctly oh okay so now if you going to
fold yeah this function takes one single
argument but when you use fold it
requires function that takes two
arguments that's
right uh okay oh God what what a pen
what the pen you know because I was
thinking you know using wolam language
it will blast through the typical
algorithms you would do in python or C++
or
Java but now it's like one hour already
and we got this this like this this ugly
fairly ugly
code and uh still not going anywhere
yet H God so we need to modify this
function again oh God
so the function right now takes a pair
okay but you want it to use fold
right if you want you to use fold you
need the function to return I mean to
take two
arguments that's right okay so okay I
got it so the function it is
incorrect I mean it's it's it's it's
rather a design flow for this function
only to take one pair as argument
because this function actually depends
on this least unique numbers so this
function what it should do a proper
design is actually it should take a
pair and a list okay so let's say x list
so let's re rename these unique numbers
by X
list to avoid confusion with
um to avoid confusion with the you know
the global constant okay so now the
function takes a pair and the
least okay yeah yeah yeah yeah yeah and
that should work yeah yes I think so so
save it and
uh and actually we don't we don't need
we don't want
that so let's work on our section so
here okay now evaluate the
region oh God still wrong what the wait
right let's double check okay so a and
the
Leist uh this
part what what is the what is the
problem normal no Atomic expression
expected at position one in first oh so
you got a
n okay so somewhere here this part is
returning
[Music]
new
why first position of
AA in X list
non Atomic expression expected it so
this part it returns SN so something is
wrong did did
we let's try oh yeah I think I forgot to
select
that uh no God
hello you are coding well drones of
unknown orines are flying over your head
that's correct drones of unknown
Orin yeah you know the news the
certain subset of white Americans
Obsession about UFO you know like like
so ridiculous you know it's it's it's
part of the American
culture um I don't know since when you
know since at least since 1990s when I
you know when I live
here but actually it may go back to
1980s or maybe 1970
you know there's certain like Obsession
about UFO and
aliens and I thought about why is that
you know but not you know typically not
the black people not Asian Americans not
American Indians you know
not black Americans not you know but
typically this white
American okay they they are not you know
a subset of of them like the Alex Jones
Alex Jones scammer and The Joe Rogan
monkey you know when you watch Joe Rogan
he's got UFO like Joe Rogan Joe Rogan
take what a idiot you know so
this certain subset of white Americans
they have like Obsession about UFO
aliens oh my God alien I I got abducted
by alien they um so I thought you know
you think about why is that
I think the answer is basically life is
too
good life is too good you know you T you
got tired of pizza got tired of
Starbucks you got tired of your trucks
four-wheel drive you know you need
something like you know you need
entertainment you got tired of movies
you
know slash and burn you know big giant
screen yeah yeah but you got tired of
that too you need some something
novel aliens UFO oh my God we got
invaded by aliens that is something
novel they insert the tube into your
ass that's a
idiots certain subset of white
Americans uh okay so back to
this code
this okay so what is uh problem what are
we doing God I'm getting
distracted okay we already coded for one
hour maybe we should
stop
yeah yeah maybe I should stop because
let me continue a little bit okay maybe
finish this Sub sub problem you know so
because I'm just you know I think it's
best just to have fun
that's you know because in before I try
to finish
it turns out 2 hours or 3 hours
sometimes you know you
know uh one time I did five hours and
it's still not
finished but it became painful and not
fun anymore
so you know this so you know just do one
hour coding if you I finish it it's
great try the best I can if not then we
do it another time so let me continue a
little bit a little bit more to close up
on
this on this sub problem okay you know I
haven't even begin to make this
efficient you know because that's really
what I want to do that's really
my let's
say the value okay if you are watching
my show
it's not it's not about typical
programming because you you can you know
a lot of people can do this in in in
procedural way in Java in JavaScript you
know there's tons of answers out there
using python or JavaScript or Java or
C++ or rust or
lisp right but if you look at their
algorithm if you look at their solution
they are pretty much all the same all
the same because all all of the
programming languages are different but
they are if you look at the algorithm of
how they do things basically just came
down to like pretty much pretty much all
the same okay not exactly but pretty
much all the same way because why is
that because most of the you know they
are
procedural based
um languages okay
even including functional
ones
but what I'm doing you know in wam
language it can be different because
it's a term rewriting systems and you
got you know you got
7,000 building functions to do things so
I
think you know when I'm doing my stuff
the interesting part the value is about
how do you do it in in a in a different
way in you know WM language or purely
functional
style and right now I'm not you see this
assignment this assignment and this um I
mean this well you can I mean it's kind
of functional but it's
not let's say it's not the Ed Matic
wolam language way there are better ways
and more
efficient and moreover what I want to do
for this
ordering I'm pretty sure you know I know
for sure there's there is certain you
know we haven't even looked into so
there's a lot functions that do sort um
and also tell you the ordering of least
I'm pretty sure there's like one single
line or two um uh that will return you
know given given this list of items
numbers and the list of pairs there is a
solution in one line or two
basically and that will reorder this
this list okay I'm pretty sure of that
and uh and it will be very
efficient now in wfam language sometimes
the most shortest and elegant is not
efficient
so efficiency and elegance of the code
is kind of very
separate uh and I think that's true in
general in any language efficiency and
elegance of code
is fairly separate
issue but in wolam language I'm pretty
certain you know you can get solve this
problem in one or two lines and uh also
being
efficient but the trick is just you have
to look into that you know you can't
like just start code you know and have a
solution you if you want you know the
most efficient and elegant you actually
have to look into uh that and haven't
done so so but let me think
about yeah
so so you know so you don't have to
like you know have these tedious Parts
you know assign assign the pairs to each
element then find the position of the
first part find the position of the
second element then try to see if they
are in order if not swap them if
yes you know this is like this is like
typical
coding but that's but but I'm thinking
just one single line you know single
line using this kind of ordering
function
so one single line W and just figure it
out for you anyway enough rambling but
okay so let me try five more minutes to
finish this okay
so okay so you got the numbers you got
the pairs but why is it the complain so
this function takes a this function
takes two arguments a pair and a list
okay and returns a new list list right
yeah it returns a new list and uh as far
as this assignment
um so anyway so it returns a new list
okay so let's not touch it for now and
uh then but it's not working why is it
not working because I don't know so
let's try this again run it
okay too many parameters uh what too
many
parameters oh yeah so you got uh you got
remember it takes two
arguments yeah so the second argument
is that okay yeah that's right so let's
run it
again let's just combine them so but
it okay
so wrong okay so we still got something
wrong in the part assignment is not a
symbol okay
so you mean
here did we get
uh
okay so you need actually
run
it what the what the part assignment is
not a
symbol so if they are ordered then
if this equals to1 then print
that uh it did print that so
7553 is in position 75 is in position
six
okay for
okay so now what is this set so this
step is
incorrect uh can you actually do
that yeah maybe I
got so let's try a list okay so here's a
list 1 2 3 4
five okay then let's say position three
and
two equals
to two and three okay let's evaluate
that let's see what happens yeah that is
what is
wrong so what you can do is let's
see do that
32 okay let's not mess with this single
line okay so let's actually make these
two lines okay so instead one line so we
just say that
okay these two lines instead of that
make it simpler okay so that swap then
just um let's try it
again
what um least
what what you can do this
right so if you have a list one two
three okay so if list position one you
can select to B right evaluate
it no
what ah this is so s basic I got this
wrong it only works if that's a variable
I
think let's try Okay so so list x equals
1 2 3 then X = to BB then you return XX
okay run
that that works but if the XX if you
have XX is the list directly then that
won't
work yeah but we do have a least um
what's going
on
so what
okay so let's
uh this okay so let's go to wam language
sort and uh let's go to
list this operations okay so I want to
know about assigning elements to a
list about swapping
elements okay create list get parts of
list add element change element in list
okay replace part yeah I should use
that yeah actually this is what I should
yeah okay I should use replace part so
replace part is a better way a
functional
way okay so for example replace
part uh wait
that means replace first part by 99 run
it that's that works okay so you know
these
two pretty much does the same but the
first one doesn't work if the you know
if it's not a variable this this this
this first
part the syntax and semantics is not
functional this is a procedural thing so
we want the replace part okay so let's
do
that so instead of doing that you just
say replace part of X list replace
position
a
by element BB and can you have a yeah
you can have a Leist okay
so so we give a list okay then
position B by a a okay
that this line is better than
those but but these two lines should
still work I don't know why is it not
working because is it because the
parameter cannot change I think it
should it can
uh maybe not let's let's do another mini
code that's just for fun to find out
okay so now you have a function let's
say input is X let's say x equals to uh
three and evaluate this
function at four okay now if you are
allowed to change the argument then this
will return three because assignment
returns three if you are not allowed to
change the argument this will return
error just like the error we got okay
run
it now error so you
cannot assign when you have a function
like that you canot assign a value to
the
function's parameter name okay okay
that's wam language I forgot about that
so that is why this this assignment this
returns a error you know it returns a
error something like
um something like set row cannot assign
to a row object okay but now we fixed it
close that don't do that and remove this
debug information so that's what we want
and it's also cleaner you don't need
this you know you don't do aign and the
V return value you just this is a
functional way okay so that's good so
now can we R run the whole thing this
block yes we can run
it fantastic now can we run um now let's
let's cut this okay now this is some
explanation stuff let's put it let's put
it at top
okay that's another interesting
thing okay but now let's go back to our
code the fold
okay run
it okay new Arrow God
Jesus no why why is it no oh that's why
why
if it's not found first position why is
it not found because you see this this
list of
numbers by
Design each element in this pair is
always there so why is
that it says this returns nor
what so let's again debug okay
[Music]
debug run
it a and BB are okay each time you get a
pair right so what is the problem
A and B first normal okay it's 47 and 53
47 is there 53 okay let's print uh a and
BB are that and this
is okay run
it go to the top and BB is that least is
that 75
53 uh 75 wait
what let's not run that
okay okay but anyway oh here is what's
wrong list is
13 oh wait uh what
let's not full let's do this run
it that works what if you try a
different
pair okay this
is getting too long 97 and
13 97 and 13
97 and and 13 so they should not
change 47 and 53 47 53 not change okay
so let's use
that
uh 47 53 no change that's correct what
about
um what about next
pair
copy OBS Studio problem
God so
9761 9761
also no change
okay and uh
but so when you run the function one
time it
works but when you
run when you fold somehow it's not
working okay A and B are that list is 97
so this list is
wrong so why is this L
fold did
[Music]
we this is 97 and 13
so the list is wrong this becomes one
single
number and where argument order is
incorrect to
fold
wait that's right argument order is
incorrect
so I should have used fold left no I
should use fold right yeah stupid so
let's change our argument order okay so
the function is simple error
okay the
here list and the pair right yeah that's
right if you change it let's see
oh
wait yeah we miss yeah the the problem
is that we are using this uh fold
incorrectly another very
basic error
uh okay before we do that let's put this
back okay the we we are using this fold
incorrectly so let's think again the
function
takes pair and the Leist
okay so the problem is something like
this okay so this all correct and here
here you need in add a new
thing okay so you need
yeah for
there okay I think
that's
it uh
okay so wait
uh list okay so actually so this should
go in
front then a pair goes in second okay so
uh all these are incorrect
order that is better okay and here is
just that uh this whole this okay and
that R
it beautiful H this this so you know we
spend an
hour fixing like trivial problems syntax
error you know the wrong Arguments for
fold and stuff like that okay but here
is
the the result for that okay so
according to so we kind of finish this
little problem we have this indeep
independent standard alone block of code
so we given this list of numbers then
this
pairs then with uh this this this will
reorder them and to create a complete
list
of um ordered sequence would be like
that okay so let me show you so that so
that will return
that okay so that is how we create a you
know like complete list this in contrast
to the
original 47
4753 okay okay that's it for today thank
you guys for watching uh I guess one
people or two bye
guys so we kind of so today we didn't
make much progress to Advent of code
uh
2024 day
five but we just made partial progress
on a sub
problem yeah okay but it's still good so
you know still good let's put the code
back syntax CCT showing browser that's
what we
have
okay okay bye guys
okay we shutting down in 1
minute that's uh that's 100
minutes functional programming
by you know it's interesting about
functional programming because I love
functional programming but
you know sometimes you wonder what what
good does it do when you use functional
programming you know wam language and uh
all these this Advanced exotic stuff
what does it do for you when you can
actually code this in the most simple
basic way using
python you know when you use Python this
would
be if you know you would have to type
much
more but you would have finished the
problem earlier is that true I don't
think that's true actually in
general
the but however when you use procedural
programming you basically just do it in
one way you don't think about so many
different ways so
anyway bye guys