good morning guys
welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh today is October
today's November 3rd Sunday 2019 5 o
clock p.m. San Francisco time and today
we are going to do some Emacs Emacs Lisp
coding and we are going to do some
powershell demo on the Mac PowerShell is
becoming powerful and very popular good
morning
wait you don't have a name good morning
nameless hello oh hello beautiful people
hello beautiful people so aren't you in
Germany good morning Thomas well hello
beautiful people aren't you in Germany
so some right now it's like let's see
what Oh what time is it
Theo o'clock 2 o'clock in the morning
yeah is it 2 o'clock in the morning I
mean yeah Czech Republic so that's 4
o'clock in the morning right like type
your time so we are going to do some
Emacs demonstration and are you guys
using Emacs hello beautiful people and
Thomas War Thomas walk away from UK ok
Thomas Lowe is from UK it's 4 o'clock in
the morning at 2 o clock in the morning
thank you guys for coming by so we're
gonna do some Emacs demonstration you
guys using Emacs right so we're gonna do
let's see we're gonna just do eMac be
smart effects our new page to add the
title okay that's a Mac based coding
then Emacs set default mod for new
buffer to HTML ok that's we're gonna do
show my tutorial then
exchange keybinding on sale look up web
we're gonna do that and that we're gonna
do Emacs workflow create a new page
we're gonna do that okay Emacs yeah so
let's do some Emacs topics for maybe
half an hour then let's do a PowerShell
demonstration on the Mac you see I have
you can see I mean footage here clear
screen
what clear screen Kay okay so you can
see PW Sh
Mr Mac and I'm starting PowerShell you
can do LS you can do LS al well you can
ho you can actually they wait they
modified it so anyway this is this is
running PowerShell and it's very
interesting so let's begin with Emacs ok
Emacs that's I want to start with this
topic first set default mod for new
buffer so do you guys how to know how to
do that so for example I want to create
a new buffer right so I know I'm in a
new buffer now a new buffer there is a
default mode for me I said it tooks
Artech text mod so for example now I do
describe variable then I type major mod
enter then Emacs tell me that the value
of major mod is not X mod so that means
when I open a new buffer the buffer is
in the major mod is Kassar techsmartt
and you can say that yourself to any mod
you want to eMac be smart to python mod
you know as your new buffer so how do
you do that
let's go to my Emacs tutorial
I don't remember offhand so you'd go to
Emacs tutorial you go to in it setup you
go to set file to open a major mod now
Emacs has quite a few has like too
two or three mechanisms that determines
which mod to set when you open a file so
you can read this page if you want but
I'm just going to do what I want to do
so let hold on a second so let me paste
that here okay now back to browser let's
see okay vs what is V s so awesome
so I want to create a new buffer I want
to make it the default mod to be two
because our HTML mod so let's see how do
you do that
Auto list so this is how you set a mod
depending on the filename extension you
for example if you want to open if you
open any dot JS file you want to open in
JavaScript to J's to mod then you add
this line to your unit file and let's
see but that's not what we want we want
any new buffer to being a specific mod
how come I don't mention it
okay set fire to opening a new mod so
that's not there so let's go to my Emacs
init file so go to settings this is my
email settings let's search for mod
let's such folks are Tex mod so such XR
text mod then we will see the code
search for all AL files
okay hon why is this becoming more
complicated when I try to explain it
oh there it is
so there it is I should so you see this
line so you see this line it says set in
it major mod so that is the variable you
want to set so the value of that
variable is any is a major mod name or
command so that when you have a new
buffer it will be said to that mod so I
was using salt X mod let's change it to
some HTML mod okay and before we do that
we want to do this on a second okay I
actually let's remove this line requires
a X mod so I want to load context mod
but but I want to go to such for so here
I'm loading my KHTML mod require XHTML
mod then then I want to set any new
buffer to because our HTML mod okay so
that is what I want to do so now before
we run that let's try to open a new mod
new buffer okay open a new buffer then
describe variable type in major mod
enter then you say start X mod that's
not what we want okay now close the
buffer now evaluate this code so I call
eval last six now it's done now I'm
going to await not not that line this
line okay so evil ass sex that's done
now I open a new buffer it will be such
TMI oh ma let's try it so new buffer
you see you can see the mud line it says
summation X on HTML so it's actually
already working but let's double check
the way you check the proper technical
way you check which major mod you are in
is by calling described variable on the
name major mod so let's try describe
variable type in major mod Enter so it
says major mod is a variable defined in
something something then it's value is
some HTML mod you see so now we did that
that's perfect
so why do I want HTML mod because
typically usually I you know I you know
I do things in text mode but now in the
past few years I find that by default
it's just more convenient to work in
HTML mod because I'm writing HTML all
the time
so for example I can I can start to
embed let's say go back to actual page
go to today's talk show let's say
showing browser you see there's an image
so for example I want this image PNG so
so here is an image so I copy this
actually I want to extract the URL now I
got the full path of this URL in
clipboard now I go to the new buffer I
paste it you can you can see we got the
full path and I can you know I can do
quite a few things for example I can
make it right now it's you see it's a
local file it's in use excel web you
know bah-bah-bah I can make it a URL so
I have command to do that for example
now it becomes a URL you see now it's
sorry dot info then I can copy it I can
you know I can go here for example I can
paste it and for other people to look at
it so if you click that you see you see
the image
okay close that so that's why I want my
default mod to be HTML mod for now you
know you know it's Emacs is always
exploration and experiment you know
after week if I don't like it I can
change it back
you know just modify my in it that's the
kind of the beauty of Emacs I suppose in
many other editors you can do that as
well but anyway so that is so that is
one topic finished about Sethi format
okay so so yeah so that that is one
topics 84 ma let's modern let's change
that to here then okay that's the first
topic we covered now now by the way if
you are looking at this this this image
this is someone crazy okay they wrote a
snake came in in browsers HTML
Javascript debugger basically are not
debugger but in the you know inspector
basically the IDE so in browser today
browser is so complex that you have you
know because browser
you know uses JavaScript and you have
this whole bunch of JavaScript framework
like react react web pack angular boo
and a bunch of others so JavaScript so
browser actually be so browser actually
has become the IDE of JavaScript and I
would claim that the browser's IDE today
is actually more complex to implement
it's actually quite more complex than
even a full-fledged C++ IDE okay I'm
telling you that so big
browser I don't know if you can you know
if you code front-end then you know what
I'm saying because you have you have
lots of issues you have the HTML element
which is you know the this nested fool
parsing stuff then you have the
JavaScript console then you have the
sources source for HTML for JavaScript
or CSS for you know cash to sources
things like that very complex then you
have the network when you want to debug
you know your website speed you see
those are in real time so we can see
right now YouTube let me stop the video
ok you can see right now you know even
the video is stopped its loading stuff
it's like lots of things going on and
you can check the performance tab that's
another thing you have to reload the
page to actually see the graph then you
have the memory you know the memory
profile profilers things like that then
you have the application I'm not sure I
haven't I've never seen this application
before actually so it might be new you
know so they are changing every day like
they are changing frequently then you
have security then you have ordered so
today you know writing JavaScript you
know JavaScript is a most popular
language I'm on the top 5 JavaScript
Python PHP C++ Java basically these are
the top 5 most popular languages so Java
is everywhere you know it's written it's
it's everywhere and and the browser has
embedded with it an IDE for Java Script
essentially and in fact I would say you
don't even need any JavaScript editors
you could I think some people do that
but I have never heard of it though but
but you could write everything in with
the browser but besides that even if you
don't the browser is essential I mean
the the debugging the whole bunch of to
was in
I would claim that this browser
JavaScript console this and the HTML
inspector the whole thing is actually
more complex than the full-fledged
C++ IDE I would claim okay yeah the
full-fledged IDE commercial otherwise I
would say it's more complex than them
does anyone do you guys agree that with
that so let's go on to the next Emacs
topic or unless you guys have any
comments questions ok type it now
so Thomas you know Windows IDE so hello
beautiful people I'm also working in
IntelliJ IntelliJ IDEA
IntelliJ IntelliJ I heard is great I
mean the company makes really great text
editors for programmers they really do
and it yeah but it's commercial so
Microsoft SQL sometimes sometimes studio
oh so that's what you use okay hello
beautiful people so you don't
so hello beautiful people nope 2:00 in
the morning Czech Republic is next to
Germany ok same time so hello beautiful
people so you don't use Emacs how you do
use Emacs okay and Thomas is using
Windows IDE how Visual Studio ok and
okay Thomas Royds Visual Studio fan
Thomas John asifa's sir Thomas is doing
sleep c-sharp I guess when you work with
c-sharp
you know the Microsoft specific
technology more or less you know
microsoft technology then you basically
stick with Visual Studio I guess by the
way you do you have to pay for Visual
Studio I know there's a like you know
free version yeah there's a free version
so it's in all jobs in c-sharp c-sharp
is also pretty popular
you know like immediately after C
prosperous so I would say the top top
six most popular languages so Thomas
Ward never got into vim or Emacs so
that's interesting so how did you find
me - Thomas war because usually my
followers are the you know open-source
or Emacs in Linux phonetics I I think of
Emacs Heidi but default key bindings
rubbish webstorm is popular JavaScript
IDE yes I'm not sure if you have files
from chrome dev tools there are some
online JavaScript editor you can I am
finish you you can save files in in in
in in chrome dev tools yes you can I'm
pretty sure of that I'm not going to
show you how good actually
oh maybe I got confused because I know
in Firefox you can I've done I've done
it but anyway I don't know the this
JavaScript dev tools that way also occur
you know I'm not going to do demos of
that
okay you don't remember how you cry most
first my phone homepage okay so let's
get on to the next Emacs topic okay well
if Thomas if you are not using Emacs
maybe we can change topic what Emacs
themes are you using the one with the
mean quick background so that that is a
frequently asked question what you know
what theme I'm using so I'm going to
show you and you are going to be
surprised you just go to my Emacs blog
and you go to practical Emacs then you
go to the things color themes everyone
loves that that's one of the most
popular page on my Emacs website so you
you go to themes search for theme in
search for color okay actually search
for theme why is every time I want to
find something cannot find it search for
theme okay so so anyway so you go to in
it setup then then you search for theme
there it is set color theme so this this
page shows you how to set a max themes
for me I don't do things I don't like
themes I want my editor to be as simple
as possible my opinion is that when it
comes to user interface the most ugly
the better so I don't use any themes so
all I do if you view this page you can
see what I do okay so wait do I talk
about here so this is about how do you
set up themes how do you load themes and
oh I do is this one this code set
background color honey true so I
actually I can show you okay so so let
me show you
okay let's copy that
okay let's just open this open the new
buffer and set go - sorry max lease mod
magnify and we're gonna set background
color
nobody is it background color okay wait
okay so the the name is set background
color yeah so you do that no set Q so
you do that let's say pink okay now I'm
gonna evaluate this buffer I mean
evaluate this code so I do it
you see it's pink then I can say C over
then that's silver basically that's how
I do this is he so the the color I use
is honey - so you just put this line in
your unit file then you get what I have
very simple it's just one line so I
don't want it to be black I don't want
it to be white you know so white is -
you know everything is white so that's
that's what I do you know I would go a
step further by using some kind of more
darker thing
I mean darker background but but then
you have to change all your text colors
then it basically becomes a thing you
have to you know use a thing I don't I
don't like use you know I could use it
it's no big deal you either way but you
know I don't go for I don't go extra
miles to you know do the color stuff you
know I I want it just purely functional
is if it's good it's good
I I want to avoid as much code as
possible so I don't want the entire
complexity of color things you know a
set of themes then you have different
color for different things you
everything is like changed so by the way
so if you want to use honeydew you can
use it or you can call list color
display so this color display that will
show you all the colors so for example
so here is all the colors and the name
if available the left column is the name
the right column is the hexadecimal code
so I want so for example I could use any
of these let's see we want to pick a
color for each one let's see let's say
we'd one is actually two wheat one let's
try it close it close it go back here
tweet one
okay so we'd won let's see what happens
okay so actually that's that's that's
two let's go back to honey true so
that's how I do with color themes okay
so let's copy that go back to San talk
show and paste it here yeah I already
did
hello beautiful people oh my god
thank you so much for the super chat
check one dot one hundred dollars so how
much is that in USD hello doc the new
lang close haven't seen you for a while
and Danielle you contributed to my exact
flight keys I'm going to you know I'm
going because I started to want to add
some changes so I'm going to you know
read and accept your pool requests soon
okay you know my keys is very much alive
you know don't don't think it's like
it's bad it's very much alive it's I
just I just haven't touched it for a
long time so thank you very much for for
for hello beautiful people $400 check so
let's see what's the next question
so actually so we're gonna do Emacs or
powershell let's see what topic I'm not
sure if I can save files from come to
hex ah good morning eyes are more rad
waving from Isom dude what's the deal
with those concentration camps in China
okay that's that's another topic we can
talk about next day not today because
today we're gonna focus on technical
stuff I like to separate them because
you know political stuff it's you know
that's different thing you know people
some people may just want to focus on
technical stuff so I don't remember how
I can okay so hi what's hi what see max
team are you using okay yeah answer dad
asked me Williams
Thomas law says but I have an
interesting programming language design
so it might have being one of your
articles on this subject
okay what about floating window showing
keystroke on the Left it's the same
thing so it's just you know background
color
honey true it's it's across all frames
you know Emacs
frame so just windows so this are you
asking what is it so that is that is
basically your mod you can download let
me show you so on a second let me let me
show you saw start command log mod ok so
I have written a command I have written
this command that start up this this
window this command log this window
shows all Emacs commands I call for
example I press a key it says keyboard
quit you know I I move my cursor up you
can see it says previous line next line
forward backward or delete context block
and do you see all my Emacs command Co
you can see on the Left panel and if you
there's something you find interesting
usually they're on my website so all you
have to do is you select you know search
for that command name so anyway how do
you get this I talked about this a few
times there is a mod which is this mod
command log mod it's on mail path okay
so you I open it open it it's this is a
source code
it's began by Free Software Foundation
it began by this guy Michael Weber and
right now it's maintained by Nick Faria
Nick farrier is a well known you know in
the Emacs community so anyway this is
this is on Mel paw but my version has
some modifications you know some minor
modifications so you can download it and
you can have it but remember however
there is some minor problems it's not
intuitive how do you begin it how do you
show the log so you might to you know
keep that in mind so basically this is
the part I modified okay so here is a
here is how you start the mod so you
started by once you install it you
started by MX command log mod then you
you call this command global command log
mod then you call this command CRM open
command Akhmatova okay that's what you
do
now in this syntax that's these three
lines so their documentation does not
mention this clearly it's like very
confusing you have to do so anyway I
added this so so if you want to use that
if you want to use that let me show you
you know you can look you can so let me
post the code here so for those of you
okay here's the Emacs code let's color
it showing browser oh that's way
so let's remove the all the comments
okay actually we need a comment here so
cut paste showing browser back to Emacs
color it and showing browser so that's
that's this might be useful if you are
going to use that start command lop log
mod it shows all your commands on the
window
not all by default it doesn't show for
example if you call backward or you know
if you press arrow keys they don't show
because you can you can filter out the
commands you want you don't want to show
because when you move kusa those
commands are very boring so sometimes
people don't want to show it so by
default they don't show that but I want
to show everything so that's why so
let's see next question and and where we
go
so let me magnify getting old and I have
a quasi he's like I cannot see
laughs like keys so Thank You Daniel for
that we're gonna I'm gonna look at that
so so so so ganz says what's the
contribution so let me tell you that
story so except like he's you know as
you if you don't know stuff like he's is
a emac is a VI like it's a modal key
binding set for Emacs
so it's a key binding set for Emacs it
changes the completely changes how you
operate in Emacs and but it's like vim
where you have command nod you have
insert mod why because that way is
actually more efficient because when you
compute when you lock your key
keystrokes you'll find that command mod
actually saves you about at least 30
percent of keystrokes so so when you are
doing if you are a programmer you do
text editing you know you do code if you
use a modal mod like modal like switch
to command more mud you know if you use
any sort of model mod you will save I
will say at least 20 percent of
keystrokes so why is this important this
is important when you have repetitive
strain injury you know all when you type
a lot you know this is important so you
want to go modal model is the most
efficient now if you don't have a hand
pen if you don't type that much if you
are already used to Emacs keybinding
that's fine you know if you are already
used to visual studio or whatever that's
fine but when you started to have a pen
or something then of course you want a
solution you want to be efficient then
you want to think about modal now modal
you can go with V you know on on visual
studio on vs code or many others you
have them you can install them be module
that's one way it beam is pretty good
okay it's it's okay but the but if you
do you swim beam beam you know key
binding I recommend you want to change
your scales escape
key to something easier okay don't don't
you know move especially avoid moving
your wrist like that to press the escape
key instead you know just move your
whole hand to press and don't do not put
Escape key on the tab you know because
that will make you you know you it will
you will it's a trap you know you tend
to do this often because it's easier to
press the tab key by doing that don't do
that so if you use vim I recommend you
map the caps lock key traditional caps
lock to the escape or you can install
there are some in many other solutions
you can install a double key you know
things like that anyway I'm not gonna go
into detail so vim is is one option okay
vim so but vim ski binding is not the
most is not optimal because wim vim ski
binding is is historical it just happens
to be developed and evolved that way so
even the model the idea of modal like
switching to command mod and insert mod
that idea is historical it's not it's
not a creative solution it's not someone
sit down thought about key binding and
decided oh wait why don't we have a
command block mod yeah I mean command
Martine in Soma that's not that's not
the case
it's just historical because forty years
ago you don't have interactive you know
real-time you know we see weak or
anything like that what you do is that
you you type a command you enter send it
to the computer then then you type
another command you tell the command you
tell the computer to update the screen
so that's why you have command mod and
in Zermatt that's how it happens so V so
Vince key binding is historical it's not
optimal so so that's how soft like ease
came by my suffer like he says long
history before stuff like he sees over
eMac smart but anyway
so cassava Crikey's is a efficient
keybinding system for Emax and its model
and the difference from them is that the
Excel flies keys key binding choice is
the key you know which key does what
command is based on economics and based
on the Emacs statistics of command Co so
you know it's it's supposed to be you
know it's designed to be optimal so
that's what cuz of like he is so you can
see so you can see this is this is
sapphire keys this is the this is a
source code you know for 4,000 lines of
Emacs ADIZ and we go up we go up you go
to the top then here's a URL so so it's
for Emacs so if you have hand 10 you
know you can try it it will take you one
month to learn and the implementation
okay so that that's the introduction to
suffer keys but there is a the
implementation is not perfect you know
it it works you know is it's working for
the past you know seven years and for me
and for other people but there is
something technical in Emacs I want to
basically the thing is that I want to
make it so that when you switch to
command mods and insert mod it does not
actually change every key rather you
wanted to switch just the key map so I
believe that's what Daniel made a pull
request that does that I think that's
you know I haven't looked into because
it takes a lot of time to you know it
will take me hours and days to to get
back into that you know you have to you
know once you do Emacs this you have to
get back into the mod so okay so so soft
like he so what did he contribute so I'm
using it to so best thing so far so
yeah if you are emacs lisp coder you can
go into excel flight keys you know you
can see the pool request but then then
your language in your landlord he tends
to write tons of stuff like he sent me
emails every email is 2,000 words 3000
works full fledged with philosophy and
[Laughter]
you know I start I almost I basically
stopped reading emails because emails is
like it's a pain you know we since I
started to do video about about seven
month ago now half a year ago so Chris
are Frankie's so you can see it's here
and it's on github and it's also also on
mapa you know it's just search for the
word stuff like he's you know you find
it so here's a link so I want to talk
about so we kind of digress a little bit
I want to talk about well I didn't
expect so many people today so this is
different from hey now second awesome
father of you greetings you this is
different for my usual time you know 10
o'clock in the morning so right now
ready now it's 5:00 so it's like 8 hours
difference so what came by these no
ideas at github you can look at my
detail ideas a github okay so yeah I'm
gonna get back to into that because I
wanted to do some there's some changes I
want through I was thinking to do but so
so then you know are you actually using
the code that you did a pull request I
want to make sure you know i you know my
grass is this class is so bad is
scratches on it it is cheap Walmart I
need to
get a new pair of glasses you know it's
in so bad so when you wear these glasses
you get teary we need stuff like he's
also in vs code you know actually yeah
so actually I have been thinking doing
that because I started to to look at vs
code about a few days ago and it you
know my impression it's just really good
okay
it's really good and also partly because
I'm really tired of the Emacs community
you know I being Emacs community for 20
years I being a contributor you can call
me a contributor for like ten years at
least and you know yeah you know many of
you guys support me but many doesn't
because I criticize open source and
Richard storm and all the time things
like that so they don't they don't you
know they don't promote my stuff they
don't you know a lot they don't link to
it since things like that so a no money
and every time Emacs has a problem you
know I talked about these too many times
in the past so I'm not gonna do it today
so I'm you know so but I've been looking
at visuals vs code wait not Visual
Studio code oh okay the full name is
Visual Studio code okay that's
interesting so what what do they call
the other one Visual Studio okay so the
the other one is that I mean the old
ones Visual Studio right so anyway vs
code I've been looking at vs code and
it's just my impression is it is is it's
really great you know and also so so my
impression is pretty good you know I
haven't actually started to use it you
know the the way because I've been using
Emacs for 20 years so when you want to
start with a new editor you know the way
you you you really start to learn new
thing you have to actually start to use
it like do things with it like like just
cut off like stop using Emacs you know
when you do some part
you useless then you started to actually
learn you can't learn that if you are
not committed you know if you are just
casual just looking at oh what it what
it does then then you don't really learn
you you really learn when you actually
need like start a project with it
you know with a language JavaScript or
whatever so anyway I have you know my
it's really good
yeah and I can I know why I know
practical reasons why because eMac this
you know all my complaints again is the
Emacs people you know the eMac this has
been stagnate stagnant for like for 20
years okay yeah there's some you know
these improvements here and there but
basically compared to all the other
languages PHP JavaScript you know see
see prosperous : compared to them eMac
this is pretty much stagnant new no
change at all you know all the other
language they have several generations
of compilers in the past 20 years PHP
you know JavaScript several compilers
that you know so many it's like so many
things going on eMac this is kind of not
no change and the Emacs people they are
fanatics you know there's and then their
opinion is that om ax is the greatest C
Magnus mrs. Grady it is not it you know
if you compare the language eMac this
would versus JavaScript for example
today okay order or all the languages
PHP they are like 10 times better than
any Magnus truly now I did a video very
popular about why eMac bit sucks you
should check out that one so that's like
one hour grant okay so that's the video
you can find it um actually I have a lot
video about eMac B's so but anyway so
you you'll find it if you go through my
eMac base tutorial you go to eat
practical eMac list
and the bottom there is okay wait this
is email is for beginner okay so you go
to eMac this miscellaneous I think okay
not here you go to Emacs miscellaneous
there okay so you go through my Agha
Emacs start okay my Emacs website then
you go to Emacs meet Emacs miscellaneous
us find these two videos 2019 much nice
ye max this sucks okay so you watch that
one now you know that that is a big one
I give you the detail of why you Magnus
is you know I'm not trying to exaggerate
but you would be like at least two or
three times is it's like a magnitude
times worse then or basically all other
languages PHP JavaScript you know
because they are they are actually you
know first of all you have okay
I'm not going to repeat you know go
check out that video the the the the
main point of that video comes in like
one hour or something after you know so
you might to skip around you know look
around so anyway so I you know I being
kind of frustrated with in Emacs so
Visual Studio code looks really good and
okay so that's one thing why is it good
I know because you know the you know
these commercial entities you know they
are truly thriving when our Emacs is you
know free software foundation open
source you are not you know you only
have like hundred people you know or
10,000 people that's it well with
JavaScript PHP you have ten ten million
people you know working on it that's
reality
you know corporations you know ten
thousand corporations trying to improve
it you know trying to each one you know
they are ultimately they are trying to
make money for themselves
you know but bringing improvements to
PHP or JavaScript and so on that's the
side effect you know so it's happening
you know so that is why so Visual Studio
is you know a visual studious code is a
side effect of JavaScript JavaScript
then you started to have you know
JavaScript for desktop then github
started to create Adam editor then Adam
becomes you know then you have the
electron component now before this is
first of all you have the Chrome browser
Chrome browser then you have the
chromium you know the v8 engine for
JavaScript then that becomes then it
appears to people then it becomes that
you can actually write a desktop you
know we think a browser this you see
this vs code is actually this is
actually a browser you know you you are
looking at you are looking at chrome web
browser essentially that you know that's
that's what this is so you have a come
you know chrome web browser this people
started to then you have atom then you
have you know electron framework that's
truly right once write once run it
everywhere like chaves chaves slogan you
all right you know write once run
everywhere on your android on iphone on
Windows or Mac you know that's vs code
or atom for anything returning electron
also discord you know there's tons of
applications so JavaScript you know it
becomes this huge monster then then you
have a vs code so I can understand why
this is should be much superior than
then email I can see it because do you
have massive people you know working on
creating frameworks and systems you know
this is no joke you know Emacs is used
by what you know let's say 100,000
people around the world
3,000 vivo that's yeah that's really you
know today yesterday yesterday you have
the virtual Emacs conference 2019 you
look at their YouTube you got ten people
watching you know it's kind of
you know I I really want Emax to go but
big but it's not really doing anything
and also you know it's not you know so
anyway so vicious of JavaScript you know
this outside would you know JavaScript
visual street vs code so I find it you
know vs code is pretty good and also
because I'm doing websites so I write I
have to know JavaScript
I know JavaScript very well I talked
about this many times
javascript I have many videos on
JavaScript tutorial and I've done many
videos on that and I have this
javascript in depth so javascript is a
language I know well in fact I spent you
know this JavaScript depth in depth
tutorial basically I spent full time for
what for two years full time diving into
you know JavaScript the language
technical details I read all the or the
you know JavaScript language spec you
know they are incomprehensible
inconvience about to read so you know so
I spend two full year to write this this
JavaScript so in fact so if I know emag
B's and I've been coding eMac this since
2006 so I've been coding him at least
and reading eMac this manual for you
know for 14 years or so but I actually
know JavaScript better because you know
the language details because most most
of the time for average programmers you
know even if you work with the language
for five years you don't know the
technical details of the language
because most of the tax because you
don't need to actually so you can you
can you can work in C++ PHP JavaScript
colon for for five years and someone can
ask you some technical question about
that language or Python and you will not
be able to answer because in practice
you don't need to because you know the
language tech details because you know
for example JavaScript this they are
let's say 100 tech did details you know
once you work with this language for
let's say five years you might know 30
of those tech details you can answer but
there are 70 other tech details you
don't know because you never looked into
that because you your job does not
require those you know things so that's
the general picture about how a person
might know you know how much you know
about a language so anyway I'm I'm
studying JavaScript you know I spent two
years so I know the technique technical
details you know like Oh aspects but
that's not the case for my eMac B's even
though I program him agrees for over
thank you for for 15 years you know I
just program in my beast to get things
to work I have you know I have I have
you know compared to lines of code my
lines of code in a Mac this is like 10
times then what I have written in
JavaScript so what I'm saying here you
know I'm trying to as a side talk I'm
giving you some kind of a practical
aspect looking at you know like the
difference between knowing a language
very well and how much of it is
practical things like that you know for
example I've written ten times more emag
base coat then JavaScript practical eMac
this you know code packages for 14 years
on the other hand I've only robes like
five you know five five JavaScript apps
that you know you might say it's a you
know you can show to people but but on
the other hand javascript language I
really know that JavaScript language far
more than the emag beast so that's an
interesting point so back to what I was
talking about vs code so I know
JavaScript whales
so so so that's also my interest in vs
code because vs code is written in
JavaScript you know you neck electrons
so I might you know I've been thinking
of is going to study you know creates a
ficus who knows you know I might switch
I might not you know I don't really want
to because you know I being with Emacs
for twenty years I don't really want to
you know when you switch it's true it's
drama you know they all the Emacs people
community who know me they all say Oh
class which you know it's drama anyway
is we will see what happens come on easy
Tron
thank you for coming by his Heatran so
Axl I talked about so I was planning to
go into actually I was planning to go
talk about typescript and close that I
open a copy yet cuz it looks a talk show
wait ok copying stuff like he's curse
off like he's chokes our talk show and
did I paste it here no so let's face it
here sucks our talk show and inks off
like he's then we talk about vs code
JavaScript in-depth
copy that paste that then we talked
about vs code so but I was going to talk
about something about PowerShell which
is fantastic
PowerShell let me show you the so
PowerShell you know that's gonna be at
least twenty minutes
so but let me show you some of the you
know PowerShell you can start to use it
if you know bash or if you know command
prompt already the Microsoft command
prompt you can start to use it because
you know it's look works the same for
example PowerShell so LS so let's exit
you type exit to exit so you let
they magnify magnify my so let's say PWS
H on the Mac the command name is PW SH
okay
on Windows and Linux is the full name
PowerShell so you can see you know you
can show directory you can do LS you can
see the trucks Rd actually CD to web
sorry you know you can press tab to
command complete info and OS for example
LS - al you can you can you know you can
make directories basically they have
aliases like so if you offer me with
special command desk Exe you can start
to use it then you can you can also do
pipe like let's see you know for example
let's see I want to show a file I want
to show the first five lines of a file
so so for example let's go to San
talk-show let's let's do this ok so case
our talk show
this is today's page wait minutes
there's something wrong ok this is this
is my page hey let's do open in terminal
ok so I opened my in the current
directory so you can see LS this is sup
talk show current directory let's make
it big and let's split the window ok
let's speak window oops
okay so I'm going to okay I'm going to
start - it's okay so none second so for
example that's yes okay so for example
some talk show I'm going to show the
first line five lines of fire so let's
let's - first of all I want to remove
the back and let's let's do this okay
so cat SART talk let's magnify okay
cats a talk show index.html okay that
shows the final content so let's do that
again let's say let's say grab so you
pirate to grep you want to find a word
Haskell okay let's say so I want to find
all lines that contains to what has gone
so there it is that's how you do it okay
now let's try in PowerShell okay so PW
Sh
okay now we are in PowerShell now we are
we want to how do you do that I don't
know
so let's go through my PowerShell
tutorial you go to PowerShell vs. Bosch
so here is how you do it select first
five okay that's how you do it wait you
want to select piping you want to do
grip right so so on this page you can
see the bosch syntax and the PowerShell
equivalent what we want to do is grab
okay there okay is complicated now let's
let's do it then
so grab how do you catch a file in
PowerShell so CAD is the same as cat so
you do cat saw talk show index.html then
you private to you private to select
string so extreme
patent okay
select stream pattern ESCO okay let's
try that
hey there it is it worked okay so that's
power shop you know power Chow is very
interesting and it's hugely popular
today now it becomes in becoming very
popular because let me why because for
example let me show you you go to my
programming block you look at this image
this is the latest image from 2019 Jun
so you can see the most popular language
JavaScript Java PHP Python C sharp CSS
then C Ruby
typescript Scala swift Objective C shell
and PowerShell right there golden
PowerShell you see PowerShell then you
started to see pearl Haskell
Coughlin's okay that's not so after
PowerShell you can say anything below
that is not that popular well once you
see Haskell you know that at that point
that's a boundary ESCA let's know not
popular so anyway I think maybe that's
it for today because yeah that's some
kind of some sort of introduction to
power shower how long have I been
talking oh wow not too bad so let me
just read the comments and let's see
z Tron Daniel Kim is a minor monster may
be just under the hood at convenient
thanks for today no answer
I'm using it I'm walking okay so great
okay so yeah I'll check it out
idea is that most frequently use command
have the most easy keys yes
okay so bot says I usually clearly
prefer open source over especially
Microsoft but in this case I think it's
the it'll be better if you would switch
from the old penny max to the trash and
juicy vision but but you are a traitor
you should you should you should dive
into Emacs man good morning Alan why do
you break in cars again yeah the my
neighbors you know this you know I you
know my neighbors say you know I don't
know what's going on so so what what's
what next guys comment oh we might end
today or we might do another eMac stuff
like oh we we dive into more about
PowerShell so Emacs more Emacs stuff or
more power show need okay let me show
you this Emacs code okay so I want to
look up let's say I want to look up
Emacs I want to search the web of some
world let's say I want to search the
word vs code so in Emacs I can press
three keys now look okay
viki's then you know it pops up the
browser in such visual studio so that
command you can see is this command so
look up web okay so that is a Emacs
package of written
so if you guys like it you can download
it it's on male pad so for example the
key I'm pressing is this one so I'm
pressing space HT envoy a keyboard and
that's sound Oh cobweb and the source
code is over here you know you know I
can show the source code here is the
source code you can look up on our
second lips it can it can look up web it
can look up Wikipedia specifically or it
can look up some definition of a word by
any URL you set yourself you can you can
customize it so you can choose a URL for
example let's let's say I want to look
up etymology of a word okay so so the
command would because I look up
etymology okay so let's call so I look
up entomology
now I have a key binding but I forgot
what kita because I rarely use this okay
so it actually goes it actually runs the
Emacs browser use I think I set that up
before like that but usually normally
you'll just go to the browser but in
this case I think I customize it
customized it so that it you know it
uses the building
Emacs browser because for etymology
typically you know you I want to be able
to copy it copy the result and you know
spirit window go back to Emacs you know
and maybe paste stuff here wait you need
to copy so anyway what does they say so
etymology the etymology of etymology
late 14th century et Malaysia facts of
the engine of the development of a word
from Old French etymology 14th century
modern French
and so long okay so for example so I can
copy that copy back pack it back to here
paste it and you know I have a etymology
so that package is called you know I
look up what okay actually I don't want
it homology so let's go to let me show
you the so here is the URL showing
browser and it's on my Appa so you guys
can use it okay close that close and
paste it here make a link then showing
browser okay so that's sound look upward
so bar says so the more I see you using
Emacs the more I find it confusing and
to be honest because I'm working too
fast because other commands is too too
advanced
okay so so let's look at the time
eight people watching okay I think
that's stopped now
so part and Z trunk crazy have a good
day in Germany and thank you guys
Alan yeah we're gonna stopped in your
language thank you guys for coming by
and thank you hello beautiful people for
the super chat so bye guys
yeah I think that's it for today I'm
gonna shut down in one minute let's look
at okay I'm shut down in one minute
let's see what else is interesting
good night Alan
PowerShell so guys you know : PowerShell
and there's a help help is like a man
page in UNIX you know you can type help
you know you just type help so and you
know the thing is that so CD you know I
can CD to my home directory that so it's
like you can't begin to use it we face
replacing patch and you can use you know
it's available on Linux on a Mac as well
and also Microsoft is becoming you know
if you look at history this is quite
interesting because you see Microsoft
today's become is the biggest
contributor of open source even more so
than Google so you know you see if you
are observer of history you know this is
a quite interesting twist and there are
many aspects to look into you know you
can think about oh is it
evil or is it good or bad things like
that anyway so Microsoft today in the
past you know three four or five five
years they become the biggest
contributor to open source not you know
and in terms of lines of code to you
know for example the PowerShell
PowerShell itself today is open source
like full MIT license I looked MIT
license not new you know not MIT license
is one of the most free license so you
have basically if something is MIT
license that means you can use it you
can modify it all it requires is that
you give credit like you know this is
originally you know from you know you
give credit that's that's all it
requires no no this big package from GPL
license you know they sting you in many
ways they want you to conform to the
Richard Stallman's
way of thinking oh that's that's GPA but
MIT Rison so well you know so they so
power shower is open-source and the the
the core that PowerShell is based on is
called
Nicole so you know Microsoft you know
the Microsoft technology stack you have
the dotnet is the foundation right but
now in the past since about 2006 thing
they created dotnet core which is open
source truly it's amazing it's that niko
is open source and it's meant for
cross-platform so so so PowerShell is
written on top of it so you know this so
this is you know at least from a
historical perspective perspective this
is a giant change of things you know you
don't you know I don't know what's good
or bad or what's gonna happen in the
future you know that's interesting okay
but that's it for today so no scene -
okay that's not
let's not extend any you know embrace
and extend a and extinguish that's what
UNIX phonetics want to call you know
they that's what they unix phonetics say
about Microsoft but in my opinion it is
the UNIX phonetics themselves are doing
that okay if you are going to start to
get me to begin a one-hour rant non-stop
but that's it for today thank you guys
for watching bye