Test test test. Hello guys. Good morning
everyone. Am I alive? Let's check uh
let's check check. So
check audio. Check audio. Good. Yes.
Video. Let's see. Show face.
The tech geekers nerds. They don't want
to show face. You know many of you anno
random. Okay. S talk show. Today's topic
uh random topic. So if you you you ask
questions, I answer. Otherwise, I'm just
going to go random and do what I have to
do. Actually, uh quite a few things to
do. Okay. So, for example, this is
Emacs. Emacs. There's a here are the
notes of things I need to do. So, every
two hours or so, I walk back and forth
taking my notebook and uh take
screenshots on on my website, read my
website, um review and uh uh write down
what I need to do. So, here's a bunch of
things. So, I'm going to go through
them.
So, this is Emacs or press a key. you
can view uh view them in a dedicated
application.
Uh okay. So I'm going to go through and
tell you. So otherwise you ask
questions. Hello Hank. Hello Pravin. Uh
number one pass. I want to build a
pomodoro timer in Emacs. Where to start?
I don't know what is Pomodoro. Okay. You
have to explain that. What is your
favorite spreadsheet program?
uh spreadsheet. I haven't used
spreadsheet for like 30 years. So long
time ago in 1991 I was a expert of this
spreadsheet called wins.
Okay, let's see if we can still find it.
I'm sure you'll find it but uh it takes
some time.
Okay. So, uh but before we go into that
topic, let me just double check last
time. Video check, audio check. Uh am I
good to go? So, ping window shows my
Emacs command and keystrokes and uh
yeah. Okay, I'm good to go. So,
spreadsheet. So, back in 1990, early
1990s 91 I was using wind spreadsheet.
Okay. So, this is on uh on a Mac long
ago. So, let's see vehicle uh vehicle
for hire company. No. Okay. So, this is
history. So, back then the the most
popular spreadsheet is Microsoft. Uh
what what is the Microsoft ones? But
anyway, let's
spreadsheet. Let's check the uh wins
wins spreadsheet.
Yeah, wins is a spreadsheet program that
was developed by innovative software and
later sold by in infomix in the late
1980s and early 1999s. Okay. So this is
was this was wins was the best
spreadsheet. Um so it's comparable to
the what's the Microsoft? Yeah,
Microsoft Excel of course that that was
the most popular and still is today.
So in the 1990s I was expert of wins. I
learned it I mastered it. Uh but since
you know since 1990s I haven't used a
spreadsheet and before that so there's a
history hypercard and hyper talk. Uh I
also have used them hyper card on the
Mac. uh and uh I'm not sure about hyper
talk uh procedural programming language.
No, I haven't used that. But hyperard so
this is you know very popular back then
this is like cutting edge well known the
best program you know it's like
interactivity you know back then you
don't have you know you don't have
videos you don't have internet I mean
you and you don't have interactivity on
the computer like your computer is doors
you know just like uh just like bunch of
command text only so hyperard is one of
the first graphical uh program and
interactive on on the computer, you
know, you can so you can write notes or
you you can draw. So that's back then 19
early 1990s. So wins is my uh
application. Now do do they have a
screenshot? Let's see if we can get a
screenshot wins spreadsheet.
There it is. Now I very much remember
this this diagram. I mean this
illustration, this cover because that's
what you know wins you know uh software
the box you know back then it comes with
the box when you buy software okay that
is my favorite spreadsheet now
pomodoro is a timer which make you work
in interval like 40 minutes and 5
minutes break okay I don't care about
that okay so you are saying you know
there's a timer in fact Emac has a such
a feature. So basically you want to use
your software like on your computer
every 1 hour or two it beeps and remind
you that that you have to take a rest in
typing. So let's see where is uh there
there's a there's such application on
emacs let's say uh not that uh I think
it's a package you have to install but
you can write one easily you know so you
know because you got the timer function
in eac or these are eag okay so so you
are saying that you want to write such a
application or something yeah you can uh
I don't think it's difficult but I don't
care for that because I don't want I
want I don't want tech geeking on top of
tech geeking you know nerds like me or
some of you guys like we sit in front of
computer 10 hours a day I don't want
another application like another
application or even within Emacs to
manage your time and stuff no so what I
do is you set up you know just buy alarm
clock you know there's a timer actually
these days I just use my iPhone or iPad
you set a time timer every 1 hour or two
hours it beeps you know then you you get
up you press repeat something like that
or cancel okay so I don't want I don't
want another like timer to manage your
timing in your computer okay you can do
that for Emacs fans you know a lot EMAC
fans do that but not me
okay that's that's your questions two of
your questions okay so But
so so now let me just walk work walk
work walk work walk work walk work walk
work walk work walk work walk work
through my stuff I I need to do okay so
this one so these are the notes I've
taken uh uh this is these are actually
from my um surface tablet okay actually
I can show you uh let's open it okay so
uh keyboard block okay
keyboard block and uh you need to search
Yeah. Okay. So, I need to expand this
window. Yeah.
So, you can see the panel side panel.
Okay. Search keyboard
surface Microsoft
Surface
uh Microsoft Surface Pro 2015.
That is a one of the you know old
computer I have. So, I take this and
walk around back and forth basically and
write down. Take notes. Fantastic. This
is fantastic for taking notes. Uh, but
the Microsoft pen sucked. It sucks. You
buy it $100 or something back then and
it breaks. So, but however, the tablet
is actually fantastic. In fact, you
know, so I've been using this one for by
now 10 years. I was quite surprised,
amazed it actually works still. So
I could, you know, so but but since then
there's there are so many uh laptops and
notebooks. So but anyway, I I I think I
can recommend this, you know, I was
surprised I'm still using it. So you
can, you know, write notes when you walk
around. That's what I do. And writing
Chinese. In fact, I did this in one of
my live stream. In fact, we can do it
now. So, you know, for example, take a
screenshot.
Take a screenshot and open it. And there
we have here is my
my tablet.
Uh oh, wait. So, okay. So, you need to
open it in uh in paint in snip and
sketch. Actually this is the best
uh you
how
me
it's been a long time I I I have written
Chinese. So this means Chinese. This
means can you write Chinese?
Can let's so this uh so let's increase
and say
can uh you
write
okay
Chinese.
Okay, that is a demonstration of the
writing tablet. So, save it. Save it.
Okay, save it. Already exist. Yes.
Replace. Close that. Back here. Shrink.
Okay.
Uh, so another question. Pravin
says, "You use lisp for eac lisp."
No, I don't use lispy. uh you watch my
video often so you should know I use all
my own packages
basically if it's not written by me I
don't use it in in fact I don't use any
you know so here is all my packages CSS
auto hard key diet for directory emac
this find and stuff keys and HTML mode
JavaScript mode lookup for lookup
internet uh lynen scripting language
mode, math input and so on, PHP and you
know so I use basically all my packages
packages and plus if you go to init so
and you know so if you go to init I have
like few thousand lines of code you know
my personal init so here is a directory
of all my other init emac this files
uh you know these are personal to me so
I don't use so if you go to my let's see
if we can go to Emacs so this is my
waitax
yes there go there and uh go to alpar
which is uh your packages repository
what do I have chatg
okay this is for interaction with um AI
chat bots
which I haven't been using. I I talked
about it about a month ago installing it
and demonstration of a local artificial
intelligence spot uh interaction via
Emacs. So, but I don't use it now
because I turn turned out if you install
local ones, you really need a very
powerful machine like $10,000 machine
otherwise it's you know otherwise uh you
know the performance
is worse than you know just using a
website you know guac or chat gvt and so
on. So I don't use it. And transient
this I don't use either. I you know this
is installed by the GPT. So I actually
do not install any other people's
packages. I don't need to because I've
been coding EMAC this for like 20 20
years by now. Okay. Close close close
that show in uh browser. Okay. So that's
surface book
surface tablet we talked about. So go to
today's talk show. uh go to today's talk
show go there open it and let's paste
the link of the things we talked about
so I also demonstrated this pen and I
can show you uh back to pen input
devices I can show you which one is that
so I have by now I have you know bought
many of these uh different type of
stylus or pens and there are different
types and I talked about it them a few
times in my video. So, which one is the
one I I'm using now? It's uh so this one
ren ren uh the nera is actually the best
if you have Microsoft surface. Okay, by
the way, if you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed because I
talk slowly. That's better that way.
more composed and logical and uh and I
ramble. So, play at 1.5 speed minimum.
So, so let me show you. So, the more
Chinese there. So, let me show you the
the one I have on my desk. Uh
act uh where is that?
So this
okay I'll find it somewhere. So this one
is just a generic tablet so-called
universal
uh stylus. It's basically just function
like your finger which is usable but but
an active stylus is much better. Okay.
So
I want to find my tablet now. Is it
somewhere here? Okay, Rafael, that's
just a pen for surface tablet. So,
drawing tablet there. So, this one is
what I have. China
Huang
H640P.
So, I bought it like five years ago,
2021. Okay, that's what I have and works
well. It's wired. You can get them
wireless, of course. So, let's copy
that. Paste. Uh, okay. linkify
and uh I observed your list
automatically adds brackets around
function. How do you do that? Oh god.
Uh that's because I'm using a list mod.
So for example, press press.
There it is. Kasa EMACB mod. So go to
the source code. Open it. So there it
is. A total of 2,000 lines of code. Go
to go to the top and uh if you love it,
open the URL show in browser eagmart.
You can buy it, pay me, you know, donate
to me $30. I'll send it to you for 10
years. All my packages are free, but I
die of hunger. Nobody give a [ __ ] And
every day they just ask you questions
cuz I need to do this one. How do you do
this? You know, that's the nature of
open source.
Okay. So you can so so e emac this mod.
So that's my mod. So when you want to
code eag this like right now default
defend press a key it become defend
press a key again it become the full
template. So all the brackets are
automatic added. So for example another
example let's see what uh point. Okay
point you want the current ka position.
Okay. So that function is called point.
So you just type P that's a abbreviation
built in in SA emac this mod. So P
become point press again becomes the
full uh function. So in the case of
point you can describe function
it doesn't take any argument you see. So
it just like that. Uh in other ca for
another example uh buffer sub buffer
substring no properties. So B buffer
substring no properties bmp
space there becomes that space becomes
that with the arguments. So it tells you
that you need a position let's say
position uh one and you know so the
position in the beginning of buffer
that's one and the whatever end is let's
say state 10. So if you run this code it
will just grab the first 10 characters
it returns a string. Okay. So you know
that's how I do it and press a key it
become pified. So all the commands you
can see in the pink window, you know, uh
you know, all the past commands. Okay.
Okay. Let's do uh let's just copy do a
screenshot of this and let's get back to
when I get a job, you'll pay me. Thank
you. Uh appreciate that. Okay. So let me
So Okay. So let's close that. Close
that. Okay. So we open that,
open the link, copy the file path,
close, close, close, close and uh put
that in today's talk show. Okay. Showing
browser
and we this is my coffee setup for the
past for about this year. So every
morning I get up, I make coffee. The way
I make coffee is via this manual
uh dedication manual
because well I could you know because I
don't have money well I could buy you
know coffee machine is not too expensive
$20 $30 but but I didn't have that money
anyway I make coffee so manually uh you
know filter coffee beans I mean this is
ground coffee. You know, co coffee is a
white man's thing. Complicated ground
coffee. So you have ground coffee
meaning it's grind the past tense of
grind. So it's ground meaning that they
grind the coffee beans. Pregind.
So you call it ground. Ground coffee. It
just means you know it has been
grounded.
Basically it became powder. So you put
this that you know and then you put that
then you put organic expensive
Costco organic American elite milk.
I my my life's quality has been upgraded
status. So and another important
ingredient is the honey elite honey from
Costco.
uh and also
elite tea not from tea bags you know so
every day I make that and it and here is
the boiling water uh
kettle that's the classic name for that
is kettle but now we have upgraded with
technology so this is electric
and that's another another China cheapo
you know everything you buy is is cheap
from China and they work fine. Okay, so
that's my coffee. So let's go get back.
I want to work on my um Yeah. So I want
to work on my so recursive edit. So I
need to uh I need to work on this fast
because there are so many things to do.
Uh recursive edit. So that means you
know uh let's skip that. Okay. So
actually let's skip that and
skip that. Skip that. Let's get into
something more interesting. Okay. More
line that's about Emacs.
Uh
okay. So I need to update uh more line
display meaning. Oh god it you know
for each of these. So this is part my
part of my Emacs tutorial and what this
note means that replace you see this is
a H2 header then this red H3 header
H3 header H3 header so these notes are
usually just meaningful to me. So this
means replace
replace you know uh replace all these H3
header promote them to H2. So each each
of these section becomes a section you
know so you know this becomes a section
this becomes a section
you know so that way it's easier to see
you know this page is telling people
about this mode line this this thing
this bar in Emacs
so these are notes for me to you know to
to do okay let's skip it because okay
there's a lot to do. So,
simple. Okay. A new question from simple
simple postman. Hi, Kasa. Have you used
an e- in display tablet for an extended
period of time to save your eyes? No, I
haven't actually. So, I never got the
chance to try e ink. Actually, I never
seen it.
Well, I probably seen it for a few
minutes, you know, in store or
something.
uh from a friend I think so but I never
used e ink myself. It will be
interesting. I would be interested to
get one. Um yeah
dose hope your days are doing going
well. Thank you dose. Okay so I need to
work on these a lot to do. So let me
just do them. Okay. So,
okay. So, this uh so this more line
page I need to change the H2.
How shall we do it?
Okay. So, okay. Let's let's just
I'll probably have to work them offline
as well. So, H3. So you can see so you
can do uh list matching lines. So you
can see all the matching lines. So
that's the ping window show my commands.
So where's uh these matching lines? So
you can see
now I need to So the pink window is
okay. I need to adjust my head. Let's
Let's see. Let's do that. So you got So
we can have more space for the pink
window. Uh, hide, show, unlock,
move down,
lock, and uh
uh
Okay, so move down. Can you move the
logic? Yeah, something like that.
Okay. So, now more room for the pink
window
history of things. Okay. And now you
just see top top of my head
tedious setup.
Okay, I think that's good. So, H3. So
this all this H3. So just call a
command.
Uh first of all delete the section.
Delete the section show in browser. So I
remove the section boxes. Back to Emacs.
Now call command H3 to H2. There it is.
Do that. Do that. Do that. Do that. Do
that. Do that. Okay. Undo. Do redo. Show
in browser. So you can see
H3 becomes H2. Now each one of these has
you know are more prominent. Now let's
add the section boxes. So I want all H2
to have a section by themsel. Okay. So
delete the reference. You can see in the
at the bottom the reference is still a
section. You got a box. So we just
remove that.
Refresh. You see? Gone. Now press press
add sections to or H2.
You can see the command there. Now
showing browser. Fantastic
mode line display meaning file encoding
and new line convention. That's the
that's the first part of this mode
line.
Okay. And then so anyway that's one
thing. So this
okay next
make new page. Okay. So that one.
Okay. So most uh update today's date. So
you can see it becomes 23rd before it
was uh 22nd show in browser. You can see
the date has been updated last updated
date
and uh then okay. So next thing I want
to do so update code to website. So let
me show you that. Okay. So
okay which what what is the key? I
believe that there it is update code to
website. So go to the source code. So
here's the code. So what the so what
what this code is that you know I have
like a thousand Emacs command I wrote
such as this one or for example what is
this one pearl format format buffer so
this formats pearl code
okay um so if I update this page I mean
so usually for each command I have
written in eag this I have a
corresponding
page to show it. Now in this example,
it's actually a talk show because we try
to write it. We tried to code it on the
fly during live. So this is in July 9th
few weeks ago. So we started to code it
but we didn't finish. So here so you can
see where's the code? Here's a code. C
code incomplete.
So usually I do a live stream coding but
but you know this issue this problem
turns out a bit more complex. So I
didn't finish
uh in one hour because also because I
need to talk about lots of other things.
So I code it offline because sometimes
when it gets esoteric I code offline
because people don't understand what
you're doing.
So anyway, what this code does, you
know, for each command, I usually have a
corresponding web page. So usually I
want to update. So when I whenever I I
modify the command, I want to be able to
press a button, then it automatically up
open the URL and update the
corresponding code. For example, for
this one is here. You see it's
incomplete
and version 2025 July 9th you see but my
current versions of close that the
current version is um oh actually I
should change the date so
you know
July 23rd. Okay. So now now this code is
finished. So I can now press a key. it
will update that page and you you can
see this part will be new. Okay, let's
do that.
So the key I have set up for this
command is uh this uh let me show you
that that okay so dvdw runs this command
okay I can show you uh cas key binding
and this is my emac init file so
uh let's search for update
update update there it is you see w key
um you know W for update code website.
So close that. Close that. So now I just
press that key and this page will be
updated. Okay. Now check the date. Okay.
Uh press press.
Okay. So update code to website by line
not found. Oh Jesus.
Uh this got an error because it's trying
to search for by line. Now I don't know
understand why by line is not found but
it updated anyway.
You see it updated the page anyway. It
opened the page and updated. So let's go
to the um messages buffer. Why does it
say by line not found?
Okay. Show all buffers. Uh help occur
messages.
So I open external app. Okay. Occur.
Wait, where does where's the arrow came
from?
Refresh. It says spy line not found.
What do you mean by line not found?
occur.
Close messages.
Search for by line. Okay, there program
update code website by line not found.
Uh, where does that came from? I don't
know. So, let's search.
Okay. It must be from a function it is
calling. Okay. So
yeah but why? Oh there it is. You see?
So every time it after it update the
page it will also update by XR you know
date.
So that is this uh update article
timestamp.
But in my talk show page usually I don't
have you know by sard date because you
know because that's you know talk show
there's always a date
and it's fixed. So that's why when
calling this command update article
timestamp it says by line not found.
See that's why. But however,
you know, if you go to uh the page, the
page has been updated already. So,
where's the page? Did we close it? Yeah,
you can see here. Okay. Now, you just
need to syntax color. Do it. Uh fail pre
what?
Search fail pre. Oh god. What?
Oh
well,
we run into problems. You see the
reasons such we want to see you know if
you go to the page you can you can see
that the code has already been updated.
Now refresh you see but now there's a
problem because the code actually
contains the precode. You know this is a
nesting problem that occurs a nasty
problem occurs in programming languages
all over because but the because we are
in HTML and you got a pre-tag but
however the content of the pre-tag
actually contains
other pre-tags you know you know like
here here so part of it become HTML
that's why you got you know you become
this funky thing.
Uh
so that's why my command trying to
syntax color this part is not working
because it's trying to find end of pre
you know it's trying to find the end of
pre end
and basically it found there but
it's incorrect. So,
oh god. So, this gets into another kind
of general issue. I need to find a
solution.
Okay. So well,
but the walk around is that
yeah, let's not let's not do it for now.
Okay, let's
let's not do it.
Okay, let's let's let's
not make any change to the file. I'll
have to do I'll have to figure out what
to do. Um
yeah, I have to figure out what to do
when you have pre-insight. This is
actually fairly nasty problem.
you know there's no general solution
because because the issue is how do you
determine if you have a you know piece
of code in HTML
inside a pre-tag
but the the code itself
contains the pre-tag so the issue is how
do you then properly determine whether
you know which uh whether uh you know um
yeah actually you can do that.
So let's wait. So we basically
what we do is we open this page
find find the pre uh tag then go to jump
to the bottom of the pre matching
pre-tag
then
then remove everything inside it then
paste the code of this code
then
then we need to syntax tax color
this. And when you do syntax color,
yeah, when you do syntax color,
basically it needs to find every pre tag
block of text.
Um,
okay. And and skip if the code contains
pre-tag, you know, ignore it. you
basically want to
yeah so that's a problem you see let me
explain to uh why is it a problem for
example if you have a emac so whatever
code okay so if you have let's say
python whatever and your python code
let's do it okay let's just do it print
let's say pre that okay run it you see
it just prints that That's a valid code.
Purify the code. Okay, run it or run it
and paste the code here. Output here. So
that's a valid Python code. Now put it
back. So you can see here we got a page
you know a pre you know that okay that's
you cannot even select it now because
where is it?
I'll search for Python.
Yeah, here you see.
So you so you got the you got the you
know Python code there.
Now you need to syntax color this part
because otherwise this this you know
going to interfere with rendering.
So the question the problem is how do
you do it? How do you dis you know so
you you you find the beginning of the
pre-tag then you need to find the end of
pretag.
So
the question is how do you do it? Okay,
you basically it is impossible
because you know in our case you can say
oh let's just search for the end of
pretag plus a empty line right but but
your Python code could include an empty
line there then it doesn't work again so
the issue is there is no actual no way
to
to automate this Okay, that's a very
actually very interesting problem. This
kind of problem occurs over and over
again. This kind of problem also occur
with string escape.
Okay. Or
or it also happen with HTML amperand
uh amperand
something. Okay. Like soal character
entity. Okay. So let's see what is my
command to
encode amp% entity decode. So we need to
encode uh tab jab j there it is. Okay.
So basically the situation is so so
let's say if you have another amp the
situation is that when you have a syntax
and uh it is somehow nested it is nested
in some sense then there's no it is
impossible to tell whether it is actual
nested or not or or this is literally
what you mean.
Okay. So this happens in
in syntax in the tree tag in HTML syntax
basically when it happens when when
wherever you have the language that
contains the language itself. Okay. So
in our case we have HTML that contains
HTML.
Uh in the escape case you have like you
have um escape you know that's that
means a new line right? But what if you
have
a Python code that tries to pass a
string
and that string contains these things.
So,
so basically you you don't know the
meaning of that you know whenever you
you know meaning of that when when when
this line is nested inside Python okay
something something like that uh and
same thing with the amperand so when you
know so this kind of problem is generic
programming problem especially with
escape for example if you want to use
regular expression
to search for regular regular expression
then that's or help all help bent you
know it becomes impossible you want to
search for a regular expression let's
say you know if you have regular regular
expression let's say uh something date
followed by ABC
something date followed by uh let's say
something uh
what is Python's
uh
uh syntax for word. Okay, w you know
that is a common um regular expression
in Python, in Pearl, in JavaScript, in
Java, Java and almost all languages.
Regular expression that's that's uh
digit sequence one or more one uh let's
say add one or more. Okay, then word one
or more.
So this is your code and let's say you
have this code somewhere in your Python
or JavaScript or whatever. Well, then
one day you need to find you need to
find all occurrences where you have this
regular expression in your codebase
thousands of files. Okay, what do you
do? Well, then you need to use a regular
expression to
to match this this pattern. Okay? So,
that's what I'm talking about. Do you
guys understand?
Okay. I'm get you know I'm going into
like this as you know very deep
technical details. I can you know I can
actually show a example. I can turn this
into Python code and demonstrate it.
But I don't know if you guys are
interested, you know.
Um,
okay. So but so anyway we got we
encounter this programming this uh
programming problem nested syntax
when that's when you have a syntax
programming language syntax nested with
in that programming language. Okay, this
is a general problem
and uh basically it's unsolvable.
Okay, so that's one thing.
So let's see next question.
I'm curious about your thought on
literal programming
s how you organize. I have all my system
config even programs other than Emacs or
in oak files. It's like cleaner version
of glue store. Okay.
My opinion on literal programming is
that I think it's [ __ ]
Okay. So why? Because it's too much ado
very complex. It's created by Donald
Guth
who is you know who is academic
uh pearl pod. Okay, that's one of the
Asian article about how pearl
documentation system is not literal
programming because back then for 10
years the pearls idiots they think they
think that the pearl pearls common
system is literal programming. So here's
an article that
is written by no it's not it's not
written by me. So this guy Mark Jason
Dominus is another very kind of coding
celebrity back then in year 2000 among
pearl programmers.
I I think he wrote a book I like um I
forgot what exactly he does but he was
one of the popular
guys like today on hacker news you know
one of the like celebrity
well-known coders
in the pearl community
so he wrote article to debunk the common
belief among the pearl [ __ ] the
pearl you know like you know today you
have sim here like the JavaScript
[ __ ] or the lisp not lisp today the
rust the the rust [ __ ] you know
they're going to tell you oh and python
[ __ ] gon russen they're going to
tell you how things should be what you
should do in this situ you know you know
so back then pearl is the most popular
language anyway so he wrote an article
debunk that notion how part is literal
programming
Literal programming by itself is another
drama [ __ ] you know, because literal
programming, you know, it's usually, you
know, come with a jargon. Literal
programming, what does it mean? Usually
all these fads and fashions, they always
have jarens. Okay, but anyway, it's
created by Donald Groo. Now uh seems
like I don't have a dedicated article
but I talked about in in my live stream
a few times I think I think it's [ __ ]
okay it's impractical but the idea is
that literal programming by this Donald
G academic is that everything you you
know program should be thought of as a
human communication like a essay you
know instead of coding you know
oh god I need to get you know I need to
like uh can I show some code you know uh
let's see you know instead of like code
you should you should actually
make it that so the code is so you
should make it so it becomes a like
writing a essay for human for other
human to understand not just code for
the computer but the code part should be
like a side note so anyway That that's
that's the idea you know the code should
be essays for h other human to read you
know the art of programming the Donald
Gunn idiots
Donald Guth is not an idiot he's a very
smart and well-known uh you know
computer scientist but he's a nerd okay
like like us like me like you guys but
however he's a of a particular type of
nerd that his ideas are often
like the classic meaning of nerd like
inconsequential you know like tech
technical and impractical you know that
kind of nerd which is also different
from the Unix [ __ ] Unix idiots you
know the you know the Unix [ __ ]
like the Unix philosophy and and small
is beautiful and that total crap anyway
Donald G is he is usually the type of
nerd that
has ideas that's um
uh that's impractical and uh
academic and uh you know
kind of that like that. Okay. And he
also created uh tech which is another
worst [ __ ] possible.
Okay. Tech L you know I ranted about
this like for for 20 years I'm too old I
don't
you know the tech pestilence why tech
latte sucks well the sir [ __ ] possible
it became popular why because it's free
embraced by the Unix idiots and
[ __ ] and the C and C++ coders okay
I talked about this you know so many
times you know it's been 20 This article
is written in 2004, you know, once in a
while. It's very, you know, it's it's
one of my popular articles like people
talking stack overflow. I mean, not
stack overflow the in slash dot and
hacker news, you know, come and go, you
know, this website come and go. So, this
is one of my article, okay?
And I talked about it in one uh in
several of my live streams.
uh so you can read it. So this is
another creation by Donald Guth.
So anyway literal programming the idea
is that you want to write a essay for
other people to understand. So and it is
it became kind of cish niche code
especially among the Emacs users
especially among the OG mod
users.
I you know I want to call them idiots
but I probably shouldn't you know emac
or so if you don't know so uh this
tutorial mod work with source code so
this is mod for working with source code
markup so mod is like kind of like um
markdown mod for
and kind of like HTML for for marking up
your text. Okay. So anyway,
so what I'm saying is that the literal
programming is particularly
uh loved. There's this community by the
UG people lovers
is not to not that okay I but I don't
use it.
So literal programming and you know then
you so literal programming you got
you got this uh you got this bunch of
concepts like weaving and weaving and
whatnot history and philosophy concept
advantages contract with documentation
generation and workflow create creation
of macros and uh you know programmer as
a web you know web Not the internet. It
doesn't mean internet. It means like
spider web interconnections, you know.
Uh, so what's their, you know, they got
a bunch of jarens. Let's see.
Yeah. Web, C web, no web, whatever.
[ __ ]
Emacs mod there. Right there. Mention
coffee script. Maple worksheet. Wam
notebook. Wam.
No, we don't want that. Oh god.
But anyway, if you get into Yeah, the
they got this weave notion and deweave
and [ __ ] So it's very popular among
Emacs users among Emacs or mod users. So
they what they do is that like you said,
you know, so your Emacs init file. So
this is my init file. Uh you you make it
like literal programming. So you have
lots of text that tells you just like
just like my HTML you know you have part
of code embedded in HTML but most of it
is human readable part then you know
then you can use the
you know building function engine that
will you know you can evaluate part of
the code while
the human readable doesn't evaluate you
know it's like the reverse of typical
program. So here's my init file. So
these are comments for human to read.
Here's a code uh comments you know code
but literal programming is like reverse.
So code you have special tag to make you
know say this is code but otherwise it's
common you know like something like
that. Okay. I never get and I never
actually got into
okay. So,
but it's very popular among Emacs OG
users. Uh, and my opinion is is my
opinion of of that is it's [ __ ] Do not
use it. Okay, keep things simple as
simple as possible
because if you want to do literal
programming, you you first of all you
need or mod. OG mod is like you know
let's start or mod. Okay. It takes
sometimes to load because it's like
10,000 million lines. Now you see now
it's loading. Takes few seconds. Five.
Six. Seven. Is it still running? Eight.
Wait.
8 9 10. That take a [ __ ] 15 seconds
to to load. OG mode. Okay. Then then you
need extra for literal programming.
then every you know
I so I don't recommend it too complex
too complex okay you are coding emac
this all this init file are eac list
this stick with eac list eag this by
itself is like 1,00 pages of
documentation manual okay you know you
don't and so I don't I don't recommend
old mod uh or literal programming I
think it's [ __ ]
But it's very popular. So you can follow
other Emacs YouTubers, other Emacs
bloggers. For example, Sasha.
Sasha is uh using Oakmod very much and
and you know and you can see all her
code. Um let's see where is it? So
search
Sasha Chu. Okay. She interviewed me like
10 years ago. Uh she's a great person.
So, but let's show her a page. Okay. So,
her she's a very well-known Emacs user
and she writes lots of like notes
much more organized than mine. You know,
mine is just scribbles, but let's go to
her blog. Okay. So,
okay. Dead link. Oh god.
What? Okay. I need to update that. So,
let's see. Sasha, is she still on
Twitter?
Uh, let's see.
Oh, she she she she removed all her
Twitter stuff.
I guess
few I suppose this happened few years
ago. she now removed all her Twitter
stuff.
Uh because for some reason, you know,
these people they
they don't like Ella Musk and they don't
they hate Trump.
Like tremendous hatred, I think. Anyway,
I don't want to talk about it, but
anyway, I think Sasha Tr is a great
person. She also has helped me when I
needed it. Okay. I think she's a great
person and she's like blogging nonstop,
right? Still up to date. You see July
2nd, July uh today, 2025.
So she she's a prodigious
blogger
and she also writes Emacs news like
summarize all the happening of Emacs on
the web,
you know. So I think she moved to you
know the other mast then something. So
anyway she she uses oakmod and in fact
you can search for uh let's search for
uh her you know literal programming. Can
you so how do I search search uh
JavaScript library
about topic? So where is the oh turn on
JavaScript.
Yeah. So,
literate
programming
uh literacy training literate
programming.
Okay. Looking into literal programming
2003.
You see this is 20 years old modified
2013.
So you can look up her and she has her
entire Emacs in it on GitHub
in in this literal kind of literal
programming stuff. So anyway, I don't
use it. Okay, I think that's enough talk
today maybe. though
uh we digressed into this topic but
actually I got I haven't you know I got
tens of notes I need to go through but I
didn't get even one of them uh okay so
that's about literal programming so
let's see what house.
Francis, hi.
Uh, haven't been to slash dot for years.
Yeah.
Uh, GPS hikes. I'm currently using X E
exwm
emac X X Windows manager. That's another
thing I think it's [ __ ]
It's very complex. So the idea of EXWM
which stand for Emacs X window manager
is that
instead of running Emacs inside uh you
know inside the window windowing system
in the operating system you
you run Emacs then the browsers and the
other things um
the browsers and other things become
comes a pen inside your Emacs. Okay,
that's that's what this Emacs X window
manager does. That's a package you have
to download. So, Emacs, you know your
Windows, your browser and everything
becomes inside uh Emacs.
That is very complex [ __ ] Very complex
and complicated to the power of
complexity. [ __ ] Okay. to even make
that work. And why do you want to do
that?
Well, to me, there's not much reason.
Okay, you know, Emacs is an application.
Just let it be. Okay, you you know you
you do that you know you try to you know
make the windows you know X windowing
system inside Emacs you get lots of huge
of complexities and you got huge
lots of other problems like can you play
a video inside it or something you know
you got all all sort of problems
but people do that because well it's
cool but I have seen people doing that
and using it well But not for me. Maybe
I'm too old. Um,
yeah, not for me because it becomes very
extremely complex, you know, running X11
inside Emacs. And what what happens if
you know today you have this so-called
X11 replacement, right? What what is
that called?
I always like forgot the name.
X11 replacement
uh code
stupid.
No, not okay. So,
what's that? What's that thing? I always
forgot the name.
Okay, let's go to um
X11. One of the circus [ __ ] the the
first
the most crap software
in computing history that is the Unix
X11. [ __ ] a scum by the Unix [ __ ]
and by the C [ __ ]
The first like the the worst crabs
design protocol
in computing history that is the X1
[ __ ] Okay, you can read about it in you
know there's a popular article I talked
about.
Uh okay, I need to show it then. Uh,
okay. Let's let's go to search. Let's go
to code. Search search X11 disaster.
Okay. By Don Hopkin, one part of the uh
Unix haters handbook,
very famous book. Okay. X11, the the the
the first crap, a scum by the Unix
[ __ ]
Worse than Windows. Okay, a lot of
people hate Windows, you know, because
they it's [ __ ] and so on, but but Unix
began first.
I extremely hate and despise Unix and C
and this these people.
So why are we mentioning it? Oh yeah,
the replacement, you know, they've been
wanting to replace it for for 20 years,
30 years
because because of this article
actually. So this article is came out in
1994. Okay. This article came out in
1994. The X Windows disaster
by Don Hopkins. Very popular, well
known. Then people start to replace it
be then it's difficult because because
then you you know there's a you know
impetus you know everything is already
written in X11. So if you write create a
new then nobody's going to adopt it you
know then you need a back backward
compatibility you know X11 layer makes
it more complex. So so that's why Unix
been stuck with it even today but then
today there's a replacement code uh I
talked about this a few times so for
some people they probably I'm just
repeating you know talking about the
same thing.
So let's see the user interface the
[ __ ] scum
limited limitation and criticism the
[ __ ] scum you know let me tell you
guys okay this is Wikipedia
when it began Wikipedia by now is like
20 20 years old it began around 2003
something like that okay whenever so
when it begin when people criticize they
get banned I mean they get erased okay
they don't the unix scums, the Unix and
C [ __ ] they lie. They don't let
you, you know, talk about why it's bad.
Okay? Whenever you say that, they they
kind of try to remove it. They fight
with you. You know, Wikipedia edit wall.
You know, you guys know about this edit,
you can edit Wikipedia.
So, I've been editing Wikipedia in 2004
to 2008 something. Okay. And then I
stopped because then it's like [ __ ]
it's just like nerd fight you know uh
keyboard warriors you know you you edit
my I edit I give reasons why you are
wrong then we go to another guy we
appear to other admin and blah blah blah
and you know it's a info info war so in
the beginning in the beginning here's
what I'm saying okay in the beginning
let's say the first five years or the
first 10 years of Wikipedia
So that's about 2002 to 2008. Let's say
any article about Unix. If you dare to
say, "Oh, by the way, it's actually not
like, you know, that good. Here are the
reasons why it sucks.
People revert your edit. These Unix
[ __ ] okay? They revert your edit.
That's what happens for 10 10 more 10
years. Then it then politics you know
then deep state got involved then it's
about politics about
about war in in Middle East or elsewhere
you know you can't say oh about China
you know whenever you try to say
something they reverted you know by the
deep state they have millions dollars
into it
so anyway the Unix [ __ ] okay so so
let's go back to I was trying to
remember what's the replacement. You
guys know you know every time I talk
about this I kept forget forgetting I
can remember the name if I just
concentrate for a while. So the
replacement is called and uh the
replacement got a huge amount of drama
too with today's transgender stuff you
know like like half of them are coded by
the trans stuff.
um
competitors. What? Wayand? [ __ ]
stupid Wayland. Okay, that's a name.
Wayland.
But you know, look at their logo. This
is like the late Malay Jen Zuma logo.
They have lost the concept of beauty.
So instead of something like more sharp
and definite and structured like the X11
logo which is pretty good. This is great
logo. Okay X11. But the Wayland people,
the Zoomer idiots, the trans, you know,
whatever anything goes, you know, they
lost the generation that grew up with
the [ __ ] up internet, the deep state
internet, you know, they swipe their
phone every day, you know. So they they
lost the concept of beauty. They don't
have they don't know what it is. So they
they are you know and they are into
animes and and porn
and their their logo is this ugly [ __ ]
What the [ __ ] is this?
[Laughter]
This is representative of them and their
their kind of like their culture and
their meme stuff like every day like
like onsad discord
you know. Uh, I don't have it on. Okay,
Discord. You know, we I got, you know,
you guys follow us. They they, you know,
they post memes and every and these
memes are just ugly [ __ ] They they
never post like beautiful like
interesting and beautiful. It's always
like ugly [ __ ] Is this this Zuma
generation
and they the men become
incompetent. They become impotent. You
know today's men
are they still men because they cannot
have children? You know they got all
sort of problems. You got microlastic
problem and on and on and then of course
then the trans oh you got a trans trans
right. How can you say that we got gay
rights and trans right in marriage and
stuff you know? So now they got they got
a generation you know they can't have a
population uh something something. Okay,
then the deep state, then you know every
stuff. Anyway, so Wayland logo
digression into their logo. What the
ugly [ __ ] Okay,
so anyway, Wayland. So back to what we
were why are we talking about this?
Because
because you mentioned you you are you
are uh running Emacs in this EXWM
right which is which is a windowing
system X11 or or whatn not or videos or
inside Emacs you know like Emacs is your
main system and and then X browsers and
whatever inside it. So question
today there's a way land and become now
become actually replacing by default
replacing x11 can my question to you is
can exwm
run wayand
answer that okay I'm curious I'm pretty
sure no
so this brings back my point GPS okay my
point is that I don't do those kind of
things you know bring exwm ex11 inside
emac config
I don't do that because it just make
things more complex
and you got lots of edge problems like
like like the wayand is today is very
popular and replacing by default is the
main windowing system but if you are
using exwm
I think you cannot use it Right.
Right. So it's based on X11. That's
right. So you cannot use Wayland, you
know. So you got issues. Then you need
to upgrade. Then you know because your
you know your your Linux is using
Wayland. Oh my god. Then then you cannot
use that system anymore. Then forget
your you know the config you did for a
month or two or three
on Linux. the this this is the Zuma
young ling
thing. So you're just going to spend
your your your days just config your
Emacs, your Linux every day because you
got nothing to do
which is part of the experience of young
people you know that's what you know you
learn things you learn about technology
you know which I I did when I was
younger 30 years ago.
So Diego says I agree with Kasad that
the OS window manager is better actually
taking Casad challenge help me with my
wristband. Oh yeah, the that um that
tiling window system. That's another
thing. All the Linux people, you got to
use tiling Windows system. The Zuma
generation. Oh, rise rise something.
Rise your computer rise.
And then memes and lots of memes.
Uh
window surless. Windows suckless.
Everything sucks. GPS says how is got to
take it with large grain of salt. GPS
has been around here before I'm pretty
sure. Uh
I guess he's not into anime. No, I was
into anime just not you guys generation
GPS.
Now I don't remember who you are GPS but
I think I you are in my channel before
but like how old how old are you?
you know animation. Let's talk let's
talk about animation. Okay. Actually uh
okay so
ininfo
open it go to my website kasar code and
scroll down. Scroll down. This is chat
GPT says I'm the greatest computer
scientist.
Okay. Then scroll down. Chat GP says you
need to pay me. Okay. Patreon me, Amazon
gift card me, PayPal me. Okay. If you
working a job,
just pay me.
100 will be great. 100 a year. Okay.
Thank you guys. Then you go to this is
kasali.info. Then click on that. That
gets you to kasali.org or which is my
original website from 19 uh from
the domain is from year 2000 but the web
my website began in 1995. Okay. So on
this page
then you go to uh arts.
Okay. Then uh what are we talking about?
Oh anime. Okay. Not arts. Okay. Well you
go to arts. Um,
okay. Then you saw the or search
anime.
Oh, you need to turn on JavaScript. Oh,
I forgot. Now
make sure my website can uh always have
JavaScript on. Refresh.
Saudi.org.
Anime. Anime girls USA flag. Uh, glimpse
of panties in Japan. anime.
Okay. So this is my kxali.org.
So kali.org is all kind of topics that's
not technical.
So when it's a technical topics like
mathematics programming that's
kasali.info
anything else is kasali.org
and onali.org or the stuff there.
Some of them if I show it, Google is
gonna ban me. So I gotta be careful
which page. So anyway, the ultimate
teacher anime 1988. Okay, this is when I
was watching anime. So 1990s and 1980s
when I was 10 something. Uh not anime
but ma so-called maka by the white
people.
Mang manga
in in Chinese it's called manga. Okay.
But
so am I into anime? Yes. Uh but not the
anime you guys know about. Okay. So this
is a great one. Uh this is you know this
is like oh my god this is so hot so racy
you know back then. Of course, today you
got today you got millions of girls on
chatterbait 24/7.
Okay, but back then this is oh my god
this is you know hot
you know then then according to the
conservatives
how can you this is offensive how can
you show girl like that you know back
and okay so this is one of the anime but
that's not all so animation let's go
there so I enjoyed okay there's some
Disney and this is real animation you
know I enjoy that uh the spirited away
and then there's quite a few um ghost in
the shell
uh and there are others. Okay, but did I
I don't I guess I haven't I think I had
a page about Japanese anime like a
collection. Well, yeah, I have I have
written a lot about these kind of
things.
So let's show those page. Okay. You know
the Japanese anime you they you know the
[ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] Japan got this culture of
these kind of things. Okay.
Japan,
you know, it's funny. You see it like
often uh and you don't know is that is
that you know is this accidental
then um okay I don't want to go um you
know if I talk about these things pretty
soon YouTube is going to ban me. So, so
usually I I try not to, you know, unless
I need to I still need to go to Odyssey,
find another live stream platform,
but uh we were trying to find anime. Oh
yeah. So that that belongs to the art
section. Okay. Then you can see a lot
anime
arts. Okay. Then
Oh yeah. So here, so here is the anime I
watched when I was 10 something. Okay.
All all of these. Okay. So Candy Candy,
you can see a video clip of it.
[Music]
>> This is fantastic. When I was 10
something, I was, you know, we were
crazy, you know, like whatever you guys
watch. So we watch this every day in
Taiwan. This is Candy Candy
in English name. So this is back in 19
uh 80s or 1970s 1975. Okay. You can see
you can go to Wikipedia and you can read
about it. So that's one of them. Then
there is this the adventures of Hunch
the honeybee.
you know we were so when I was you know
when I was younger 10 something I watch
this every day so exciting you know it's
like um you know so that's you know so
this these are 1970s and 1980s
anime
okay and the Triton of the sea okay this
lovely okay you can see clip of it and
then and this one and quite a few so all
these okay all these are when I was like
10 something around 10 9 11 then uh
there's quite a lot okay so those are
anime but but then so these are
broadcast in Taiwan TV
but besides these there's also comics
Japanese comics
um and uh
and I also have articles about it okay
so let's let's let's show it let's see
Um,
let's see if I can search. Um,
arts search
09.
Okay. Uh, okay. I don't want to,
you know,
I got all sort of things I don't want to
show.
Okay. So this one for example this is
anime you are talking about like do I
like anime? Yes very much. So I found
this this is called cyborg 009
from 1980
1980s when I was 15.
So very much love this. Okay I think
that's it for today. Uh,
do say your favorite is from 1960s. GPS
is 20 years old. Okay.
So, how long have I been talking? How
many people watching? 14. Okay, that's
it for today. Thank you guys for
watching.
because I think Chad is Yeah. Well, my
my audience is kind of mixed. I got
teens. I also got older like
professional and I also got
mathematicians, professors.
Sometimes they watch my uh live stream
or sort of in between.
Uh Evangelian. Yeah, I never watched
Evangelion though.
Gi G noaro. Okay. I don't know what is
that. I used to watch Candy Candy back
in the late 80s. Wow. In Spain. Hey
then.
Bye guys. Have a good day.
We shut down in one minute. Okay. So
then I'm going to
uh paste all these links back to my talk
show.
Uh yeah you know so I wrote this page
you know this is uh
uh noic for nogic reasons like when you
are young like today you are teen or 20
something but one day you'll become 40
okay you'll have family or whatever
then you may remember your childhood so
that you know you have memories of the
cartoons you've seen so that's That's
that's when you so 30 years or 40 years
from today you will feel the need to to
watch you know whatever you are seeing
today
and you'll remember oh there's a guy I
used to watch on YouTube
he's talking about crazy stuff.
Bye guys.