welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh today's topic is going to be one of
these oh just ask me questions and I'll
talk about it so these are the topics
I'm going to post in view youtube video
information there and just look at it
and let me know what you want me to talk
about let me say something here
poor type topic hi guys
one person watching good morning this is
here is California time 11:30 in San
Francisco for those of you don't know I
mean something I mean I'm in Mountain
View which is which is a city that is
about 40 minutes drive south of San
Francisco in USA of course and the face
I live is is known as Silicon Valley
that's where all the Google Facebook
Apple PayPal you know other major web
companies are at so today I'm going to
talk about things talk about things and
so it can be Emacs it can be technical
or it can be non-technical tech
technical means Emacs javascript
programming languages and so on and also
it I can cover the programming culture
those celebrities you know the Emacs the
Richard Stallman Kaido yeah actually I'm
going to talk about Kaito Kaito is the
inventor of the Python language and he's
well simply put I don't like he I don't
like he's the way he think about things
I mean that that many his ideas about
Python so I don't like Python and hey
Scott good morning great to see you
hey Duncan so I mean your conference
call with my peers in Santiago the
opposite cause to me Oh conference call
how can you join the video in the
meantime then I mean aren't you okay
great
Scotland oh my god from Scotland yeah
I've never been to Europe so I don't
know much of anything about Europe but I
you know I know that Scott you know the
the Scotland and the England the United
Kingdom is a bit complex you know
there's a complicated relations like
this the there is this guy on YouTube GP
Quay I think something like that so he
did a video explaining you know all the
countries in UK United Kingdom and Irish
you know the I get confused but about
that okay so Scott so do you want to
talk about Emacs like yeah you I
remember you asked me about doing a
Emacs demo I mean something you know how
I work flow oh actually Scott you know
what you know soon you know maybe next
week or next few day this week you know
we should do a conference hang out
together I mean it's it's up to you we
can do it hang out together just you and
me or I can like kind of like invite you
you know to be a guest on a talk show so
you know we're gonna be chatting you
know and people yeah you know we can do
it like we can do it so that I interview
you and you're gonna show us your Emacs
knowledge yeah you know your and and
your you know history and how you use
Emacs
so Scott says I was wondering to you
render your site locally and push it to
the main website yeah exactly yeah in
fact I can show you four so for example
this is my programming block so and
notice the URL it's local file so it's
now I'm going to create a new entry new
entry here today and and for the date
okay
then view in browser you can see it's
there and I'm going to put it to my RSS
you know it's all you max command you
can see the commands on the Left panel
so new entry close that then I'm going
to go to a shell then I just our sink
then if you go to okay so it's uploaded
you know three files updated the XML
file is the RSS file so close it and go
to the browser sorry
Casali dot info so see the programming
blog over here and you can see the new
entry there so that's how I do it hey
green green tag can you talk about UNIX
philosophy like program should do one
thing yeah let's talk about that that
that's that's one of my favorite ranting
topic you know I'm gonna rent long for
hours about UNIX philosophy you know
basically I consider it you know it's
like a coat you know there's no truth
whatsoever it's just a bunch of slogans
and jargons and every program lights
well every the elite kind of hacker type
of program as they all like forward you
know they all spread it all UNIX
philosophy isn't that but anyway UNIX
philosophy you know it kind of died down
I mean the hacker culture and the word
even a word hacker God is not you know
it's not mainstream these days for other
political reasons there's you know the
social justice movement so you know it's
like you cannot be your hacker to be a
hacker is you know like a privilege so
that kind of died out so yeah I'm gonna
talk about that so
[Music]
Scott you cannot use our sink only FTP
or web dev to push the command line so I
mean so are you looking are you looking
for a way to update your site or what I
mean you you have a website or is it for
your work or something like I mean are
you asking a question or are you just
you know commenting by the way
do people still use FTP that died long
ago right and I don't know what is web
day wait web Dave you mean David like
div or DV oh you want to push in a
minimum amount of files then I think is
the right choice I mean what like why
can't you use our sink yeah I don't know
what is web dead the web dev there's a
bug in brave browser anyway so so web
dev Wikipedia web they're web
distributed authoring and versioning is
an extension of the hypertext transport
oh I didn't know that is an extension of
the hypertext Transfer Protocol that
allows clients to perform remote web
content whole thing the web dev protocol
provides a framework for users to create
change or move I never heard of this
before so is there a like a client like
a tool you used to do that hello and and
this is old web dev began in 1996 so
yeah I don't know about these oh yeah
it's been around for a long time so guys
if you have a questions you know just
ask me okay in the YouTube information
box below the video there's the list of
topics oh you can ask you
you can just ask me anything you know
after all this is the talk show so I'm
gonna go you know this is one thing I
want to talk about which is Python the
keidel you know Mercado invented Python
the title character you know I don't
like the Python language as I started to
learn Python in 2005 from Perl you know
I was a professional Perl program I you
know I'm a master Pro but the Perl
cultures you know most people don't know
these days because product but the pro
culture is like okay the Perl culture is
the group is in the same group with the
UNIX philosophy people you know it would
be the so-called hackers type you know
they like you know grant they like
jargons you know like in UNIX you have
all sort of junk jargons cat you know
besides you know philosophy okay there's
UNIX philosophy you have kiss like keep
it simple stupid
you have punch up but you know I'm gonna
talk about that but Perl is kind of in
the same group you know pro people in
UNIX people Pro people they have like a
thousand slogans and jargons you know
like the onion that the onion the the
the state of the onion like they use a
phrase whenever they have a conference
like each year like the state of onion
and the Perl mangas you know mungus and
you know a like huge amount of that like
more they out more than one way to do it
and every programmer is like chanting it
every day
and it's the same way with UNIX
philosophy I mean you don't hear it much
anymore because you know it died out but
that was then so I really I you know I
despised it very much I mean these
people these hacker types I don't I
don't get along with I don't like their
opinions I mean I mean was a person they
are fine I mean I'm a like a nerd you
know I'm like in the same group you know
I am and and I I wallow in UNIX and you
know Solaris UNIX pearl that is what
that is my thing so an open source you
know I never forgot
I never programmed in Microsoft
technologies like I tried to smell a
little bit it you know a few years ago
but just never you know got into it and
also I never programmed the Apple any
any Apple of stuff so you know their
technology their you know API or
whatever so the the programming stuff
I'm into and do every day is basically
well today you just call it open-source
like Python Perl Apache Linux and back
then it's UNIX Solaris hp-ux I actually
ported our software to HP us
hp-ux that's you know that's HP's UNIX
you know back then there you have also
have AIX which is IBM's Unix
you have Eric's Eric's is the SGI's UNIX
you know they kind of all died you know
of course you know so Microsystems died
part by Oracle and so on so um you know
that there's one thing about them you
see all these UNIX is they end with X as
as kind of a unsaid unsaid agreement you
know because it's fun you know you have
all these operating systems ending X and
also there's PASOK's
by the way PASOK's POS IX POSIX is a
actually a standard for for unix-like
systems and by the way UNIX is also a
trade trademark and and in order for
your operating system to be called UNIX
or UNIX like I think I am not sure but
you have to like test your certificate
and this is a commercial I mean kind of
I mean this is a greedy org you know but
anyway the interesting thing about that
is Microsoft Microsoft Windows NT
actually passed the UNIX certificate
you know they submit you know and you
have to pay money I think and so they
passed it so Microsoft NT it's actually
UNIX technique is freaking and you know
so you got this passed
in UNIX that you know PASOK's in UNIX
certificate and also keep the comments
coming okay I'm gonna read it every few
minutes so you got all these UNIX
operating systems and what was I going
to say then they yeah so I mean the UNIX
so you know you got this bunch of UNIX
and I forgot what I was going to say
pass a key okay anyway POSIX is not
really an operating system it's just a
standard and it's pretty bad I mean it's
like all the geeks well not today but
other it kicks back then also IFC like
every FC every every [ __ ] kick is
gonna tell talk about IFC everyday you
know when you when you would talk about
some subject or you know some missions
and problems in programming assisted me
they all say oh read IFC this this isyes
is one of the worst specification and
and it's also anyway so you know I have
been you know in a UNIX community for
well III began in an industry industrial
programming since 1998 you know starting
with Perl and Solaris on Solaris and in
MySQL and Oracle database and Apache and
but I develop so I and you see the UNIX
does this kind of people this group of
people hackers types you know it
attracts it attracts me because I'm I'm
you know one of them you know you can
say that literally so I never you know I
never went to Microsoft you know
although i don't i don't hate microsoft
you know most almost every of the unix
fans they hate microsoft the any
opportunity they are you know they'll
push they all say something like
Microsoft is evil you know Bill Gates
should die you know they say that back
then there's lots of website you know
they want to you know they say like P or
gate I you know something like that
anyway so so
unikz people but I don't I don't you
know I don't hate you know Microsoft you
know I
in fact I hate those UNIX people that
hates Microsoft so so what okay so back
to the topic so I was saying you know
I've been you know I wallow in the UNIX
community for like you know 10 20 years
and I don't like them so and they call
me a troll because because I always you
know constantly fight with them you know
oppose their ideas what they say I
disagree but also I do it in a attacking
antagonistic style so you know including
swearing you know I swear all the time
so the many of them call me a troll but
I'm not I mean all the things I say my
opinions that that that is my true
opinions including for example all the
things I just said you know I don't
think I have sees a good good good good
spec for example I think the writing
sucks and I think the IFC community it's
kind of a it was a non-profit oak I
think I mean the the committee that the
way they create things I think it's bad
you know and UNIX of course I hate so
many things about UNIX and the UNIX
philosophy and so on I think it's a code
you know and I have my reasons you know
when I when I kind of you know criticize
name I always list my reasons I mean
even though I swear a lot and you know
sometimes Rambo and you know do things
but but almost always I have I give you
know detailed reasons I mean if you just
remove the swearing the reasons are
there but you know the online you know
if you know even in the back those days
they don't you know like all the replies
they just attack you they don't they
don't read much of the reasons but but
also also the other thing that we the
other reason is that when you criticize
a community let's say you program Python
basically you you you any negative
opinion about Python doesn't matter how
you would it how polite you are is
basically unwelcome same thing with
Emacs any negative opinion about Emacs
emag baseball or Emacs people in general
they are just unwelcome this is the
situation with these hacker type of
communities by the way it's not true in
non hacker type of communities by that I
mean for Mike for example Microsoft
programming communities you know there
are of course Microsoft is big and they
are you know huge amount of in fact much
more people in that community as well as
JavaScript and PHP for example these are
two great examples for example
JavaScript and PHP these two unknown
hacker languages every hacker hates them
you know despise them at any opportunity
they all say bad things about JavaScript
and PHP because why because the hacker
they have some kind of elite attitude
because they see this they think this is
really bad you know javascript is really
bad you don't want to use it and same
thing with a PHP well it's true they are
bad but anyway that's another topic you
know we you know but anyway so the
hacker people the what was I going to
say yeah basically they form a coat you
know so what I'm saying is I so this
coach situation happens in Unix
in Perl very much UNIX Perl in in these
communities especially Common Lisp okay
and UNIX Perl Lisp in let's see in
Python okay he also impact on
communities but however it's almost
non-existent this code kind of mentality
or hackers they they they do not exist
in PHP community like none well I'm
talking about at least thing I mean ten
years ago I don't know about today I
don't know about the past five years you
know things have changed you know
javascript has become something else you
know so javascript today there is kind
of a little code formation but anyway
but let's I'm talking about the year
2000 okay so you you don't have any code
kind of mentality in PHP community you
don't have any of that in JavaScript
community because these two communities
live needs they begin their language is
you know not that elite hackers they are
not from some elite hackers you know we
gonna you know create this language that
you know that's the best of everything
it's not the or engine you know they are
just PHP for example is just from a
teenager who wants to create his
homepage pretty homepage that's original
acronym okay pretty homepage in my
pretty homepage you know they created a
script using Perl and I became PHP and C
and similarly JavaScript is from you
know Brendan Brendan Oh Brenda what's
his name Brendan Eich you know he
created JavaScript back in Netscape you
know but anyway I'm not going to be into
history about that but anyway the
arrangement I mean the original
intention of javascript is for the I
mean it's for dynamic HTML and but the
context is that so that well it's
designed to be like easy language for
beginners to learn you know so it's not
like elite you know it's not like Oh
tail recursion Oh monad you know that at
every culture you know list
comprehension you know this the codes
like the the codes kind of people like
all these they spread all these things
every day so JavaScript and it's
designed for you know kind of like that
beginner you know who don't know how to
program it's designed for them to use
you know so they you know so they never
had you know it is you know in the first
fifteen years it doesn't have you know
the elite code mentality so and every
hacker despises him to this day today
you know Java and
and it's funny this is very interesting
it's funny both PHP and JavaScript
became the most popular language of them
all
thank you know like a slap to the hacker
coats you know the PHP became the number
essentially basically the number one
depending on how you count you know the
number one the most popular language
throughout mm I don't know about today
today is still top 5 okay
for example Facebook they you know PHP
could you know technically speaking the
language has lots of problems right but
the but the Facebook you know the that
guy you know Zuka but he doesn't know he
doesn't know how to code so you use PHP
and then he build his empire you know he
says come by the way he P or the Empire
and now you know they're growing going
billions billions millions you know you
know dollars a so they and they use PHP
and they create a new language of PHP
which is called hack hacklin you know so
so PHP so when so anyway so you know PHP
is like became the number one most
popular language and same thing with
JavaScript it became you know number one
language I mean so if you think if you
think about this you know it's quite
interesting you know how is that the
situation you know these hackers you
know you know the language they despise
they became the greatest you know the
most popular language but anyway so UNIX
philosophy I'm gonna talk about let's
say UNIX philosophy you know I have like
I have more a few hundred articles on
UNIX philosophy it's it's you know it's
my grant you know I for all the things I
talked about you know like I have Co AG
I have lots of all of us yeah let me
just go to it quick readin sorry dot
info this this great browser bug by the
way by the way bribe is a great browser
it's also invented by the brain brain
then I guy who created JavaScript so you
got excited that info go to programming
and on the left you can see entire
hacker year to K now this our collection
of articles this this these articles are
pretty old
they are mostly written in 2000 but
anyway sorry UNIX philosophy okay
and sorry sorry UNIX pestilence okay
I mean I'm I want to show you some
articles I've written and I'm going to
talk about them so so unique special
attention so it's I mean let me get
articles ready
yeah around second the nature of UNIX
philosophy okay dad that is a one that's
a prime everyone I'm going to talk about
the UNIX philosophy and it's okay let's
open another one
sorry Microsoft hatred you know about
the Microsoft hatred if you if you lived
through the 2000s you know you know you
know it but if you are younger than you
probably don't know but it's funny you
know you see how how we you know hackers
you know hate Microsoft but however
today Google Facebook is like few times
more evil than Microsoft back then and
Microsoft today it is actually becomes
the most contributor to open source you
know things change you know like in many
ways is sad you know anyway so you know
Google was the great you know to no evil
company we supported in I support ice so
much support at Google you know you know
that for the first ten years but today
it became so extremely evil
I mean blatantly lie and to devious
things you know techniques you know to
and and with their ads and browser I
mean I mean not not just not just a
decision you don't like it's like they
they go underhand you know they try to
bypass you know law or my I'm not sure
about buy pepper by passing laws yet but
they do you know also the things that
you know evil and yeah for example they
they they monitor you know everyone is
using you know phone right Android
that's owned by Google so they monitor
your every movement and even
you turned off all the you know privacy
you checkmark you know you don't want
them to track you they still do
you know they just then then when the
new spoke out they will just say oh it's
a mistake
oh we put the battery we put a you know
microphone in this device by mistake
it's not our intention you know it keeps
happening okay so back to the UNIX
philosophy I'm going to talk about but
let me read the comments let's see by
the way keep the comments going okay so
I know you know I know I'm going you
know I don't want to like going into a
direction that's just you know of
interest to myself you know so so let's
see let's see the comments so Duncan
says Rob Pike say something like the
UNIX philosophy is already dead and it's
funeral yah eulogy its funeral eulogy
was delivered that's interesting I
haven't seen that code before yeah and
not opposed also dead ok Scott says the
way I do it is this touch a time stamp
on file P odesite and use NC FTP with
any files new ok but what what I mean
what crying are you using as far as I
know web tab web table is a protocol
right I mean what tool you used to sink
your site I mean and why can't you use a
sink why is our sink not available
ok I'm gonna read the next comment I
think you can do webdive a simple file
manager okay
so Duncan says I think Mac OS is
currently certified UNIX and Linux isn't
funny since hardly anyone runs Mac OS on
service yeah that's true
yeah you know it's it's kind of you know
I to me okay this is my perception you
know always search for yourself you know
because okay so so I I don't like I you
know at this echo you know the UNIX type
of people right but so to to me the
situation you know today we have Linux
you know Linux is a free office
operating system you know it's it's free
you can get it for free but it's also
you know so called you know free
software foundation you know and open
source and that is great you know when
in a beginning in 2000 we have a vision
like you know we have a vision you know
UNIX is going to replace Windows and
Microsoft is going to perish in ten
years and that didn't happen you know
and also Linux you know the Linux you
know even so it's open source but you
can see people fighting each other all
the time you know you have so many you
know in a Linux Linux for first of all
you have so many distributions you know
it's not okay you you might think okay
oh it's peaceful co-existence not really
the fact they really fight each other
even though they cannot make money but
they do but actually you I mean
well if you cannot make money you do it
you get Fame and when you have Fame and
you became popular you make money you
know that's that's many of the
open-source projects that's the way or
you go into the crowd you know crowd is
a service so you cannot say you know I
am NOT an open-source you know I'm just
running a service anyway so it means
Linux you see you have so many
distributions then within one
distribution you have so many so called
window managers okay and and and
constantly every year you know oh you
know you have group within them they
fight you know it's a political fight
it's not just you know we I disagree
with
your technical you know philosophy it's
not just that it's the they fight
politically no for power that's what
happens that's so you know back then I
was a fan of Richard Stallman I was like
a fanatic you know I have been banned in
a Mac Manning list because they call me
a Richard Stallman fanboy and you know
not today I of course I think reaches so
many is is I think he's still a good guy
but his speeds is no good so I know you
know so back then I was a Richard storm
and Fanny and I also am Pro Free
Software Foundation I'm anti the open
source I mean they they are at war right
I talked about this in previous talk
shows you know a few times so they are
at war but I'm very much on the Richard
Stallman side that was back then in fact
I have wrote an article you can see a
quote you can see my mentality back then
so so unique specimens pestilence listen
this is an article I wrote back in 2003
but anyway if you you know I was talking
about back then you know internet is not
like today there's no Wikipedia yet
I mean 2003 you know Wikipedia maybe
just began so you don't have the
information like when you
there's no Stack Overflow there's no
reddit there's no hacker news okay back
then the only thing you have is slash
dot so and and there's no resources like
if you want to document a ssin for
others are things you look you try to
find you know maybe some programmers has
blogged about it you know it's still
very well you know like there's no does
not even concept a blog yet you know
there's no plug-in yet so I was written
writing this article it's half rent and
hot have a collection of good resources
for UNIX you know the documentation
resources repository resources you know
there there's no github backing and
there's no this not even centralized
you know code repository except Perl you
know
so you know it's a collection of
resources but but it's also grant a lot
of it is rent and and over the years you
see how Susi kind of you know died
debian you know it's not you know you
know so today the most popular is Ubuntu
writing Ubuntu also became greedy you
know they create their cloud and you
know let me I mean that's a course that
is a natural course when you derived
people of the I mean when you when you
want communism essentially that like the
free software foundation open-source
when you prevent people making money
they they do what they can you know to
to to to to to do that because otherwise
nobody do a thing you know I mean the
idea is everyone contribute you know you
if you have money or something if you
have time you contribute but yeah in
reality you know you don't so we had so
anyway so I was going to oh this girl is
beautiful this goes this is back in 2000
Linux word conference and she's dressed
as a BSD daemon and Apple this is owed
Apple logo bleeding bleeding rainbow
yeah and mac os/x you know you know the
X stand for 10 like it's a Roman numeral
10 but you see but they don't call it
Mac OS 10 because you know they want to
like in sync with a UNIX culture you
know I Rex AIX hp-ux HP u8x
you know Linux you know that's why Mac
OSX so anyway so this one arc I want to
show here good new is not Unix okay now
now remember the name acronym is so
called because if acronym is actually
stupid you know the term the term
recursive acronym is just a term
invented by these geeks okay it didn't
exist in English so you know
all these hacker cultures you know the
hackers oh it's great you know they mean
they get PD they get excited do [ __ ] is
not uniquely sorry it's called recursive
acronym it's like it's like they are
trying to teach you about linguistic so
or English but it's actually just idiocy
idiotic it'sit's it's just they created
this thing and they they they created
this phrase because they've acronym it
doesn't exist
I mean well if you try to look into
history you might dig up you know you
know you're you it's you know often you
can dig up some previous occurrence
before but but practically speaking that
you know the recursive acronym is just
invented by the hacker geeks well anyway
so here is a article I've written so you
can see my mentality back them I'm full
free software foundation I'm against the
open-source camp so you see I says I say
of the open source which is one of the
most poetry idea of humanity of doats
musing poppers feed a offshoot an
outright turncoat of strohman vision and
hardship dressing itself as the mediator
between FSF and businessmen fiddling and
Hawking a pipe dream of its own a part
calling the kettle black thieves and
slouches backseat and in the end is just
another fantastic fat test of the world
that is lingering a sucker of
programmers blood rules for the
enterprising cops disparage incongruous
splash of vapor in nothingness that we
shall see so this is back in 2002 when
the open source and free software
foundation are fighting each other you
know so I was you know you can see I was
very much for free software you know
fold on the Richard Stallman society and
the reason is that you know Richard
Stallman he
that you have the idea you know you know
you have the Morag idea there's a moral
element in the free software foundations
ideology because you want to be good I
mean the key is not just open-source I
mean it's not about you know being able
to look at the source code but rather
it's more important about you know how
you help other people you you know if
you have a software use you you let
other people use it you can see the
source code well I was young then so so
anyway so that that's how i came i mean
i'm mentioning that because i was
talking about something that came to it
but let's go to UNIX philosophy so scott
says by the way I do a lot rent right I
mean that that's wow that's that's why
it's a talk show and and and you know I
talk about my thinking's and my mindset
and and I know for sure many of you like
UNIX you know and you know you don't
think you don't agree with my opinions
that that's totally good I mean you are
here probably because you know a little
bit about me and you want to hear what I
say so anyway let me read the comments
despite the ugly syntax the thing I like
about pearl was that it was easier to
write a script and work on UNIX Windows
and Mac yeah exactly
Python is not the case in in fact Python
documentation you know it's so bad you
know I it's worse than Perl
despite the Perl you know Perl
documentation is full of jargon and kind
of sloppy writing and they enjoy that I
mean they intentionally do it that way
you know full of irrelevant jargons mess
you know messed up with UNIX jargons and
you know stuff that's the nature of pro
but Perot documentation like every few
paragraphs they give you an example you
know they show you how to use it
so I switched from pro to Python because
I'm tired of Perl I don't like this you
know mentality I don't like this garbage
sloppy you know thing I rather prefer
I like formal languages like I prefer
kind of like you know correct as you
might call it correct way you know of
writing or whatever so I switch to
Python and that's a mistake so I'm gonna
I think I'm going to do a talk show
about Python Kaido the person okay I
mean he's not about he's I mean he's a
good person okay
you know I yeah I know he's a good
person but he's opinions he's the way he
write things you know he has certain
like attitude certain passive-aggressive
attitude and the Python documentation is
very bad the writing quality is
extremely poor and in practice too like
you try to find something you cannot
find it and he he's so he's a
passive-aggressive guy you always want
to you know you can see between the
lines in his writings he always want to
tell you something else like he want to
push you know he's like opinion onto you
but so in practice when you went so I
got into Python you know so but him when
you read Python dog it's it's it's less
practical than Perl you know pearl at
least like an OS I can easy trivially
find whatever I need to do there's an
example I mean even I don't like the
syntax all right okay you know but this
always you can find what you want to do
would need to do not so with I found
Python they force you they kind of you
know Kaito and his minions you know well
of course because sky dog created
language you know and he's got followers
so whoever follows him tends to be you
know under his you know influence so you
know agreement with him so he so you
have the Python organization you know
nonprofit and stuff so they create this
pep you know and Geiger Godot is kind of
you know he like things you know he has
a tendency
inclination to like formal you know
formality for example he created this
path you know like it's a committee it's
a procedure you know a formal official
procedure to advance you know Python
language design or you know evolution
you know another jargon pep anyway so
that's about Godot in Python so it's
back to the so yeah if I I'm going to do
I'm probably I want to talk about Python
some another day but when I do that you
know I'm going to give you a lot
examples like example in documentation
or the programming language did and lots
of problems you know the other thing
about the programming code is that when
you are in a programming language code
such as Python Perl Python Perl these
two are particularly severe typically
the UNIX kind of Python Perl and you
know for example not so much in Java not
I don't know about C first first because
I don't code in C password but I don't
think it's it's not that much in Ruby
community but Python and Perl is you
know two good examples of where and
Emacs yeah of course Emacs is a is a
community kind of coat like community
where this coat mentality is very heavy
you know they have like everything well
it's like that so so back to the so
scarce a is certainly one can say that
now that Python Python Ruby
okay tell us why you use four separate
browsers okay yeah it's been like that
for like 20 years
but basically each browser will have a
specific purpose so Google Chrome these
days I used Google Chrome only for
Google accounts nothing else like a
login you know I used you know I don't
visit any other site on Google Chrome
except Google owned stuff like Gmail and
stuff good you know because you know
Google now it's becoming so evil evil
and massively empire you're a massive
Empire I don't know if technically they
are more they have more assets than
Microsoft I don't know if it's that's
technically true I mean you have to look
up you know the economy Act you know
they have numbers I don't know if so I
don't know if that's true but Google you
know they do you have you know the cost
a I machines you know they have the
military they have you know satellites
and you know and you know it's and the
phone is in everyone's pocket so
extremely powerful so I these days I
cannot even trust the Google Chrome
browser okay you don't know you know you
turn on all the privacy features on you
don't want to tracking right even so you
cannot be sure that you know they are
actually you know taking photos of you
every every minute or something you
don't know and also they recently
started I noticed you know they in the
settings preferences I think they
actually have an item that says clean
your hard disk so this is the browser
now they start to get into it they they
want to clean your hardest now so you
click that they're gonna like you know
check your hard disk over for viruses or
something so so I don't trust Google so
I mean I'm still is using Gmail and I
hope to migrate I hope to and also today
you know the social justice happenings
you've you know you've probably have
heard of and the Google is part of
it you know all the technologies and you
know one day if I say something wrong
then Google pencil my account gmail scan
you know that's the situation so I don't
trust Google so that's for Google and
Firefox Firefox I have ever I have
JavaScript turned off
I have cookie turned off everything
turned off so Firefox is my default
browser so anywhere side I visit there's
no JavaScript you cannot do things to me
but mostly actually it turns out mostly
I use JavaScript to mostly I use I mean
mostly I use the Chrome browser just for
local development of my web sites so you
can see all these tabs I'm working on
stuff you know these are the pages I
need to work on that's basically I do
every day they are or you know local
files you can see in the URL field you
know and some linguistic stuff some
writing stuff this is this is
interesting by the way this is the
what's called a log graph where for
example capital letters and lowercase
letters in English they are called
autograph because basically it's a
different graphing that represents the
same thing so but back then s is written
like that like a long F and that is
actually how the integral sign the
history of integral sign so that's
interesting so anyway I use my you know
the my firefox browser for you know web
dev you know like I can just press the
button from Emacs and it switches to
Firefox and it's very fast because
there's no JavaScript Safari are used
for basically mostly just for Twitter
because I have to Twitter I have to
three Twitter account but to the two I
use is basically Yoko Emacs let's see
oops I made okay so yeah so Twitter is
Safari are basically used for Twitter
for my Emacs Twitter account but
sometimes for example this my weblog
let's go to Unicode so this this is my
unicode page let's go to emoji so let's
go to hands actually let's go to food
and drink so food a drink
food food and drink now there's no
remember there is no JavaScript but
sometimes I I need JavaScript because I
have JavaScript running on this page so
i i i can open here in Safari Safari has
JavaScript on so you know I can click
you know I got that I wrote the
JavaScript for that but by the way I
want to show these so this is my wait so
you can search Unicode let's see
g-gee are a em so it will show all the
Unicode that contains to what G I am for
example you know and it's turning real
time for example let's say W a tea water
all the Unicode characters whose Unicode
name contains the name water so T ha and
you can type in other words that filter
out let's say melon so if you type water
space melon you got watermelon so you
know you if you like it you know
if you write blogs link link to it help
me out
so that's so that's why I use Safari
sometimes for this purpose and the brave
browser the primary I use it for my
Twitter but also for anything I click on
Twitter you know when new solder goes so
by default the JavaScript is off but I
can turn it on if I want to that's
that's a good thing about three browser
great browser is a browser build the the
engine it uses is the same as google
chrome the purpose of Brahe browser is
that today the add you know tracking is
getting out of hand because the web was
not designed for you know ads in
JavaScript in JavaScript you know when
you want to put ads in your website
basically you caveats a snippet of
JavaScript you put it there so
essentially it's like you know you grab
code it's like putting a virus in you in
your website that's you know and so it's
very difficult extremely difficult to
for security you know to do security
correctly so the idea very browser the
guy brand and what's his name P re and D
Brendan Eich this guy so I'm following
him so he created the brave browser the
the intention is that to revolutionize
to read of rid of the the previous
generation you know the the ad tracking
all that stuff so he is trying to create
a new platform for the internet for the
web sobre browser by default it filter
out all ads or ads or tracking just by
default its building into the browser
and he also creates a system where
purpose Ashoka but publishers can
benefit by cryptocurrency I think I
haven't looked into that much but so
he's trying to be all this new system
so I recommend to support web browser
you know if you have a geek I'm pretty
sure most of you are you have a tendency
to resist any cooperation like you
prefer you know the free software or
small groups you know you so when you
look at brave you you know you a lot you
know hacker types will say oh you're
cryptocurrencies method is wrong you
know I'm not going to use it I'm happy
with Chrome with you know ad blocker you
know bye-bye this another hacker you
know all right you know that's that's
not a good way to go because do you want
to forever stay you know inning is small
you know hacker group like nobody cares
about you you have to spend hours every
day just to be sure you you know you you
you are free without tracking you know
that's no good instead instead of you
want like you want you want a society
you want a community you can you don't
have to worry you can easily go and get
what you want and do your things without
being tracked in order to do that you
need you know you need society you need
well this unique at least in USA in
Turkey in much of the Western countries
you need companies you need to you know
you need these companies to do that to
have this mentality so you want to when
you when there's something like brave
you want to help you know to support it
you know try try if you can that's
that's what I think I don't have money
to give to break but but you might try
to you know you might think it's a good
idea so what else how long have I been
talking 56 minutes I think I talk 10
more minutes about UNIX philosophy get
to that topic and we'll be done for
today yeah this one one article I want
to talk about which is the UNIX
philosophy proper the meaning you know
yeah I was young yeah so I mean so yeah
the the the the the the question is that
you know it's funny how often the quote
does I was young applies as one as one
discusses past views yeah so logically
you know yeah I mean that's common
saying you know so whenever a person did
in the past you know and okay let's put
it this way whenever a person changed
his point of view then one can easily
say you know oh I was young so it but it
does not necessarily mean that I mean
that the implication is that you know my
opinion the opinion the person had in
the past is just wrong it is wrong
because he's young you know so but it is
actually not necessarily true I mean
everyone gets old so you can you know
whatever you don't like anymore you can
always say oh I was young but it's not
necessarily true yeah
so one more question then I'm gonna talk
about the UNIX philosophy for maybe five
minutes or ten and then that that's it
for today so this question message
I might probably pronounce your name
room but okay so they say he says have
you have you tried dragging files
between systems what do you mean
so for example you have text file in
windows system and want to drag it into
Emacs open in your Linux VNC session do
you think it's possible okay I don't
100% understand the question I suppose
you are running I suppose you are
running Windows and you are using a
virtual VNC what does VNC stand for I
mean I suppose you have some kind you
are using some kind of emulation you
know what's that VirtualBox or something
and the VirtualBox is running Linux and
you want to drag a file from your
Windows desktop to the to the Linux in
running Emacs so is it possible I don't
know but I think in general that's just
not a common feature I mean even even if
it's possible it's not so easily done I
suppose yeah I don't know the I don't
have much experience with that so so the
net so back to the nature of the UNIX
philosophy so the UNIX philosophy is a
jargon that that is widely spread
special especially in night 9:19 1990s
and 2000's so you know typically the
Tonetta net of UNIX philosophy is it's
loose loose you know it's loose there's
no exact definition but typically it is
he says things like small is beautiful
make each program do one thing well
build a prototype as soon as possible
choose portability / efficiency store
data in fire text files yeah so that's a
typical elements of the UNIX philosophy
so-called univee philosophy but ok its
total [ __ ] in my opinion it Y is a
total [ __ ] so in my opinion ok so
it's ok let me explain this way it's you
know every code
there are many codes if you study code
you know you can begin with Wikipedia
and you'll see you know tens of them
some of them are quite large you know
they are powerful organizations for
example Scientology Falun Gong both of
these are international octopus's
powerful you know they even the FBI
cannot do much to them in fact they they
tell FBI what to do
ok there at least that's the case of
Scientology well I don't mean tell FBI
what to do but but they can you know
kind of influence you know so so so the
so if you look into code you know a code
typically you have jargons just like you
the UNIX philosophy oh they have like
rules or whatever they call it you know
you know the yeah yeah I think you get
what you what I mean so the way so so
the way I see this UNIX philosophy is
just like that it's the it's a bounding
things principles or you know things of
the code element but why do what but why
is that so because you see these things
you can never you can never exactly
precisely define what they mean you know
basically this UNIX type of people when
they see something they like that's from
UNIX okay they say oh that's UNIX
philosophy because it's small now when
they see something that is not small for
example email
in po po is a good example for example
and especially today there's like the
UNIX philosophy is completely con
there's no more you know share of small
little programs that that that kind of
thinking it's long long gun for since 14
years now
well anyway so you know they just you
know they these tenets you know this
so-called unit philosophy they are just
codes you know sayings they have no
technical meaning they have no qualms no
they are not precise they can can always
apply to anything however you like
which basically it ends up whatever you
like is you apprised you know the UNIX
philosophy applies whatever you don't
like it doesn't apply for example let me
give you an example you know there's a
popular book widely popular it's called
the UNIX haters book you see this cover
it was it was created by this these
computer scientists down hop King and a
few others it's is widely popular in the
1990s it's free by the way you can
download and read it read it and yeah
it's very funny too yeah and for example
in UNIX you have x11 so there is one
chapter let me show you
I've got too many things here oh I think
I don't have the article here I removed
it so why that's okay so let's go to the
handbook then okay well there's a famous
article let's say let's see by the way
anyone remember that alcohol that's one
chapter of the eunuchs haters book it's
about Y X 11 sucks it's written by dong
Hopkin by the way you can see down
Hopkin on Hacker News he frequent hacker
news he is also a Mathematica code he
loves Mathematica by the way
so any anyone remember the X 11th
chapter
yeah this one the the title is called
the XX windows disaster oh he oh this is
his blog I didn't know he had a medium
blog okay so there it is so now he has a
he has replicated actually it is my on
my website yeah I forgot it should be on
my website as well but anyway this is
the official okay
he's official he put on his blog now so
for example X 11 it's it's one of the
most worthless hack okay and it's huge
it's not small you know as UNIX says you
know UNIX philosophy say it's the most
beautiful x11 is not small it's dumb
it's a monster okay it's it's what
typical program has caused a monster
it's a it's it's huge
you know and so so where is the UNIX
philosophy in this now when you know
when UNIX type of people oh you know
people are influenced by you know the
hacker type of people when they see this
article I've seen you know I've seen
people I've seen a lot because I argue
with them for 20 years now you know I've
seen old all kind of these replies and
responses so when they see this article
their response is that let me tell you
that's not Unix
oh let's just say x11 that's a component
we can switch it out anytime that's this
is not Unix at all you know that's what
they say you know in in bash you know
the bash show it's it's pretty bad they
say oh that's not Unix
you know tah for example the UNIX star
there are many versions you know to folk
for archiving a bunch of files together
into one the tar file that also sucks so
badly you know back then in year 2000 if
Utah a bunch of virus the name is too
long like if the directory name is like
more than 120 characters
it corrupt your filename so you taught
the directory untie it
Oh your file name got you know truncated
let me I mean UNIX UNIX has the thing
about truncation about silent truncation
they like to truncate things you know it
silently and that's part of the UNIX
philosophy so it's pure garbage it's
extremely bad you know so I mean in my
opinion I like to say it's UNIX and see
the language see they are the father of
everything bad in the computing industry
they you know they focus on speed they
focus on simplicity I mean I mean not
simplicity but a simpleton like you know
it's like crude you know crutch no
design no brain no design but make it
very fast so you spread you you put it
out and people say oh wow this is fast
and it it's never about correctness UNIX
for UNIX philosophy UNIX people UNIX
things they never care about good design
quality design you don't care you don't
care about correctness they don't care
ninety percent you know works you'll be
fine that's that's good enough ninety
percent so so in my opinion okay so they
spread you know because it's speed is
fast its small and it's by the way
mostly is free you know you know if if
all the open source programs if they are
not free money okay if they are not free
the open source philosophy and free
software they'll crumble down in one
night tomorrow you wake up nobody likes
open-source anymore it's just because
they are free not because the freedom
because it's zero money and it's a worst
[ __ ] that's how they spread like also
like the latech of Donald Knuth you know
when you when you have something that's
free it spreads like a virus
you know as long as it's like it does
something like it's good enough you know
people don't want to pay even one sense
you know you know that's just a human
nature you know you
you anyway so back to the UNIX o UNIX
philosophy so you have this yeah so x11
you know it's monster it's it's huge
it's not small so why is it you know how
is it UNIX philosophy but anyway you
know so x11
is so bad but however because it's you
know it's free and open source and
nobody can do anything about it because
you know you try you know nobody willing
if you are capable programmer you are
not willing to to write something that
we place you know x11 and contribute for
free anyway let me get back so for for
for now thirty years people try to
replace x11 but it's hard I mean there
are new things now I mean but what I'm
saying is that this thing became people
have tried to replace like x11 since
like 1998 at least okay
I have articles I can show you but it's
it's in my you know it's in my this UNIX
pestilence page you know if you look at
this page you know you can find things
anyway so back let's back to UNIX
philosophy and and we'll be done so okay
so these are called like so what I think
is actually happened I mean what the way
I see the UNIX software the older UNIX
software Oh UNIX related software such
as Perl this the way I see is that they
are just hacks I mean they are they are
the most clueless hacks that are put
together by by clueless or lazy people
who don't care about correctness oh they
didn't want to spend energy they just
want to create something quick and fast
okay
when that happens and when you have this
software but over let's say five years
ten years you try to improve it you know
it works 90% but then next year you try
to fix a little bit make it 99
91% you know so over 10 years what what
happens to it what you got is unix-like
you know today's UNIX and Linux that's
the way that's how I think with the UNIX
philosophy software that people like to
call Co it from UNIX philosophy
I mean people you know the hacker types
like to think of it as the fruit of UNIX
philosophy yeah so I think it's just a
bad hack you know by clueless people but
you know given enough time like five
years ten years you put it out make it
free you know then you people try to
improve it a little bit you know what
you got is Unix
you know the thing UNIX philosophy thing
okay that's it for today I think so
so 11:30 great that's a good time 70
minutes so anything else let me know
okay so I mean so I have this chat thing
and you know so you can you can type on
the youtube comment like after an hour
your show on YouTube in one of my videos
so you know if you do comment comment
and let me know what we should talk
about it next one or in any comment you
have you know if you have a question
about Emacs or something you missed you
know or something I sometimes I I didn't
see some questions in a comment because
I'm trying to read it fast
I don't read fast you know you know
because I always thought I can you know
read you know as fast as native you know
American you know that's it turns out
exactly not true I read you know quite a
lot slower then you know the obviously
because you know I didn't grew up
English it was is not my native language
so anyway thank you guys for coming
great to see you Scott by the way Scott
is a Oh time Emacs user and we met in a
we met in a Emacs hangout we should do
that you know sometimes yeah and you be
my guest or something
so see you guys next time bye