good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi oh and so nobody is
here yet I'm just going to start random
so yesterday we did the demonstration
not demonstration but the oh they they
found this new mouse yesterday this is
fantastic
okay this is a critic this is fantastic
mouse let me show you let's talk about
this mouse and I was you know yesterday
we did talk about this keyboard let me
find it so do it yourself not this is
not actually do it yourself you buy it
from Aliexpress so this keyboard
yesterday about like 15 minutes into the
video we did a talk about this keyboard
now what's special about this keyboard
is all those snobs in wheels 1 2 3 4 you
know you can see and I was saying this
this wheel is the best physical input
device for controlling any type of
commands that comes in pairs such as
previous page next page scrubs go down
forward forward backward forward
backward cha delete forward delete
backward and you know okay so quit don't
save reopen the you know forward
paragraph backward paragraph all these
kind of things and the previous tab you
know next time you know you can you can
fly through them I have a key I can just
hold it down and you'll just fly to them
you can see
you know it's going through so fast that
the fraud the browser doesn't even have
time to update so there are these are
pairs of commands and they are so many
of them they are tens of them and also
next window previous window next
application previous application and so
on so I was saying for these kind of
pairs of commands the best physical
input device for that is the wheel or a
drum this kind of you know thing because
and also because for volume up and down
for example why because this kind of
control when you have a wheel when you
have a knob you can these commands needs
repetition you know it needs fast
repetition and also need precise control
you know like forward for what cha you
you need precise control because you
don't want to go over especially when
you repeat it repeat it too fast and for
this kind of thing that we are is the
best and also these kind of commands
often you want to quickly reverse
direction and that is also the wheel
works the best so I want to show you
some kind of some Emacs demo okay let me
show you some Emacs things I can do well
first of all for example you have scroll
up and down okay you you have scroll up
and down that you need to control
actually let me show you my mouse okay
my mouse got this infinite wheel for
example and you know I can just you keep
scrolling this is spinning wheel
Logitech so by that mouse I recommend it
the Logitech makes it makes several of
them so actually let's just go to the
exotic page and let's create today's
topic infinite
squirrel and let's see if I'm alive yes
hey guys good morning guys comment ok
post in comment in the chat so infinite
squirrel show Emacs mouse wheel command
customization ok
in finish school so so yeah so you want
to have and show these mouse okay let me
type in the topics you want to have this
this kind of wheel input for for those
kind of commands and so we were talking
about that yesterday and we are I'm
going to demonstrate a new Emacs you
know something related to Emacs a
command for doing that yeah
so let's go to Emacs blog open let's go
to in each set up and search for Mouse
mo us e okay it's not here let's go to
practical Emacs search for Mouse
should be in here mouse useful settings
default so we want to modify we want to
customize the mouse wheel for Emacs and
I have a page that's dedicated to that
oh that's in Emacs keys so you go to the
Emacs key section then search for Mouse
MOU as there is how to set mouse buttons
in Emacs now I'm going to demonstrate
some of the you know interesting use of
the interesting setup of the mouse wheel
okay let's see how to say it mouse
buttons
we are uptown okay so here they are on
the Mac we are up we're down okay okay
so let's go to small talk show and let's
paste it here
that's the Emacs mouse wheel and what we
want to first of all we want to see what
we love what is a command name when you
do wheel up it's called describe key
then move the wheel up so yeah okay so
it says wheel up and wheel down okay
it's on the mat now on Emacs each one of
them is different on Linux is mouthful
mouse 5 on wind Windows and Mac its way
up wheel down ok so let me put this here
and on this window you can see all my
Emacs commands wheel up queer down wheel
up we're down wait we're down okay so
let's let's try this
okay the email is pasted global wheel
mouse wheel let's see we go down let's
copy that paste it here so global said
key wheel down what do you want to do
for we are down
I want these commands okay okay and
wheel up will be
oops so that's a that's a to command I
want now IVA Bertha you vow it deleted
paste it here now look I'm going to
school Mike wheel you see you see how
the cursor moves by paragraph like right
now we're up it goes up by paragraph
let's go into click MA so queer down we
go down we go down we go down scroll
down scroll down scroll down up up up up
and it can do it very fast you see so
you can is so this is the example of the
wheel and uptown customization example
of demonstrating the power of the wheel
so so okay that and now I want to set my
wheel back to the default the easiest
way is actually just to create Emacs so
let's do that
create Emacs and we started
okay now Mike Weir is back for doing
school event down okay so we were
talking about this
yeah the wheel so so that is that now
let me show you one second let me put it
here close that let me show so I
yesterday yesterday I found this mouse I
think this is a fantastic mouse and
especially for programmers this is and
this is never seen before
yeah I have you know you have never seen
I have never seen this the design before
and I think it's truly great first of
all it is a vertical Mouse now a
vertical mouse is for you know
repetitive strain you know you have
problem with the mouse because normally
when you use the mouse your hand is like
that because mouse is flat you know you
move like that and that's no good
that's rather a natural posture the more
natural is you know something like that
because if you just put your hand on the
table it's something like that you know
or even that so the mouse you know this
way it's no good so if you you you if
you have a demo or Photoshop or you know
you use Mouse four hours a day that's
going to cause problems that that is why
you have these vertical mouse and there
are so many of them today let's go to
let's have a look so you see vertical
mouse ergonomic Mouse there are so many
different designs now they are tens of
them especially from China has so many
from China you see one thing in common
is that they wanted to be angled so
anyway you have these options but I
think this one is the best design
because you see so so most of them are
like they are more like more or less
like typical Mouse you know they have
you have three buttons or five buttons
okay
one two three you know five
including a you know forward backward
button that's not enough buttons because
for a mouse you also want to you don't
want to move your hand to go back to
keyboard to close tab to switch tab to
copy and paste you know that's you know
keyboard and mouse back and forth that's
no good
you want preferably you want everything
on the mouse but typically for these
vertical Mouse's they don't have many
buttons you know if you go for a game of
mouse yeah you have 10 buttons 10 or 20
even 20 buttons I have that one so
vertical Mouse usually they don't have
many buttons but this one is fantastic
first of all it is it's got many buttons
you know you have the five standard
buttons left right middle and backward
forward but even better than buttons you
have this joystick this joystick is a
four-way joystick but also you can put
press it down so it's like a functions
like five buttons so why is this
joystick better than buttons because if
you can see the patterns you know the
dynamics buttons hey good morning
bathroom you and good morning the young
great to see you guys so if so the
joystick for many many aspects is better
than button as far as economic is is
concerned and info controlling things
for example you so so you have this
four-way four-way joystick first first
of all joystick is ergonomically better
than then the mouse buttons okay
keyboard buttons mechanical keyboard key
are better than mouse buttons because
mouse buttons show you then I guess let
me show you okay so so you have
mechanical you see you have keys now
keys are fantastic because
because they are easy to press and they
are huge and they do not require much
pressure any of these keys
but however for a mouse button the Mac
the the actual physical mechanism is
called micro switch you know they call
it micro switch and it's you know it's
click click if you compare them like if
you have to do this let's say hundred
times you know let's say hundred you
know let's say three hundred times let's
say five times a second and you have to
do this for an hour then you will
realize you will see that the keyboard
mechanical keys is far better ergonomics
because the mouse you get tired very
very fast like normally you you don't
you may not believe it because if I say
Oh a mouse button is ergonomically was
then you know keyboard keys you don't
think of you don't really see it because
you don't use you know like when you
compare these kind of things one way to
see the difference is that imagine you
have to do it many many times for an
hour so if you imagine you have to press
a key or mouse button five times a
second you know like one two three four
you know five times a second for let's
say 10 minutes then you compared to in
that form also compare pressing a keys
on keyboard then you realize the
difference the you know how it you know
which one is harder and how much harder
that's when you realize that so from you
know most people when they talk about
you know key binding and they don't
consider much yummy one of the most
important thing is how much you have to
press the key actually because if you
only press you know let's say 50 times a
day
it doesn't matter okay it Mouse is fine
you know but if you have to do is a lot
you know every day for years for example
in the past 10 years I've been sitting
on the
chair then you realize is actually a big
difference long term so now I don't I
don't even press my mouse my mouse is
Auto click let me show you okay so so
you see when the the way I operate my
computer I don't press them I don't
press buttons
I just nudge the mouse to whatever
windows I want this is fantastic
I don't you know it it's got Auto quick
you know it's it's truly convenient but
however the thing is you you have to get
used to and if I don't want Auto quick I
just moved my mouse to the to the lower
left lower right window then there's no
auto click right now you see so you are
getting switch between easily
no no Creek is back
so notice you know all my windows our
God our God sites you know to this to
the edge of the monitor so I can just
nudge my mouse to there and fly there
like Tmax is typically lower right and
Firefox is typically middle middle
button middle bottom and you know that's
how I operate but you have to get used
to it and actually so I have articles on
that for example you go to you go to
software like I have explanations of
what I just explained why you want to do
that and how to do that for Linux for
Mac for Windows well actually in fact in
Windows 10 they removed that feature in
the UI so you cannot do it easily now
but in Windows Vista Windows you know
before 10 you can go to the control
panel and say that so lets you know
let's look at that hoover to switch
window okay for example this is this is
the instruction for mac hoover to switch
window okay so
let's type that
so greetings
I don't like mice I use rat poison for a
while well yeah I talked about this the
keyboard versus mouse you know in in my
videos few videos you know I last week
or something I don't know if you think
that because that's one of the hackers
you know that's one of the hackers they
all say that especially you know rat
poison for example the name oh wow okay
let's it's let me talk about a few
things
why hiding windows sucks why tanning
window managers sucks on Linux that Arco
becomes so popular I I talked about this
before a month a few months ago let's
let's show that ok so let's go to Linux
Linux Keys search for tidying ok
this article becomes so popular every
every every year you know if they showed
up on Hacker News and headed why spot
why is it popular partly because you can
say I'm trolling ok I'd you know I'm but
rather more correct it's more correct to
say it's dramatic not show something I
don't like the Wardrobe because it means
a thousand things but anyway so this
algo becomes popular so and in anyway so
let's go back to our topic
so I was saying
Oh rad boys okay rat poison is this one
of the first tiling windows manager for
x11 for Linux and I know the guy the guy
is a Emacs user okay I chatted with him
like 10 years ago on IRC he is Canadian
I think he's a Canadian he leaves around
Vancouver or something I think so that
way maybe not but anyway he okay let me
explain the two persons let's go ok did
so many topic ok rat rat poison the guy
and his friend the IRC the Emacs IRC guy
and he's also on Twitter the rat poison
guy is on Twitter
he is a Emacs user and he has a friend I
also know ok so many source stories in
Emacs keyboard frequency ok let me tell
let me talk about these people a little
bit so first of all ok so let me start
exhausted command log mod
okay and let's start another window and
move this window over here and let's go
to such let's use a goal and script to
such so I type find and I want to find
it in the web directory so in this
directory that's all my website and
let's search for rat poison because I
don't remember where is the file so and
such this is a : script then you have
come up meanwhile let's let's look at
the IRC guy so there is a guy who wrote
the Emacs IRC mod it's called the full
name of the mod is RC IRC and his name
is let's search it for okay so let's use
another let's use the Emacs command to
search it so go to my eMac directory
search for it
our CI RC that is search for IRC oh
actually I know where is the Arco so you
go to my Emacs home page there is a
acknowledgement then search for IRC
yeah here here is a guy Ryan yeskey Ryan
yes key
he is the author our CI RC which is
bundled in Emacs since about 10 years
ago so you know we can actually start it
so meta X IRC it's alias to the command
name RC or you can type our CI RC the
same so our CI RC enter you know so
that's the mod you know you you start to
get into free not net or you can connect
to other IRC so okay I haven't been
using our C for over 10 years so anyway
in RC RC in any major mod you can do
describe Mart okay with a shortcut ctrl
H M so let's do that
so you can see this RC IRC commands now
you go to the top you go to the link and
here's the source code it is 3000 lines
and you go to the top and you can see
his name you know Ryan yes okay
and he also contributed he is the orange
and he wrote the Emacs command frequency
mod okay he is our engine once again
even close this close it
cue it close it kill it what close it
do I want to say no so okay so let me
copy the name
and now let's go back to my talk page so
ah see IRC guy he is also the author
original author of e Emacs command
frequency mod ok let me show you that so
you go through Emacs Emacs keys and
search for statistics
Emacs command frequency statistics now
this is a study statistics
my study of all command call frequency
now how is this generated it's you know
there's a major mod you can download
that that we will log all your Emacs
command cause the latest version is by
David Capello let me search the name
David Capello ok so it's on github and
it's called key freak key frequency he
fought he it but the original one
is began by Ryan yes guy you know
because what in 2006 you know I was in
Emacs IRC free not you know Emacs room
so we were chatting and I was you know I
was into designing of keyboard shortcuts
and then I mentioned you know it would
be nice to have a log then he wrote it
he he wrote it right away
like 20 lines that you know 20 lines so
he began that then then you know I added
little things then it becomes larger
then then other people contributed
Michael Michael NASA way wig mikonos ray
wigs
he made it into a full package then
later on David Capitol folk folk to it
and made it a frequency mod so
the reason we are mentioning this is
because the dry and yes yes key guy
now the Ryan yes key guy he is a hacker
type well like me like like many Emacs
users you know you I don't think he I'm
not sure he works in a company I think
he does freelance something like that
you know typically we we don't work you
know the instead of being a company you
know you you move around so that's him
so so let's put that here okay so then
why am i mentioning Ryan guy because he
is a friend he and this guy rat poison
guy our friends I think they are they
are you know real-life friends I think
they are in Vancouver Canada and the rat
poison guy let's find his name he wrote
he wrote the rat poison now rat poison
is a window manager for X 11 on Linux
and it is written in I think it's
written in common lisp
okay I've in Co in Common Lisp I forgot
by anyway then later on he created
another window manager that's completely
written in Common Lisp that is the
supposed to replace the rat poison do
you remember the D on do you remember
who what
what's that window manager's name come
on is it wrong
so window managers or rat poison
rat poison you know these names you know
the the reasons named rat poison because
he oh these people they hate Mouse and I
have a giant grand against them okay I
think they are just wrong they are
totally like idiotic okay so I actually
took so you still use it oh you use it
before okay so rat poison well it's on
Wikipedia okay I mean yeah let's look at
let's go to Wikipedia it's alright
Wikipedia rat poison yeah with a logo I
despise you know this this rat poison
you know like actually my system is more
efficient you know that that's part of
my rant on this white having windows
sucks let me copy that oh okay white
tiling wait do I have it okay I don't
let's copy it so white having windows
sucks
this article is is basically my frame
again is all those people especially you
know eMac eMac slim UNIX philosophy
these type of people every day they say
oh don't use a mouse use the keyboard
that's idiotic
okay because I sometimes I I go I spend
like 30 minutes talking about that so
it's not I'm gonna I'm not going to
repeat that but you know you can read
this article and and and I you know I
explained why you know the lot you know
with the recent logical rational why I
don't you know I don't think that's good
and you can you know you can do it you
can you can compare scientifically most
of these people Emacs users or this whim
you know keyboard or nomads these type
of people or UNIX philosophy for
instance they never actually do anything
scientific you know they they they go by
law they go by hacker law oh yeah I
never use a mouse
yeah let's swap you know the best thing
to do is always swap cap locks to
control you know that that's what they
say so do it by you know to
measure it scientifically define measure
you know statistics you know nation you
know you Kiki keylogging you know lock
your key key stroke then you see what
what's what so yeah I talked about this
you know let's not talk about that again
so anyway so that's this article about
and so rat poison
so rat poison let's go back to rat
poison okay
so close that let's go to Wikipedia
because there is a common list version
so rat poison is written in C then this
guy this guy is a big lisp fan okay
Shawn okay Shawn bets that's his name
Shawn Shawn bets
he's on Twitter okay now and then I see
his posts he and also he's a juggler
okay let me show you my juggling ugh
okay I am I was a juggle around was a
team like since six sixteen I was
planning to become the greatest juggler
and I do juggling on a street in
Montreal Canada you know I write
unicycle and stuff
Sean bets author author of rat poison
friend of Ryan yes key okay and okay and
what and the next version of rat poison
it's search for common list okay so
there it is stump stump VM so stump VM
is the next generation of rat poison
it's written in common lisp so you know
oh you list friends you you'll love it
you're getting excited and you'll love
it
so stumped window managers stamp stamp
window manager it's written entirely
common list
it's like has cows you know has sky as a
thing has cow has a white talent manager
sucks has cow has the X monad you know
so you see that these timing managers
it's not just an auto scheme scheme list
also has one called swim
I think anyone remember scheme this also
have a telling win-win tiling windows
when I'm not sure that one is hiding but
it's a windows manager with a mean
scheme this you see this Linux tools
it's not about how good is a tool but
rather it has it it also has to do is
with your fanatism with a particular
language you know if you are a Haskell
fan you are thinking you need to create
a window manager that's written in a
scowl and everything you do is just in
Haskell then you have you know the stump
wm4 common list and there is also one
written in scheme Lisp which is the
oldest of them all and of course this
you know if you go old school then there
is a new step which is you know kind of
like trying to emulate the next
operating system the next OS from Steve
Jobs you know the the next interface
many so you guys any one of you remember
that so let me let me read the comments
ok so Sean bets so that guys so Sean
bets
he wrote rat poison and
so let's all get organized organized we
have a nice thing to see now this is
Mike's our talk show page view in
browser so today's section is here
but however let me show you let's create
a new page so saw talk show date meta X
X our new page ok that creates a new
page showing browser empty ok back close
now cut cut cut cut cut
ok now back to here make it a list go
back to the link open it pace it showing
browser so there it is that is today
then close that you see I just not touch
my mouse you know around oh I can press
a key a single key to go to the last
last window application so here where am
i ok so we are here and then just delete
that did d delete then put this into
here showing browser downtown so that is
there today ok so we talked about these
things
Emacs setup buttons Ryan yes and and we
talked about white honey manager sucks
okay Sean bets they are friends
and Joe green okay so Joe green it so so
so Sean Betts is a juggler he can do
five balls at least I can also do five
but I cannot do now you need practice
you need to practice I haven't been
juggling for for several years but I can
show you three for sure but anyway but I
have an old video that's me juggling so
let me show you
sorry juggling okay so hold on a second
sorry juggling okay Shawn is age juggler
okay sorry juggling and let me show you
my juggling website I have quite a lot
videos of the best juggling photo of
sorry so let's go there now this page is
a bit controversial so I'm not sure I
want to
that's my sister back in 2005 okay here
is me juggling let's see if we can do
that
easy job cheering chuckling is quite fun
there are so many tricks you know I'm
not sure I want to do it here you can
you can you know for three balls you can
just juggle but you can also do catch
that is that is not difficult I have to
I have to get out my juggling balls you
guys want to see it I haven't been
juggling food so for example you have
three balls now I don't want to do with
this because these are metal and stone
you know I don't want to drop it's gonna
break my keyboard so you can juggling
like that okay but you're okay you can
also do with this way by by like that by
like that you know catch so I did that
in that's not that's not too difficult
there are so many tricks okay but I'm
gonna show you some videos my collection
of videos on YouTube yeah
it's all from YouTube YouTube has tons
of juggling things and you know juggling
is a is a community by itself just like
emai extreme programming math you know
it's like a community or gaming you know
particular a specific game you have like
a community or a second life you know
yeah you know you're all these
communities against if you are against
you know you know about gangster stuff
every day what's going on you know if
you are in gangsters so so juggling
juggling is a you know community it's
there's a lot of people in it and a lot
hacker hacker types and you know so they
are also so they are you know
celebrities jugglers celebrity jugglers
new you know if you are in this
community you know okay this these
people are celebrities you know this
person is famous for what that person is
always dramatic and he always you know
did something something you know it's
like that and who is the world's record
holder
is the best juggler and so on and and
what kind of juggling there are so many
types of juggling so I you know I have
like some kind of collection of videos
you know it's my blog basically this
this guy's fantastic well I'm not going
to show it you can just go to my website
and see it just
you can you know agent you can just go
to my website and see it but let me
impost let me get the link just such
Fork sorry juggling and you'll see it
and and some of them they did that they
actually acquired many interesting
things in juggling you know juggling you
know it's jugglers is kind of like Emax
you know people who loves in emacs the
type of personality are kind of
congregated you know you tends to often
many of them are Wanderers you know you
wander around you know you don't hold
jobs you wander around you join the
circus
I was I was going to join the circus
back then and you meet many interesting
people's for example there is a I don't
know if I should mention that there is
this guy okay there is this guy who I
met back in Montreal when I was 16 and
he is he is four time he's a world
record holder he is a great juggler his
name was Andrew Allen okay he is a often
I think of often you know he I think so
he doesn't have a parent but he you know
so when I was 16 he is like you know
he's maybe five years older than me
something like that and he he he is he
knows like 10 languages he speak ten
languages including Chinese I think he
grew up he is a white guy American you
know I think he grew up in New York and
and he saw he speak like ten languages
including Chinese and he also write and
read Chinese you know that is rare
because for people who learn Chinese
usually they don't they don't learn to
read and write because that's too
difficult so he speak you know
Chinese is one of his language he also
you know all the most popular languages
he speak but he also speak you know the
some of the rare languages not
mainstream you know languages and also
he studies Old English okay now in
English literature you know like you
have Shakespeare right but but I don't
know the details but III think before
1500 you know even or before that you
have what's called Old English he be
that he read that you know so he's a
mean but he is not he doesn't have a
degree he doesn't you know yeah he is a
high school I drop out something like
that you know but however I think he's
in jail now
for reasons I don't want to I don't want
to get into okay he has been hiding for
for fourteen years you know something
like that yeah I wrote about it I don't
want to yeah let's not talk about that I
don't think it's fair you know I I do
not think he should be in jail but you
know for reasons you know but anyway I
met him when I was 16 and the stories
you know I don't want to say but yeah
but I don't think he should be in jail I
think I think I think he's in jail so
let me read the comments so that's about
juggling so so on this page you know you
can check it out let me post LinkedIn
and let me read the comments
so what's up bathroom you and dr say
things okay
like yesterday I read the comments there
are some comments I missed you yeah
usually web I'm just busy like I'm busy
ranting about something there's some
comments you know whether either
question questioning my you know my
thesis whatever I was saying oh you know
something related but but I I'm too busy
to read them that yeah so
Sebastian amuses reminds me of the super
children in China where some four years
old church jogger like they are born
with these sports now Chinese typically
they don't juggle okay I mean this
juggling juggling balls or juggling
clubs they are like western style of
juggling that I they are why this today
I don't know about Asian but at least
today this kind of juggling that's kind
of Western things Chinese traditionally
they don't do this kind of thing they
they do actually what they do is cut
more more artistic and more creative and
more beautiful to look at they'd for
example they kick they kick chairs okay
then let me show you some example
Chinese chairs okay
Chinese chair Joe Greene so you you lie
on your back and you kick a chair with
your legs yeah in this vase you know so
so I was you know very much into
juggling so that I know a lot about this
I know about you know a lot about
circuses I watched so many of them on
video even back then that some VHS tapes
you know in fact breaking 18 1986 around
that time yeah I was in Montreal Canada
so I you know I watched lots of that and
talked to a lot people you know all my
friends are Chopra and unicycle riders
and stuff so Chinese children typically
they don't do this sport juggling you
know that the traditional what we you
know when you say juggling people think
of you know throwing bows or clubs you
know that's juggling or rings but that's
usually Chinese circus they don't do
that they do these kind of things they
kick you know this they kick a table for
example this is one of their act
they you know they kick a drum you know
they do and they have you know this kind
of thing so it's like different and this
vase thing this this is also spectacular
okay they this is one act of Chinese
juggling specific to you know Chinese so
what you have is okay hold on a second
what you have is Chinese vase juggling
okay let me show you some pictures some
some photos it's that way it's easy to
see this one yeah you see you see that's
a classic traditional porcelain
porcelain vase
you know weights like I don't know 10
kilograms or something so you you you
put it on your head you can spin it you
can flip it things like that okay so and
also by the way many of these you know
you you will find an article on
Wikipedia PDI has lots of info you
actually you are fine for example you
such that you'll find lots of info
Wikipedia they are did you know yeah
yeah I'm pretty sure I've seen it before
so Chinese struggling and in Chinese
Aquabat you know unlike Western for
example Western you have gymnastics you
have you know you know Olympics you have
gymnastics tumbling but the Chinese
struggling they they have different they
kind of they have they have kind of a
more artistic touch rather than just
plain performance so anyway so that's
that's that is my so yeah I actually so
I have a lot of videos on this web page
you can go around and you'll see I love
those things but now I'm too old and
[Music]
now I am anyway so let me finish the
comments so dr bathroom uses you reminds
me of the super children in China I'm
not sure what super children you
referring to four years old sugar like
they bond with both white America men
the root of all evil I forgot where that
came from
you mean like Casa yeah maybe I don't
know much I don't know anything about
that guy Casa I don't even remember I
don't know if I pronounced that right
but I recognize that some kind of old
English author wow he is in prison
because I don't I don't want I don't
want to mention it I don't have to say
why but I did blog about it if you if
you are diligent you can find you you
know I think you will find my blog
somewhere anyway yeah I don't let's not
talk about that well party because he
you know it even involves him you know I
yeah I don't yeah so they did chuckling
you know the circus stuff
oh yeah lunch Oh green so with how do
you do young 30s or 40s or 50s
okay I don't I you know actually so let
me tell you where okay um you know there
used to be blogger from Google there's a
blog there's a blog you know Google
spraga which kind of died so I used to
post on bloggers like synced to my own
website blog because for one time you
know this you know you know Google
created a blogger there's you know blog
instead that's one one era of online
history so good thing you know it but
what at one time is hugely popular it's
like everyone saying oh everyone should
write a blog you know the the the
information will come from people and
things like that then eventually after
10 years Google killed it you know the
the the blog leader the the aggregate
you know RSS aggregator Google killed it
by the way by the time Google killed
Google Reader that's already blogging is
already dead because the social media
the Facebook Twitter took over that is
why and that is also the time Google
started to Google created Google+ you
know Google the thinking was that social
media is the future you need to get into
so Google pushed Google+ by all means
necessary yeah it's like by or evil
tactics they try to push Google+ they
force people on YouTube too much you
know account with Google+ and forced
people to use real name and so on
because why because it was Facebook who
who started to use vo names and that
becomes successful because most people
you know unlike programming notes they
actually you know they want real names
they don't want they don't want to go to
online and they see a bunch of Batman
and prince and princess and you know the
Joker that's I don't want that you know
you know I don't want that either I hate
every time I see the programmers are
rated on hacker
a bunch of you know anonymous crap you
know and you see the result of it to
that that is why unrated on YouTube how
can use you you you get all these
comments you know brainless comments and
many of them they try to you know they
want to try to write it so that you know
it's like cat pictures so they get a lot
of votes up you know then they feel
happy oh I got you know loaded up it's
like that you know brainless degenerate
so anyway so so so that that's Google
first so I was saying so bra bloggers so
I'm blog so back back then I have count
I have like two or three blogger
accounts where every time I write on my
own blog I also post they're you know
trying to her trying to be popular that
is why well yeah part of the reasons I'm
trying to I also want to be popular I'm
trying to get a pie of it
the other reason is that I want to be
explore the technology you know Google
is doing this let's see how it works you
know how they do the CSS how how can I
customize what interface you know that's
your part of the reason so anyway so
forward for like four years about for
yeah for about four years I have a I
have several blogger accounts then about
three years ago I deleted them why I I
wouldn't mind living it up just there
but the thing is then spam you know like
every debut have to deal with tens of
spam comments you know spam well good
you know Google has spam filters right
but it doesn't work you know so well so
you you still got spam and spammers they
change techniques you know every every
month they change techniques you know I
can I can write a book about the
spamming takes techniques to over the
past 20 years you know you have this
that so anyway the lots of spam so
finally I killed them I did
did it for example you can go to Saudi
Saudi blogger I think you will probably
find it they are there okay so I wait so
there is one of my blogging account I
had at least three okay so you know I
can i I know where to find it but right
now I don't know oh wait what this one
is not deleted what
second there is I should teach it I
didn't realize this one is still up yeah
so this one is my main blog account I
did it like three years ago because I'm
you know I don't really want to delete
it you know I don't mind you know I just
want to leave them up because that's
history you know that's what I like
typically that's my mindset leave
everything up you know I don't care
whatever you know whatever you've done
that's that's that's history you know
leave it you know leave it there but the
the part of the reason I deal with them
is because Google you know Google
becomes evil and abusive then you have
the bunch of spam so I have to deal with
it every day you know then so so I just
deleted it because I don't want you know
I don't want Google to have my
information it's not your if it's not
yours Google so anyway on this blog what
one of these account I don't remember
which one I wrote about this jugular
okay so you might you might find it in
archives but typically every time I post
to blog I also have a version on my own
website but for this particular case I
don't remember I don't remember whether
I have it on my website his his name was
Andrew Allen okay
Andrew Allen that was his when I met him
that was his name but later on he
changed he changed name legally okay so
if you want to find him you can find him
yeah if this is open information okay
bathroom you you can easily find his
information because for one time he is a
word space jugular he has a you know
word best table stick or something he's
one of the most famous you know world
famous chakra energy
community like everyone knows him heard
of him because you know he because he's
he is such fantastic you know yeah you
can say you know that one of the best
juggler in this century you know one of
the best let's say top 100 not what that
you could say top 10 okay but in top 10
there's so many other people you know
one of the best okay and and he also is
a scholar you know he's he's often he
you don't he doesn't you know high
school dropout or something but he knows
you know he's to be you know 10 language
20 languages
he read you know Old English and so on
and he he travels like as far as I know
he travel around the country around the
world you know one day in China one day
in Germany one day in you know and he is
known in the circus community and also
among circuses like circuses I don't I
don't know if he ever ever performed
you've worked with the circus probably
but he's a friend friends with many
circuses you know so he you know he go
around people you know love to have him
stay you know like if he comes by help
stay at my house for a month you know
things like that so he's like that so he
his name was Andrew Allen so he so so
back if from from nineteen let's say
1990s - let's say 2000s he he's well
known okay so the so first so you find
that his name you'll find him then your
your easy see what's the situation
because he because people talk about
that yeah you don't even need to find my
blog it's he's you know
Julian Lafayette okay
tes Daggerfall program okay I don't know
who is that and I don't know what is TS
tagger for so what else
so maybe that's it today I think
the elder scrolls what elders grows the
elder scrolls yeah I don't know what
that is
so the Elder Scrolls is a series of
action role-playing open-world fantasy
video games primarily developed by path
dog game studios okay the game everyone
knows saw you knowing I don't know it
RPG series I don't know I never heard of
it you know a lot of people I think
hackers you know they a lot of them are
interested in these war playing games
but I mean the the type that where you
like you have a text-based mu D like mud
and you know dragons something dragon
the in turn dungeons you you have mud
you know text-based role-playing game I
never find that interesting like you
have to type a lot and like they did you
know you're sure you say you know right
now you are seeing a you know a coda you
can turn right or left then you have to
type you know so pick your choice you
know especially the text-based I don't
see what's appointing that you know
that's City
I like role-playing I like you know I
like Zelda you know Zelda 64 I played on
in Nintendo 64 that's one of the
fantastic greatest game Zelda Ocarina of
times I think that yeah that's the one I
played that's fantastic now that is also
called role-playing game so that I like
okay so the Elder Scrolls I don't know
what I don't know what it is
so apparently it's a big game
Oh Skyrim what's what the Skyrim have to
do it
Skyrim I heard of oh oh okay Skyrim is
part of it okay
I mean it's one of the yeah but I don't
know 3d 3d is good okay I like 3d stuff
you know one of the one of the most
idiotic game is minecraft you know in
principle I think that I cannot possibly
like that game because you know as
computer graphics technology progresses
then you have this guy who creates a 3d
game where everything is a Lego block
what I did and then it becomes
tremendously popular okay um what else
Daggerfall yeah I don't know I don't
yeah I haven't been playing yeah I
haven't been playing games other than
the 90s you know those arcade games so I
prayed you know I'm a gamer okay what
that's that's a bit complex demon
depending on what what you mean so I'm a
gamer in a traditional classic sense for
example arcade games since 1980s let me
show you some some of the games I've
played since I was you know 12 yeah I'm
addicted to it you know back then you
have to put money so you know I take my
dad's money and you know play a lot and
you know and I'm the type where when I
play a video game I have to pass it you
know like III can go three days one week
continuously no eating well not eating
much okay sleep wake up immediately play
play until after 16 hours my eyes
becomes also and sleep wake up play
again I have to finish it you know so
for many periods in my guys the you know
that happens you know so that way I'm
like that so so I played a lot arcade
games
since I was small and you know even in
1990s Street Fighter and but but then
sweet 3d games became popular you know
doom or whatever doom and you know I've
never actually played any of those okay
the only I could say only three games I
played modern you know what people think
of as game today three one is Zelda the
Ocarina of Time on Nintendo 64 that is I
would consider that is the best game I
ever played in my life
Zelda six you know on Zelda Ocarina of
Time that's my friend you know back then
this is 1998 we are in a startup and I
have this American program you know he's
he's a game he's a gamer
he showed me that he let me play so
right that opened my eyes you know the
other six Zelda Ocarina of Time that I
played then around 2002
I played Alice let me let me tight let
me show it okay so actually let's show
arcade games strong okay search for that
okay then I'm going to show so I played
Zelda I'm not sure I spell that
correctly Ocarina of Time
so these are some of the fantastic
arcade games strong and so Tron
light-cycle
optimal strategy you know this many of
these games has a math aspect to it and
ladybug is fantastic ladybug and let me
show and there are several others you
know 1980s for example this one when it
came out I played when I was like 10 or
something the Space Invaders then there
is asteroid asteroids is fantastic is
one of the first vector graphics game by
the way there are many modern versions
today with fancier graphics instead of
on a Mac they are civil I played you
know you know once I'm a dolt typically
I don't play I try not to play at all
because I kind of consider game is like
a waste of time so high so it's a taboo
you know so I in my mind I have this
mindset where you don't want to touch
that that's something it's like alcohol
for some people okay like some people
are addicted to alcohol and they they
constantly try not to touch it you know
every time they do they got drunk then
then tomorrow they woke up they say I'll
never do it again so I don't drink
alcohol so that doesn't apply to me I
don't really like alcohol that much but
for games yes that applies to me so
every time I play games you know is it's
going to be like the whole week you know
I do nothing he just forgets it after
that okay I you know for several years I
don't touch games that's kind of like
that so anyway so the the the the the
modern games I played is Zelda and
then Alice okay Alice American McGee's
Alice
I have a website of this game this is
kind of okay again I wouldn't say I
wouldn't say it's super good but but
because I love the Alice in Wonderland
because Alice in Wonderland Alice is one
of my most favorite literature at least
back then I wouldn't think so today but
Alice you know I have a correction of
Alice Art Walks yeah let me show you
some of these it's interesting but first
volume let's type it
okay so so this are a bunch of Alice
artworks and I have these are classic
and some let me show you some of the
rather interesting ones and there is
fashion
you know we women also girls for reasons
they love Alice you know they love the
Alice in Wonderland the character they
they have yes particularly girls they
they have a obsession with Alice every
everything there for reasons for example
these these are fashion photo shoot for
the Vogue magazine
it's magnified so and and it's well done
it's fantastic it's beautiful so you
have this Alice and look at the Queen
you know the Queen is is constant
constantly saying off with her head and
here is the story of the turtle and the
Gryphon look at you know the guys
expression that reflects the story of
Alice in Wonderland to a tee so this is
a great fantastic fashion photo shoot
out very well done
look at this guy's expression and she
you know she's a Russian model she is
exotic beautiful and this is this is
actually 15 years ago almost 2007 okay
mm 17 years ago and yeah Alice the story
of Alice in Wonderland this actually a
lot of stories of that you know
interesting stories also the
mathematician dodges and touches and he
is a mathematician he doesn't really
actually did much in math he's just most
well known for writing Alice in
Wonderland and he's a logician
so some of the interesting art hard work
for example you have you know this is a
Alice yeah especially girls you know you
know there's a lot artists who are tip
often women for a period of time like
for two years I dived into the artist
community like people who draw who like
to draw things like that I also like
that but I never drew anything I never
learned it so but anyway so for two
years I went into the I I immerse myself
in artists community you know to see
what they do what they are what you what
kind of person are they what do they
have to do what they what things they
draw you know because I like that yeah I
like to explore all kind of things so
these are artworks about Alex about
Alice and typically most of them are
true by women you know girls so here's
the repeal and bloopio and this is
influenced by by this skin you know
American McGee's Alice you know the in
this game he pictures Alice in this
horror was a horror show
so anyway ripio bloopio Alice in the Red
Queen the Red Queen Queen is typically
the bad bad guy that's considered
solid so so I was saying so the top the
games I played okay so the games modern
game I play is Zelda and American
McGee's Alice then in 2008 to 2012 2007
to 2012 I was everyday spending five
hours about five hours or more in second
life sick second night and I have a
website dedicated dedicated to that
entirely
not not this one yeah second life I have
second life scripting tutorials you have
a computer programming language in
second life which is completely
different than any language because in
second life linden scripting language
that's what what it is called so when I
was in second life for four years I also
wrote a mod for the second life
scripting language LSA or mod for Emacs
and I studied this a lot you know I
spent huge time I'm owning it so second
life
so yeah so that's the three modern games
I played there nothing else since so let
me read the comments in that I think
that will be it until unless they are
more interesting comments so elder
scrolls okay elder scrolls equals to
Skyrim okay now that I understand
I know Skyrim I heard of it because like
two years three years ago it's over the
web you know on Twitter people talk
about it they have seen some YouTube
videos that's what I do today so you
know I don't actually play any games but
I look into them like like like you know
there's a shooter you know first-person
shooter game which is popular
you know the what's the name and and you
know where you have this different
character anyway so I but I look into
them i watch youtube videos I I get a
sense what they are you know like kind
of like observing what's going on you
know the technology part what's going on
the people you know what young people
are doing these days what are they
thinking
what's their you know what kind of
language what kind of jargons they use
you know just it's just a natural
interest more rowing more wind more
rowing no I don't know what's more wind
okay I know you guys are gamers you guys
you guys deploy this you guys are
younger you know that Daggerfall and
deep conscience I have to admit the
voxel graphics in Minecraft makes a
functional things since so what what
does växjö graphics me
Zork i heard of his oak I think is that
some kind of a spa like supposed to be
this ambitious game where you start with
sports in sales and you you you become
it becomes a civilization and universe
things like that
we don't you not have five in that way
ocarina yeah ocarina okay so ocarina oh
you didn't finish it so after ocarina
there are several versions you know and
then I'm not working so I don't money
then I did I knew ID generated they had
suffer from hunger and I was living in a
car for for like two years then I sold
my car and that's what I am now teaching
and you know doing petty you know
teaching writing petty Emacs tutorials
yeah that's that's not that's not what I
want to do how can we now have time you
know the video talk show yeah they are
talk show that's not that's not what I
want to do but you know as time goes on
life changes you get old and your
viewpoint may change and you know if you
become poor or you let's say you went to
prison to jail you just that that just
becomes your life you add art adapt to
it you know that you adapt
what do I want well that's how to say
well I want to I want to get out of my
I want to do but then again you know
it's you know it's difficult to say and
also that's a very interesting
philosophical question okay
hey good morning Alan so Alan
you bought my Emacs tutorial right did
you ever get my sorry Todd info like
answer okay because you know like I
hardly read my emails these days you
know I don't like almost I don't want to
and so I think you asked me to send you
something so I today I just generated
Saudi info yeah which one was the Emacs
wait wait first of all let me ask you
did you ever part the Saudi dot info let
me ask you that one and so that first
did you ever get did you ever paid for
Saudi darian phone I can actually easily
check you know but but it's easier if I
just ask you okay so I okay so I need to
send you the Emacs then okay okay so
great thank you thank you for the
donations yeah yeah I'm gonna send it
today so right now my Emacs solution I
think it's like one month old anyway
I'll send it today okay will be out
today for sure then then I'll check my
email okay so if I did say say I'm gonna
send you the salary info and rescinded
well you see the thing about solid are
info the whole website I just generated
today it's two point eight gigabytes to
point a jig about so it's a problem for
me to handle it you know because
because if I just put on my website each
time a person downloaded its two point
eight gigabyte bandwidth and then if I
you know then then I put two do you know
the way Dow so what do you mean well I
know what thou is show me that way show
me the way show show that way oh yeah oh
yeah that Dow okay I think that's it for
today unless there's anything
interesting what do I want
so what do I want so that that's an
interesting question there's so many
ways to go into it you know and and it
also gets personal but I don't know but
yeah so anyway I think that's it that's
it for today
go into it tomorrow and make a schedule
what do what do I want that's III want
to talk to that topic you know like you
know so what you are much has to do with
your personality for example what do I
want that I can talk about but you know
you know I am not sure what's going to
happen you know what I mean doing with
my video but if I just go naturally then
my video is just it's like what I have
been doing you know I just talk talk
about random things and often it becomes
you know focusing on myself and focusing
on myself you know like like I talk
about my own stuff like my problems or
whatever you know my everything is sorry
okay and I am the greatest okay but
that's not that's not good you see this
so first of all do I want to be popular
that's a you know like like so when I do
introspection a lot so I think about
things whenever there's a question I can
I can do I can do analysis on it very
well and there's so much so much
introspection and analysis of things
that's crazy to most people okay so so
what up to what what do I want for
example what do I want what am I doing
with my video okay that's a question and
I can I have full analysis I have
complete detailed analysis on what what
what's going on what do I want to do but
but that's you see you see that doesn't
make you do those things so that that
that doesn't change you like if you want
to be a leader okay
for example let me give you example of
these thought if you want to be your
leader
now most I'm a nerd okay maybe of most
of you are nerds probably a lot of you
are I know so as a nerd naturally you
are not the leadership type you know to
be a leadership type first of all there
are a few characteristics let me just
mention them out of the blue one well
first of all a good thing to have is
charisma that like you look pretty
handsome
you know handsome for guys handsome you
know you have charisma that's one thing
you don't it's not necessary it's not
absolutely absolutely necessary but
that's a good thing to have for leaders
for leaders then you have to talk well
you have to be able to submit speak
smoothly not not like me okay start
stuttering and jump jump around topics
and and not for now see pronounce things
where and things like that and you know
you know you know that that's not good
you okay you have to talk smoothly
that's the second thing to be a
leadership the leadership type
personality another thing and another
thing is that you have to you actually
don't want you don't you can you know
for example you cannot be a philosopher
and also also be a leadership type
because these two personalities are not
the same are not in the same hole okay
so it's it's almost like either
oh of course there are exceptions but
you know because philosophers if you
want to be a good great philosopher you
know you you tends to be the person who
think a lot who think about all all
things or details and reserve your
reservation that you reserve your
opinions until you have overview then
you you know discuss in detail in depth
and so on that that tends to be
philosopher you you don't you don't just
you know say something right away on the
other hand leadership's for leadership
types you don't want that okay you want
to you kind of you want to your
personality you don't want to think you
don't want to be the thinker type rather
you have opinion on things that came
from your your background your
experience and also the your communities
your community
community's general tradition or
convention or beliefs for example if you
are a Christian then you have certain
beliefs in that groups and if you want
to be a if you are a leader type for
that group you typically you you know
these things just by nature just you
know so so for example women the topics
something about religion you you you
naturally and automatically speak a
opinion that most people will agree or
find you know find easy to be take take
taking even even controversial subjects
so that that's that's kind of leadership
personality okay
so what what's my point my point is that
now if you are not like me you know we
can stir these lots of things we are
engineers you know we can study we can
analyze the leadership but are you going
to be a leader like that that is a
question you know it's not like you just
you can what you you can you can be if
you really want but that takes effort
and that takes effort and some some
practice okay and you you could be a
leader
needed ship type of person but however
you you may not want to it is a lot
trade-off once you become a leadership
type for example once you become a
leader of a company or leader of a whole
you know a movement or whatever you know
any anything there are trade off you you
may not want to be I don't want to be
for example yo you know you you you know
as an engineer know type you you can be
something but maybe you don't want to
actually because once for for example
for the leadership once you become
leadership you lost you lost the
Philosopher's trade you lost the
engineering trade you you know you knew
no longer program for example you you no
longer have time to study or interesting
academic things such as math programming
languages you know
human languages or even history or
historian or the English literature you
no longer have time to do not much to
explore all these things and also I mean
that not just time not just lack of time
but also there is a trade-off in in what
you are going to be able to in what you
are willing to think you know because
once you are leader your mind changes it
changes your mindset changes UK because
you cannot you you cannot have two
personalities
you cannot keep two personalities in
yourself like you know like keyboard
layout you cannot be both a Great War
act typist and also quality typist you
you could but this a lot problem you
know you you become inefficient you know
then eating in both of them so so so I
am saying you know if you are a
programmer you know another type
engineer you can learn to be to be a
leader type and you can then leader team
then be great leader but you may not
want to because once you become leader
you can you no longer have the
programmer mindset you rather you become
a good leader type mindset in so in a
sense you are changing yourself so the
question is do you want to make that
change do you want to so that's about
that okay so that so then back to back
to the previous topic what am I doing
with my video and you know what I am
doing with myself you know what what do
I want to be so I'm a philosopher type
so I think about all these things so
what do I want to so for example let's
you know a specific example what do I
want to do with my view Tube videos
that's easy to know yeah the answer is
very easy first of all what is my goal
do I want to be popular for example
let's say at least 10,000 followers
10,000 is not much everyone's got 10,000
if you just focus on specific topics and
not not live you know just to you know
ten minutes video on Emacs for example
every day
10 minutes on Emacs topic not live you
know and folk and and do some practice
like rehearse you know then and edit you
know you focus on ten minutes Emacs
subject and then after after half a year
I'll be I don't have ten ten ten
thousand followers I'm pretty sure I
mean yeah just focus on that don't do
don't talk about controversial things
you know don't flame free software open
source don't don't get into that thing
just do that so that's one if so if I
want to be popular that's one of the
thing I can do I'm pretty sure I can you
know I'm and I'm capable of doing that
that I know this at least for Emacs you
know I know that you know I can do that
okay some things you may not be capable
of but for Emacs I can do and I can also
email this anyway so first of all what
is what you want to do so so you have so
one of the question is do you want to be
popular okay then there's also
subtleties for example what what do you
mean by popularity do you want to okay
10,000 viewers let's say 50,000 okay is
that good enough for you or another
another aspect is like popularity like
do you want to make money I mean is is
your puppet popularity meaning making
money like once you have a lot of
followers you actually yeah you do make
money so that is another question
okay so popularity first of all do you
want to be popular that's one of the
question then there's two branches I
mean is this popularity do you intend to
make money or not or or as a separate
question do you want to make money or
not so that's question then they are
other you know first of all sit sit set
up you know explore this this question
about what you want to what one person
can do on YouTube so there are these
issues popularity
whether you want to make money and then
there's also what kind of things I mean
do you want to content you know for
example content content is in style what
do you want to do and what
what does those has to do what's the
relation between content and style to
the popularity and making money for
example I know for sure that if I do
eMac list then if I focus on Emacs then
I know I will not be as popular if then
if I do something else something
non-technical now I don't know what what
things I can talk about non-technical
that that that that I can do for example
most people with medium follows they are
not none of them almost none of them
very few none of them are like focusing
on technical topic they are all about
memes and you know drama and shows and
stuff Opel eat politics politics is one
of the easy way to become hugely popular
I can do that oh yeah that I can do so
what I do I just talk about politics
politics no Emacs no nothing no
programming well maybe a little bit but
you know so one thing I can do is I
focus you know like I talk about
politics from a programmers point of
view voting from my notes programmer
point of view and what politics I focus
this is important focus on this you know
the social justice the the political
group you know the community like focus
once sometimes you know even try to do a
little quick bait some click bait some
you know dramatic things I mean the
point is you don't want to be fair you
don't want to just talk about true what
is true you because once if you talk
about you know if you are you know focus
on what is truly fair then almost
nothing you know see because politics
you use have to dedicate your life to
retool
research nothing you can make a claim of
something rather the more traumatic the
more by para bipartisan the more popular
you become he almost exponentially so
for example today on the web there's
tremendous popular website that's social
justice warriors on the other hand
there's many tremendous very popular
website that's anti social justice
warriors okay you can you can do them
for example and and a lot of their and
you don't have to have knowledge for
example they are a lot you know we call
them as comedians but they are not
really I mean if you want really want to
classify them then you call them
comedians but they are just like for
example me so I just start to talk about
politics
Oh social justice trying to make it fun
and just you know random talk okay so
that will make you popular so so you
explore the question about what what
what do you want to do on YouTube and
also so that's one way to become popular
but this oh and again is that what you
want to do I mean do it do I want to do
that you know this this is a trade-off
yeah you could do that but is that what
you want to do so they are all this you
so I can analyze the situation well but
but but but there's a question like do I
want to do that is that what you want to
do you know and for many people for most
people you can you know there are many
self-help books that talks about how to
how to change your life oh the eighth
the eighth habits of successful people
I've read them like 20 years ago I've
read these kind of books you know
psychology books what is happiness and
Bertrand Russell has written what is
happiness you know how to be happy you
know I I you know amaz nerd I'm a
philosophy type of guy I've read all
these books how to make friends their
carnage you know how to how to be the
greatest salesman
so for most people you know there are
these self-help books you know as if
you're under you you you can you can
change your life to some other style or
some other things you want but
ultimately there is a question is that
do you want to and and also for a lot
people you that just never happened okay
because you were born with certain
personality is it takes a concerted
effort and also it changes you are
changing yourself that you know you are
this almost like a metamorphosis you can
change into something but there's also
always the question do you want to I
mean even even implicit subconscious not
necessarily a conscious decision you
know you may not want to and then
ultimately there's a philosophical
question about about like I mean
ultimately trace to you know what's the
meaning in life you know that kind of
okay so that's it for today I guess
that's a make it schedule
yeah so that so that is one of the
problem you know I don't have a schedule
why do I not have a schedule because I'm
like that I don't I don't I don't follow
I don't stick to anything and that is
also the reason I'm you know I I don't
have money that's I could I can change
that you know but then you know I you
know that's the question and undecided
no decisions
so yeah I don't know about you guys you
know each person is different like I I
have no idea what you guys look like so
you know I actually so if you guys I
don't know if that's something you guys
are interested but since some of you are
you know you know talking you know
watching my show so often we you know we
could do it online how'd you know if you
guys want to so so anyway I was saying I
don't know nothing about you guys
because from text you know little very
little but if I see your pictures then I
know a lot so so what I'm saying is that
maybe you guys think the same thing
similar or or what it's like what do you
think about what I just said about you
know changing yourself and all that and
maybe you guys you know like maybe you
guys are already happy you know or maybe
you guys are young people you know
struggling or something I don't know
like I have no idea so okay what so
would with what you are yeah that that's
a good point so anyway that's it for
today that today is getting wrong
Microsoft leaders leadership no I mean
not necess not necessarily politicians I
mean you're just a general leadership
personality I mean just even just even
among ten people let's say you just went
to a meet-up with your friends ten
people there naturally among you know
your friends ten people let's say you
went to a picnic naturally like if this
happens naturally it's almost never
artificial it's not like oh let's get
together and vote so for someone no but
naturally when you have a group of
people let's say just among friends
naturally there's someone you know we
all like we tend to think that you know
we let him yeah we let him you know
leaders like when he says let's let's do
that then we go you know do that you
know tends to happen
this is natural so you know I'm not a
leader type so I always like did you
know sewing a goof I you know I also
naturally know someone you know follow
their his lead so anyway but by the way
leadership is not this is not it's not
the best thing is nothing like that I'm
not saying anything like that leadership
is just one of the personality okay then
you have the scar scholarship type
that's this is the engineers you know we
we build things you know as far as
community goes you need you kind of need
all kind of type of people and I'm just
mentioning a few of the personalities
anyway so that's it for today thank ya
thank you guys for watching bye guys