no sound okay so now we have Sun sorry
about that this is screwed up or scooter
okay let's start over
so today's 2020 today he's 2020 January
13th Monday and noon San Francisco time
so today's topic is going to be Emacs
and eMac these live coding press
tutorial so if you have comments
possibly here okay so it's gonna be a
technical session today and if you have
not already joining this code you can
find midas code on solid out info or on
my youtube channel you just go around
and you'll find my exile this discord we
have lots of interesting people and lots
of great topics great people so okay so
let's let's start by yeah so we got we
are going to do Emacs and technical very
technical so if you have any MX
questions Emacs radiates things asked ok
post in the chat ok the first thing I
want to do is I have this odd odd odd
odd blog okay let me show you so we I
started to do just this yesterday but
instead of I end up talking about all
these topics for one hour plus these
fantastic topics about art these are not
just pretty girls but art and humanity
and communication and psychology and
neuroscience in artificial intelligence
and longevity learnt longevity you know
all kind of all sort of things but what
we want to do today is that I have this
art blog you can see so this is a
website and and this is the this is the
source code corresponding to that and I
want to you see this art blog has is
very long so it's like 40 screen 40
screens if you go all the way to the
bottom
the last entry is about you know it's
back to 2018 January so I need to make
an archive you know what what does I
mean so archive for example you click on
here
let's see archive so when it gets too
long I put them into an archive it's not
automated I do it same I manually
whenever it gets too long I manually do
it so let's go back to the art blog and
let's see so we are going to create an
archive of it now let's see how long
have I been so 2018 May so let's grab or
2018 into one page ok now this is
interesting this this this
twing this pears they are how are they
call kappa you know they are mixed race
they are half asian half American half
AC half white something like that but
they are you know they are young people
and they are couple they are actually
married they married like two years ago
or three years ago and they are great
people at they are on Twitter but the
interesting thing about them is that
they are posters you know the things
they put out are usually very artistic
you know it I find them very interesting
for example this this picture so you
have this guy you know sitting like that
you know it's a it's got a post and then
girls looking it at him her lover like
that so I find you know it's I will say
it's artistic
so anyway I'm not going to talk about
these topics we are just going to do
Emacs so so on the Emacs page this is
HTML source code I go to the button
search for archive okay it's right there
so I open it so it's a list of archive
so I'm going to create a new one so I
copy this line paste it enter so you see
this line is now double cut
now I'm going to change the date to 2018
okay 2018 January let's go back to the
blog to the bottom page up page up yeah
2018 January so I rename these to 2018
January okay and this page does not
exist so I press Enter
he says file does not exist okay do I
want to create new No instead I want to
kokum and you can see the left window
the pink window it shows all my commands
you can if you find a command that's
interesting you can search the command
name on my website you'll find the code
so I want to create this new page based
on this page basically make a copy so
what I do is I move the cursor to this
to this href to this link to this
position and I call the command saw copy
HTML by link you see that's a command at
the mini buffer so enter it's done now
if I you know the cursor is moved here
now if I press ENTER you're open that
file so you see this is a copy of that
of the previous archive blog archive so
so I open this in search for section
search for section wait okay so there is
no section actually I want to delete all
these contents okay and delete go all
the way down and delete them section
sections section TV them okay so now you
open in browser again it's empty we
accept the ads so back to Emacs rename
the title so I want to say 2018 January
enter okay the you see the name is
changed in both places in both this
title and also in this h1 header so in
browser you can see the header is now
2018 now
close this file and close this archive
file now we are back in my blog that
don't blog file so I want to now I want
to move everything that's 2018 to that
new page so what I do is I search for
least matching lines okay let me show
the command so I'm going to search for
this word okay this matching line is
state so you can see in this window it's
all the entries so I want to go to 2018
so here okay so I enter you'll jump to
your jump to that position which is here
so I copy I select it and go all the way
down to the last section cut okay so I
just cut the whole thing now go back to
my blog archive and open open this 2018
one the one we just created it's there
and paste the entire thing showing
browser now you can see we have just
created a new page so arts blog 2018
January so this is basically January to
December or 2018 and you can scroll down
you can see all the you know 2018
entries so that's good close it back to
Emacs close it and on this archive page
this 2018 needs to be on top so cut it
move to here and paste it so now the
18 entries on top showing browser that
is correct okay close it back to Emacs
close it now this is my this now this we
are back at the long block page so if we
go back to my art blog page let's see
here you see this is my art block now if
we go
all the way down you see we have not
refreshed the browser yet so it's still
2018 here you see 2018 but now if we
refresh it all the 2018 entries will be
good you can observe the scrollbar the
scrollbar will kind of get longer so let
me do it so we're gonna I'm gonna press
refresh okay
refresh there it is you see the last
entry is now 2019 so so essentially this
my blog has shrinked by half almost and
you go to the bottom you click on the
blog archive so you have 2018 entry
click on that there it is
so I just I just you know made the blog
archive now there's one more thing to do
so go to the top of this page search for
section showing browser okay so you see
this is my art blog and there is a
subscribe RSS feed you see this is the
last entry yesterday's entry now let's
go back okay go back now I need to on
this ISS feed
I need also also need to truncate it so
if you go all the way to the bottom you
can see the last entry is 2018 I need to
remove them so let me show the show you
the ISS file so in backing Emacs go to
tired so this is my block art blog and
here the block dot XML is the RSS atom
entry so open it you see it's got 667
kilobytes right now so you open it go
all the way to the bottom you see the
last entry let me show you the last
entry is this one tick 4
sit and it's the entry date is 2018
January so like before we need to remove
all the January's January general
January's entry so what we do is we
leased matching lines and I want to list
all lines containing the word tag okay
so there it is
magnify magnify so you you see the tag
contains the creation date so we want to
remove all the 2000 and 2018 entries so
the lat
so the oops I already clicked but that's
good so this one this is the 2018
December 31st so I jump to it okay
expand window that's this one so from
this one on onward to all the way to the
bottom delete it it's deleted you see
now the last entry is 2000 wait there's
another 2018 okay so we we had a off by
one arrow so this this entry is also
2018 so delete it delete it delete it
okay so now make a backup and save one
shot in one shot okay it's done now go
to tired refresh now you can see this is
a current file plot dot XML now it's 200
I mean it's 26 kilobytes and you can see
this backup file it's 67 kilobytes
because we have removed lots of things
so that's good so close the XML file
close that we are done now all we have
to do is go to a shell and saw let me
show you this command so I mean ischial
now I want to call a a sync command to
so to sync to my server but
however I have a the icing command is
very long like 200 300 characters I
don't remember all the options you know
the UNIX philosophy idiots you know with
the commands with incomprehensible 100
options like like like this one okay
like that one in a top so I want to code
I command I have a brief but I forgot
what's a brief because I have hundreds
literally hundreds of abbreviations
abbreviations in Emacs is the best
feature okay so I did a video talk about
Emacs a brief so you you might want to
watch it you know goes such Maya on my
youtube search for Saudi Emacs a brief
so I have a tutorial anyway so I have a
brief I have hundreds of brevis and
sometimes you know some of them I don't
use every day so I forgot what is
abbreviation name you see that's the
thing for example I want to call this
awesome command and I remember I do have
a brief but however I have several are
synced to different servers to to my
professor server to work server to you
know I don't remember what's a deviation
for that a sink you know command in that
situation what you need is Casa smart a
brief so in fact that command is called
this okay so let me show you
echo it so this command is called saw
interactive abri so you see in the mini
buffer it will show me a list of names
that I have a brief for so you can you
know in fact I can you know go over them
wait
so you see I call the command saw
interactive a brief so you can you know
you have all these ssh youtube download
vm inbox vm of image one for changing
image size or converting image from jpg
to PNG so on image scale image 256 that
means reduced color to 256 so the all
these are abbreviations so if I type it
you know if I select that one you see
then I get this command this is the
actual command I want now this is more
efficient than the bash alias okay now
now my friends you know I see on this
code many people they discuss their bash
aliases which is great but if you want
ones level up one level up in efficiency
you want you want to do it in Emacs Asia
and you want to do it within a brief or
short cut
that's more efficient and in better in
many ways I can go into detail why it's
better but maybe not so anyway I want to
sync to my server so I call a
interactive a brief I think that's the
first entry okay enter and password now
I have a Emacs commands that typed my
password which is in in secret in you
know it's not in my Emacs a pre file so
there it is now I have synced to my
server okay that's one thing we want to
do does that make sense people does that
make sense does that 14 people watching
okay so say something guys so now I sync
to my web server fantastic I'm done I'm
done with this job but actually this
page is still very long so 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
8 9 10
about 30 page 30 screenful maybe I
should do another one that removes all
year 2019 to a different entry yeah no
I'll just leave it okay so leave it and
this is this is web feed RSS file we
don't need it close it ok that's one
thing that's one job done let's move on
to the next Emacs Tech geeking thing
let's see what's the next item we want
to do so ok any questions
Jen's comments posted okay so the next
thing I want to do let's see they are
quite a few things okay so you can see
let me show you let me post this so you
can go there and tell me what is your
what what do you like to see so you can
go there and tell me make a selection
all these are Emacs or images related
things so let me check my server status
my health 21 minutes good 15 people
watching so what is the next thing so
Paris I should get some drink
that was that was great
grape juice grape juice 100% grape juice
first energy drink now now tea
okay next topic let's see what I want to
do Emax modify command log mod yeah
let's do that
maybe you think I should let's see let's
try something control X control F okay
control X control F ok so let's you see
on the left window you can see all my
Emacs commands and that is done by this
command let me show you saw start
command log mod control H F that will
code describe function so this is my
this is a command I wrote that start up
the command log mod you see on the pink
window good morning Justin so if you
guys have comments questions about Emacs
post it ok so here here is a command I
wrote that starts the command log mod
why do I write this command because the
command log mod let me show you the
command log mod ok command log mod is
this one ok here is a source code of
command log mod by by Michael Webber and
also by Nick Fourier lai-wan and back in
2004 v free software foundation I guess
ok wait how is this 2004 copyright by
free software foundation so that means
this should be so is is this actually a
new Emacs package I mean is this bundled
in Emacs oh so it looks like this is
actually part of Emacs although it's not
bundled in Emacs but it's
Sigurd part of Emax possibly in ALPA
because normally when you see a package
you read a header normally it will say
this this file is not part of Emacs that
means you know people created it and the
copyright does not belong to Free
Software Foundation no money so but in
this one you don't see that but that
doesn't mean much because maybe they
didn't they forgot to add that you know
there are lots of things going on so
anyway so this this this package we
unlock your commands like I've shown on
the Left window but however the
documentation and the user interface is
very lousy it's it's like very confusing
so I wrote this paragraph that tells you
exactly what you need to do in order to
start this command lot mod ok so these
these few paragraphs
I added but it's but it's not on their
github this is just my personal copy and
I've also modified part of this code
what I want to do is that you see this
this printout you see there is a big
number of spaces between these you know
on the left the key on the left is the
key on the right is a command name and
there's a big number of spaces I think I
want to shorten them or something so
let's see if we can do that so search
for print list matching lines print so
nowhere to be found
let's try again this matching lines mes
s a message ok nowhere to be found so
that means they are actually not using
any sort of message or print they are
using insert I think
least matching lines insert okay let's
see you know I want to write my own
version of this command log mod because
I'm not happy with this I'm not happy
with the way it is I don't want you know
so I'm trying to modify it so that the
output will contain less spaces like
that and so that is one what I'm trying
to do and now the question is where do
you want to change that so apparently
they are not using any print command
because okay search PRI n oh they are
they are using there it is indeed so a
Emacs if you don't know you have three
print commands actually more than three
depending on how you count for example
insert is one of the print command and
you have print see print T and print one
so you have three versions of the print
command then you have also message
command so it's a bit confusing if you
don't know go to ha the Emacs this
tutorial so you go to my tutorial and
buy my tutorial ok bye my tutorial if
you like my stuff so you go to my eMac
this practical eMac B's and you search
for search for print you are see at the
bottom at the bottom you are see where
is it let's search again print print
item print there writing script print
output print and output so
so on this page I explain everything you
need to know about printing output so
you have the messages command which
prints to the messages buffer then you
have the insert command which just
insert a stream to the current buffer
then you have print you have print one
then you have print see three variations
of print what they do is that they print
to the default output stream by default
it is standard out it's a bit complex
but anyway they did they print to you
know a channel and the wifey of them
because print is to print in a human
readable form okay wait print see the
print see is to print into a human read
of readable form for example if you
print a list of strings the strings we
are not print with a double quote you
know so it's more easy to read princey
let's print see then print the print
command is just to print in basically a
in a format that lists can read back as
much as possible and it will also
include a new line at the end now that
print one is just like print except that
it does not include include a new line
at the end so minor differences so
that's why you have this anyway so there
it is my tutorial you can you can read
about so let's close that let's go back
to the talk show and paste it there so
we have one topic we paste the topic
here okay
so actually I won't want that showing
browser okay so print so let's go back
to the code the command log mod output
code I want to find where does it print
to the command sank so it actually takes
some time to read into print so what is
this okay so looks like here is this is
a line that does the print and that is
printing so what is current okay it
trains to current is the current buffer
yeah any comments questions type it I'm
getting bored I'm getting bored with
this so I'm trying to find out so this
line this line is trying to print to the
current buffer and command repetitions
so this line what this line is doing
corresponds to this part you see that
three times that corresponds through
that okay so that's these three lines so
what we want is somewhere before
so this part is trying to get the number
of repetitions okay and command log of
so where is the part that prints
prints the actual key and command name
okay so here is okay so let's see what
is is so condition base
good morning base any questions comments
okay so I see this is trying to print to
The Times right and the printing Times
comes before printing a command because
because if the current command is the
same as the last command then it just
update the time so the actual code that
prints the command name and key comes
after the comes after the printing of
the repetition times okay so we know the
code comes after these okay wait okay so
let's see so now let's see when
something-something text okay now this
part is for typing this part for example
let me show you okay so let me speed the
window new buffer magnify common buffer
type something you see normally this
will show up here but I suppress it okay
this is getting more complex complicated
let me just try to fix this okay so so
I'm trying to do a live coding press
explanation but the explanation part
part is often very difficult because
pretty soon you know I'm good I need to
explain all over the place
you know it's like when you do a live
stream you want you want only to touch
the most basic part because
you know it gets complex and people
don't understand but if you start to
explain the complex part then it gets
you know it becomes a ten hours video so
you have this dilemma which is right now
I'm stuck in because I'm trying to get
this to work but meanwhile I try I want
to try to explain it anyway so let's see
so the other option is just to simply
get what I want you know just to code it
without explanation okay so let's see
okay so where is it so insert okay so
insert let's see insert profit profit
eyes key description this command keys
okay so this part this part is inserting
the key on the left column you can see
on the pink window on the left column so
this line is inserting the key now we
are very close to where we are so there
it is
so when when the current column is
greater than this command lot this this
indentation then you insert a new line
okay so this is so let's so looks like
all we have to do is to modify this CRM
log command indentation so let's look at
it
search for it such such such there it is
CRM lock command in temptation 11 okay
11 I don't want you Devon and actually I
don't like it okay so I don't like this
command okay this is not this smart this
package is not written by me
I don't like things not written by me
the way they do things you know this so
because what you wait what I pressed
some key and that okay so apparently I
pressed SOG read novel mod okay let's go
back so you see I want to modify this I
want to modify the space the number of
space here is too much I don't like it
so I want to modify it but not just
space because I want also to add a unit
unicode character such as lying or a
bullet so we can clearly see as the
separation but this package do not does
not allow me to do it because you got a
number here which which is a number of
spaces so what you can can you do well
let's say five let's just say five okay
let's see what happens and also define
var define Y is a very annoying thing in
Emacs because when you have defined var
now you cannot change the you cannot
change you know if I change the value
and I if I read this buffer that will
not walk because define var the the
thing with define var is that if the
value is not neo then Emacs will not
change it that's actually a bad design
you know do you guys know what I'm
saying you know because otherwise I have
to explain that then you will take five
minutes but we have a lot other things
to do so so what do you do is instead
let's try this if this works okay set Q
SiC you okay that let's say six okay
let's change this back to 11 okay now
I'm going to evaluate this line done
okay then that's let's let's just say
let's just say six there okay then let's
just restart create Emacs let's restart
Emacs
I'm actually cold and let me put on a
coat
there it is
Emacs as we started now let's start
command log mod ok magnet magnify buffer
ok it worked that completes that task we
have completed another Emacs task any
any questions questions base justing
megalo schemas outshined questions
comments so look at look at the shell
okay so in Emacs you have these lot lots
of unix garbage
you know the unix garbage you know these
lots of arrows this happens all the time
you know it just spit out warnings or
whatever and and they are
incomprehensible okay so look at look at
this 2020 January 13th 12 o'clock
something Emacs x86 64 you know this
idiot
these UNIX idiots with these job ins you
know like when you go to when you go to
Kunal
Emacs website you try to download you
have no idea what they are saying so let
me show you
sorry max soca' sorry max you go to
practical practical Emacs tutorial you
then you go to then you see this is Mike
sorry max - Toby oh and you have a poem
there hi I wrote this poem like 17 years
ago the church of emacs feeling of
Charles lispy and binding buffers insert
young meta sex at hook 8 megabytes and
console swapping this is the church the
song of church of emacs ok
had this poem since about 16 years ago
and I removed it in the in the last
three years or so because because in
today's environment the social justice
has you know mentality so I was thinking
you know maybe I should try to be more
professional and remove this language
kind of thing but no that doesn't work
so I put it back you know you want to be
yourself so this is my Emacs website
this is my style and this is my poem so
I put it back here so anyway this is my
eMac to the Emacs tutorial so you go
there and you go to where to download ok
so this is where you download Emacs and
you have windows you have Mac you have
gnu/linux you know on Windows on the Mac
it's that you have precompiled binary
meaning that you just go there download
it unzip it or you'll drag to your you
know app folder you can use it right
away but for Linux and UNIX that doesn't
work you have to compile it yourself you
know Tech qicang that is why in Linux
nothing works everything is [ __ ] up
you know and Linux you love it it
doesn't work like you know you go there
you have you have to compare and stuff
by the way it's pretty easy if you want
to compile on Linux you just follow
follow my tutorial I tell you four easy
steps to compile it you know these days
today's generation most people they
don't know about compilation stuff
anymore
but wait what's going on with this yeah
close it close close close shell what's
going on so in Emacs
yeah the today's generation you don't
know these things anymore you know
basically config you download it
Xzibit then you run
config configure make and make install
basically that's all you have to do this
is what you have to do to compile stuff
on Linux but actually more than that
because then you have to install build
tools you need to have GCC you need to
have make of certain versions and you
need to have dependencies things like
that so anyway you follow my guide
you'll know how to do it but I'm I'm
going to tell you I was going to tell
you so our Mac and Windows you can just
download it but on Linux you have to
compile it okay so that's why Linux is
always you know how to use among other
things and of course you have
precompiled binary but usually that's
two years old so anyway you know why am
i saying this because whenever eyes
wherever you criticize Linux about
something then there will be an army of
Linux fanatics they will come up and say
oh no no you are wrong because you just
all you have to do is you know Afghan
but the thing with app get is usually
whatever most programs you want to use
the version from app get is like 2 years
old ok the [ __ ] Linux on the other
hand on the Mac you have something
similar you have proof ok you can just
you can just type root install something
it's actually much more simpler than app
get meanwhile the programs you install
by Abreu is not 2 years old like the
Linux Mac you know you might think oh
it's open source therefore Linux is the
foundation of open source so only knows
is actually easier no it's actually not
it so happens on a Mac the proprietary
Apple the Evo Apple where they make your
phone slower whenever they have a new
version things like that you know evil
apple but it so happens some of Apple
things are actually much more easier to
use even even for the open source
programs like when you install Python
not yes no for example let's
update not jeaious okay I think it's the
command is prude update not jeaious okay
let's try blue update not I don't even
have to man page or something like that
you know
okay so brew upgrade not yeah so you see
it just tell me the right you know I
don't have to dig so brew up great not
okay before we do that let's check what
what what is current my current not
version not yes is the program that runs
JavaScript okay so which not okay so use
a local be not I don't think that's the
current version let's try not - -
version version 12 it's pretty decent I
I think it's from last year but you see
the thing with not is that they update
every year so I have version 12 let's
let's try to run it okay Globo GL obal
todd BL e GL obal dart version I think
no that's not I have to look up I forgot
anyway so I'm running north version 12
ok exit okay
now let's prove update not
my roommate is back so it's running
update ok so just in says you living
inside the church of emacs yes of course
can I build one too yes if you are on a
Mac you can also be old
Emacs but however I do not have
instruction for how to build Emacs on
the Mac but it's not difficult because I
can tell you that there's a guide from a
friend from from this guy he's got he be
odd he be Oates Emacs on the Mac every
few years so I've seen how it so it's
not difficult so if you want to be old
Emacs on the Mac you can but you don't
you don't need to ok for the Mac just
download this one this is this this is
the one I'm using you know go to my
Emacs tutorial the first page download
Emacs then you just go to the Mac and
download this one ok
download this one 26.3 hi this is what I
recommend
this is plain kun Emacs no fluff once
you download it you can install other
things ok we are back to shell updating
phew now it's a still update improves ok
so what I wanted to say is that you go
to you know download Emacs then you go
to windows ok so this is a windows
download and
so Alan good morning Allen says the
MINIX are started talking about mac OS x
just working my macbook just crashed
okay so you go to you know this this is
goon website
this is goon website so they have Emacs
versions you know you click on Emacs 26
this is for Windows ok and you see this
crap you know this you see this tech
tech clickers tech geeking [ __ ] these
idiots this open source and free
software extreme idiots you know you see
this filename suppose you are mom
suppose you are your mom ok so people
say oh you can download Emacs oh you
don't need to be a programmer you Emacs
is actually easy to learn you know you
you hear that from Emacs from the mouths
of Emacs phonetics they will say that
they will say actually Emacs is not at
that difficult actually you know they
they will tell you the story about how
secretaries are using Emacs you know
like 30 years old story so ok so you try
to be you know think think you are your
mom ok so you go to this page you are on
Windows you want to download Emacs
because your son told you Emacs is the
greatest editor so now you are on this
page which one which wonder of the [ __ ]
to download tell me these [ __ ]
these idiots you know you tell them that
they don't understand this typical Linux
open source free software foundation of
foundation phonetics you know they tell
you everyday or Linux is great new nice
react actually better than Windows
Windows sucks you know now suppose you
are your mom you hurt so much good
things about you know UNIX leaner so I
mean about you max you go to this page
the first question is which one which
one of these [ __ ] should you download so
look at their names so you they have
Emacs 26 I 6 a
I six eight six - steps okay then you
have okay then you have AI 6i6 a six
then you have x86 okay then you have you
know then you have zip and six six six
six a as sick you know they are thinking
they want to make it secure these
[ __ ] the then you have okay I 686 I
you know then x86 okay then yeah so
that's the two variations oh the only
wait okay x86 then 64 okay so I mean do
you understand what I'm saying do you
think so you are your mom do you think
she know which one to download do you
think she knows that's the first
question and if she don't know how does
she how do you look up like how do you
know which one to download you know yeah
of course your mom even though she's not
technical person but she's not a idiot
right she is very intelligent
maybe she is a mathematician so I am a
mathematician and I've been programming
for 20 years I I don't know what the
[ __ ] out is fact the Linux people I
don't know which one to download because
you know I 64 probably means 60 bits CPU
then I 86 well I kind of know ok so I
686 and the x86 they are kind of short
you know a brief for Intel Architecture
you know it's Intel CPU architecture so
you know I you get my point
so the thing is cannot these Linux
[ __ ] today I mean my question
here's my question ok do they ever
thought about the whether this is a
problem or not you know they think they
are so hot that you know they are
hotshots they are techie cuz they know
so much
okay I should stop ranting about this
you know this this is this is a problem
okay this is this is a real you know one
example of the medium problems with
these Linux UNIX people they think they
know technical details the they are take
kickers they don't know it they are an
incapable of thinking about things okay
I I'm going to stop ranting about this
all right
well today I was supposed to work on
Emacs and emag beast so let's do that so
anyway so we finish this task it works
it's kind of my talk is kind of screwed
up now because I started to run and stop
now let's get back to let's get back to
what we were doing
so Emacs
modify command log mod we did that and
that is successful and what what what
else let's see how many people have how
many people is here yet
13 people okay we already did an hour so
I think that's it I don't get comments
from you guys so I kind of
so yeah so I have a lot more codes I
want to write every time I have these
tasks I was thinking you know I'm going
to do a talk show about it so on one
hand I can do these things I want to do
on the other hand I can also explain and
show you guys as an opportunity to you
know work on a real-life problem these
are real-life problems you know these
are the things I want to do I need to
write the commands to code them but I
think that's it for today
anything else
so just in Skyfire says I thought there
is a physical Emacs Church of course
there is not are you kidding
like sometimes I don't know you know
what your questions always very strange
person but sometimes I don't know if you
are kidding or not so that's it for
today
I think Emacs stuff okay who are you
people say hi you know so I guess I have
many locals you know about that topic
you know I know some people they don't
want to show partly because you know
when you are on the internet you have no
idea like who is watching you whether
maybe your life stream or maybe online
on social network because it could be it
could be your mom your co-workers your
boss or your neighbors or your friends
they are watching you and you don't know
yeah that's that's the case with the
Internet so when you go on internet you
want to be sure that everything you do
is public you know just keep keep the
mindset that everything you do on the
Internet is public that way
you don't get into the situation where
you you know maybe disclosed some of
your secret by mistake
and by the way goat go on internet
publicly is a good thing I recommend ok
so instead of using you know nicknames
or hiding your names things like that I
think it's actually a good thing you go
on internet you know with your name we
will see today's live now I will see
today's name now ok bye guys bye then
demo demo is is from from Brazil yeah
makers wrong they are that's why we need
privacy and pseudo names for zero time
zone complicates me yeah Paseo tamson is
not too complicated
Paseo time zone is only like two hours
ahead so it's like 3 o clock in the
afternoon
ok I'll see you guys bye and bye my Emax
Troy oh ok
in America so this I need to address
poor Dora says in America you can be
targeted in the workplace for political
views that is correct but however that
does not mean you should not get on you
know you should not use your name you
should use your name you go on you with
your real name say what you believe then
[ __ ] then those people who target you
they will be [ __ ] up we are in this
situation today where nobody dares to go
public because you know they they hide
like nuts you know they use nicknames
they they talk garbage it means it means
the fortune stuff they talk garbage it's
because because all of you nuts since
like 20 years ago have the idea that you
want to be anonymous that's why this
happens okay that is why this happens
and it will get worse it will get worse
and worse if you don't start
satis use your real name show your ID
and speak up okay that's my rate that's
my opinion that's my recommendation hi
guys