good morning guys welcome to another
episode of saw talk show today is 2020
January 11th Saturday
théo o'clock in the afternoon San
Francisco time good morning guys I'll
shine zoom welt and Israel and Justine
just seen scoff I and we have one ton of
things to do to talk about I think the
main topic today is supposed to be
mathematics because we have a schedule
we have Linux config okay so let me show
you okay so talk-show here so supposedly
this is schedule we have set you go to
my talk show page and you'll see it okay
Monday Emacs Tuesday JavaScript and so
on so today's Saturday so we supposed to
talk about math so therefore we will
talk about math but let me do some
digression so okay so what topics you
guys like to see but anyway so so what
I'm saying is that so we're gonna talk
about mathematics is the main topic and
today today's talk show so let me show
you today's talk show I want to talk
about several things so many things so
so first of all let me show you my
breakfast and this is my breakfast okay
this is this is Nauti bread with cheese
milk honey and coffee powder and that's
my keyboard and that's my new mouse this
mouse that we're gonna talk about okay
so today we're gonna I'm gonna show you
like 1,000 things so you can see my desk
you see and that is the Logitech g600
Mouse okay so we have this is blue
Windows setup windows shortcuts it it
has like 20 keys
stupid camera on hold on a second let me
get this right okay so it's kind of
clear wack it's kind of hold on a
second so let me move here so so here so
you can you can see those are you then
this is Linux setup so Mac it's red
okay stupid camera this Logitech worst
camera on earth blue is Windows and
white is for Linux
you know it's annoying between Macs and
Windows because on Windows it's
control-c control-v for copy and paste
but on a Mac its command C command V for
copy and paste so if you have if you
want to program a key to switch you know
to copy and paste you have to have a Mac
for file and Windows profile very
annoying people
c-3po boarding balls
zimwi all says ok zoom well is here for
the cellular automata so we shall begin
that because I was going to have a
thousand things then we can never get
into the topic so let's let's begin with
cellular automata ok the game of life
which is a fantastic subject and you
programmers will be interested about it
ok so so so now so we're gonna talk
about that later and so I'm gonna show
you the photos first my photos so this
is the hole I'm in this this desk we're
gonna begin our cellular automata in a
minute okay so but you see the the hole
I am in so this this is my desk
ok that is this monitor is connected to
a odd
odhh OTC okay that PC has hasn't been
turned on for over two years and that PC
is running Linux Linux guys the things
you love and so that is my photos and
then the overview and you can see the
Canisius foot pedal which I did video I
did a video I did a video on this
keyboard on Kinesis keyboard on the
Logitech mouse both of them the spin
wheel Mouse on my right hand and I did
the you know video of that and this is
yesterday's lunch or something and that
Mouse is the Chinese cheap Chinese mas
so okay that's about the photos let's
get down to the cellular automata the
fantastic topic good morning qu for
school
controlled chaos yes control chaos
okay sit automata so let's begin with
that topic let's see let's see so Game
of Life
now do you guys know Game of Life now
have you played some world
have you played game of life game of
life actually I wanted to show you let's
go to Wikipedia okay so have you played
game of life
zoom world answer that please
so game of life it's a fantastic
fascinating subject okay so we can this
is we're gonna talk about that and
cellular automata in general and these
are some of the things people bought for
my Amazon links so this memory stick not
interesting I'm gonna close it okay $219
what is this savage rocket q2 terabyte
PCIe internal SSD oh okay so it's a
storage solid-state drive 2 terabytes
$200
no I'm not interested I'm interested
about our game of life okay you haven't
seen it
Jesus you know a game of life good
morning Cathy game of life I played for
several years in the 1990s you know you
remember this is 1990s computers are not
as fast as today but I played game of
life for several years and so so did
many mathematicians and programmers play
game of life and the game of life is
it's a thing it's a thing that you
learned how you actually visually see
you understand how deterministic things
determinism deterministic things does
not imply predictability now this is
seems like a contradiction like a
paradox because you might think oh it's
deterministic you know like
deterministic means means you know you
have a simple rules like a programming
you know like when you write a program
it's all deterministic as long as you
don't have random numbers well even the
random numbers in programming languages
pseudo-random numbers they are also
deterministic because they repeat so
when you write a program that's it let's
say C JavaScript or Python whatever it's
all deterministic but however it's
unpredictable you see that's a person
because how can it possibly be
unpredictable because you you you code
you know every you know the CPU the
logic you know that the motherboard the
CPU or it's by logic you know it's all
deterministic your program flow but
however it's entity unpredictable why
because the simple okay the the one
single word to to to to say why that is
the case is because complexity okay so
so deterministic things are very simple
no I don't know not artificial
randomness I don't know what you mean by
that but but okay let me what I'm saying
is that so things
deterministic but when you involve so
much so much computed computation it
takes billions of years to run you
cannot predict what's the outcome
because the only way to predict it is to
run it and you will see that
demonstrated in cellular automata but
let me show you okay so let's start to
talk about city automata I was just
going to show you some of the Amazon
stuff so let's let's begin with cellular
automata but I want to get on to discord
first so silly automata okay give me a
second
discord yeah so if you have not already
joined this code
okay cellular automata so let me let me
show you solute HMDA so this is solute
this is game of life Kim of life is one
of the cellular automata okay you look
at the pictures on the right let me show
you let me show you some demo okay so
actually so let's go to best game of
life okay actually we jumping a lot we
jumping all over the place so let me try
to follow some kind of order so game of
life is such that you begin with a grid
okay let me show you a grid you know
just a rectangular grid and on this grid
you you can have each cell each you know
cell in a grid it can be either black or
white
okay then each cell can be black or
white okay you you begin with the empty
grid then you start with some cell you
know black cells either random or
whatever you want
everywhere you want then that you you
say that's the first generation okay so
the next generation you see let me show
you okay you see how these things look
at the picture over here you see how
that how those things kind of moves you
see how those things kind of moves
because
you go by generation so let me get back
to the generation again so you begin
with a grid you put some dots on it then
that's called the first generation let's
let's say the first second okay then the
next generation that the second second
is that you determine it follows a
simple rule that determines that tells
you which cells should be colored which
cell should should remain blank so the
rule is very simple let me tell you the
rules okay you can also go to Wikipedia
and watch it so diminish so they have
some you see they they made some of
these animations to show you and let me
show you this one okay this one this one
is the game of life on a Torah on a not
on my this knot is called try for you or
not you see those stars patterns they
move they move according to a very
simple rules okay so let me talk let me
tell you about what are the rules so
sounds can be modeled by stochastic
process in lower dimension no well
stochastic process is a random process
that's a different topic this thing is
not random this thing is fully
deterministic by a simple rule so let me
let me tell you what are the rules that
creates this moving things you know what
are the rules that creates this moving
things let me tell you so we go to
Wikipedia you know you can read
Wikipedia very simple so let me just
read so here are the rules okay
four rules okay so any essays let me
read it any cell with fewer than two
live neighbours dies as if by under
population so so you have cells I mean
let me show you okay so let me open this
so this picture this grid each point on
it is called a cell so for each cell you
have like 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 8 neighbors
you know the neighbors surrounding the
the the cell whatever cell you are
thinking so each cell has 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
8 8 neighbors so let me let's get back
to the rules so yeah let me be the whole
thing the universe of game of life is an
infinite two-dimensional orthogonal grid
of square square cells each of which is
in one of two possible States alive or
dead okay
alive is black that is white so another
way you say you say it's populated or
unpopulated okay so every cell interacts
with its eight neighbors right so so if
you have a cell here you have 1 2 3 4 5
6 7 8 8 neighbors okay which are the
cells that are horizontally and
vertically and diagonally adjacent you
know neighbors at each step in time the
following transition occurs so these are
the rules these four rules so if if a
cell has fewer than two live neighbours
then it dies okay if a cell has two or
three live neighbours then it leaves on
the next generation okay if a cell has
more than three live neighbours then it
dies again a dead cell with exactly
three live neighbours becomes alive okay
so so here are the rules so in summary
if a cell if if it has two if a living
cell you know a black cell even if it
has two or three live neighbours then
the next generation the cells remain
that cell remain alive
okay but if it has fewer than two
neighbors or more than three neighbors
then it dies in the next generation it
becomes white you know it becomes empty
so that's a rule and also I'm only a
empty cell if it has a day cell with
exactly three live neighbours becomes a
live cell right so a empty empty cell if
it has three black cells as its neighbor
then then in the next generation it
becomes alive you know it becomes black
- so these are the rules very extremely
simple rules so so and they create
things like that they create a pattern
like that
so actually which I should show you
I should demonstrate a live JavaScript
app somewhere so let me search it okay
so game of life
I want to I want to have an applet game
of life download game for Windows PC I'm
gonna show you the best programs for it
okay so don't rely on these random
websites these are mostly I think they
are garbage websites created by Facebook
and Twitter
you know they commercial you know ad
spamming garbage information garbage
websites but I want to find you so does
anyone know a good JavaScript website
that shows scheme of life I want to show
you a live demo so but but anyway this
is a game of life on torus now remember
the thing to remember is that you know
how they moves is all deterministic so
it's very it's extremely fascinating you
see by these simple rules then you have
this pattern it seems to move by it
seems to have a life by itself you know
it becomes it have a life by itself and
so game of life this kind of thing this
scheme of life this is called cellular
automata why is it called cellular
automata because it sells you know it's
just cells and why is it called
automaton because automata is a
traditional term for machines that that
that run by itself so that's why this is
called cellular automata it's
automatized cells and it just run by
itself it just appears to you know have
a life of its own and the game of life
we just described this thing is one of
the thousands of the infinite number of
cellular automata okay so these are all
cellular automata so that's why I'm
talking about cellular automata today
and game of cell is one of the most well
known cellular automata and let me show
you we need to actually we need to
to run a application to show you how you
know you have to see it to you you have
to see it to believe it
so for example on Wikipedia they show
this one now this one is based on
hexagon hexagonal grid so then you have
different situations you know you have
you know you see different patterns
emerging
so this originally came of life or
internally is trying to model population
they are trying to you know Conway you
know this guy John Horton Conway very
well known mathematician John Horton
Conway this guy he's a British guy okay
so yeah I'm going to show you great
softwares you know - children children
is the greatest one because I've been
watching this scene since 1990s you know
it's a big big it's a huge science topic
it's a fatty I mean it's being very
extremely popular among or basically all
scientists and mathematicians you know
so originally it began as a models
started by this John Horton Conway they
trying to find a model to model
population growth growth and also some
theories about population growth or die
out you know population it may grow may
be in might die out become a ghost town
and everyone dies
so they trying to model it by by certain
mathematical rules and you know there
are many theoretical questions about
population growth so for example is it
possible you know one of the question or
internally about game of life you know
with these specific rules is that so is
it possible to begin with a pattern such
that then if the population will grow
infinitely you just grow and grow and
grow and you know go forever
is it possible that's one of the
question and do you know the answer you
don't know
you have to actually pay it because you
see by this simple rule so let me repeat
so you start with a blank you start with
a blank universe you know the grid then
you you put some patterns on it you know
it doesn't matter what pattern but let's
say 1 dot okay if you have one dot in a
next generation your tie because it has
no neighbors and when it has no
neighbors
according to the rule it dies it so you
become empty then instead so one cell is
not interesting but if you put two of
them side-by-side the next generation
will also die die out because each cell
has one neighbor and when you only have
one neighbor you die so next unit so you
become dead again becomes all white
again so but if you have three cells
let's say we arrange them in a
horizontal line that start to become
interesting then you start to have this
pattern this one this one called plinker
you see this one because so for the
sails on the side each one of them has
only one neighbor so in next generation
they die but however the one in the
middle it has two neighbors so in a
channel in the next generation it
becomes it stays like the one in the
middle it stays alive now however the
empty ones you know on top and bottom
each one of them has three neighbors so
in the next generation they become alive
again so you so you begin with a three
dots horizontally the next generation
they become three darts vertically then
they just flip they just repeat forever
so this becomes a stable population you
know which so when you have a three dots
it just flips you know it it's called
each pattern we have given them a name
so this pattern is called Brinker and
then you know over the years so so this
is a verdant you know this is a verdant
Theo two-two
approach you know you can you can play
game of life just just get out a grid a
piece of grid paper enjoy it but that's
very tedious you act you really need to
do this on computer so you know great
programmers lot tons of professional
programmers amateur programmers and
greatest programmers they have dived
years into writing this program and make
trying to make efficient so for example
one of the very well-known game of game
of like programmer is this mathematician
whose name is somewhere here I don't
remember offhand but his name is he
lives right here in California his name
is a great mathematician okay so so he
you know he's a great is one of the
great programmer you know one of the
greatest programmer in the you know in
the past 100 years I what's his name so
his name is I'm sure I can find his name
just give me a second I need to remember
his name he is also the one of the
original lead programmer for the
computer algebra system called Mac you
know written in Lisp máxima yeah a
maximal what was it maximum or do you
guys remember I can't remember the names
but but we all get there okay so
so many so many references I mean I'm
pretty sure one of them is this guy
because he he not only you know he wrote
he devised some of the most efficient
algorithms and data structure for game
of life and also he he discovered many
of the games game of lives patterns in
theories they are a lot there are
tremendous theories about game of life
about cellular automata in general for
example one of the question is you know
what you know one one of the question
for example is reverse scheme of life
that is given a pattern let's say you
draw some random sales you know so is it
possible for this pattern to ever occur
that's a question so in order to to
figure that out
you have to trace back you know you have
to find a pattern that becomes that
pattern is it possible so that's one of
the question so there exist patterns
that can never happen and this is code
anyway there are many jargons and names
for you know then so eventually after
ten years twenty years even today it's
still going
we have many patterns named patterns you
know we have spaceships these are this
on the right column is called spaceships
what they do is that they will just they
will just move okay let's just move and
you know it's a big thing you can you
can play with this in dive into for for
a month
every day you spend on our day and dive
into study you know all the jargons what
they do the speed the movement you can
study it for a month at least but many
of us spend years you know doing this
because for example space this these are
called spaceships okay so what's the
interesting interesting thing about
spaceships what they are is that they
they become a pattern
that will move on a grid you know you
know in the next generation they become
a some other shape on a grid and next
generation they become some other shape
on a grid eventually they become
themselves you know or in general shape
but in a different position so they just
move so these kind of patterns is called
spaceships so once you discover the
first spaceship ship discovered is this
one called glider you know the the
hacker the the hacker guy ESR Eric
Raymond remember he created a hackers
logo that is this one space space ship
code glider okay this this is the first
spaceship discovered now once you
discover spaceship you answered one of
the most original question about game of
life that is is it possible to have a
pattern such that it grows the
population goes infinitely yes to create
that all you have to do is you is to
create a pattern that generates a
spaceship so these are called spaceships
how do you generate a spaceship then you
you have patterns that will generate
this spaceship infinitely let me show
you okay for example this one okay this
classic this this picture let me magnify
okay you cannot make that very much so
you see the okay so the the pattern on
the top row that pattern is called a gun
so you know generation after generation
it creates this glider so so that
pattern is called a gun you know now we
call it a gun so that pattern is the
core good and this gun just creates this
glider and this glider just shoot out
you know infinitely forever so so this
answer the question that it's possible
to have a pattern such that it creates
you know the population
forever so once you have you know this
is fascinating because once you have
this pattern this gun you can you know
you can play you can play with it you
buy you can play by creating several
guns and thus the gliders shoot at each
other you know once they meet they
become some other pattern and then then
you it then you don't know what will
happen sometimes they grow so large like
the explosion they kill the guns they
destroy the guns you have but sometimes
not sometimes they they die out you know
so it's very it's incredibly fascinating
so actually to actually see that I need
to show you some kind of interactive
application you know these days I
haven't been following this for the past
10 years so I don't know right now what
is the best website that has game of
life you know I've been following this
in 1990s and 2000s but not in the past
10 years so I don't know I know they are
you know tons of you know websites that
has this but you but the point is you
want to find a good one
does does anyone of you know okay so
these different life forms grow
organically from the initial cells yes
exactly
so and there are so many theoretical
question about it so one of the things I
learned this in in 1990s is that once
you play this okay you need to find a
JavaScript I'm gonna show you the
programs okay let me show you the
programs now this one this one is what
you want golly
okay so so actually hold on a second let
me sync my website so you can go to my
website for the photo files okay so copy
it
pace it so you go to that link then
you'll find my link about the best
programs for cellular automata you can
download now this one Kali has been
around this guy and root Rev low
Trevorrow he's been writing program
since 1990s so he wrote the best the
best okay I know I know because I saw I
surveyed all of them or cellular
automata programs on a web or on the Mac
or on Windows I know them all in a year
1990s and early 2000s I've seen I've
tried every one of them so this n true
traveler guy he he started to write us
you know this game of life program since
1990s and he his he sees the best
program and then in 2002 he started to
port it to Mac OS 10
you know Mac Mac switched from Mac OS to
Mac OS X you know Unix so so so anyway
this this is the best one okay check out
this Andrew I mean you know you go to my
website and you check this one out
code golly so why is it you know there
are so many so many interesting things
about game of life you know I actually I
want to show you I want to show you a
real gaming in in process because
without without actually actually
showing you you don't get you know like
like animation is worth a million words
you don't you don't see you don't get
what exactly is a deal but once you see
it you see once you see this almost
random ish remember they are not random
at all there's zero random thing going
on the rules are very simple it's
deterministic so you can run this for
million
generation for obedient generation for
kazillion trillion raised to the tritium
billion power of generation pet pet
regeneration or whatever even infinite
so the question is so so you have this
very simple deterministic you know thing
but however let me ask you for example
if you are given this pattern what will
happen in you know will this pattern die
out or we or this pattern become stable
or we are this pattern grow infinitely
one of three choices where they die out
or will they become stable like like you
know the population doesn't grow and
doesn't shrink neither it becomes you
know one like one of those blinker
pattern stable oh we are it you know
grow and grow infinitely so that so
that's a question given a pattern what
will happen to it now you so before game
of life you know before silver automata
you might think oh it's so deterministic
obviously so we can we can predict you
know because we just follow the rules
but the problem is you have to follow
potentionally trillion you know
gazillion trillion you know more than
the life of the universe num x to know
the answer so yes it's in a sense it's
deterministic you can predict it in a
sense but by the time you predict it you
know centuries you know years the earth
will be already dead
so that's the thing the only way to know
the future is to compute it is to live
through it that's that's a thing so this
relates to you know this theoretical
thing relates to many philosophy in real
life as well because you know in real
life we have the question of will do
humans do we actually have power wheel
and you know and what does prediction
means so this you know touches or
answers many of their questions in
part at least you know one thing we know
is that deterministic seem the
deterministic seem systems is may not be
predictable because then it opens the
question of what does prediction mean
you know if we can predict you know what
what does prediction mean it opens that
question so so so I mean if you follow
the game of life you know the sailu
automata then you will see you know we
humans we are you know physically we
there's atoms in quotes or whatever
quantum mechanics
anyway that's getting complicated so
that's about that okay so I want to show
you so okay you you go get that programs
okay and there's another thing I want to
show you for example this one this one
is someone
yeah stupid someone created a cellular
automata on a hexagonal grid she is a
student of computer science okay so I'm
just I'm showing you this example as a
different cellular automata so you see
you can see she's running this on okay
let's open that open it let's go to code
pin yeah what happened to code pain
currently offline Oh code pain is down
Jesus
let me show you okay game of life
JavaScript
yeah I want a page that I want a page
where you can run game of life on a
website a mess you on okay so that's any
questions comments
so if you guys found a good website to
run game of life I let me know okay I
mean obviously there are many apps for
phone Jesus they are awful phone in
stores Jesus these apps in Apple stores
in Android Google stores so the
JavaScript let's say online game of life
online there it is
play on pokey I don't know what what
kind of thing is this Jesus
Franco this is probably not what we want
I can tell because all this garbage you
know these pop cabbage icons on the side
this is a cabbage website yeah I don't
want this
you see these websites when you read
their title you can tell what's in it
their nature you see this played play
the game of life a free online game you
know when you see that kind of wording
it's crap it's just garbage website okay
this this is promising
John Conway's Game of Life let's open
that
okay there this is a good one looks like
yeah this is a good one so let me begin
so we let's say we start with this
pattern
okay let's start now it's that shows the
evolution okay this looks like you know
this start to show evolution of it what
is this clear
Grider okay this is not interesting stop
and we need to run this faster okay so
you can go to the next generation you
can click go to the next generation or
you can just let it run by itself so
that's game of life so you can see okay
wait
so you see those things those are called
beehive those are stable patterns bloat
and mobile oh yeah so anyway that's a
game of life and we actually we want to
make it go faster so you can play these
for you know just for hours and for
years and then you know today as
computer becomes so we I you know this
began in 1990s and okay so so right now
it reached a stable position you see the
generation you can see the generation on
a lower right corner it right now it's
800 and still going but the generation
but but the pattern becomes stable
they don't change anymore because if you
have this pattern by the game of life
rule the next generation they remain the
same because for each cell you have
three neighbors so that means the cell
remains alive and nothing else changes
so that's those are the stable patterns
these three is called beehive this this
square is called I forgot what's the
name block okay so this square is called
block and so once you study so they are
actually a website encyclopedia or wiki
of game of life so you go there you have
thousands thousands of patterns you know
these so discovered by people they don't
you know these things you now we look at
them you see it's all there but we don't
know before so it's discovered every
year so next two years you discover
something new for example once you have
space spaceship you you want to measure
how fast the spaceship moves so they
have you know so in a game of life they
have jargons you know they called a
speed of light speed when you have a
spaceship that moves at speed of light
that means for every generation it we
are
itself you know in every generation
usually you know nothing
typically in you know in principal
nothing will move that fast so they
created this joggins speed of light
similar to the real-world speed of light
you know basically that's impossible
because many of these spaceships they
move by like every five generations they
move how sudden say certain number of
cells so you divide by the generation
the the number of cells
it moves moved divided by the number of
generation it takes to move there is the
speed of a spaceship pattern so you can
read Wikipedia and and there are there
are wiki's and encyclopedias of game of
life and there are still unsolved
questions quite a lot you know very
theoretical questions
and one of the thing let me show you
another thing you know this this this
game of life and cellular automata in
general it's part of theoretical
computer science okay like you know you
guys programmers you you may not heard
of it this is actually part of
theoretical computer science and I want
I wanted to say yeah so one of the
fundamental question about this cellular
automata is about chewy machines you
know you guys probably heard you know
every nerd every idiotic nut says chewy
machine everyday on Hacker News on this
blog every nerd is like oh - new machine
- new machine Oh lambda calculus you
know they don't know now game of
life is one of you know cellular
automata is one of the one of the model
of computation like chewing machines
okay turning machine happens to be you
know becomes a drama kind of thing you
know every nerd is just repeated chewing
between machine to machine doing my ass
dream machine is the most
idiotic most ugly model of universal
computation okay and also because Alan
chewing because he's a gay and he a de
Appel poison you know things like that
so it's drama is by this idiotic
computer with programmers like the
Haskell people s cow and UNIX fever
Linux Fievel so anyway Sandro Tompa is
one of the one of the model of universal
computing machine like chewing machine
okay they are in the same category same
nature and and one up so so so there are
a lot of theoretical computer science
questions about it
and one and I want to show you one of
them yeah so Universal computers so cane
the the question is can you model a
universal computing machine using
cellular automata the answer is yes but
the another question is can you models
universal computing machine using came
up specifically using this this
specifically and the answer is yes you
know we don't know the answer until I I
forgot when like ten years ago or
something you know we then we you know
computer scientists they publish in
journals then you know they publish or
we we discover this pattern that can
model that is that is a universal
computing machine and one and and to do
that what you need to do is basically
you want to find a pattern that emulates
logic gate like you know the or xor gate
so let me show you some of the
interesting things okay so anyway you
you have to play this with this okay let
me let me let me clear a bit more and
show you
Crider okay i don't care about Crider
crea stop crea okay so I'm going to
create a random patterns so the question
is you have to predict what will happen
to this pattern so let's start okay so
there's one grader going off oh so it's
stable it's this is not too interesting
so what what one of the question is can
you have the least number of studying
cells and and such that it goes to the
most number of population like or never
stops that's the question so one of the
well with the pattern we already know a
record you know is one of them I don't
know if they show it here here this are
poorly me no okay this pattern you know
the simple patterns people have
exhaustively already people have already
exhaustively tried them you know you
begin with one cell once they are always
dies you begin with free sale you know
two then three
so people have exhaustively tried you
know the low number up to you know I
don't know what 10 or 13 or something
sales possibility but but you can you
can see how this is computate
computationally intensive because
basically you have infinite number of
patterns and you want to know what what
what they will become you don't know the
only way to know is you have to run it
so let's try this
our pentomino pattern okay let me let me
do that let's try that clear
crea so
okay so let's try that and start and
shrink shrink shrink this will run a
long time like a thousands of generation
I mean I you might have to wait for five
minutes or ten minutes he'll run for a
long time break the loop hey break the
loop break the loop I think I know what
who you are right yes you haven't been
here for a long time I was wondering
where have you been
break of the roof break the roof says is
it a misnomer that the game of life is
called again because it is not a game in
a board of video games yeah in a sense
game in a general sense also he rocks ah
long time no see yes indeed I was
wondering where did you go I was you
know thinking of trying to contact you
on Twitter
but I checked actually I checked like
last week I think you are not active on
Twitter so anyway great to hear from you
and Happy New Year
I have not gotten into trough fortress
but have friends that do and they have
fun stories straw fortress what is that
okay anyway this pattern died stop so
anyway so that's about game of life you
can see it's very computationally
intensive so so this web-based thing is
not that fast you see because most you
seriously get into it
you have a universe that's millions
millions of cells going on
you really the the faster the
computation you know
the the your CPU CPU or whatever your
help so that is why I recommend you get
this program this is pretty much one of
the fastest okay Gokhale I mean also
this is a great programming exercise
okay so you can go and write your own
game of life in JavaScript in Java in :
in C C++ in name whatever language you
like you can write it but however don't
hope for that you know your program will
not be good because because people you
know computer scientists they have dived
into this so much that they have devised
you know the the best algorithms and the
best data structure for this how does
the game of life simulates a computer so
what you have to do is basically you you
want to create a logic machine how do
you how can I explain it
let me see you don't remember you
remember me yeah let me let me tell you
okay so abacus okay let me show you
abacus in you know abacus right
so here we have some pictures of abacus
this is Chinese style you know old old
Chinese style nobody used this style
style anymore and this is Japanese style
abacus so abacus is actually one of the
it's you you know you can call it a
universal computing machine you know you
you you in you know you have bits you
move their positions and you you know
and it follows certain rules algorithms
you know so this is this is actually it
can be a model of universal computing
machine so basically if you want to
model if you have want to have some
motto of universal computing machine
there is a technical way to how that is
defined but I'm not going to go there
I'm not you know there's a technical is
it's really actually it's very it's not
easy to understand basically the way
people do it you know if you are a
mathematician if you are a real computer
scientist you know professor in computer
if you want to publish your paper one
way to do it create a universal
computing machine is to demonstrate that
your model your machine can emulate to a
machine okay that's that's the most
common way in other words you want to
create a system that can model emulate
that can emulate known universal Turing
machines and this is the most common way
to to prove that you indeed have a
universal Turing machine now but what's
the what's the exact definition of
tuning machine without relying on some
existing Turing machine that question
actually I I am NOT I cannot answer that
okay but anyway but I can tell you how I
can give you the idea
of what it means to create a model that
that is a universal Turing machine
basically you can you can for example
you can emulate a calculus
I mean abacus that will do so anyway
let's skip that question I I don't I
don't know how I don't know the answer I
don't know how to that answer that you
know that's a very interesting question
because I really wanted to know that but
that's not a trivial question you have
to read a lot and usually it's difficult
to read so but only of those people who
have really know this stuff well they
can explain and you know don't listen to
any of the programmers they don't know
okay they they they have 20 years
of programming doesn't matter is Haskell
they don't they cannot they cannot
expand and and also or whatever they
spend it's misleading okay so don't
listen to any of the programmers if you
want to know that we you answer you can
you can start to read Wikipedia
Universal machine okay so you you go
read Wikipedia there you have
definitions I can actually if we read
Wikipedia I can kind of interp you know
I can I can explain what it what what it
is universal Turing machine okay Rob Rob
introduction stored-program computer
mathematical theory okay
examples of universal machine coding
okay and programming and they don't yeah
so anyway you have to dive into this
this is this this is a you know this is
a post this is a graduate level
programming computer science okay so if
you are a computer science student you
go to university you get a degree then
you yeah and you wouldn't know you
wouldn't be able to explain that's
that's that's the context about that but
but though although but however it's not
that difficult though you just have to
dive into it a lot but I want to show
you I want to show you some of the
interesting things and that'll be it for
today okay so so yeah let me mention
this as alright so Stefan Wolfram has
written this book a new kind of science
let me show you
my stack of books heavy math books and
stuff
and let me show you
a conflict of vision by Thomas Sowell
this is my one of my favorite author
Thomas Sowell the expose keyboard
fantastic an elementary introduction to
roofin language by Stephen Wolfram he
sent me the book three years ago five
years ago also theory of sets I had this
book since 1990 so you guys can have it
you know I don't money so you see I
don't like that book but you may like
that you know because you know the book
writing style its taste and different
people so this this I talked about this
topic before this is patterns tight
tidings and patterns the professor sent
it to me in 1990s this professor tidings
and patterns this is a classic book on
this is the encyclopedia the Bible of
all theories Smith theories about
tidings and patterns this book a friend
gave it to me
Kuang okay
he gave it to me I haven't read it it's
it's understanding computation
in Ruby so they use Ruby to have code I
haven't read it but I don't think it's
it's not you know I just read Wikipedia
but and here is Stefan Wolfram a new
kind of science this this is heavy big
toe stop her okay
create fantastic pictures you know
detail in detail this this book just
just for the illustration issued wing
award but it's not winning award because
all the people in a scientist or the
scientist don't like this guy because
he's braggadocio that is why he is not
winning awards from this inferior
scientists he think he is the greatest
scientists you see a new kind of science
this entire book is about cellular
automata the things we talked about and
and I have a notes annotation on this
entire book
the crucial experiment experiment the
world of simple programs you know I read
that book like twice system based on
numbers so anyway so this entire book is
about cellular cellular automata and
Stefan Wolfe and he happens to be a
nutcase you know he's a nut job he's
very highly you know he's very into it
he believed that the universe is
actually a cellular automata and he you
know he he's a he's a genius okay when
he's seventeen or something he warned
the bug authors what genius award and
when he is fifteen or something he he
got a PhD from Oxford or Cambridge
something like that he's from UK you
know and when he is and he created
Mathematica and he is twenty something
and he become a entrepreneur you know
run in Mathematica and successful and
when he is you know twenty seventeen or
something he published he's a
theoretical physicist
you know publishing papers in physics
physics journals
you know quantum mechanics or whatever
you know that's so that's this guy's and
he you know he's he's a big he's he's
one of the pioneer or the possibly the
greatest expert on cellular automata and
he believes he's also a nutcase because
he believes the universe is kind of
models are modeled on stereo dominance
and things like that okay so you have to
so that's my that's my that's my notes
about that's my notes and opinion about
that guy and so let me show you one more
thing okay two more things actually so
one one of the things I want to show you
is scheme of life recursion and the
other one is jargons of chalk and
automata in finite state automata now if
you are a programmer you
might have heard of automata and you
might have heard finite state automata
you know it's especially if you study
compilers you will have heard of that
because you know yes yeah
and why automata because like I
mentioned before automata and cellular
automata they are they are kind of the
main topics in theoretical computer
science you know by the way you don't
you don't hear about these things in
average programming community you know
the average in farming community hackers
you know you hear about Linux main page
you know UNIX Unix Linux so small it's
beautiful UNIX philosophy hotel
recursion or has come on add or category
those of those are crap
okay those are the most are
idiotic you know they telling you
about you know that's that's what you
hear every day that's your brain if you
are that's why you know sometimes I
flame programmers and many of you
you know maybe many my follow I think oh
my god so this is a weird guy very weird
but I'm trying to show you why that is
the case because you know I'm trying to
give you something examples why I said
is true ok maybe exaggerated maybe in a
dramatic way but it makes sense because
you don't hear you don't hear what I'm
talking about
you know today for example today the
topic about computer science about
theoretical computer science about
cellular automata about what does it
mean a universal Turing machine not just
to a machine ok we're talking about
universal computing machine and over
about automata you know this you don't
hear you don't hear in a hacker news you
know this computer programmer
idiots
every day they are like vi v vr I mean
you know the Haskell
oh-oh-oh-oh-oh-oh parallel you know
there's something something something
there jargons you know the
object-oriented programming patterns
these foreheads meanwhile you don't
where you know when I talk about these
it's like he what he said you never
heard of that's the thing you see that's
a difference that's the difference
between the programís community they are
not doing any computer science at all
they are just drama okay I digress into
a rant so I wanted to show you the the
one more thing okay
oh yeah so so about the jargons automata
that's very interesting story because
automata this jargon began about 2,000
years ago in the story of Europa Europa
in the book okay III talked about this
in one of my videos before you rope I in
the pool let me show you there so this
pool and which is a foundation of
Western philosophy Western society
Europa and the bull Europe is named
after her Europa and the pool is God the
Zeus the omnipotent the all-powerful God
and he seduced or waived Europa okay so
that that is why the word rape is on
every white guy's mouth every day bleh
bleh bleh bleh bleh this this is that
bleep every day they they are they their
brain is filled with it because this is
part of the foundation of Western
society the philosophy their their their
train of thought you don't see anything
else they see they just see justice
justice rape and you know this this this
thing that that's the foundation so you
refine the bull and and you have you
know we have several of these artworks
it's fantastic okay fantastic and ok let
me tell you the story so how it relates
to automata so Zeus the all-powerful God
he saw this pretty girl young of course
younger pretty young girl those lovely
beautiful
so the Zeus wants to her so
u.s. change himself into a great giant
beautiful white pool okay and you know
he just go go to the girl you know you
know like like trying to do nothing and
the girls then girl being girls you know
oh my god beautiful boy and you know she
tries to start to pet the bull so that
this is the story of the seduction of
Europa bye bye bye Zeus the God the
all-powerful king of God king of all
gods Zeus so then the ball just went off
you know the the the once the Europa
hopped onto the poor the poor just run
off and you're like oh my god they
cannot get off so they are poems about
it since like 2000 years ago 43 PC okay
so here's a poem described in the
situation okay so let's see how long
have I been talking okay we are losing
audience quickly so it says and
gradually she lost her fear and he
offered his breasts for her
caresses his horns for her to wind with
chains of hours and so on and in anyway
so but Zeus gave her three gifts and one
of them is okay so the escape gave her
three gifts when one of them is a giant
automaton which means a robot and that
that is this thing you know this this
coin from from what era 2,000 years ago
300 BC so so 2,300 years ago this coin
so that's automata basically a giant
robot so when you see maker today the
arrangin is
not Japan it squeak automata this thing
2,000 years ago sewers created this
thing as a gift to to this girl Europa
that's one of the gift okay so so let's
see so you can read about my articles ok
Europa so one more thing I want to show
you is recursion okay so Kesari game of
life recursion i'm gonna show you that
and that's that's it for today Conway's
Game of Life recursively defined
so let's go to you YouTube
so let me copy that and put it in my
talk show
okay let's go to youtube magnify and
watch this and that'll be it for today
great to see you great break loop break
the loop and
there it is you see that that's
recursion so you have game of life that
emulate game of life by itself you see
that you see on the surface we see you
know these cells black sails and white
cells but actually that black cell is
actually 1 billion cells inside it so
you have like Vic ocean you have game of
life within a game of life we and this
is how you do this is what it means to
have a universal computing machine now
that's a bit hand waving because yeah
I'm not sure what I'm saying here but
what I'm saying is that recursion this
kind of recursion thing is intimately
tied with about how you can how about
the definition of creating a universal
computing machine ok so I don't know
exactly how they relates but I do know
it's like very much related I don't know
if it's one implies the other or not but
there it is an example so you can see
recursion with yeah so thank you guys
for watching yeah you know why am i saw
this this begin this video came out in
2011 and this guy later on I learned
Mike stay Mike stay is also a
mathematician he's on Twitter he was you
know he's also on Google+ and you know I
talked to him once once way anyways so
he created this in 2011 and turns out
he's a student of that mathematician I
talked several times what's his name
there is a mathematician I who taught me
a lot of math ok I can find his name
easily just give me a second
this guy okay so this guy John John bass
okay so John bass is a great
mathematician he taught me a lot things
so that this guy who created this
because if Gambel of life is happens to
be a student of John bass so yeah so I
mean so this is very much theoretical
computer science stuff but what's my
point
oh yeah so so this came out in 2011 okay
and I when I saw it it's amazing it's
like it it's it's kind of you know it's
it's sent a chill down your spine it
kind of gives you a different perception
of the universe okay bye bye guys