Good morning everyone. I'm alive.
Welcome to another episode of talk show.
Video check, audio check. So we are
going to code Emac Lisp today. Pure
Emacis. If you are here, say hi. If you
are not here, play at 1.5 speed because
I ramble just like the Joe Rogan monkey.
Okay, so we're going to code several
things, but let's see, you know, if we
have time, we're going to go to the next
one and next one. So the first one I
want to do you know I I the title of
today is HTML amp% code decoding code
and let me show you that command. Okay
something let's say you know on my on my
Twitter uh let's say you copied some
text that's my keyboard by the way glove
80 fantastic I have reviews video
reviews and on sali.info info, lots of
photos. Okay. Glove 80 keyboard. And you
can see, you know, several uh photos of
it. Uh glove 80. And uh so that's that
one. And this is ultimate hacking
keyboard. By the way, there's Ultimate
Hacking 80 coming up. I think I'm going
to review. Uh I need to contact them.
They, you know, anyway, I think I'm
going to review it. So, Glove 80,
fantastic. Okay. So, GLV ultimate
hacking keyboard. Okay. And you can find
it on sudi.info and um and my YouTube.
Search for it. You'll find it. Okay. I
need to adjust. So, this one is uh
Swarboard SV A L B O A R D. Fantastic
device. I have a uh I have video reviews
on it too, but other people have
reviewed it. I'll be using it, you know,
down the road. So today uh let's code
let's start coding email list shall we
shall we? Okay. So, video check, audio
check. Good. Okay. Let's go.
So, let's see. So, the uh so the the the
title is HTML amperand. Okay. So, let's
say you know let's let's say if I copy
something from uh Twitter or anywhere
um you know this is a device about
keyboard. Copy it.
And let's say if there's some amperand
uh this and that.
Okay. And you want to put on your blog.
So you cut that and uh you know paste it
on your blog and make it paragraph
showing browser and you got that. But
actually that is technically invalid
because for the amperand character you
need to encode it. Okay. So let's
magnify.
So you need to actually encode that amp
percent. So there's a command uh let's
see what is a key. Press
uh press press
undefined. I forgot what's a key. So
let's press and uh control H. Let's see.
Search for amperand. Okay. Tap j. That's
keyboard layout. Okay. So you can see
all my command codes and the command
name on the right side in the pink
window. Command keystrokes on the left.
Okay. Tap j on bora keyboard. Encode
amperson entity. Okay. Search for
ampersand. And there's also decode amp%
entity. Tap j. Okay. So
place a cursor anywhere in the on in
this block of text. Tap j.
You see they encoded the whole thing. So
that's not what you want. You see now it
becomes you know paragraph. So undo. So
basically you want to make it you know
let's remove the paragraph. Okay. So
save it. Close. Reopen. So there we are.
And uh and uh tap j. You see that emp%
got encoded. Now you put in the you put
in the paragraph show in browser. Now
that is correct. Okay. Similarly, if you
have programming languages such as x =
to 3, if
you know x= to 3 something, you also
want to encode that greater than sign
because that is uh technically require
well
it is in XML it's required but in HTML 5
uh as long as you have space around it
that's kind of okay but strict you Oh,
you should encode it. So, let's try it
again. So, tap j. You see now it's good.
Fantastic.
Okay. So, that command is uh let's see
describe key tab jet. That command is
this encode HTML encode entity. Okay,
let's open it. And you can see the code
the the code is actually on this page
showing browser.
So you can grab it but it doesn't work.
It won't work because it requires my
other packages replace pairs region. So
you can see this command is written in a
very compact way
you know replace entities very compact.
So you do do is find replace you know
this amperand characters and less than
and greater than
and uh it's calling one of my function
my package replace pairs and you can get
that uh by click on that you get this uh
you can get the source code. So actually
if you want to use this command you can
copy it and grab it. But however what I
want to do is I want to replace the um
custom call I mean replace using my
custom function. So it so it is not so
it doesn't have dependencies.
So it's pure e- magnes.
Okay, that's what we're going to do.
Okay, that's and also once you highlight
it, you can see let's see open it back
close uh close. You can see it actually
highlight where wherever this uh change
occurs. So that is a great feature.
Okay, that's one of the things I want to
do, but I was going to do others. Okay,
let's just since we already spent five
minutes talking about this, let's just
do this. Okay, so let's uh amperand. So
where is that's let's let's move to the
top. Okay, so put it there. Show in
browser. This one the first one we're
going to do. Okay, let's rewrite it.
Okay, so percent in code. So let's um
let's do it. Okay, so the key is tab j
in sa html mod. That's the command. Jump
to the source code. And what we going to
do is we just going to copy
make a new buffer. Paste it there and uh
save it.
xx today's state command name.
So we're going to work work on this. Uh
make it underline underscore. Okay. So
uh wait
a percent there. There it is. Okay. So
you need not to make this bigger. So uh
you can do shift paren then it hides all
the details. So this all my commands.
So there it is. Open it. Okay. At the
top add x UTF. That's the abbreviation
for this declaration. Lexico binding and
UTFA encoding. Okay. Save it. Make a
backup. Okay. So, we're going to modify
this command. So, actually we can write
it from scratch. Okay. Let's see what is
uh Oh my god, the font is so large now
that I'm not not used to.
Okay. Comments if you are here. Okay. If
you are not here, watch at 1.5 speed.
Okay. replace HTML characters amp% less
than greater than to this this encoding
on current current text block or
selection. Okay, we're going to modify
this change the date. So let's think.
So effectively what this command the
requirement is that first of all you
need to make a se uh you need to set up
a block that is uh you know like what
region you want to uh deal with. Okay.
And we have it here. So let's you know
this is one gga line. This one ga line a
long line. That's I I like that format
very much. Okay. because I've been
coding wufam language. This is normal
one, you know, one gig got long line.
But let's reformat it so it's uh easier
to read. Okay. So you got if statement
then that else then you got another if
statement then then you got list. Okay.
Jump to the back. Put a uh then okay now
now purify the code. Now it's much
better. Do it again. Uh
so the first job is to determine the
beginning position and end position. We
want to work on this. Okay.
Okay. So so that is what this this block
of code does.
Video check, audio check. Good. Okay.
Okay. So now
uh this block of code so so this
function takes a begin end got now the
font is very large okay but it's good
for the YouTube so region begin end
then report true if it's true you print
the report and if it's true highlight
then you highlight the changed locations
okay so okay let me just work on this.
So, so that's this. So, begin end that's
our local variables. That's each one is
a integer meaning the cursor position.
Okay. And then we set sequence set this
beginning end variable. Then if if the
parameters begin end are already given
you see that's you know that's the
parameter then just return a list. So
you know make them the same otherwise.
So if beginning end is undefined new
then determine if region is active. If
so then you just say region beginning
and region end. Okay. That returns the
beginning and end position of a
selection. Okay. Now if there's no
active region then what you have to do
is you need to go to search to the
beginning of the empty line and search
for the end of empty line. So that's the
text block or known as paragraph kind
of. Okay. So that is this code this long
line is about. Okay. So let's purify uh
shall we? Uh so if that then that that
okay
uh so if so that's a lot of code wait if
that that okay so this this save
excursion again if that that that that
that that that
okay so this block of mode
basically just set the beginning and end
position. Okay, that is clear. Yes.
Next.
So, we got beginning and position now.
So, the next part is the replacement.
So, in between the beginning and end
positions, we want to do some text
replacement.
Okay. Oh, there's a misspelling. Okay.
Printed below if any this command. Okay.
So,
so now this is the heart of the program
this line. So, I'm calling a you know,
so let's look up the documentation of
replace pairs region.
There it is. And you can read about the
documentation and that is in this
package. Okay. And this package is I
showed you guys it's online. You can
grab it. Okay. It's very convenient
because you
close close close. So you all you have
to say is a beginning and position then
uh a list of pairs of find replace.
Okay. Now this this code is actually a
bit tricky. is not as easy as you as it
seems because you would think all you
have to do is just do find replace this
then find replace the second pair then
sequentially you know for each pair of
text and replacement you just do it that
would be incorrect because if you do
that you got it you got this recursive
problem did I explain it somewhere yes I
have okay so let me let Let me show you
guys that this is a very interesting
generic algorithmic problem. Uh you
would have a recursive problem. So So
how do I where is it? So let's describe
this function. Go to that function's
source code. This package go to the
homepage for this package which is here.
Open it. show in browser. So this is
subreplace pairs.el. You can grab it the
code right there and it offers you all
these very convenient functions
including regular expression multiple
pairs.
So but
but there is a find replace feedback
feedback loop problem described here. So
you open it then you can see let's say
if you have replaced pairs you know you
you want to replace text in a region
multiple pairs. So let's say the input
string is ABC D. Very simple. Now you
have two pairs. You want replace A by C
and C by D. Okay, very simple. So what
you should get is CB D
because A by C gets you, you know, let's
magnify. Can you magnify to see the full
glory? So you got ABC D. You got two
pairs of replacement. A2 C and C2 D. So
A2 C is C, C2 D is D. So you you should
have C B D there.
But if you do this sequentially,
A becomes C and C becomes D, you will
get DB D. That would be incorrect. Okay.
So that is why so this especially
happens real world example if you do
this uh amperand replacement
because this amperand you got into a
situation of kind of recursive amperand
you know that's kind of complic
complicated issue but you know it's
incorrect. So this so this this is the
find replace feedback feedback loop
problem
and
my functions here fixed it. So my
function does it correctly that is why
we are uh let's close that close that
close that you know we can simply do
this no problem.
Okay. So, but
oh god, you know, coding is already
always tedious. Uh, hungry man Hasa have
a massive coding stream.
Uh, yeah, three people are watching.
That's kind of sad. So, anyway, Emac is
this. That's kind of esoteric topic.
Okay. So, so, so let's, so
our job now is to rewrite this. Okay.
Let's just do it quickly. Okay.
So you given a text we given a text we
want to replace do find replace of these
multiple pairs. So what can you do
is first of all you got these uh pairs
you can define it you know this multiple
pairs then you want to go through each
uh wait um you don't want to go through
each one of them what you can do is uh
let's see um replace string okay let let
me just do Good.
Okay. So, this is a function. Wait,
that's not uh colored. That means should
I color it? Yeah, I should. This is
actually
So, you can do this replace string.
Let's copy the documentation.
Close that. Close that. Go back here.
Uh so here is the replace string. Now
it's not colored. Let's color it. Okay.
Uh normally you shouldn't use this
function because this function is for is
meant for interactive use. Um let's see
from string to string.
Okay. You don't want that because not
that's not regular expression. Okay, so
you want to do
replace rejects. Okay, that is the
function you want replace using regular
expression. Uh okay. So
delimited start and backward region non
continuous. Okay, this is tricky
argument backward and uh region nontuous
dashp means whether it's true or false
are passed to perform replace which see
oh god what the [ __ ] is perform replace
okay let's highlight highlight this
nonontiguous
p okay okay The neo region nonontiguous
P means that the region is composed of
nonontinuous
nonontiguous
pieces. That's a idiot idioty of English
you know just say nonontinuous
but in English we have nonontiguous
okay so this means that the region is
composed wait uh
okay this region is composed of non
contiguous pieces the most common
example of this is a rectangular region
Oh.
Oh. So you So this replace can actually
work on a rectangle.
Do you guys know what I mean? So for
example, let me demonstrate. So
rectangle is like this. Okay.
Uh
let's see what is a key. I don't use
this key too much. Uh
space I believe. Wait.
Uh okay. Let's see. Search for
rectangle. Rectangle. Rectangle. Open
rectangle. Q. Rectangle mark mod R R.
Okay. So, let me show you. So, let's say
uh backspace R. Okay. Now you can see I
can select the rectangle. You see? So I
can now delete this re rectangle. Let's
see. Delete it. You see? Uh wait, not
that key.
Uh but anyway, so you see you can you
can start to type you know it insert the
rectangle. So undo
undo.
Undo.
Undo. Undo. Don't Don't [ __ ] up my code.
Redo. Okay. So So that means So this
means region non continuous. That means
this
replace string or the regular expression
version actually can work on a
rectangle. That's interesting.
Okay. That's uh that's interesting to
know.
uh but uh we don't need it. Okay. So
let's see uh let's just start to code.
Okay. Let's just uh put this in one
line. Let's just start to code. Regular
expression
uh add. So wait a percent. So what is
the regular expression? Let's let's see.
Okay. Delete.
Change brackets
square bracket to none. do it. Okay, now
it's much better. Uh, actually you need
and let's just type them
emp% back slashbackslash
and uh vertical line then that
then backslash back slash back slash
vertical line then greater than equal
sign. Wait, what? Oh yeah.
Okay. This means regular expression or.
So you find that character or that
character or that character.
This will do it one shot. I hope. Let's
see. Uh
did okay. Two string.
Oh then it depends. Oh [ __ ]
Uh Jesus. Can we actually do this? You
know the two string needs to be
dependent on what is matched.
Yeah, it will be dependent on what is
matched.
But do we get the ampand recursive
feedback problem? I don't think so. For
for example, let's just say the two
string is emp%. Okay. Wait.
Okay. Two string is just an amperand.
Okay. Let's ignore that greater than
less than for now. Okay. Then optional
delimited.
Uh what does that mean? Delimited
uh describe function delimited. What
does what does that mean? The third arg
delimited prefix arg if interactive.
Okay. If n means replace only matches
surrounded by word boundaries. Oh, okay.
Oh, we don't we don't care you know it's
basically just means word boundary.
Okay. Close that. So delimited.
No, we don't want the word boundary. and
start end. That's our start and end
position. So that would be X begin
and X end. Okay. And backward no Neo
region non continuous Neo. Okay. So Neo
Neo remove that. So that is our
function. Now
now let's uh remove that. Delete. Let's
just say that. Okay.
Yeah. So, but you need
now. Okay. So wait does the regular
expression the second argument the
replacement does it take a function
because this is important the two string
part
because we need it to depend on what we
found.
Okay. Yes indeed it does. So stand for
whatever match the whole or regular
expression and n. Okay.
uh stand for whatever match the nth.
Okay. So
yep.
And does it take a lisp expression? It
does. Okay. So this will work.
Okay. But now let's look at the source
code of this docu this uh rejects. Let's
see if it's very complex. Yeah,
it's fairly complex because
you know because it's doing interactive
and uh so meaning that means if we use
this function it's going to be fairly
slow.
Okay, it's going to be fairly slow.
Oh god. And that's going to be fair.
That's going to be fairly slow. So
yeah, you run into a lot of issues. I
mean, not really problems, but you know,
decisions you can you have to make. for
example, I can simply stick with what I
have here. But then that means you know
other people needs to download the extra
package.
So that's why we are trying to write it
you know without dependencies.
But then
we run into issue because then we if we
call call this command uh let's remove
that. Let's also remove that. If we call
this command, this is supposed to be
interactive use then therefore it is
slower.
Um but let's just do it for now. Okay.
So make that one line, comment it out
and pify the whole code and I think
that's it.
So we can evaluate the buffer. Okay. So
and right now it just changed. So
optional you need to remove that.
Uh that should work.
But uh does that have the recursive
problem?
No. Because in this case
each of the character is distinct. Okay.
Do you guys know what I'm saying?
Because for the recursive for the
feedback
for this find replace feedback loop
problem to occur.
For that problem to occur
one of the requirement is that one of
the your replacement character also
occurs in your find character. Okay. you
I mean the one of your
okay here's a way to put it the subse
what one one of your subsequent
find
string
occurs in previous
replacement string. So for example here
a replaced by c and c replaced by d. So
this second pair CD occurs
and the that fine string C happens in
the previous pair of the replacement
string. So when this situation happens
then you got this find replace feedback
loop problem.
Okay. But
in our case what we want to uh let's
type it again. So wait does it occur?
Let's see. That becomes uh amp and less
than becomes
uh less than that.
Okay. And greater than becomes greater
than. So does any of the
character
in the find string occurs in the
previous replacement string? No. That
means fantastic. That means we can just
go ahead using the no-brainer approach.
Okay. What is a no-brainer approach? Is
this okay? So let me show you. So um
so while not when while not when while
okay why do I have a shortcut no while
okay so while search for word
yeah let's do this no-brainer approach
emperand so while you find search for
that Um
okay before you do find replace you want
to narrow to region. Okay narrow to
region region beginning and region end.
That means limit the buffer to just the
posit the region you are interested.
Okay. Then we search for then we go to
chart
point mean go to the beginning of the
region then start search
then okay bound no arrow uh we don't
care no arrow
wait bound no error count we don't care
okay then replace it with um replace it
with
empas Same replace by that.
Okay. Then
fix case. Yes. Literal yes. And strings
are that we don't care. Okay. Beautify
the code. Fantastic.
Okay. And in fact make it one line. So
this this is one unit. Okay.
in fact make it unit syntactically a
unit too.
So that you see that's the beauty of the
lisp syntax.
And now
cut that and paste and paste repeat
beautify it. And now we just do the less
than.
Okay. less than. Okay.
Then greater than
greater than. Fantastic. We are doing
this replacement sequentially. Each time
we go to the beginning, then while it's
found do the replace. So you can see
when you compare the code, you can see
this block versus versus our previous
one single line. This line. Okay, I got
a call. Let's see.
Spam,
spam and scam.
Our modern life
are funed with spam and scam,
scam and spam and marketing [ __ ]
American life.
So ACP says how is save restriction
different from save excursion? They are
entirely different. Okay. So save
excursion is very common. That means
just save the cursor position and the
buffer the current buffer. So here you
can do whatever code you know and when
this code is done it'll return the
current cursor position and the current
buffer. Okay inside the code you can
switch to another buffer like you know
you can switch to another file but once
it's done it this save excursion means
return it to to whatever the current
buffer. Okay, that's why it's called an
excursion. You know, that's a
you know, let's digress to the
department of English linguistics
excursion.
A usual a a usually short journey made
for pleasure, an outing. That's exactly
right. You know, we are doing a
excursion save excursion.
Now save restriction is is something
else. Save restriction that means you
see when you have this narrow to region
you can call it. So for example I select
this let's say I select you know let's
say I select this part. Okay. Now call
meta x narrow to region. Okay. So do it
then your whole buffer become just that
you know Emac pretends the other part
doesn't exist. So this way allows you to
you know you can move to the end it'll
stuck there you can move to the
beginning you're stuck there you know so
you don't have to worry about
uh the previous part and after you know
especially when you are doing find and
replace right so okay now we can return
it by call
widen
do it so now you return so you undo the
narrow to region okay That's this narrow
to region.
Okay. So that's fantastic.
But what does the So but then why do you
need save restriction? Save restriction
is basically undo whatever narrow to
region. You see once you narrowed
if you do it manually
you know you have that then you call
widen to widen it. then you just extend
the whole you know undo the narrow to
region but however you can
narrow to region let's do it narrow to
region and now I select this charact
this word and narrow to region again
narrow you see now I the whole buffer is
just like that one word but now if I do
widen
it undo all the narrowing you see it
undo all the narrowing but that's not
what you want. You you just want to undo
one level of narrowing.
Okay, so that is what this save
restriction is for. Okay, let's make it
back. Okay, so it returns the previous
you know whatever previous narrowing
that may be in effect.
Okay, that answers that question.
Okay. So now uh now comment out then we
don't need that comment out. Okay. Let's
purify the buffer.
Fantastic. In fact I think that's the
code. That's what we want. Okay. And
then then this comment you know we don't
actually need them
and comment out. Okay that's the whole
code. And this decode amperand basically
reverse. So, this part will get more
complex. Anyway, let's not worry about
it. Okay, delete it. Now, go back here.
Now, let's uh I think that's it. Uh
let's see. So, we don't use our custom
commands and remove that and purify, you
know, let's make it not purify the code
and remove the comment purify. Pify
purify. Okay, so the whole code is like
in one buffer.
Okay,
one last check before we run it.
Uh, replace match. What? What? What?
What is this? It is incorrect. What?
Replace match uh
optional fixed case literal. Oh, we mean
uh fixed case. So, it should be just T.
Okay. So, that is that. So, let's see.
Go to the beginning of the region to the
replacement while still found. Keep
doing the replacement until it's force.
Then exit. Then next, go to the
beginning. Do that until fantastic. I
think that's it. Evaluate the buffer.
Make a backup. Go to the directory.
Hide the details
by compile. Yes.
Warning. Oh, warning. Unused lexical
report. That's right. So, we got some
extra argument here. They are not used,
which is a feature because we want to
highlight it. But for for now, let's
remove it. Okay, we're going to add it
later. Okay, so eval the buffer. Go to
the directory by compile it. Yes, now no
error this time. Fantastic. Open it.
Delete it. Close it. Eval the buffer.
Fantastic. Now we can try.
So go to go to go to go to here. Go to
here. Okay.
And can we undo what? Uh wait.
Uh what did we So uh okay so we got this
um
let's just say that okay
this and that this and that this and
that. Okay. So
describe key tab j.
Okay. So html encode emperand entity.
And now it's in defined in this file we
just created. So that this step verifies
we are running the correct code because
we I you know we have another version
but but this version is you know the one
we created. Okay. So now go back. So now
tap j
arrow wrong number of argument. What the
[ __ ]
Uh message and wait. What what's going
on?
Go to messages buffer. Okay. So
wrong number of arguments something
optional. Okay. So I think I can I think
I understand what it means.
What?
Oh yeah. Because you see we removed two
arguments. So now it's just two
arguments beginning end. But however in
this section interactive we fed four
arguments neo neo tt. So let's just
remove that. Okay.
So now
in fact this is optional. So this we
don't even need you know. So evaluate
it. Go back to here.
Tap J.
Fantastic and beautiful.
Okay there is a search failed message
which is you know so undo. Let's go back
to the code.
Search failed. Let's make it pretty so
it doesn't say that.
Uh
so you know so search for word it failed
don't complain okay
just do that bound neo and no error true
okay
okay to repeat that that that that That
that that that that prefy the code.
Evolve the buffer. Go back here. Try it.
Tap J.
Fantastic.
And now there's it's saying you know it
gives you a message change printed below
if any. So that's the report feature you
know in our original code. Now this is
our new code. Now let's make this one
line again. So you see that's why I like
single line format. If you seen my live
stream about wam language how everything
is automatic that's fantastic.
Okay but anyway so so should we okay
let's leave it like that. Okay so now uh
we want to add a report feature. Let's
see let's think about what feature we
want. So here is our original code.
Um,
so we got begin, end, then report.
Report just, you know, usually it's not
useful because it just prints a bunch of
lines, but highlight is very useful.
Okay, so we want we do want highlight.
Okay, so copy that. Let's add that
feature. Now, this is extra.
We already finished the task, but now we
do some extra stuff. So far so good. Is
it fun?
Thank you guys for watching. Pay me. Uh
yeah. Yes.
Sorry.info. Okay. Excursion. We had one
excursion. So now uh today's ad is
sponsored by you. So kasadi.infocus info
casad code.info
no https because this Google and firefox
scums they they are deep us scums these
days they prevent you from visiting
websites that's not https and worse they
automatically change anything to the s
they add s you know for example my
site.info
info
sorry.info info works. But if you use
Google or if you click, you know, from
Twitter, you know, if you are using
Google Chrome or Firefox, they
automatically
add a S to your URL and then then they
will say, oh, error, security failure,
scary tactics. Then you can't visit my
website because security. Oh, there must
be some hackers going on.
[ __ ] Google. [ __ ] Firefox. Okay.
Excali.info. Then you go all the way
down slowly. You got coding stuff. You
got mathematics. You got lots of stuff.
And you got to the place where you can
pay me. Patreon, Amazon gift card,
PayPal. $100 is nice
if you have a job. Okay. So, let's go
back to code. So now we need to add this
highlight feature. How can you do that?
How can you in EMAC how can you make it
highlight something programmatically?
Uh you know so we can for example this
beginning end we can do it
interactively. Press press press press
and you can see all the beginning got
highlighted. What about the end? Press
press press press. Oh they become pink.
Fantastic. So good for your eyes and
helps you programming help humanity.
That command is called highlight symbol
at point building. Okay. But how do you
do it programmatically?
We can do that by here. Okay. So once we
found a replacement, we highlight the
region. Okay. How do you do that?
Uh basically you go to search for kasar
eac lisp
and then go to create a major mode. Then
you there is a section about
highlighting
uh it's called
uh font face uh major mode font face
syntax table font face no brief uh what
is it uh
it's called overlay there it is can you
see overlay highlighting click on that
tells you all about it how to do it.
Okay. So then all you have to do is you
just copy the code.
Okay. Back to Emacs.
Close that. So we want to highlight. So
paste the code. Uh make over overlay
bold region. Make region bold using
overlay. Okay. So what are the
difference? Cuz over remove. Okay. So
this remove we don't care and this this
we don't we don't need the defend
anymore.
Okay. So it's just that okay overlay put
make overlay you need to have a
beginning and end position to make it.
So how you want to make so where is the
beginning position that would be
so begin would be match beginning.
Okay so match beginning yes and end
would be match end. Okay, zero means the
whole match the expression which is just
the amperand. Okay, but
plus
you want to plus one, two, three, four
characters. So match n + 4. Okay. So,
let's see.
O overlay put set mark. That we don't
need that. We don't need that. We don't
need pedify the code. There it is.
You
So, let's purify the code. So, you do
the search, you replace it, then you
highlight it.
Okay. So cut the code and also put it
here.
Okay. So
paste purify fantastic eval buffer. Go
back to
the test page. Now undo. Close. Save.
Close. Reopen.
Now
tap J.
No highlight.
Oh, wait. It did. You know, it's bold.
Okay. I don't want bold. So, let's go
back. Let's say red.
Can we Do we have a red face? Face
highlight. Oh, okay. Maybe use face
highlight.
Uh, instead face bold, use face
highlight. Okay. Let's use the standard
highlight color in Emacs. Okay. So,
instead of bold, just say highlight.
Instead of a bold, just say highlight.
Make a backup. Go to the directory by
compile. Yes. Uh oh, you got error. Oh,
and use lexical argument.
Oh, that's right. You forgot to check
you know maybe user don't want to
highlight it.
Actually we always want to highlight it.
Yeah. So let's just you know let's just
always highlight it.
Okay. So interactive list
Neo true.
Well wait well we don't need that
argument. just always just highlight it.
So we don't need that.
Okay. If the buffer make a backup go to
a directory by compile it by compile and
no error open it close it rem uh delete
it. Close it back to the testing page.
And this line we don't need anymore. You
see this? You see before we have this
one single line and now we need this
entire block you know like 15 lines
but our code is now faster because
faster and no dependency so let's just
remove that you know that that's what I
wanted evaluate it go here close it
reopen now look carefully especially
Check the highlighting. Okay, the
amperand is red because I'm using some
HTML mod. It it just highlight the
amperand.
Okay. And and let's say x greater than
one. Okay. Y - 2, you know, extra. Okay.
Save it. Now put the cursor somewhere
there and tap J.
Fantastic. And wrong.
Okay. The replacement is correct, but
it's highlighting
[ __ ]
It's highlighting.
Okay. Oh, wait.
Okay. So, I don't know exactly what's
going on, but let's we can just try out
an error here. So, don't don't plus
four. Okay, I think it um
yeah, so evaluate it. I think this
replace match automatically update the
match end. Okay, so now evaluate the
buffer. Go here. Go to the HTML.
Undo. Close. Reopen
now. Tap J.
Fantastic and beautiful.
That's superb. Superb and success.
Now let's make it list and showing
browser.
Fantastic. Correct code. Valid HTML. You
can pass this to HTML W3C validator and
it'll work.
Okay, I think that's it for today. Thank
you guys for watching. Uh ACP says the
match beginning end has changed after
replacement. Yes,
that is why I was adding you know I was
make you know adding four you know this
that you know that's why but apparently
when you do the replacement here it also
automatically update the match end
position. You see is do I is it clear?
So let me explain. Okay. So suppose you
are you know trying to find the greater
than sign.
So once you call this search forward it
will have a match beginning and match
end position and these two functions
will get you their value which are
integers. Okay. So this you know so
match beginning and match end they will
differ by one obviously because you only
searched for one character right one
character.
So then you do the replace match which
actually added one two three uh three oh
not four it added three more characters.
So I thought then you might you know you
need to add four to the match end but
apparently that's incorrect because
if you when you call the m replace match
it actually update the match end
position so you don't have to like add
extra. Okay, this is actually better.
This is smart. Okay, so evaluate the
buffer. Let's try it again.
you know. Okay. So, showing browser.
Let's just copy that. Copy back here.
Let's open a new buffer and let's make
it fundamental mod so it doesn't
highlight anything. So now let's
manually call
HTML amperand
encode ampers entity. Do it.
Fantastic. And beautiful success.
So fantastic. Now let's close that and
put the code back. So this we got this
fantastic and beautiful code. Copy it.
Uh
so let me let me show you the
difference. Okay. So let's see. So this
is the old code here. So let's paste the
new code here. So update the pages state
and uh let's
emac this. Okay, here's a new code
syntax color show in browser. So now you
got two version of code. So the first
one is what we coded today.
Fantastic and beautiful. You can see the
date 2025 August 11th. the the now the
previous version if you scroll down is
this one 2025 February last time I
updated you see the previous version is
tur
you know this one single line does it
does the heart of the problem
but
if you are a user you go here then you
try it oh it doesn't work replace pair
is not found and you go back oh you look
oh you need to this package. And what is
this package? Oh, then you need to
download this one. That's dependency.
Dependency is the worst [ __ ] in coding.
Okay, like today's JavaScript mpm
you open the gate then the flood of [ __ ]
comes in to your computer.
Okay. So, so, so now the code is verbose
30 more lines but there's no dependency.
Okay, we finished that and uh you know
very good but there's ex this second
problem. Now we need to do the decode.
Now, the the decoding is a bit more
complex because if you do the decoding,
I think you're going to run into the um
you you're going to run into this
problem
of where is it? Did I close it? Yeah.
Jesus.
You're going to run into the feedback
loop problem. Okay. So, let me So, let's
Okay. [ __ ] Where is it? Okay, let me
let me put it the link. Okay, so copy
that. Close it.
Go to today's talk show. Paste this
link. Okay, entity. Open it and search
for replace.
Okay, so search for package. Okay, there
it is. Open it. Copy it. Close. Close.
Put a link here. Linkify. make a list
and join the list showing browser. There
it is. So this package it explains this
feedback
loop problem. So open that copy the URL
back to Emacs and
and uh put it here because we talked
about this issue today. So feedback loop
loop. So when you are doing the decoding
of the amperand encoding,
you're going to have this feedback
feedback loop problem. Let's see.
So
any of the fine characters do they
appear in previous um replacement
character?
Oh actually no.
So again the problem is
for each pair of find replacement
any
subsequent find
string
if they appear as a substring of the
previous replacement string then you got
a problem.
So does the problem occur here? uh you
know it's kind of like tricky to
to know. So let's let's make it easier.
Okay. So now it's easier to see. So does
any of the left hand side appear? Here's
the left hand side. Does it appear as a
substring of the previous right hand
side?
this no and this part no. Okay. So that
means in fact the decode can also be
easily coded just like we did here.
Basically you just copy and paste and
just replace you know the swap the you
know swap these characters. Okay that's
it. Thank you guys for watching.
Fantastic. It's clear you know like when
when you know like if you are a
professor
or if you are a lecturer lecturer you
know the happiest thing is that when you
you know explain something your student
understand is attentive that's actually
that the happiest
you know that you know that that is what
the professor lecture lecturer is doing
their that means their intention is
achieved that that means they are
successful.
So if you are a student in college you
know I don't by the way ACP how how old
are you you know I have all kind of uh
audiences from teenagers to
professionals and some professors too.
So you know if so if you are in college
you know
usually I mean if you are in college you
know the you know you you want to learn
something that's that's what that's why
you are in college for but the problem
is for most people you know your parents
paid it you know like you go to college
to [ __ ] around
you don't you get bor bored about
whatever biology or mathematics you know
you don't care
But
if you really want to learn, of course,
you pay attention to the lecture. But
then there's other problems such as
half of the time the teachers, you know,
the professors or lecturers are not that
good. They also got problems, you know,
they they, you know, they, you know,
they are bored. you know they don't want
to you know do the teaching you know
they got other things to do or they got
a problem they got some personal issues
whatever you know or they are just not
good at teaching because there's huge
amount of corruption going on in in USA
United States of America in the past you
know let's say 20 years so these
professors you know they are there not
really to enjoy teaching they are just
there because
because they are good um
you know they obey they are good obeyers
so they get paid you know they get jobs
you know especially the social sciences
professors you know they teach you about
feminism and uh stuff and gender stuff
those are all super corrupted.
So
yeah, you are in college to learn but
maybe you are not but even if you are
half of the professors are not that you
know they got the problems too anyway.
So that's why you came to the right
place if you want to learn Emacs. You
got a dedicated obsessive
lover of Emac this. Okay. Bye guys.
shut down in one minute.
Oh, far removed from college.
Fantastic. And good luck.
Okay, bye guys. Shut down in one minute.
Uh, by the way, I got fairly popular on
Twitter somewhat. I mean uh you know in
the past three days I became I got like
few hundred or was it a hundred more
followers
began by a post about Emacs about the
Emacs couer font problem because if you
are using Emacs
oh [ __ ]
whatever I was doing uh so let's okay so
uh let's open a new one.
Okay. So,
control.
Okay.
Okay. So, now let's start EMAC 30.
Uh,
no. Uh, wait. Okay. Q means no personal
in files. Launch the plane emacs. There
it is. Instantaneous. Okay.
Then you magnify. Let's see. Was it
control alt? Yeah. Control alt scroll.
So you magnify.
Okay. Then you enlarge the window. So
there you got Emacs. So this is plain
glue emac. Now you
control X. Wait. What's the key? Ctrl XB
to switch to a buffer. You see that ugly
font that most ugly possible this [ __ ]
Now what font is that? Control H. Uh
wait there's no shortcut. So you have to
do meta x
describe. You see this ugly font
describe chart.
Okay. Then that will tell you let's
magnify again.
Then that will it will tell you okay now
how do you switch the cursor to the
other panel? Well that's controll X
control XO. You know this is how Emacs
[ __ ] up your fingers.
After a year you become a [ __ ] thanks
to Emacs and the Emacs fanatic
[ __ ] They refuse to change. Emacs
is actually the the most the editor the
software that's the most responsible for
repetitive string injury you know
crippled programmers. So anyway in this
window you can see what is my font you
see there it is couer new that is like
that that font couer
is about 100 years old. Okay, that's
that font is 100 years old and courier
new is like 30 years old. So the Emacs
on Windows is still using this this font
by default.
Very bad. So I posted that and that
became somewhat popular. Then I posted
another thing about
you followed the wrong guy and then a
lot people like 100 s.
So now I have 5 5,666
followers.
Oh. Oh, it's not 666, it's 69. I got 69
Uh, and uh, recent and yesterday and
today, Brendan Ike, the creator of
JavaScript, followed me.
Okay. Okay. Bye.