Hello guys, good morning everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Saga Talk
Show. Uh if you are watching offline,
play at 1.5 speed because I ramble. If
you are here, say
hi. Uh let's pop up. So we are going to
do Wuam language exploration.
I'm going to explore Wuam language
uh artificial intelligence and neuronet
networks
uh kind of
features. So if you don't know already
search foram language tutorial you can
find indepth tutorial from the ground up
if you know a programming language
already. So this is my tutorial very
good and you can download it for free.
It's free since like 2000
um you know few years ago. So Wuam
language. Okay. So uh so we are going to
explore what Wuam language can do in
areas I'm not familiar with. So it can
do like like it's designed to be
anything you can do with a computer you
can do with wufam language. So in Python
they have a slogan they say battery
included you know I never get that joke
you know like what battery included what
the but they mean what they mean is
that you have like building libraries
that lets you do lots of
things. So Python they say battery
included then language is like entire
military included. Okay. So because by
default you have 7,000 building
functions. Okay. Uh you know lots of
interesting discussions. So you know we
are just going to go easy random and
explore wuam language. This is my
discord. You can join. We have
similarminded people uh you know
programmers uh debate. We uh we debate
we I mean I we debate a lot with Dion
and uh lots of uh programmers many uh
professional programmers such as
Dion Emacs for success. Hello. Uh hello
are you are you pranchu? I forgot. Are
you pru? So anyway so yeah we're going
to do wuam language exploration. So we
already started. Now the way you want to
do wufam language expression uh
exploration is go to their
website wufam okay
wam.com so they are famous for wufam
alpha which is computational query
engine so it's like a search engine you
know Google where Google search engine
for example you type something it search
the vast amount of web you know
trillions trillions or whatever
gazillions
pages. Uh but Wuam Alpha is like uh more
of a computational engine. So when you
type a query, it actually computes find
the right answer. It's not just it's not
searching the web but actually it has
database of information and woven mafa
is best used for when you have concrete
questions like how many people in USA
how many chemicals
uh with this property list all of them
things like that so wuam alpha so it's
like artificial intelligence but this is
different from today's AI chatbots Gro.
Okay. So, Grog is fantastic. I highly
recommend it. Okay. Oh, yeah. So, I let
me demo a feature of
Grog. So, hold on a
second. You know, Grog now comes in
voice, so it can actually talk and
listen. Fantastic. It's incredible. So
you know in summary the AI chatbot
starting about two or three years ago it
became incredible you know starting with
chat GPT
uh okay so let let me let me just random
random talk
okay artificial intelligence you know so
I'm very deeply interested in in this
topic since 1990s but actually didn't
know much about it and machine learning
machine learning became became a craze
since about
2010 began you know promoted by Google
Facebook you know they say big data
became a jargon big data and data
science and machine learning but
actually I don't know much about machine
learning but but starting with chat GPT
um Stefan Wu chat GPT so this is 2023
chat GPT AI bots then you have ex you
know explosion of Okay, like today you
have gu is very good. Okay, guork. Yeah,
let me demo gu. So let me uh let me let
me um again if you are watching this
offline play at 1.5 speed. If you are
here say hi. So let me organize into
topics. So we talked about wuam alpha
uh how it
differ
from search engine and AI chat bots.
Okay, that's one thing we talked about
the rise of AI chat
bots. Eg for example chat GPT.
Okay, the rise of AI chatbots and uh let
me show you. So Stephan Wuam on chat GPT
that is a indepth dive. I highly
recommend it if you don't know anything
about how how the chatbot works. You
know you need to be you need to be a
technical person and programmer. So this
you know I talked about this a few
times. This is um this is like
explaining how it
works not as opposed to the vast
majority of chat GBT or neuronet network
or so-called large language uh
model you know most of them majority on
the web tutorials they tell you they
they they talk about how it is coded how
do you code it okay but Steph Stefan
Wolfan's article They they explain how
it works. Okay. So like you don't they
don't care I mean you don't have to be a
coder but it's like how do you like
explaining how uh a jet jet engine works
how car works how car engine works how
steering wheel works how chemistry you
know some chemistry magic you know how
how material science works. So in that
aspect
explain how is it possible that the
machine can write poems can answer
questions how is it possible that is the
perspective of Wuam Stefan Wuam's uh
article okay so I like it very much and
and this is my favorite article
explaining how neural network the large
language machine model how they can
possibly write a poem and and pretty
good Okay. So I recommend this very
long. I mean you you'll spend you know
you'll take you a day or few days to
read it. So Stephan Stefan Wuam. So
Chach GPD began in
2023. Okay. Then I started to learn
quite a lot
about neuronet networks and machine
learning. So I I I started to learn
about that in 2023. So I learned quite a
lot but I'm not expert. Okay. So these
are the videos I collected. I watched
some of them and uh you know decision
and also Mo you know we we got the
moedo
guy teaching me about machine learning.
So you got decision tree random forest
and you know and there's uh a lot of
Python tutorials out there too and also
books. Okay. So, so this you know neural
networks large uh language machine large
language models chat GPT and uh let me
demo GU okay demo
gu demo that fantastic that's really fun
okay uh so let me open the
app I installed it it's only available
on iPhone I mean on on Android or
phone. So, uh can you see it? Let's
see. So, do I have like personal
information there? No. Okay. Can can you
actually see
it? You know, so you have to install the
phone app Gork. Okay. So, you you click
on voice
mark. Hello, Gork. Now, I'm doing a live
stream. Can you introduce yourself?
Yo, what's good? I'm Grock, your goto AI
buddy created by XAI. I'm here to drop
quick, real answers with a bit of wit,
maybe some humor. Got a question or need
help with something? I'm all ears. Well,
all code. What's up? Fantastic. Hey,
Gro. I'm a programmer. Are you a
programmer, too?
Nice to meet a fellow code wrangler. I'm
not exactly a programmer like you, but
I'm built from code by the XAI crew, so
I speak the language. I can debug,
explain algorithms, or even throw you
some code snippets if you want? What's
your coding vibe? Webdev, AI, or
something else? Okay, let me post a quiz
for you. There is the application called
Mathematica. What is the name for the
programming language?
The programming language used in
Mathematica is the Wolf Ram language.
It's a powerful symbolic language
designed for everything from math to
data analysis. What's your next quiz
question?
Thank you, Gu.
No problem. Happy to help. What's next
on your live stream? another quiz or
something totally different.
So that was amazing. You know it you can
it talks like human you know like when I
tried it. So I just installed it like
last week. So when I tried it I thought
it's going to be you know synthetic
machine voice like uh uh what can I do
for you? You know but but that talks
like a human. So you cannot tell it's
not a human. Of course you can probably
tell it to change the personality, the
tone of voice. Now that is, you know,
that chat style is kind of too flippant
for my taste. You know, I prefer more
serious tone. But that's but that's
incredible. You see, you know, it chats
like a human. So and you can just ask it
any question or something on your mind
you forgot that moment, you know. So he
just talked about how Mathematica is
known as Wuam language. So that's just
amazing. So that so that's you know um
the progress of computer is today. you
know, you can you can have like
humanlike
uh you know, chatting
bot and you can get deep into that. You
you know, you can just like use it as a
companion. But I never actually tried to
do it. But I know a lot of people do it
because they especially non-coders you
know if you are not a programmer if you
don't know anything about these neural
networks or artificial intelligence you
know
algorithms if you are just a normal
people you know average people you tend
to just chat with it you know like a
buddy or like you know a person and then
you get you can ask it you know ask it
you know all sort of personal questions
or like how do you you
about relationships whatever advice and
I'm not sure what is the you know what
what kind of um like development you
know what kind of u conversation you get
into I never do that I never did that
because my interaction with AI bots is
always almost always like very technical
so for example I just asked today some
someone mentioned the cotling
programming language
You know, someone mentioned um let's see
my uh notification. Someone replied
starting soon. Oh god, this is a spam.
You know, it started a few days ago.
They, you know, so they, you know, some
random spam account answer your post on
Twitter and they immediately block you.
So you can you can see you go there you
see you have been blocked and they
mention some some other guy who is
usually doing stock trading and stuff
you see massive scam you know the scam
bots and and you know bots
anyway that is actually another I mean
this is actually very related to AI
because many of them are using AI to
help automated and all that. So I gotta
report this guy and also reporting
doesn't do do you much you know like h
the corruption of USA you know the the
the collapse like the beginning of
collapse of USA began with these social
networks starting with Facebook
uh anyway that's another top topic okay
so we talked about uh let me show wufam
alpha which can uh so how Let's ask
let's uh for demo let's uh try a
question. Let's ask some kind of social
question not technical. Let's see what
is the language
in Mathematica. Let's see if wa
alpha can answer that. Let's see.
Enter. There it is. Okay. So input
interpretation Mathematica language
used result wam language C Java. That's
correct. This is interesting part
because Wuam language is written in C
not C++. It's written in C back in um
1986 around there. Okay. And it is
written in Java. You know, beginning
around
1995. When Java was born, Wuam research
heavily invested into Java. So, Java is
part of the Wuam language technology.
So, it's amazing. So, Wuam language
written by Stefan Wuam and C Denise
Richie uh Java James Gosling. These are
you know giant guys. James Gossling have
to do, you know, he created the first
Emacs called Gosling
Emacs and uh Denise Richie, you know, we
all know or you guys the Unix
hackers. Uh date introduced 1988. Okay.
C
1972, Java 1995, official website. Okay.
So, there it is the logo. Okay.
Fantastic. And you can, you know, if you
go to
kasali.info, you'll see my collection of
programming language tutorials. And one
of them is Wuam language. I changed logo
to to this official wam language logo.
But you know, I'm also a logo
offic you know like I look into the
design of logos. Uh so you know let me
show this again. Uh for
example, so if you are here, say hi.
Okay, comment. Your hand dwar says that
was the best at AI voice I've heard.
Yeah, it's incredible. So I plan you
know like I type so much I have hand
pain like even right now and I right now
the thumb started to hurt here
uh like right here for for some reason
about a few weeks ago. So I plan to you
know just to talk to you uh talk to a AI
bots and there are so many you know chat
GBT has a version they also do voice gu
is my favorite I use gu um okay so let
me show let me write them down so we we
are coherent in this talk show the rise
of AI chatbots chat GPT wuam alpha demo
and Steph Stefan wuam on chat GPT gu
voice demo And there there are also
um so let me let me go to it. Okay. So
there are also
um yeah the incredible things you know
the network neural network and the
universal approximation theorem. So
there's a theorem there's a theorem
about what is the limit of neural
network. You see chat GPT and all these
parts are written you know so-called
large language
models and they are done by the
technique of neural network which is a
technique in artificial intelligence and
then and and and then there's a theory
that this tells us the ultimate limit of
the neuronet network approach.
So the universal approximation theory is
saying with enough n and m the result g
approximating f is possible. So
basically you can
approximate in so essentially it means
you can answer every
anything as long as there's an answer
okay if you know like if you ask it ask
it what's the meaning of the universe
nobody knows okay but I
mean whatever it will answer is the
answer available to human knowledge
that's the limit okay so anything we
already know in books in These three we
already know AI via the neural network
can answer it but but they do it in a
approximate approximation way because AI
bots not they you know they are
basically statistics
okay but it can just answer anything we
already know okay so that is the um so
there's like like this one came from
Wikipedia so if you search for the
universal approximation
theorem uh you'll find it on Wikipedia.
Okay. So, so I started to talk about AI
and we should go back to Wuam language
explor. So, there is a uh Wikipedia
article the universal approximation
theorem. Okay. So, why how do you you
know how do you have this theorem? That
is because let's go to it. Okay. So that
is that is because the AI um the large
language machine models or neuronet
networks they are actually um let's see
neuronet network tutorial they are
actually just a function you know
actually they are just like one single
function okay so whenever you talk to gu
or or chat gbt you say something or you
type something that something is the
input to the function fun and the
function just will
output and that that is the output of
the chat bots you know so that function
and and essentially that function is
just a huge
nested matrix multiplication. Okay, so
you got like hundred you know you got
thousands thousands or tens of thousands
of matrices and each matrix is like 100
by 100 or something big. So you just you
know multiply them with the input
multiply the input is a vector
basically. So matrix matrix
multiplication then you output a number
then you turn that number back into text
that's how uh neural network works and
that is the foundation of chat GPT AI
bots you know the gu so that's amazing
okay and and uh let me show you this one
okay so cotling so so that's amazing so
let's go one by one let me let me let me
um hold One
second. Yeah, neural network tutorial.
Let me post that there. And this one is
um Gu wrote a simple tutorial on Kotlin
programming language. Okay. Amazing. So
you just ask write a short tutorial of
Kotling because someone mentioned it.
You know, I find it interesting. Then
Gro just wrote it. So you can see you
know how to get started install JK uh
JDK Java you know development kit IDE
cotlin compiler then this is how you
write hello world you know it explains
then basic
syntax so this means if you are a
programmer or if you are a technical
person you know if you are you know if
you don't know any special language like
lisp e emac lisp Pascal or u
uh or Elm or any any any uh you know
esoteric language or even bash common
language like Python, Bash, Ruby, PHP,
you can just ask it you know show me a
simple tutorial and it
will write it on the spot generate it on
the spot. So it's amazing you know so
you can like quickly quickly uh have an
understanding of the programming
language.
Amazing because before before AI bots
you have to search the web then you got
then then you know then then there's
like tens of results you have to like
decide whether they are good quality or
not you know because a lot of them are
just
quality then and half of the time the
good quality ones are esoteric you know
they are written by professional
programmers or
hackers and when you read them they They
like they tell you like like esoteric
like how great this is language features
you know tens of jarens you know like
you don't understand but then but the
you know AI bots they they truly just do
the job answering the question a simple
tutorial with explanation and then if
you have any questions you can ask it.
So this is tremendous. This is
incredible human uh actually
technological
achievement and of course there's lots
of questions about AI. We don't know
like you know like whether it's going to
taking over uh lots of questions and uh
lots of scams spams you know writing on
AI wave to make money grifters lots of
that too but in general we don't know
what will happen okay that's what I have
been kept saying we do not know what
will actually happen okay but the thing
we already know is that there's lots of
like thousands of bots like right now on
Twitter on any social media you do not
know they are humans they are just bots
but you cannot tell just like just like
the gu you know the AI chat you know
some like someday you receive received a
phone someone talk to you asking you
something something and turns out it
doesn't exist it's a AI bot you know you
don't know you know so for me like I
cannot tell you know But you know you
know I cannot tell but you know unless I
spend an hour chatting with it then try
to you know maybe I can tell but the
point is that for vast majority of
majority of people they don't they
cannot know you know so AI bot is
like
incredibly dangerous and it's already
happening right now.
So and then there's also more
um more other issues like ethics you
know ethics or whether AI is going to be
conscious you know so-called
AGI which I I kind of don't think so but
uh because when AI become conscious you
know that's really uh like I think
that's going to be the end of humanity
but we don't know you know some some uh
scientists would say it'll never
happen. Okay, that's like some random
chat about AI. Uh and let's go back to
UFAM language. Let's see. So I wanted to
um let's see what else. Yeah. So
um so Gro wrote a simple tutorial on
Kotlin uh neural network tutorial. Okay.
So let's let's look at
um yeah so also a demo of this
wir. Let's make a screenshot of
it.
Fantastic. Okay. So let's let's do some
let's go to Yeah. So uh wra let's go to
just like wra Mathematica. Okay. So
Mathematica also known as
um wam language. So let's go to the
website. Let's explore some machine
learning related um
things. So where do I go?
Uh sign in to apps. What apps? Web apps,
mobile apps, all products. Okay, let's
go to all products. Wuam offer products
and
services wam alpha for mobile. I don't
want wuam alpha. I want
Mathematica. So, by the way, anything in
Wuam alpha you can do with Mathematica.
So for example let's you know you have
to do is just type a equal sign then
just type your question. So let's say
what is the
language of Mathematica? Let's ask the
same question. Shift
enter. Okay, there it is. Output wam
language C Java. So this is simplified
version. Now let's ask yet another
question. Okay. Uh plot a curve of sign
Okay, shift
enter. So this way you know you can ask
it to plot. You don't even have to know
the syntax of wra language. So it
actually shows you
that that's a syntax. So you click it.
Let's see what happens. Okay, click it
and uh shift
enter. Okay, so you need to change the
X.
Let's see. Let's ask again. Okay, let's
get it.
Um equal sign plus a curve pl plus sign.
Let's just say plus sign.
Okay, plus sign first has zero
[Music]
um replace cell with this input. Okay.
So,
let's Can we So, if you click it, it
disappears. I don't want it to
disappear.
So, copy. Click it.
Then, then put X there. Okay. So,
wait.
Undo. Undo.
What? Wait. You can nest it query
delete.
Delete. Okay. So yeah, X shift enter.
There it is. Okay. So you you can just
ask it a question. It will show you the
syntax. So that's some of the feature of
you know. So that is the wam alpha
inside wam language. So, you know, you
you don't get this if you get the free
version because the free version runs in
terminal. Um, but
anyway, so I want to know, so let's go
to Yeah, I want to go to the Wufam
website. Let's see. Wuam alpha in the
Wuam language. Oh, it act it actually
shows that there. And let's open the
Wufam homepage. Okay. So here is Wuam
natural language understanding system
enable JavaScript.
Okay. So WAM natural language
understanding system. Okay. Um so
next computation data decisions just use
wam. Okay. Turn javascript. Uh
refresh. So technology consulting wra
language. Click on that. Okay. Wuam
language overview. Let's see. Get
started. Can you like run it online? I
think they they have an elementary
introduction to the wuam language. Wufam
language wufam university. Okay.
uh certification available about this
interactive course.
No, I want to go to I just want to go to
the Wufam language website. Okay,
so document tagger programmable. Okay,
simple deployment.
uh you know Wuam website they have like
hundred thousands of
pages perhaps what over a million pages
because
anyway so it becomes very confusing and
lots of um oh yeah let's magnify okay
lots of uh marketing
stuff so let's
I just want to go to the wolf
documentation. So let's click on that
source footers. Okay. Zero learning
usage talk to the intelligent assistant.
They added that feature just like chat
GPT in Wuam language.
Um okay. So technologies click on that
language go
there and okay try now let's see try
now enable Java okay enable Java do
that let me enable enable
JavaScript sign
in yeah so you got to sign in well I can
sign in But uh but I need to type
password and stuff. So let's go to um
UFM language overview.
Okay. Now where do I get to the
documentation
part? You know I can easily go to it via
here but I want to navigate to
it. Overview playground learning
resources. Okay. learning resources.
There it is online documentation. So by
default you have like 7,000 functions
built in. Okay. So uh if you don't know
for example uh question mark
asterisk so that will list all
um functions building. Okay. It's going
to be like 10,000. Okay. So you can see
uh so let's magnify this to can you show
in two
columns you know it's like
endless okay let's go to the top let's
do this
um let's not do that okay so names and
uh uh names
um then you want to show it uh okay
So table
form okay not
that
names okay there are
like
1100,000
items show more okay so that's not what
I
want I want so let's just say length
okay shift Enter. So you got
11. Wait, you got 11 and
8,000 100,000.
Okay. Uh anyway, so that's the function
spiel in
uh let's
see let's try
that. No. So what? So what is names?
Let's see documentation for names. So
names gives a list of the names of
symbol that match the string. Okay. So
you can also be a pattern. Okay. So
let's
[Music]
see. Okay. Yeah.
7,000
7,600 functions. Okay.
Now, Ctrl L to copy
the input and shift enter to show all of
them. So, here are a list of all the
functions. You can
see 7,000 building. So compared to
Python building library is like you know
like like 100 times small unless you
install the Python you know the Python
uh math you know math or whatever you
know then it's like two gigabytes
anyway. Okay. So so here's a list of wam
language names. Now let's go back to the
documentation. So when you code woofer
language this page is the most important
because it documents every function
building. Okay. So uh core language in
structures you know it's because it's so
huge 7,000 of them. So they organize
them into um sections and fields. So you
got core language and structures
language overview list
expression association which is like
Python's dictionary or hash table um
variable and functions rules and
patterns functional programming. So
let's try you know let's say let's go to
functional programming. So then it list
all these functions that's related to
functional programming.
Okay. So let me demonstr let me you know
let me just showcase you know show my
own tutorial. So you go to wuang
language tuto tutorial on kasali.info wu
language in depth. Then you have a
section a section on strings you know
everything you need to do with strings
numbers boolean list. Okay. So if you go
to list, so here's an introduction to
wam list which is the most fundamental
uh thing in wam language because wufam
language is like a list. It's based on
list. Okay. Then you got list position
uh nested list array tree dimensions
list level depth and list operations.
Okay. So then you got you know all these
operations you can do with
list and let's go to
iterations. So here's a introduction to
iteration in wam language. You can
generate a list using um using table.
This is like Python's list
comprehension. They can generate a flat
list or nested list or matrix. Okay. So
then you got mapping you know map index
map thread variations you got recursion
nest nest while fold fold while like
reduce fix point and you got filter. If
you want to filter by a function that
you would use select. If you want to
filter by a pattern then you you uh
would use cases. So you see this is
different from Python or Ruby others. So
you you can also filter by a pattern.
Okay. So go back uh then find
membership, find their position or if it
exist or how many of them you know count
and so on and grouping. So so so these
are my tutorial you can go into. Now
let's go back to the Wufam language
documentation. So you can see this
subsection wam functional programming
they they list lots of the things I you
know on my tutorial. So each one is a
function. for example, go to next nest.
So this nest allows you to nest any um
function. So if you have a function and
you want to do recursion, a function
calling
itself, you can just use nest on any
function. Okay? Like typically in other
programming languages, you write you
define a function and in the body of the
function you call itself, right? That's
recursion. But in Wuang language, you
can do that. But also you have this
function nest that allows you to nest
any function you know that. So you know
you can do recursion on any function. So
let's see if I can copy
that. So this you know so all these are
you know so list function. Okay. So they
don't okay. So let's just
try this is kind of my favorite. Um so
we want to nest a function called f and
the nest the first argument is x let's
say three times. Okay shift enter then
you got that you see in python or lisp
or javascript or
hascal or or camel or f this won't work.
When you do this, it'll say f is not
defined because you have not defined it
yet. It doesn't know what is the value
f. But woofam language is a
symbolic term rewriting system. Symbolic
is a key word. So you don't have to you
don't need to have a value of f for it
to work because all it does
is is
is syntactical transformation. So f it
doesn't know what f is. That's okay
because it's just a simple symbol. So it
just return whatever that you know this
is what is supposed to be. But if you
now
define f let's say uh clear f let's
let's define it f let's say
fx. Okay, let's use pattern matching
uh colon equals to let's say x +
1 shift enter. Now you define it and now
if you run
this next shift
enter that that simplifies to this 3 +
x.
Okay. So, so that is the kind of the
power of symbolic computation you know
it you don't have to need anything to be
defined because everything in Wuam
language are just symbols all they do is
like symbol manipulation
okay so let's go back to um so go you
know go back to the wam documentation go
back and go back so we have seen part of
these you know core language instru
structure and this part is mostly what
my tutorial
uh you know is about you know uh
teaching you about wuang language as a
programming language okay but now let's
explore
um let's explore so there's machine
learning there's symbolic and numerical
computation higher mathematical
functions this is you know linear
algebra polomial algebra tensor algebra
complex analysis, discrete calculus,
uh probability theory. Wow, there's also
a neural network some uh neural network
section under higher mathematical
computation. Okay, and discrete math
number theory, group theory. Okay, let's
and crypto cryptography. Okay, let's
open some of them interesting
uh things. So I want to know why do they
list neuronet networks under higher
mathematical
functions. So first of all we got we got
cryptograph encrypt decrypt lets you
encrypt or decrypt any algorithm by a
key by a symmetric or a symmetric
decryption. Okay. Encryption.
Okay. Okay. So these are related to
encryption. So you can do symmetric key
public key public key for uh um let's
see for
uh wait I don't want that blocking
symmetric
key giving complete information for for
a symmetric encryption
system public key public key for a
symmetric public key encryption system
private key for a a symmetric okay
generate generate symmetric key.
Generate a symmetric key. Okay, let's
see. Yeah, let's do this one. Let's try
this
one. Gener Generate a symmetric key
pair. Okay, let's just try
it. Okay, generate a symmetric key pair.
Do we need any?
No. Shift
enter. Wow. Private key, public key. And
this output is formatted in this special
way. So, but let's see the real content.
Okay. So, let's do it again. Let's say x
equals to uh no not here. X equals to
that. Shift enter. Okay. We got X. Now X
we want to get
um private key. private key gets to uh
that.
So okay so you get the you know so the
output this notation means it's a
dictionary or hash table. Okay so the
hash table got two items key value
pairs. So the key is private key and
public key. So let's get the private
key. Okay shift
enter. Um, no. Okay. So, Oh, yeah. So,
okay. So, you
got you uh Okay. So, well,
uh,
what?
Wait. Okay. So, you need you need a
string. Okay. Shift enter. Okay. So, you
got the private key and uh then that's
not enough. Then you need to extract the
first item.
Shift enter. There it
is. Okay. So, type RSA. By default, it
gives you RSA cipher RSA padding
PKCS1. Okay. Public component. Okay. So,
you got that. Then public
modulus. Okay. Then private
component. Okay. So anyway, that's an
example of using this encryption stuff
building
function. So you can do a lot more you
know signatures and power mod uh so cryp
cryptographic number theory factor
integer you know so on and on. Okay. So,
encryption, you know, I don't know that
much and I'm not too interested. Well, I
mean because there are too many things
to learn. You can't learn everything.
So, what about this section
experimental? Okay. So, this neuronet
networks
under under math special functions they
are experimental. Okay. Neuronet
networks are a powerful machine learning
technique that allows a modular
composition of
operators operations layers that can
model a wide wide variety of functions
with high execution and training
performance.
Okay. Okay. So
this this requires
um this kind of requires some
understanding of neuronet
networks. So let's see what you guys are
saying. Uh what do you think of vibe
coding? I think people became dumb if
they let AI think for them. Yeah, I
started to hear vibe coding, but I have
no idea what exactly it
is.
Uh, cyo
ganten skater for pan.
What? Yes, I start the game now. E,
start now. What the
Okay.
So, so let's go back to look at this
uh cryptography. So, mathematical
functions, string and text, symbolic and
numerical
computation, machine learning and
geometry, time related function. Oh, we
were talking about
stream day and time signal processing
time series. Let's look at
um time series. Let's look at signal
processing, knowledge representation and
natural language,
geographic data
manipulation. Okay. Maps, maps and
cgraphy.
So time related okay engineering data
and computation okay systems modeling
control systems reliability
analysis survival function hazard
function wow so go back notebooks and
documentation
uh external interface and connection
this is how you can connect your game
controllers to wam language uh mail
messages services API connected devices
network programming channel
communication internet and computer
system data and databases let's see what
kind of things you have database data
set so you can talk to a SQL database
and no SQL. Okay. So, relational
database and object store. Okay. And
triple store. Wow. That's a new thing.
RDF symbolic representation of a
relational database and its schema.
Wow. You know, I never use these
features. So you know mostly my my use
of wam language experience is mostly um
let's see cloud and deployment you know
so my my use of wam language is mostly
core language
structure and uh okay data manipulation
and an analysis including export and
import.
Yes, machine learning, statist
statistical data analysis, uh data
visualization. I use that a lot and and
this visual and graphics I use
tremendously for you know visualization
of mathematics and
geometry machine learning I'm starting
to learn. So let's look into that and
symbolic and numerical computation I've
done quite a lot but uh but not recently
but those are about calculus you know
doing mathematics linear algebra
calculus solving
equations okay and the higher
mathematical functions is similar to s
you know symbolic numerical computation
but kind of more advanced um okay math
function string and text I do a lot
graphs and networks that's about graph
theory so this is kind of newish like 10
years ago I haven't done much about
graph visualization so that allows you
to generate
uh any
graph so let's see algorithm for graph
layout so
expand so you know you can define a
graph and it can show you different ways
to lay it and this is actually
non-trivial
uh you know so you can have options to
show how you want the graph visualized
laid
out so this is graph layout algorithm
okay show okay so let's go back go
back yeah so mostly I use it as like
kind of like a normal computer
programming language with the ability to
do math and visualization building. You
don't have to load any extra uh
language. For example, let me just
quickly show you 3D. You know, this is
like most typical. Let's copy
that. Yeah, I hate it because, you know,
I cannot copy it because I don't have
cookie turned on. Um but
um
yeah but you can you can just ask
it plot 3D. Okay. So is this plot 3D?
Yes. So now you show the documentation
within Wam language itself. So there it
is. So now you can copy this. In fact,
you can evaluate
this. You can evaluate this right here.
Shift
enter. You see, now it's evaluated or
you can just do it here. But shift
enter.
Fantastic. Okay. So, you know, I do this
a lot. Um, so let's go back. Let's close
that.
So visualization functions and uh let's
go back. Yeah. So let's get into machine
learning. Okay. Let's see what
um machine learning overview and
neuronet networks. Okay. And uh okay.
And it's also got a large language
machine model. Let's go to
it. Okay. So how long have I been
talking? almost an hour
already. So let's see, let's demo some
of these then you know that'll be it.
Um so machine learning overview let's
see
uh LLM related functionality
experimental. Okay so you got chat
object chat evaluate.
Okay. Okay, this is about like chat
bots, you know. So, it allows you to
like create a chatbot on the fly, you
know. So, this is pretty new. The wolf
language includes a variety of
capabilities of making use of large
language models. Chat notebook provides
interactive chatbased access including
ability to offer natural language-based
assistance in using the woofer language.
The woofam language also includes
powerful functions for calling
functionality
programmatically and for allowing LIM to
access wam language tools. Okay. The
wuam prompt repository provides a
curated collection of prompts for
delivering a range of.
So, so I know like since two years ago,
Wuam Wu language started to uh add these
functions. I think they are pretty new.
Let's see. Experimental. Yeah. So, what
year is
this? 2023. You see, introduced in 2023.
Yeah, that's when chat GPT
um came up. Okay. So,
So, LLM function represents a template
for a large language model
prompt. Okay, I'm not clear what it
does. Okay, let's go back now. Let's go
to the next time series, next signal
processing, next machine learning. Okay,
this I'm interested.
So machine learning you know there are
many approaches and
uh part of it is using neuronet networks
uh but let's see datadriven applications
are
ubiquitous market analysis agriculture
healthcare transport networks and
machine learning algorithms have been
developed with a with the specific
purpose of analyzing
patterns and leverage encouraging
correlation with real world measurements
in order to turn data into applications.
The Wuang language offers fully
automated and highly customizable
machine learning
functions to perform classification,
regression, clustering and many other
operations. Okay, this is critical to
perform classification. That's one of
the main thing about machine learning.
Regression is about prediction and
clustering is is kind of similar to
classification. Classical methods are
complemented by powerful symbolic deep
learning frameworks. Okay, let's try
some of
these. Um, so you got classify. You
know, classify is easy to
understand. Let's see. uh
classify
then generate a class classifier
function that attempts to predict class
from example. Okay. So
you you give it a hash table dictionary
also known as association here. So you
give it a data in the form of giant uh
key value pairs. Then it returns a
classifier function and this function
will you know given any input will kind
of classify what data it is. Okay. So
let's
see classify is used to train algorithms
to categorize data into classes based on
observed patterns. Okay.
uh feature extraction what does it
do? So you know all these are fairly
deep and complicated you know so you got
all these
options
but and different
method class distributions decision tree
gradient boost
trees logic logistic
regression and neural networks nearest
neighbor random forest okay I'm somewhat
familiar with some of these but let's
try some examples. Okay,
examples. C
classify one equals to A. What does it
do? Uh let's
see. So let's see. So we call classify
which takes a list of key value pairs.
Then we
got keys one, two, 3.5, four values. We
got a b. So what it does it? So it
returns. So let's see. Shift
enter. It returns a classified function.
Okay. So it re returns a classified
function which is kind of a peg. Okay.
So, oh,
so, so then you give it a value, it will
predict what key it is. Is that
right? Oh, so if you say C 3.1, then it
returns B. Okay, let's try it. So C is
the function we
defined. I mean it returns. So see let's
say uh
32. Okay, shift
enter. Oh, so that's how classify
works. So wait, let's think about. So
you got key value
pairs. Key is the label is like the
category you want to
classify. Uh
wait, wait. key is the input is a value
and the
value is actually the label. Okay, so
given any number you want to know what
how it classifies. Okay, so that's what
it's
doing. So how can we use this? Uh let's
imagine some example classify you got
you know you need something like
billions of
items. Okay, so you can say you know
here's here's the thing. So let's say if
you have a billion of random
numbers and uh you want to classify it.
Let's say it's greater than one or less
than one. Okay, either it's greater than
one or less than one.
So if you want to do this
mathematically, of course, you just
check it's greater than one or less than
one. But you don't know you see you
don't know if you know this is a simple
example so we know of the answer is just
you know greater greater than one but if
you just have data then you have the
information about certain numbers are
like yes certain numbers are no you have
two groups yes and no but you don't know
what is a function so the classif ify
will return a function that
basically is a approximation
of whether it's greater than one or not.
Okay. So actually we can uh try
this. So you need you need a list of
random numbers. Okay. So let's say 1,00
um yeah we can we can we can try to do
this. Okay. Would that be
interesting? Uh, you keep that, you
know, this guy, you post that again, you
get
banned. So, do we have like actual
people watching here, you know, let's
finish this classify. Okay, so let's
generate generate uh uh generate number.
Okay. So let's
begin begin a wuan language code in um
in um so what we want to do generate a
list of random
numbers between zero and one. Okay. So
how do we generate? So
random let's say random real. Okay. So
random real is the function. Let's check
the documentation. It returns. Okay. So
you need the min and
max optional. So min is zero, max is
two. Okay. So that returns
a random
number. Okay. So this is output. Now you
want how many you want them? Let's
say let's say 10. Let's begin small.
Okay.
uh my random
uh my random list. Okay. Uh let's say X
random list equals to
table. Okay. Uh
table random real call that and how many
times? Uh let's say you don't need a
variable. You just say 10 times. Okay.
So run it.
you it'll give you 10 random numbers.
That's correct. Okay. Then you now now
real number is like lots of decimal
places. So let's
say let's say 0 to 100. Okay. Uh
integers. So instead of random
real random integer from zero to 10.
Okay. Uh and 10 of them. Okay. Let's run
it. Okay. That's easier to understand.
Okay.
Now you want to
create Now create
a list of
pairs. If number is less than
five, label it
small.
Okay. If it is greater than
five, label it big.
Okay. So, we want to uh so let's say
uh x table
uh let's say x data. This is like the
big data supposed to be trillions of
items. Okay. But let's start with 10. So
big data will equals to let's how how do
we do that? We can do
um uh map. Okay. So it will equals to
uh map. Okay. So
map a function to the random list. Yes.
We don't care about the label the depth.
So we want to map a function. That's
right. Okay. So the
function x is the input then what they
do? So if uh it's
uh so if
if
x less than five then label it then you
want to create
um then you want to create
uh a rule. Okay.
So then you say X
is small. Okay. Otherwise you say
X
is
big. Okay. So this is our data. Let's
try it. Run
it. Uh no. So wait. Oh yeah. We need to
define random list. Okay. So random list
is not defined. So you need to evaluate
this. Run
it. Okay. So we got yeah this is output.
That's what we want. So nine is big.
Nine is big. Two is small. Nine is big.
Seven is big. One is small. Four is
small. That's what we want. Okay. So now
we let's say remove that. Remove that.
Okay.
uh between zero and 10. Okay, so we got
that
now. Okay, here's the result. Now, so we
got the data, big data. Fantastic. Now,
what we want to do with data, we want to
turn it into a association. So,
um association just
means key value pairs. I mean, it means
dictionary or hash table.
Um, but right now we got a list. We want
to turn it into a hash table. How do you
do that? I forgot. Okay.
Uh, well, let's go to my wam tutorial.
So, let's go to wam language in
depth. Then number
list expression items. So, we got uh
list
loop iteration function
then data structure association. Okay,
let's see how do we create that. Okay,
so just replace the head. Yeah.
Okay. Okay.
So, association. Okay. Just replace the
head. Uh actually you can put it inside
and let's
see. Yeah. Okay. So all we have to do is
um association. Okay. So let's just you
know all we have to do is
just say the whole thing is
that put this inside there but we can
just say at okay that's the same thing
okay so that will
return select
all run
it there it is that's what wait yeah
yeah that's what we want okay so remove
that remove that okay so there so this
returns this association so 7
48 so so some of the item are repeat you
see repeated items are removed okay so
anyway now we got the data now we want
to
classify classify
I uh it returns a
function classify that data. It will
return a function. Okay.
Then then all we want to do is to
apply the function to a number. Let's
say some number that doesn't exist.
Let's say three. You see? then that will
say small. Okay, let's see how Yeah, I'm
pretty sure that will return small. Then
that demonstrates this classify function
works. Okay,
so let's just run it. Double check.
Okay, classify function equals to. Okay,
this returns a function data. Then we
apply it to three. Run it.
classify the data is not formatted
correctly.
Okay.
Why why is the data not formatted
correctly? Doesn't is it the
association? Let's see now. Let's go
back to So wait. So you see this is
formatted. So you got keys are the
numbers, values are its
labels. So it seems I'm correct there.
So why does it Oh, so it's it's a list.
It's not association. I got it. So we
actually we don't want association.
Okay. So hold on a second.
comment there out and now let's run the
whole
thing. Yeah. So we want this list. We
don't want association. Okay. So this is
the
result. We don't want the hash table.
It's a just list of pairs. Okay. So now
we say classify then run the function on
number three. Do we have number three
here? No. Okay. So, it should say small.
Run
it. Wow. Wait. Uh, where's the result?
Time lapse training example used.
Fantastic. Current method. Best method.
Current current accuracy. Current lost.
Wow. Wow. There it is. Can you see that?
Small.
So here is the
output. Fantastic. Now let's try to run
this in wra language.
Okay. So we demonstrate the classify
uh function classify data. So shift
enter. It just directly returns small.
Fantastic. You see three is not in the
input but now it
inferred you know it learned that three
belongs to the small
fantastic okay that's it for demo I
think that's fantastic hello Hank ching
do you think notebook interface are good
yes absolutely
uh hang says replace head thank you hang
um yeah fantastic Think we got this to
work. Uh so this is
titled demo the
classify classify machine learning
function. Fantastic. Now put it back
color it show in browser and that is
what we have done. Fantastic.
Now uh yeah so Hank's question uh good
question because I have a big rant on
that notebook interface. So you know so
let me talk about that for a few
minutes. So
normally in the beginning you have
command line interface. So for example,
CD CD web and let's magnify control uh
yeah okay CD web
si info okay so okay and cd to talk show
today's talk show directory so you can
see that's you know my talk show
directory so you can d the list all the
files again. So talk show page and you
can list the backup you know let's see
you know those are t backup. So we can
do the
uh files and uh
filter
ft filter
anything ending in a tilda. Okay. So you
can can you see let's do it again. There
it is. Then you can just say
remove. So this is command line
interface in the beginning. So then you
just pipe it. Pipe uh pipe to remove.
Okay. Are we sure? You know I don't want
to delete my stuff.
Yeah. Okay. So now you can just say
remove do
it you know like Unix joke they say
remove dash f
slashroot remove the entire your disk
data so let's list again there's no more
so it just
removed you can see let's go back here
so let's see uh you you can can you see
it removed now
refresh refresh Now it removed all the t
files. So in the beginning you got the
command line interface. For example, you
can start Python like that and 1 + uh
two oneplus 3 enter four right command
line
interface. Now beta is a
um is kind of the notebook. So for
example we can show so a new file save
it.x X Python. Okay. Py uh today's
state. Let's just say XXX. Okay. So now
you can say 1 + 3. Same thing.
And and look I going to run it. Okay. So
do
it. Uh do we have um
wait? Oh, I do I do I have
uh
Python is my streaming is my streaming
good has been okay. So let's try this
again. Okay, Python print that. Okay,
now do it. So here's the result four.
Now if you want to compute something
else you can do it here you know five
you see. Now if you want you can go back
here let's say edit it modify and redo
it five. You see so when you have a kind
of the file interfa notebook or file
interface you have the power of manipul
manipulating history and everything you
do. you have a history of it instead of
the command
line. You also have a history but like
you cannot see it. You have to like up
arrow then you know and when you want to
edit history it's
hard. So a notebook kind of interface is
much superior because it allows you to
edit anywhere. Okay. So I have an
article on that. Uh let's see. Let me
show you ripple. Okay. So history of
notebook interface uh closure. So get
script notebook. So let's
see there command line interface versus
ripple interface. Okay. So ripple just
means command line.
Okay you know command line ripple versus
notebook. So command line allows you to
sequentially evaluate the
expressions. That's you know this is
most familiar to everyone okay everyone
is used to the command line interface
but however notebook is much better
because you can do whatever the command
line does the ripple do by just you know
type something uh 3 + 4 plus whatever
sequentially but you can also see your
entire history and you can re-evaluate
any part of the history anytime you
And by default the the thing is saved as
a file. So you have a record you know
you got a file you can do a backup you
know if you want.
So so this is kind of the notebook
interface in
Emacs but like one level up is to
actually have graphics you know. So like
we demonstrate in wuam language you you
know you can have like this
is one level up in addition to just edit
any part see the whole history but you
know you can see the entire history of
your computation but you can also have
graphics or sound or v or and then you
can manipulate it and so
on and interactively. So notebook is far
more superior than
um command line interface also known as
ripple. Okay, that's it for today. Thank
you
guys. Hank says your stream better than
mine. You bet. You've been doing it
longer than I have. Thank you. So Hank
uh so this guy we need to
ban this
guy report remove put in timeout uh ping
channel
remove where is the
ban hide user in this channel okay too
much spam
Okay.
So, yeah. So, Hank, you did a video, but
I didn't see it. Let's see. But that's
it for today. Thank you guys for
watching.
Um, yeah, Hank. Hank been on uh
streaming for quite a while, I think.
[Music]
Um yeah uh Hank let's check
out beating Vatron jelly room. Yeah I
don't know what is
Vatron. Wow. Four hours. Wow. This is my
last day vacation for,
you know, like they just just a creeper
just up on you like that's a fun wild
Yeah. Yep. They blow up.
Okay, that's it for today. Thank you
guys for
watching. Uh, yep. So, if you guys like
my stuff, you know, remember to check
out my website to, you know, like, thumb
up my videos or whatever. I don't like
that. But but post my videos to your
Twitter, to your blog, and uh share with
others and so on. And most importantly,
you can pay me, okay? Go buy me a coffee
or whatever. Pay me a $100, okay?
Something like one shot, PayPal, Amazon
gift card
on. Code at the bottom. Okay, that's it.
Bye, guys.
Okay. Shut down. Shut down. I'm just
going to shut down. So this Python. So
this is about notebook
interface. Okay. Uh
cut. Close. So wam language
uh notebook
interface. Copy that
link. Paste there. Linkify. Make a
list. Bye guys. Fantastic. this make
let's make a screenshot of
this. I I like this
game, you know. You know, it's like 2D
game but in 3D like a Voltor.
Yeah, you lose all your stuff.
How many times I like died and went back
to you know? I never got into game
programming. I like to, but you know,
I'm too old.
Um, bye.