Hello guys. Welcome to another episode
of Xah Talk Show.
And today is randomish topic. We are
going to talk random. I'm going to show
you my keyboard new discoveries, new
things on keyboard. And
fantastic symbology of the Unicode.
Um
And several things, okay? And and
JavaScript.
And JavaScript of course we need to talk
about fascinating JavaScript. Okay, so
multiple things today. Captain Captain's
log.
0221.
Okay.
Shall we begin? Hello link. Hello link.
Good morning. Good afternoon. Good
evening to Russia.
Uh
so, the first stop is this fantastic
keyboard I discovered, you know, from
this guy Malvago, Stephen from Malvago.
Now, this is a fantastic ergonomic
keyboard, you know, it's just like
Kinesis. You know, you are looking at my
Kinesis keyboard. So, let me show you.
So, you go to Xah keyboard blog. Just
search for it.
Xah keyboard guide.
Then you go to the blog. There's several
videos. Go watch them. Fantastic
dense information. Everything you need
to know about keyboards. You know, the
layout, the key binding, the physical
keys, you know, the ergonomics, the
tenting, how many how much how much
degrees is good. Everything's there. So,
keyboard blog. And
there are several new items. Also, one
of them is this fantastic ergonomic
keyboard. And you are look looking at my
keyboard video here, you see?
Right now my keyboard is
So, let's magnify it. So, okay. So,
let's magnify it. Okay, so so Kinesis,
so that's this one. And uh
Ultimate Hacking, that's this one. I use
it as a key marker. I talked about many
times. But today, the main star is this
one.
Glove 80 keyboard. So, you can see it's
curved like, you know, the surface is
curved like a ball. And uh you know, the
one thing special, truly special about
this one is it's wireless, wireless,
okay? Because of all the ergonomic
keyboards,
they are they are almost always wired.
You know, you cannot find one
you cannot find one that has a ball
surface
which is not
wired, okay? They are all wired.
So, for example, let me show you a
do-it-yourself, you can see more Dactyl,
that's wired.
And the Dactyl ManuForm, that's also
wired. And this one, and this one from
Dygma, our friend Dygma.
Uh and the Red Box, okay, fantastic. So,
anyway, so the main thing today, you
know, they are all wired. So,
so this is a fantastic discovery. This,
you know, they make this
Glove 80. Right now, it's on
Kickstarter. And uh they already got
their um
required uh number of money.
So, they're going to make this. So,
you're going to If you If you want to
buy, go buy it. Okay, go to the, you
know, where to buy. There's a link at
the bottom. Just search for Xbowdy
keyboard. Xbowdy keyboard blog. So, it's
wireless.
And uh apparently, they spent You know,
when I first saw this, I I thought, "Oh,
it's just another variation." But
apparently, they spent a lot time
uh you know,
like five In five years, they made like
500 prototypes. And they designed they
finally arrived at this design, you
know, with this particular thumb keys
layout. Because according to them, this
is, you know, this came out the best.
So, this is great. I think it's great.
Of course, I haven't used it yet, you
know, I you know, I don't have it and
we'll have to see. So,
but I think it's a great and also the,
you know, they use they choose to use
this uh
thin profile switch, which is
which is the um Kailh Chocolate switch.
Which is great because I had I have this
switch.
Excuse me. So, I had that switch. I used
it on Let me show you where
I used that switch before.
Uh
and that thin profile switch also comes
in
linear or clicky.
Uh or tactile, you know, variation uh
various versions. So, I've used that
keyboard. So, let me show you, okay,
hold on a second. Let me gather all the
links.
Uh
there. So,
I have, you know, so I have this
keyboard I talked about before in my
previous talk show.
Uh
it's great. And
and this, you know,
and this guy is great, okay? This the
guy who makes this in Canada.
His name is Gen Bernard.
He's one of those wearing programmer's
socks.
Okay.
So, anyway, so that's a
you know, that's his keyboard. That's
great.
And also I also have this one.
Yeah, this one, but actually I never got
to use it because I haven't
you know, requires studying of the QMK
software and I just never got to do it.
So, this is like 30 only 30 keys. This
is 30%, right? Yeah, something like only
uh 36 keys. So, it's it's extremely
minimal.
So, wait. Is my video uh going I haven't
checked. Video check, audio check. Okay.
So, I'm going to read the comments in a
bit, okay? Keep them coming. So, Choc
switch and I I also use this one. This
is kind of No mush have it keyboard. A
cheapo from China China. The cheapo
empire.
You know, so
and you know, it's it's great. So, Choc
switch thin profile, they are good,
okay?
So,
so back to the Glove 80. Uh where is it?
Back to Glove 80 keyboard. So, check it
out.
Okay, so that's one topic. Now, let's go
to to the next topic.
Several random topics today. Let's go to
the next topic. So, let me get my Emacs.
So, Emacs is one of my main topic as you
know if you watch my video. So, Emacs
C-a-f-l-y keys fantastic. I'm using
Dvorak layout and on the pink window is
you can see all the command calls and
the keystrokes I press such as moving
cursor by block or by word, forward or
backward or by character. You can see
all the all the command names on the
pink window. And if you just search for
one of the command names, you can find
the source code most most of them.
C-a-f-l-y keys it's on GitHub.
Okay, it's one of my most popular
project. Okay, so that's about Emacs.
That's about keyboard. So, what's the
next topic? So, let me talk about let me
show you the
the um
Okay, I don't actually have a link, but
let me show you the
Keyboard symbols, keyboard symbology,
you know, the most fascinating.
So, let's take a break. Let's see what
you guys are saying. There are some
modded wireless ductiles, but yes, they
are rare. Okay. Link Link is a keyboard
expert. Okay.
You know, Link Link did a keyboard. Let
me just mention it again. So, um
Russian, you know, keyboard love from
Russia.
So, where is it? So, let's go to Okay.
So, let's go to Xah keyboard blog.
Actually, you know,
a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a a
a a a a a a a a a a actually
Xah keyboard
blog. Let me show you. Just search for
it.
Keyboard blog, okay?
Then,
there's a Russian.
Russian do-it-yourself. Actually, I I I
need time to finish this page. So, Link
you going to help me. Okay. So, I talked
about this in in the past videos. So,
Link created one of these. Yeah, this is
Link's keyboard.
clackernet
Okay, so, let's see the comments. Then,
we going to talk about
keyboard symbology. Break the loop. Long
time no see. Hey, long time no see.
Uh
Okay, so, Archie Duck. Yeah, and
something one Break the loop.
Keep starter. Yeah, that's nice.
Uh
Okay, so,
Okay. Okay. Okay. APL uses a lot of
symbols, right? That's correct. Now,
Okay, I
I wasn't planning to talk about APL, but
since you mentioned it, let's go to it a
little bit, okay? So, you just go to Xah
keyboard.
Yeah, just
Xah Lee APL. So, you can find quite a
lot articles about APL. So, for example,
all the images about APL, all of these
are for my website. So, let's click on
one of them. So, this article is about
how do you create a APL layout on your
on your keyboard, on your operating
system, on your Mac, on your Linux, on
your Windows. So, you can actually
create a keyboard layout to type APL
symbols.
Now, what is APL? APL is a programming
language, okay? I'm not going to talk
about that today. So, Unicode APL
symbols, these are the all the symbols
you see on the APL programming language,
and they are in Unicode. That means you
can
Uh let's turn on JavaScript, so we have
fancy features. Let Google know what you
are doing. Refresh. So, you can see
pop-up, you know, showing the Unicode
information. For example, this character
is star operator.
Notice it's different from star. It's
different from Unicode star, but rather
it it's a
star operator. You see, that's a black
star.
This is a light five-pointed black star.
And this is heavy five-pointed black
star.
And this one is black small star.
You know, you see, the Unicode, you
know, many of them look similar, but
they are actually they have a they have
different semantics, okay? So, let me go
back to the
APL.
Ah, where where is the APL go? Ah, it
went away.
APL, Kxali APL. So, yeah, so open that.
Open that.
Unicode search, okay? So,
open that.
So, here's APL symbols, and you can see
several keyboards, you know, old
keyboard, ancient keyboard with APL
symbols on it.
Uh and so APL is a programming language,
okay? So these are operators. So before
you see so that, you know, we back to
the star operator. That's a character
from the APL programming language. APL
stands for A Programming Language, okay?
So and APL
you know, and and Wolfram Language, you
know, I mentioned many times, you know,
my main topic, Wolfram Language, the
love, the programming
uh language love of my life, you know,
go watch my videos, okay? Wolfram
Language, the most
efficient tutorial, you know,
well, you know, my my tutorials on
Wolfram Language, okay? The the best
language.
So
so why am I talking about Wolfram
Language? Because Wolfram Language is
based on two languages, APL and Lisp,
okay? Basically, you take APL
and you take Lisp characteristics, you
combine them, you add pattern matching.
You add pattern matching and lots of
mathematical functions, that's Wolfram
Language. So that's how they are how
they relate, APL. So so APL and Wolfram
Language and and MATLAB and uh
uh GNU
uh GNU uh Octave
Ah, getting too old, I forgot the names.
You know, MATLAB Maple, you know, these
math-oriented languages, they they are
in general, they are called array um
um
they are called um
array languages. Uh no, that's that's
not the right word. Anyway, I'm not you
know, I'm not going to talk about
programming today. But anyway, you
mentioned APL, so this is a bunch of
information about APL. So
So and this article is yeah, creating a
layout for APL and not just APL symbols,
but you can create a layout for uh any
number of mathematical symbols like all
these. You can type them easy. For
example, let me demonstrate. I
demonstrated many times. Magnify. So,
let's say I want arrow, there it is.
Uh you know, or I can type a key
directly if I want to do that. But right
now I'm using a
a brief system.
Uh they have different um
depending on how often you need certain
characters and depending on how
yeah, how often you need them.
How often you need these special math
characters and also depends on how many
you actually use. You know, they are
they are hundreds of math characters.
You don't Most of them you don't use
every day.
So, depending on how many number of
characters you want to type the math
symbols or emoji and depending on which
one which one of them you use most
frequently,
you have different methodologies to
input them.
So, right now I choose a brief that
suits me for the right arrow, but you
can also like press control alt and
arrow that to enter a brief.
Which one is better depends on like I
said, depends on how many characters you
have and
how often are they used.
For example, the the
the this character, okay? The
uh
acute E, right? This is This is This is
called acute E and uh describe char, you
can see
Latin small letter with E.
Latin small letter E with acute, that's
the name of that. And you can also uh
have um
E
grave, okay? this So, describe char, you
can see Latin small letter with grave.
So, for example, this character, acute
E, is used
uh very frequently in French.
Uh in French and some other languages.
In that case, you you don't want You
don't want a brief.
You probably you want, you know,
like pressing a key combination to
insert that. So, anyway, and I have an
article on that.
Okay, let's let's show that. Okay, so
uh
yeah, about the methodology of
inputting, you know, which methodology
is the most efficient for inputting
special characters. In other words, you
are creating a input system. Okay, so
let's go to it.
Uh let's go to So, let me show you,
okay? So, we haven't talked about
Canadian keyboard yet. So, keyboard
layout design,
then you go down all the
you know, all the ergonomic layout,
Dvorak, Colemak, QWERTY, Workman, you
know, and so on.
Then
then you have international layout,
which is layout of different countries.
You know, so this is a map of which
countries uses what layout in Europe,
mostly in Europe. So, you have, for
example, uh German keyboard layout. You
see You see that they got
you know, Germans got a few You see
umlaut, you know,
um
You see those characters, UO
A with two dots above. They are called
uh umlaut or not
Did I pronounce it wrong? Umlaut.
Umlaut. Something like umlaut. And
another way,
you know, the another another name for
those are
um
I forgot, but I have a article on that.
But anyway, so
So, keyboard layout. So, this article is
all about uh you know, so you have
efficient keyboard layout, you have
international keyboard layout, then you
have input systems. Okay? For example,
here's also French layout. Then you have
input systems, which is when
which is when
which is when you have a language that
has 1,000, you know, 10,000 symbols, you
cannot type them. That's when you need a
input system. So, we were talking about
APL symbols, we were talking about math
symbols. This is, you know, basically
you are getting into input systems. So,
input systems, how do you design them?
You know, that's a big topic. So,
for example, here's input system for
Chinese.
And the input system for Japanese.
Now, besides input system, then you have
layout, you know, for example, in for
Japanese, you know, when you type you
when you need to type Japanese, you have
the input system is involved. How do you
design
a software user interface, basically,
input to input this, you know,
10,000 characters because Japanese also
use Chinese. So, that's one thing, but
then you also have the layout.
So, let me show you. So, layout of input
systems for Japanese and for Chinese.
So, where is it? Um
Okay, here. So, let me show you a few.
So, Japanese keyboard layout. You can
see,
you know, these are normal. This is kind
of modern and normalish, which is not
good, inefficient, and boring, and
inefficient, most importantly.
It's in They are in inefficient. But
then, but Japanese still do have
efficient layout for various Japanese
input systems. For example, this one is
a thumb layout.
Nicola
J keyboard layout. That's a technical
name.
Then you have thumb shift layout. You
know, they got thumb shift thumb keys.
You see, they are actually different.
You see, this one is thumb shift
keyboard, okay? Then but this one is a
Nicola layout, which is uh uh uh
Well, uh
Oh, wait. They are the same thing, okay?
The you know, they are the thumb shift
keyboard. But then you also have
you know, for example, M system
layout. Layout and input system kind of
uh
merged together.
You know, comes in as one sometimes. So,
this Japanese For Japanese, you have the
M systems layout. Then you also have,
you know,
J J I S X 6004
layout.
Uh or input system. Then you have the
Tron input system. You know, also
Japanese Lots of thumb keys. So,
Japanese keyboard is fascinating. You
study their design history. So, we back
to So, we were talking about input
systems, right? That's why we got into
this topic. So,
what I want to say, let's get back to
what about math symbols? For example,
uh
let's see, where is it?
So, these are about layouts.
Okay,
yeah. So, if you want to know the
efficiency,
the study of efficiency of input systems
for math symbols or emoji, then you go
to um
layout, keyboard design key binding key
binding design. So, all these this
chapter all these articles is about key
binding design such as Emacs, Vim, or
Neovim.
Emacs, Vim, Neovim, or
uh
or uh Photoshop, you know, Photoshop,
Adobe Photoshop, and you know, but all
video editors, you know, you have 100
keyboard shortcuts. How do you design
them? What's the best design? What's the
most efficient design for keyboard
shortcuts system? Now, input, you know,
Emacs key binding in fact is you can
consider it as a keyboard shortcut
system. And so so is so is uh typing
these math characters. For example, in
TeX LaTeX
nerd's favorite thing. So, this article
so you see
math input design uh math input symbols
uh design of math symbols input system.
So, for example, you can, you know, like
most Linux phonetics they would
they they they they they would know they
would
advocate they would say, you know, the
old graph that's familiar to them old
graph or the dead key. Okay? In fact,
those are not as efficient.
So, anyway, this article studies all the
differences. Is it better to have a dead
key or is it better to have a old graph
key or is it better to use a brief
system like a brief system like RA
press enter.
LA press enter left arrow. Okay? Up
arrow up arrow press enter
sum
then press shift space, you know, I'm
using a different different systems. So,
emo
emoji, okay? So, input systems, you
know, which system is more more
efficient.
Okay, so
I talked about here uh
Yeah, basically basically it comes down
to how many characters are there you
need and which one of them you need most
frequently. Basically, that's the
issue.
Okay, so next topic so this so let's
talk yeah, next topic. So let's talk
about let's see did we talked about yes,
we talked about that. Jap- Japanese
keyboard Japanese input system Japanese
layout Chinese input system I did a
video talking about this few months ago
two two or three months ago Chinese
input system.
Then you have the design of math symbols
input system
which relates to APL.
Okay, keyboard symbols, okay. Now let's
get on to this topic. This this this
this is about you know, on keyboard you
have symbols, you know, most of them a b
c d e f g you know, letters but then you
have
you know, arrow keys down arrow up
arrow, then you have shift key, you have
control, you have command key
you know, so you need you know, volume
up key, volume down key, search key,
redo undo cut key.
You know, search key and help key.
So that's about keyboard symbols. So
what what labels they put on keyboard,
you know, what symbols they do they use?
So this article is a
kind of a complete survey of them.
So you can see some of them. So you see
Windows logo key and special here is the
control key. Microsoft, you know,
they they started to use this asterisk
symbol with open open center asterisk
symbol
to represent control key. Why? There's a
reason. You know, so anyway, this
article talks about them. So, you can
see undo, redo,
help key,
paste,
then you have
open file key, document key,
screenshot key, or turn on camera key,
zoom in, zoom out. You know, zoom in,
zoom out is very common function in
modern
um
you know, you need it. So, you see I
have all macros set up. So, if you look
at my mouse,
so can you see my mouse?
Yeah, so okay. So, let me put it here.
So, if I
go back here,
uh go back here. So, if I nudge the
wheel to the left,
they shrink the page.
If I nudge it to the right, they make
zoom in, magnify. So,
this zoom in and zoom out
becomes frequently used today everywhere
because
because this mon- monitor size, you
know, the resolution, and also the phone
phone, very small monitor,
they vary a lot. So, often times you
need to zoom in, zoom out down when you
browse the web. So,
so that so that's why so you have the
Now, these days you have dedicated zoom
keys, for example, on this Microsoft
keyboard, fairly common.
And uh okay, so let's
go back. So, now
symbology, okay, keyboard symbols. So,
you can see
you know, and this is a bit
rare. For For example, this one. This is
French Canadian. This is actually
Canadian multilingual layout, which I
which is this one, Canadian multilingual
layout. And this is used mostly in
Quebec, Canada.
You know, to type French and English.
So, you can So, you can see they are
full standard all in French.
So, you can see they use these symbols,
you see?
The helm symbol,
you know, the for
You know, the the controller for a ship.
That is the You know, that's for the
control key. Then you have the old key
symbology, you know, you have page down
or home end key. You see each one of
them. Break, pause,
uh and caps lock, caps lock, num lock.
This is scroll lock, scroll lock.
Yeah, so the And look at the escape key
symbol. So, this
This is a standard documentation from
Quebec, Canada government. Okay? But But
they didn't design it. It originate from
It's actually from one of the ISO
standard um
document, you know, about what symbols
to use on keyboard. So, they
you know, they create a standard for
that. But actually, most keyboard do not
use these symbols, you know, like
What the are they incomprehensible?
For example, this one is insert key. You
see? This This
A with kind of arrow, that's That's a
That's a kind of standard and popular
notation for
for um editing for
How do you say, you know, in in a
profession of writing, you you have tech
You have editors. How they uh
proofreaders and uh
um editors, anyway. So,
when you want to, say, you need to add a
word there, you use this is a
kind of the
conventional symbol to for insert. So,
so, therefore, on the keyboard, they
also decided that this symbol is for
insert.
You know, it which does make sense, but
because nobody use it, so, you know,
it's rarely seen.
But, however, they use it on the
Canadian, uh, keyboard, and you can see
some examples here. So,
so, this is a keyboard, uh,
let's see here, here.
Uh,
okay, so, this is a keyboard. This is a
Mac keyboard for Quebec, in fact, you
know, in French part of Canada. So, you
they you can see all these symbols, and
they also use it on this Mac keyboard,
Apple's keyboard, you see? There, there.
You know, one of the interesting thing
is the old symbol. You see, they use
kind of a double
They use a up arrow with double head,
double-headed white arrow for the old
key. That's a bit strange, because
there's a standard symbol for old key.
Let me show you. So, anyway, on this
article, okay, so,
so, you, uh, we talk about so, Windows
logo key, there's no symbol for that,
because that's actually Windows logo is
actually, uh, trademark.
So, but
but this character, black diamond minus
white X, is somewhat common to represent
the Windows key.
Uh, so, Windows key, Mac command key,
Mac command key also has a history, you
know, historically it's a place of
interest site.
So you have you can see old key. This is
a standard key standard Unicode symbol
for old key.
And uh
um
and option key and so on. And then you
have meta key and so on. So that's So I
just um
updated this page. I made some, you
know, I improve on my website often. So
today I actually made some changes to
improve this page.
So, you know, for one of the thing I did
is make all the Unicode red. So now they
stand out.
So let let me let me show you, okay? So
So let's go back to coding. So here is
the page you are looking at. That's the
page you are looking at. That's the
source code. And you go to CSS this
line. And you can see mark Unicode red,
okay? So if you say white, go back here,
refresh. You see? It was like that. But
I changed it to red. And I also changed
the font size
to uh
much bigger before. Refresh.
So keyboard symbols.
Okay, uh let's go on to the next topic,
okay? So lots of interesting keyboard
symbols. Meta key.
Hyper key.
On this machine keyboard. Okay. Uh
let's see.
Menu key. Hamburger menu.
Uh friend uh
our friend
in you
is here or not.
In full, okay.
Uh
then there's a standard symbol for
compose key. But you you know, but
actually you rarely see this symbol
used. Actually, that symbol is actually
used in
Let's see. Let me try to find it. I need
to put a picture here actually. So,
that's another to do.
So, old graph key, compose key, and dead
key. Oh, I forgot about compose key. So,
there's old graph key, then there's also
compose key, then there's also dead key.
All these keys are used to insert
special characters or rarely used
characters. So, you can see compose key,
old graph key on Sun Microsystems
keyboard. This keyboard is mine. I have
it.
I have it I had it 20 years ago.
I used it 20 years ago. So, um
yeah, so there it is, compose character
key.
And I I do remember seeing
seeing a keyboard with a actual
uh
compose symbol
as a label.
Hm, it's not here.
Uh
Okay.
Maybe I'm mistaken. I forgot.
Okay, so that's, you know, some of the
very interesting things about,
you know, keyboard key symbols. And for
example, tab key,
you know, the most popular standard way
to use standard symbol for tab key is
this
kind of uh left and right arrow.
But,
you see, but that character is actually
not too intuitive. I think it's more
intuitive to use this character. Right
right words arrow to bar.
And you can see some of the actual
examples. I'm not going to show it, but
you You see, you know, for example,
here, tab key.
Uh okay, so that's about keyboard
symbology, okay? And Apple
Uh
okay, one more thing interesting about
you know, one one thing interesting
about Apple's
you know, symbol used on Apple keyboard
is that
in recent years, about 5 years ago, they
changed you see be- you know, before
before 2018, so 4 years ago,
4 years ago, the home key, home and end
key, Apple uses this, you know, to upper
left corner for the
home key, and arrow
towards right lower corner for the end
key.
But after 2018, they changed that to
just that. This is much more intuitive.
Even though you see the the reason is
that you see the reason is that if you
use these, you know, up and down arrow
two bar,
then it's not
accurate, you know, it's not accurate
because up arrow, I mean, the home key
is for on Windows, it moves the
character to the beginning of the line,
for example,
like that. You see?
So, if my cursor is here, move to the
beginning of line or move to the end of
line. That's home and end.
But but in browser, you should be when
you press home and end, it moves to the
top of the page, for example. Yeah.
Uh yeah, my home key is mapped here, so
you see home and
You see? So, sometimes it's used to move
to the be- beginning of the line or end
of the line, but sometimes it's used to
move to the top of the
document or bottom of the document. So,
that's that is why Apple
you know, Apple's decided they're going
to use this, you know,
diagonal arrow to represent home and
end.
Before 2018, they they did that for like
10 years. But after after 2018, they
decided, "Nah, that's
Nobody understand what the is
diagonal arrow." You You You see, you
try to be precise.
You try to be too precise, that's the
problem. Because,
you know, in
Nobody can understand what's a diagonal
arrow mean. So, they Apple change it to
the simply up and down arrow to the bar.
So, that's some of the interesting
aspect in the choice and in the design
of choosing a symbol
as a label for a key.
Okay, that's about that topic. So, let's
move on to the next topic.
Okay.
Let's go back here.
Text, let's add it here. Showing
browser.
Uh next topic, let's talk about
JavaScript. Okay? Let's now Next, we're
going to talk about something related to
programming and programmer culture.
Okay? Let me read the comments first.
We talked about 40 minutes, that's good.
So, there's a question from
from Jack Smith
uh about, you know, he's new to
programming language and only coded
Python for 6 months. And the question
is, "What's your advice for a newbie
about learning multiple languages? Is it
better to master one language or should
you learn uh several ones?"
Okay, so that
So, my answer to that question
So, first of all, should you learn just
focus on one language first or you
start learning several at a time? Um
I think there's no
right answer to that. That mostly depend
on you, your learning style, whichever
is best for you. So,
you know,
so if you study multiple languages at
the same time or roughly around the same
time, you might get confused. And also,
if you are
the type of person who easy get
distracted,
so
if that's the case, when you learn
multiple languages, you will never you
tends to never master one of them. You
know, you just go about like see oh oh
oh someone is talking about C++ then you
go there, look for several days, then
has got it, you know, you never end up
learning one one programming language
well. So,
so should you learn just one language at
a time or
you know, that or several that that
really depends on you. Um yeah, there's
no right answer to that.
And um personally,
I mean, even for me, I don't have one
correct one one single answer for that
because
back in the days, when I was younger,
let's say 10 years ago, 20 years ago,
I'm the type I'm the type of a guy who
we are just learn one language at a
time.
Until I I either mastered it or I
decided, okay, I had enough. Then I
switch, like one thing at a time. I want
to focus, you know, just focus on this
one thing at a time.
That is my uh that's how I used to be
when it comes to programming languages.
But that way has a flaw to me because
you because when you have you know and
also I kind of like a profession
perfectionist so when you focus on on
one thing I tends to want to master
until I master the whole thing I will
not touch any other thing okay.
So that
has a problem that you know because that
tends to
make me
uh stagnate you know basically you know
I just stagnate and go don't go anywhere
else so that's not good.
So on the other hand if you study
different languages you also have some
problems like you never concentrate.
So you you know there's no right answer.
So I would say you know pick pick one or
two uh
yeah one or two at most three you know
like
you know just remember just remember you
want to
get in depth
into a language not you know like most
you know you want to get in in depth
into a language until you decided okay I
had enough of this I know enough now
then I you know you focus on other
languages.
Okay so either way okay just remember
you don't you don't what you want what
what you do not want to be is like
today's millennial gen and today's
zoomers like you know we have quite a
few on discord.
Jokeru Jokeru and and and several
others.
You know they they don't really act like
I mean they are not they don't learn and
the four chan four chan type of people
they they actually don't learn anything.
Like they talk about oh Haskell Haskell
has hacker news say something about
Haskell Haskell is this way or C++ is
that way or because syntax therefore
something some language this way they
just babble they don't they don't
actually
sit down and learn a language that you
know, that's the extreme worst case
worst case. That's today's people. Most
people are like that. You know, when you
see people talking about programming
language, they they don't know.
Okay, so just remember
you want to master a language. Doesn't
matter what language. You want to master
at least one language. Master meaning
you code it for
1 hour a day at least or several hours a
day for at least 1 or 2 years. That's
what you want to do. Doesn't matter
which what what is your approach, you
know, looking at multiple languages at
the time or whatever. You want to master
one or two languages in your life.
If programming is what you want to do,
okay? Master it. Spend one several hours
a day for for at least 1 or 2 years.
Go you know, I you know, Go lang,
JavaScript, Python.
Uh even Java, okay? So
be sure to do that. Just be sure to do
that.
And in fact today you could if you are a
programmer, you probably should master
more than one, okay? Because today the
information is so wide, you know,
Wikipedia, they you know, and tutorials
is tons of them, okay? Tons of them. And
I I have, you know, I recommend I
recommend my tutorials. For example,
this uh this article
carries uh this this talk show video.
Characteristics of Haskell, Perl, Ruby,
Python, Java, Closure, JavaScript, Lisp,
and Wolfram language.
So this is 1 hour talk show. In fact,
programming language is what is my main
uh topic in my talk show. So uh watch my
videos, okay? Now, okay, so now let me
mention if you guys like my stuff, pay
me, okay? Buy me a drink. Donate,
PayPal, Patreon.
Buy me a drink. Amazon.
Okay, and so
so yeah, so you can watch my videos and
learn a language and you know, I have
lots of tutorials, you know,
Emacs Lisp is good. My tutorial,
you know, Wolfram language my tutorial
is good. JavaScript, this is the most uh
in-depth tutorial on JavaScript. I spent
2 years full-time on it just for writing
this tutorial.
Uh PowerShell, my PowerShell
introduction is pretty good.
Go lang, my intro production is pretty
good and I I love Go lang, okay? Go
lang, I love Go lang, PowerShell.
Emacs Lisp
and then I also have Python tutorial
which uh
which is a good introduction, I would
say.
Complete good introduction.
And I have some others. Not They are not
uh
they are not too
comparatively, they are not as good as
my others I mentioned. But anyway, so
Yeah, so
try to master
uh one or two languages in depth, okay?
Don't be like a millennial or zoomer
blah babbling like babbling about
languages all day like you know, you
know, this or that or shallow. No brain
no brain. Shallow.
And the most the most proficient method
to program to learn a language
depending on depends on the person, but
one of the best way to learn a language
is right actually write a program, a
sizeable program. Create a project,
write a sizeable program. And important,
this project must be useful to other
people. Not not just some toy program
for yourself. Like hello world, like a
little exercise. Yeah, those are good,
too.
But
eventually, you want to
create a project that is useful to
all the other people. Like writing an
app, you know, a phone app or whatever.
Okay, that's what you want to do. Useful
to other people, not just yourself.
And uh when you do that, you will find
lots of tiny problems, like headache.
That's real programming is about. Not
just about academic, you know, in
theory. Oh, you know, then you
understand that actually you don't. You
don't until until you actually write a
practical real-world application.
Complete, like finish it. Because when
you do that, you'll probably run into
problems, like tedious, you know, then
you go, "Oh, I I know how to do it, but
I'm not going to do it."
That's that's your failure. That's the
beginning of your failure. You want to
push through. So, that's what the master
of programming language means. Because
when you actually write a real-world
application, you'll discover lots of
tiny details that
you will not find in any tutorial, any
book. You know, you suppose you read all
the books in the world about Python. You
will not find the answer there. You
know,
most of most of the problem, you will
not find the answer. Not even the Stack
Overflow.
That's real-world programming.
Okay, that's uh that's it.
Uh
I think that's it for today. We talked
about, yeah, 50 minutes.
We talked about about programming
languages. Uh
Do I Do I use Logseq Logseq? No, I don't
use that. Uh
So, what are the other questions? How
would you convince people to try out
Wolfram Alpha?
How do I, you know, I already did
several videos, you can watch. Did I
convince you?
Uh
Yeah. I mean well, yeah, especially
today in professional environment if
you, you know,
become a programmer, a paid programmer,
you almost always needs to know more
than one more than one for sure
programming languages.
Uh
That's how things are.
Uh and also, but today, you know, like I
said, some some much information. You
have Wikipedia, you have tons of
tutorials. You have Wikipedias tutorial
Wikipedia actually has a tutorial.
You know, you you go to the bottom and
you'll see some of them.
Then you have official, you know, tons
of tutorials. Then YouTube, you know,
lots of people talking about uh
programming language tutorials. Uh
some of, you know, a lot of them are not
good, of course. How do you know?
Uh
you have to know only by
you know,
you can only tell by after you have a
lot of experience. So, there's no magic
criterion that tells you which YouTube
tutorial about programming language is
good or not. You just have to, you know,
you just have to spend a lot of time
uh with them.
Okay. So,
so that's
Anything else? Yeah, okay, let let's
let's let's I I want to talk about
JavaScript a little bit then uh then
about some issues about programming
culture, okay?
So, JavaScript operators, uh I don't
care about So, here, okay, so JavaScript
class JavaScript guide for functional
programmers. So, this is my guide for
you JavaScript programmers.
Uh
especially if you you interested in
functional programming. Now, JavaScript
is a language
it's one of the worst programming
language because it has lots of
problems, lots of bug, lots of design
bug,
and lots of actual bug from the source
code 30 years ago.
For example, null is also an object, you
know,
you know, let let me show you, okay? So,
for example, in JavaScript, you have
null.
Uh where is it? Undefined? Uh okay,
that's not even global.
Uh
global object. So, null is not a global
object. Null is actually a building
primitive, okay? So, you go to So, it's
very confusing, you see?
Undefined is actually a global object,
okay? But null is a building primitive.
So, JavaScript is full of full of these
complexities, you know, that because
it's a
it's a language that's created and
designed and implemented
in 10 days altogether, in 10 days,
literally. That's the history of
JavaScript in 1995.
So, uh let me show you about null, okay?
So, let me show you about null. So,
value types, okay? So, value So, So,
here are the data types, you know, the
actually the
the value type, not data type, you know,
the
Here's another topic of a confusion
confusion to most programmers and the
most tutorials and textbooks do not talk
about it.
When when you talk about, you know, for
example, programming languages, you have
data types, but actually
what they have is value types, okay? Not
data types, value types, okay?
Because data types means so many things.
For example, list, array,
list, array, vector, slice in Go lang,
you know, they have different
terminologies. But basically, these are
what you call data type, hash table, or
dictionary, you know, data type. But but
in a programming language, you actually
have value. You have
you have a type
to designate
each value in the programming language.
For example, number, okay, number and
string. These two
value type are the most popular. Almost
in every language, you have a value type
called a number. You have a value type
called string, okay? And and usually
also you have value type called boolean,
okay? These These value types are the
most popular in just about any language.
C, C++, Java,
uh
Python, Ruby,
PHP.
So, remember,
I'm telling you, so in the programming
language, you have values, and values
often they have types.
These
you you should remember to characterize
them to you know, these are value types.
These are types
associated with values, okay?
Now, in
but typically in programming language or
documentation, they call it data type,
okay? For example, Python.
Okay, so if for example, if if you
search Python data types, you know, they
call it data types, right? Then then you
can look at you see, here's the official
Python documentation.
You see, this W3 tutorial is, you know,
one of the most popular, but the most
inaccurate
tutorial.
Since like 15 years ago, you know, like
today's generation changed, you know, 50
in year 2000s, everyone, every
programmer despised this website,
W3Schools, because it's the most
silly It's basically it's it's it's a
it's a tutorial for non-programmers who
never programmed anything. They don't
know they don't, you know, but they
maybe they need to do schoolwork. They
are not, you know, good student. They
just
party all the time. But there's a
homework, they need to do homework. They
go to, you know, W3Schools. So it's the
worst website. But today,
you know, after 15 years, they also
improved a lot. But, you know, today the
generation also change changed. People
don't really care about what is actually
correct, because most of the, you know,
that's like I said, millennial Gen
Zoomers. They don't care.
You know, they just, oh, how do you do
this? Go to Stack Overflow. Google
search Stack Overflow, W3Tutorials. Oh,
just type just type this thing, then it
will work. And then
that's why they're That's why
So the consequence of that is the
program is full of bugs, you know, it's
incorrect. You know, it works 90% of the
time, but but tomorrow
it doesn't work anymore.
So that's why I I say you have to you
should master language, okay?
Not just not just, oh, how do you do
this? Just type this thing. You know, go
to Stack Overflow. Oh, just type this
thing, it works. You have to understand
why does it work? What what does type
mean? What did What is a data type? So
right now I'm trying to explain one
example, which is commonly misunderstood
in programming community,
and even in official documentation. For
example, here's a
documentation of Python official
documentation. Let's read, okay?
You see, it says data types.
The modules described in this chapter
provides a variety of specialized data
type, okay. That is correct. Uh that is
correct. They are not talking about the
programming language value types.
Anyway,
well, should I should I actually press
on to find the problematic example in
Python documentation?
Uh
so you have to go to language reference.
Yeah, so lexical analysis data model. So
operators, okay.
Data model, okay.
Objects, values, and types, okay.
Python documentation is the worst.
You know, on this chapter
they talk about objects and values and
type, and the guy, whoever wrote this,
I don't I think this is um
I forgot. I You know, this one is either
written by Guido van Rossum or by
another guy, you know, very early, like
20 20 years ago.
But anyway, this page is bab- babbles on
about
inconsequential details.
Implementation details, standard type
hierarchy. Hierarchy, my ass.
Okay, anyway. Okay, forget about what I
said. Any anyway, so
so let's get back to my point about
value types in programming languages,
okay? So let's get back to the null. So
null is actually a value type in
JavaScript, and it's actually a mistake,
okay?
I'll I'll I'll show you, okay?
So anyway, null is a data is a value
type in Python. I mean, in JavaScript,
okay? And you click on null to get the
into the detail of the null.
So, when you type
You see, let me let me try this again.
So, null
is one one of the value type in
JavaScript, okay? And the only value of
that type is just the null literal.
Okay, you see what I'm saying? Let me
let me try this again. For example, a
number
a number is one of the value type in
JavaScript.
That is when you have an expression, it
is a value and uh it belongs to a type,
one of the type. So, when you have a
number
you know, one of the type is number.
Now,
however, the possible values for number,
they are basically infinite. For
example, 1 2 3 5 6 34 1.35, the all
those are numbers. So, they all belong
to the number type. So, this number
type, this number value has many actual
different values. In fact, they also
include the special literal NaN
n a n, which stand for stand for not a
number. They also include the literal
infinity, which stand for like
infinity, okay? Usually, that's a
you know, any anyway, so that's number
type, okay? Now, another type, one of
the type
is called null.
And in this type in JavaScript, there's
only one single value.
And that value is null itself, you know,
the literal. You just type null, n u l.
So,
that is the Java specification, okay?
Java specification.
So, null is one of the value type in
JavaScript and the only possible value
of that type is a literal n u l l, okay?
So, null is a type null.
Okay?
But, however, when you
in JavaScript, when you when you say
this, okay, type of null, okay?
So, let me show you JavaScript, okay?
So, let's let's let's uh turn on
Let's go to the JavaScript console, so
we can type this in a browser. Let's say
3 + 4.
Okay? 3 + 4 is 7. Now, type
type of 3.
You know, it tells you it's a number.
Type of, let's say
Let's say um
that.
Uh type of, you see, it's a object. You
see, it tells you object. Now, if you
say type of uh let's say type of
infinity.
Okay?
It's a number. Why? Because, you know,
remember we talked about, you know,
number, okay? So,
So, now, uh we we we we
type of 3,
type of infinity,
type of uh array. This is array, it's
object. You know, that's another school
of a JavaScript. This is a This is a
syntax for array.
But, when you say type of array, it
returns object.
Why? Because, in JavaScript, there's
actually no array type.
Arrays, you know, actually just a
object. You know, that's why JavaScript
is a very complex, badly designed
language. But, now here's a null, okay?
Uh
type of, let's say null.
Okay?
You see, type of null returns object.
What's going on? You know, because
remember
JavaScript in depth.
Uh
value types.
Remember
null belongs to the type null.
But however, type null returns object.
Why is that?
Well, that's because
back in 2000, back in 1995
there is a bug in the code. You know,
this guy, Alex Russell, he's a he's one
of the top JavaScript
expert in the world, okay? I would
consider him In fact, I would consider
him probably my my personal, okay? I
also
know JavaScript a lot, but I
I consider him a expert. I would trust
what he say. Anyway, he he's got a blog
that tells you, you know, this guy,
okay? He he wrote JavaScript uh he also
wrote several JavaScript book.
So, this guy
you know, so the history of type of
null, you know, so you can actually see
the source code. Here is a original
JavaScript implementation in C.
Basically, it's a error, okay? It's a
programmer error. You know, that's
that's why so
So, since then type, you know, in
JavaScript null when you say type of
null
you get object. You know, it just stuck.
You know, that's So, that's one of the
problem of JavaScript.
Okay, that's it for today. Uh we going
to you know, I was talking about
JavaScript
uh programming language guide, uh but
style on but anyway, so
Yeah, well, no so we talked for 1 hour
already. So let's let's let's eat for
today. Thank you guys for watching.
If you like my tutorials, pay me, okay?
Buy me a drink.
Okay, bye.
I'm going to shut down
in 1 minute.
Any comments and questions?
Thank you, Big the Loop.
Hope all is well or is well
over there. Oh, no, no, you are over
here, yeah.
Okay, Big the Loop. I haven't talked to
you for a long time.
Uh
Okay, so yeah, we shut down in 1 minute.
Um so let me let me just gather what we
talked about today.
Gather all the links here.
So Python reference, we don't care.
Python data types, we don't care.
Close that.
Okay, JavaScript, why is null type of
null null? Okay, close that.
Copy that.
Our bottle, are you the our bottle? I
know.
Totem, I missed the stream.
Type of, okay, so JavaScript type of
JavaScript is the language
filled with fuck-ups
to the brim.
So I would not recommend JavaScript, but
however, JavaScript is one of the most
popular, the top three most popular
language on earth.
Okay, undefined.
Uh we talked about a lot about
JavaScript. Yeah, so I was going to talk
about this JavaScript style guide.
But you can read about it.
Um
That's my JavaScript style guide for
functional programmers.
Close that.
Close that. We're going to not going to
talk about that about that. JavaScript
operators. Close that.
Math symbols.
Close it.
APL.
Close it. APL symbols.
Close it.
Unicode stars.
Apple Pro keyboard. This is a keyboard
where you see those
symbols.
And here's another one.
Close it.
And here's a Japanese keyboard and
layout.
And here is another article on Jap-
Japanese input method.
And here's article on Chinese keyboard.
You know, in China, actually, keyboard
like this, you'll never see a keyboard
like this. It doesn't exist. You know,
because
keyboard in China, they just use
they just use, you know, basically, the
keyboard in China, they are identical to
to keyboard in USA. Like 100% same
keyboard.
They don't have, you know, these Chinese
characters printed on them. You know,
but this
photo is from a screenshot of the
of the James Bond movie. So,
you know, they went out of their way to
to create this keyboard, so it looks
more dramatic.
It's like James Bond, you know, all the
spy,
you know, all the soldiers military, you
know, and you don't understand Chinese
in a Chinese keyboard. But, in China,
the keyboard is just identical as
American keyboard. Except in Taiwan, you
do have these, you know, this one is
from Taiwan.
You see, you know, yeah, popular in in
Taiwan, you have keyboard like that.
This one is from Apple,
you know.
But, you still have the English alphabet
on them
almost always.
Because you also need to type English,
you know.
Okay.
Uh
design of math symbol input systems.
Okay, you need to put on that.
Paste. Make a link.
Make a link. Show in browser. Fantastic.
Close that. Close that.
Oh, yeah.
And that.
This is uh
old graph key, compose key, dead key.
Oh, and this is keyboard symbols.
Close.
Oh, the And this is Canadian
multilingual layout.
Close.
And this is
Habit keyboard.
Close.
And this is
Google keyboard. Close.
Google and the Google Docs.
Close.
And Globe AT keyboard, which I already
have a link.
Close.
Oh, this cat This page I needed to show.
Uh let's not do it.
I was going to talk about this page.
What characters are Unicode later? Okay,
next next time.
Bye, guys.