hello welcome to another episode of s
talk show today we are going to unbox
the new
keyboard the new keyboard here this is
uh let's see if I can see
it ex talk show this is
kinesis form keyboard okay this is
totally new KES is from
keyboard so we're going to unbox un box
this
thing uh yeah so let's
begin if you have comments and questions
post it
okay uh we're going to unbo this let's
see how we going to do this uh I have to
adjust my camera okay so let me adjust
my
camera let's just do it here okay so
there it is I haven't opened I mean I
opened it but I haven't um opened this
thing yet let's
see okay this is very
thin okay so there it
is let's see let's take this
out oh there it
is
fantastic very
very slim very thin you see it's pretty
heavy okay I would say it's over 1
kilograms uh okay so there it is
fantastic
USBC it's a USBC and this is also
Bluetooth this is called Kinesis form
keyboard okay let's see what else is in
the
box so you take the
out okay that's just so there is a key
puller very simple very nice and this is
a bunch of key
caps key
caps
uh can I see it okay a bunch of key cabs
for Mac in touch for mac and here is the
cable so you got USBC on one side
and the the usba A on the other
side okay so this very
nice so far superb superb welcome to
another sound talk
show and that's just a cardboard okay so
design and engineered in United United
States States of
America
kesis form keyboard
fantastic
actually so I'm going to use it
today uh my my desk is crammed but
mostly it's because
my well because my camera and uh okay so
it's pretty heavy
Wow Let's see if I canjust this down
over there it's that's glove 0 keyboard
This is Ultimate hacking
keyboard okay I'm going to use this
keyboard the kesis form
keyboard for three months in my live
stream so I can tell you guys the
all what I think about it everything
but I can tell you right away I like it
I recommend it because I have so many
keyboards now I can tell it's good or
it's
bad uh this is very very quality build
the whole thing is metal okay you know
these days they have this kind of metal
that that it doesn't feel like metal
it's like they what they call metal
carbonate or something thing
anyway I cannot emphasize enough it's
very
heavy and uh it just superb um let's see
can you see
it can you see it you know it's so you
got screws actually so you got screws
one of the nice nice things about
keyboard that you can take them
out so there is I suppose that's a reset
hole and uh this is a track track pad
okay this feels very good you know one
of the issue about trackpad is that when
you r on it it doesn't feel good then
about five or 10 years ago Apple came
out with a new track trackpad that fixed
it so this is very comfortable this one
too very
comfortable so I can tell you know it's
a good it's a great keyboard I can
recommend it now there are some
issues I would say it's negative you see
this function keys that's Escape fub1 F2
F 3 four five F6 they are in one row
there's no Gap in between that's not
good okay it would be better if you have
a gap between the escape and F1 and also
also another Gap let's say I would say
between F4 and F5 because that's
traditional that way you can you can
find the keys by just touch like usually
I don't look at the keyboard you know
you can just move up you know now you
know you see there's a gap here right
below the F Keys the function keys some
of the keyboard you know just do it
yourself or some of the you know
fashionable Chinese Che they don't have
that Gap so that's no good that
essentially makes the function keys or
number number row Keys
unusable okay so the physical quality of
it is
superb
superb okay uh again and and this is
pretty wide the reason it's wide so is
that you know it's kind of ergonomic but
it doesn't allow Ting you know like like
like you know ting
so let's
see okay the physical quality is
excellent and you have the the insert
key delete
key uh that is a function key oh you
have a FN key here you see there's no
Gap in between these keys so that's a
negative f s 8 9 10 11 12 so all these
six six keys are together but worse
there's no Gap in between
there you see no Gap no no Gap is not so
good and
the okay so the key switches they come
by is called this is a low profile okay
low profile key mechanical
switch it is uh let me tell you what
what key switch it uses
gateron
k33 low profile 2.0 switch so it's a
gator wrun low profile switch KS
33 and
2.0 and uh
it's it's
linear red so it come with linear red uh
no other choice I mean it come with it
okay so this according to the
specification is 50 g activation
force uh that normally is a bit heavy
for me because I have repetitive injury
so anyway so we'll see how it goes so
actually let's
start um I can plug it in or I can start
to use
Bluetooth so
is there any
documentation that tells
me how do I connect to
Bluetooth no but there's a website you
just go to the website okay let's go to
the
website hello people
Leon Oh I thought that was going to be
the kesis 360 I already reviewed kesis
360 quite a few times and uh I used it
for three month in every one of my live
stream video the kesis
360 uh could you check the OBS audio it
seems slower than ear streams okay yeah
sorry about that so I turned it on a bit
should be better
now so they don't have a you know they
don't have a pamphlet telling you about
the uh how do you connect to
Bluetooth so let's switch
to my website so you can see my typical
cassa talk show this is kesis form
keyboard and you can just go to their
website okay
now so right now my my question is how
do
I
uh turn on Okay so there is there are
two switches at the back so you can see
there are two switches in the
back you see so but they don't say what
is which so let's just blindly try
it okay is there any light oh no there
is light there a white back light oh I
didn't know fantastic okay let me go
back
here so there's white back backlight
there are two switches here but it
doesn't say what set but on the left one
you turn it on apparently that's turning
on the
keyboard now even
the oh oh the blue oh
okay so I suppose the the switch on the
right is turning on the Bluetooth let's
see does it work yet no so let's try it
again turn it
off turn it on then the Bluetooth light
flashing okay it's very highly quality
build you can see this
light so let's go to Windows and
uh let's go to the
Bluetooth right now I have Bluetooth
turned
off okay now it's connect to glove 0 now
actually so
let's um
go to devices
Bluetooth add
Bluetooth blue
truth oh there it is it says right there
form Okay click on that
connecting okay
done there it is connected now let's try
to type on this thing
okay so I need
to yeah I need to
move I need to
move my this drawing tablet away move
these papers
away then put it up
here so it's stable okay oh and right
now this is
uh this
is quy
okay I think this is qu okay so I'm
typing vak I am typing
on touch typing okay let's magnify
control but this is quy so we need to
type quy
i m t y p
i i n g
on
this this uh touch
typing
Form K E ke y b o r d so I haven't I
haven't touched typed uh quy for a long
time so let's switch to quy I mean let's
switch to VOR keyboard layout okay so
that would be Windows space so let's see
Windows is this
key window space vac
fantastic
now
now now now this is VX
layout layout using
Windows fantastic now I can type
fast
and oh there it is the
mouse okay wait the mouse got a
delay okay now I have to figure out why
the mouse is got a delay
I mean the
trackpad how come you stop using
360 well the reason is that I have so
many keywords so I can only pick one so
for me the you know
the you know I'm using the glove 0 okay
so I have a page you know so yeah so if
you have a question about keyboard let
me tell you so I have you know I done so
many live streams you know uh some of of
you may not see each and every one of
them because each one is like 1 hour
long and so on but everything is on my
website so if you just go to uh kesis
360 for example you go all the way down
so there's video you know so you can
watch my live stream videos introduction
or unboxing or the whole I mean the
entire entire detail in one hour one
hour per
video then you go all the way
down you know I have like over 10 pages
about kesis keywords so you go all the
way down you know the software and all
that you go all the way down then you
have you can see
conclusion uh then you can see there's
also difference between kesis Advantage
2 versus
360 and you go all the way down so you
can read about conclusion uh you go all
the way down you can see there is a so
all these are kesis keyboard
Advantage keyboard layouts everything
you want to know about it and what are
alternative layout what are the
advantage disadvantage you know I myself
have like two or three versions so I I
offer you three versions of different
layouts for the kesis advantage
keyboard and then then there's a section
on how how to program the keys this is
for kesis kesis Advantage Tool uh anyway
you go back here then you know then you
have a gallery by the way there's a new
Gallery okay so I mean there's a new
photo so this is somebody else's photo
beautiful it's got this exotic cat uh I
I I I don't know what species that uh of
that cat but that's some kind of pure
bread anyway beautiful photo okay and
here's another guy who bought the
keyboard uh due to my recommendation so
this is his battle station and uh you
know and uh my website so this is uh e
value so anyway I want to say what I
want to say is that there's a by the way
there's a new photo is it here uh
there's a new kind
of anyway so I want to say so a lot
people are wondering which one is better
so you can go all the way down here
there
is
uh there's a
page there it is glove 80 versus Kinesis
you know this is one of the most
frequently Asked question which one is
better so this page tells you all about
it okay you know I don't want to say
which one is better because they are you
know in my opinion both are great and
but there are some differences you know
for example
portability price do you touch type well
you for this you do for sure because if
you if you do not touch type then
neither of this gra8 or is 360 is good
for you you have to be a touch typer in
order to appreciate them okay but this
one for example you don't have to be a
touch typer so this this this one is
good for
you so the you know there's all sort of
details key switches you know do they
have Bluetooth or are they wired uh do
they how much do they wait do you want
them to be portable things like that so
full detail there
okay okay so so there is a delay with
the trackpad I need to figure out let's
let's go back to uh any
comments uh maybe that's it for today
okay so let me just let me just type
type there
myself yeah I need to figure out how do
you fix the delay so here is the
battery uh
oh caps lock is
light you know most high quality build
for sure the
most the best engineering so yeah this
is truly a piece of
art so I will have to so you can adjust
the back light
level
so okay so you have to hold down the
function
key okay then you you can also turn the
back light off
see
great uh what else
oh so battery okay so this shows
battery but I'm not sure what it
means it just shows Capital
lock okay let me type some more
some more and more and what do you think
about this
keyboard
and whether it is fantastic okay I think
that's it to this keyboard everything is
pretty simple there's no special things
you know you turn on the uh Bluetooth or
you can plug it in
USBC and and uh this button is Bluetooth
this button is just on
off okay I think that's it for this
video any any other questions
oh what's going on with the wait
what wow you see in
my wait what is that I don't
know good night guys bye