Good morning, good evening, good night
everyone. Welcome to another episode of
Excel talk show. We are going to cover
JavaScript.
I'm going to do a tutorial on JavaScript
module system. The fantastic and complex
uh crap. Well, not exactly crap, but
very complex. Not very good. So,
JavaScript module system introduced
10 years ago, 2015.
Took me a long time to get it to work
because there's complications because
they actually banned local modules. You
know, it requires HTTPS to run. So,
we're going to talk about JavaScript,
which is technical for you guy hackers,
coders, okay? And okay, JavaScript
module system. That's today's topic. And
and right now let me show you my
keyboard. This is glove 80. Now if you
are watching this offline, play at 1.5
speed minimum. If you are watching this
here live, say hi. Love to see your
comments. Okay. So this keyboard glove
80 I mean sorry this is ultimate hacking
keyboard 80 UHK 80. I did a video review
in depth one hour alone 50 minutes about
10 10 days ago two weeks ago glove 80.
Okay, fantastic. So go check it out on
YouTube
and Nia Track Ball and the Logitech M
G50. Okay, th those are good. Nia Track
Ball. I love the track ball. Okay, track
ball is fantastic. Okay. And and notice
the my Hoover. Let me switch back. Okay.
My keyboards and Hoover to activate
Windows. So I don't ever have to click.
You know, one of the thing with mouse is
that when you buy a mouse after a year
or two, it broke because every time you
right click or you left click, you drag
it, it you know, the button got
problems. Especially with Logitech
mouse. It's a commonly reported problem.
So they force you to buy a new mouse
almost every year. So that's very bad
Logitech mouse. But now with the Hoover
to activate Windows system, you I almost
never do click. Can you see? Can you see
my screen? Yeah. You see I almost never
click. So it's fantastic. Okay.
Okay. So let's let's talk about
JavaScript. So uh uh is there anyone?
Nobody is here. Okay. The poverty of the
Kasar talk show. It's nasty. You know
every time you know I want to do live
stream but usually my videos everyone is
about 300 views typically. 300 what am I
what am I doing it for?
You know. So you want to make it popular
of course but how do you how to make it
popular? I know because I've been
studying the social issues, the
marketing, the brainwashing, the
influencing, the um persuasion, all
these are related topics, psychological
involve psychology. How do you persuade
your friend? How do you for example
salesman Steve Jobs the greatest
salesman? How do you you know how how
can you talk to people? So they or
negotiation when you you know for
example job interview you want to
negotiate how much you get paid you know
negotiation marketing and al uh
and trends and fat and fashion they are
all related about the psychology fat and
fashion. what makes some something
popular at for some period of time or
what makes some posts go viral you know
so and also marketing that's a billion
dollar research you know marketing so
all these are related it's about
how it's it's about influence and also
brainwashing is a heavy you know
government um research they want to know
how to control people's mind control
also part of Okay. All these are related
related topics. So I had a f fascination
fascination. I've been kind of studying
these related topics for you know like
like on you know casually my adult life.
So for example YouTube how do you make
yourself popular? You know I only have
300 viewers. That's a problem, you know,
because you spend a lot of time. For
example, it took me
uh two weeks actually to go through the
the JavaScript module to finally have a
complete understanding.
Okay. But then I do a YouTube video 300
views. So that's not good, right? So
that's a problem. How do you solve this
problem? That's a like for a nerd. It's
a problem, logical problem we need to
solve. Of course, I know how to solve
it. But it's it became the condition of
society today. It's very nasty, you
know. So, let me explain. Hello uh
Spencer Pope. Hello Damski.
Happy to Tuesday. What what is toad
Tuesday? Cheers. This is red wine and
juice.
So, so we we will start to talk about
JavaScript module system. Okay. So but
so we were saying about how do you make
yourself popular on YouTube of course
there are many ways I know first of all
don't do live stream okay you don't
because live stream YouTube do not does
not promote it instead you want to do a
recorded video you wanted to make it
short like 10 minutes 15 minutes you
know something like that and you want to
make it like focused for example
create a you know do a video about a
lecture on JavaScript module in fact not
lecture because lecture is associated
with old professors you know people
don't want that today's people young
people zoomers they want something in
five minutes they want to understand you
know they don't want like formality okay
so you want to do a short video 10
minutes 15 minutes focus on the problem
and you want to focus on the beginners
Because the millions of people they they
they are all beginners. They don't know
a thing. They may not even know how to
program. But they heard JavaScript can
make you money. So that's most people.
That's why you go to go to YouTube,
there's like tons of JavaScript, you
know, for beginners, you know. So
anyway, short, focused, well packaged,
you know, like put it on a in a lunchbox
like the American way. capitalism, you
know, come with a nice packaging, you
know, like when you go to a shopping,
you know, you go to your local
supermarket, you know, let's say you
want to buy a shampoo or soap or
whatever, you know, the packaging is all
nice, you know, or beautiful. You don't
know what's inside though, but but you
know, you can just judge by the
packaging, right? So you want to make
your video short and so nice lunch back
lunchbox it and you want to um you know
don't don't babble about random things
like what I'm doing now like today's
video is about JavaScript module but
first of all let me tell you about what
I thought about brainwashing you know
you don't want to you don't want to do
that okay so you you you want you want
to do your things for the mass as the
masses, the idiotic, brainless masses,
okay? Like even grandpa, grandma, you
don't know who is watching. And then
package it. Don't swear, you know, don't
like, oh, randomly starting to say, "Oh,
this is the most idiotic design I've
ever seen." Don't do that. And uh you
know so nice and and also don't remember
create a great thumbnail like learn
JavaScript module system in five
minutes.
This this is the best JavaScript tuto
tutorial you've ever seen.
I was shocked by this tutorial how
concise and perfect it is you know big
red title then people will be attracted
to it you know so and or you put you
know your face oh my god
you know like I I learned this
JavaScript trick in five minutes.
So all these are tactic tactics to make
your YouTube popular
but
it's pretty sad because
that is why when you go to YouTube today
the all the contents millions and
millions of YouTube videos you watch
them and after a while you find it's
empty it's empty of humanity there's
nothing in them. There's a [ __ ]
nothing in them. These [ __ ] million
beautiful JavaScript tutorials will show
you, you know, keyboard or mouse
reviews, you know, beautiful beautiful
face talking men or women, you know,
they all happy this devoid of humanity.
You you know, you started to feel that.
So that is the state of the
what how shall we say it corrupt
American capitalism system you know
everything is focused on money. Why do
people do that? You know, nice tutorials
and short and concise and happy face
because money. Because YouTube offer
money. This is how you become popular.
Follow it this way. You'll be popular.
You know, you'll be influencer. You
know, like the Mr. Beast [ __ ] face.
One of the gravest Mr. Beast, you know.
He's the most popular YouTuber.
>> [sighs]
>> So is that interesting? So shall we
start to do
JavaScript tutorial? I guess I've
already driven off those whoever who
wanted actually saw oh I wanted to learn
JavaScript module system
but they saw the first five minutes.
What the [ __ ] is this? they already went
away. Okay. So now for the rest of you,
are you guys still here? Let's uh do the
JavaScript module system. Okay. Yeah,
that's enough introduction. Okay. And
I'm using Emacs, of course. Can you see
this is the most powerful editor in the
universe.
Plus,
especially when you are using it with
fly key system. This is my package. It's
free and you can use it for yourself.
Let's remove the backup. You see how
Emacs, how powerful is ESMAX? I, for
example, let me show you. Um, what
I press a key. Wait. Okay. I press a key
and all the backup files are
highlighted. Then I just press a key. Do
you want to delete them? Yes. So all
backup files are deleted. And let me
demonstrate another thing about Emacs.
For example, this is a directory. By the
way, if you guys don't know, this is
actually directory you. Let's show in
Windows
Explorer.
Let's see. Control magnify. Control
magnify. Control magnify. So they become
icons. Can you see?
So this is actually files, but you can
view it in Emacs. So now I uh select by
regular expression eel dollar sign do it
enter so they selected I can press B2 by
compile but actually I don't want to
compile this these are working uh files
for my code so press B to bite compile
by compile 34 files yes or no yes
You see the computer is doing work heavy
work
and what is this uh miscommand
miscellaneous commands assignment to
free variable is shell history ring uh
ring why is that
shell history ring that shouldn't um
okay describe variable what
copy P now describe variable E is shall
his wait what why am I not copying
oh there's some delay for some reason
okay is history ring let's look at that
so is history ring is defined in this
its value is new em history okay so
anyway let's go back to let's start to
do the emac Okay, I mean let's start to
do the JavaScript. Let's not um
anyway the point is I'm using Emacs.
Okay. Uh for you coders, you probably
have heard of it.
But um for you guys who have not used
Kasafly keys, let me just quickly
introduce you keys. So it's a key
binding system for Emacs. It's free on
GitHub. You can see GitHub. Download on
GitHub. Download it and you'll be more
efficient than VI or Vim or Neoim. Okay,
the most efficient then there's tens of
videos I did in past six years. Okay,
that's a introduction
keys. That's what I'm using like right
now. Okay.
And Okay. Close. Close. Okay. So, copy
the URL back. Close. Close. Close. And
what is this Kasar talk show? Uh yeah
today's talk show. So paste the link fly
linkify make a list show in browser
there. Okay so okay let's talk about
JavaScript module. So JavaScript
JavaScript begin let me do this just um
off the top of my head. Okay say
something. Hi hi guys. Introduce
yourself.
Let's double check. Sometimes I talk to
myself like in my video or voice is off.
Okay, JavaScript. Let me just talk about
it. JavaScript began life in 1995.
Okay, long story short. So anyway, for
the first 20 years of JavaScript, there
is no module system. What does a module
mean? like a library, you know, like
when you program, if you know any
programming language, Python, Golan, C,
Javas, uh C, uh whatever language,
programming language, um you have the
library concept, you know, you can put
part of a code in a file as a library
because, you know, those are commonly
used. So whenever you want to use them
you load them you know like require
something something or sometimes called
uh load something something library
okay but JavaScript is pretty lousy
language for the first 20 years there's
no library so so you so people get very
frustrated okay now long it's long story
short in 2015 JavaScript finally created
a module system called module which is a
library system. What is JavaScript
module? JavaScript module are JavaScript
files designed to be used as a library.
So when you need it, you load it you
know uh and any JavaScript file that
imports module is also a library. Okay,
this is slightly complicated and
different from other programming
languages because if if you have a
JavaScript code and you call you load
another library then this JavaScript
code itself is considered a module.
Okay, so this is a bit complication.
So anyway in 2025
ECMAS script 2025 ECMAS script is the
standard standardized JavaScript name.
Okay, very complicated [ __ ] ECMAS
script. So anyway in 201 uh 15 they
introduced the module system into
JavaScript. Okay, so it's it's good.
Okay,
now um okay so uh we're gonna go through
this. So are you guys following me? Is
this so good? Hello again. Hello. Okay,
so JavaScript module.
So let me uh think about how we going to
approach this. Am I like doing a
tutorial? Are you guys have you guys
been coding JavaScript before?
Um let let me see uh how do I approach
this? Okay, let's go slowly. Okay, if
you are watching this offline, play at
1.5 speed.
Okay, JavaScript module. So in 2015 they
introduced it. Okay, let me just start
to talk about it.
So how is the JavaScript? You know, I
assume you have some experience with
JavaScript like half a year because
otherwise you wouldn't know what I'm
talking about. Okay. Uh so if you don't
have like have a year experience coding
JavaScript
this video is not for you but I have you
search for oxali JavaScript in depth.
Okay let's see if I just search for
JavaScript in depth let's see if you it
will show my tutorial
JavaScript inepth that's the one you
want kalei.info info. Okay, go there.
Okay, that is my tutorial. So, if you
never coded JavaScript, you can begin
there. It's for beginners, but it's also
for those professionals. Let's say you
work at Google coding JavaScript
for a couple of years. You'll still
learn something from this JavaScript in
depth because JavaScript is a very
complicated language. Very complicated.
There's lots of things you don't know.
Okay, you thought you know, but you are
mistaken.
So anyway, JavaScript. So for you
beginners, check it out. Okay. Uh
interest to hear your perspective on it.
Fantastic. Okay. JavaScript is my main
language at work. Oh my god. Now, now
I'm um now I'm nervous because I I
[laughter]
I'm talking to a professional JavaScript
code coder. Anyway, let let me let me
just go ahead go through it. Okay. So,
so JavaScript in Yeah. So, so you can
check out my tutorial and actually you
can you know it's um
how many pages? Uh 500 pages by now
actually uh 1,00 okay this is there's
1,000 files but half of it is
CSS and HTML. Okay. CSS anyway few
hundred pages and if you like it if you
guys like it you can oh [ __ ] uh
skipped you know the
Firefox been like updating frequently
very annoying so if you guys like it you
can actually buy my entire tutorial in
uh as a zip file I'll send it to you 35
bucks send me Amazon gift card or uh
PayPal okay then I'll email use a zip
file. Okay, just zip file of the
basically the whole JavaScript and and
go go up and the entire tutorial for
HTML and CSS and JavaScript in depth and
JavaScript object reference and DOM
which is actually what you do when you
actually code JavaScript every day. this
uh most of the time you are dealing with
dome which is much more complicated than
JavaScript the language but there's SVG
so if you buy it you get the whole thing
okay so anyway let let's go back let's
go back to the um let's go back to the
uh uh module okay so 2015 they
introduced it by now it's 10 years ago
okay um so okay So,
you know, I'm going to skip part of it
because, you know, less important. I'm
just going to skip. Okay. So, how do you
load them? So, let me show you a
JavaScript module. Okay. So, uh uh so go
to
go to my module page. Uh yeah. So, there
it is. My tutorial JavaScript module. Go
back and go to the top. You can see
actually there's a there's my module. So
you see this is how you load a
JavaScript module in HTML as you know
when you you know you need when you want
to load a JavaScript file in HTML you
use this script tag but if it's a module
you need to add this type equals to
module okay that's what you need to do
and there's another thing is that your
source value for the source attribute
must begin with a dot slash hash. Okay,
it cannot be just uh just that that
won't work. You'll get error. You'll get
error. Let's see. Uh let me show you.
Okay, this is that value is called
module specifier. Okay. So, if you don't
include the dot slash in front,
you'll get an error that says
type error. Module specifier does not
start with slash or dot slash or dot dot
slash, you know. So, that's a
complication. So, you need a dot slash.
Okay. So, let me show you a module. So,
this is what your module looks like.
Okay. So you know it's just just
JavaScript code except you got this
import statement or export statement. So
for example this import from that file
open that file then this file got export
statement. So [snorts] any JavaScript
file if it got import statement or it
got export statement then they are
considered module. Okay that's the
difference. You know what what's the
difference between a module and just a
JavaScript code? Well, if the file
contains export statement or import
statement, that's a module. Okay? If it
is a module, then when you load it in
HTML, you must
include a type equals module. Okay?
Otherwise, it won't work. It won't load.
Okay? So that's the first thing to how
to load JavaScript module in HTML file.
Now once you load one of the file let's
say you know for example this JavaScript
module main once you load it and and in
this main file you can actually load
other modules for example here import
these two function names from this
module name you know so in this this
module name this JS module add is not
loaded from HTML you know in HTML you
basic you you can just load the main
file. Okay. Then then the main can load
imports code import other modules. Okay.
That's basically how you load it.
Now so there's another complication. Now
remember we said that this this module
file name must start with a dot slash.
Okay. There's another complication.
If you are running things locally like
right now I am you know like file SL
it's local files you know this is my
local directory
modules does not work over local files
so in order to actually have this line
work your file must be served over HTTPS
I mean I'm sorry HTTP server okay
Another
complication very bad it's idiotic. This
is one of the flaw of JavaScript module
since 10 years ago 2015. You must load
it over um
uh over HTTP server for example let me
show you. So for examp I got a module
here let's say console log and let's say
console let's alert alert
a e t alert something okay alert is old
something bad
okay now save it close it run this in
browser did I get alert no why because
this line actually doesn't work never
load because I'm not running uh HTTP
server. So I need to uh run it in HTTP
server. So let's do it. Okay. So how do
you do it? So if you don't know you um
you can install Python. I mean if you
work in JavaScript professionally,
you know, you know what to do. But if
you are a beginner, what you do is that
you go to uh you install Python and you
can uh start the HTTP server like that.
Okay, but first of all, you need to go
to your directory. Okay, so let's see.
Let me just do it. Okay,
magnify.
Okay. So this is this is the PowerShell.
So we need to cd
uh cd web
info. Okay. Go there. Then paste. Okay.
So paste python-m http server. That will
start the http server from this
directory kasali.info. Okay. Let's do
it. Fantastic. It's running. Now, um
now to view this page, you need um
uh you need to use this URL. Okay. So,
let's let me show you. Okay. So, copy
the file path. So, localhost 8,000 and
uh
okay, that is the
so open it. Wait, can I open it? Open
it. Error response. Uh.
Oh, okay. So, I know. Wait. Why is that?
Uh because you because that's you don't
need that. Okay. Run it. Open it. So,
you see now I'm viewing this source
code, this HTML source code in the
browser via HTTP.
uh and you can see the log you know so
it's it's saying that someone is
visiting this page someone visiting a
page that's not found
excuse me so anyway so remember for
beginners you just download Python and
start it like that first of all go to
your directory you want to be the web l
web root okay so Now
this is um this is running. Okay. So now
can you do the alert? Wait, why is the
alert isn't isn't isn't showing.
Did did they uh deprecate alert? Let's
refresh.
Yeah, it's not showing. So let's control
shift I to see the console log
and uh go to console
and uh let's refresh.
Uh
so I loaded the module
and uh is there a uh error?
So it's wait warnings loading failed for
the module resource.
Okay.
Loading failed for script resource. Why
is it failed? I don't know. So
control.
Wait, can I magnify this?
Wait, what is this?
So, why is this module failed?
Um,
do you guys know?
Okay. Uh, so loading failed for the
module source http localhost 8,000
jsjs module main.js.
Okay. And loading failed for the script
with source.
I don't understand why are they failing.
Okay. Actually I don't know.
Yeah, this is very bad.
So um what we going to do? So even that
highlight script is not working. This is
the highlight of the current link page
you are in.
So it says loading failed. I don't I
don't understand it.
What the [ __ ]
So
So even highlighting is not working. Why
is that?
So file name extension. So normally this
will be pink because this is a current
page.
And if you uh click on comment you see
this should be highlighted but
actually am I actually seeing uh this
update
so let's
value type yes it's the log says you are
loading that page
But um
yeah, JavaScript value type. Now control
shift I
loading failed. So
okay, this is a frustration. This is
unexpected.
I do not know why.
Is it in a directory? Oh, I know. That's
why. Thank you. Thank you guys
because Okay. So, Ctrl C to cancel the
server. Is it Ctrl C? Yeah. Ctrl C to
exit the server. Okay. Yeah. So, thank
you Spencer
because I started in the wrong
directory. Okay. So, because that
JavaScript file is actually in a
directory in front of it. Um,
but okay. So let's check. So so you see
this highlight link direct open it go to
the directory this highlight link go to
the top it's info wait
so why is it not um
it's ininfo
right is it So, um anyway, let's let's
let's um
let's cd to a directory before because
that's how I usually do it. Uh so now
let's start a server. Okay, now let's
try it again. Let's close that. Uh now
refresh
arrow. Okay, now you need the ininfo.
Okay. So, close that. Close that. Uh,
yeah. Now you need.info.
So, open that. Fantastic. Now, click on
file name extension. That still doesn't
work.
God.
Okay. This is bad. Now, what to do? He
can we can either move on
or we can
stick to solve this problem.
uh very frustrating because
so the page is loading but
but it's not so control alt I control
alt I
wait control uh control shift I
so why is the loading failed now how do
you magnify this this page
Uh let's see control first.
Okay, that's the biggest you can go.
Loading failed for the script with
source.
So why is that loading failed?
This is how to run JavaScript.
So if you look at the source code, you
can see
uh so this is CSS inspector
and you can see the file is at the
bottom right there. Okay. So can we
magnify this? Oh god.
Control plus I I don't think I can. This
is the biggest it will go
stupid. Okay. So anyway, so you can you
can see it's loading that JavaScript
file but it's not
allowing it.
Is it because
Oh god. When I run a server,
it's all not working.
Does it say any error? Warning info.
So do you guys know
[ __ ] close that? So you see is this file
right? So showing browser again
now it's
oh wait this is working. So let's click
that.
It is working because you can see it's
pink. The current page is pink
because
because of this highlight link
JavaScript. So it is indeed working. So
go back to module now. Why does the Oh,
now now this part is working too. Wait.
Oh well, because this is a local file.
[ __ ]
Now this is the HTTP file. So HTTP file,
you click on file name extension. It's
not working. You go to module and go
down. You see it's not pink. And so
that's not working. And uh I really
do not know why. control shift I
um
uh very annoying. Okay. So, what we
going to do so we can keep talking of
mod? Let Okay. So, what
Okay. Let me let me quickly try to
finish what I want to say about module.
This this this video is kind of [ __ ]
with this problem. But so maybe we'll go
back to that problem. Okay. So, let me
just then quickly talk about module. So,
you can load it. You can load the module
in HTML. You need you know use a script
tag and type module type equals to
module and then the source the value for
the source is called module specifier.
Okay.
The module specifier you uh there's some
there's some uh so there are some
examples. This is HTML example and uh
HTML example. HTML example. all these.
So they can be a full URL starting with
HTTP or they can be uh slash which is a
relative link or they can start with
slash slash which is what's called um I
think it's called protocol
protocol link anyway that defaults
whatever http or https from the root of
the web okay or It can be uh it can be a
relative path with slash in it. Okay. Or
so these are examples of loading a
module from HTML.
But also you can load that load them in
JavaScript code itself like that. Okay.
Same syntax. So all these source they
are called module specifier. Okay.
So that's one thing. So we yeah uh the
slash slash is called http I mean
protocol relative URL. It will just
slash slash is the shortcut for either
http slash or https slash slash
depending on whatever current page is
using you know which either one. So you
can have slash slash. Okay. So anyway,
so the these are the syntax for the
module specifiers. That's what it means.
This the value for the source. Okay. Uh
then there's more
um there's a new feature in 2020 which
is called import map. So usually a
module
URI or file path may be long. For
example, here's a module specifier your
URL, a very long one. So, and usually in
real life, you may have different
versions. So, it's complicated long
line. So, you can make it simpler by
creating a what's called import map like
this. So, so import map. So, it's
getting complicated. This is the
complexity of JavaScript. So you you say
you in HTML you say you know script type
equal equals to import map this is new
in 2020 then code okay and what's this
code import mat that's a JSON file and
the JSON file must have this format you
know the import
is a key imports okay a string then the
value must be a another object which is
key value pairs. So the keys are kind of
the name you want for the module and the
value is the actual URL or
relative directory you know
you know or a path or a path actually
this part is wrong. This part should
should begin with a dot slash remember.
So let me fix that. So close that. Open
that. Uh okay. So you cannot open that.
Jesus. Uh because of this local. You see
this is this is one of the very annoying
thing about module because they require
you to run things over uh HTTP server.
So you can no longer run
things locally. So what that means? Let
me talk about this. This is a major
problem with the JavaSc with the module.
Okay, because before that you know the
HTML with CSS and JavaScript they serve
as a documentation system extremely
powerful you know like I can zip I can
zip my entire for example Python
directory I can mail it to you and you
can you know it's like a EUB you know
like a digital book so you have the
power of JavaScript and CSS and HTML ML
you can format it you can do things
interactively
you know like number highlighted comment
comment is the current page string is
the current page you know Python string
so
uh local documentation system
but now with a JavaScript module
requiring requiring HTTP server that's
all [ __ ] up
because if you want to use module then
It cannot run locally like if I sent you
my zip file of the entire JavaScript
tutorial or whatever mathematics
you can't just unzip it and view it
because then you need to like otherwise
because the JavaScript won't work you
know this highlighting doesn't work you
need to like start HTTP server most
people have no idea what the [ __ ] that
is noncoders right So
this module system [ __ ] up the local
file documentation. The concept of
JavaScript, HTML, CSS as a local
documentation or ebook format, they
[ __ ] it up.
So that's very bad.
you know, I've been working with this,
you know, the HTML, JavaScript for like
30 years, but starting a, you know, the
the requirement to start a web web
server is is pretty nasty because then
you have to deal with this. Um, so
that's a okay that so in summary that's
one of my major criticism
of the of the JavaScript module system
introduced in 2015. Okay, because
because it you know you you can't
develop it locally unless you start a
HTTP server very bad. So that's a one of
my criticism. Okay, so let's go back to
module.
Wait, so is this Yeah. So this is still
running HTTPS. You can see
I don't think there's a way to magnify
this UR URL field is there. I don't
think so.
Uh dev tool. So uh is it in directory?
So does it show a response in network
tab of dev tools? Okay, let's see.
So
uh control shift I to start the
console log. Then click on um click on
network. Okay. And reload this page.
Okay. So does it show response in
network? So let's reload this page. F5
to reload. Now let's look at
Oh, okay. Great tip. Thank you.
Oh, blocked by you. Block origin.
[ __ ] stupid. [laughter]
Blocked. Blocked by you. Block or
engine. I forgot about this. Yeah,
that's right.
Oh, you block our engine. [ __ ]
idiotic. Okay, lock it. Okay. In fact,
turn it off.
Stupid. Okay, so let's try again now.
refresh. Fantastic.
Finally. Thank Thank you.
It pays to be a professional uh Jav
JavaScript dev. So, you are right.
Why are you sending JavaScript file to
not non-coders, you know, for people?
It's it's not JavaScript like I have a
JavaScript tutorial, but I have some
other things like Alice in Wonderland
for example.
Uh
Alice in Wonderland.
Okay, that's that's literature, you
know. Uh I don't want that. Okay. So,
where do I go? That is in in Wonderland
in Through the Looking Glass. So, that's
literature. And you this Arabian Knights
uh 1,000 years old literature, you know.
So, so I can, you know, people might so
like EUB EUB is for anything, not just
code. So, if you send this to other
people, they can run it because now the
JavaScript requires, you know, HTTP
server, right?
The reason these clowns I'll just be
assump you know I'll be I'll just be
pres presumptuous about these people the
JavaScript standard this you know lead
we lead the technology group JavaScript
standard why do they want why do they
have this feature by the way this is
great uh debugging thank you Spencer you
know why why do they decided that
this module must run over HTTPS because
they think it's a security thing because
this way it's more secure. They don't
want random files to load on your
computer, local files to run arbitrary
JavaScript. That's what they think.
However, JavaScript has always been that
way. you know like if I don't use module
I can load any file I want you know like
um like right now for example
this JavaScript file open it you know
showing browser showing browser it's
loading it's loading this this
highlighting you know you don't see it
it's loading it anyway so why is that
when you started with a module you you
you prevent it you don't you know
it's city you know So the the way they
think might be okay moving forward
people will start to use module instead
of just you know this local you know
JavaScript file loading a local
JavaScript file people will just start
to use module then
then it prevents you know random local
HTML file from loading JavaScript that's
idiotic
you know but you you still have this you
know this They didn't ban this. This is
not going away, you know. They didn't
ban like from now on you you cannot load
JavaScript locally. They didn't ban it.
So what's the point of you know for the
module system to have like the [ __ ]
idiots, you know? They have like they
have the word cross origin
error [ __ ]
you know? They that's what they call it,
you know, was origin, you know. They're
[ __ ] idiots. is you know like for if
you don't know JavaScript or if you
haven't been in the software software
industry for like for long like me 30
years 30 years in software industry I've
seen you know many languages in
different communities
you might think oh this is you know just
technical this is very you know advanced
cross origin resource sharing cos you
know is a browser security mechanism
that controls how a web application runs
in on one or engine defined by domain
protocol port. You know you think this
is you know absolutely
you know so so advanced designed by
these great knowledgeable people
but
my opinion is like totally [ __ ]
[ __ ] [ __ ] them. Not totally wrong.
There's some reasons for certain certain
things and naming of the jarens but but
overall they they are like they are like
they are just like in in you know they
they are the they are the result of
corporate corporate interest you know
different browsers they they have
interest you know they uh or JavaScript
standards organization they have their
interest you know the programmers or who
whoever wrote JavaScript or you know
there's different like programmer
communities they have their interest.
So, so usually that's so usually the
things we work on every day, the
standards, the protocols, the jargon,
the cross origin fact is a result of
this combination of forces. They are
almost never
well designed. Okay? And they are almost
never like necessary out of like you
know be because mathematics
you see the complexity of mathematics is
necessary because they came from nature.
You can never change 1 + one or real
numbers or what's a complex number or
what's a fraction. Why can't you have
like a you know a rational number? Why
can't you know why why is rational
number different from real number? Why
have you why do you have so many
complexities? Why do you have infinity?
Why do you have one divided by zero? You
know why can't you make it go away? It's
not going away because that's that's the
nature we are in. You have to ask God.
Okay. But this cross origin, you know,
this [ __ ] that's humanmade man-made
complexity just like the C and Unix
[ __ ] make them all the time. Okay,
that's my rant. [laughter]
You know
that's that's basically the case. Okay,
the cross origin.
So for now for example let me give you
practical reasons
you know practical reasons you know I
work on my website you know I you know I
do tutorials I dive into programming
language right so I want you know so now
there's JavaScript module yeah I want to
use it I want to turn my
JavaScript into modules because I want
modular code you know for example let's
see Unix fire instantaneous. You see all
characters of Unicode characters
containing
whose name contains the word fire or I
can type water w a t
and it shows dynamic dynamically as I
type or I can type l a t i n. all unic
code characters containing the whose
name contains the word Latin. So they
are Latin characters. You can you can
see hundreds of them. So this is a
JavaScript application. Let's look at
the source code. Okay. Open open open.
So showing browser. This is source code.
Back to Emacs. Search for.js.
So there it is. Uh search data popup
three files. So this is a search. This
is the code JavaScript. So I'm loading
them traditionally without being a
module. But now there's a module. It
would be nice. I want to make my code
module,
right? Module rise. But I cannot because
if I do that, actually I can do that,
you know. Actually, actually I can start
to do that, you know.
But if I do that, I can no longer
do let's say let's try something else.
Smile. Okay. Let's say heart. H E A R T.
Okay. All characters whose name contains
the word heart.
If I turn them into modules, this no
longer works. It [ __ ] up my system. I
have to go to Python, go go install
Python, start HTTP server, whatever [ __ ]
that is. They have then then do this
because they say this this standard
organization this priest says oh it's a
cross origin security [ __ ]
yeah this [ __ ] I'll just call them
[ __ ] out of my 30 years of of
coding experience they yeah they are
[ __ ]
it's things are this way not because
it's necessarily so But it is because
it's a product of different interests of
different corporations. It's a kind of a
mess and there's some require there's
some security requirement but overall
it's just like overly bloated
complexity. [clears throat]
Okay, that's what I have to say.
Uh
so uh why are you saying JavaScript? So
why does this page need JavaScript load?
It's a static content. Well, you missed
you missed what I was saying. Okay. So,
for example, let me explain. So, for
example, this module file or any file uh
like any file actually, let me show you
any file. So, let me go to a local file.
Okay. Uh let's see this. Okay. This is
loaded locally. Any file. So I want to
highlight you know the the current you
know this here is the topic box. So
these are all pages related to the
JavaScript module system. So you can go
to the next one examples. You can go to
the next one. What are exports? What are
the different syntax? How do you what is
export? So there are two exports. One is
called default export and one is called
named export. They're very different.
Okay. So anyway, here's the topic box at
the bottom. Every page about module
subsections. Okay. So you see they are
pink. You see the current one is
highlighted pink. How is that done? I
explained before.
I explained before. That's because this
highlight link JavaScript code. Okay.
You open it. You go to the top you can
see um windows.loation location path
name highlight link of current page uh
document query select all panel and
topic and dotd
that's relative links so or with the
anchor link so you basically select all
the topic box or the panel box
and you look at them if the current file
if the current link is the same as the
current URL then you hide highlighted
pink. Okay, JavaScript
that's why you need it, you know, even
for whatever page, you know, about not
about programming,
you know, like just like what do you
need JavaScript in EUB for EUB, you
know, the Amazon digital book or or
whatever digital book different format
you you need them
to even take notes or whatever. Okay.
So, JavaScript that's general purpose,
you know, you need you need a
programming language in a documentation
system. That's why you have them.
Okay. So, so uh it's static content. So,
you don't need Okay. So, I think I
explained that branches holder.
Okay. I think that's it for that today.
uh you know so we haven't explained
um
we I I ranted a bunch but we haven't g
actually go over
as a tutorial of the JavaScript import
export you know module system but I
think that's okay that's it for today I
think I think
can be done in CSS? No, it can. Yes, it
can. It can. Let me show you. Okay. So,
go to CSS.
So, what you are talking about is
using CSS to highlight the current page.
Okay. And you can see that in uh tabs,
okay, tab A, tab B, tab C. So, let's go
to tab C. So, let's go to tab A. Uh
actually, they changed, you know. So,
tab A, tab B, tab C. Okay. Now, this is
implemented without JavaScript. No
JavaScript. Okay. How do you do that? I
explain here. Okay. This is written in
2006,
20 years ago.
You don't need need it. However, you
don't know a [ __ ] Okay? because you can
do that but then it becomes it becomes
very complex because for because I have
hundreds of topic boxes. Okay. Anyway
just in general you you you can you
cannot do whatever JavaScript can do by
just CSS. Okay. In some in some
situations like the tab or the current
page. Yeah, you can do it with CSS, but
then you need to manually you need to
what you so I need to for every topic
box of my 10,000
manually crafted HTML pages. For every
topic box, for example, let's go to um
is there a topic box there? Okay, so
let's let's copy that and search topic
box. Let's see how many I have in
sarali.info. Okay, you get a 100 of them
basically. So you wait, you know, you
take 10 seconds to show. So for every
topic box then you need to craft you
create this CSS CSS. That's no good
because then you can't work dynamically.
Every time you create a new page, you
have to consider, oh, what what topic,
you know, what other pages is going to
be used in conjunction with the current
page I'm writing or in the future, I'm
going to have another page that's
related to what I'm writing today. So, I
need to think about that. That's not
going to work. Okay. So, and in general,
CSS cannot replace JavaScript. Okay?
Right now, it's still searching.
Okay? I think that's it for today.
Does that Does that make sense? Use the
attribute equals to syntax.
No, I don't think you I don't think you
make much sense. Are you like are you
are you like a CSX
expert?
So, let's see how long have I been
talking.
Uh, so I this video has been going on
for an hour. Okay. So, now it's time to
shut up. So, let's consider what you are
saying. So, right now it's still
searching my website. Yeah, it takes a
while because loading the disks
but
but you are saying uh you just Google
it. Yeah, you don't know. Okay. So, but
you know like because in I mean like I
said in general you cannot use CSS to
replace whatever JavaScript do. Okay,
it's too many. So here is all my topic
boxes. You can see there are thousands.
Okay, they are like 47,000 lines, you
know, divided by 10, then you got
4,700
about then you divide it by the
by the duplicate you know
you remove you make them unique you have
like I would say few hundred 100 or 200
300 topic boxes Okay.
Yeah. Okay. So, I think that's it. Uh
let's see what else.
Okay. So, I've done today. So, it's kind
of a rant on the um so close that show
in browser module. So, we didn't really
go through everything.
So, but we criticize this, you know, the
module system is not very good. Not
good. Okay.
It's got lots, it's quite got quite a
few issues. One of them, the most
fundamental is the requirement of HTTP
server to use it. Okay, in my opinion,
that's one of the worst.
The second um worst problem is that when
you export so let's go to the topic box
when you uh export.
So let me let me show you guys what's
the syntax you know just just quickly.
So this part you can see this is an
example. So you have a module file a
library then you can say you know so
this is a file you have two functions f1
f_sub_2 then you can export them by this
export statement okay so that's a module
then in your main javascript file you
can say import okay from this javas you
know this module file name relative file
dot slash okay then you can call the
function f1 But you can use it now for
the main file. You can load it again.
Remember you you load with a script tag
with the type equals to module
and the file path must dot slash. Okay,
this is a simple example of module. This
is this is
of importing named
named export. Okay. Now when you export
there's a different another thing
there's called another thing called
default export. Okay. So in that case
you do it this way. So this is a module
file. You say export default then a
value. It's not a name but a value like
a object. Then the import you say import
something G from that. Okay. So anyway,
so the the thing here is that when you
have a module, when you write a module,
you need to export, right? So to export
there are two different kind of export.
One is called default export, one is
called named export.
Okay. So this is a major problem. This
is a major idiocy in the JavaScript
language design.
They dis you know they have these two
kinds which is not necessary at all
because so what does a default export
do? Basically they just export one
single value. This value can be a object
can be a array can be whatever can be a
function
or it can be a name like a name of a
function name of a like a variable name
like variable name. So basically the
essence of this export is it export one
single thing could be a name variable
name or a value. Okay. Then you have
named export which is more kind of
logical and normal in all the other
programming languages. You know you just
export whatever functions you want or
variable you know in your package. You
say I want to export this name, export
that name, this this, you know, a bunch
of names. But in JavaScript, they have
these two, you know, they have now they
combine these two. I mean, they created
this idiocy like, oh, you have the
default export, then you also you have
name export. The default export is not
necessary at all. Why? Because if you
just want to export a value, just give a
name and use a name export. export this
variable name. Simple, logical.
Why do you need a special like there's a
special export called default export?
What an idiocy.
And if you are thinking, you know, we
need to def we need some kind of default
export so people don't have to think
about names. That's very easy to solve.
just have a named export with one of the
variable name special this variable
value will be just called default. So
everything is the is you know you do the
same single syntax with named export
then you have a default name that means
the default export very simple too but
JavaScript they created two like
completely different export one is
called default one is named and you when
you import there's more complexity more
than that when you import you can import
just the default export. You can also
import one named export or more than one
named export or all of the named export.
And you can also import the default
export and you know one or more of the
named export. So it's like [ __ ]
complexity
idiots the JavaScript committee you know
that whoever created them you know. So,
so that's what I'm talking about is um
uh let's see where do I talk about um
export expand okay so here there are two
kind of export default and named okay
now when people import they you can
import one or more than one or all of
named export or you can import just the
default export or you
import both of the above. Very complex
idiocy.
But that's not all. Then you know then
when you export may it be default export
or named export you have 1,00 syntax for
it
[laughter]
do the doing the same thing you know for
example you can have export all the name
here. This is the most simple you know
just export at least you know name one
name two this is the best export syntax
for named export this is the best
okay but then you can also put the
export at each location of the variable
or function declaration
so now you have two syntax to do exactly
the same thing the JavaScript committee
idiots the industrial idiots They did
this. Okay
then. Okay. So these are we are talking
about the syntax for named export. Okay.
There are many
then you you can also export from
symbols that you import imported from
another module. Okay. So that's that.
Well this is useful. Okay.
Then you have the different thing that
you know the default export thing which
is entirely entirely different from the
named export. So then they have a set of
their own syntaxes. Okay. So this is the
whole thing is just extremely idiotic in
my opinion. Okay. So that's the import
export. Okay. So uh so I kind of so I
explained my criticism.
Uh then okay. So then you have static
import. Let's see.
Uhic
AI can write my code now. No, it cannot.
Okay. Skeletor delight. You know AI
helps a lot but they so far they cannot
write they can write toy code you know
10 lines of a code solving a puzzle but
if you ask it to to write anything
that's more than few hundred lines it's
always never works it doesn't work
you know mo I would say more than 200
lines it just don't work okay you have
to know what you're doing AI so anyway
so there's It's also
so we need to explain static import but
then in 2020 they created dynamic import
okay I'm not going to explain because
it's going to then in 2020
wait this is they they created import
map okay complex and more complex um
then there's history of it common JS and
uh AMDJS Okay, common DS. That's kind of
history. Okay, I think that's it for
today.
Cheers. Hope you have uh you guys have a
good life.
I hate default export, you know. So, why
do they create that? Do you have any
idea? I kind of [clears throat]
I asked you know I well I think
the reason they create default export is
because back then you know JavaScript
does not have a module system for for
like since 1990
since 1995.
So 95 and 2005 and 2000. So for 20 years
JavaScript does not have any module
system. So people started to you know
coders when you create large product
large project you need libraries right.
So they started to create their own
convention. So there's common JS
beginning in 2009 very popular. So okay
even before common JS you know you walk
around. So before this common JS you
walk around the no module system by
by including let's say you have a file
you know let's say this file is all
related to let's say about creating
random numbers or cryptoraphy
or whatever
let's say for drawing for drawing okay
so you have a library it's all about
drawing circles or squares in SVG Okay,
but JavaScript doesn't have a module
system. So what you can do? So what you
do is that you put all the code inside
the object inside the object. I mean so
yeah
um
wait you you put the all the code inside
a function because back then before 2015
JavaScript doesn't even have like you
can't have local variables in a block.
the only local variable you can have
must be inside a function. So you have a
whole bunch of files you know functions
you put all of them inside a function
and this function serves as as kind of a
block of code serve serve as a your
module scope. Okay. So this function. So
then when you want to load the library,
you basically load this function just
one single function name. Um
um yeah kind of like that. Okay. So so
that's why you have this default
module system because basically what
people were doing before this system is
that they are just loading a single uh
object
something like that. Okay. So that
that's so that's why for kind of tr like
traditional like for habit reasons they
added um they created this default
export that is my guess okay actually I
should ask Gro about
why maybe Gro you know AI can tell me
okay that's it
I'm not sure off hand I I guess is
legacy thing. Okay, thank you guys for
watching. Now, if you guys like my
tutorial again, you can buy
my entire JavaScript tutorial. In fact,
I should um so we didn't go in detail
about this um history and stuff, but
that's it for today. Okay, so JavaScript
in depth if you want the entire thing,
you know how well which plugin have you
used to do this thing?
None.
So my entire JavaScript is without any
framework. You don't need any framework
you know or just pure
building in browser you know all just
works you know. So you can if you like
it go there s JavaScript in depth and
send me money and I'll send you uh the
zip file. I can read it online. Why
should I pay? Because you are beautiful.
Thank you. Thank you guys. Bye.