Hello, good morning. Welcome to another
talk show. Casar talk show. We're going
to code wam language uh part two
writing a customized function to convert
wam language graphics to SVG. So this is
part two and uh two days ago we did part
one. So we we we made some progress and
let's continue. Now if you are watching
this offline play at 1.5 speed minimum
and if you are here say hi. Okay so
let's start wam language. Play at 1.5
speed. Okay not emac. We already got
emac. Let's launch wuam language
mathematica.
Okay. new notebook
and uh new notebook three shift enter
shift enter to evaluate it and start the
kernel. Okay, magnify. So there we are
and uh here is my Twitter wam language
Firefox Emacs and this is a new instance
of Emacs. So, let's make it um what?
Uh wait. So, kept uh shift lock is on. I
have sticky keys. Undo. Undo. Okay.
Sticky keys. Turn uh turn it off. Okay.
So, now
let's begin coding. Okay. So this is
EMAC I'm using and I'm using uh wait
I'm using SFly keys the most efficient
key binding system for for Emacs and
here's a source code SFly keys and go to
the top you can get the package on
GitHub this is the homepage keys there's
a video intro like tens of them in the
past five Yes. Uh, Safy Keys and the
left the pink window shows all my
command calls and keystrokes as I type
them.
Okay. So, uh, the font is really large.
Okay, that's good. So, close that uh,
close that. Close that. Show today's
talk show and the wam language. If you
don't know already, search for wufam
language for programmers on my website
kasari.info.
HTTP no s uh then you have a complete
tutorial from the ground up for
programmers. So if you have one year of
coding experience in Python, JavaScript,
[snorts] this is good for you. Uh no
nonsense, okay, deep dive into the most
advanced programming language and you
can download it for free here. Make sure
follow follow this link, okay?
Wufam.com/developer.
then you can download it for free. It's
like 4 gigabyte or something because the
wam language is a magnitude more
powerful than all existing languages
like Python, Haskell, Lisp or whatever.
Okay. So, so uh so let's start to code.
So let's start. Let me show you. Okay.
And in EMAC I can code wam language in
Emacs. That is because I'm using Wufam
mode. You can download it on GitHub too.
Okay.
Thanks for warm research for
sponsorship.
Okay. So let's begin coding. So let's so
uh practical SVG tutorial. You know in
order to do this you need to know SVG of
course. So there's also practical SVG
tutorial. And here is code to write a
clock. So you can see uh the code is
just 50 lines 60 lines JavaScript to
create SVG. So you need to know this in
order to do what we do today. Okay, if
you are here say hi. Okay, if you are
not here play 1.5 speed. Now let's just
begin code. Okay, so start a wolf
language. So let me uh start to show you
graphics.
Okay, so this is graphics. Anything of
2D graphics begin with this function
graphics and uh last time we did a
circle. So let me just demo wam language
um
graphics. Okay, circle you need two
arguments. Uh the first one is the
center. The second one is radius. Let's
say one. Okay.
Okay. Copy that and paste in wam
language and you get a circle. Okay.
Then uh wait shift enter. Okay. Then you
want to ctr L to copy the previous uh
input. Then let's add option axis
uh axis
true.
Okay. Now this will draw axis. So you
have a clear idea where the circle is.
Okay. So that's one example. So let's uh
copy that. Let's copy the code here.
Now you cannot show graphics in Emacs.
That's why we are running this uh in wam
notebook. Okay. So copy that. So so
let's do that. So that's one example.
This is the most simple example. This is
example with a option uh axis true. Then
let's do another example. Um let's see
line. Okay. So now we're going to
include a line in here. So first of all
the first argument is going to be a list
a list of graphics primitives. So this
part is going to be a line.
So this is this is the function for
line. So for a line you need two points.
So,
so let's say zero zero to
[clears throat] to one. Okay. So,
so that is what we going to plot. Okay.
So, go down here. Uh, so this is the
fundamentals of wam language graphics
programming. There you go. Fantastic and
beautiful. So, now okay. So now this
that's a basics of wufam uh language
graphics. So uh let me so there so this
circle and line those are called
graphics primitives. You see circle
and line that's graphics primitives. So
you you got quite a few. You got
rectangle you got um others. So let let
me show you. Okay. So go to wra language
for programmers. There is a section for
graphics. Um expression atom and list
number boolean list expression item
variables conditional
uh loop iteration define a function
pattern matching. This is the most
advanced critical pattern matching in
wolf language and data structure.
Uh hi hello sunrise midnight midnight
live.
Hello
kitastro
uh data structure association that's a
dictionarial hasht advanced symbol
graphics there so graphics you know you
don't have to so graphics you know you
don't have to like learn the complicated
programming you can simply plot by
default there are hundreds like plotting
functions such as you know for example
we can copy that let me just show you So
you know so then you can rotate it and
so on you you know like parametric plot
parametric plot 3D or surface plot 3D
plot 3D vector graphics uh vector fields
you know uh pie charts and so on. Okay,
so that's simple you know just plotting
it just like the way you use a graphing
calculator but
obviously you can program it and that is
the like where the power come from. So
let me uh so we want to go to yeah we
want to go to so here is a list of like
how to how to use the default graphics
then what we want is graphics
programming. So this is like what we are
doing today. So graphics programming. So
first of all you have a what's called
graphics primitives.
Those are like basic shapes. So for
example if we go to the SVG tutorial
SVG basic shapes you have line which is
represented by this you know this this
XML element line. Uh and here's a full
example in HTML.
If if you copy that create a file show
in browser it will draw a line like
that. So you got line rectangle uh you
can have corner you know round corner
for rectangle you can have circle ellis
polygon
and polyline and text and path.
So these are like the
graphics primitives. Now in SVG how do
they call it? Uh do they call it
graphics primitives? Uh maybe not. They
just basic shapes. I'm not sure if they
have a particular name. But anyway, in
different programming graphics
languages, you have you have different
name. So in uam languages, it's these
are called uh graphics primitives. Okay.
So circle line. But what I want to show
you is uh a lot more. So you got points.
So you got point, line, polygon, text,
disk, circle, rectangle and much more.
Okay. So you can look at the reference.
So these are 2D. So so far I listed
them. Those are 2D two-dimensional
graphics primitives, but they are also
three-dimensional ones.
So but for SVG, SVG is just for
two-dimensional. So we're going to focus
on the two-dimensional ones. Simple. So
you can click on this link that's the
Wuam language reference website. So you
can see the entire list of graphics
primitives
which include
you know like the the ones we talked
about disk. Then you also have field
curve like getting complex. Okay, you
got conic hole region circumsphere.
Circumspere is like you can specify
three points. Then you uh three points.
Yeah, you'll draw a circle passing those
three points. You also have circle of
course you have blline curve. You have a
s triangle that is angle angle side
triangle. You give two angles and give
one side length. It draws a triangle.
You have like and you also have ASA
triangle. Okay. You have arrow if you
want to draw arrow. So you know you have
half line which is like a ray like
normally you have a line segment or
several of them forming a path. But you
can have a ray like starting at one
point
into one direction but it it's infinite
line half line. Okay. So, it's like a
ray. Then you also got half plane. Wait,
these are 2D or 3D. Half plane. Wow.
Wow. You got a half plane. So, basically
that's like a uh where uh let me show
you where half plane uh
infinite infinite. So, you got infinite
line which is a line pass you know
uh infinitely long on both sides. So
let's see. So we got a half plane. Half
plane is like a linear equation, linear
inequality. So it feels like it feels
the plane half of them by a line like
like one side of it. You got half half
plane. You got insert. Actually I'm not
sure what is insert. I think that's
embedding a
image
insert.
Uh I'm not sure what is insert represent
an object
insert in a graphics. Yeah, I think
that's embedding a graphics into a into
a graphics.
So close that. So you got you know you
got like 50 or or over 100 um about 50
graphics primitives. Okay. Rectangle
raster which is a uh bit map image
polygon point parallelogram
locator locator is uh dynamic more
complicated [snorts] and text and
triangle. Okay. So that's a those are
graphics primitives
and we are using two of them circle and
line. So now so that's an example. Okay.
So that's a basic fundamental example of
graphics programming two dimensional
graphics in wam language. Okay. Now
we going to so last time we going to you
know we we we need to write a graphics
to SVG. So let's go to two days ago. We
did um
yeah actually we did so many sessions.
So let's go to let's visit um
we did wait 709
769 789. So yeah, so we did three
three of them before because this can
get very complex. So so far actually
today is like the fifth
but previously we don't actually have
code. We we went into something else.
So anyway, so let's let's get back to
Okay, so let's get back to code. Okay,
so let's show today's talk show. Today's
talk show. Then let's go to two days
ago, episode 717,
and let's grab the code because we we
already wrote the code.
Okay, let's copy that and uh show
today's talk show. Okay, so let's
let's um
start a new language code, paste it
there, and pop it out. So here's the
code. So this is the inline
documentation for this function graphics
to SVG string. Okay. So what we're going
to do today is we're going to add so
this function yesterday I mean two days
ago we called it that already converts a
circle okay to SVG. So we want to so
today we going to add converting to
line.
We going to modify
modify the function. So it does lines
two
does. Okay. So
two days ago
we wrote this function that convert
circle to SVG. Today we're going to
enhance the function so it does line
two. Okay. And
and
we going to
make it actually export to a file. So
right now it just output a string but
you actually need to save to a file. So
this this is going to show you how do
you you know take a string and uh save
it as a file. So so first of all let's
do the line. Okay. So yes. So let me
tell you guys the how the code works. So
the code is um
so you got this uh this is called rule
delayed. It's a delayed set. Okay. Colon
equal. So on the left hand side is a
pattern. So that means whenever wam
language see this syntax this this code
and it it is a pattern this underscore
low line means match anything. So
whenever you see something something
graphics to SVG then inside it is a
graphics then inside it is anything and
we that are match okay and whatever the
match expression is going to be named
Gia that's a reference okay so what we
do once you match is you have this um
basically that is string join okay so
let me let me just show you
uh let's say a string
string sum and another string bing we
want to join them. So what you can write
is that that's a shortcut that would be
that would be exactly equivalent to
this. Okay let me run it string join
same thing.
Am I doing good? Am I doing good? Okay,
so you see something. Now let's run this
code,
it's going to return exactly the same
thing. Okay, that's just the syntactical
shortcut. Okay, so so now this function
when you when this pattern match what it
does, you see this this uh bracket
bracket that's a shortcut, right? So
it's just one huge string join. You
begin by this string SVG header you know
SVG width and height and at the bottom
you can also see the closing tag. Okay.
Now so you join then you got this part.
So basic so the middle part is again a
string join uh here then
that that at sign it just means square
bracket another shortcut. Okay. So in
the middle you string join this
expression.
Okay. So this means replace all
replace all of the graphics.
Okay. This this GIA thing which is
whatever is inside graphics then you
replace it by
by this rule. Okay. So what what does
this rule mean? This means given a
pattern. So whenever inside the G
whenever you see circle something
something anything like circle braces
then anything name it X and anything
name it Y then another anything name it
R. So when whenever you see this pattern
in in in you know in the GI expression
you replace it by this. Okay. So what we
going to replace? We're going to replace
string join another string join.
Uh so you can see you see string join
circle
then x to string then circle cx is the x
coordinate that's the svg syntax. Okay
then that c y is the ycoordinate. Okay
two string y then r is radius in svg
syntax for circle. then two string are
then you give it a style field none
stroke blue stroke width okay so that's
how this function works basically you're
just a bunch of join string uh mostly by
this
replace or you know the pattern matching
find any pattern that that is of this uh
circle thing replace them by this uh
string okay then wrap it with the SVG
header SVG G tag. Okay. So we
demonstrated that works. So for example
uh so copy all uh wait. So let's show it
again. Okay. So paste it here. Paste it.
Okay. So remove this example. Delete
that. So the two days ago. Okay. So we
got clear then inline documentation.
Okay. Then our function is here.
Okay, our functions is here. You can see
the GIA is green
uh syntax coloring. You see those are
patterns. You see this screen G
and this X and Y those are patterns.
They highlighted become green. Okay
then. Okay. So now split this cell.
Control shift D to split it. Okay. So
here is the definition of the function.
Okay. Now shift enter to evaluate it.
Done. Now you see input six right there.
So now we run the code. So we give it a
graphics and two circles. You see uh we
don't want the documentation. Two
circles. circle 0 0 one 021
then shift enter. So you got this string
SVG width height then a circle.
Okay, then another circle. So that's how
it works.
Okay, take took like 20 minutes to
explain what we did.
So
it it's a node or tag or element naming
is not consistent. Right?
Right. So that's about SVG. So circumsp
diagram is where I first learned it.
Okay. Fantastic. I first learned
circumsp
uh in geometry uh because back then so
you know circumcia is very interesting
with triangles because when you have a
triangle
you can uh circumscribe a circle around
a triangle. So that that is basically a
circle passing the three points of the
triangle.
So that's a circum circumcircle.
Okay, circum circumcision
version. Uh you can do that with the
tetrahedrin. Okay, so anyway for for for
the plane two dimensional you got a
triangle any triangle. Then if you have
a circle passing those three points
that's a circum circumcircle.
Then you can have also a what's called
inner circle. Uh what's it called?
inscribed circle which is a circle the
maximum size but inside the triangle. So
the circle will touch the three sides of
the triangle. Okay, very interesting.
Then you got alo also lots of other
so so lots of other so-al centers like
when you have a circumcribed triangle.
Okay, we we getting into uh like
interesting geometry. So for example,
let me let me draw it. And uh you know
we are digressing but but but [laughter]
let me do that a little bit. That's fun.
So we want uh let's see snip and uh so
so now I can draw.
So let's say if you have any triangle
then you want to draw a circle passing
these three point. What what what would
that be? Oh god. So that would be almost
like that. Okay. Then you can also have
a inscribed circle. Okay. So each of the
circle will have a center. So that's a
center A and uh that's another center B.
So these two centers are related to the
triangle. Now
there are several other centers of a
triangle. So for each side of the
triangle, if you um
if you uh drop a perpendicular like from
the opposite point to a side from the
opposite point to a side but
perpendicular
to the side then you draw another one
here. Okay, that's another circle.
That's another center.
Each one they have a name like or center
and other in center and whatever and
there's more. Okay, there's quite a few
more. So,
so that's how I learned about this
circumcribed circle circumcircle circum
sphere and so on. Very interesting
geometry.
Uh
save already exist. Yes. Okay.
So, let's go on.
many plotting primitives. Wow, that's a
lot of episodes. Is the Wufam language
patterns all the way down?
Uh yes, Wuam language is a
pattern matching basically uh pattern
matching is the main way it does
computation. Okay, it is like the main
way to do computation. So in computer
science you call you you use you you
it's called term rewriting system term
rewrite. So what basically in practice
what that means is that you define a
bunch of rules whenever the programming
language you know the code match those
patterns
in one of the rule. So a rule has left
hand side and right hand side. So the
left hand side is a pattern. So you have
a bunch of like hundreds or thousand or
million of rules. So whenever you
evaluate any expression like any
expression you evaluate the wam engine
tries to see which rule it match. So if
it matches the pattern on the left hand
side of the rule the right hand side of
the rule says how to replace it. And in
fact that's what we are doing here. this
function you see is this is the left
hand side and this is the right hand
side. So that's a rule defined. So now
when we run this code the woofam
language sees that oh this expression
began with this graphics to SVG then
inside it's a graphics match and inside
it's anything
match then this rule kicks in. So, so it
it does whatever this the right hand
side replacement do. So, that's a
result. Okay. So, and this is in fact
this is almost this is like the main
core
way of doing computation in wam
language. That's how woofam language
works. In other language you got you
know you have object system you got you
know object system function system they
then they they
you can't explain how they work how they
do computation exactly because they
compile to like many of them they they
compile to like they do computation in
terms of the CPU like memory
uh bytes and data types like data types,
you have integers, you have floats, you
have strings, you have objects, then you
have methods that you know so they are
computation model in Python, in
JavaScript,
in Goland, in Hascal, in C++, in Julia,
in C.
Their computation is based on
in in in for C and C++ for example their
computation is based on bit diddling you
know in terms of the CPU's like
low-level architecture in terms of bytes
basically like everything is just become
a bite and what do you do with a bite
okay but for higher level languages like
python javascript
or eac bisp their computation is based
is is not is not bytes. It's higher
level but it's um usually you know like
it's hard to they don't they don't
specify it exactly but in their language
specification they kind of tell you
what's their model that the that's the
word model of computation they kind of
tell you objects
um and so on okay so in the case of lisp
it's based on basically a list basically
everything is parenthesized list okay so
for example example, you can look at my
softly keys code source code. So that's
immac. So if you let's say let me let me
scroll up 4,000 lines of code. Uh let's
scroll up to something useful.
Uh you see so let's say you know delete
current file make backup.
Okay. So you see the emac list code and
you see all the paren they are actually
a list. So the the the list the lisp
computation model is basically based on
manipul manipulating list. Okay that's
why actually it's in the name lsp
which stand for list processor. Okay,
that's arranging of leisp.
Okay, so computation model that's you
know that's kind of computer science. So
every programming language have some
kind of computational model. In the case
of Wuam Wuam language, it's mostly
uh basically just text replacement, find
and replace. Okay, that's it. That's it.
You type whatevers that's a syntax
that's your code. You just do find
replace. Okay, but in computer science
that is called term rewriting system.
And this kind of model is the most
powerful suitable when you want to do
algebraic symbolic manipulation.
Okay. So that's why you know other
languages they don't have that they they
are less powerful but you know this
there's uh pros and cons. Okay. So
symbolic
pattern matching and replacement called
term rewriting system.
Okay. So uh wam language sort of like
Jupyter notebook. Yes, that's you know
Jup Jupyter notebook is
copied wufam language you know that
that's a history uh wu uh you know the
history of Jupyter notebook they are
just they copied Wuam language notebook
wam language wuam research they they
invented the notebook idea back in 1989.
Okay. So, so that's about computational
model. Hold on. So, we let's get back to
this. But let me um uh Okay. So, let me
let me let me uh let's regroup a little
bit. So, we have like coherent topic of
what we talked about today.
So, we talked about triangle in so let
me show you. Okay. So, let me uh
triangle
in center. Okay. So, so that's one of
the center of triangle, right? So,
search it look up web. You can see right
there. Search it. In center of a
triangle is a point where the three
interior angle bis sectors intersect.
That's right. That's the one I didn't um
explain before. So, there's another in
so let's go there.
Let me just uh so here's a nice
illustration triangle in center. Okay.
Now there's also other centers. So they
are called centrid. They are called
circumc center. They are called ortho
center
and uh there is also wheeler line. Very
interesting. Uh and this more actually
so um so you you just have to look up
Wikipedia. So let me show you. But so
there's also battery center. Okay. Wait,
no. So let me show you. Okay. So here is
centrid.
Here is circumcircle. We demonstrate we
showed here is or center. Okay. We we
showed that ortho center. Yeah.
And there's oiler line. This is very
interesting. Okay. But let's not you
know the you know let's go back to so
let's just copy
uh it here so we because we talked about
it. Okay. So copy
copy
circum center. And what is this one?
Centrid. Okay. Delete. And uh this one
is in center. Okay. Each and everyone is
interesting. Okay.
Copy it. So close that. Refresh. So we
got bunch of Wikipedia centers. Wait,
something went wrong. Okay. So hold on a
second.
Uh that's the you know when you link you
you just want the name. You don't want
the full URL. Okay. So delete that.
Undo show in browser. So you can see
those are nice Wikipedia links. You
don't want the full URL. So remove that.
So that's one thing we talked about. And
meanwhile we can show the pink window.
Go back here. Press press press.
That command is called HT HTML move
image file. So the image file is now
here and it also optimize the PNG. Close
it. Open it. So you see so now
showing browser.
So we have kind of we did that
illustration. So uh and and okay
and now uh we are talking about notebook
history. So you go to kasa you can
actually just search kasali.info info
search notebook.
So you got notebook file format uh wam
language get script path notebook
directory wam language notebook tutorial
uh just basic history of notebook user
interface so open that so there is also
closure you can you know closure
interactive notebook closure you know
that's like Jupiter began about 15 years
ago 2010 or later. So that's so we go to
the history of notebook. So here is a
wam language notebook the history of
notebook user interface. So you can see
the first one 1988
Mathematica version one. Okay. And here
is Stephan Wuam talking about the
history of notebook idea. Okay. Then
everybody just copied it. And the most
popular copy is from Jupiter. Okay. So,
did they talk about
uh this is uh this is uh Wikipedia.
Uh Jupiter has a page that credit it.
Okay. So, anyway, copy that. Let's put
the link here.
Notebook history. Okay.
And close that. And notebook. So,
so notebook basic notebook you can have
headers like press old one title. Okay.
So, this should be title of this
this this
um let's see.
Let's have some coffee to refresh my
brain. I'm out of coffee. Okay, one last
sip.
Mamograph. Did I use that correctly? I
don't think so. I was thinking uh
monograph. That's right. So, this should
be
monograph.
Okay. Title and you then you have
section. Wait.
uh 02
section
then you can have 03
03 subsection something like that. Okay.
So you can have bold itallic whatever
it's like a markup. Okay. So that's
about notebook. So okay copy that. So
let's just uh history of notebook and
notebook intro.
Okay. And uh okay let's get back to what
we doing.
How's it going? Opto MTB.
Oh, copy copy. Oh, copy the good thing.
Okay.
Uh, one thing I want to tell, let me
digress one more. Okay. One thing I want
to tell you is that the notebook is in
fact the best interface. You know, a lot
of people they like,
you know, they they like the shell
so-called um
kind of idiotic, you know, they call it
um
repo.
Wait, wait, not repo. What what is the
jargon? they call this uh for example
you can do ls I mean windows so I don't
have ls but I have the well you can you
know eac this emulates the unix ls
command so you can do ls but you can
start powershell
so you can you know you type command it
it prints output then you type another
command that's so that's a shell
interface that's shell interface or
command line interface and [snorts]
in EMAC you can have also have that. So
for example we are looking at eh shell
okay so you can also start powershell
there it is so duh you know that's
powershell and you can also start uh
emac interactive
okay so that's emac this
shell interface now what they don't call
it shell interface they call it Um
God I I must remember the the word but
let me demo it first. Okay. So plus
let's say 2 three then enter. There it
is. So you can run emacisp the
programming language like a shell the
shell interface. You type a command it
gives you output. Okay. So all these are
shell interfaces.
uh what what is the word they use? Uh so
for example uh I don't okay so close
this one close this one and uh go back
to talk show open
this directory in shell and control
scroll to magnify then I can do uh wait
I can do the okay listing the god
uh the okay so you can you
digressions and digressions. So what is
the word for this uh interface? What the
like [snorts] a fad idiotic name
which came from the schem
but borrowed by the industrial coders
like Python for example you can do that
in Python too. Python there you got it.
So let's say 3 + 2 this um what they
call it.
Okay, you guys remember ripple. Yeah,
right. That's right. Ripple. Okay, I
said that before. I forgot. Ripple. It's
the most idiotic by these people
because they the ripple name. So let me
show you a history. Okay. Search for
EPL.
Uh
EPL. Well, there. Okay. Jargon Ripple
and hackers. Okay.
What is Ripple? Why is it called Ripple?
What is the ethmology of Ripple?
Addict of the day. Any hacker using the
term Ripple is to be despised upon
immediately. Okay.
So how should one call ripple?
It should be called command command line
user interface. Okay. Why should one
call it command command line user
interface? Because first of all you are
an idiot.
You know so ethmology of ripple. So why
why do they call it repo? Because it
came from this book structure and
interpretation of computer programs.
So ripple stand for read r evaluate e uh
p print
p loop re e pl l read evaluate print
loop. So whenever you do something in
shell that's kind of what's going on.
You type something you press enter the
program reads it then the the program
evaluates it. Then it prints it the
output then loop. Then you are back to
the you know prompt. Okay. Read eval
print loop. Okay. So let's go back here
and let's uh yeah this book. So let me
just open that in a new tab. Okay. So
read eva print loop.
This jargon came from this book
structure and interpretation of
computer programs. Uh fantastic book. I
recommend it.
It's not necess it's not a practical
book though like you won't get a job if
you read this book. But if you will get
a job if you read Python books. Okay. So
this is kind of the situation because
this is
and this is not exactly computer science
neither. It's kind of like middle
ground. Okay. This this book I read it
in 1998.
Okay. So this book
basically use that term. Then the Python
idiots they picked it it up. So they
think that you know a shell bash you
know it's not cool. you know, it's no
longer cool to call a shell. We need
something cryptic. That's when the
Python idiots picked up the ripple
jargon. So, they don't call a shell like
Python shell. They don't say that, you
know. Well, we we got a ripple. So, know
that's a situation. Anyway, back to my
point. What I want to tell you guys is
the ripple interface, the command line
interface is is not good compared to
notebook. Why? Because when you have a
command line interface, you can only
type one thing at a time, you know, and
uh and uh you cannot refer to past input
like well you can you know you backspace
and you know you backspace backspace or
in bash you controlr you know like then
that's the one you want then then you
maybe modify it you know but the
basically the idea is is linear you know
input output the input output linear.
Okay. Meanwhile, if you have a notebook
interface, you can jump and modify each
part anytime you want. For example,
let's modify this to be center uh 0.5.
So, you know, then shift enter evaluate.
You see, you can copy any part, evaluate
any part any time
in this command line interface. you
cannot you know you you are you know
forced forced into these linear
sequences okay so the so the notebook is
much superior
that's that's a thing I want to say and
I have an article on that too so let's
regroup and uh let's put the link back
so we organize on the things we talked
about okay so we talked about notebooks
then we got uh this ripple jargon
arranging of the ripple jargon.
So close that and structure and
interpretation of computer programs.
Okay, hope I close it and notebook we we
talked about that. Okay, so and so what
I want to tell you is there this article
command line interface ripple versus
notebook interface which is better.
[snorts] So I give you my thoughts.
Okay, my analysis and we also
demonstrated many command line interface
in Emacs. Okay, copy that. So, let's
just paste it. Okay, and uh we also
demonstrated Emacs
uh for example, we demonstrated Emacs.
So, let's also get that link.
So go to Emacs blog, open it and search
Emacs tutorial.
No. Okay. So this interactive
uh
Okay. So I don't have a independent
page. So you go to EMAC list basics
quick start quick start file name
extension comment print output
uh working with emacis there.
So evaluate emac this code you go there
open it. So that tells you all the ways
to evaluate
emacis programming language. Then you
can see this ripple.
Okay. So copy that. We demonstrated that
uh where are we going? So okay. So we
yeah today's talk show link list.
Okay so far yeah so we that's a
digression and uh let's go back to our
shell. So we open so many shells. So
let's just copy.
Okay shell screenshot. Close it. Close
it.
Uh wait. So okay close talk show. Close
it. And what is this shell? This is
PowerShell
in Emacs.
Power shell. Fantastic.
Screenshot it. Close it. There's a
process running. Are you sure? Yes. Kill
it. And there it is. Emac list shell.
Okay. EM
We demonstrated
close. Okay. Now is Okay. So now we back
to the talk show page
and lots of digressions. Let's put the
um
the images here. Okay. Press press.
There it is. Showing browser.
Okay. We demonstrated several ripple in
Emacs powerful
running concurrently.
Okay. So now we back to wam language.
Yeah. So let's go uh we wanted to do the
line. Okay.
Uh press help for the name. Yes. Uh repo
terminal. Yes.
Mamogram. Oh yeah. Mamogram. That's
something else.
Um
mono okay I got it wrong. Monograph
monograph is means like basically an
academic
um work publication monograph.
Uh so
so let's get to the code. So showing
browser we have the woofam code here at
the bottom. So let's start to modify it.
We already like wasted lots of time.
Wait. So not that one. So this one we
want to modify. So this string
let's copy it. Uh let's put it.
Okay. That's just demo of the syntax
shortcut. Okay. So now that's what we
doing. Okay. So now
code code code. No. So so let's add. So
now this code is hard hard to read
actually it is true wam language is kind
of hard to read even though it even
though technically is like lisp it's
fully nested but
but when the code get complex it's
harder to read okay you can see in
notebook they render it with automatic
indentation so for example
I demonstrated this many times
So you see you see notice how the line
got cut. So okay so look at this circle.
Okay circle is a pattern. Now if I
change the window size you can see they
automatic automatically format in a nice
way
you know when they cut the line those
are points where the expression stops
like you know. So this is fantastic
feature automatic formatting on the fly
as you type. Okay. But the Python
idiots, the kido vanosome, they thought,
"Oh, we should have indentation baked
into the syntax."
So this this automatic format started in
1996.
Okay. Wuam language Mathematica version
three. I was at there at Wuam language
Wuam research. Okay. This this feature
began in 1997
90 96 or 97.
Okay.
Uh and also I can uh I can format you
know math formulas but let's not do that
today. Okay. So anyway, so let let you
know we we we got uh a file. Let's get
back to get this to work. So
uh so this part so let's see this part
is for replacing
okay so this part is for replacing
replace all you you see that and uh this
is a list of rules. So,
so let's cut that and make a list of
rules. Okay. So, paste. That's one of
them.
Okay. Then we put another one.
Copy comma a new rule. So, this rule
says line.
So whenever you see a line
uh of this pattern
okay so let's just name name then AB
okay A B C D okay two points of of the
line you want to replace it by now we
need to look up the syntax for line in
SVG
basic shapes so syntax for line is that.
So let's just copy it here. So paste it
just for
um
okay so basically that okay so what we
need to do is so you got x1
y1 x2 y2
that's a syntax for line.
So you here you say
line
x1.
Okay. Then this is a
then
x
b o. This is y1. Okay. So y1
this is this is getting tedious.
Uh so god x1 y1
so then you need x2
c. Okay. Then you need um
X2
Y2
D then style. What should style? Just
stroke black. Okay. Stroke black
be. You don't need just stroke black.
Okay.
Line width. Uh well do you need stroke
with let's let's leave it. Okay so I
believe that's it.
Let's put it this back here. Okay.
So,
so this is the SVG syntax for line. But
in Wufam language, the syntax is this by
this pattern. So, whenever you see that,
replace it delayed
by this string. Okay, I believe that's
kind of I think that's work. That works.
Let's kind of uh compact our code.
Let's hope that works. Let's hope.
Okay. So, let's try it. So,
that that that that. And here we need to
add a line. So, now you got two circles.
Okay. Then you need to add a line.
Okay. Do we have example line? Yes.
Copy.
Just paste it there. Okay, we got a
line. So, copy all. Copy all.
Paste it.
Big code.
Okay. Shift enter. Shift enter. Let's
see. This is the output now. Is it
correct?
So we can modify it. Shift control L to
copy the output. That's right. The whole
thing is a string. Then so you got you
enter. You got the first circle style
something something. Then you got the
second circle something something. Then
you got there it is a line XY X1 Y1 X2
Y2 fantastic and style fantastic and
then SVG so looks like it's correct
now two primitives
then you got like 20 more actually
something like 10 more okay so this
function we made we made a progress.
Now, next thing we want to do is let's
make it uh so let's put it back first
show in browser. So, today's talk show
is it organized? Yes.
Here's the code. Okay. So, next thing
given a string you want to write that
string to file. How do you do that? I
don't remember. So, that's the next
thing we we want to do we want to export
this string into a file. So name it
something SVG that then we can show the
SVG in a browser or whatever. Okay, for
example this this uh this output.
So how do you write to a file? I don't
remember. So let's go to wam language
for programmers.
Uh print print and print no number
boolean list expression function loop
conditional pattern matching data
structure advanced symbol principles
full form graphics read write file we
want write file. So that is the syntax
right string file name or path then
string fantastic
just that copy
okay so let's demo so first of all demo
this uh this this this
okay so
another one language paste it pop it out
so let's see this test something okay so
file name here then
a string
uh then
uh then you have to close it. Uh
write string uh why do you have to close
it? Right string to file. If the file
know exist, it is created. If the file
already exists, it is overritten. Okay,
so you got to be careful. Uh when done
writing code, close to close the file.
Oh god.
Okay, let's try this. Let's evaluate the
code.
Should be done. Then by default, if you
give a relative path, it's saved in
documents. Okay, documents on Windows.
So, let's now search for XX
uh search search
XX test. No, it's not there.
Where did you save it? Oh god. So
that's when you need to read the
documentation,
but I didn't document it myself. Why is
that? So let's see. Go to the directory.
Search xx test. Okay. It's saved in the
current directory. Whatever the
directory you are in. Okay. Uh so there
it is. That's a file. That's a file. The
current directory. I mean a temp
directory. Okay.
So, close that. So, that's how you save
a file. Okay. Let's close that. Close
that. Close that.
Uh, write string to file. Okay. Now, put
it back. Syntax.
So, now
we want to change the function to uh
write to a file. Okay. So, let's uh that
should be here. Okay.
Okay, now let's see here is our
function.
In fact, we need to define a new
function. So let's do that. Okay, so
copy copy copy copy. And this this part
is testing. Okay, so a new function
paste there.
Uh instead of two string to file. Okay.
Change to string
to SVG
file. Okay.
Something like that. Change change.
Okay. Now,
so documentation export
X graphics to SVG
as a file. Wait, now you need a file
path.
So the documentation is a graphics. Then
you need a file path.
Okay. So export X graphics to SVG
and save it at
file path.
Let's name it X file path so that stand
out
so that it doesn't have normal English
meaning you know it might be confusing
because now this is a param parameter
name but the name embeds a meaning so
the parameter name also tell you it
should be a file path so that's what I
do instead of just saying for example
instead of naming it file path because
then when you document And that file
path the word file path has a meaning
you know it means file path but it also
means the parameter it you know so it
might be confusing that's so that is why
I always name my parameter names
something not normal English so you add
x in front something like that okay so
that is that is why so export x graphics
to SVG and and and uh SVG string and
save it at file path. Okay. So,
so um
so yeah, so that's the documentation and
now we just need to change this. Okay,
we defined that. So let me hold on a
second. Let me uh wait.
So now this function what will it do is
we don't need all these parts anymore.
We want to just write to file. Okay. So,
copy that. Write to file. So, here it's
going to be graphics GI and
uh wait.
So, this actually we can uh just name
expression. Okay.
expression and file path.
Okay,
so this pattern match two things. So
whenever wam language saw a code that
began with x graphics file and inside it
got two things any two thing because
that's underscore that low line means a
pattern of blank means match anything.
So whenever you see something something
this SVG file contains two things
then what you do is you um you you call
um
so uh you write file. So this this part
is the
X file path. Okay. Then the expression
is
two string
and
there you see
then you close it. So now you got two
expressions you want to combine them
into one expression. So what you can do
is um
well normally you put a uh semicolon.
Oh god this get complicated. So one way
to do it is you just put a a paren.
So this in lisp this is like p o gn
program group. Okay. Uh you know do you
guys understand what I'm saying?
Can't you just write to file the string?
Yes.
Okay. Save from having to close every
time.
Oh, you can use save. I didn't know
that.
Do we have like
save tech tech save URL save dumb save
HTML save? Oh god. Cloud save notebook
save. Uh okay. Let's see what is save.
Hi just joined. Hi.
save file name symbol append definition
associated append definition associated
with all symbols no I don't think that's
one anyway let's let's just go through
the way I know okay anyway that that'll
do it okay so this function
that should work uh oh yeah close close
this needs to be that okay
uh in fact this function can be returned
is as like this. Okay, let me show you
compound expression. Okay, compound
expression. Then two things. The first
thing is that
then the second expression is that.
Okay, then we don't need the par. So you
see this is identical to this. Now you
see that semicolon
that is just a shortcut. This semicolon
is a shortcut for this compound
expression. And this compound expression
if you code emacisp or lisp
that means in eagisp it just means p o
gn like a grouping expressions together
as one. Okay. Uh
okay. Anyway, let me let me write it
this way. So this way is kind of
shorter. Okay. So I think that should
work. Now we can try it. Yeah. So here
is a test code. So
uh so so graphics and second argument is
um
my SV
my
fantastic
SV uh
function
SVG. Okay, we're calling the function.
So
I think that's it. So in fact we can run
this without notebook. We can run this
directly in Emacs because
because we don't need to show graphics.
Yeah, actually we can run this. Yeah. So
let's do it.
So let's say evaluate the buffer. Let's
see.
Oh, fantastic. Process finished this
one. Open the file. There it is.
So go to a directory. So that's a file.
That's SVG. Open it in Inkscape SVG
editor.
So you have to wait inkscape to open.
So we got it. It is correct. It's saved
to a file. But there's something
incorrect. I know why. Uh, I'll show
you. Okay. So, you see we got our circle
there. We got two circles. You see how
to see? Can uh let's see. Can you see?
You see, we got a we got two circles and
we got a line. Wait, how do you
uh uh Anyway, you see we got we got two
circle, we got a line, but it's off. So
this is about SVG coordinates.
So you see in mathematics coordinates is
the y axis the more higher it is the
higher value it is the positive side is
up the negative side is down but in SVG
computer graphics
it's the opposite so the vertical axis
the
if if you go down the value is higher if
you go up the value is negative so it's
reverse first.
So you got the coordinate issue. So also
you got centering issue because in
mathematics
you know circle
you know you can plot the circle and
usually it shows you know 0 0 is origin
in the middle but in computer graphics
whatever you do the 0 0 is on the upper
left corner. Okay. [snorts] So you can
see our code
our code here the width and height
also needs to change
because right now we are plotting you
know a circle of one radius or two you
know but but the the canvas is 100 by
100. So our circle become a tiny dot in
a corner.
So we need to but at least it's kind of
working. Okay. So what we need to do
let's close that close that close that
okay what we need to do is in this code
here
you see this width and height we need to
change it needs to be
it needs to be the boundary of whatever
is your current graphics like we are
doing 2D so the boundary you know it
needs to be whatever
the m the the minimum and maximum of x
and also the minimum uh and maximum of y
of the entire whatever graphics you
have. We need to find those values.
Then we can specify here what is the
width and height. Okay. So that's one
thing to do. The other thing is you need
to reorient reorient the center. You
need to flip the axis. So whenever y
occurs you need to make it negative
then then you need to move the whole
zero zero you need to do a translation.
Okay.
Uh then what but and another thing you
need to do is what if you have like
typically when you draw something the x
and y maybe 1 billion right you can plot
something you know one to one billion
like in real life real world graphics
typically that's the case so you need to
scale kind of scale the whole coordinate
in other words you need to have a
userdefined coordinate not pixel
Okay, by default they are pixels but
your computer screen is only like you
know 3,000 by you know 2,000 something
or even 10,000 by by by 5,000 but in
real life the the coordinate may be
maybe a median. So you need to scale the
coordinates okay so that
would be the next job. Okay. So you can
look at
uh you can learn about SVG SVG tutorial
and the circle specifying styles shape
styles view port that's what we need to
do view port that explains the view port
in terms of pixels then you need to read
about
uh the view box which is user coordinate
basic ically rescale
the the the screen. Okay. Like port port
viewport is like the part of your screen
view port. Okay. But you need you need
your own coordinate of the canvas scale.
So that's that's the next to do.
Okay. So let's make a comment here.
need to center the origin. Okay. Origin
means the 0 0
need to reverse
the y axis or any point you know any
coordinate the yaxis needs to be
reversed and
okay and
need to
rescale the coordinate.
that is SVG so called in SVG they call
viewbox you need to create a viewbox
okay so put the code back syntax color
show in browser and that's it for today
uh and this this let's make a screenshot
this this uh this SVG thing we created
>> [laughter]
>> Okay. Inkscape. I haven't used for a
long time. How do you um space? Oh,
yeah. So, you need to do that.
And uh where is the scale here,
right?
Uh scale it. And uh
God, you need to
So, Inkscape.
Wait, let's
So, right now we are 500 times larger.
So, we are like
I just want to make a screenshot of
this.
So people know
can clearly understand what's going on
with our uh example. So let's paste it
here.
Uh let's go to
move the image here
and [snorts]
uh look at it. That's correct. Now show
in browser.
Fantastic and beautiful. Okay, that's it
for today. I think I hope you guys like
it.
Uh, we got a lot to do here. Uh, anyway,
it's fun.
Are you using an XML helper or just
directly writing the string?
Uh,
what do you mean I'm directly writing a
string? Uh, I'm not using any helper.
What do you mean helper in Emacs or
what?
I will use full English. Okay, bye guys.
Okay, if you like my stuff, okay, go to
kasali.info
talk show
code which is kasali.info
http nos and pay me $1,000.
Okay,
some people have done that. for me. Um,
a few people
in in my life, you know, they actually
pay me a thousand.
A few, a handful. Uh, so if you like my
stuff, go down, you know, Patreon me,
PayPal me, Amazon gift card me. Okay,
thank you very much. That's you guys are
the sponsor.
Bye, guys.
So, let's shut down. We shut down in 2
minutes. So, close that. Close that.
Wrame language. Fantastic. Close that
view box. Copy the link. And uh back to
here. We need to paste the link so
people can see user coordinate. Okay.
And go back here. And we we got view
port
SVG view port also. Paste there. Linkify
make a list combine the two list.
Okay. U the and remove the Okay. Close
that right file. Okay. Copy that and uh
paste. Okay. So close that basic shapes.
Yes. Ripple. We got that. Bye.
10 people. Wow. So many quite a few. I
mean 10 for me. So bye guys.
H happy holidays.
Happy Christmas. Merry Christmas.