yeah
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi oh wait how long
have I been going did I just start long
ago
oh I started two minutes ago okay um
something came something came up I
have lots of problems and I haven't been
doing my video for a while it's a mess
when when did I start the stream I
didn't click the button so am I am I
actually talking yes so what am i doing
I'm going to do so so how come to
another episode of saw talk show and so
we are going to do Emacs okay so so here
is what I'm going to do is to do a Emacs
workflow and one second hello beautiful
people
hi guys hi Allen and hi Justine so okay
so let me do let me do a today's topic
so what I'm going to do is I'm going to
work on my Emacs website so this is
going to be a Emacs work workflow demo
and you're gonna see how I work with my
website and HTML and what I'm going to
do is that I'm going to change my Emacs
website navigation bar or table table of
contents you see the way right now it is
is that if you go to Saudi just search
for Agha
Emacs dog you go to the website you will
see things like this so on the left you
see this panel and see
I can you can see it yeah so the on the
left you can see this navigation panel
which is kind of like menu or topics so
you have practical Emacs then you have
everything about in each setup then you
have everything about Emacs keybinding
how to set keys everything keybinding
related things then then you have
introduction to eMac this then you have
eMac these examples then you have
tutorials about how to write a Emacs
major mod so that's the left panel
basically the the topic so menu so if
you if you click on any one of them so
for example let's go to practical Emacs
then you see the list of topics and if
you for example these you start with
where to download Emacs the so you we
are on this page the left panel remains
the same many of different topics but on
the page at the bottom let's go to the
bottom so you will see a list of indexes
of that topic so where to download Emacs
so you can click the next one
Emacs first day which is a tutorial for
those of you who never started Emacs
before so again you scroll to the bottom
and you see the next topic and you know
so basically the menu at the bottom is
on every page for for this topic for the
practical Emacs in the same way in a
similar way if you go to for example
eMac base B examples then you see this
sparks of all the pages about eMac based
code examples so you can click any one
of them for example let's click on
change title case so here's a code
example in eMac this you know code
example then at the bottom again you see
these indexes so you can pick another
eMac this example so this is a current
structure
of my Emax website but what I'm thinking
is that I want I'm thinking to for
example let's go to practical Emacs and
it's go down so you see a bunch of
topics about how to use Emacs I'm
thinking of moving these index box
navigation box to the left so so this
whole thing will be on the left side and
as in a similar way if you are on a
practical email based introduction it's
let's say let's click on this one
evaluate how to evaluate eMac this code
and you scroll down to the bottom you
see these boxes indexes about basics of
eMac B's so I want to move that to the
left so this way so this way is actually
more typical of online websites on the
left you have a bunch of you know
subject related like index of topics
meanwhile the overall category of the
website typically you go to the home
page you know the top page of the
website then you can see you know what
kind of categories are available on on
the website so that so that is what I'm
thinking I'm going to do today so I'm
going to just demonstrate how to do that
so I'm going to make a backup and you
know so I have two versions and in in
the end you will see how the two
versions actually look so what do you
guys think do you think the current way
is better or the new way is better let
me know type in the chat box ok so good
morning and Dee Dee break the loop you
changed your name so I like the index
links highlight a different color by
mousing over yeah that's great I added
that recently like few months ago so so
that's a new edition so
so what do you guys think that the two
ways that the way I have it right now or
or have all these indexes move to the to
the left of the page the left panel what
which which one do you think is better
so type in the Box type in the chat box
let me know but anyhow let's just start
to work on them okay so let me check how
long have I been talking for 10 minutes
this is gonna take a while 40 minutes I
think so break the roof says wait break
the loop and and dee dee aren't you the
same person I thought so break the loop
says it makes sense for the index to be
on the left side okay big loop says
cause otherwise user has to scroll to
the top to navigate
you mean scroll to the bottom for
example I'm practically Maglis let's say
let's go to practical Emacs then let's
say split windows so this page discuss
about spirit windows so you have to
scroll all the way down then to see
other you know to continue with what you
are reading so actually there are pros
and cons in either way you know I tried
to design these navigation box in the
past three years and it's lots of
frustration it's really because CSS does
not let you do it meanwhile does not let
you do it really that's a fundamental
issue meanwhile the HTML of 4.1 4.0 one
frame set you know that that did it TTT
that solves a problem but that that
technology is being absolute it is being
defunct
anyway that that's getting complex
that's getting the history of the tech
technology and actually I have a article
on that so I'm not going to talk about
that but anyway the thing is that today
you just have you need to use CSS to do
this and there's really no good way to
do it because if I move for example if I
move all these topics
you know this index of the current topic
to the left of the panel what will
happen is that actually means maybe I
can show you an example JavaScript let's
go to JavaScript okay it's not here wait
let's see yeah it's not here let's see
if I can find an example where I can
find the example so if we go to sorry
down info and you go to my programming
tutorials for example let's go to Python
so for example this is my Python page
python tutorial and you have the typical
list of topics on the left you know you
can start with Python 3 basics you can
start with Python 2 basics then you can
start with you know you go to another
topic about print statement and about
building help so it's all on the left
you see or you can look at true and
false in Python so this is so this this
web design is the typical website design
but there is a problem too because for
example you are on this page true or
false so you read it you read it ok it's
done now you want to go back to the next
page you know the next topic after to
reinforce you cannot you have to scroll
all the way up then you see that then
you click then if then else you see so
when you are reading this page if they
else you read read you know sometimes
the page is long then you have to scroll
all the way to the top and click again
so either way you know so in this
typical traditional way you have to
scroll back to the top if the page is
long meanwhile the way I have it on my
Emacs page is that you
and read then naturally you hit the you
know the topics box so either way it's
kind of and it's you know it's unclear
which one is much better break the loop
cause okay same person and D so just
switched YouTube account okay so current
way is kind of nice in in that when you
reach the bottom of a specific topic you
see that index of the other pages
allowing you to naturally look for
another page okay yeah so I asked asked
this question a few times to different
people I think most of them they prefer
the traditional style like the like like
the Python page because this is what
people are used to meanwhile for my
Emacs page where you have you have this
high higher level of categories on the
left you know so anyway so so but you
see once you explain to people the pros
and cons of both then people started to
say oh maybe the current way is better
that you know that's the thing there is
no decisive judgment on which which is
better so anyway let's let's just go
ahead and do them you know let's just do
the email code flow let's see okay so
okay there's a lot to do so I'm going to
show you so let's see saw start command
log mod okay so on this on this window
you are going to see all my Emacs
commands
okay so right now my I am on my website
so this is the this is the directory
path
this is where my Emacs website is so if
I search for I go to the index on a
second so wait
so let's magnify this oops let's magnify
these windows so you can actually see
better okay so we have a lot to do
actually so let's start so so on this
page first of all I want to make a
backup so let's go down here I want to
make a backup so this is not usually how
I do it but let's do it this way so copy
CP not go point CP - ha this directory
copy to backup
so there is a command I want to do so I
go to shell I paste that and yeah let's
do it
okay enter
I just hit enter and it's gonna take a
while
now Emacs is stuck what's going on
Emacs is stuck wait Oh is my computer
stuck
ah this is bad Emax wait normally when
you do a ye shall copy it shouldn't
stuck right
let's see what what else is going on
okay we have to wait these okay so oh
it's done so finally it's done so let's
go to let's go to the new directory
Emacs but back up so okay so we did the
back up so let's let's start to work on
this closely Shou and close these no
safe okay so what I want to do is I want
to close that I want to close that
showing browser again actually it's
gonna this is going to be a lot work
okay click on practical Emacs so let's
go to the top of the directory okay I
have this category here then let's go to
practical Emacs so now I'm going to put
every of these index pages to the left
panel there's a lot now when you
actually work on these there's a lot to
do and I also have to explain it so so
I'm opening the page what I want to do
is let me explain what what what I have
to do so on each and every of these page
for example for example let's go to
where to download Emacs okay so let's
open that page the source code where to
download Emacs this is the source code
download Emacs for Windows Mac and Linux
so on each and every of this page in the
navigation box there is at the bottom
you'll see let's go to bottom okay so
let's go to bottom so at the bottom you
will see this this block of code and
this block of code corresponds to these
navigation box
I call them navigation box and
so you can see so for each and every of
this link which which are here they
contain this this this list of pages
index pages so for each one of this page
I need to replace this page basically
DVD deleted
okay for each one each page I need to
delete this navigation box and I need to
also let me show you the source code so
the source code here on this page also
every of every one of the page also has
this this code okay and that code covers
one correspond to the this navigation
box I mean the panel the panel on the
left so let me repeat on each and every
of this page not others okay only these
remembered because I have other many
other topics pages so on each page in
this box I need to one remove these
marks remove remove this text to also
remove this left panel text and replace
the left panel text by by this
navigation box text so so first of all
what we need to do is we need to find
out just exactly which page we need to
make this specific change you know this
is just one of the change for the
practical Emacs then we have to do the
same for in its setup then we have to do
the same for Emacs keys you know each
category of topics so but let's focus on
the practical Emacs so first of all we
need to find out the list of pages we
need to change that is easy okay so I
just go to here let me show you this
okay so you see okay so
so that you see this highlighted section
you know if I'm doing this by myself
then it's fast it's much faster I just
you know I know what to do but the thing
is I have to expand if I do not expand
you have no idea what's going on you
just see see me you know punching
keyboards so anyway so first of all I
need to find out a list of files file
path so okay so I select the the nav box
then I press a button which cause the
saw HTML extract URL command ok this
command then what I have is a list of
paths so these are the list of files I
need to change you know it extract the
URL and changing into a full path that's
one of the command I wrote which is very
convenient when you walk on with HTML ok
so I have now a list of pages 148 files
file path so I'm going to cut this then
I'm going to close that and I'm not
actually going to switch to a goal and
script yeah let's go to Golan Golan we
place so I've written this find and
replace script in Golan so you are
looking at the source code right now so
what I want to do is you see there is
the file list so I'm going to paste the
bunch of file paths here there there
they are so when you have a bunch of
file paths here that means this find and
replace we are only Find and Replace on
these files nothing else ok and now I
need to make them into the Golan Golan
syntax which is like I'll show you what
it looks like ok so each line must look
like that
so basically add the quotation and a
tacoma idea so I have a command so I
just caught that Saco lines and press
enter enter so it's that it's done for
me
180 lines so you see now each line is a
string so this this is a list of files I
want to change now the next thing I need
to do is to to say what's the
replacement text I mean what what what's
the fine text and replace text so the
fine text will be oh my god
to do this and to do this live stream
takes a lot explanation because if I do
not explain you have no idea what's
going on
so here the Golan we have find in reface
pairs so so the fine the first of all
the fine pair and see what I want to do
the fine pair okay so so here you see
the find/replace pair let me just do
this okay so you can see quickly so this
script allows me to do multiple find and
replace pairs in one shot all you have
to do is add the lines here so let's
copy that it's so we have two of them so
because we need to do to pay yourself
find and replace so let's so so now we
go back to the find/replace we want to
first of all we want to find the left
panel
the left panel which is the here you see
okay so let's go to the goaline page I
pasted here that's the left panel and we
want to replace that panel by let's
place it here okay wait yeah let's
replace it by let me tell you what we
need to replace it by we need to replace
it by the navigation box which is these
so let's go back let's see if I got
correct me if I got it correct
let's see find and you need to be super
careful here because otherwise once you
do it it's gonna replace hundreds of
files so you have to make sure the fine
we paste is correct so find that and we
place okay so we don't want that topics
you know nobody if I'm doing it this by
myself it's just typing and very fast
because I do these thousands you know
thousands of times every day for the
past ten years okay so we did one paper
find/replace let's let's we need to do
another pail find finding replace which
is which is remove this rebou remove
this navigation box okay it's basically
meaning find these texts and just delete
it replaced by empty string so that's
what I'm going to do here paste that
then replaced by empty stream
okay that's that's it let's just run the
code and let's hope everything is fine
okay now before we do anything let's go
back to let's go back to my Emacs
website let's go to the directory
magnify issue let's go to hold on a
second okay then go to a top directory
then get status I want to make a git
commit in case anything went wrong so
get status okay git add then get commit
okay then now let's delete or Emacs
backups because for example you can see
you know sometimes I have lots of
backups Emacs made backups so let's just
run a code so what we shall delete
backup ok it's done so now it's now I
have a get committed get backup so let's
run the goal and find replace code ok so
where is that so there okay so in it
it's just a net yeah syntax a row
unexpected new line yeah I knew
something is wrong gold we place 179 oh
yeah so the in goal and syntax you need
a comma at the end ok let's do it again
run it we it's working so you you can
see the output here it it did find we
face on all these files basically 180
files now if we go back to browser and
refresh let's hope it works you see now
this is the old right you are seeing the
old so in the old on the Left panel is
the is the category menu meanwhile at
the bottom of each page is the index box
the navigation box now if I press
refresh the navigation box should become
should move to the left let's refresh no
it failed
hahaha I failed where did I um refresh
what's going on click on down it worked
ok it worked
yeah I'm not sure why it didn't work on
the first page sometimes but anyway but
let's see if we it worked okay so look
so here is Donald let's click on Emacs
first day looks like it worked
click on Emacs basics
then basic tips then lesser-known tips
then fun with Emacs then
Emacs on Windows frequently asked
questions simply it worked
sweet Windows Restore split windows
looks great yeah so we have lots of
topics of this category on the Left
panel so it worked but meanwhile but I'm
not sure why is this index page does not
work okay that's something I have to do
so anyway that that basically walks
worked ok now the next thing we need to
do is to we need to click on the unit
setup again we need to do the same thing
for all these files for the unit setup
for example you click on Emacs init file
this page explains what init file is
about how do you wear where does Emacs
look for it and so on and again at the
bottom you move down to the bottom then
you see the topics index so we need to
do this find replace again for this so
that all these are on the left ok but I
think I'm going I'm now going to do it
right now so but you get idea of what we
are doing today basically I just need to
do the same thing so which one do you
think is better do you think the current
version is better where where for
example you know you know what I mean so
you know the current version where the
the left panel shows the high-level
category of topics
meanwhile the 4 for each specific topic
you have a bunch of indexes at the
bottom of the page so that's the that's
a current way or what we did today where
the current the index of current topics
is or on the left this is more
traditional solely so which one do you
think is better
George Fernan so the morning okay so I
think maybe that's it for today you know
I have I have not been doing a
livestream much for the past 10 days
because I got there's something there's
family issues okay family issues coming
up so so I'm busy and let's see how long
have I been talking 35 minutes so I
think maybe that's it for today you guys
you guys have any questions or comments
hello beautiful people you can have the
navigation on the same position all the
time can stay at the same pace the thing
you might want to Co is position yeah I
know that you see so that's why these
topics is very complex I know what you
mean exactly because I have been trying
to do that you know I tried it you know
I've been trying to research and doing
this I mean you know doing it and didn't
like it and revert it and try another
way it's very very complex topic you
know you can you know like you are
saying make the position fixed for
example if I if I scroll down the page
the the menu does not move with a page
or you can have a scroll bar within the
menu within the Left panel right so you
see there are quite quite a lot design
issues I mean there's on one hand you
have design issues on the other hand you
have the implementation issues both
these two design issues and
implementation issues they are separate
separate concerns but however for each
one of them if we forget about
implementation okay let's just think
about design then that also have quite a
few different ways and it's not easy to
know which one is actually better and if
you already picked a specific design
then you want to implement them there is
also quite a few ways you know like
whether you want a little scroll bar
here or whether you want the whole page
to scroll and you know I've tried to
survey what's what does people think in
general there is no one agreement that's
a problem there's no one way that's
clearly better than the other so so this
is you know fairly complicated in fact
in fact I have an article on that anyway
so so just let me you know so let me
know so what do you think I mean given
the the way that two ways I have right
now you know one one way is this way or
my current website way which which of
these two you think are better and also
like him you know like I mentioned
before when if you want to have a if you
want to the if you want the Left panel
to be fixed you know not moving with a
page then if the number of things in the
left panel is long longer than one
screenful then you do need a score bar
but but then this complexities because
because it's more complex because your
page no longer behaves like a piece of
paper now it becomes like an app you
know it becomes an app kind of thing you
have a scroll bar here then you have a
Escobar here you know so it depends on
you know your preference and yeah it's a
big issue
you know usability there's no agreement
on which one is better
exactly
no scrolling after reading is there
needed no squirting after reading his
they needed
okay so I think that's it for today so
thank you guys for watching anything
else any questions any comments
interesting things George
Pano's ooh where are you from I don't
think I've seen you before
so break the loop anything else
MP fares MP there's I like having the
link links near the top after
introduction you like the links near the
top
after the introduction what do you mean
that's ambiguous because in both in both
ways you have the links at top like like
what you mean
okay that's it for today thank you for
watching and I've been working on my
Emacs website updating the website a lot
in the past two weeks so if you like my
Emacs stuff buy it you know now you can
see a big Buy It button on you know on
each of the top page so so you can you
know so yeah well yeah they're saying
and also eMac this so buy it like my
stuff thank you guys bye and also join
discord okay you know I have a discord
account you go through any of my website
and you can find my discord and in this
code you can you know you have the
latest information about what am i doing
and many interesting people they're
talking about keyboards about
programming languages and many weird
ideas too you know you get the worse
opinions on all sort of things
like on Wikipedia pages okay
Oh at least Oh topics okay so I like
having the links near the top
after the introduction see you guys bye