hello welcome to another episode of
guitar talk show
today we are going to do Wolfram
language coding so this is gonna be
relaxed session so and it's probably
going to be boring for you so if you
want a focused tutorial on Wolfram
language uh you probably better just go
to my woofam website okay wufam Language
tutorial and I've done a lot
introductions to Fan language so you go
there and you know search for Language
tutorial you go there and watch a
collection of my best full-time language
videos there that gives you an intro and
today I'm just going to code Wolfram
language uh going to so I'm going to
code Wolfram language and it's going to
be about walking or directory so you
want to get a list of files in all
directories and subdirectories and you
want to tally the word count and you
want to also work on Wolfram Association
data structure which is
like Python's dictionary Pearl or Ruby's
hash table or JavaScript and Java's map
data structure so in Wolfram language is
called Association
this data structure and in list
languages it's called Association list
so it's basically a list of key value
pairs so I'm just going to leisurely you
know today we are going to I'm going to
work on them live coding okay so there
is there it is a Wolfram language and
here is XR Discord
uh you can join this start Discord and
you know we have fun chat okay so we are
going to code Wolfram language today's
topic you know just live coding uh hello
guys hello Johan
and immortality and Jr
Okay so
so if you have comments and questions
post it okay love to see it and don't
forget to donate that's the most
critical part okay that's why you know
if you like my stuff
just do it five dollars twenty dollars
just do it just like Nike you know
okay so with my language so so let's do
so last time
a week ago uh two weeks ago
we did uh we did this word count so
let's let's start okay so let's so here
is Wolf and language we already started
uh let's magnify
see let's magnify and see
150 okay
and what we want to do
now I want to read the file and tally
the word count and uh
and also the count of every two words
you know the frequency so
okay so let's see why don't we just copy
the code here we added the code here
okay so anyway so here is today's talk
show
and let's start and let's start coding
okay
uh U fan language paste the code here
pop it out to a subwoofam language mod
this allows me to work on Wolfram
language uh in emacs okay and here is
the file last time we used this is
Arabian Nights it's fantastic I
recommend it the book of one thousand in
one nights the real thing not the Disney
version uh you will see lots of
amazing you know amazing uh Tales the
Arabian Nights
not the Disney thing so so we are going
to use the this
okay so here is the file we want to
count the words in that file so uh input
string so let's see
yeah okay so
so let's let's do it let me let me just
show you one by one actually so
uh delete that wait
did that no you need to press the DD key
so
first of all clear
X yeah
okay because I had an X there so
so here is the file path so we want
um let's just copy it then
okay so paste that yeah
delete paste that
copy that
back here
select all delete
paste okay so input read string so that
will read the whole files content into
the X input and now we want to do find
replace Okay so
find replace
and paste it so this wheel here's a
regular you know find string replace is
a function you want to use
X input is a HTML source code for
example let's look at the source code
control U so here is the source code let
me magnify the browser's font Okay so
so we can see better
okay so here's the source code you can
see lots of HTML so we want to remove
HTML tags so you that's why you call
screen replace X input first argument
that's a giant string and do regular
expression this is how you do regular
expression in Wolfram language you see
this part represents a regular
expression and here is a regular
expression you are probably familiar
with if you code python C Java you know
not C python JavaScript and so on Ruby
and you want to replace it by empty
string so so that will remove all the
tags HTML tags okay
and and now you can just simply call
what counts okay so let's paste it here
so you can see
World count input there it is so you see
so V happens 376 times n happens 319
times okay so that's the word count now
I let's say okay this is kind of long
um
we want to truncate it so now so this
this data you can see this thing the
output that is the in Wolfram language
it's called Association okay so let me
go to it
so this code Association list it's just
called Association new from language and
that basically means a key value pair in
other languages it's called hash table
or map or
um
in Python it's called dictionary okay
basically the same thing uh key value
pairs in an efficient way that's a key
point because otherwise you can just
have lists of pairs or array of pairs
but that's not efficient
so hash table you know the association
list now
okay so now we got an associate this is
the output so it it's in this data
structure now uh word count now you can
give it two that means count every two
word phrases okay so let's evaluate it
let's see what we get
you see one of the nice things about
Wolfram language is everything is so
um all the functions are building
because otherwise in Python for example
if you want to do there's no such
function for word count you have to do a
hash table you know you have to pass the
file you know read every word you know
split speed the big giant string by a
space then remove the comma and so on
then you Loop through every word
then you add them to a hash table as a
key and if the key already exists you
increment the value by one that's how
you do World count in Python and or
basically essentially every other
language
but in Wolfram language there's so many
things building now in this case we are
doing a word count but background
phrases okay let me show you the maybe I
should show you okay so I can ink
subwoofer mod you can search online I
talked about so in xavu fan mod in emacs
I can just press a key uh wait not that
key okay
you know I want to know what's the
documentation for what count function so
here's the key
we get into the Wolfram language
reference turn JavaScript
okay so here's the world count right so
you but you can give a second argument
and that will give you the end Grant so
if you if a is true that will give you
the count of
um
okay so show more uh show more you know
when when the output is huge like 10 000
lines ten thousand you know then Wolfram
language automatically truncate the
output then allows you to you know show
or show more show less so let's show
more
show more okay so now we got a lot so
you can see the king the the two World
phrase the king happened 13 times uh
the wise the the Vasa happens 11 times
the fish happen 12 times okay so that is
the um
now are they sorted by frequency yes
they are so this a something happened
234 times now this is probably an error
this is a encoding error okay
encoding I haven't figured out let me
show you what what this what does that
mean what's the encoding error so
so you can see so okay so let me type A
let me magnify
so you can see what I have here is a um
this character okay that's a curly quote
so curly quote it's called Left double
quotation mark you know it's called
equal
uh and this happens for example let's
search for it you see for every time
there's a quote I use a Cody quote you
know for example there is this is a you
know
and showing browser if we show this in
browser you can also see if you search
for curly code let's copy that
so search for it
you see there it is it's hard to see
because
you see there
oh it's interesting you see in the
browser in the Firefox when you search
the beginning color code it will also
find the N Curry quote Oh yeah that's
because the Unicode
equivalence you know that's interesting
so let's search again so anyway the
point is you know you have this curly
quote and they and those are not ASCII
characters okay so you can see lots of
occurrences
so it has to do with encoding and here
this is not correct you know that's
there's no character a hat okay there's
no such character in this file but
however you know that's because encoding
error I haven't figured that out why
that happens so
but that had a should be is probably
came from the curly quote uh encoding
error of the curly quote there Okay so
so that's about encoding so so let's
ignore it you know that's ignore those
um so let's see if V happens 33 times
let's search for uh V there it is there
it is there it is
okay so now
the
and they are sorted okay now we want to
let's say how do you truncate a hash
table
you know in other languages
I'm not sure you do have a function you
know Wolfram language table is so rich
um
so let me show you okay so
okay close that now let's go to talk
show again and let's open that new
windows
down it's big
let's go to talk show today's talk show
this one showing browser go back yeah
show in browser uh what we want to do is
oh yeah so I want to show you the wufam
association list so I I've been working
on this in the past few days so
all these are about Association lists so
you can this is how you get values and
this is how you add key and so on and
right now we want to truncate yeah
you know in most languages you have get
value check key existence let me show
you okay so let's go to python
and let's go to emac please okay so for
example in emac lisp you also have
Association list you know because wolfam
language is you can consider it as a
family of list you know very interesting
so you know in lisp you also have the
some you know the association list
they almost work exactly very similar to
Wolfram language you can see
you know very similar
uh but in lisp you also have hash table
which is
dedicated its actual hash table while
the least associate Association list is
not really a hash table it's just a list
of pairs so anyway
so in most other languages you have you
know how do you get get a value by a key
you know get value by a key then you
have get pairs by key check a key exist
get Pair by value add the element you
know add a key value pair
that's about it in most of the languages
similarly in Python so let's go to let's
show python
so in Python it's called dictionary so
you can you know create a dictionary add
entry delete the entry check key exist
get keys value get count uh get all keys
get all values
and how do you Loop them what type can
be used in key in this dictionary and
you know then you have how do you Loop
through a dictionary
uh then you have dictionary methods so
that that's that's all the dictionary
methods basically in every language
that's about it okay
but in Wolfram language it's far more
Rich you know you can
um
so let's go back to from language yeah
so
you can add a key delete a key uh you
can let me let me show you something
interesting okay
so
so this is add a key delete by key let's
see get value
um you see let me show you about the get
value function you know
so in Python you want to get a value you
just uh
dictionary.get okay return the value of
a key if it if it exists okay
that's basically it
now
in Wolfram language you can you know you
use the lookup function
uh but what you can do is that you can
specify more than one key in one shot
you see that's a kind of the power extra
power of Wolfram language and then you
can also specify more than one hash
table in in one shot so all these bunch
of you know suppose you have thousands
of hash tables you want to know all of
them
you know get the value of a key so you
can do it one shot you don't have to do
a loop typically in other languages then
you have to do a loop loop through a
bunch of hash tables you know or
dictionary so that's one of the power
okay one of the power
uh now I want to end this a lot more so
a lot a lot more so you know so for
example this miscellaneous I haven't
uh write a tutorial of them yet but I'll
get to them
you can also
um do Union on the key Union and
intersection on a key do I have them
here somewhere Union and intersection on
a key you can do a filter
you know you can filter a dictionary by
key you know uh here okay you can filter
a dictionary by a function on the key
and but you can also filter by a pattern
okay so lots of Rich things
so let me get get on okay so hello T
corpse thank you
uh so ticov says thank you for the large
repository of knowledge on your website
much better than that internet AI spam
that exists now where yeah exactly yeah
you know in the past 10 days Google
Facebook Twitter they poisoned the
internet so these days and you know then
the millennial and Zuma these days if
you search anything you won't find
actual information
doesn't matter it's programming in what
well basically you only thing you get is
stack overflow
so
you used to be you type something you
know especially on programming stuff you
will find technical blogs by nerds
that's reach very rich information but
today every page is saying the same
thing copy and paste you know especially
from spam tutorial website you know
tutorial point you know they copy is
copy there's no content
and part of the problem is because
Google you know algorithmic control they
you know lots of money money is uh the
ultimate reason
so anyway so uh thank you for the
donation and could you explain what is a
hash table please okay hash table is
just a key value pair okay
so hash table you know well if you if
you know python is in Python it's called
dictionary it's just key value pairs the
purpose of that is allows you to
um
to accumulate a bunch of key
and
for example
for example you have uh persons names
you want to know their age so it's kind
of like a database in some sense so you
can have lots of names you know John
Mary each name should be unique you know
suppose they are social security ID so a
unique name then each one has a value so
you can quickly the point is fast okay
that's a point the the point is that you
can quickly
query this data structure by a key and
get their value you know such as a
person's age and so on
now this is in contrast to a list you
can do the same thing by a list or array
you know whatever your programming
language is called you know basically
you have a giant list of
pairs
where a nest at least each element is
again a list of two things you know name
and value or key and value you can do
that with a list but the problem is
array at least every time you want to
check if some key exists you have to
literally Loop through every item okay
that's
that's what happens with the array data
structure or List you know
technique technically called linked list
depending on which language you know so
so that is the point of hash table or
dictionary or sometimes it's called map
in Java in JavaScript it's called map
okay so let me show you some
Golan
JavaScript
okay so in JavaScript for example that
thing is called a map object and it's
added um
there okay so in 2015 JavaScript
JavaScript added to several new objects
one of them is map now what is map map
is basically key value pairs now if you
don't know JavaScript you might ask if
you already know you might what's the
difference between object you know
object is already collection of key
value pairs well the problem with object
is that it's a hack map object the new
one added in 2015 is the actual real
um hash table for example you can get
the length you know how many items in
them so anyway that's the JavaScript so
you can you know create a new map it's
called map it's essentially dictionary
or hash table they are all the same
thing okay just different languages have
different names for them so
you can add a new item you can
um
you know you can delete a item by key
and a pair by key you can check if a key
exists you can you know and so on so
that's JavaScript called it calls them
map in Java it's also called map okay
but in Python
you know in Python it's called
dictionary okay in Golan it's called
um
uh it's called hash table I think in
Golan let's see array slice map okay
Angola is also called map so you can see
you know create uh you can see get value
that's how you get value in Golan bio
key you can set that you you know so on
okay that's what hash table is
uh let's see let's go back okay so
I want to I want to actually truncate
this
um
I want to truncate this uh Association
these so let's go back I'm gonna read
the comment in a minute okay so how do
you
how do you uh truncate let's see uh take
okay
okay I think Tech is what we want
take is a function in wufam language
that gives you the first n elements okay
and I believe it also it works on list
and it also works on Association uh yeah
exactly
yeah okay so let's try take so we have
this word count
okay so let's you know
this is very long so let's let me show
you okay so let's do this again welcome
so you got a huge list and now you want
to get the length Okay so now let's use
length
that's a this is a post fixed notation
so you have
4700 of them okay now you do take okay
so you um
take the first
um
100 one of them okay
do it
there it is that's the first hundred
let's take first 50.
uh let's say take the first 20 okay
there it is that's the output now let's
see how many items are there let's
verify
okay 20. so take is how you truncate a
Association okay so we got this okay
let's get let me get on to what we want
to do today so I want to
not just to the count of one single file
I want to go through a list of
directories and count all you know I
have 7 000 files in my um
what
um
let me show you so I have something like
study info
so let's go let's go to Powershell
and
the
uh what's going on
because
file
filter
okay filtered by I want all HTML files
and that's gonna be your long list okay
so stop let's do it again now pipe it to
measure so I want to know how many so I
have 700 7 7 700 HTML files anxiety info
not counting saudi.org so all these so I
want to do what count on all these you
know files that's what we are doing so
so we want to read the directory okay so
let's see how do we read the directory
uh so Wolfram language uh true Force
equality so we have read file list files
there it is file names file name String
pattern
um
directory there it is that's that's the
thing we want okay copy it
let's do it here
now string pattern will be
let's just say star HTML you can also
use a regular expression
now directory will be let's see let's
say directory is let's just for now
let's limit it to some talk show okay so
here is the directory Star Talk Show
um
you know so they are
700 files in Santa's show
okay copy that directory and
so that's the directory and this is the
depth okay it's you know depth you know
since in South talk show there's no
essentially no subter so I mean this
doesn't matter let's say 10.
okay evaluate it okay so it gives you
uh it returns
[Music]
it Returns the list of files okay it's
quite long so 700 files
yeah
so now we can do
if you say length
you know 400
oh what 440
waited wait shouldn't it
shouldn't it be 700
oh yeah because I have a lot of text
files
yeah
but here we are not counting text files
okay yeah so 440 uh HTML files now we
want to go through the directory Okay so
uh let's see what we want to do
navigate directory we want to you know
we can do a map
we want to map a function to all these
um
actually I have already written here
somewhere
so here is a script to find and replace
all files in your directory
uh so process file write string scan
yeah so we can use scan
so let's look at the scan function
okay
scan evaluate function applied to each
element of expression in turn okay
that's what we want
you know that we can also use map but um
scan is just like map except that it
does not return a value
okay let's use scan
so
actually it's much faster if I work in
emacs so let's do that in emacs scan
uh so scan yeah we want to show a list
of directories so here is let me let me
just make this clear
the equals to
uh
X Files so that's a bunch of files and
now
and now we want to write a function
okay function equals to we can do it
this way there are many ways to do it
but I'm just going to do it in the kind
of the simple way so function one
argument X
and the body of the function will be
yeah you need to read the file so read
string there it is
so function
X is the argument the parameter and we
want to read yeah X is a file name so X
so we want to read a string then
feed it to what count
and uh yeah and and we don't want to
take
we don't want to truncate it
okay so here is a function so the
function
is given a x is a file path and we read
it
and do what come and let's say what
count what just for Simplicity for now
okay so now we got a function now
now we want to scan
now remember the scan the syntax is a
function expression level spec okay so
the function is f
the expression is X Files
and level spec is the depth of the
expression you know in this case
uh in this case we just want one so by
default it will work
let's see apply to each element yeah
so okay so we got these three things
let's try this okay
uh
but now
so each function it will return a hash
table okay
yeah we can run this but the result will
will won't be uh correct
so let's try it
you know it's gonna read each file and
each time it's a result it's a hash
table but it doesn't return anything
because you use the scan so instead you
want to use map instead okay
so then that will return 400 hash table
okay so you can see and you can see
percentage sign stands for last output
so now we use a postfix operator and
apply the function length to it to see
how many items so we got 444
hash table okay now we want to merge all
of them all of the hash table each one
we want to you know if the word if one
hash table has the work saw happen four
times another hash table have happened
three times we want we want to combine
them okay so
so we uh basically merge a hash table so
how you do that let's see
so we go back to fame language
um
uh Wolfram language Association okay
let's look at them
Association key value pairs
merge okay there's a function merge
now there are probably new more
efficient ways but I don't know yet
Association you know the association
data structure is actually new in
Wolfram language around 2000 uh 16 or so
it's pretty new so it's very interesting
because
because you know Wolfram language began
in 1989
and the hash table data structure is not
there for 25 years you know only in 2016
so let's look let's see how uh when is
it added
you see 2014 so after 25 years
then we'll find language added the key
the hash table data structure you know I
can tell you why because there's a
design issue you know the association
data structure is actually kind of
um against the
the term rewriting
model of Wolfram language that's why
it's added so so late you know so why do
they wait until 25 years to add this
because because in all other languages
starting with pearl in 1995.
hash table becomes critical you know in
C before that you don't have you know
it's not in in almost every language
because if you want a hashtrip table do
it yourself you know just write it
yourself but as as over the decade
decades as a machine gets faster more
higher higher level languages such as
starting with pearl then Python and Ruby
you know every language has a hash table
data structure building you know so
that's so that becomes uh you know very
popular so all the programmers they when
they go to fame language they are going
like what you don't have hash table like
what's the deal
that you know that's I think that's a
major reason Wolfram language added
um
Association list
you know but
actually I'm not sure it should
because you know that's another topic
that's about the design of a language
you know I think it should be
automatically done behind the scenes
when you have a list of pairs okay but
anyway that's another topic that's about
design of the language and the
uniform syntax like one single syntax
represent everything because when you
think about hash table a list of key
value Pairs and when you think about a
list of payers they are actually the
same thing you know at least from an
interface point of view
from a syntax point of view and combined
with interface point of view they are
actually the same thing
the only difference is that hash table
performs much faster now that's a
implementation issue therefore as the
programming language you should you
should not
you know you your compiler should be
smart so that when you see a list of you
know 10 000 pairs it should
automatically automatically compile them
to a hash table behind the scenes you
know that's the power
so I think that Wolfram language should
do that but for some reason they didn't
of course there are other complexities
and considerations but
you know in general I think you know
that should be done but anyway so
Wolfram language now has an association
so it's kind of new in 2014 and uh I
haven't you know by 2014 however I don't
have Wu from language so
I'm not very familiar with the
association so right now we want to
merge to Association okay let's see how
to do that
uh yeah so merge okay here is the
documentation for much
uh yeah so you just give a list of
associations and you add a function okay
easy enough so
so let's do it so here is a map so
um
so let's see let's define this to be so
we got a bunch of hash tables okay
okay
now
now we want to map through the hash
table right yeah we want to merge them
into a single one
okay much is the function the first
argument is a list of associations the
second argument is the function so let's
write it on the spot Lambda now in this
in this this
function would be called Lambda in
JavaScript is called function
in Python it's called also Lambda but
python is
uh has a crippled Lambda so anyway so
function
so this function what this function will
do is it will tell you tell wolfen
language how do you merge to uh entries
of the same key okay so what does the
function take let's read about it
merge the association uh using the
function f to combine values when uh
when with the same key okay
so the function is fed two arguments I
suppose um
ah okay so the function only take one
argument
I mean uh two arguments and each
argument is the value
so so this merge function it will find
all the keys that's the same and we'll
merge them so each key has a value so
this function will take you know
different values from different
Association lists and this function will
tell you know this function will
actually take two or more arguments
depending on how many associations you
have in our case we have 440
associations so this function each time
you'll be fed 440 values of the key so
so but okay yeah so but what would it do
so
yeah so it should uh so this function
is going to take arbitrary number of
arguments two or more and it should
return one single argument one single
value and and in our case we just want
to add them together so we don't even we
don't even need to Define our function
the function we need already exists it's
called total okay total is just like in
other languages in Haskell it's Sun okay
you know that's what we want
okay so that's it so let's see copy that
copy that back to Fan language
and let's see
yeah so that should do it
that's that should be the final result
okay fantastic so we got 12
um
Keys we we got about 12 000 keys in
order associations
um
and that's just
um so yeah so let's now take the
let's let's give it a value so
say word come
equals to
so we assign them a to a variable so we
don't have to compute it again and again
so let's do it this way okay
um
so that's it
so now let's just compute it one more
time
do it
so how am I doing
four people are Jesus three people
watching
okay so here's a result let's see what
count and let's see how many items there
12 972 okay and let's say let's show the
top 10 uh results
okay so take the top 20.
okay so inside talk show directory the
word Kobo happens five times sa happens
uh 200 2020
times
okay and you can see we have a bunch of
HTML tags there now we forgot to remove
them so we need to modify this yeah we
forgot to remove them
yeah so let's copy the remove
stream
so here's the read stream and then you
want to yeah
do string replace
there it is okay let's do it again
so now you should get rid of the HTML
tags okay there it is now
copy that
paste it
there it is much better so
for some reason Kobo happened five times
now what why is it not sorted
okay it's not sorted now we need to sort
it
uh let's see how do you sort
um we want to sort a hash table by their
value okay now in other languages you
basically have to there's no building
function you have to
you have to
convert them to a list then sold it
that's that's what you have to do in
Python in Golan in all the other
languages but let's see how we do it in
Wolfram language
so yeah so let's go to Association
and uh miscellaneous I still need to
work on this key sort
uh do we have a value sort uh
let's see key sword
key sort by Keys uh oh yeah so
all you have to do is just say sort now
many functions
you know in Wolfram language you have
like tons of functions that work some at
least okay all these functions will also
work on Association list and when they
do when they are applied to associate
Association list they will automatic
automatically work on the values Okay so
so that's why you have an extra function
for key sort that's when you want to
sort by the key but otherwise just use
sort okay so let's do it again
so uh so let's sort
okay
sort World count you can see now you can
see okay now we want to sort in a
reverse
way because now it Source one two three
four okay we want to reverse
so how do you reverse
there's an option to say in reverse
order
you have sort by reverse sort okay
there's an actual actually a dedicated
function to reverse the holder that's
reverse sort okay so let's say reverse
sort
okay
evaluate it there it is so excited
happened two thousand something times
sure happens 1600 times talk happened
1600 times that's correct that's all the
things inside talk show okay
so now
we we get in there so
so the goal is to do all the seven
thousand files on my website and let's
see what's the word that's used most
frequently okay so let's add the reverse
sword
so hash table
so let's see
all the merge of all the hash table okay
then we want to sort it
yeah reverse sort we want to sort it
then we want to
uh yeah okay that's it that's that
yeah we can now it's all clear
this is our whole code do it
yeah so now we are going to do it to the
entire directory now of study info first
of all let's change it to let's say
python directory okay
you know the entire let me let me show
you go to python so you can see here's
my python it's only
140 files let's go to emacs
emacs directory there are 800 files okay
so let's let's do the my emacs directory
what let's see what's the most
frequently used word
okay it's already done so there is the
result wow this is
800 files so emacs the word emacs
happens for you for two times 44 times
okay now let's do the entire study info
directory of 7000 files do it
fantastic but here's the result
fantastic
so last result let's do a take
let's you know show the first 50 top 50
um
so I'm gonna write a function cryptic
here let's say top 100
so here is the final result this is the
top 100 words happened in sardi.info
about seven thousand files so emacs
happens the most things are in
JavaScript
then end oh my God the word JavaScript
happened more often than the conjunction
end
sure wait I'm not sure this is correct
wait uh
no I think this
this is not correct this is incorrect
because the word v
should happen more often okay we got the
error somewhere
read files oxide info okay I know what
to do
you know I I you know I think sometimes
there's a cash issue in ufam language
like once you read a
um
you read a file somehow it stays in okay
anyway the result here is incorrect I
don't think so so let's let's
um
that's
let's try to do this again fresh okay
so I'm what I'm going to do is
quit wolfam language
don't save
and start over and that'll be it for
today so of course that
okay so actually close that
okay so start the new
evaluated
okay
magnify
okay and uh let's do this
let's make sure it's correct
function X
each stream
expression
and count
will count
returns a Association okay then you want
to
uh
apply that function to all files that's
correct
then you want to merge the hash table by
total okay then reverse sort
then yeah so you do take
the first argument is that then you take
the first hundred items okay so that is
the code
paste it here
do it
ah this is this is this is kind of
strange
there is the the word
now the word happens even less
than e-max
is that true oh yeah because every file
you have the H1 header
then you have the title they are or
emacs
actually so this is correct
very interesting uh
and xar happens the most often because
every page you have a
you know you have the footer
you know
yeah that makes sense in JavaScript
because in JavaScript directory
you have like 700
um
you have 900 files and almost every one
of them
have several words oh yeah because all
the panels you see that's why yeah you
see all the panels wait that
yeah well because
um
well it does make sense because there's
lots of files here JavaScript
okay that's the result so let me read
the comments we shut down in one minute
um
so there's a question from Crazy Frog is
it worth paying for Wolfram rather than
using this for everything yeah well
one language is a magnitude Beyond lisp
you know you know I talked about that
many times
so but the thing is you you have a free
version of Wolfram engine you can start
with
you know just go to my website you can
see download free uh free wolfam engine
you know watch my video I talked about
this before
yes Julia is a very good language Julia
is a great language I don't know it
though but
for my experience and here what people
say I think Julia is a great language
but it's not a Wolfram alternative okay
depending on what you want to do you
know if you want to solve equations
symbolic computation you know machine
learning AI you know Wolfram language is
100 times you know 100 times in whatever
100 times a magnitude more powerful more
rich
than all the whatever Julia Haskell
closure what whatever fancy language
that's that's just you know that's just
true
okay bye guys thank you guys for
watching
donate okay pay me
um bye
so I'm gonna shut down I'm gonna shut
down and I'm going to
um
yeah so I'm shutting down clean up my
files
so here is what
yeah this is today's talk show
clean up
so that's that's all you need so here is
a code
let me show you this so here is a code
for going through
7000 files and get the award count you
know you can if you add you if you add
this word count
um
you know if you say this would come
here okay so if you say two then you get
a list of all
bigrams okay let's let's run it okay
just for the sake of interesting what's
the most frequent occurrences of two
word sequence okay
of oxali dot info website
okay so start talk happens 429 times
then then talk show happened 426 times
yeah that makes sense
blog archive their properties happened
258 times
uh
emac this 100 happens 230 times you know
that's so this is a
two-word phrase programming block
happens 78 times yeah that's interesting
now let's change it to three
now because if you change this to two or
three then in other languages it's a lot
more code you know because then you have
to partition you know given a list of
words before you simply do a split
you know then you look through each
words then you tally them put them into
a hash table by key but now if you want
a trace of two
World sequences you want to you can just
split them you have to sleep split them
but you have to kind of a shift split
you know so in other languages it gets
more um work so anyway let's do three
let's see what's the three word uh
combination
so Casa talk show happens 400 uh
times curves and their properties 100
258 times and their properties there it
is XA emacs plug
okay that's interesting and somewhat
it's it's surprising because I thought
it would be and that you know they are
there is something like that but it
turns out it's all my word
um
titles like file titles and so on
emac this coding their properties
roulette
their properties spiral so that's only
11 times yeah very interesting what
about you know I wonder if you go to an
English text then
we can do it so let's see let's try now
let's try Alice in Wonderland okay let's
try Alice in Wonderland Wonderland okay
or the Vlog let me show you
so what the English
literature classics
then you have Alice in Wonderland let's
see let's get the word Teddy let's copy
the directory file path there it is
uh there it is then there it is
put it here okay let's do Alice in
Wonderland
okay and actually what count yeah so
let's do it here
you know if there's any if there's a
flaw in wufan language I would say speed
okay because the speed is not so great
you know you for any task
if you write in Golan in Python let's
say it takes you one hour
okay especially if you write it in goal
and in JavaScript it might be take you
two hours
but it's fast you know you take two
hours two hours to write it and the
result come out let's say five seconds
but in Wolfram it takes you one minute
to code it save you 60 times the human
effort but the the result is um
slower you know slower than Golan or
python
depends for example it really depends if
you have a very specialized task then
Wolfram is 100 times faster than
whatever language you use for example
let's list pi
to
2000 phases okay
doesn't matter what language you do you
try to do this it's gonna be 100 times
slower than Wolfram language okay and in
wolfen language you can call this in one
minute you know in in one second pi to
to the 2000 places you can say
five thousand ten thousand you know it
depends on your memory and so on so
anyway so
Alice in Wonderland
and uh if we count Words it's going to
be
wait that's two okay that's two word
phrases let's just say one
so the and a two that's the expect
expected space of
uh that's a quotation sign Alice it she
okay that makes sense but let's see
yeah so uh out they won this not if okay
now let's see two word phrases
hey Reaper thank you Reaper
Ripper says to what extent do you think
lisp uh expression symbolic Expressions
power for most programmers is
essentially serving as an association
dictionary and not because of uh Macross
hmm
to what extent to what extent do you
think
lisp symbolic is expression power
for most programmers is essentially
serving as an association dictionary
no I don't think you know I don't think
that's true you know so I think you are
saying that
what do you mean serving as an
association dictionary so let me let me
just explain what I
maybe maybe that's your question so lisp
you know a lot at least Fanatics they
love lisp because for several reasons
they like the least syntax because
everything is parenthesis uh
and everything you know everything is
just a function call so functional
programming is part of it
the nested fairly regular syntax
and uh and you deal with symbols so that
allows you to have more quotes
you know which is kind of like term
rewriting but basic one uh I I did the
explanation of this in lots of my
previous videos uh so you might check
out that
so for example if you go to ufam
language
you go to
um
you go to the
okay let me read it okay so
I mean so let me say first that I did a
lot about this language
um
I did a loud video about this language
where is it definitely no problem let me
see come land serving yeah so search for
that you'll find several videos
talking about the lisp syntax and the
and different languages why this love
them you know so that's very much
related
so let me see
okay so you are saying yeah so I think I
know what you're saying so you are
saying you know these programmers they
love list let me show you some this code
uh okay so here's a list code and then
let's go to up
so for example these are list code and
let's go to some you know lots of you
know parentheses and you know so this
like you know
these people they love them this
for one of the big reason is that
so-called um
home your iconicity okay meaning that
either the the syntax
[Music]
um
corresponds to the data you know
something like that that I don't think
that that
that's that makes sense so basically
what they are saying is that let me show
you okay so
that's yeah so I that's a different
topic so
okay so you might want to read these
fundamental problems of lisp okay and uh
[Music]
um
yeah so let's see fundamental problems
of these syntax irregularities
uh syntax semantic correspondence okay
that's what I think that's what you are
talking about home your iconicity okay
uh and the source code transformation
okay yeah home your iconicity you know
so a lot of these people you know they
think of the syntax as data data data is
a language language is data something
like that I don't think that makes sense
at all in fact what actually what they
actually appreciate
the gist of their appreciation is not
about some data and language are the
same thing that's that's incorrect the
gist of their appreciation is regularity
of the syntax okay not not some home
iconicity crap okay
these people one of the major reason
these people love these languages is
because the regularity of syntax okay
that's my view okay that's that's my
view for fighting with the least
phonetics for 20 years okay regularity
of Syntax for example other examples are
XML and Wolfram language okay you have
regularity of syntax okay I talked about
this many times in my video now Okay so
so that's what you know these people say
about
sex you know symbiotics expression
so you are saying I mean somalic's
expression are useful for storing data
and this programming use them in a
productive way like Pearl and PHP or
JavaScript programmers use associative
already
I think I know what you are saying so so
anyway so these people like that okay
but really but they don't have anything
to do with uh
associative arrays though
you know in this you do have Associated
lists and hash table but that's a
different thing and these people do not
actually use them much
these programmers they love to use just
least okay and associative list is a
list but hash table in this is not a
list okay so for example if you're
looking at the emac this you have
Association list which is a list but it
has a problem of inefficiency when you
have more than 10 items you know if you
have more than let's say 10 items of
pairs key value pairs then you want to
use the actual hash table which
ceases to be a list because you know
look at the hash table syntax it stopped
having this typical symbolic expression
form you see look at this here is a hash
table
a literal expression for hash table for
emac this you can see it's not a list
anymore it's kind of got this special
syntax and these programmers in iMac
Beasts for example you don't see this
used much
people go back to use Association list
which you can see here the syntax is
actually is a list
okay so I think that's what you kind of
saying
so so what I'm saying is that
um
yeah yeah so I guess yeah a lot of
people you know these people like the
you know what I'm saying is that
they will say they like the idea of home
your iconicity or data is program
program is data now I think that doesn't
make much sense what they actually love
the just the essence is regularity of
syntax okay
okay that's it for today bye
it's too long
bye guys