Hello guys, good morning everyone.
Welcome to another episode of talk show.
We are going to code emac bisp today. Uh
emac bisp. Let's see. So programming
language blog uh talk show. Emac bisp
today episode
663 eacisp coding. Uh I'm going to write
a command that shows all duplicate
links. So, let me show you what it is.
So, if you are watching offline, play at
1.5 speed because I ramble over and skip
about. If you are here, say hi. Okay,
love to see your comments. If you are
here, say
hi. Okay, so let's uh so what what is it
we're going to do? So, let me going to
uh let me show you. So, this is my
programming blog. So, um let's go to the
article garbage collection and scroll
down. Uh not that one. So, let's see.
Let me show you what uh am I
doing. Why Unix man page sucks. So, this
article. Okay. So, scroll down. You can
see um there is a lot uh links. Okay.
Why Unix sucks
uh series of articles about this topic.
So why Unix shell syntax sucks? Okay. Uh
let me try to find the place. Okay.
Uh yeah. Okay. So let's try another one.
The nature of Unix philosophy which is a
sham. Okay. Let's try this this article.
Okay. So let's go to um talk show. Go to
today's talk show and uh paste the link
here. Showing browser. Okay. remove the
link live stream. Okay, so this is about
this is going to be Emac Lisp coding. If
you don't know already, Emacs is the
powerful editor. I'm using the most
powerful more powerful than VS code or
whatever the most powerful you know uh
editor and I'm using HTML mod. I'm using
um I'm using Safly Keys which is the
most efficient key binding for Emacs
more efficient than VI or VIM. Uh and
you can watch a video about it. Uh and
here is the key binding. So basically
softly keys if you use it in EMAC you
don't have to press control keys or meta
keys basically. So it's like VI but the
key binding is more efficient.
uh than Vim for doing the same thing.
So, Safly Keys and I'm also using Kasa
HTML mod. So, there uh you can you know
if keys is free and HTML mod you have to
pay me. Uh my stuff has been free for
like 15 years but nobody cares. So, so
now you pay to get it. It's open source.
Okay. So softly keys the pink window
shows my command codes like I can delete
the entire list and that's smart delete
undo or I can delete you know I can
delete the whole panel
um and uh and so on. So you can see the
command codes on the right and the
keystrokes on the left and I'm using a
vorac keyboard layout. So, Vora keyboard
layout. Uh, so you can go to saw
keyboard blog and you can read
everything about keyboards you ever
wanted to know. Okay. So, Vora keyboard
layout
that's, you know, efficient keyboard
layout. Okay. So, copy that. So, showing
browser. So, uh, close that. Showing
browser. Okay. Let's put the links here
so people can see what we talked about.
Okay, that's a introduction. Now let's
code the today's problem. So you go to
this page, you can see there are several
links there. There's a see also see also
see also like related uh essays related
to this page the nature of Unix
philosophy and then you also have um a
topic box. So all the articles in this
uh links in this uh box are all related
to why Unix
sucks. So I have like 6,000 like 10,000
HTML pages written in the past 10 years
uh manually like like what I'm doing
right now. So sometimes the articles
move about. So for example today I just
created um you know this this topic box
is new. So but you see but some of the
links are repeated. So for example this
article do Unix tools do one thing well?
You know that was the premise of the
Unix philosophy. They say the Unix each
you know shell tools do one thing well.
That's a good quality. That's why Unix
is so great. But that is actually total
because Unix tools they do
don't they don't do one thing well.
Okay. Uh so the article gives details.
Do Unix tool do one thing well. You know
you can read about the
examples. So you can see there's article
related you know uh but here but that
article do Unix tools do one thing well
is repeated also here. You know I just
added this this topic box. So there's
reps some repet uh repetitions. So let's
open this page. Open it. Show in
browser. Okay. So let's go
down. Let's go down. Then you can see
here is the bunch of related uh essays
link
uh you know. So you got that one, you
got that one, then you got this is the
topic box. But if you go to the do Unix
uh does Unix uh do one thing well let's
highlight it
yellow. So you can see yellow they are
repeated. So when I move the you know
when I create a new topic box and move
these links about they you have
repetition. So now I want to remove this
you know uh do Unix tools do one thing
well since it's already here. So but
there are other links. So the problem is
you want to write a command you want to
be able to know like which links are
duplicated. Okay. So let's close that.
Reopen it. So we get rid of the color.
And now so now let's
um I already have that command. So let
me let me call it. Okay. So I press the
key. You can see in a ping window site
HTML show duplicate links. So it reports
it makes a report or these links are
duplicated. Uh and but close that it
actually highlight the duplicate links.
So you see they become red. So that
means
this this uh file is
duplicated oh twice then another time
there. So it's actually appears three
times. So but but there's a problem. So
So let me show you the source code.
Okay. Press uh Okay, hold on a second.
Um shrink the window. Press press uh
wait. Describe key. Press press. And
here is a command HTML show duplicate
links. Let's go to the source code. So
there is a source code. You can see copy
it. New buffer. Paste it. Go to the top.
Uh make it emac this mod. So you got
syntax coloring. Okay. You need to
um anyway. So so you can see. So here's
a command 50 lines of
code. So you I so I need to modify this
command. So it will uh let's see close
close go to talk show. So it will
highlight all links that are repeated.
Right now it doesn't do the job because
for example because because this one
search for
it, you know, it does not highlight the
first occurrence. It only highlight the
repetition. So copy that.
Um let's highlight it yellow. Okay. So
you can see that's the first occurrence.
Then the second occurrence is here.
uh you see so I want to make the command
to
highlight all links that has repetition
so let's write that okay that's what
we're going to do let's write that
command if you ask here say hi of the uh
you emac uh
lovers shall we do it from scratch or
shall we um just modify I think let's do
it in from scratch Okay. So, but let me
explain why this is tricky. I mean this
is not simple as simple as as it seems.
Okay. Because when you have a link uh
let's see where is the the nature of
Unix philosophy. when you have a link
you see some of the
link I mean it's not simply just
checking the duplication of the value of
href because it depends on where the
file located the file if the file is
located in a different
directory then the path will contain you
know dot dot slash things like that so
you cannot simply just check a
repetition of the of the value of
href. So
instead what you have to do is that you
go you know search from the beginning of
the file for each
href
occurrence you want to take the value
then generate the full file path for
this
file. Okay. So for example, open that,
copy the file path, close it, and let's
uh paste it here. So here that that's
the full uh file path, absolute path for
these. So for so you do this for all
h values then you can see which one um
they actually repeat. You cannot just go
by the file name because then different
directory may have the same file name
but they actually are different
articles.
Okay. So, let's write that command. Uh,
shall we do from scratch, you know? So,
this is the current command. Let's look
over it. Comments. Okay. Juang. Is it
bad for a woman for a woman to marry
someone younger?
No. Uh, my parents keep saying that my
girlfriend is too old.
That's well I you know that's your
personal problem. There's no absolute
answer.
Okay. And so there are there are se
there are two issues. One is the age
difference of a man and woman for
marriage. Um you know and that's one
issue. The other issue is your parents
opinion versus your opinion on marriage.
Okay, so these are two kind of complex
social issues and there's no right
answer to that. Okay, so first of all
the age difference between male and
female in marriage.
uh and you know so again it's a complex
issue that also depends on your cultural
background and also depends on your
personal situation. For example,
typically if if the man is wealthy,
powerful and
wealthy then you know young girls will
just marry you. Okay. Um you know that
like so this is about the willingness of
the partners partnership you know if you
are a powerful rich man even if you are
60 years
old young girls they just you know they
are attracted to you okay you know you
can say they are attracted to your money
but you know but in general you know
they always are attracted to powerful
men. Uh so then there's cultural norms.
So depending on the era, depending on
the location, which country, if you are
in western European tradition and
there's also differences or if you are
in Russia, if you are in China, Japan uh
or South Asia or if you are in Islamic
countries, the cultural
um preferences is different. Okay. So
for example in America right now and
also it depends on time right now at
this decade in USA America for example
the cultural situation is that if you
are too old you know you know if the age
gap is too large then they don't you
know they don't you know the US
Americans culture they think it's a
problem it's like oh no you cannot do
that okay that's the current US American
uh euro European
American cultural
norm but not Asia not Asia and I don't
suppose not in other other uh uh
countries anyway so there's personal
situation personal preference there's
cultural issues and uh then there is um
am I digressing too much we supposed to
do EMAC list okay we'll get get back so
Yeah. So, we were talking
about marriage between older man and
younger woman. Okay. Now, what about if
the woman is older, the guy is young,
let's say the guy is your age, let's say
20 something, and the women let's say 30
or even
40. Now typically that doesn't usually
happen because for women for thousands
millions of years they need to be young
in order to have children. When they are
past 30
uh the chances of having healthy
children is become very slim. When they
are 40 they cannot have children. So so
by the this is so this involves
biology. So
typically for humanity for human animals
in past million years it doesn't happen
you know it typically doesn't happen
when women is like older than 30
marrying a young man. Okay. But it it
you know so that's like biology and
that's in every culture.
Uh so but what about slightly age
different you know like if the women is
let's say 30 but not normal and you are
um what what do the specific American
culture think about that well they I
don't think they mind you know so again
so we are talking about culture so
American
like I don't think
they mind too much the European uh
culture. Uh for Asia, they don't I don't
think they care too much. Chinese,
Japanese, Korean, for example. Um for
Islamic countries, I don't uh I'm I'm
not so sure. Okay. I don't think they I
I mean this situation don't usually
happen. Usually the younger girls marry
older men. Okay. That's
more that's more common. and so and
normal because of biology. Okay. Because
the man needs to be you know to be able
to provide for the women
typically. Okay. So, so involving many
issues then there's a issue about your
parents opinion versus your opinion
regarding your marriage. That again
depends on lots of
things depending your specific family
situation. Uh for example, you know, how
how well you get along with your
parents, how they you know, do you
usually listen to your
parents? You know, that's one thing. The
other thing is uh for
example uh and you know if you are not
very close your with your parents then
obviously your parents opinion on this
usually doesn't matter much. So
depending on your bound with your
parents and that is different from for
each family. You know, if you usually
have a good family, then you know, you
care for each
other. Then typically when your parents
give you some advice, they really care
about that, you know, you shouldn't
marry this girl because she's like uh
you know, a bit too
old, you know. Then then you don't then
you might listen because um you always
listen to your parents because you look,
you know, you you have you know, you
kept on good communication and so on.
You know again that depends on so many
things. Then and another thing is
another issue is like how much do you
really care about this girl? How long do
you know her and you know things like
that. So it's uh there's no absolute
answer. So let's get back to uh emac
coding.
Okay. Thank you for the
digression. Okay. So we uh so yeah so
let's get back to eac list coding. So
yeah. So we so we already have this
command that show duplicate links and uh
the question is do you want do we want
to write it from scratch or do we just
modify
this? Am I doing good? Am I doing
good? Keep keep saying things. Okay. So
we
um so algorithm so I uh detail algorithm
find find each link then for each
extract the link. If it is local then
expand to file absolute path. Okay.
Check if the path is in hash table. If
so highlight the link else add to hasht.
Okay. Repeat to Yeah. So this this code
already works except it does not
highlight the first
link that has
repetition. So we can Yeah. Okay. So
it's quite a few code. So actually so
let's write a new one. Okay. So let's uh
I mean let's modify this code. Okay. So
let's just name this
um create a new file. So we're going to
modify this code.
Okay. Highlight and print any duplicate
links in current HTML file. Also push
mark at each uh each of the duplicate
link. Okay. Also
uh push mark at each of the duplicate
link position position. So you can
universal argument set command set mod
command to jump to it. Okay, that's a
feature I forgot about. So it also do
that. Basically that means it lets
you easily jump to the duplicate
location. So let's try again. Okay,
close it. Reopen it. That's this file.
So you got several duplicate links
there. So you call the command. Okay,
that shows the report of the duplicate.
You ignore that. Then then you'll see
the red lines. That means this link is
duplicated.
Okay. Then you can uh it set several
marks so you can jump to it. So let's do
so press. So then okay duplicate you
know you just press press
press. Okay. Yeah it just all the
duplicate appears in this in this
section. Okay.
[Music]
So okay. So go back to the code.
So today's
state version okay so let's say so
initial um local variables begin end
xlink duplicate list uh link
table okay that's a hash table make a
hash table okay then set beginning end.
So if region active just do the region
otherwise do from beginning buffer
beginning to buffer end the whole buffer
okay that's a beginning end so then you
narrow to the region like you limit the
buffer to just that beginning end okay
then
algorithm so find each link then for
each extract the
link if it slow code then expand to file
absolute path. Check if the file path is
in hasht.
Okay.
Um if so highlight link else add to hash
table. Okay. So the problem here is that
it does not highlight the first one.
So how do you uh how do you want to fix
this?
Check if the file path is in the is in
hasht. Okay.
So okay. So well let's look at the code
first. Okay. So then you go to char. So
the code is not too
long. Then you just go to the beginning
of the position. Then start to search
forward for
href. Then declare some variables. X
beginning 88. Uh that's you know
that's my convention. So let's rename
888 is just a random number. Okay. So
let's just show it to eight.
Okay. So boundary beginning end. So what
is this beginning end? Uh so begin from
the beginning start to search for it.
Boundary is the uh oh okay bound of the
thing. Okay that's annoying. That's the
that's so you search for href.
Then this boundary is a con pair of the
beginning and end of the file name.
Okay, the hf value. Okay, then you set
the beginning and you set the end. So
let's improve this little code by using
um sequence set.
Okay. List
car. Okay. These two lines is
equivalent.
This is better because you are setting
beginning end in one shot. It's a little
bit slower slower few microsconds but
anyway let's don't let's just clean
up. So you got the beginning end of the
file
path. So let's let's rename. Okay.
Uh okay. So
that's X file
path begin. Okay. Let's rename it. And X
end 8
is okay. So now color it, save it, close
it, reopen it, make a backup, color
that, color that. Okay. So now you got
beginning end of the file path. Then h
value is you extract it. Okay.
uh then the link
is so if it begin with
HTTP then just remain that otherwise you
make it otherwise it's a local file path
you expand it to the full path okay that
is the link
okay then if then you check if it's in a
hash okay so now this is beginning to
Check the hash table. Check the hash
table if it's in. If
so, you push
it to the hash table. So the hash table
will
contain all the duplicate links but
except the first one. So if a link has
you know repeated you know like if a
link appears three times the hash table
will contain the you know the second and
third occurrence but not the first. Okay
that we need to
fix.
So, okay. So, so then overlaid what this
does is it this
overlay means highlighted. Okay. Uh for
example, uh let's
see. You know, it's basically
highlighted red. Okay. That's what this
overlay does. Face
Font lock warning face. That's the
That's what kind of color you
want. Then um XL begin. Now what is XL
begin?
What? Oh, that's a new local
variable. Excel begin. So that's the
beginning of
line. Push vector buffer substring no
properties. Exhale begin. Exhale
end. Oh, line begin. Line end. So line
begin, line end. You push
it line beginning position, line end
position,
you you push it to the duplicate list.
Okay. Okay. So this is for printing out
the final result the
line. Okay then
you okay so if but if it's not in the
hash table you push it to the hash
table.
Okay then you just print the output make
a report. Okay so now we understand the
algorithm.
Let's Yeah. So now we understand the
algorithm. The important part is the
adding to the hash table. Okay.
So am I doing good? Okay.
So the important part is a hash table.
Okay. So
let's Okay. So let's get to code.
hasht. So whenever you find a link, why
don't we add to the hash table
directly? Yeah, let's let's just add add
to the hash table directly.
Okay, make a
backup. So for each
link, just add to the hash table.
Okay. So, so go to the file for each hf
value add to the hash table. So, so the
the key would
be the
key would should the key be the href
value raw or should it be like expanded
absolute file
path? Okay. Uh, I'm a bit
unfocused. Yeah, let let me just code
this myself. I don't think you
guys I don't think you guys are actually
care. Uh, okay. So, let me just code
it. So, the hash table. So, what the
question now is what should the key of
the hash table be? There can be one
first choice is the row value of the
um the row value of the
href. Okay, that's
one
way.
Um no that's that would not be good. The
other the other solution is I mean the
other choice is that the hash table key
should be the expanded version of the
file
path. That would be better
because that is how you find
duplicate. You need to rely on hasht to
be able to remove
duplicate because hasht can determine if
a key already exist. Okay. So, okay, you
build a hash table. The key should be
the expanded version of
that. Uh, and what about the value? The
value would
be what what should be the value be? The
value would be the beginning
position of the file path and the end
position of the file
path. That's one thing. A list. Okay. So
the value will be a
list. Okay. And each element is a
beginning position and end position a
pair let's say vector. Okay.
Then when you want to find the
duplicate, you
just go through the hash
table, find
any keys value that has length more than
one.
Okay. Yeah, let's do that.
Okay. So, um
So uh add to hash table if it if already
exist add to the value of that key.
Okay, this is the key for hash table.
Okay, add that to hash table. If if key
already exist,
uh add to the value of the key.
The value of hash
table is a list
of of
vectors begin position
uh and
end. Okay.
Position begin, position
end where the position is
the hf
value string.
Okay. Um Okay.
Then so you create this in you know big
giant hash table
then okay you build this hash table
first.
Okay.
Now find the
duplicate algorithm. Okay. The duplicate
algorithm would
be go through hash
table. If a value has a list of length
more than
one, it means that key has
duplicate. That
key it means that link is repeated.
Okay. Okay.
Then for each of those highlight
them by the
beginning and positions in the value.
Okay. Then that's
it. Okay. So uh then
yeah. Okay. So this way this way we
build the entire hash table first then
we go through the hash table to find
which one is repeated then we do
highlight. So this algorithm is slightly
different from our original which
is which is as as soon as you find a
duplicate then you highlight you know.
Okay. So let's do it remove that. Let's
uh rewoke this code.
This is annoying. This thing this
boundary that's let's you know this this
thing at point is very annoying because
it doesn't this this thing at point
library is kind of annoying because it
doesn't allow you to do functional
programming. Um but let's make it as
much as functional programming as
possible because right now you need this
boundary because this boundary thing at
point of the file
name it returns the beginning position
you know if your cuser is here it
returns the beginning and end position
of you know of of of the current file
path.
Okay. Um so it returned that in a in a
conspair. So then you need to so you
need this temporary variable boundary.
Then you extract the boundary like this
you know beginning and end um equals to
car and
cutter. So this boundary is just a
temporary variable. Uh I don't want
that. Okay.
So okay let's let's uh let's you know
let's remove it. Okay so where is it
used one two three four just these four
places. Okay, let's remove them. Let's
refactor our code. Remove that. And uh
let a local variable here and here will
be
xboundary. Okay. Then we move this thing
inside X boundary. Set we don't. Okay.
So set that set that boundary
and this move that inside there.
Prettify the code. Fantastic. Now it's
localized. This boundary thing is
localized. So get the boundary because
we we don't care the boundary. We don't
we really care about the beginning end.
Okay.
Uh okay. So we got that. Then next set h
value. Okay.
Then set the link. Okay, we need
that. Set the
link.
Um, so what are you guys saying?
Hello, Mr. Ka. You should do travel
vlogs.
No, because I don't travel. I don't have
money.
Uh
Hamza Clown says, "You use EVO mod or
how do you navigate that
fast?" Uh I guess you are new. I talked
about this all the time. I I'm using
Softly Keys. So if you if you check out
my today's talk from the beginning, you
can see introduction. There's a video
about it. It's more efficient than Vim.
Okay. Softly keys. you know, I've been
demonstrating it in the past three
years, so you probably new here. So
anyway, and and you know, besides Softly
Keys, so for example, Softly Keys,
here's a source code for,000 lines, and
it's on GitHub. You can grab it, you
know, just search for Softly Keys
GitHub, you'll find it. Okay, the GitHub
link is here and there's a video
tutorial and there's a full you know
explanation uh install um you know I'm
also using Kasawa Emac this mod so uh
describe key press so Emac this mod
because I've been coding in Emacs for
like 20 years so I
use you know basically everything I do
is my own code
uh like I rarely I like basically don't
use any other people's package.
Okay. So anyway, let's get back to this.
Okay. So we we so we are uh going
through the hasht algorithm. So you get
a link. Okay. So you get a link. Um then
okay the link is the absolute file name
of the local file path then check if
it's in the hash
table. In fact we don't have to check
always add to the hash table.
Okay. Um in
fact you see if you always add to the
hash table you
see check for it's existing hash table
if you add it to the hash table then but
later on you got a
problem. Uh, wait. So, check if it's in
a hash table. If it is in a hash
table, push mark. Okay. So, push
mark. Uh, you don't care about the mark.
Okay. Don't push
mark for now. We don't care about that.
And overlay, that's making it highlight.
You know overlay is a mechanism to
highlight some part of the text
temporarily.
So we don't care for now. Okay. Remove
it. Simplify the code. Then this is line
beginning, line end. Line beginning and
line end. For now we don't care.
Okay. Line beginning position and line
end position. For now we don't care.
Okay, let's remove it. Okay, so this is
a local variable. Let's
see. Let's highlight it. Okay.
So, so if the hash key
exist so if it exist Yeah. So you need
to do something.
Okay. So if the hash key already
exist, you push
it to the hash table.
Okay. Put the link in the hash table.
Okay. Then the value would be the
beginning and end position. Yeah, that's
the difference. So the value would be
file path begin and file path end.
Okay. So it will be a vector because
vector is a fixed size. A vector in eac
bisp is a a fixed size array much like
python's turbo. Okay. So vector begin
and position actually uh so if it
already
exist you want
to yeah okay so wait okay so let's make
a local variable
[Music]
uh x
exist
Um, right. So, hold on a second.
So, okay. So, x exist. Let's make
it that's the value of the get hash.
Okay, let's just result. Okay, get hash
result. So, set that result.
If the result is true that means this
already exist in the hash
table
then okay then something if it doesn't
exist you push it
uh and this should be a
list of
pairs. Yeah the list a list of beginning
end positions and here's the first one.
Okay. Now, but if this is if it doesn't
exist, if it already
exist,
you want to push
it. Okay, you want to push that link to
a existing
item. So, this part would be this part
would be X result.
Um this part would be
actually cons that's how you
construct here's the result you add that
to that okay so that's how you do
it. So if the hash table if the key
already exists in hasht that's the
result then
you add
um yeah you add the same key the link
already exist you add it but the value
would
be the previous value plus the new
um vector the the beginning end
position. Okay, that's
correct. I think that's correct. So, so
far so good. Yes. Then the output.
Um, so now here is
the make a report part. Uh, make a
report
part. And do we have duplicate list? Did
we remove it? Yes, we did. Okay.
So make a report. Uh for now we don't
care. Okay. So delete
duplicate. Okay. So make report. Let's
say we don't
care.
Okay. But anyway, now we got a hash
table. Now
um now we can print the hash table.
Let's just say print hash table and the
hasht
uh what xlinks table. Okay, x links
table and
just result is something like that.
Okay, purify the code. Evaluate the
buffer. Make a backup. Go to the
directory. Delete all the backup.
Delete. And by compile. Wait, wait.
Rename the file. So there's no space in
it. Do it. Now backup. Now by compile.
Yes, there is a problem. Warning. File
has no lexical binding. Annoying. Okay,
so open it. add a lexical binding X UTF.
That's my abbreviation. Abbreviation is
the most useful thing in EMAC. If you
don't already, search my Exac tutorial.
You'll see. Okay. So, you know, this is
the static declaration. It makes it
lexical binding. Uh, so it's better
code. They added that about 10 years
ago. It's a hack. It's, you know. So
anyway, now back up by compile again.
This time no error. Open the bite
compiled file. Delete it. We don't need
it.
Okay. So now this code works. It just
prints hasht result. Okay. Now go back.
So let's look. Let's go back to this
file. Close it. Reopen it. So there's no
highlight. Now uh now call the
command. Fantastic. So let's go to the
messages buffer. So you can see here is
our result. Open a new buffer. Let's
clarify. Okay. So let's see how do we
clarify this. So for each saw web let's
make a new line.
Okay. So you can see this is a hash
table each entry. So this this file path
only got one
occurrence. Uh and this
HTTP wait so HTTP also we need to make a
new
line. Okay. So this this link only occur
once. It's a position it
occurs. But this
link do Unix to do one thing. Well,
occurs a few times. That's a beginning
position. That's a be and that's the
other one. Okay. So, we got the hash
table. It's all good. So far so good.
Now, we just need to go through the hash
table. for each one. If the values
length is more than one, that means it's
duplicate. Then just highlight each one
of them.
Okay, good. Okay, close it. Close
it. Go back here. Let's uh write out
what we going to do
now. Go through hash table.
If a keys
value as length two or
more highlight it in buffer okay
fantastic and
beautiful okay let's go through the hash
table so how do you go through the hash
table well you
got hashmap
map I believe no uh map
hash there it is fantastic beautiful
so if you don't know you know again I
have a emacisp tutorial from the ground
up you can see just search for kasar e
emacisp tutorial on kasari.info info and
uh you got strings, number, buffer,
boolean, variable, uh condition, loop,
list, data structure. Then you got
sequence, special list, list list
structure, vector, sequence, then you
got hash table. So here is a groundup
tutorial on hash table. Okay, so now we
want to go through the hash table. You
do map hash and the table would
be xlink table. Okay. Then lambda key
and value. Okay. So what is the body?
Well, the body let's predify the body
would
be if uh wait
what
okay
if length
uh uh if length of the value is greater
than one.
Okay.
If let's just say equal
XV length of the value is just one then
do nothing
uh then just do nothing. Okay otherwise
that means it's duplicate
otherwise otherwise let's create a local
variable. Okay. So local variable
uh x sorted. Okay. X sorted will
be sort
uh sort XV actually
uh sort in eacisp is kind of complicated
but there's a new version that fixed it.
Okay. So let's go back to eac list
basics. Let's go to
list list data structure. Let's click on
list. Okay. Uh then you need to sort it.
Let's see where is it? List vector uh
vector sequence hasht list iteration. Uh
convert where do I find sort create get
elements modify list list iteration
check element
exist sequence join convert a where
is it sort let's go to sequence
type okay sequence type then for each
sum every filter sort reverse there okay
so this sort because list and vector and
it's stable. They by the way they in the
past uh three years also they fixed it
before it was not stable. Okay. So
return sorted sequence original not
changed. Yeah they fixed it you know few
years ago three years ago it was
destructive. So when you sort a list the
original list variable is like destroyed
and also it's not stable. So they fixed
that since Emacs 30. Oh, they they just
fixed it uh this
year. Yeah. To you know to uh so yeah
2025. Yeah. Fantastic. So yeah. So can
we use sort? Yes. Sort then uh by
default. Okay. So, and they added these
uh
key
arguments function to function. Okay.
Um, okay. So, I know what to do.
So
sort you want to sort the you want to
sort the value which is a list
of pairs. Each pair is beginning
position and end position. You want to
sort them by the beginning position
because you want to highlight the first
occurrence will have a different color
than the rest repetitions. Okay?
So that's why you want to sort you want
you want to know which one is come
first. So you sort it and by what
function by the function will
be lambda. Of course the lambda will
take two uh wait the the key extraction
function. Okay. So actually it should
be oh so I need to uh update my
template. Okay. Let's do that.
Go to emac this smart kas emac this
smart search for sort okay so there is
the abbreviation template for sort now
it's updated so this part should be
key and uh key something lambda okay
uh let's let's name that EP. Okay. Key
uh key wait the key just extract the
key. Okay. So that is our new
um template for sort. So evaluate the
buffer. Make a backup. Go back. Now
let's try sort again.
Sort. Okay. Didn't work. Save it. Close
it. Reopen it. Sort.
Fantastic and
beautiful. Okay, we got the sort. So,
let's you know, so here's a new sort and
the sort the sequence is XV and remove
that. So, the key this extract the
[Music]
key. So, how do you extract it? Because
it's a pair, it's a vector pair. So, a
ref that's how you extract the elements
in a array. So the array is xv uh wait
the array is xx index zero. So that's
the beginning position.
Okay. Purify the
code. Okay.
So if the length is one ignored
otherwise sorted then what you do then
highlight. Now remember now we need to
highlight. Okay. Now let's see where is
our highlight code.
Um, show duplicate links. Yes, this is
our old
code. Highlight would
be this. This. And let's push mark two.
So, copy that. Close it.
Actually, go back to our code. Here is
what we want to do.
So first of
all, so okay. So, so this is highlight.
Um, okay. So
wait. Okay, let's put them in a program.
Organize them. So we have the sorted
key. So this is a
list and each element is a vector of two
things beginning and end
position. Okay. So you want to go
through this list. Okay. So that would
be map C. Go through this list. So for
each so go through the
list. Okay. and the sequence is exorted.
Okay, what to do with it? Well, for each
element you
um for each
element well depending on the first or
last. So for so you
um yeah the first one you it will be
different. So you need to pop
it. Pop the first one. Okay. So pop get
the first element. Pop X sorted. Okay.
So okay. So let another
um let's say
first. Okay. First
pair. Okay. So the first would be pop it
out. That's the first
occurrence. Okay. Then you say
highlight. So you got to put this
code. Okay.
So,
so push
mark push mark
uh
reference of the you know get the first
element of
the
what index the first element of array
and the array is the first. Okay. So you
mark the beginning
position of the link. Okay, that's one
thing. Then you highlight it. You
highlight it
by Okay, so you highlight by the
beginning and position that would
be zero and one.
Okay, you know we can Okay. Anyway,
so make
overlay. Okay. Beginning and position
and uh you highlight red a warning face.
Okay. So that you don't care clarify. So
let's make it another
um that's fine. Okay. So get the first
occurrence, the first pair.
you highlight the beginning and end
position.
Okay. Okay. Then you then then for the
rest of the
uh occurrence of the links you highlight
them with a different
color. Okay. So for the rest of
them you Okay.
So you also need to push mark. Okay. So
let's copy this. So for the rest of them
you do that. Okay. So the for the rest
of them
you do you need to
sort. Uh for the rest of
them push
mark for the rest of them you map to the
sorted
uh push mark the first and overlay.
That's
right. So the first um the first color
let's use the highlight color. So let's
uh display phone lock um let's
say font
lock font face
uh okay display face
uh where is
list faces. Okay, list faces display. So
this command list faces display lets you
see all the
predefined like faces meaning the font
and
color. So we want yellow. we we kind of
want
um you know so let's use
something okay diff we don't I don't
want to use the package in diff okay
okay so we want uh you know high yellow
okay let's just use that high yellow so
high yellow means the first
occurrence then the rest occurrence
would be let's see high
yellow and high salmon. Okay. Wait, high
yellow and high
pink. Wait. High yellow and high
green. So many choices. Okay. That's
high yellow and high green.
Okay. High yellow and
high
green. Okay. Close that. So this would
be the first one is high yellow. Then
the second one is high green. Now is
this a variable or just a symbol? Let's
check. Uh describe variable and type it.
No. Okay. So it's not a variable, it's a
symbol. So you need to have a quote
there. Okay. So I think actually we are
done. Okay. So double check.
So now go through hash table. If a keys
value has linked two or more highlight
it in buffer and also mark
it.
So map hash you know we go through the
link hash table hash table of links.
Okay. And what you do is
you so this is lambda function. And
it's, you know, this annoying
indentation, you know, I wanted to make
the indentation just one space, but in
EMAC it's not, you know, it's it it's
it's not so trivial and also it went
against the EMAC this code format
convention. So anyway, so map hash the
lambda function do this. So
if
the value is just one ignore it you know
so this is new
otherwise otherwise you sort the hash
table
first I mean sort the list of beginning
and position first you pop the first
out. Then you push mark the beginning
position in
buffer. Then you
um let's ignore push mark. Okay. It's
let's it's not just
um
okay and also this this overlay. Let's
make it simpler.
Okay. Make it simpler. And uh you don't
need these
lips. Color the first one yellow. Color
the rest occurrence
green. Okay. Uh remove
that. Okay. So here's our
code. I think that works.
And we don't need this message. Okay. So
this message will be just
say
done. Okay.
Now make a backup. Go to the directory
by compile it
problem and use lexical argument xx. So
we are not using the
key map to the key value pair. Are we
using the
key? Well the key well right now we are
not. So let's use underscore because
that's a convention. If you don't use
the variable you you know name the
variable
underscore. That's just a convention. So
okay and use lexical variable. We fix
that and use lex equal variable x. Where
does that
x? Oh, x.
Oh, so this is curling coloring the
rest. Okay. Oh, yeah. So, yeah. So, this
needs
Okay. Okay. Back up color first
occurrence.
Yep. By compile it. No. No arrow.
Fantastic. Delete the bite compile file.
Fantastic. Evaluate it. Now go back. Now
let's test it. Show in browser. You can
see many duplicate links there. Okay.
Now let's call the command. Press press
press. Beautiful.
Fantastic. This is the power of oneshot
coding.
So the yellow lines
means they are repeated but each one
each yellow is first
occurrence. The green ones also means
they are repeated but they are like the
second or third or fourth you know the
rest of
occurrence. So showing
browser. So you see now I can properly
you know now I know which link to remove
because this topic
box you see this repetition in the topic
box that's more important you know this
is the all related topics about this
Unix sucks topics while the the C
also you know this see also is like re
related links they are secondary
importance
So if a link is repeated in the C also
and in the Unix you know and in the
topic box the topic box once remain okay
so that means for example Unix for
example this link let's see where it
occurs so it occurs here you know you
know it occurs
twice so the rel you know Unix
uh Unix file system case sensitivity
extreme idiocy you know the Unix crimes
anyway so this means this one must go so
anyway now what I can do is that I can
show you okay so if it's yellow delete
it so it's all yellow here delete delete
delete delete you know I don't need the
whole like like I can just do that okay
then go up here it's all yellow that
means it's all repeated here so that in
fact I can just re uh delete the entire
related box. Okay. Showing browser now
go down.
Fantastic. So now actually so so this
beautiful we did what we wanted. So now
I mean you know my job is done for for
today for this talk show. But you know
for me I need to go through each one one
of these and do the same thing. Of
course, then I can write the new Emacs
command to automate. So you see on this
page Unix pipe as functional programming
language, it details the
extreme idiocy, the incompetence of the
Unix, their design of the pipe syntax.
The pipe syntax is actually fantastic
because it came from functional
programming languages.
uh the creator of the guy Alfred
Aaho who is creator of Oc you know one
of the Unix tool major you know 30 40
years
ago critical and also he's the you know
co co-author of the dragon book the most
famous compiler book okay the classic
comp compiler book so this guy Alfred oh
a ho
He says you know doing a interview you
know these days you know many many of
these blogs are guns so so it's in in
this book okay so anyway it's in this
book masterminds of programming
conversation with the creators of major
programming languages okay so this guy
is the creator of the orc programming
language and he says you know someone
asked him is the you know the where does
the idea of the Unix pipe came from and
he says it came from functional
programming mathematics
okay but when you know so that's my you
know that's what you know so in the
1990s when I started to learn Unix I see
it right away but but when I talk to the
Unix people they they don't know they
don't understand what I you are talking
about you know functional programming
like what the They don't know. So,
but eventually until 2009, I found this
article, this
book, the guy himself said as so, you
know, it came from functional
programming because it allows function
composition.
Okay. So, so, so this article, you know,
I wanted to show the extreme
incompetence and ignorance of the Unix
code. Today it's known as Linu Linux.
Okay, this this this whole code filled
with lies and they don't know you know
they just say oh we don't know but you
know but they don't know not a thing
anyway that's a history that's the
origin that's how the Unix pipe idea
came from okay from functional
programming function composition okay
from the
creator Alfred AO who said
it and Now, but then I discuss how the
Unix it up entirely. Okay, here's
some detail like the Unix pipe, you
know, it up entirely. Unix is the
most
incompetent no
design and filled with lies. Okay, they
call it Unix philosophy and all that.
Any anyway so that's my this so this is
my se you know series of articles on the
Unix
crime as a as a joke you know crime but
the but but more realistically it's my
documentation of the damage that the
Unix operating system Unix and C has
done to computing industry
okay so in this page for example let's
copy copy Copy
it. Copy the file path. Open it here.
Unix pipe as functional language. Now go
to the bottom. Go to the bottom. You can
see there's a bunch of links. So here is
a topics link and here is related links.
Topics link. Topics link. Okay. Now
let's call the command. Let's see which
one is
repeated.
Uh press press.
Fantastic. So you can see this related
box. This the nature of Unix philosophy.
This one can go. Okay. Did okay. But
this one is not repeated. This is lisp
syntax problem of piping functions.
Okay. That's a different issue. That's
about lisp and that's that's a problem
of lisp because in lisp common lisp and
eac lisp you don't have the pipe
operator. You don't have the pipe. You
need it. you really want it need it but
lisp doesn't have it okay but in closure
lisp they do so they closure in many
ways fixed many of list fundamental
problems okay the pipe function you know
function of programming pipe it's the
most greatest idea okay
um and you can see there's a repetition
here this is the first occurrence I
don't care because the topic box so show
in browser go to the bottom the topic
box each one is like independent. So
even though this is repeated several
three times
uh but however they um they are in
different topics for for example this
sequence of articles is about Unix pipe
okay and dot notation and postfix
notation. So the dot notation for
example you can commonly commonly seen
in Ruby and in JavaScript you know very
convenient you know something dot
something that's related to the postfix
notation and Unix pipe. So these are all
related topics. Then you know this box
is all related about Unix shell for
example. Why bash sucks.
Okay. Why is it related to pipe? Because
you know pipe is part of the like
fundamental syntax in
bash. And this sequence is about why
Unix sucks. Okay. So, so for example,
you have
X11, you know, X11 Windows
disaster. This is one of the most uh
well-known article in 1990s and in 2000s
and today they are
desperately trying to fix it by by the
by the new Windows manager, you know,
what's the name? you know, they've been
trying it to fix it for 30 years, but
the Linux but the Unix refuse,
you know, for 30 years for for like 30
years, they refuse to
acknowledge that the the Unix X11 system
is the worst possible. They lie.
Okay, they blatant blatantly lie the
Unix for 30 years in n you
know since I know about it in 1990s. So
this article is written in 1994 by Don
Hopkins is like a well-known figure in
in Unix and in lispu community and also
he's the I think original creator of the
pie chart menu which is about user
interface you know like like today
mostly we have
this you know uh linear menu but there's
also pie chart menu used in second life
for example and other basis. So he's a
like origin creator or something.
Anyway, Don Hopkins, he's well known in
this community and Unix
um because this article is one chapter
of the
Unix haters handbook. Okay, the this
well-known Unix haters handbook in
1994. Okay, uni. So this
this so this is the beginning
documentation of the
extreme lies and incompetence of Unix.
Okay. Like
extreme then X11 is part of it. Uh and
Don Hoping is well known in lisp
community. He's also a programmer in
wuam language. Okay. he ported the sim
city's game to uh
Unix. Okay. So anyway, so don't you know
so so anyway that's it for today. Okay.
So if you like So by the way this
picture, this photo is from Hang. Thank
you,
Hang. Uh where is Hang is where is uh
Where is my window?
Uh, okay. So, you need to move that
there. So, yeah, that picture, this
photo is from Huang. Thank you,
Huang. Okay, so that's it. If you liked
my stuff, go to my website,
okay?info, and go all the way to the
bottom. You can see uh PayPal me, okay?
PayPal, Amazon gift card me, PayPal me
100 bucks. Thank you. And uh you know if
you well just pay me, okay? So but also
you can like uh post my link to your
blog to your Twitter uh spread it. Okay,
that would
help. Wayland. Yeah, that's the word,
you know. So Wayland began about like 10
years ago but even you know like 30
years ago 30 years ago people already
know this this article X11 disaster is
well known like every Unix users read it
okay or seen it heard of it in
1990s but the Unix people they lie you
know they they lie all the time they you
know they they
they you know it's like It's not a
malicious lie but it's a lie from the
code created nature of Unix because Unix
people they love it. Oh, Unix
philosophy. Oh, we most powerful. We are
the most powerful operating system.
Look, you know, blah blah blah. So they
lie because not not malicious
intentional lie but they lie because
they have a code. Everyone just see the
you know good point about Unix. So they
tell each other Unix you know small is
powerful. Look at the Unix you know
shell command line pipe. Oh we are great
you know. So they create you know. So
they they lied for 30 years. This is
well known and people have been trying
their projects. Okay. They try to redo
the X11. In fact, there's already a
better one called uh by some micros
systems Solaris X. It's called uh new
Windows or something. I think it's
mentioned here or if you look at
Wikipedia, you'll find it. Okay.
Anyways, the Unix people lie, you know,
because then then after 20 years, you
know, the the project didn't go anywhere
because it's not easy to fix this
because if you create a new one, nobody
not going to use it because there's a
huge amount of backward compatibility
issue because every Unix operation
uh application in GUI, they rely on
this. So if you write a new one, you
have to make it kind of
uh em to you know backward compatible to
emulate the X11 somehow so that all the
existing thousands of graphical
applications can work in your new
Windows system. Right? So you have to do
that and that's not
trivial. So there's a lot of problems.
There's a lot issues you have to
overcome non-trivial issues in order to
fix this Unix problem. There's technical
issue you have to fix. Then there's a
backward compatib compatibility or
emulation issue you have to overcome.
Not easy. Then there's a social issue
because if you create a new one like
today's, you know, the Xway line, who's
going to use it? like you know people
like people there needs to be a strong
reason for people like going to switch
and kiss your ass. Okay. Either you have
like lots of money. If you are Google,
you can do it. You know, Google can
write a new wind, you know, if Google
can fix this problem overnight because
they are so, you know, so like too
powerful, you
know, but so you have lots of social
issues to overcome. But um then there's
a power struggle issue because the
unique standard just because you created
something new they going to they are not
going to adopt whatever you create you
know you see there's a social struggle
issue you need to have certain power you
need to get other you know people to
support you like you need to get HP
Solaris some micros systemystems or
Oracle or whatever or today's Red Hat or
whatever to sports support you then you
possibly can make this change. So it's
you know this is not easy change and
today we see that in wayand by the zuma
generation and and wayand today is going
through lots of troubles you know like
today's new things you know this got
trans they got they make dramas and then
you know lots of so anyway that's it for
Hey. Hello.
Mo from from Middle
East, expert in machine
learning. Uh, okay. Dragon Book is not
good.
Well, that's you know. So, Juan says
Dragon Book is not book is not good.
It's too much about pausing which is has
been researched to death already. No,
you are
incorrect because you are a zoomer. You
don't know. Okay. Dragon Book is the
classic V reference for compilers for
about 30 years. Okay. 30 years. There's
no other. So, I would say it's up to
date until I mean they they have a newer
version. Okay. Actually, do I have you
know I you know I I I read the dragon
book like 10 years ago. Uh is it
somewhere here? So, dragon book. Let's
talk about the dragon
book. Uh where is my uh
uh dragon book? Okay. So, where's the
dragon book? Yeah, that's in the that's
mentioned in the
um Okay. Unix philosophy. Show it. Uh
close it. Show this Unix pipe there.
Okay. So, Dragon Book. There it is. Open
it. Okay. So, this is classic for 30
years. There's no
better Alfred
AO. And there's a new version. Okay. The
new version's cover design is not good.
So here is the first version. Here's
second version. Here is the latest 2006.
I believe that's the latest. Okay. And
some of the author changed because you
know it's so old you know like that's
another topic. But you know when you
have a book when it became
classic and after 20 years usually the
original author is like very old you
know they cannot write anymore 70 years
old or they died they passed away but
for commercial reasons typically they
remain you know they they they came up
with a new edition with new authors but
often they don't mention sometimes they
don't mention the new author they just
say you
because they want be- because people are
familiar you know with the original
authors. They don't want to say oh but
the original author are too old or
passed away so there's a new edition by
new author. They don't want that. People
like don't want that. So when you know
so for marketing purposes usually they
keep the original author name but
actually the
book like like the new edition if they
change a lot of things the original
author has nothing to do with it and
sometimes the quality went down too in
in in in a lot of cases the quality you
know is just different. So anyway do
they have a new version? Um, no I don't
think so. But anyway, so for 30 years
this is classic. So last edition is
2006. Um, so
today today this is not the best
reference because today this tremendous
technology you know this is tremendous.
This beginning with Wikipedia for 20
years like before you don't have
Wikipedia. Today you can actually look
up like all the compiling parsing
subject in Wikipedia and it gives
tremendous detail. Okay, even far more
correct and correct than the books in
the
1990s. Okay, so so then today you have
like not just Wikipedia, you have AI AI
just can write a write a tutorial on
compilers on the fly and we it would be
99% correct. Okay. So to so so today
this book is not the best there's
another one u I believe Juan suggested
before I I was going to read it like
there's a like on GitHub writing a
compiler you know from ground up you
know creating a new language from the
ground up based on I think Goland or C I
mean Golan or Rust I forgot which but
you can easily find it you know like
just search for compiler book Okay.
how to write
um okay so today you know that dragon
book is not the best but um I believe
this
one writing a compiler part one so is
this the one I'm thinking anyway so
today you you know you got tons of
resources okay and you are saying you
know Jan is also saying it's not so good
it's too much about passing that's
totally incorrect Corct. Okay. Like you
don't know
incorrect. So passing about
passing. So let's go to the dragon book.
Passing there is the compiler book
doesn't cover much about passing at all
because when I read this book the one
thing I'm most interested is is passing
technology. Okay. And this compiler book
doesn't do a good job. Okay. It only got
like one chapter. Okay, like when uh
lexical analysis, syntax analysis,
syntax directive translate, it doesn't
even cover passing
much. If you want
passing, I can tell you which one is a
good book. Okay, passer. Okay, let's
see. Uh, Dragon Book Passer. Okay,
because I worked on passing for about a
year, but I'm not expert. Okay. But I
can tell you what is the the most
authorative
passing from the perspective of computer
science. Not just practical programming.
Okay. From the perspective of computer
science. This
book passing techniques a practical
guide by Dick Gron. He's also very old
like very very old. I I wrote him an
email about 10 years ago asking him
permission to publish his book on my
website in HTML form but I never did it.
Okay. But so this book is um the first I
think the first edition is free but the
second second edition is not but it's
like this book is like long and kind of
b it's kind of like very verbose.
But this is a book for passing. Okay. I
believe still so today. This is a
comprehensive reference on passes.
Everything you want to know about
passes, all the possible techniques.
Okay. And in terms of computer science,
not just in terms of like programmer's
perspective. Oh, how do you write a
puzzle in in Java or or
Rust? Okay. So, so
that bye
guys. We closed down. Uh, okay. We close
down in one
minute. So, let's start a new
EMAX and go to um I'm just shutting
down. Okay. So, go to this. So, what is
this pipe? Unix pipe functional
language. Copy that.
Bye bye
guys.
Uh change font size to 18 because
usually
the when I do live stream I have to
change it to to on my screen it's huge
but when you watch it on YouTube it's
small. So when you do live stream you
have to make it like
23.
Uh so close that. Wait open it. Copy the
file path. Go to talk show. So today's
talk show. Add the link
here. Add the links we talked about and
close that pink window. So Unix pipe.
Close that. Close that.
Show. Okay. Uh sort close that.
Reopen. Delete that. Save. Close. What
is this? Talk show. Okay. That's today.
What is this? Oh, this is our new
function. Oh, yeah. We need to put it
back. Wait. Uh, okay. Copy it. So, I'm
going to put to the talk show. So, you
guys can see the
code. Paste
it. Colorify it. So, here is what the
code today. Fantastic and beautiful. You
guys
probably don't need it because this is
very specific to my website.
So the code is good. Okay. Close it.
Close it. Close it. Bye guys.