good morning guys welcome to another
episode of star talk show
you are looking at me and alan captain
allen at the meta
one hacker way it's amazing
so we had me and alan a friend from
discord went to the facebook headquarter
and we see the meta
so
so so what topic are we gonna do today
um
so ahmed says powershell okay let's do
some powershell uh i i got some other
okay let's do powershell then so
today's 2022 january
12th
okay so let's go to today's talk show
let's go to uh let's do some power
shouting
okay uh today's talk show let's um
yeah let's focus on talk show and
there's another this um
well okay let's do uh powershot then
okay so let's go to notes
and uh
there's some powershell to do so
powershell write a
song named file to hash you know when
you have lots of files from the internet
especially image files you know they
usually have random names if you know if
you know what i'm talking about so
one of the great um you know they have
lunch bunch of random names so you so
one of the way to organize those
files especially duplicate image files
is to organize them to rename them so
their name is their hash value so that's
one of the things we can write
uh
so you guys post questions comments and
questions okay keep the chat going and
let me know which of the powershell you
like me to do so rename file to hash
rename file to their hash value that's
one thing we can
i can try to do
uh
and report file name length
okay that we can do as well
then
we play string so this is find and
replace in powershell actually this is
the one i'm more interested to do so
without any comments or
choices i'm i'm just going to do that
pause
find and replace
uh stream okay so let's go to talk show
today's talk show
powershell
find and by the way the pink window is
my emacs commands you can see all my
commands command calls
my keystrokes the keystrokes i typed all
the command names that corresponds to
the keystroke i'm using software keys
i'm using some flag keys this is a
source code 4000 lines of code and here
is the home page soft fly keys a
official emacs key system and i'm also
using vora keyboard
and you are looking at my keyboard
so for our keyboard if you don't know uh
this is like lottery you know
roulette
i'm using a vora keyboard so that's what
it means something like is
work layout fantastic
okay and of course you are looking at my
you are looking at my ergonomic keyboard
i have reviews by it
connects his advantage to an ultimate
ultimate hacking keyboard right here
okay
so without further ado so let's go back
so let's go to um
you know that was my keyboard blog
there's lots of things actually you know
use there's lots of topics you know i'm
gonna talk about
but um
powershell today okay
so go to talk show showing browser let's
type what we wanna do
write a powershell find
and replace script
okay
um
actually this um you know so yesterday
we did a talk show about
find and replace among different
languages yes
yesterday or the day before um and uh
this is a lot to do so let me show you
okay so powershell
finding script okay so let me show you
what's going on so go to replace so you
can see
in this directory
let's clean it up so in this directory
is all my find and replace scripts in
different languages
so let me turn on my cruiser position so
you can see where my cursor is
comments and questions okay
tag me
uh and i'm gonna get to them okay so you
have uh find and replacing golan in perl
in python and a regular expression
version in go in python and in wufang
language and in
and
and also um
and and in pearl okay golan
pearl python golan and powershell in
wufang language okay so
so i don't have one full powershell here
yet that's what we are going to do today
so when you write the find and replace
script there are two kind of two or
three types you know it's usually better
to separate them okay let me explain
them so one of them is find script okay
so one of them is find
so where's my talk show so
find script
you know you might be wondering why do
you want to why do you need to write a
find script because in bash you know
graph in unix script it's already there
and lots of variations you know there's
silver whatever there's you know over
the past 20 years lots of people have
written like faster parallel versions
so anyway but by default there's a great
what is already and on windows in
powershell it's very easily done so let
me
go to the powershell so you are looking
at the powershell
windows console
so in in this directory uh talk show
directory you can see now if i want to
find all
lines that contains the word haska for
example so i just say
the recurse
file
and include i want all files ending in
html
oh and
okay so then you want to select it you
want to find all the lines containing uh
haskell so how do you do that
you do
select i believe it's select string okay
select string
haska okay
do it okay so there it is that's all the
files you can see let me show you
highlight okay so
that's all the lines that contains the
word pascal highlighted and it also
shows you the file name in the in
beginning let me move it here so you can
see it shows the file name for example
let's look at this line
uh
okay this is
you know it shows the file name
the position the
occurrence position in that line and
this is the line and contains the word
has got so
the point is you already have grip on
unix you know by default on linux on the
mac and you already have powershell so
easy why do you need to write a find and
why do you need a script that
is dedicated to find strings
let me explain because i'm dissatisfied
i'm dissatisfied
with this graph or the powershell
version
there are many problems okay let me
explain okay so
let me write it down okay what is the
point of writing a
find script
when
there
is
already
unexcept and powershell
okay
why is that
okay let's uh
what is the point so let me explain
there are lots of problems with finding
grip so in order to explain that let's
just go to uh with my website study
problems of
gramp
problems of unix script just search for
it
i type a key and it automatic
automatically searches okay let me close
down this window
so you can see
the command i called is
look up
so let's widen it so
okay okay it doesn't
um
so anyway that's a that's command that's
all the commands you and keystrokes dd
by the way that dd key is right here
under my thumb
so
so you can see so i just search for
search for the for it
in emacs and here's a result
there it is problems of coding unix
script in emacs okay select copy
uh paste it here make a link delete that
remove that
so we have a record of what we talked
about okay so now the problems of coding
unix script in in emacs well not just in
e-max but the the unique script itself
have lots of problems
okay so what what's some of the problems
let me explain okay in well if you're
gonna do it in emacs there is the
external program problem because
if you are if you are running emacs in
windows you don't have grab installed
and emacs you know all the emac script
commands they rely on the unix script so
you have to install it then it's a
headache because they are you know how
you know today is much better but used
to be you have to install the
sick wing
okay today the young generation don't
know what i'm talking about so let me
let me just show my articles
one thing at a time and we are
digressing into lots of things
installing sequin tutorial
sig wing essential install list
sequin path and window path conventions
it's that's a major headache you know
the window path has a backslash although
it also supports the slash you know but
the sequin you know the path is a major
problem major headache when you
do lots of um
shell scripting you know it's a major
headache so it's a major headache when
you run
unique stuff on on on windows
that's before that's 1990s and 2000s but
of course today you have lots of you
have m cases
you have mk6 as a
as a bash in windows you have then you
have you know today the latest is the
windows linux subsystem in windows
so and you don't even that need that
today because the powershell came up
powershell is like powershell is pretty
old powershell began in 2003 also but
until 2008 it become
stable and very popular you know
powershell building so when i switched
to windows this year
you know last year
april or something i was thinking i'm
gonna you know i'm gonna either install
sequin or
or or let's try the you know windows
subsystem for linux but it turns out i
don't need it
why do i need linux i don't need the
[ __ ] linux all right you typically on
windows all i need is the unix bash
shell back commands but now powershell
powershell is actually a magnitude
better than bash in just about every way
every way the design the naming the
documentation the power the
powershell
is just a magnitude better than bash
okay for for those of you unix phonetics
or linux
you might say oh oh
what are you saying you lost all credit
well you haven't heard you haven't
watched and you haven't you know read
enough of my rants yet okay so back then
you have let me show you okay
sigwin sea green is a classic
beginning in 1990s so i have a tutorial
this is uh this article is 2009 sigwin
so
let's uh paste it here so you have
sequin
how to install it you know uh
then you have sig wing
essential install list like that is if
you're on if you are on windows you know
if you came from the unix you know
assisted me background which is i am and
uh and tuned to the open source stuff
pro python uh you know
all the bash you know all the
apache you know my mysql you know the
lamp stack
the lamp stack now it's asian jargon you
know you don't call it lamp anymore
but if you came from unix background you
know you you want those so see green is
one of the solution and once you install
sigwin you have like the question of
what you know there are thousands of
programs which one to install so
i wrote this in 2011 this is the
essential list you need a zip unzip
bzip2
xz those are the essential decompressing
you know the unique software there are
so many variations
uh compression and decompression and
archive
then you need open ssh very important
for ssh you you need ca certificate
you know you need to uh you know seek
reinstall that then you need git
subversion you know now now this now
this page is written in 2011 you see so
now today subversion is like dead
but back then subversion like git and
several others are fighting for it
so of course get one get one with github
and they are they are now owned by
microsoft one microsoft way you open
source [ __ ] idiots don't know
nothing that's what happened they are
owned by microsoft and and and and
and then the the open source phonetics
they say oh no now now let's let's
switch over to the to the you know wolf
something you know another new
kid huh
you know that what's what's the name
you guys know
say something okay am i still going
let's see um
check check status video check audio
check okay so you know
you you know git
github got bought by microsoft but
there's a new one there's quite a few
but they they kind of die so i'm talking
about history then the linux open source
phonetics say oh we're gonna switch the
problem is the you know the issue they
never thought of is that
when you become big let's say you okay
you are a open source phonetic you
believe in open source or free software
foundation you know you believe the
ideology so you work yourself then you
are successful you are you're working
hard you are smart you work you know
after five years you start you know you
have a company and successful let's say
you have a github you know
a web interface you know
then microsoft comes in but you don't
get money like no money you ve you are
very poor to be almost always you are
very poor then microsoft says not knock
knock knock
hey hey i heard you you made this great
program we we we would offer you one
million dollars to to buy it and what
you're gonna do you're gonna say yes oh
thank you oh my god thank you [ __ ] you
open source [ __ ] it
that's what all you do so so so all
these programs they they got brought up
then the open source fanatics you know
who are not involved they are they'll
just say oh look at microsoft's so evil
they just buy things and kill it no
that's because you sold out
because you know that that's that's
natural because you work hard why not
microsoft says you know 10 million
dollars they're gonna buy it why not
you're gonna sell so all the you know
basically that happens every all you
know uh
that's basically that way if you become
successful in open source someone will
value it and buy it then you will sell
it for
you know
99 of the time you will
because money because i mean that's
natural you know
so anyway so so that's a lot of
digression you know github subversion
dead so this here is a list of the
essential you know um
unix tools you need you know make
patch util you know make you need
because oftentimes you need to
when you install something unix you need
make and patch your tear is kind of
also obsolete you don't hear about that
much anymore because kit took over
you see before get
or before subversion you know before
this sometimes you need patch ut or
patch your tier is that when you have a
um
let's say um
okay let's see these okay let me show
you okay vc diff okay that's the emacs
command
so you can see
the the current file the talk show today
this file
this file you are looking at you know i
now my website is on
is a git you know so you can
call the command vcdif and it returns
this thing so plus means new additions
minus means removed
so for example i can remove something
let's
remove this part
and
let's see we see diff you you can see
now the minus is red you see so this is
a diff file then you can use that uh
patch utils patch your tears to
to to for example if you have the same
file i can
send you the div file then you use the
patch util to
merge
the changes into your file so that's
what patch you do is so this the these
are the unix essential unix programs you
need you need you need rsync
you need unison unison is also dead unit
you know you see rsync is one way
sync you know you sync your file or
directory to a server or
from one machine to another okay that's
rsync it can also be used locally
but that's one way only one way so
unison is two-way sync
so for each file that differs it can
check which one is new and update in you
know either way to or from
so but unison is also dead and by the
way unison is written in ocamo or camo
the powerful functional language better
than haskao
okay so unison and then you need code
you need we get and you know
then as spell spell is also dead okay
nobody use a spell in any anymore these
days and of course you need image magic
uh graphic matte graphics magic is
replacement up tp png is a tool that to
optimize png files because png files
usually it's a bulky they have
redundancies
and x so each one of these actually have
a tutorial so you see
exif
exif is a perl program written in perl
that
removes metadata from your image files
so you so you have a bunch of image
files you can
call this program you can just call by
by this okay
there you call this command line
then you remove all metadata of gmail
file so so so i have a tutorial on that
anyway so these are the essential lists
okay so
i talked about lots of random things uh
let's go back here
we see diff okay uh
emacs so let's type them out so we have
kind of a topic of what we talked about
uh github essential list
and move on
okay and here is another article about
sequin path and window path conversion
a
very complicated [ __ ] you know that's
part of the complexities of software
engineering
you know because you thought programming
language you know you have the
programming language you have the unix
philosophy you have the unix
shell you know
you can automate anything why don't we
just automate anything but when you
actually do them like working your job
every day you are spent why the [ __ ] it
doesn't doesn't work well why the [ __ ]
that doesn't work you spend hours every
day just to get them to work
see green path and win this windows path
conversion very highly complicated fact
and this is written in 2009 okay
so next
so then sigwin is one solution then
beginning in 2008 also
uh yeah 2010 you have you know you
started to have this virtual box becomes
uh very popular so you can run linux in
the wind in windows you know
so i back then i was
dying of hunger you know i don't have
money
so i was running on a pc that's from
walmart you know 500 pc the cheapest
and
and i need to learn linux so you install
this okay so
so that's some of the articles okay so
let's uh clean up
so let's uh clean up and uh
okay
let me just uh
that
then
show in browser
so we have a record of what we talked
about okay we haven't get to powershell
yet okay so i was going to explain
why do you need find script so back to
the previous level of hierarchy of
discussion
why do you need um
why do you need to write a find script
since there's already grep and so easy
in powershell as well let me explain
because that so
yeah so back to this i'm gonna read the
comments in a bit okay
problems of coding unix script in emacs
so if you have any emacs in windows you
have the installing external program
problem you know sigwin or others or
linux subsystems you know on windows you
have the unique shell quote escape
problem that that that is one of the
biggest
complexity in software industry one of
the biggest if not the biggest that is
the escape the c [ __ ] the c
language they invented the kind of okay
the c language invented the escape thing
this this kind of thing
the [ __ ] c language the unix
[ __ ] they invented this thing then
then it's
complexity
extreme complexity because you know have
you ever you know if you are in the if
you've been programming for a few years
you'll know
so what's the complexity suppose
let's suppose you want to uh grab
let's say okay
okay so you you see this you see this
directory
you see this directory there's lots of
uh programming source code you know if
you're working if you're a programmer
you have you might have thousands or ten
thousands of source code right so it's
called they make they might contain
regular expressions and so on now
suppose you want to find you know
there's a bug you want to find
you want to find search you know grab
uni scrap the greatest power tool you
know unique script you want to find all
occurrences of
of these
this backslash and backslash t you won't
find you know all currencies
what can you do
it's
it's nearly impossible okay this is a
simple case what if you want something
like that okay
for example you know
a lot of you guys doing web dev right
web dev this is the image file image
file this is a regular expression for
passing you know html image embedded
image files the height the height and
width you know
so in your source code you know doing
web web dev front end or back end
javascript or not js or whatever
golan even or python you know web dev
back-end or front-end you know you you
probably contend
probably every web dev source called
content kind of this line okay so you
but there's a bug you want to locate it
so how do you search this
you want to s you want to
do a grep you know find a string that
looks exactly like that
in one of your source code that's almost
impossible because
the escape [ __ ]
you know
so if if you go to bash you know i don't
have bash you know i don't have bash
since i'm i don't have uh bash installed
actually i probably do
uh let's see
you know because i noticed git installed
bash so
let's open a new tab
by the way right now i'm using the
windows terminal
not not the powershell okay so let me
show you the difference
so you're looking at you see these two
different uh you know windows
this one is a windows console
you know that's a windows
console you know window kind of terminal
thing
um it's been around for like 30 years
but but microsoft about two or three
years ago they started the
new completely new program the windows
terminal and it's fantastic lots of
features you know i don't i don't care
for fancy you know new features but
rather i care for
critical things for example on the new
terminal you can display unicode okay
lots of digression let me show you
for example this directory okay so let's
uh cat
um
help cat i believe the program name get
content okay so
let's magnify okay
okay
1000 digressions and i'm not done yet
okay so clear screen so let me show you
cat
okay magnify okay
magnify
cat
unicode
unicode animals okay
do it
you can see you see that
gibberish
question square square question in a
square
you see that you see that questioning
your square
[Laughter]
okay so that's a problem
and it cannot be fixed because this
program is you know because they need to
re maintain backward capacity and so on
but but in this
in this
um
new microsoft
term not not here okay so in this
terminal
here
so you got cd to web
sadie info
comp okay
magnify
now
cat
unicode animals do it
magnify
so let's see
who is it
okay so
you see
there you have it you see you see animal
heads unicode animals you see microsoft
windows terminal the new thing fantastic
but meanwhile in this microsoft console
you see this crap
question mark square crap
okay so that's a
progression of the microsoft microsoft
actually did a lot of great things in
the past 10 years and they are now all
open source you see the powershell i'm
currently
currently running it's 100
open source
plus the net is 100 open source
and in fact they
stopped
you know developing the windows only
powershell or the
windowsonly.net so net now is 100 open
source that's what microsoft is doing
now is it good or bad i wouldn't say
it's
i mean ask yourself if you are unixfonet
open source phonetic do you think it's
actually good not not really
why because the open source
phoneticism the idea itself got lots of
problem problems
so anyway so that's advantage of unix
terminal okay so
so what what am i doing so i've been
going over digressions and digressions
okay exit
so i talked about unix terminal okay
microsoft
terminal okay
uh and this is about unix escape okay so
let's
make it
that
c
escape
syntax it's a one of the damage that's
one of the permanent and
perpetual damage to the
programming industry
and i you know i haven't expected or
actually i did but i haven't actually
showed you an example of how this you
know how you're gonna grab that how are
you gonna how are you gonna do it you
know can you do it you you you you know
unix philosophy unix linux [ __ ] it can
you
answer the question okay this is not a
troll you know you think oh truly throw
your ass
i want to grab this literal string how
do you do that in grip
so you're gonna start to escape and in
xiao you know it's going to be
[ __ ]
[ __ ] it's going to be a [ __ ] up [ __ ]
that's what it's going to be
so why so that's a so that's one of the
one of the problem of the unix script
you know because usually when i say oh
uh you know i wrote the emacs version
image-based version or golan version and
this linux unix idiots they all say oh
why do you need to do that just script
you know
they don't know they don't know
so
so if i want to grab let me show you how
do i do this in emac list okay emac this
finance replace let me let me do it
right now okay so i'm just call the
command three key strokes you see you
can see
you you see that three key strokes space
space k cause start find replace text
okay let me do it again space space k
then paste it
now magnify the mini buffer so you can
see you see the mini buffer i pasted
that
and press enter
replace string okay i don't want to
replace so actually i want to find
version so do it again there there there
none found
none found okay because i'm not in this
directory so but let's open this file
you see i'm open this file in emacs now
let's do it again
you know search for that
actually this will not work in this
directory html files it will not work
because
you still need to do the escape
so
so how do you do this let me show you
okay
okay so this is the string we want to
find
but if you're gonna grab it so be this
again this is not because it won't work
because the seas escaped [ __ ]
because in lisp
it adopted you know in images it adopted
this this escape crap
so you can you can't just grab this
literally you have to let me show you
how to do it okay
uh you have to you have to add the
backslash okay
okay so this is gonna be i'm not even
sure that will work
uh
backslash slash slash okay let's try
this okay i'm not even sure that worked
so search for it
magnify paste it
do it in this directory
or html files not found
uh so you know it's going to be headache
you know you can spend for i did many
times in the past 20 years you spend an
hour you cannot find the right
escape
very complex especially when you
involves you know in e-max
that needs to talk to the
shell
that needs to you know
that runs smash you know
too many levels so one of the actually
easy solution is to
being 64 pin 64
uh you know a bit
of this stream then in xiao and being it
uh you know if you know what i'm talking
about
uh
was it not being 64 something like that
x64 i forgot the name
search for it
being 64 encoding okay i forgot what's
the name
x64 um base64 okay base64
uh
64 okay uh let's
copy that
okay so let's i i talked to over so
let's go back to talk show so let's just
um
you know this is a
headache put it here
kind of make it like that
then problems of unix scrap
do it
so shrink the whole thing
now so far that's what we talked about
okay and we haven't finished the problem
of calling unix script so external
program problem
unix shell quote escape problem okay
dependency on familiar familiarity of
your unique
syntax you see because emac this regular
expression and the unix shells bash
regular expression great all the great
regular expression they are different
okay they are
they differ you know they differ quite
big by quite a bit
so
you know if you are emax user
you know you are familiar with maybe you
know you're familiar with e max regular
expression but when you need to find
some text then you need to use the unix
regular expression why because e max
depends on the unique script
you know it doesn't you know it depends
on
[ __ ] idiocy
so that's another problem okay so i'm
talking about these pages about calling
unix script in emacs meaning of this
problem actually happens by applies to
grab itself not just e-max just
when you run grip in the terminal by
itself so let me explain okay so
for example the escape is a problem in
grip itself
but when you call emacs
you know you you you call grip from
emacs that adds the complexity because
the emacs needs to
send your string to the shell then you
know the escape mecha so first of all it
begin with the emax string
so you need to probably
properly encode this in emacs string
then you need to pass this string to the
shell the bash you know the grip
you know it's basically impossible so
depend so another problem dependency on
familiarity of unix graph you know
because they have a different
regular expression okay i was talking
about this regular expression not
compatible to the e max regular
expression so you have two regular
expression syntax you need to talk about
and and another thing is dependency on
the familiarity of unique shell syntax
because the unix graph depending on what
unix you are on bsd or mac os or the
linux which is gnu you know the gnu
uto the graph they have different
options you know
incompatible
so if you are a emacs user
but now you need you know
imagine emacs is the best text editor
right so one of the thing you need to do
in text editor is find strings right
but when you want to use emacs to find
string you need to learn the unix script
syntax
[Laughter]
so
emacs is the most powerful editor no i
don't think so
but [ __ ] all the other text editors have
grab building but when it comes to emacs
you need to you need to use
another
program which has a different
regular expression
[ __ ] the emacs phonetics
you know why do i [ __ ] this [ __ ] that
because when you talk when you express
when you show these opinions you know
like politely to the emacs typical emacs
edit hackers online you know the famous
emacs bloggers you know online
everywhere
they don't like you they think you are
idiot okay they think oh no no no you
know
they they don't know they [ __ ] idiots
ultimately the reason is because code
okay code and the open source
phoneticism
because for example when you put
you know when you show this article to
this
popular emacs bloggers i you know i know
their response because i've been knowing
them talking with them arguing with them
for 20 years now their response is that
some of them at least they'll say yeah
okay you know they'll say this is valid
reason
but
even if even them they are
it's impossible to change because
there's the whole cult
beneath them i mean even if they are
reading they agree with me
you cannot change anything emacs
so lots of problems okay so interface
problems you know different regular
expression problems you need to learn
the unix version problem uh then
no that's not all this is not this more
okay unix stream problem okay
the unix script have a [ __ ]
bug okay so it's documented here okay
another page let me show you let me
paste it here okay
linux shell util unique unicode book so
for example if you have a file
you know i don't i don't have a unix
unique in store so i cannot demonstrate
it but you can do it if you are on unix
you can uh you can you can try this
right now okay so if you have a file
containing these characters okay
you know some containing these
characters and you want to call the unix
unique command to remove difficult
duplicate lines okay
it doesn't work okay so for example you
want to do this you know remove that it
doesn't work
you see it the output is 33 equal it
thinks
i have 33 lines of equal sign
you know so it consider all these to be
equal that's unix
that's a unix
philosophy [ __ ]
the [ __ ] that was the unix [ __ ]
you know but unix goes by propaganda it
creates a code so nobody knows this when
it comes everything is everyone is like
oh eunice is the best unique unix is the
best
unix is the operating system that begin
when you have a bug just crash just
crash because
because restart is fast let's just crash
it
that's the design of unix that's the
meaning of unix philosophy
the new jersey philosophy
you know
so
that's history okay in contrast to the
lisp community
so okay so here is the unix
unicode bug okay and they don't consider
it consider it a bug because the unix
they they say you know they have
actually
i don't know if it's fixed now but you
can you can look okay
um so lots of digressions um
okay so
so let me finish this
because this is you know
right now i'm trying to explain the
unique script problem the grep utility
and so far i only covered half of it
half of the reason yet
i already already already talked for
40 minutes
and okay so so you see the unicorn
string problem okay
then you have the problem with with long
search string you know for example
for example you know i do i i do web dev
right so for example i
this this block of code you see
that block of code is a
it's a google tracker
you know basically every website you see
they track you using the google's
uh tracker i like too including all the
open source vast majority of it
including
most okay now
depends i mean
so this is the google tracker okay it's
used by the top you know
the 4000 website the most popular
website you know google google
tracker so i do a lot web dev so i have
you know 20 000 html files in my
directory you see
you see i have you know each one so for
example this perl tutorial you open the
file
you can see
you have that but however sometimes you
know i want to know if maybe i missed it
some files is missing that tracker
so what i do is i need to grab this
block of text okay
copy it you know i need to
grab this block of text
now if you are a unix phonetics you know
you you say oh let's just unix script
but unique script they cannot grab
multiple lines okay that's the
fundamental problem of the great unix
[ __ ]
unix script because unix is line based
everything is a line you know you cannot
you cannot have multiple lines that
doesn't you know unique script
you actually you can do it you have to
put it in a file okay you have to
specify your option
a file name you have to put this text
block in the file name
that's how you do it in unix script you
know i
like this okay i have i have full
detailed explanation but nobody reads it
okay this is how you do it
but let me show you how i do this in in
emacs okay so copy that
press one button to put copy let me show
you the show you the pink window so you
can see what keystroke and what command
i'm using okay so press the key select
that
script
tag block okay
press the key copy that
now
press three keys through called saffine
text
paste it you can see in the mini buffer
paste that
search
search all this per directory yes
regular expression file name extension
html yes there it is there it is shrink
you see you move the arrow it can you
know you see the pink lines are file
name
the yellow is the found instance
and you can jump to it like press enter
you jump to the file you see show in
browser
so this file is perl these available
modules this module search path a
tutorial okay so that's how you do it so
this is the power version let me show
you the gold land version okay
so let's go to the uh
not gold land uh
golan version is best used for um
find and replace but now let's go to get
let me just show you okay
so go land so you go to
fine go i just i just okay so here's a
golden version
so where is the part you say the string
here okay
so it's here delete that paste it okay
multiple lines multiple lines okay
now
now you need to give it a directory so
what directory to search okay
copy the file path
now go back here
select that paste okay
so this directory okay pearl
now just run it
there it is gold needs to warm up you
know that's why it's a bit slow so if we
do it again then it's instantaneous okay
so now open it
this is the result okay you see here's a
result go all the way to the top now
ko
xr find mod so
in emacs so that will highlight it so
you can see same result i can move the
cursor let's shrink
i can move the press the arrow key and
move around all the occurrences
or i can move by file
by move by the previous file or jump to
the next file press enter to open it
showing browser so this file is per hash
table a tutorial okay so back to emacs
so you can see
there
so this is how you
find
why it's useful you know find multiple
lines you know grab
if you're going to do this in graph it's
first of all you have to copy you have
to save this
multiple lines in a text file
the [ __ ] unix
okay i'm going i'm going to read
comments okay
so you see so why so why do i write why
do you need to write a find
you know script to do find
because unix sucks that's why the great
unix script sucks and the people the
unix idiots they don't know they don't
know
now over the past 20 years there's lots
of replacement for grip you know for
example silver
you know that's you know i have a i have
a blog about it but i forgot where so
easier
it's easier just to search for it
grab alternative
you know i have so many blocks i forgot
which file but you can see you know grab
alternative let's see
you know so
you know this this usually all these are
[ __ ] scum
websites they are written by idiots they
are ad you know they are they are ad
spam sites you know grape alternative 25
plus similar file search utilities 25
this site which is gonna tell you 25 of
them and then this one graph equivalent
okay this one i don't know what a shell
hacks you know
usually they are all spam written you
know churned out by
spammers
you know you know low quality you know
[ __ ]
then then this one you know the okay
this this is great uh stack overflow
okay regular expression graphing using
the
vertical line alternative alternative
okay then this one unix.com i don't know
what the [ __ ] that is okay let's just
open one of them
ah this is old page whatever this is not
even
the unix.com mysql database has
encountered a problem
let's open this one okay this is spam
website alternative to a god this is
this is machine generated spam [ __ ]
by some coders by some you know the open
source [ __ ] you know like you
typically you don't know you think you
are not them they are that's you that's
you guys that's you you know some of you
among you the
phonetics you know spam
the machine you know they are developers
you know they write they
they
crawl or the website they draw
information and use machine to generate
this page so that they can get traffic
like usually there's a difference
between
several of these kind of things
difference between
and
here's grab a grab alternative okay so
what is uh
and this other crap okay rip
rip grab is one of the new one
the silver is a new one okay i don't
know what's the other ack okay the ones
i know that's genuine is
ack okay ack
silver
and rip grape i think
i think the older the year the
the history
the the way the the the older they
happened is um
reef grab is the latest
silver or rib grape i forgot which one
is the latest
ack is probably the earliest okay i
might i might be wrong i forgot so that
my point is just show telling you that
over the past especially in the past 10
years this like new grip every
few years
so
so these new grips i
believe some of them
um
some of them fixed
some of the problems i mentioned about
grip okay
about
you know problems of grip unique script
so
okay so i was explaining explaining the
multiple lines problem okay then there
is um
file directory uh filter you know filter
file directory problem
okay this this is not a strong point
here i mean it's not a strong criticism
uh
and then there's yeah so
the most important
items are on top on top
so the earth other issues is
too many incompatible versions of a
graph you know in unix history
you have grab e-grep f-graph
then i believe the glue merged them into
just grab you know that's unix history
okay
you have e-grab f grab and grab they all
use different regular expressions
okay
then you have the grip is not powerful
enough for nested syntax that's true
that's also important because
regular expression by their original
history their design is for
theoretical computer science
of formal languages
that's what regular expressions are
they are expressions to
represent
linear
uh linear recon
linear non-recursive grammar of
languages meaning just string meaning
just a bunch of sequence of symbols
that's not recursively defined that's
what
grep regular expression quote unquote
that's original meaning
in theoretical now this is important
okay because most of you don't know okay
the unix people idiots
regular expression
original purpose
how they came up and the meaning why is
it called regular you know is because
it's a tool
in
it's not a tool it's not actually a tool
but it's a theoretic theoretical thing
okay to represent
income in theoretical computer science
of formal languages meaning just
syntax okay informal languages
theoretical computer science science
to represent a pattern to represent
languages that are regular okay here
the regular means
essentially
in practice in you know in in a way easy
to understand
regular means regular language means
means uh
a sequence of symbols or characters a
sequence of characters that that is not
defined recursively so there's no
nesting no nesting whatever that's why
that is why today you cannot use regular
expression to
to pass anything nested you know
so that's what regular expression
originally was then it became a tool you
know unix became a tool then uh
then they started to enhance it and and
serve them
so but i mean the important thing is
just to know to know that regular
expression originally is a different
thing than today but
you know we as programmers
we use regular expression it's extremely
useful
just
for the purpose of searching text okay
so it's almost has nothing to do with
the original purpose whatsoever and this
has nothing to do with regular
expressions anymore i mean regular
expression is actually a bad name
because
the proper term should be originally i
mean it shouldn't be regular expression
it should be um
[Music]
a scheme of a syntactic representation
of non-recursive
languages okay
let me say it again
a scheme
a syntactic scheme to represent
none
not to represent all
linear languages
more or less okay that's essentially
that's what it originally was
but anyway so
but then it becomes a unix tool and we
all use it today
so the way we use it
the proper name should be just a string
pattern matching tool okay it's not
regular expression [ __ ] okay it's just
find and replace
tool that's what that that's a proper
name as far as we understand it as far
as
how it is used in the industry a tool to
find it replaced by string patterns okay
that's what it is
so grab is not powerful enough to for
nested syntax that's true so that's why
that is another reason
because when you do when you use regular
expression you really don't care whether
it's a linear you know
formal language or not all you care is
that you want to use a pattern to search
your bunch of files okay
but
but oftentimes your files
contain nested things such as html
svg
xml golan c
javascript
python pearl ruby you know they all have
nested construct you know the curly
braces are parentheses you don't need it
so you want you you you you want to be
able to be able to pass them
so usually you cannot do it with regular
expression at least not in one shot so
usually what you do is you find for
example let me let me show you okay
oftentimes i need to find you know
title okay for example i need to know
if my 2000 html files
if it's missing a ending tag okay so you
see this this title
you know usually you have the beginning
tag
and ending tag
so i i want to know if i'm missing or
any tag
can you do it with regular expression no
but however you can using multiple
regular expressions like for example you
search first of all you you search for
that
then you search for
then you grab the string in between then
you search for if there's a
if there's you know
uh something mismatched you know
something in you know
so you still use regular expressions but
not in one shot okay
that's what you do that's that's
you know that's happens the mass
majority of text processing programs
but would it be nice wouldn't be
wouldn't it be nice if you have a
kind of a
a scheme
to represent any nested expression
that would be fantastic actually there's
such a tool called um
passing expression grammar okay
so i i talked over okay so i don't know
even though
okay
pausing expression grammar
okay you can search for it
you will find the wikipedia passing
expression grammar okay but as far as i
know that hasn't been become really
practical but however i want to tell you
wufam language
wufan language does have
a system to similar to regular
expression
that repres that can represent nested
grammar okay wu fam language now i
haven't explored it but
um
okay let me just show you the
documentation okay
where's the key
what's the key
okay
okay first of all
first of all let's do that
yeah okay
and
so let's go to the documentation so this
is how you represent regular expression
in wufang language okay so wufam
language does have regular expression so
all these things you are are familiar to
you but however it has a alternative
let me show you where string patterns
okay
okay well so
string expression there it is okay
so
string expression
is woofing's own
scheme
to represent string pattern okay and
this
string expression is much more powerful
than regular expression and it can
represent
nested grammar next you know language
with with nesting so that's what i want
to tell you wufang language that's why
it's very expensive
but it's free okay so you can buy it
just search for xali wufang engine
you'll find my tutorials about it i talk
about this often wolfen language often
in my videos
okay that's a long digression okay let
me stop i don't know you know
where we're going so we
we didn't get to
code um
powershell you know i'm just beginning
to tell you why
do you need to write a script
to do grep okay and we talked about
why
the problem the problems of grep why do
you do you need to write a you know a
script in golan in python or in bao xiao
in whatever
and
another thing i want to tell you i
didn't mention let me just finish that
then i'm going to read the comments and
that's it for today okay another thing i
didn't mention is that when you do a
grip okay let's see sequin okay
so let's say i want to grab sigwin
okay i'm using my emax
xr find tool package okay
so grab sequin do it
you know in in this directory so you can
see
all these are occurrences
now notice something okay normally when
you do in in in graph or in powershell
let me let me show an example okay
so let's um
this is how you do it in powershell okay
grab sequin
so you see
again it's line based you know it's just
like the unix script so you have the
file name
then you have the line
the line that contains the word sequin
okay line based line based okay
this is important remember line based
so but there's a problem with line based
graph because you don't see the context
for example
for now look at my list version okay so
this is the result for my list version
you see
it not just show you the line but
however you can specify how many
characters before it should show
and how many characters after it should
show okay
so
so you can see the context the actual
context not not cut off by lines okay
you can actually see the context when
they occur
can you do that in unix script no
can you do it in powershell grip no
select string power xiao has the proper
name select string okay can you do it no
can you do in can you do it in xa emacs
find package yes okay so i'll show you
the context
why is the context important because
suppose you want to search for um
title okay so let's just do it okay
title okay so you can see you can see
what comes after the title
you see but if you do it in line based
you cannot okay let me show you
you see title
you see
you cannot see what happens after the
word after the word you just searched
that's a problem that's a line based
[ __ ] line based is the unix philosophy
[ __ ] because unix back then in the 1990s
1980s
any file anything cannot have lines
longer than 80 characters
80 characters come came from the unix i
mean the punch cards because they are 80
horse
80 by 24
holes you know that's where the terminal
you see all these terminals
you know these old terminals 80
characters by 24 typically or 80 by 40.
this this one is for example 80
characters by 24.
it's smaller than this you know that
that 80 characters by 24 would be
it would be like or something like that
okay
so that's that's what that that is you
know this is this this is a very popular
terminal
and this is the
yeah this is a very popular terminal so
this is back in
1978.
okay so that's what this you know so
my point is that so unix back then
they you know they truncate lines when
it's over when you have a text over 80
characters it's silently cut it off
because they cannot they are too idiotic
they cannot handle it the c buckets the
c
unix and c buckets
you know they are c coders right the
rich denis which oh it's too long we
just let's just cut it off fast fast and
simple [ __ ] unix that's what that's what
unix
do
to this day the unix created a code
that to this day many of the programmers
you know if you look at the python
conventions coding style commission
golan c c plus plus java you you know
any of them almost almost all of them
you'll see a coding style guide oh
please please you know when your lines
is more than 80 characters please you
know
chunk it [ __ ] [ __ ] unix
okay i think that's it so uh so i talked
about so
let's let me wrap up so i talk about the
problem of the grip the history of
regular expression
uh why do you and why do you need to
write a find
script
you know
um
okay that's it
okay so i'm going to read the comments
pay me okay guys you liked my video you
enjoyed it
as a comedy
oh it's a tutorial pay me okay like buy
me a drink
i'm done for today
one hour rambo this today's talk is
gonna be titled
why unique scrap sucks
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching and i'm gonna read the
comments
we are you okay one of the comments will
you react to a youtube video which one
that that depends usually i don't do
those things you know reaction videos
that's a male engine idiocy
so nick
maleki says
check out the windows video on my
channel i'd love to see what you have to
say paste the link
just paste the link i might you know i
don't
actually go to discord okay you guys go
to saudi discord join
then we can you know maybe talk and also
lots of people you know
because i'm a little bit
popular i'm kind of you know because
i've been writing blogs for 20 years and
now i'm doing youtube so i have the
i have a
a minor problem the slate celebrity
problem
every day i'll get email because i look
at this what do you think of these side
you know every day then they you know
people are going to friend me on discord
on twitter you know they get i don't
know who they are
um
you know so i that's a minor problem
that's just a celebrity problem
so if you want me to look at video and
just post it you know maybe you can
let's see
okay that's good um
[Music]
newton's method you know wolf and
language already have solution solving
solutions building
so okay another day because today is
already we talked for
75 minutes probably already
that i agree
i kind of agree
okay too many you know you you have to
tag me if you want to ask me a question
okay
bye guys
you know be careful with your comments
because i don't want uh youtube to
reduce my whatever
it's already pretty bad
[Music]
now what the [ __ ] is this
this thing this vor omg thing
can post link yeah that's that's right
so
okay let me let's let's look at your
video just for
um
let's try if it work
no it doesn't
so you have to
whatever
[ __ ] look at the youtube this
spam and scam [ __ ]
this small engine
most expensive iphone good face your
[ __ ] male engine
so let's go to talk show today's talk
show
so there's a video right here so here is
your link yeah i mean this that's your
um
so let's open to soundtalk show let's
click on that so we get the real link
close it back to emacs
and now
paste it here remove that conjoin them
there is your link okay let's go to it
okay i don't know you know this is too
long so what's the point in theory i can
build anything i want from scratch and
this is something i couldn't do unless
you'll find equivalent tooling on linux
there's also the adobe bye guys