foreign
hello everyone welcome to another
episode of sun talk show
so today's topic is random you ask
questions I answer okay random any
questions so we got just three people
watching so when there's no question I'm
just going to code I'm just going to do
something useful for myself okay
so uh useful there are quite a lot of
things to do you know I always have like
Mega tons of things to do
uh let's see let's see let's switch to
the video so you can see my the full
Glory of my video my mouse my keyboard
This is glove 80. search for xali
keyboard you'll find my review and video
review and this my trusted Logitech
mouse and coffee and stuff and me my
face okay
so no questions okay so okay so let's go
let's do
so again I'm using emacs of course now
now let's see tab yeah so I'm going to
I'm going to do my own stuff okay I'm
using emacs stuff like keys with Vora
keyboard layout so on the left you can
on the left the pink window you can see
all my keystrokes
and the command core as I do them
okay and uh let's see right so I want to
write
let's let's figure out what to do when
there's no question
uh let's talk random okay so let me show
you my you know I my work I have been I
have been doing huge amount of work of
course study code now let's magnify the
font okay so that would be
alt t s in Firefox and let's magnify
let's just say 10 okay close it
okay let's show let's why don't we show
my keyboard blog my programming blog uh
let's show you some of my latest things
I did
lots of things okay so starting with e
Max I guess
Okay so emacs
you know emacs so recently I updated you
know there's a quite a lot update you
can see every day almost every day lots
of things I update I work on my website
non-stop for the past 20 years about
15 17 years so anyway the diet
customization there's several updates so
for you emacs users go there okay let's
see if there's a question how are you
feeling about the gravity about one
month using it
it's great okay my my opinion haven't
changed
uh
yeah my opinion have changes change have
not changed it is one of the best
keyboard great for the question okay so
when there's a question I'm gonna answer
the question so group 80
you know as my review said you know so
these are the ergonomic keyboards you
can see
let's see magnify the screen so my
ergonomic keyboard
uh let's see
what is this oh I don't want f11 [ __ ]
okay you know the there's a Windows
complexity there are different ways to
make to maximize the window so
in browsers you have f11 key
then it you know all the tabs disappear
or the windows bar also disappear so
that's that's usually no good you know
that's the that's when in the 1990s
Windows 95 Windows 3
because back then the the the monitor
size is 640 by 480 okay so the back then
the monitor size is about this big so
that's why you have
what's called full screen so you hide
the title bar and all that so you need
the space but not today so you have f11
that's a traditional classic Windows
thing then you have
Windows key up Arrow that's maximize
window so this is typically better
because you still have all your tabs you
can see what's the current bar and you
can you know
maximize but Windows being idiotic
extreme
it's uh
wait not oh okay okay so it's a window
key yeah window key up Arrow Windows key
so there's no toggle you know what
typically what you want is you want the
single key to toggle uh
to toggle the maximum nice window or not
but this this is not toggle so so in
Windows it's like in every way every
everything you go you try to
you know fix it you can't you know first
of all there is this idiotic f11
and then okay then you realize okay so
there's a Windows up Arrow windows down
arrow so you do that but there's no
toggle like you have to you have to kind
of spend half a second a micro second to
figure out whether you are currently
maximized or not
okay so that's another problem and
there's no single command so you so you
might think okay I'm gonna use Auto
hotkey you know one of the key tool or
programmable keyboard like the glove 80.
you know so I can make it one key but
but no you cannot because there's no way
to know which state it is in
so Windows is like [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ]
up in every way okay windows
and and that's not all okay worse when
you sometimes if you mix these two then
you got [ __ ] up so for example I press
f11 I maximized but I forgot which which
way did I maximize it so now if I press
uh
you know uh
windows down arrow
it it hides window it [ __ ] hides the
window and you cannot you know you can
it doesn't show even in the
um
oh it it does show here
but it doesn't show if you if you use
this way to switch you know any anyway
so that's
you know I started to rent so it's very
problematic and and okay so my point is
that once you do that in f11 and now if
you press windows up Arrow
so that's maximized you press f11 again
okay it works here but sometimes it got
confused so there's no way to go back to
the you know restore you know what's
called restore and also another thing is
that you have old space that creates
this idiotic you know
thing minimize maximize restore restore
you see there
anyway that's windows so anyway my my
opinion on Globe 80 is the same okay so
I think though these keyboards are great
uh they I you know my honest opinion is
that they both they all have advantages
and disadvantages you know some you know
the ones I have a thumb up I think those
are great so which one to get really
depends on you so I really like Club 80.
but um you know because I have isi for
15 years so these days I really need
super light key switches uh and so you
know I asked them they're gonna send me
a one with a super light
key switch
okay
so you ordered it glad you do
you have a way to efficiently keep
common links on your web pages in sync
if you change them for example
navigation links on
on the top of the page yeah so I you
know I'm using the way I build my
website is all static you know because
I've been writing HTML manually since
1996 so in the beginning I'm using
Microsoft Word I tab I type each and
every tag what did I do
so undo
okay so you know in the beginning I use
Microsoft Word
so oh the shift Keys here so
shift you know in the beginning I I type
every tag
like this manually okay
uh
okay that that's the beginning
1996 then uh you know in Microsoft Word
then I also use BB edit then I also use
um
then in 1998 I started to use emacs and
even at the time in emacs I still type
the text manually
something like that you know then
there's Edge you know the then I started
to use emacs HTML mod then around 2000
10 or something I started to write my
own
saw HTML mod so you can see I talked
about this many times now it's 5
000 lines of code size HTML if you like
my stuff you go there
you pay me to get it then you get a
source code it's uh free software it's
open source okay
so the question you know so I'm using a
you know all my the entire website is
static HTML okay so for example you can
see in this directory sorry info
keyboard now they are over 100 1000
articles
um and uh it's so static okay I don't
like
in you know in general you know I don't
do
Dynamic you know if if there's anything
Dynamic it's gonna be JavaScript only so
for example you can see
so let me show you some Dynamic
JavaScript for example Unicode search
you know so you can search for Sally
Unicode search so you type w a t e r so
as you type the you know the all the
Unicode characters whose name contain
water will show up or you can type Latin
so all these are Latin Unicode
characters
hide hexadecimal
hide the code Point hide the name so you
can see all these uh Latin characters
each one is a single character they are
not composition so anyway this is an
example of dynamic with uh
web page that's done by JavaScript you
know in fact I've shown
um
you know in in my past videos live
stream or video I have shown how to
write you know we did several JavaScript
things
JavaScript coding okay so but mostly
it's just
um
Dynamic HT uh static HTML for for
example here you can see this pop-up
that is also done by JavaScript okay and
I have tutorial for it for example you
go to you go to Unicode search you go
one top level and actually I want to
show the Unicode search again so anyway
you go to you know sorry
dot info then you go to
uh
yeah so so I was saying that all these
are on my website as a tutorial so for
now for example you go to JavaScript in
depth you go to Dom then you can see how
to do the pop-up and things like that
and it's here so you have image row over
and go down
so you see that highlight that's also
done by JavaScript for example let's let
me show you okay so copy you know we
just copy the URL and there is a command
I wrote the Emax you just press the key
it will open that file in the in the
clip board okay do it you see so this is
the file
showing browser that's this file okay so
if you go down or just search for DOT Js
okay you can see this is uh
JavaScript uh what does this do oh this
this does the image roll over
actually image rollover can be done with
CSS you don't need JavaScript so let's
go here you can see that's a CSS okay
but anyway I want to show so search for
JS again
you can see
uh okay there's JavaScript search uh
what I wanted to see I want to go down
oh here okay so you open that here's the
JavaScript
what that do is to highlight the page
you are currently on in the panel so you
know we are on image rollover so you can
see so then you you go here so there's a
digital clock
okay and go down
then you have a stopwatch JavaScript how
to
you see the code is over here and you
also have a fade an element fade and
fade okay so the point the the one about
pop-up is here
so this is create a tooltip so this is
this page shows you how to do that
okay and let me show another one I show
this often this is a falling snowflakes
effect
the code is just here
you know 100 lines
150.
it's done using JavaScript and CSS
layers so each each this is very
interesting this is actually a hack you
know JavaScript is not designed to do
you know so it's very interesting and
you know when you see this you you might
be wondering how is it done how is it
possible so it's actually your hack
uh very popular since the year 2000s
okay so this has been around for 20
years but my code is modern my code is
the modern JavaScript okay so you can
copy it you can study it so it's
interesting you know you might be
wondering how is it done you know so but
in fact it's a hack each one of those
heart is actually a CSS layer you know
with you know I have full explanation
here so you can see you can go here and
click on
you know you you need to use CSS to fix
element to window and CSS layer and you
know he's all explained there but anyway
each one of the heart is actually a
layer of CSS then you use
um
you can use CSS to rotate it use CSS to
position it so each one of the heart is
actually
position a CSS element in a layer by
itself so it doesn't interfere with the
other HTML tags so it's a layer of upon
100 layers you know so very interesting
and this is very CPU used to be very CPU
intensive so for example let's see Ctrl
shift Escape
to turn on the task manager
uh performance okay these days
JavaScript has been optimized so much so
now it doesn't use that much CPU and
also because my code is extremely
efficient okay you can always trust the
quality of my code if you if you write
this and if you are not careful if you
don't know what you're doing it's very
easy to
to maximize the CPU when you do this
because you are literally having 50 100
layers and every micro second you see
this update
every 900 microsecond you know
millisecond one tenth of a second it
updates all the layers and their
position that's how you see them
so
so anyway but JavaScript so if you write
but if you write official code and you
and today JavaScript has been optimized
a lot because it's billions of dollars
industry you know the browsers they
heavily compete you know the gouging
each other's eyes out Google Firefox and
mostly Google and Microsoft you know
so the JavaScript engine has been
optimized so much out of shape it's not
it's not just because whether you are a
good compiler writer that that doesn't
work you know let's say you are the best
you get the top 10 best compiler writer
to create your JavaScript engine that's
not enough
if you have that you know the best
compiler
experts to write JavaScript your engine
is going to be slower than all the
existing ones
so what do they do they you have to dive
into detail to optimize to get you know
to to optimize out out of shape it's not
it's no longer proper engineering you
know you are going Beyond just to make
it fast you know that's what happens
with browser JavaScript engine and
everything in browser HTML browser and
for example so it's not a matter of
whether you are expert you can be your
top expert in HTML passing and and so on
you won't make it so there's no chance
for you to compete
that that's what happens in the browser
okay so the equation so back to the
point so my point is that my website is
all static HTML okay the only thing
that's not static is all done by
JavaScript JavaScript okay as opposed to
the server generates the page on the Fly
I don't have that okay anything
generated is just by JavaScript
so
I have a constant need to update
the panel for example in this JavaScript
page if I added a new page I need to
basically add a link to each and every
one page and you know sometimes change
the the the top navigation so that's
your question so what I do is that I
just do find and replace on typically
100 or 1000 files thank you Reaper
chinching any questions Ripper
complementary that you know it's a
complimentary breakfast if you have a
you know if you pay and you I answer
your question
so if you have a question post it okay
anything goes today
so my website is static so
like your question I have to do a lot of
you know when I need to change anything
or footer for example footer for example
today's year 2023 so every year I have
to change the
copyright kind of you know update to you
know
the current year so that means find and
replace for for about seven thousand
files on my website
Okay so I talked about this many times
in my live stream just search for you
know YouTube Sorry find and replace so I
have you know I talked about this a
thousand times so I have for example
let's let's go to kasari info
so I have find replace returning let's
search okay for example this search page
is also JavaScript let's go there so
let's go there
so you can see this is the search page
you know and it's all done Dynamic
JavaScript search for JavaScript so it's
there open it so the first
six thousand lines is the page title and
file path for Sally dot info but there's
also xari.org so kasari.info now have
about 6 000 files so anyway this is a
JavaScript
so yeah so let's search for find and
replace
so you can see I have find replaced in
Wolfram language in in in
um
find replace package pure in pure emac
Beast does not rely on grab does not
rely on silver or whatever pure emac
beasts so you don't you are not
dependent on on Unix on find Unix fine
Linux find you know you know anywhere on
in emacs you'll do for example let's
let's search for um
you know I talked about this topic uh a
million times
and I demoed it a million times let's
search for Haskell in all HTML files so
you can see all these uh Pages
containing the word Haskell find and
replace and you can do replace so anyway
so emac this then in Golan in JavaScript
uh not so much in JavaScript
let's say find replace Okay so let's
narrowed down so in emacs in Pearl Pearl
is my first one find replace
uh script I wrote in year 2000 my first
one
okay yeah date created year 2000
February uh and here then you can see
the version in Golan in Python in Pearl
in emacs in in wufam language okay so
over the years every few years
the first thing I do when I learn a new
language is write a find replace
script
so that is also extremely practical for
me because that's what I need to do
you know because of my static website
okay so anyway so now
okay now what uh
what is the next topic or question
so let me go one by one okay
do you have a vision way to change
commonly links yes find and replace okay
all the code you can see here just
search on my website
have you thought about making a function
that turns HTML into 6.
into symbolic into lisp syntax back and
forth
yes
so you know so let me show you so you go
to search again
okay sorry search show in browser and
search for
HTML
6.
[ __ ] HTML5 [ __ ] HTML5 you know they're
gonna have HTML5 why don't we have html6
so this article html6
Json
sxml simplified now you may not know
what is XML I mean you you probably
heard of XML but you may not know what
is
sxml back then around year 2000s you
know year 2010 so this is written year
2010 that that is part that is popular
among lisp Community this
is the group of people who likes to talk
about this because they think XML is
just
bastardized HTML I in fact I have 10
articles on that okay just you know just
search my website
ex search for
uh why don't we why don't I show you
search for
okay let's show another search page XML
and the lisp okay so you can see several
articles nested syntax XML versus lisp
is XML inferior version of lisp syntax
you know and I I did a talk show of
talking about it too
yeah so
so what you are thinking I suppose is
that you want some kind of you know
because you are thinking that this
syntax is very suitable for HTML and
also you know HTML is very verbose
verbosity worthy so why don't we use
this syntax to represent XML you know
for example this is
XML or HTML and this is my version of it
using kind of the lisp
concept of nested brackets okay now
there are there are already existing
Concepts lots of okay this is this is a
very popular topic around year 2000s or
the lisp heads are talking about it and
in fact there are several proposals one
of them is called sxml you know at the
time 20 years ago the least people they
hated you know they think that XML is
just
borrowing the list concept however the
XML did it wrong because all the you
know the
verbose brackets you know slash you know
so the least people have you know so
they created several proposals you know
for example
um
uh I talked about here
sxml that's one of them that's just one
of them there are others okay you can
search the Wikipedia you'll find it okay
and I tell you them I tell you here
what's wrong with them they are not good
okay so
okay so so that is why I created you
know I wrote this page HTML six somewhat
ingest
you know you you could I you know I
could write a parcel and start to use
this but I didn't do it because that's
not you see
even if you do it you know you you you
know if you create a new syntax you
create it in Python Ruby JavaScript in
all the languages you made it very well
superbly done nobody is going to adopt
it okay what's
you know what's what is going to be a
topic adopted depends
a lot on
social reasons okay and most the gist of
those social reasons is money
okay so if you are a billionaire you
have lots of money so first of all you
you write this parser then you spread it
you add you you put ads marketing you
know you hire entire marketing
department you make Google use it you
you you you tell Google hey Google
Google come over here here's a billion
dollars okay
spread this spread this my new invention
html6 they will do it okay they are not
going to do it doesn't matter how good
your code you know nobody cares about
your [ __ ] your design your Your
Excellence your elegance your Supremacy
your efficiency nobody give a [ __ ] that
is why today all the languages in the
web tag is full of [ __ ]
piles and piles of [ __ ] especially
especially because of the sea and Unix
[ __ ] and C plus plus
you know these [ __ ] this crap
in permeates US Computing Society why
because money
why C plus plus money where does came
from games you know the young young the
teenagers you know you want to play
games
C plus plus you know the huge industry
and
spam industry as industry you know
basically this is the part where the
tech geekers they think they know
everything but they don't know how
things work so the skin fans the skin
Fanatics the you know the list Fanatics
they go nowhere you know it's been in my
personal experience it's been 20 30
years you know the scheme elegance and
whatever good technology they are going
nowhere okay
the technology that became popular is
because money PHP
JavaScript you know these two are the
the most hated by this this Elite hacker
types you know they became more most
popular PHP the circus language and
JavaScript a long story I talked about
this many times
so anyway the question about have you
thought about making a function that
turns HTML into this expression yes
maybe that's what you are thinking
so next question
uh
yeah I get what you are saying so
so here is so on the design of nested
syntax that's a proper name for this
topic on the design you know the the
design of nested syntax so imagine if
you are going to have a programming
language or a computer language such as
HTML
you know and if you want a purely nested
syntax there are many ways to go okay
there's many different design HTML is
kind of one of them or XML you know so
the list is another way
or in fact the python indentation that's
another way to represent nested syntax
purely necessary syntax now in each one
of these there are exceptions you know
they are not really pure because in this
you have you know you have you have you
know you have several you have a DOT for
cons con spare you have a quote you know
I talked about this many times in my
video too search for this syntax study
video this syntax versus Wolfram
language you'll you'll see the details
so anyway my point is that an HTML is
and also H uh XML is not pure for
example in Edge in in
HTML you have this
band doctype what the [ __ ] is that
that's not nested you know there's no
ending tag for that and some tags are
there's no ending tag okay
so I have you know you know I have lots
of articles on that okay so let's go to
uh
let's go through my HTML tutorial so you
can see
uh so HTML tags then you have
self-closing tax okay by the HTML spec
these tags there's no closing tag okay
for example the most used is image and
input
and uh you know
so that's not regular that's not purely
nested syntax you have this exceptional
[ __ ] okay and some people today like
George
he thinks that we should meet or meet
some of the ending tags no
no so anyway
then XML is
kind of trying to fix this XML starting
around year 2000 so they started to have
a strict strictly regular syntax okay
purely more it's more purely nested but
not hundred percent neither okay so let
me show you an example
uh so you go through my computer
um what is this
hacker code okay so you go through my
programming language blog okay showing
browser you go to the RSS so the RSS is
a
XML file so that is the syndication you
know the so this is
this is the atom you know the version of
web syndicate syndicate the version the
technology I'm using is called atom it's
a variant of RSS ISS is [ __ ] okay atom
is better so
and this is in XML okay so you can see
the file XML okay open it so XML is a
much more
regular regular syntax than HTML and
however it's not 100 regular because
you see the first line question mark
xml's version something something that
thing
there's no uh there's uh there's no
closing tag okay again that's called DDT
document something you know crap this is
you know the standard you know
organization the idiots anyway
XML is much more regular but still you
you do have these irregularities much
less okay the first line and
I think that's about it okay the first
line
and well unless you talk about C SCV
okay uh
you know I when I when I talk about my
random stuff on my website it's gonna be
endless okay it's
scalar for vector graphics SVG okay
complexity of SVG there's one article so
SVG by the way
so you have S V SVG animation scripting
SVG canvas versus SVG okay
you know so SVG so this SVG tutorial
okay let's open it
so
this article complexity of SVG SVG okay
canvas versus SVG scripting SVG SVG path
tutorial if you go to the top SVG Basics
SVG is XML okay SVG is also XML
then so what's my point so anyway my
point is that you do have these lots of
these um
wait that's HTML you do have
irregularities okay so back to the
design of a nested syntax now I have
article on that
let's see
uh there's a lot of complex issues okay
nested
syntax okay so there it is message
syntax brackets versus speaking and
versus indentation okay that's one
article the nested syntax XML versus
lisp okay so if you want to know the
detail the you know the technical issues
on the design of necessary syntax you
can read my articles okay so back to
what I was saying so when you want a
nested Syntax for example here is a kind
of the Python indentation style of
nested it it it can also represent the
tree so this is nested syntax is
essentially a way to represent a tree in
a textual manner okay so all these uh
you know nested syntax you can also use
begin and end that sucks that's Ruby
Ruby adopted that idiotic [ __ ] Ruby
begin end
Okay so
necessary syntax okay
so first of all you you it's
it's better if you have a purely nested
syntax you don't want the exceptions you
don't want oh when you you know if you
have this syntax in front then you don't
need the ending bracket or something you
don't want that you want it regular okay
then um there are many details okay
so for example one of the detail you
know you might so for example here is
XML versus this okay you can see that
this code is much more clear Clarity
crab Clarity brevity more readable okay
than the XML however there are some
advantages of the XML for example
damage
you know it's very common you know
suppose your cat jumped onto your
keyboard in and you don't know what key
said has been pressed so some some
bracket got removed
now if you are using XML then it's much
easier to recover it because each tag
you know actually has a name it's much
easier you know if you have one missing
character no problem
you can almost you use an automated way
to recover to revert it okay
if your case is least
oh
don't don't think about it you you are
done you are screwed okay so that's so
that's one of the aspect you know this
is not you know you have to consider all
the aspects the least syntax is more
readable it's more clear it's easier to
type but it's not
better in every way
you know the the XML syntax is more
resistant to damage okay so that's you
know one you know depending on what's
your utility what's the goal of your
your syntax your language you you you
might consider different things okay
that's about that
so repossess
uh represents what do you think about
new search engine war between Google and
Bing to implement AI chat as part of the
search interface how do you think this
wall compares to search engine Wars
before the 90s okay
huh
okay so that question
um
what do you think about the new search
engine war between Google and Bing Okay
so
chat GPT is very interesting okay I
talked about
yesterday or two days ago you know in my
last previous video
I briefly talked about chat GPT for 10
minutes so let me let's try it okay
uh
which
search engine is better okay let's just
ask it
let's see what they say which search
engine is better
it's magnify
you can control apparel
so it says as an AI language model
that's very annoying you know chat GPT
let me repeat this again chat GPT in
became hugely popular
in the past month
because of that there is a heavy
censorship went into it you know to
prevent people asking at random
questions you know like how to how to
make a bomb or how to you know or tell
me all the secrets of some popular
person you know
trying to prevent that so there's a huge
heavy censorship going in
now I saw you know I started to use it
last week so lots of questions you'll
say oh AI language model I'm not
something something biased or something
[ __ ] you know template answer that's not
the real chat GPD
so anyway so then it says there are
several popular search engines available
including Google being Yahoo dock.go and
others okay Google is the most popular
and worldwide yeah yeah tell me
something I don't know you [ __ ] idiot
okay it's also offers very various
features Google Maps Google Images
Google news making it comprehensive
comprehensive platform being is another
widely used search engine that's similar
to Google something something uh
and is known for its integration with
Microsoft product blah blah blah office
and windows okay on the other hand focus
on user privacy my ass
and does not track user data you know
blah blah blah [ __ ]
no you know Duck Duck Go was good 10
years ago but but it's got rotten okay
let me show you my Arcos just in case I
forgot Let's uh let's do it now
search
okay so you have such uh you have a lot
of articles on search on the word search
so let's say
so yeah let's check out this one this is
uh 15 years old blog on Sergi bring
you know the Google founder around 2005
you know it's interesting when you look
back what do it what they say this
article oh
this video is private the [ __ ]
YouTube censored it
the [ __ ] YouTube
you know it's Google very corrupt today
they they censor things they don't want
you to read history anymore now the
[ __ ] this YouTube is gone
uh let's see let's see the Google Blog
let's see do they still have
you know so this is uh
uh I don't know yeah so they the video
is gone you know whatever the video I
link to is gun
you see Berkeley you know search engines
technology and business by Sergey Brin
at UC Berkeley 2005. they they they they
hide it
uh Google okay they you know erase
history they are trying to erase history
you know when Google 20 years ago when
Google when when Google was very good
you know do no evil they they would
never imagine they would do this because
they you know this is public info you
know they are trying to
make information available to everyone
on Earth that's what their goal was not
today today ago is to [ __ ]
make money and uh sensor information and
the lie lie to the public about war
about the weapon about you know new nuke
weapons whatever you know the war going
on with Russia
[ __ ] and the censorship you know gender
stuff you know [ __ ]
okay so that's Google
now let's go back what I want to uh
grave so I want to show you this article
Brave okay Brave search engine is a new
one
uh I which I use okay so for example
so for example
I'm using Brave search and it's pretty
good so far I've been using it for two
months now okay so I recommend Brave now
Duck Duck Go was good 10 years ago but
they also become corrupted you know when
the war with Russia
Russia and USA USA war over Ukraine
you know they the doctor go guys oh okay
now I see a lot of Miss info now I'm
going to start to censor this guy
Gabriel Weinberg [ __ ] okay you know
let's read what he says this is stated
2022 March 10th on Twitter
Gabriel Weinberg the founder of Dr girl
says like so many others I am sickened
by Russians Russia's invasion of Ukraine
and the gigantic
humanitarian crisis it continues to
create
stand with Ukraine
at the Taco we've been rolling out
search updates that downrank sites
associated with Russian dyst for this
information
you know so they started to do
censorship
so what is the truth what is the truth
regarding the Russian invasion okay I
shall not talk about it okay those of
you who really want to know
I have articles on my website on
sally.org or there are tons of
information out there okay you just you
know if you really want to know you can
find the information the truth you know
what's really going on with the war okay
um you know otherwise no matter what I
say it won't convince you okay so I just
but here I just want to point out that
girl is now corrupt
okay
so I recommend Brave now back to the
question about you know so we tried chat
GPD so Google
what about Google search Google search
is pretty much you know like I said it's
corrupt filled with censorship and also
YouTube you can find information you
want anymore even you know exactly the
title you know you it hides it you know
you
um you know so Google
I wouldn't use it
and what about Bing you know so Bing I
tried being
um for several months
in 2020
to
or 2021 so be in Search and it's not
good okay being such
a you know intro introducing the new
Bing as real question okay so yeah so
they started to integrate integrate chat
GPT so I you know two days ago I tried
it apparently you need to um
you know join the wait list you know
what the [ __ ] I don't I don't I don't
need to join the wait at least you know
you can access chat gbt directly just
sign create an account okay
so
being
you know so even before a chat GPT so I
tried Bing last year also for for two or
three months because I'm trying to find
a uh you know replacement search engine
so what I found is that the best
is ecosia okay
e-c-o-s-i-a dot org ecosia search engine
okay
now it so happens the coach ecosia the
marketing is about saving trees you know
that's that's one of the lie that's one
of the very corrupt thing I don't care
about trees okay but purely from as a
search engine
as a user point of view ecosia is the
best okay I have tried star star X and
tried several others doctor including
girl okay God problems even before the
censorship you know so
I my my findings are ecosia is the best
even though I don't like whatever you
know planting trees my ass it's likely a
lie I can tell you right now you know
this is whatever you know the pantry is
my ass
but as far as as a user you search
things because yeah it's the best okay
but but Brave came up Brave browser came
a search engine started you know I
noticed three months ago or so so I
started to use Brave search so brave
search is my now my default uh as for
being God's you know being God's several
problems being
like when you search image
um what's what's the detail of the
problem I don't remember but there's
lots of technical problems and also the
result is not so good okay
so that's my opinion about that
so if you uh there's one more thing Let
Me mention so someone on on saw Discord
uh the uh of lamio show this video so I
watched it I watched the first 10
minutes out of 14 minutes it's very good
video
you know the title is what what happened
to Google search by this in Rico tatara
T guy I don't know who he is
you know it seems popular you know this
video has got 1.5 million views since
three months ago so anyway this video
the first 10 minutes at least it's very
good it gives you kind of overview
history of Google search Okay uh pretty
much on the spot you know since I lived
through the
so you know I watched the birth of
Google you know
so you can watch my video pretty good
so Google so it's for the browse search
engine wall okay so Reaper's question
about the search engine War
uh I don't think it's really happening
okay this knows I don't think it's much
of a big deal because people don't use
such
maybe that's wrong that's wrong
um
yes I mean search is kind of
not as important as let's say 10 or 20
years ago because today you use you know
Discord like like this video said you
know you have Twitter you know Twitter
you search Twitter
for the latest happening is always on
Twitter okay especially news political
news or disaster Twitter has the most
information nowhere nowhere else okay on
Twitter first and first hand you know
earthquake flood you know you see actual
voice pictures photos videos of people
at at that region okay whatever news you
know
on the ground you know so you you can
skip all the fake news you know
Twitter is the best for that then
there's of course there's uh you know
this Discord where you can get
information from your friend you know
people you know or some of them you
trust uh you know so search engine is
not that important as 10 or 20 years ago
and Google has basically failing failing
very bad plus censorship you know
intentional censorship and also on
YouTube so you can find the video you
wanted you watched before anymore unless
you bookmark it and even if you do you
know now now they make it private you
know so you know a loud video because
I've been blogging for like 20 years 25
years
you know I started to blog in 1996.
you know so
so I
I often welcome at work you know or
update my old blogs so over the past
decade I see a lot of videos gone uh
sometimes hard to find a copy okay so I
think that's about it two o'clock yeah
that's about it today
any other questions uh
so would you consider myself a hacker
yes and no you know I don't like the
word hacker I talked about that many
times you know the you need the youth
hacker typically that refers to the MIT
uh era the 1980s 1990s hacker typically
yeah you know
if you you know I I prefer
properly to my I prefer myself to be
have the title expert programmer
top programmer expert computer scientist
okay
but hacker is also okay but you know I'm
kind of a hacker you know like like the
traditional sense of that word
but I don't like to hack okay very
different I'm you know I don't like [ __ ]
[ __ ] the C C plus plus or or even least
you know little tricks you know do you
do you know this is clever [ __ ] them you
know I despise
that's what hackers this typical the
gist of meaning hacker you know they can
they can code quickly they can code you
know quickly but one of the important
element of the hacker is that they they
know you know they also they are very
knowledgeable you know about programming
languages about operating systems about
even Hardware kernels memory how they
work
but one of the important thing in the
world hacker you know is that they
they they they they create clever tricks
to to make things work okay and I
despise that that I despise you know the
the classic
prototypical
type of person of that nature is
is that game you know that um
that game programmer you know the most
popular you know what was his name
ah
if you know type the name okay what's
what's that guy
John Commack
you know he he's a hacker he's the
extreme you know although you know
typically hacker usually is associated
with the Unix background or Linux you
know but
John Carmack you know what how do you
spell uh his name
Hallmark
John karmak
something like that okay but so John
Carmack he's a you know he's one the one
of the best game programmer he's that
type he hacks you know he clever you
know he needs to understand make it fast
you know [ __ ]
I despise I do not
you know a door or any any way like
whatever he do like he is a [ __ ] okay
that's [ __ ]
what I like is mathematics you
understand proof Theory you you know
that's you know the kind of thing I like
okay that's it for today uh okay there
are some other questions but uh
yeah junk car Mac
Johnson below is another another
interesting guy
I have uh
I have some blogs about one or two you
know so this is one interesting one okay
so let's show
keyboard
let's go to no more keyboard and you go
down
there is a article Never by Razer Razer
keyboard okay never buy anything from
Razer crap and here is a video from
Jonathan below
who I learned about around 2018
you know so he he's a programmer he's a
great programmer I yeah I suppose and he
created he is also creating his own
language you know each person have
different ideas what's the best language
so according to him he looked at all he
says he he's got a new idea because he
thinks that a language should be
you should design a language not
anyway I am not he thinks that you
should design a language such that
the language should not
always prevent you from doing something
wrong
he thinks that you you should the ideal
language should be a language that
sometimes allows you that that is
possible to allow the programmer to do
something dangerous or
incorrect but however it relies on the
knowledge of the programmer to use those
features
so in his point of view he doesn't like
rust for example he doesn't like Golan I
mean he doesn't think those are the best
design because in Golan or rust they
have like
they make something impossible to
prevent you know Common errors memory
League or something you know so he and
meanwhile he don't think C or C plus
plus is good because they you know in
those languages too complex and it's so
easy to make lots of mistakes so he
wants a language something in between so
he created a new language anyway I think
it's still working on it
but that's that language is not my thing
okay I don't like low level languages so
anyway he this is a video where he
trashes the
the Razer keyboard okay that's
interesting
uh
okay that's it yeah I can't get over to
all the questions but that's
um so there is one more question okay
stop hating so much
okay too many questions okay but I think
that's it
chatterbaits
uh
of lamio try Brave okay brave brave is
better than ecosia I think
okay so too many questions okay guys
don't forget to donate okay money keeps
things afloat if you always just want
stick with three things that's what you
get today with all the censorship and
control and Corruption okay of all the
you know about everything
okay bye guys
we shut down in one minute
uh okay so
uh
Coffee House
bye