Welcome to another episode of S talk
show. We are going to code wufam
language. Today we are going to code uh
wuam language 3D graphics lighting
system. So it's fantastic. You can have
different light sources. You you can
have multiple light sources. Uh each one
can have different color and uh and uh
that you have different types of light
source. You have ambient light which is
like a room wellled
uh well lled room. Uh you can have
direction light which is like sunlight.
You can also have spotlight which is
like a flashlight outside of it is dark.
Or you can have a point light which is
like a lamp. It radiates lights in all
directions. So you can have different
different light sources, multiple light
sources, uh different light color and
different types of light. So the Wuam
language 3D graphics lighting system is
fantastic, flexible and powerful. But
also the Wuam language uh the material,
the surface uh let's see, let's go to
Wuam language. So, I've been working on
uh can you see it? Yeah, you can see my
screen. Uh if you are watching offline,
play at 1.5 speed uh or higher. If you
are watching here, say hi. Okay. Uh I'm
doing well. Thank you, Palash. So, I've
been working on the Wuam language
graphics systems. Okay. So, there are
kind of two parts. One is the uh wuam
language uh wait plot and visualization.
So you can see can you see it? Yes. So
you can see there are like literally few
hundred functions to do plot. So you can
have uh simple plot of a function or you
can have pie chart and uh you know so
you have hundreds of them and then you
can have uh plot 3D. Let me just show
you some of it.
So you know uh you can so this is a
function plot of a function. Then you
can have plot points and perspective for
example this one. So let's copy the
code. Let's let's show that. Okay. So
start wam language.
So, play at 1.5 speed or more and uh ask
me questions if you have any questions.
Starting wolfen language. Okay. Uh,
woofen language if you don't know it's
the most advanced programming language
by far
like by a magnitude more high level than
Haskell list closure
uh rust uh or camel F or C++ by you know
by magnitude you can do machine learning
it's all built in like by default you
have 7,000 functions so let me just
let's code let me show you Okay. Uh,
wait, not control shift shift enter to
evaluate it. So, let's make it larger
150. And, uh, let's make the window
larger. So, okay. So, there you go. So,
you know, and uh, so you can see we got
uh, lots of cubes cubes on a lattice.
Fantastic. You see? And here is
perspective. You know this illustrate
perspectivity.
You see
fantastic and beautiful and and uh and
when you view this bunch of cubes, a
grid of cubes, you have this phenomenon,
you know, you can kind of see, you know,
you can kind of see they became a
hexagonal star shape
when you view it in different angle. So
it's amazing. You know how many lines of
code? one basically you know two lines
of code to do this. Okay. In other
languages you're going to need 50 lines
or more.
Uh so let's so if but if you view them
now if you don't know so normally our
viewing system is uh is called um
projection point projection you know so
projection from a point. So that's our
visual system.
But you have or you have what's called
orthogonal projection which is like
which is kind of like if you are viewing
things from infinitely far away like
very very you know infinitely far away
then you got this um what's called
orthogonal projection.
So you see they they they look very
different. So you see that's their
effect. You see you can rotate it you
know a bunch of cubes you can rotate it
to such a way you see like like that
uh you know but if you view the normal
you know projection point projection you
you never get to see of all of them like
you know like 2D squares you see so
that's a demonstration of perspectivity
okay one is perspective projection the
other one is orthographic projection
So, but that's not what we're going to
do today. I'm just showing you some of
the, you know, uh features of Wuam
language. Um, so, uh, you got plus
style, color function. So, let's see. We
we uh we're going to show lighting.
Okay. So, we're going to do some
lighting. Um, okay. So, let's let me
just do it. Hello, Tamid.
Uh, okay. So let's just code it and oh
yeah so if you don't know and wam
language you can download it for free
okay since like uh seven years ago
download it for free uh and you want to
also download the Jupiter
so that you can have 3D graphics in
Jupiter notebook okay or just buy just
pay for the wam language then you get
the wuam language notebook so everything
is integrated it you don't have to like
oh go to GitHub this one and configure
you know every you know it's just one
single
uh thing okay so download it for free
and you can get my wam language
uh
emac wam mode so you can code wam
language in emacs that's what I do okay
so today we want to build a lighting
system so let's just code it okay so
showing browser So that's you know uh
let me just code it
pre uh wait let's start a wuang language
code okay so we begin uh
objects okay so x objects
okay we define a bunch of objects
brackets so uh so we want a taurus okay
uh taurus
inner radius outer radius Uh the center
of the Taurus is 0 0 0. Okay. And then
you need two radius. I believe that's um
so center radius one out radius. So
let's look up the documentation.
Uh turn on JavaScript. Okay. And
magnify.
So good. So good. Comment. Okay.
Comment. So Taurus you got inner and
outer radius. So let me just show this.
Okay. So you got a Taurus then you if
you want to show it. So you just say
graph graph 3D
graphics 3D parenthesis you put the
graphics primitive inside. Then you add
options. So I want axis
true. Okay. So copy that. You can you
can type it in Wufam notebook of course
directly. So paste it run it. So you can
there you got the Taurus. Okay. So you
see as I rotate it you know there's one
feature. Let me show you. If I rotate it
you can see it kind of jumble around. So
you see if I stop there it like all of a
sudden shrink because it wants to fit
this 2D display. But if I make it, you
know, I rotate it, then it becomes not
la large again. You know, if I rotate
it, I good. So I don't want that. I
don't want this jump. So what you do is
add another option. Ctrl L to copy the
previous input. Then you want add
another option spherical region. Okay.
Uh spherical region. True. Now shift
enter to evaluate it. So now you see
when I rotate it, it doesn't jump. So So
Taurus is a graphics primitive. You got
tens of it. You got Taurus sphere and
all the all others or you can have a
mesh or whatever. Then you use graphics
3D wrapper to you know to to to
basically this makes the Taurus uh show
as a graphics. Then you can add options
access true uh you know and so on. Okay.
Now let's add color. Okay. So copy that.
Copy back to emac. Uh so we we kind of
have that sphere spherical region. True.
Okay. So let's delete that. D that.
Okay. So that's a graphics and uh so
this is a graphics object. Now is the
Taurus the way we want it? Yeah. That's
that's fine. And uh no we want it to the
Taurus. Let's change the position. So x
equals through -2. Okay. Okay. Let's say
that.
So we we got a Taurus and let's have
another subobject sphere. Okay.
Uh sphere. That's right. And uh by
default radius one, right? So sphere.
Yeah. So,
so that Okay. So, copy that. Uh, and uh,
okay. So, let's, you know, we
copy that.
Paste it. Wait. Paste it. Uh,
evaluate. Oh, missing a comma. Paste it.
Evaluate it. Uh, what did we miss? Oh,
okay. So the graphics 3D takes two
arguments.
So if you have more than one graphics
primitive, you need to put them inside
the list like that. Okay. And you need a
comma there. Okay. So back here, uh,
select, paste. Uh, why do I have extra
comma? Yeah, remove that. Okay.
Select, paste.
Uh why is the
why are they red? I don't understand.
Evaluate it. Wait, something is wrong.
Graphics 3D.
Oh, missing a comma here. Comma. Okay.
Evaluate now. Fantastic. We got this
funny. Okay, we'll leave it. Um, so
yeah, comma. Okay, so now we got two
objects. Let's add another object. Uh,
let's add another object. Let's see.
Cylinder.
Okay. So by def. So where do you want
the cylinder? So how do you specify the
cylinder? Uh cylinder the Okay. So it
takes two
two points. That's the end and the other
end. Okay. So, let's say cylinder um
where do you want it? Uh let's see.
Let's see what is so
zero.
Okay. Cylinder I I want it on the right
side. So, cylinder
takes two arguments, two points. The the
first one is
uh x is two, y is zero, z is zero. The
second one is
same thing but the z is three. Okay, so
let's show it.
Paste. Run it. Okay, something wrong
again. Did we miss a comma somewhere
again? Wait, cylinder. Oh, you're
missing a radius. That's right.
Uh,
wait. Radius is optional. So, why uh why
do I have a problem? Let's see. Sphere
Taurus. Uh, do you need to Oh, yeah. You
need to bracket them together. So,
bracket them together. Okay. Radius. Uh
let's just be explicit one sphere. Let's
add also coordinate for the sphere.
Let's be explicit and radius one. Okay.
Copy that.
Okay. Select. Select. Select. Paste. Run
it. Fantastic. And beautiful.
So you can see
now we are using kind of we are using
the default lighting system. Okay. Now
let's add some lighting system. So but
now we got the objects. Am I doing good
guys? Comment
how to uh so how many people? Two. Okay.
Wow. Fantastic. Two people watching.
Okay. So now we got a bunch of objects.
Let's save the objects as object here.
Okay. So this is the object you know you
can evaluate it so we don't have to type
it every time you know. So that's the
object. Okay. So the object is that then
uh then you just say
so you don't so x objects. Okay. And uh
now lighting. Okay. Now the thing we
want to do
uh not light uh lighting. Okay. Now let
me get my coffee and tea.
So there is my tea. Fantastic. And now
this is fruit juice, melons, and a bunch
of Let's see. Can you see it? Melons and
and uh
and grape juice and bunch of juice.
Wife made. Fantastic.
Oh, you have to shake it.
Okay, let's switch to you see the
beautiful graphics we are doing.
Okay, now let's add lighting system.
So, I've been I've been studying this
the entire lighting and stuff. There's a
lot because it's um it's like a
you know it's like a cat system. You
have all sort of lighting specification
and ambient light and so on.
So let's go to my uh programming blog.
So you got you know the whole system of
graphics. So lighting let's go there.
So you got let me let me just introduce
you. So lighting interacts with surface
color. So first of all you can have
surface color. Surface color you can
specify you know any color or any color
and any color model. You can use hue,
you can use RGB system, you can use
named color and so on. But then you got
glow. So you know it's a like a light
you know you can make it glow. That's a
surface property. And then you can
specify specularity that is make it
shiny
shiny like a metal you know
uh and then you can have material
shading that's more comp that's more
complicated you know you can like
specify material shading uh then so and
and uh okay so material shading and then
you can have let me show you okay color
function which is um
where is it? Okay, so
color function. So that lets you
change the color of a surface or
whatever by a parameter. So for example,
typical like that. Okay, then you can
have so anyway. So on a surface you can
have like maybe it's shiny or you can
have transparency. Okay, where where's
transparency here?
You know, you can have transparency, you
can have shininess property, you can
have different colors. Okay, that's one
thing. Then you can specify lighting.
Okay, then the lighting interacts with
the color of the surface at particular
places. Okay, so uh where is my lighting
page? Uh
okay. So let's go. Not there. Uh
yeah lighting. So let's go there. Open
it. So lighting. So lighting can have
different color can have multiple light
sources can have can be different type.
You can have directional light like
sunlight. You can have spotlight like a
flashlight.
where outside of that spotlight cone is
totally dark. Okay, spotlight or you can
have point light like a lamp.
So imagine a lamp in a in a forest you
know there's no light. So you know so
different you know it cast shadows all
all around it. Then you can have ambient
light. Ambient light is like in a room
like basically no shadows. There's light
light all around. So you can have all
these different light sources. Okay. So
let's let's try to spec one. Okay. So we
want directional lights, point light,
and spotlight. Okay. So
Okay. Let me just copy. Let's just copy
uh code. Okay.
So what is this? Close. Close. Close.
Yeah. So the lighting we're going to try
um ambient light,
directional light, copy
and uh let me show just show you. Okay,
so we we can you know keep this
interesting.
So you can see wait this is uh
uh no this so so in this case you can
see in this case the light is attached
is fixed to a position relative to the
graphics.
So as you rotate it you know it doesn't
change it just fixed to you know this is
a directional light like sunlight.
So you can see um
so the light is like you know 111 you
know it's on the upper corner but I want
it to I want the light to be like in
front of the screen so that as I rotate
it I can see the light will cast
different shadows. Okay, let me let's
try that, you know, just let you know.
So, directional light. Uh, so you want
to check the documentation
and uh here it is. And uh you want to uh
let's magnify.
Okay. So I want it to be um
you know I want the light source fixed
with respect to the screen. So it's like
so you see the 3D modeling is fairly
complex
when you say you want the light source
fixed to the screen. It's kind of you
see it's kind of detached from the 3D
modeling at all. So it's like it's
outside of the modeling. It's actually
it's kind of a met meta uh modeling.
So yeah. So image scaled scaled. Image
scaled. That's what I want.
Image scaled. Okay. So that's what you I
need to use. So let's um
copy that
paste. And uh the light source will be
let's see image scared
um
Okay, I think I want I know what to do.
Directional light. Okay, so normally so
it takes one point. Yeah. Okay.
So we can just um
image scaled.
Okay, I believe that's it.
Click paste. Do it. Okay, now let's
rotate.
Wait, that's not happening.
Oh yeah. So I kind I kind of know why.
Um
you see that's the reason is because we
are using parametric plot. When you use
parametric plot it kind of just fixed
it. Um
you know okay so let me let me try to
get let me try to get it to work. Okay.
I cannot be sure it will work but
um
so we want to display that and lighting
will be that. Okay. So that is the
option and the xx is the graphics. Okay.
And uh the color we we going to make the
color just totally white. Okay. So, try
it. Yeah. Okay, that's good. Now, you
can rotate it. Okay. So, I want the
spherical region. Okay. Uh so that when
we rotate it, it doesn't jiggle. Uh so,
color white sphere spherical region
true. Copy that. Okay. Back to here.
Paste. Reet.
Okay. Now you see now it's uh by default
the light is fixed to the screen. So you
can see that's good.
Um but also by default they have more
than one light. By default they have
like uh four lights. One ambient light
and the other three are uh a direction.
They are like uh directional light or
something. Anyway, so we want to go
hardcore. We want to specify everything
ourself. So let's not rely on the
default. So So let's do that. So
lighting. Okay. Uh in spherical region.
Okay. So yeah, let's try
run it. Okay. You got error. Why? Why is
that?
Uh
graphics 3D box is not Oh yeah, I forgot
you need to extract. So
you can first
okay add
that means take the first part of that
XX.
Okay. Now let's see. Fantastic. You see
now, now there's only one lighting
there. Okay, there's only one lighting.
Um, let's make it red. Okay,
now we have a red light, directional
light from one direction. Uh, okay. It
didn't work.
Why is that? I don't know.
So you know it's supposed to be red
light.
Uh I do not know why it works why it
does not work. Okay. So that's the
reason you know these complexities. I've
been working on this in the past week.
So you know to figure out there are so
many many issues. I think the reason you
see we said we want a red light but it's
not working here. I think the reason is
because we are using parametric plot.
Okay. So, but let's go back to um to uh
using uh graphics directly. Okay. So,
let's uh like here.
So, let's Okay. So, now let's uh
uh ambient light. Okay. So there's
lighting ambient light and lighting um
lighting directional light and uh
okay so that's all the possible options
and ambient light. So, let's get the
rest
lighting point light.
Okay, so point light and what's the
other one?
And lighting spotlight. Copy.
Spotlight is like a flashlight. Okay.
Okay. So, we got these options. Now, we
can uh do this. Uh so, so first of all,
uh image scaled. Yeah, we want that. We
don't want that. So, let's uh say that
uh yeah. So, let's say that.
Okay. Copy that.
and
paste. Run it.
Okay. So now, so you can see
the lighting is kind of on the right
side, right upper corner. Okay. So you
can kind of see
uh let's see if we rotate it, you can
see the light, you know, look at the
sphere in the middle. So you can kind of
see the light is always on the upper
upper right hand side
of my screen. So now let's change it to
red. Now red light. Now it works. You
see?
Okay. That's directional light. Okay. So
that is directional light.
Okay. Now we can change it to uh ambient
light. Ambient light is the the kind of
the most boring one because ambient
light basically no shadows. It just
everything just glow.
You see that's ambient light.
You know ambient light boring. Okay. So
next
um spotlight. Okay. Wait. Point light.
So when you want a point light, where do
you want it? Let's say, so uh so point
light, let's see where are objects. So
point light, we want
we don't want directly at top. We want
um
let's see sphere.
Okay. So let's see. Okay. zero
zero zero and uh
three. Okay. Like right in the middle
above.
Okay. So now let's try it. Paste. Show
it.
Point light. There it is. So this point
light is like a you know light from a
point like a lamp. So right now the
light source is right above the sphere.
So and it's fixed. So you see fantastic
you see bottom is yet uh or shadow
fantastic.
Okay last one.
So we got point light uh and then we got
spotlight. Okay. So let's do the
spotlight.
Copy paste. Let's say spotlight uh
green.
Okay. So spotlight from 0 0 03
and at the degree of pi over3. So in
other words that's uh let's say 60
degree. Okay you can do that. Okay so
now paste it run it.
So it's from top above
three units above and 60 degrees. You
see? Can you see? Fantastic.
Okay, I think that's it. Uh that's what
we going to that's you know that's what
I wanted to demonstrate. So you know I'm
writing a tutorial right now. It's like
incomplete.
uh you know so you can see right now you
don't have graphics so I'm writing a
tutorial and also
you know why is that when we use on the
parametric plot it does not seems to
work
um
I think the reason is because
there are some lighting properties
attached to the to the uh to uh graphics
objects already. So when you do a light
when you add a light, it it doesn't
work. So anyway, that's what I want to
demonstrate, I think. So any questions?
Are the Thank you for the demonstration.
Thank you for watching.
Is everyone good? Happy six people.
Okay. Uh you know, donate to me if you
enjoyed my stuff. Um, if you work at
Google
or if you are a professional programmer,
go to kasali.info.
kasali.info. Lots of stuff. kasali.info
at the bottom. PayPal, Patreon me, uh,
Amazon gift card me. Okay. Uh, I want to
buy a shoe $30 like a flat shoe
and stuff. Anyway, donate. Okay. So,
that's it. Any questions? Otherwise we
shut down in two minutes. Yeah. So today
is short. Sh short is good. Then we're
going to do another tomorrow. Tomorrow
is maybe uh Emacs or maybe some other
thing. Okay. So the code here we going
to copy it. So those are successful
code. These are experimental code.
Delete it. So these are successful code.
Put it back. syntax collect show in
browser. So that is what we've done
and I'm going to upload this so for
people who came in and watch later they
can um
you know uh use the code. Okay, that's
it. Bye guys.