good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of xl talk
show
today we are going to talk about emac
list
and javascript i'm going to code
emacs lisp live and first tutorial
i'll explain what i'm going to do and
what i'm doing in my list
so you'll learn fantastic emac bisp
and today's task what i'm going to do is
i'm going to code emac bisp
to automatic automatically format
javascript code you see i have
javascript
code here now this is a uh in
a uh in a stylistic
style of choice one single long
logical line you know you see so i'm
going to show you
i'm going to write the emac this code to
reformat it using deno you know the tool
deno i'm going to explain
and format it in a traditional way with
indentation and multiple lines
by the way this this single line uh
style of code
it has to do with functional programming
in fact this
this is i like this style okay
you you probably don't know nothing
about it uh this is for mathematica we i
you know i'm going to talk about
formatting uh
uh after we've done this
there's a lot to talk about formatting
because
code formatting is a big non-trib
and then trivial uh uh subject matter
okay
because i have tens of articles about
code formatting
and in fact i'll show you uh
syntax soup okay this here you can see a
collection
of articles all about syntax and
formatting and idioms and styles
okay and this happens to be the most
lame
topic concerned by programmers the
idiotic programmers the mainstream
programmers they don't know nothing
but everyone has opinions about
formatting
they don't know nothing they don't know
math they don't know computer science
they know nothing they are no nothing
else
good morning matt good morning alan
allen says
parenthesis party tonight indeed and
javascript
i'm going to call javascript in lisp
style so you'll see
1 000 brackets okay so today is 2020 we
forgot the date 2020 september 23rd
uh now it's 8 30 in the afternoon san
francisco time we don't have many people
uh only five people watching so that
means i'm just going to
code and you know explain and do my
stuff
so first of all uh yeah so you remind me
to talk about formatting okay
for example some of the issues later on
there might be more people coming
some of the issues about formatting the
typical idiotic programmers are fond of
uh are such as cut the lines you know
you must have you you must not have
lines longer than 70 characters
the most [ __ ] idiotic [ __ ] that came
from the unix philosophy you from the
unix
[ __ ] from the unix people you must
not
you you must not have a line that's
longer than 70 characters okay
in fact i did eight i did a one-hour
talk show about this before
and one of the idiot actually of a
friend
he might discover he watched it and he
got he didn't get a thing
he didn't get one thing a single thing i
said
and he just counted oh yeah you should
but you should
you should format you you should not
have long lines because
long lines are hard to read the [ __ ]
idiots you know these
many of the programming con you know
issues uh you know the
uh induct indoctrinated programmers by
these mantras and things you know styles
idioms the guides these
idiots they
it's like in a coat you know when you
are brainwashed you just believe in that
thing you you seize
thinking you you you're you're you you
sees
your ability to think uh kind of stopped
you know you don't
when you hear a different opinions you
you kind of it just doesn't get you into
your head doesn't matter what you say
you know it doesn't matter your
explanation
they don't they don't address the
explanation they don't like
you just fly by their head anyway
we digressed so let's get get back to
remind me to talk about formatting okay
there's tons of to talk about
let's get back to the emac list okay i'm
gonna write i'm going to demo this demo
is fantastic
and okay the background image you see
let me explain that the background image
is this picture
and this picture is from
so i just created this page it's a photo
of my keyboard now
in every every one of my video i i show
a photo of my keyboard i'm not going to
do it today but this here is
and here is my
my uh chinese bowling balls
okay so you can see oh you have to be
here
chinese boarding footballs you know and
now i have three
uh one of them i put on the floor so i
can step on it
it's sort of uh function as a foot
massage
and you also have this hand squeeze
uh
and squeeze you know i i use this so if
you have
repetitive strain injury of your hand
you can buy
you know go and buy it
so uh and you have juggling balls uh
it's over there
juggling balls and squeeze balls and uh
uh hand rubber band and hand putty you
know go buy it
go go buy it now okay now let me demo
emacs workflow the efficiency of it okay
press one key to copy the url switch
back to emacs actually not here
hide it switch back to f hide it switch
back to emacs
and magnify it's all single key press
okay not control [ __ ] [ __ ]
and paste it here one single key press
and on the right window the pink window
you can see all my keys
and commands uh in emacs you see all
single keys
so you see now i we just got this url
press three keys and it becomes a you
are a real url from a file path
and now and just condense the line into
one single long line
[ __ ] you the stupid coders with 70
charts per line
copy it back to
safari and paste here so you guys can
buy it right away
good morning dub the bennett the bennett
okay so now let's start coding okay
let me show okay let's let's let the
show begin night people okay say hi
say hi and post your comments okay now
so what are we going to do today we are
going to
we are going to okay now let me show you
okay let me explain you see this code
one
single line okay now back to emacs let's
make it you know uh put the
code into a window by itself so you see
this
we have the code this is javascript
now the first line is a long string okay
it's a you know
a constant a variable a long big string
and here we have two functions okay now
let me just
let me run it okay the first function
what it does is
it takes a string it takes a string
and reports how many occurrences
of you know of all characters okay
the second function takes that output
and truncated to the top 50 characters
okay
if i run the code you'll see what they
do so
i run the code here's a result so the
the first result is uh here
so you can see it's a hash table you
know it just tells you
k occurs one time e occurs 41 times you
see
y occurs 12 times and so on and there
are tons of characters
and the second function
will just truncate you know to the top
five so if you see
so you see uh here's the second function
f3
okay actually let's rename it uh f2
renamed to f1
f3 renames to f2 okay so
f1 f2 okay
let's run it you see here's the result
it just count characters the second
function just truncated okay
now save it now let's go to e shell okay
let's go to let's split
split the window go to e-shell and the
file name
of this uh wait
the file name of this file is this one
okay let's close it
so let's paste it there that's the file
name and let's look at the magic okay
i'm
going to do a magic so i'm going to say
deno format this file okay
do it oh it's already done
now look look no no no no look it's all
nicely formatted you see
from a single line like that it formats
them to uh
to the nice indentation style so in fact
deno is the most powerful uh the the the
greatest uh formatting two i have seen
now the other one i have seen the second
the other one that is go format okay i
demoed that before go format
go the golan language it's also greatest
fantastic and deno is
uh even better because in deno it will
format
single line to um to multiple lines
so yeah so but of course both of them
are inferior to mathematica
i'm going to uh get back to code emac
this soon okay but let me explain
uh some of the things first so for
example you go to my programming blog
um okay sorry programming blog let me
show you some of the formatting issues
so uh of course we want to go to
mathematica
let's see where is it so click on that
and click on
come blend hold down second comb land
perving complain perving
now i did a few videos about that and
now we want to go to mathematica okay
actually not here so go back to hacker
code
and go back to programming language
tutorials i'm going to show you some
formatting issues of mathematica
now you see this uh okay hold on a
second okay
you see this code you see this code
now now that's mathematica code okay
mathematica
or also also known as
wufam language beginning
uh in uh 1999 1999
you see this line of these you see these
complex lines
there is no manual indentation this is
one
single [ __ ] line okay the you
programming idiots listen
you see c plus plus python ruby
javascript you [ __ ] idiots
this is one single line in 1999 as you
type
it automatically format them to to to
what you've seen
and that's not all but by the way this
is trivial let me show you something
more
uh uh more fantastic okay
hold on a second that's too big let's
shrink a little bit
uh
okay so so what what i'm saying is you
have
automatic formatting okay
automated so the the the the [ __ ]
idiots the unix philosophy and linux
people you know these type of people
and also including this whispers they
they they have this mindset you know
deeply
deep seated idea that lines should not
be uh 70
more than 17 characters and all sort of
other things like
you go to python you know if you code in
python or perl
or javascript you have formatting
formatting style guide
or in the case of python you have like
um what they call
a pep tap you know the official that you
know from from the python priest the pep
uh number something something they tell
you how you should
format your code they call it um
pythonic you know
but let me show you okay that's not all
about mathematica okay
let me show you some some some things
you have not seen before in your life
you're in your
idiotic industry or programming idiots
you know that i have a deep hate uh
of them
not just because they are idiotic you
know
even me everyone okay we don't know not
we don't know everything we in fact
all things considered we don't not we
don't know nothing each one of us don't
know nothing
but however it is when you don't know
nothing but you think you know
everything that is the typical that you
know the elite programmers they tell you
what to do
they think they know they tell you that
oh you should you know you also
you know they they tell you what to do
let me show you the mathematica code
okay just go to one of my math page and
go to the math
home page let me show you the
mathematica
code okay plane title
and let me show you i i showed
i showed it in discord before
uh now this is written 20 years ago in
1997 okay i spent a year
half a year to write it uh where is it
okay i i guess i i we can go there we
can get there by clicking this link
uh what oh there
there it is there it is
now you see uh let me you see this this
code uh let me show let me show magnify
okay you see this code on the
on the left let's see if i can magnify
and move to the left
okay hold on second
you see now that's mathematical code
there is no manual formatting involved
okay a zeo type as you type the code
it automatically format on the flag
interactively
and this happened in 1998 okay 1997 1998
uh but the industrial programmers they
they have not seen it they never know
they've seen it but they think they know
everything okay back to the let's go
back to the
um code and let's do the emac this code
okay
so back to the code and we are going to
write the wrapper okay first of all
make them one line okay by the way
why do i prefer it one line that's
another topic i'm going to explain
why is it a single line like that
logical you know
the reason you have the one single line
is that like that is because
it's a logical unit that's a logical
semantic
unique unit okay you understand a
logical semantic unit
unit let me do uh let me compare okay
let me do this so you can see the
comparison okay
so for example this second function now
now i make it one single line
you see of course the first one is
easier to read but
what's the merit of the second one
you see the first one you organize your
code
by by kind of the by kind of the
syntactic
syntax you know uh nature
but the second one is a logical unit and
and okay we will
we'll get to that later okay first of
all so so let's make them one line again
okay save it and now let's let's start
to write a emac list
code to so i so i can the goal is that i
just press a button
and it automatically format i don't have
to go to e-shell
then you know deno and type the file
name
okay so uh let's first but but let me
now
read the comments to see if that there's
any comments
george says might need a demo to
understand how that automatic
indentation works yeah well
unfortunately i don't have mathematica
on my machine
i have actually i haven't coded
mathematica for
10 years uh because
because for reasons okay okay so
l cook hey good morning our cook i
prefer how golan
enforces one particular style with gold
format
exactly that's that's a great point okay
that is the point
you know i've been telling these two
programmers for for ten years
for for for 15 years now
uh but you know then you then they call
me a troll you know this big argument
controversy 1000 posts you know
half of them call me cause me a troll
idiot you know
but until you know this is like 15 years
ago until then go
go the go format you know the gold
language the rob
pike guy created golan and now they
suddenly realize oh yeah
oh yeah i mean i'm talking about them
i mean these things happen let me show
you article
uh let me um well anyway i have
i have like uh uh 20 articles about
formatting issues uh
many interesting details let's write a
emac this map
now okay so i'm going to write a command
okay so first of all uh cut this
and cut this uh wait delete this file
paste it back uh qualify it show in
browser so we
we get back our page but now we
let's go to let's uh document what we're
gonna do
write a um
write a e e this
code to auto format
javascript code using deno okay
that's that's that's what we are going
to do now okay so
okay so let's let's begin okay so create
a
create a uh emac base template
okay and start code here
magnify so defend define a function
uh and let's call it format
uh okay wait
format javascript okay um
it's let's just say format javascript
okay
so first of all so what first of all you
need to find
the file path of the current file okay
so
buffer how do you get the file path
uh buffer file
uh i forgot i forgot what's a command to
get the buffer file so let's go to
um go to
emacs blog and let's look up my
tutorial that's how i do i
i write the tutorial for myself as well
so what we need to do is to get the get
the buffer
file path okay uh so you look at you go
to buffer
and buffer file name yeah how could i
forget that
but for file name right here okay you
see that function
so close that so buffer file name
right so um so file path
is buffer file name okay
then uh that then we just call a shell
command
shell command okay uh yeah that's the
one we want
shell command a string
deno format
f path okay optional output buffer we
don't care error buffer we don't care
i think that's it i think that's it so
make it prettify and add
the dark string proper
format current buffer javascript
um i need my brief okay
hold on second let me show the pink
window
format current buffer javascript code
okay that's that's uh you know the so
there's a bit technical writing uh so
it's better written as
format javascript code in cleaning
current buffer okay
now that's a little tip in technical
writing now technical writing is a art
okay yeah you could say
so compare these two sentences the
second one is better
format javascript code in current buffer
okay
so that's our stock string eval the
buffer okay
now let's go back here we now we got a
command
okay now now let's let's try it okay now
let's make this javascript on its own
file again
so now meta x
format js okay that's the command we
need
that's okay do it
oops something something something error
no search file or directory
what
oh yeah you forgot the file name of
course yeah let's go back to this code
uh where is the list code you forgot to
give way oh yeah so you know this is a
dead string
we actually we need the
social command so let's say let's use
the format command
okay and here actually need the
percentage size
percentage s means a string and
you give the argument here f path so it
will create
you know format file denote format
file path that's and actually you need
to quote it now let's
it's not prettify it
evolve the buffer go back to the
javascript code
uh where is it there is our javascript
code
now this is you you see these single
unreadable long lines
now it takes it's a acquired taste
okay you you can see this
long line and get used to it it's
acquired test and
taste and and it's affiliated with
functional programming because if you do
functional programming
you'll find that this is
um sometimes good okay one single long
line because you can
because you don't because the goal is
not about the details of each
each construct you know each each
language construct the goal is to see
what's the input what's the output and
every
every the way you code functional style
everything is one semantic unit okay one
semantic
unit one semantic unit it's not syntax
it's not you know
do for you know the add a variable you
know the
two while looping it's not like that so
it has to do with functional programming
style
so anyway so i'm going to call the
command it should format it okay
so meta x format javascript do it
fantastic we
so now we have a command that does that
you know forget about the [ __ ] idiot
industry coders like that they are going
to tell you oh
oh you should you know they they do it
manually like uh like
i can try i can demo okay for example
let's switch
switch to javascript mod okay um
for example it's a javascript mod okay
that's a default mod in
in emac this for javascript so the
normal way people do is that you
you you know you do you you do it
manually basically almost one by line
with semi automation you know these
these
idiots they will say they will tell you
oh but most editors
support automatic formatting no they
don't you [ __ ] [ __ ]
you [ __ ] you idiots
okay you don't believe me yeah try
try it okay show me an editor that we
automatically
at this one single line of code by the
way this single line is a valid code it
runs
you can you see it's valid it's not it's
not missing semicolons or anything
all you have to do is reformat it but
that's not trivial in fact that's
uh that's uh you know the problem that
the problem of revamp
reformatting a programming language code
for most languages
is as difficult as writing a compiler
okay
yes you know i can tell you that it's
it's and
it's not the same thing as writing a
compiler but it's similar but it's it's
um as difficult as writing a compiler
maybe not not compared to writing an
optimized compiler because
optimization depends on how you know the
degree of
optimization but it's it's not it's not
a trivial problem
and deno you know this denote did it
great
so anyway about a week ago i did
a uh video talk show about deno so you
might
if you do javascript i recommend it okay
you might go watch my video so anyway i
have this command now this is fantastic
oh wait wait
uh what what happens now so
uh yeah java's javascript you know yeah
okay so
uh so let's go let's switch back to
javascript mod okay i don't like the
default javascript mod yeah
i have i'm learning javascript
okay so now we got a command command uh
let's try again okay it's because it's
so so great let's let's just call it
again
uh format.js okay
now watch single line becomes nicely
formatted do it oh god this
is so satisfactory
ah okay actually we can shut down today
now it's like
like you know this is nice one thing
done
so how long have i been rambling
check check video check i'm alive
audio check i'm in animation
uh so i've been talking for 30 minutes
okay
we can talk some more so we can talk
about formatting you know
many of the details of formatting or
some other things you know uh
so type your questions or anything okay
then i'm going to go random depending on
how
you know we can shut down in 10 minutes
or more
uh
hypocrisy in commercial software award
yeah
well it's not he i wouldn't say
hypocrisy you know
you might think so why is the industry
programming
you know they have so many uh ideas and
concepts that's not really good
but however it's so wide to be popular
you know
like you have fat and fashions you know
oop agile
patterns programming patterns you know
you they come and go
then you have fun functional programming
i like functional programming okay then
you have you know
you have all these uh why does it happen
and also about formatting and style like
the idioms you know they tell you about
like almost for every language
and even google they publish idioms like
they tell you how you
should do it the you know usu
programming style guide they
should be banned okay the [ __ ] they
should be completely banned
because the more formatting guide you
know the formatting style guide
the more your language becomes lousy and
cannot
incapable of automatic formatting that's
a big
topic okay i can talk about that for an
hour because
so so now we can start to talk about the
many of the
issues about formatting okay now again
look at mathematica
automatic formatting is on the fly and
not just that
not just other you know you see you you
look at these uh equations you might
think oh that looks like la tech
you know many of you love gnu's donald
glue
tekken like tech you know these [ __ ]
idiots the unix philosophy and elite
hackers they all love uh uh you um
you know unique you know uh donald
grunts latex
so you have to come back you know you
write you write incomprehensible
[ __ ] that's like that's tech created by
donald glue
then you have to uh render it you know
[ __ ] idiocy
in mathematica you type you know you
type
reasonable math formulas without all
those you know
unreadable [ __ ] you just type you know
for example square you just type square
square you know like correct two squared
you know
then it does the rendering on the fly
so it's not just automatic formatting
but it also
automatic you know render your math
uh formulas like that you know and it's
all automatic and this is
back in 1997 okay i
you know and the industrial programmers
they have not seen this
they don't know because mathematica is
not open source you know you want to buy
two thousand dollars two thousand
dollars
you have that um
but but they have student version like
for two hundred dollars or something
or hobbies version so
average programmers i mean i'm talking
about the c
c plus plus facts the java the c sharp
you know the average you know the
industrial programmers
uh including javascript uh python
ruby apparel and what else
you know they php you know in their life
they they have not seen this
they are you know but they had they have
great opinions like the
guido the the guido von russo the python
head you know they
they they think they know what what
should be you know
and the python the python language is is
there's the its syntax is the most
idiotic because
because he failed to understand this
concept
of automatic formatting in order to for
this to happen
your programming language needs to kind
of the syntax needs to support it
why is that because well that's another
topic
you know i have a lot of explanation to
do you know you read my articles you
know syntax soup
you know there there's like 20 articles
30 articles about
about the connection between between a
programming language
syntax and formatting okay this is not
trivial for
it's not programming language syntax
it's not a trivial matter
okay there are some computer scientists
idiots they say
oh syntax is not important semantic is
important they're [ __ ] idiots
syntax is the most important thing in a
programming language
because it governs your thought it it
directs your thinking thinking you know
towards future
if you know if you study mathematics the
history of math
notations you'll understand that you
know most programmers they don't know
nothing about math not
not to mention math history or the
history of math notations
but mathematicians know some of them you
know you study math history the history
of math notations
why did math for example create this you
know integral i mean what
you study it you know this history of of
almost
everything then you know how notations
change
they in many cases the notation okay
the notation direct your thought
it creates a new branch of mathematics
such as
abstract algebra okay this [ __ ]
programmer [ __ ]
funkheads anyway so i have 20 30
articles
about notations okay so so so
i was saying you know in order to have
this automatic formatting happen for
example you've seen mathematica
right uh where's my page
mathematica in order for this notation
to automatic
home formatting happen in order to
implement that
it helps greatly if you have a if your
programming language syntax supported
how for example this okay
this is a big topic okay for example
some
some example of programming language
that kind of support this thing
includes lisp okay this
api the programming language api uh xml
okay
because they are regular when it's
regular you you have
a great power to automatically format it
in any way you want i mean in automatic
and trivially you don't have to
study 10 years threading a password in
order to do that
for javascript you do you do need you
know you do need
complex very complex um
code to reformat the javascript code or
any c
syntax c see the [ __ ] head c and unix
that's a that's the the source of all
things wrong in programming
industry in uh c and c
and and unix the [ __ ] heads see
see anyway so
okay so i ran it a lot so so what are we
going to talk about now
i was going to say
uh yeah so programming language
programming language syntax
they have to do with formal language
okay the
theoretical computer science of formal
languages that that's
that's the fundamental uh branch of
theoretical computer science science
called formal language okay so
syntax formal language um
uh and and and and functional
programming
and math notations and they are all
related they are related okay
so so if next time you hear some some
people say oh syntax is not important
the the most important thing in
programming language is actually
semantics
such as you know they will say well
actually uh you know
what you know when people talk when
these programmers talk about
uh programming languages which is better
oh you'll say oh yeah
syntax doesn't matter yeah you know
next time you hear people say say that
slap them
[ __ ] idiots
you are watching talk show
that's what it is talk show okay so uh
more comments let's see
so am i like just rambling do you see
any content in what i'm saying or do you
just see
[ __ ] this or [ __ ] that if i if if all
you hear is
oh besides just [ __ ] this [ __ ] that
without no content then i failed okay
and you failed too
okay there's a lot of content i'm
talking about
why this is so uh post check
has a live freddie hey good morning
freddie from germany
come come bail button and
the idea of agile by the industry is the
worst you know so
yeah so so back to why does the industry
have
so many false ideas it's you know i
thought about that issue a lot
well basically it's because money you
know money drives these these
this uh code and force ideas
for example why is oop popular what i
mean why is for ten years ops
over the craze because java because the
microsystems they want to sell java
why they want to sell java because it
sells their servers
you know when back in year 2000 in 1995
some microsystems is pushing for java
over you know they spend
millions dollars marketing java and
pushing for the
oop uh numana you know
in the future every programming you know
every programming language will be oop
and you don't have to write much code
anymore because every
because oop is reused code reused so you
just
it's all you know all code will be
written
the ideal situation of op you know and
java programming language
you know right once run everywhere you
know that happened today
javascript not java javascript
uh you know so so why did op became a
fad you know all these false ideas which
is not true
we today we know you know the op fad
kind of died and today we know and
functional programming
also has some roots now so
most people average programmers we all
know okay op is not
you know the the the god you know
actually
there are pros and cons so then you have
functional programming you know
but but why is that back then let's say
20 years ago everyone you know
most programmers deeply believed oop
because
some equal systems money money is
talking
they they market they want to sell java
and and use and so they want to sell
they push for oop because java is
a pure oop language and they want to
uh and when java is popular they sell
their servers
hardware like uh four grand you know
ten ten thousand twenty thousand forty
thousand
servers because i was working on some
micro systems
so that's op that's why you have so back
to the topic you know
so why why does the industry have so
many fake force ideas
because money so java op is an example
from javascript system uh azure you know
why did why does azure become so kind of
popular in
circles money because with agile you
know they push for
methodology of of managing programming
teams
basically so that managers can control
the programmers
and then then you have thousands of
companies selling agile they
you know they come in as a consultant
they're gonna cons
you know they tell you what to do they
you know if you are a small company
they tell you how to improve your you
know your product
your your company's productivity and
control your programmers
so your programmers becomes a [ __ ]
a [ __ ] in a wheel they become
replaceable
so if you are the boss of the company or
manager you can just replace programmers
because they don't matter anymore
they want to make your company that way
someone paid me connect pay me isk
1 500 [ __ ] thank you
so what how so what is that worth
i want to know i mean doesn't matter how
much it it is worth i
you know i thank you uh so much but
how much is that
ten dollars thank you they're fantastic
ten dollars a nice
fat dinner and a nice fat
salmon sandwich okay so you know so
agile is popular because money basically
you know i
i i thought about these issues and
my conclusion comes down to
becomes quite boring you know my
conclusion is just money you know when
you hear
it you think oh that that's that's
that's not big
of reason that's that's like uh what
what kind of
um but actually you know that's just a
conclusion i get
you know so so agile is popular because
money you know
these snake oils then you have uh
pattern you know uh programming patterns
that's also popular for like 10 years
and so on so anyway but i need anyway i
want to get back to
um syntax okay
uh so so so many articles but first of
all so
let's wrap up okay i need to clean my
code and put my code on my
on my github so you guys can also use it
okay so i'm going to
so right now i'm going to cut this out
back to my talk show page okay put the
code here the javascript code
and also now go back to the lisp code
let's rename it
okay uh because i want to put it in my
javascript mod
so let's go to microsoft javascript mod
okay hold on second split go to
xr oh it's not here so let's
jump to it so um
okay here is our javascript mod
go to it so here is uh here is the file
javascript mod
so let's uh find all functions different
this matching lines so we have this
uh 10 functions so let's see where do i
want to
put the code uh
soft format okay
complete symbol i do okay uh here let's
put it here okay so
jump to it so there i want to put the
code here okay
so back to the code uh could
cut it d ddi file paste it
back here and
rename this to format
js code okay cassandra.js format js code
okay let's
uh yeah let's name that
okay and let's add this
command requires that uh
they know okay command
line tool let's just say that
command line to deno okay
okay save it go to the top and change
the version date
to okay and this is a
minor major version save it
ms for magic
i'm going to push to the
push to the server to github
so you can see uh
okay that's a new function okay
so stage it
push it commit
new function okay
that okay xr.js format js code
push commit then pp
to push
okay it's done now if you use just
search for xrd github
javascript mod you you have the code
okay close that
close that close that close that
okay and this is my talk show page
reformatted show in browser
uh there it is so i think that's it for
today
let's see how long have i been talking
now there is a lot of
issues i mean there are a lot of
interesting things to talk about
formatting
uh maybe next day unless you guys have
questions
questions anyone
pp what does uh pp mean clawfoot
let's see so i have been talking for 46
minutes okay
good time to close i guess
so connie where are you from corny
vs code okay uh aging is not
a kind process the older you get the
harder it is to recall stuff
okay i don't remember where that came
from
uh post check uh the idea the idea of
agile by the industry is the worst okay
kanban says i used clan format with cc
plus plus okay so is it well i don't
call it cc plus first so i
don't know how well so let me ask you a
question come back so
can it if you
c or c plus code if you format them into
a one single line
i mean a legal code so it still runs
and if you does the clan format
uh detangle the line into multiple lines
does it do that i want to know that let
me know if you know
so freddie have a unrelated question
shoot
iceland oh okay iceland great
uh so freddie says probably you have an
article on that
do you have an opinion on ogmod oh yeah
that's uh that's a common question
people ask me i saw
augment emacs oakmod is very popular uh
a lot of people
use you know love it you know it's you
know it's so-called a
killer feature of emacs you know the
killer app
of emacs for for the past 10 years
a lot of people use oak mod they came to
emacs because of ogmod now i don't use
it myself you know i tried to use it you
know since 10 years ago
i use it you know now you know i found
that i
don't really use that much because
i just use raw html because i grew up
with html since i started to use html
since 1997
you know manually code every tag and
i began to use emacs since 1998
okay so i you know i i manually code
html i write every i type out every
character of the tag in 1997.
uh you know in fact that's one of how
one of my website is created let me show
you okay that was
my earliest website uh
let's see okay so let's let's go back to
my math page
so uh go to go to
it math blog
go to the math home page
a visual dictionary of special claim
playing curves okay that's my first
project in 1997 so i wrote it
i typed every tag you know character of
html attack manually
since 1997. then i started to use emacs
in 1998 okay so it's actually after
uh and by you know
so i'm i'm so i'm very used to html i
know you know i know everything about
html then then css then javascript
so so i just do
i i don't use oak map much it's a it's a
nice
package you know i yeah i
i i'm not a big user
uh
oh so you also your so clan format
on save okay cleanse cam format i mean
my question is k
it will it reformat so that one single
long line i mean if you
compact your code into one single line
when you
use clan to reformat it will wield it
separate it into multiple lines that's a
key question okay
i'm not asking just about reformat
because there are
tons of reformat reformat tools but
almost always they they they are
incapable of
separating your single long lines into
multiple lines
they they simply just pre they are just
like trivial pretty print
most of them they do not actually
actually pass your code like a compiler
and and separate your lines that's
my question so does the clan reformat
tool
you know the c clan format does it
actually separate
one single long line you know it's
let's say 20 000 characters you make
yours your source file into one single
long line
20 000 characters we are the kind of the
format to separate into loneliness
that's my question
so answer to my question is yes okay so
so
society has improved you know i haven't
been so yeah
so that's great thank you
okay so that's it that's it for today
thank you guys for watching yeah
if you like my stuff buy my tutorials
okay you can buy my javascript tutorial
javascript in depth okay or you can buy
my emacs tutorial
uh uh you know buy some keyboards
for my website on amazon buy my emacs
tutorial
okay thank you guys bye
shut down in one minute shut down in one
minute
and join discord okay we have diversity
diverse people
hey alan so what is alan saying
thank you freddie freddie oh yeah my
opinion about oakmont
it's a good it's a great it's a great uh
tool i personally don't use it because i
happen to
use html for you know 20 years
for 25 years
uh okay so go and go to
go to yeah i'm done