good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show today is April
12 2019 and the AI singularity is coming
soon we don't know for sure and so today
I'm going to talk about so Assange
Julian Assange got as god erase arrested
you know there's a video you probably
have seen it you know you go to youtube
it's everywhere
so he has been holed up in the edge of
Kuato embassy
you know without seeing sunlight for the
past year things turned bad and then
he's you know the the cops in UK went in
and grabbed him and you know put him
into a truck so that's a sad thing
so what we gonna talk about today
santosh show Emacs
the fantastic Emacs our talk show today
state faded the press the key and good
morning guys good morning guy so pick a
topic you know there's this interesting
about videos you know when I started to
do video I was thinking you know I
wasn't sure what's a goal you know it's
like some people most people vast
majority of people on YouTube for
example when they create a video channel
you know typically their goal is to make
money you know they prepare everything
is nice you know things are prepared and
they
patreon lady PayPal ready and you know
they focus on topic on one topic
especially you know I noticed that since
last year or maybe this year maybe since
2018 there is a surge you know a huge
amount of people starting to do youtubes
and I'm thinking you know the
implication to of that I mean what you
know where is society going you know a
lot people are doing you know videos
youtube and I'm kind of thinking you
know so since 10 years ago everyone
started to have a cell phone and and a
camera of course a camera and the video
camera you know that wasn't so before
you know before for example in 2005 for
example we we kind of thought of that I
mean I thought of that in and other
people of course you know we thought of
that but nobody is sure that everyone is
going to have a camera in their pocket
you know if fail you know a small
computer of very powerful and video
recording and so what's the implication
of that we don't know but anyway you
know so you know apples began iPhone you
know Microsoft actually began it you
know Microsoft began some kind of
Windows tablets and if hopped you know
until Steve Jobs
you know the genius marketer so he
created you know iPad and you know iPad
then iPhone and and we have and then
Google you know want you know piece of
the pie Google started Android phone and
today we have you know the situation of
where everyone is using you know I have
a cell phone in the pocket a fairly
powerful computer in a pocket and so hi
guys say something
and you know yeah so you have a small
computer you know so the question is
what what is the implication you know we
don't know I mean it's hard to say it's
really hard to say and the concept of
singularity you know you know what the
singularity means singularity wait am i
talking right yes they are like talking
check yeah good so do you
okay the concept of singularity is that
hey Benjamin great to see you so
singularity is you know the concept of
singularity is is that when when the day
a I became sentient Oh a I become or we
really have some sort of strong AI
artificial intelligence that's that that
that day is called the singularity
basically that's a concept you know I
have been you know observing humanity
I'm you know as a hobbit hobby as a
hobby and you know I've been you know
reading about all these technology
advances in observing it and trying to
see what happens but you know I read a
lot but even so if you ask me what's
gonna happen oh we are singularity come
actually I don't know I mean there are
many experts on that you know for
example they are philosophers there are
computer scientists there are
mathematicians they all talked about it
and you know robotics and AI but we're
talking about strong AI you know in when
you talk about AI they are you know you
roughly you can say they are weak AI
artificial intelligence and strong AI
basically weak AI is when when for
example computers Google fr0 can play
indeed human okay that's kind of weak AI
and strong AI is basically the concept
where when machine has human
intelligence you know now AI has
improved to you know we have automated
you know driverless cars you know
machines can drive cars and we have
machines can fake go which is far more
complex yeah more complex than chess and
machine can beat you know the words
coach champion and but however you know
as far as human intelligence goes it
appears you know we are quite far from
it you know all sentient you know it
appears we are quite far from it
the other thing is that you know the
definition of strong AI you know the
definition of AI is really elusive
because because when we try to define
what what means intelligence we cannot
basically we you know there is no solid
mathematical definition of intelligence
now one of the way to test AI is so
called what's what's the name of that
thing you know you so you you have you
talked to a computer basically I'm a
human ok you so you have a human and you
type like online CH online chat you know
you chat to another guy but the other
guy behind the screen you know you know
you you don't see him
Turing test yes exactly thank you so
there there's these two mean tests
actually how do you pronounce that
turning or to mean to mean I guess so
basically the idea is that so you know
I'm a human and I chat you know using
text you know with another being that
well basically it's a machine okay I can
ask any questions I want I you know just
like chat you know online chat text you
know text messaging and if I'm not able
to tell you know the other side you know
his machine then we say that it passed
Turing test you know the the but the
machine has to mean test but even that
is kind of elusive you know I I don't
think that that meaning that meaning
that suppose one day you know suppose
one day the machine has tuning test but
even so we do not have a machine that
actually have human intelligence you
know so that's an interesting thing you
know yeah let's look at genuine test
let's Wikipedia Wikipedia is everything
wait wait how do I get so many windows
close that train has live okay go back
here and so tune it has let's see
magnify magnify
yeah but anyway it doesn't say so let's
check Allen tuning
so Alan Turing is a gay you know he's a
gay and back then when gay was illegal
so the government you know yeah act you
know and you know put him in prison and
basically kind of I don't well the
government you know put him in prison
and he you know he eventually he ate a
poisoned Apple and killed himself
I'm not I don't remember it's forced or
not I don't know I don't think it's
forced but anyway he killed himself
because of that because you know being
gay and it was illegal homosexual yeah
so anyway Alan droning how do you
pronounce that I'll just say chewing
yeah so anyway so the Turing test and
history philosophical background
versions okay strength weakness
variations
excuse me emotional and aesthetic
intelligence human behavior intelligence
behavior behavior so anyway so there is
there's actually quite several other
tests you know people you know a
philosopher so computer scientists you
know or mathematicians they they created
they proposed so they are variations but
actually I remember reading an article
that that is it's somewhat isn't it's
somewhere here or maybe another article
basically I read another test is that
you know you say that when AI has human
intelligence is when a robot you know
can walk into any person you know any
let's say American's home and make a cup
of coffee it's just a you know so you
know for example I can go to anyone's
home and you know I can just make a
coffee even I have never been there but
when when apart can do that you know
they say it's it's a we have AI but you
know so AI there's a weak AI and strong
AI well let's do this go to Akali anyway
so I kind of lost so anyway what's up
what's up guys so what topic should we
talk about I wasn't prepared here you
know I you know I wasn't prepared for my
videos because I don't like scripted
videos ok the here's a this okay here's
another topic the the thing is yeah I
was saying you know a lot of people
coming to YouTube I noticed there's a
surge of you know youtubers they they
usually
you know like 99% of them they come to
YouTube they have one they basically are
they do that for to make money you know
they they focus on some subject you know
and you know a lot a lot people are
apparently you know talk about politics
because these days politics can make you
reach you know it for example your you
know especially if you are anti social
justice
you know those scan you know those scan
so you go on YouTube you do you talk
about them and a lot of people want to
watch it but I'm not sure about the
other side oh yeah yeah absolutely the
other side as well if you are you know
like I'm dividing us in not just us
basically all the white nations white
Western people nations United States
Canada Australia and much of Europe
especially Western Europe like UK and so
on you know these white people Western
countries they they they are pretty
infected you know it's going it's like
pretty bad it's going down here down
here because you have excuse me okay
here's the lemme
so I'm back so yeah these white people
countries they are you know doing pretty
bad this political instability you know
they start to have heavy censorship
every day they are banning people and
you know and there's a protests and
there's violence you know yeah so it's
it's really it's it's going bad but not
so much for you know it's China or Japan
you know these or or Islamic countries I
suppose you know because I think this
has to do with language you know because
you know before I was thinking you know
Chinese you know you see is each you
know there are so many countries they
speak different languages and you know
today you might not think much of it but
languages is actually a huge barrier you
know for example the Western thought you
know they don't happen in China because
China you know most of them they don't
they do not speak English you know well
some of them do like you know maybe 1%
actually if if you talk if we are
talking about people Chinese people in
China or Taiwan who can actually
understand let's say when they watch
news on TV American TV it's less than 1
in 10,000 you know even less money in
100,000 now not even that you know one
your median you know people actually do
that so this so language you know
different languages it's actually truly
a barrier but even but you I mean today
we have like globalization you know
Twitter and social medias we can
communicate and we have phones that can
translate but even that that you know
it's still you know it's a language
language it's a pareo
so you know so you when you know when
trends or things happens in
english-speaking countries they don't go
to you know they don't go into Russia
they don't so this Western current
situation you know the the social
justice kind of thinking they don't go
into Asia they don't go into Japan like
if like they are YouTube's okay you can
go to youtube you know there are people
Japanese people they ask Japanese you
know what do you think of you know
feminism and and many other topics you
know that's that's hot potato in USA for
example you ask them the Japanese their
response is like completely of like they
don't understand what you're talking
about like you know what is feminism
Oh feminism is good it's for one you
know women and but then you start to ask
them details like they they don't they
have no idea what you're talking about
you know you know these social justice
concepts and things you know that
cultural appropriation many explaining
this this this you know a bunch of
things they have like jargons you know
so there are people you know and in
cultural appropriation you know back
then few months ago and it happens to be
constantly like there are some white
girl okay she is wearing a Chinese cheap
out let's let's show sorry so so guys if
you have a topic just type it okay you
go to my talk sorry showed
talk show page and type the topic and
we'll talk about that okay so it's not
showing here but I won't go into it then
didn't find the page but anyway cultural
appropriation so there are people on
YouTube you know they ask Japanese or
Chinese this concept you know you find
it they they have no idea what you're
talking about like you know this social
justice issues
so language is you know a huge barrier
you know but before you know before the
past few years I you know India India in
India it so happens that India
English is actually their official
language one of okay the other one is
Hindi you know in India's it so happens
they have like tens of languages you
know mutually incompatible hey Ronnie
I'm gonna answer that question so India
is you know they have lots of languages
and you know and it so happens that
India decided because of the UK you know
Imperial imperialism you know the UK was
ruling India so they decided anyway
when Indian India becomes independent
they decided that English is going to be
the official language language basically
so so they grew up with in English in
fact you know all the technology
programming you know the English is like
almost like their official and which
Hindi and others are kind of like I mean
technically they are also official but I
think you know I think they are actually
just secondary you know so well if if
any Indian is watching you know feel
free to correct me so but basically
India you know they use English as a
language you know one one time I was
looking sorry
you know one one time I was studying
Chinese websites let's say encoding yeah
I was doing research what character
encoding do Chinese sites use so you
have you know I found the most popular
you know the most popular ranked sites
around the world you know you go to
Alexa this this website Alexa they rank
you know the top 10 1000 you know the
top 1,000 sites by traffic so so this so
I did this report back then back in 2012
so back then the pie do which is a
Chinese search engine is ranked globally
number 5 QQ is ranked globally numbered
nice so basically lots of the top ones
is Chinese sites but anyway my goal is
to find out what are the most popular
you know the big Chinese websites what
encoding do they use okay and here's a
result you know the pipe I do is using
utf-8 on the front page and so on you
know this is backed in seven years ago
so anyway you can see their ranking you
know I did for you know China websites
these are the most popular Chinese
websites and these are the most popular
Chinese websites in Hong Kong in Taiwan
and Japan they you know Japan speaks
Japanese you know these are the most
popular in the ranking and South Korean
website 308 is the highest ranked
website then I found they they I looked
into Indian so it turns out Indian you
know they don't have their websites or
you know basically they use whatever
American is using you know so in USA you
know whatever is the top website is also
the same for India because you know
English is their official language you
know that's you know that's just the
it's like their language I think there
are also websites of using Hindu but
it's kind of very small very rare you
know you don't see it I'm not sure it
even ranks within 10,000 you know so
yeah so Indian they use English so and
here's a point you see the language is
superior okay so before I was thinking
you know when I learned that you know a
few years ago I learned India oh they
are adopted English you know stay
official language and I was thinking you
know maybe China you know should do it
too why not because then you just have
one single language as a global language
you know it's kind of I mean from a
technical you know computer engineer
nerd the point of view it's kind of
efficient if you know the whole world
just uses one language you know why not
so I was thinking you know Chinese
because Chinese they you know Chinese
character is very complex and since
1950s they you know Chinese people have
been thinking trying to they are trying
to modernize China and why over the
problem is was considered the Chinese
language the writing system is a problem
so they at one point they want to
replace it to be Latin based you know
like read of Chinese characters instead
of you use English alphabets you know
kind of romanized Chinese well anyway so
I was thinking maybe you know I was
thinking about idea why not just adopt
English as your your country's language
and when you talk about languages this
year the issue my the garbage truck is
our size making our noises it's
very annoying hold on a second
yes there on the English programming
languages they are used in China there's
one but it's not it's it's not very
popular there is there's some popularity
but not very popular the the the garbage
truck making loud noises it's going away
so anyway back to the I was so I was
saying you know why not adopt English
but about last year you know a few
months ago half a year ago or something
I realized you know I realized it's a
great thing you know China or other
countries you know it's a problem it's a
great thing that China having adopted
English because all the languages who
you know speak English fluently they are
infected with the social justice thing
you know including India because you
know there they are India this is
happening India - I don't know too much
about it but I can see you know I yeah I
can see that India also got into this
feminism social justice stuff so I
thought so so that's when I realized
actually a language barrier is a good
thing you know we don't want to we don't
want to have like one language for you
know the other thing is that is is that
when you talk about languages there is
always a cultural aspect to it you know
for example in Canada you know on the
east the quebec east side of Canada they
are French speaking and there's always
political fights you know about you know
that region they want you know they want
to speak French and you know they don't
want to be unified like winning one one
language falls in this you know constant
political fight about languages same
thing with
you know in Taiwan there is a part of
Taiwan they switch they speak Chinese
dialect that's that spoken in southern
China and you know this is also a big
political issue so I mean so when you
talk about languages the it's not is
it's not like nerds thought it's just a
matter of you know efficiency like why
not let's just have a universal language
actually it's not like that because
there's a lot culture attached to it so
so anyway so I was saying Indian
Parliament vengi is shin ho ho cane yeah
who can oh yeah um so yeah so I realized
you know this you know so so if you know
if for example it's you know if the word
adopted one language you actually lose a
lot cultures you know the a lot culture
will be good good so what I was what I
was saying I was saying something else
before from other feature intelligence
to I need to go back I forgot what was I
talking about why did we start to talk
about languages because of India I
mentioned this because of India but but
why did I start to talk about English
languages I forgot
oh yeah YouTube so so a lot of people
are making videos on YouTube oh yeah so
the other thing I want to say about
YouTube is that yeah they want to make
money
the thing I want to say so I'm making
videos but I always wasn't sure exactly
what to make you know what you like I
don't have a goal I you know I want to
make money of course but that's not you
know that's not my like go I don't want
that to be your core you know I had and
the thing about the thing I want to say
about the video is that you know I I
don't actually watch a video because
watching videos is extremely time
consuming you know you spend hours you
know maybe you read new so sometimes I
mean language tutorials you watch video
you can just watch a few and your day is
gone you know and as compared to writing
if you especially for learning
programming languages I prefer to read
you know I almost never never watch any
videos on foreign languages but the
thing is that actually you know so so
reading writing is great you know it's
kind of efficient but actually you lose
a lot of things because it's not natural
you know it's great for recording
history or for mathematics you
communicate complex ideas where you know
for you know recording knowledge like
encyclopedias and so on but but it's
actually not natural because the natural
way is like video you know human you
know you talk face-to-face you see all
the expressions you see all the nuances
you teach you know that's a tradition
you tell a story and people learn from
it you t apprentice apprentice you for
example I'm gonna teach you you know
Emacs or something you learn you know
you learn from all the sort of nuances
you know and
and and that is actually natural because
that's you know that's that's with us
you know for thousands of years we see
we observe we learn but not reading not
not from reading and and you know I'm
thinking about this peak I also noticed
a lot people a lot programming tutorial
website you know they are commercial
websites they they teach you for example
if you want to learn Python there are
lots of websites that you pay and they
have prepared videos like lectures you
know course one two three four then
after you know watching those videos you
spend maybe five hours or something then
you learn you know you learn how to
program Python and I noticed actually a
lot people like that I mean even even
experienced programmers I don't really
like that myself but so I've been
thinking actually that's actually that's
a natural way to go you know so a lot of
people like that so what am i what am I
saying I was saying yeah so I the I
guess the point I'm making is that video
is actually you know today we have the
technology for video and video when you
can see people face to face it's
actually the more natural communication
yeah but the drawback is of course you
don't you have to spend a lot of time
but it's kind of you know that it is
natural so let me read the comments
India is an aberration no doubt it will
split apart in the near future why what
do you mean interesting China China
still uses ASCII for domain name yeah I
think the you know the International
domain name where you can use anything
other than ASCII - for the domain is I
don't think it's popular yeah yeah I
don't remember offhand I've seen one
searched
yeah I don't remember so if there are
any non-english programming language
yeah there is
let me show you so I'm gonna type
Chinese this one a lot of people we are
using it but it has not become popular
to the level of being an industrial
programming language you know in Chinese
in China there are lots of websites you
know they are equivalent to Facebook
something equivalent to Twitter
something equivalent to YouTube and they
are very big
you know they I just in some cases even
bigger than you know the Google ones I
think you know I don't know for sure but
I mean you can see from this character
encoding you know the pie dough is the
words ranking number five you know all
these are within top 100 Chinese website
they are all Chinese you know they are
all Chinese characters used by you know
because China has allowed people that's
why it's a huge market 1.4 billion it's
it's like 20% of words population and
they are thriving you know I see Chinese
photos and you know there are cities
it's like you features look at the
photos it's like better than better than
New York better than more like more you
see it's like more advanced than New
York or San Francisco or LA all the
skyscrapers you know like brand-new
skyscrapers over like so many yeah so so
there is so so there is this language
that's completely you know in Chinese I
mean other keywords are Chinese so China
has all these websites
consistent he went on e CH Indonesia so
they are oh yeah so there are tutorials
of this language
wait there's a logo and so he says easy
to learn I'm trying to find a logo
because I'm I remember I have seen a
logo let's go to buy do so anyway there
is this language but it's you know for
example all these Chinese speak websites
they are not using this so this language
has not reached the level of being
industrial it's more like considered
like visual basic you know it's a it's
design for easy to program easy to learn
and I know they are I know there are
others I think in Japan and I think in
other languages I'm not sure but and
this one I know Chinese people who
program me in this language
yeah they have this I never seen this
but I recall they have a logo but I'm
not seeing the logo here yeah but the
last time I look at it is like four
years ago yeah this week this window I
remember this so that's how you program
it you know it's just Chinese characters
anyway so so Finch says oh yes there are
Finch says q al B is one example that
comes to mind a lisp like a Rea big
script based language I see and Finch
says many old ones used to be
Cyrillic Oh language is tied with
culture and identity yes India bother my
French is a I spend some time there and
keep an eye out skill for geopolitical
reasons so you spend some times in India
were you were you from okay and so that
is very true so Finch what's your
ethnicity that's why that is why I find
Chinese characters fascinating even if
input is difficult with modern keyboards
yeah but actually as far as I know you
know if you the speed is actually not
slower than English because you know
like average Chinese person typing
Chinese for you know daily chat to his
family or you know her mom or her
boyfriend girlfriend you know Chinese
college students you know they they do
their chats stuff compared to English
people chatting with each other the
keystrokes is actually not more because
well because to type one Chinese
character
well one Chinese character usually is I
mean it is one word so you know on
average one Chinese character is
equivalent to about six five or six
English letters you know alphabet
letters so in general if you you know
type in Chinese and having English is
about I think it's about the same number
of keystrokes so George George says
interesting how a Chinese programming
language works seems like it would be
hard to pass since they are usually no
spaces in Chinese no not really
I mean as far as parsing goes passing
the difficulty of parsing depends on
your syntax but Chinese language oh but
you know basically like just consider
Python you know you just be placed on
English words by Chinese and there you
have it you know it's just it's just a
different Unicode that's oh by the way
there there was okay there was a Chinese
version of Python language different
from this one now this one this Chinese
programming language is called if you
translate this evn if you translate it
it means easy language okay that's
that's what it means but there there was
a Chinese version of Python which
basically is Python you know exactly the
same Python but you replace all the
English keywords by Chinese characters
so last time I checked which is four
years ago it wasn't it kind of died died
off yeah maybe that's
let's try that see if we get Chinese
Python
yeah I think that's it
Python information in Chinese there are
some ground rules what now it's not this
but I can show you
this one
yep
yep this is Chinese this is Python in
Chinese language yeah it's I think it's
dead version 2.1 3 let's see translate
to English lieutenant is a Chinese
foreign language based on Python
translation language yeah it's I think
it's dead you know among Chinese I mean
Chinese for Emma's in many ways like
just like you know English programmers
you know we have you have elite you know
you have elite group like we think I
mean community okay you have certain
people who think they are better than
you you know this happens in every
community you know people compete so in
Chinese programming community there are
certain people they think they are elite
and these people their ideas is
basically following whatever you know
the American you know is going you know
like like the UNIX philosophy you know
the Python whatever you know Python pep
and whatever so they are certain you
know group the certain programmers you
know a small part of Chinese programmers
they think they are they are kind of the
elite type and they they read English
you know they do everything like almost
like everything they do they prefer the
English version like you know very very
English so it's like they are superior
you know and their idea is basically
they I would call you know brainwashed
so whatever you know you know whatever
you know for example Emacs you know in
in in America is Emacs you know Emacs
users are considered you know like elite
you know like oh the eMac you say oh he
uses eMac it's like oh he's a hacker you
know he's you know high high high open
above us something like that
so this similar thing happens in China
you know a man
his programmers and in these people
their ideas tends to be to follow
whatever you know American for example
in Chinese when you program check Python
for example or Ruby or any any other
language there's a question like in
comments for example in comments I can
type Chinese you know you know improving
in comments I can type Chinese so there
is a question in fact I can use some
variable names or function names in
Chinese so there's a question you know
sometimes Chinese they talk about I mean
there are Chinese forums I can show you
they talk about they debate about you
know whether should you use Chinese in
function names you know well first of
all you should you use yeah usually for
comments it's quite common
yeah to see Chinese characters you know
because English is not their native
language you know but the but there is a
question you know should you use Chinese
for function names so variable names and
typically the answer from the elite
types you know what I mean by you need
for example you go to you go to stack
overflow suppose you ask the question
then you know usually you get a bunch of
elite elite facts
you know they sit there they tell you
what to do you know they tell you what
should be the correct answer you know
like they have a tendency to to shape
what length answer should be okay
besides you know whatever the rules I
mean the rules is one thing but they
tends to their answer you know the
philosophy or idea tend to be shaped
into a certain way on Stack Overflow for
example and if you deviate that they
vote you down you know for example I go
to stack for floor I ask my questions
some you know I had you know I had asked
questions and they they all they pan you
if you are not too polite they pan you
they don't like your opinions okay
rhaggy
utter stupidity like one they are
about JavaScript compiler anyway that's
another story so you know these idiots
they sit there all day you know they are
lobbying to hack to Stack Overflow all
hacker news you know read it all day I
mean there they are like a small group
they sit there all day they they like
monitor and they you know they monitor
they ban people they if you ask a
question you know that's not what they'd
like to see they make it you know your
question is answerable oh you know this
is violate this or that you know the you
know and make it you know things like
that they control it I mean this is like
a formation of power I mean it existing
anywhere in any form in companies you
know in companies you have cooperate you
know fight man you know who becomes the
manager who gets a raise and so on you
know and same thing is same thing in you
know the programming groups but anyway
so in China there are also certain
people like that they tends to be you
know whenever they have these elite
ideas they tends to follow whatever you
know the American types the UNIX
philosophy you know that you like Unix
Linux you know kind of thing okay how
long I've been going 11 people watching
great so hello from India hello
so let's let me finish reading a comment
says
so Finch says India India has three
major ethno-linguistic groups and a
thousand mini languages and ethnicities
yes it is an artificial state created by
the British I see and looking at current
developments it's heading for partitions
within half a century at most okay that
seems that seems bad
I'm not your Indians we will find that
you know may not agree so Ben says India
will soon have a bigger population in
China yeah you know China they have like
one child rule you can only have one
child because China by tradition usually
everyone wants son they want boys you
know because guys you know boys are
considered the family girls are not you
know girls you marry the girls off you
know girls belong to whoever the
husband's family so you want to you know
that's the traditional thinking you know
so so you know to to continue or your
family you have to have a son and also
son makes money girls usually not you
know because you know in cultural
agriculture countries you know son can
you know have muscle to to work in the
field you know the rice field and so on
so they always want a son but so if
we've you know a couple they had a baby
it's not a son it's not it's a girl
they're gonna have a baby again you know
until they have a son so they that's a
traditional I mean this is like you know
that oh that kind of you can't is Oh
tradition not today not meaning I don't
think people think like that today's
generation so anyway that was before so
so try China but China you know the
population is a problem you have you
know 1 billion people when you have a
lot of people you really do have a
problem you know American when America
look at Chinese you know they say oh
they are not they are inhuman you know
yeah
wait until you know what you know China
Chinese says why don't we send you 1
billion you know we sent 1 billion
Chinese to USA let's see if what you
gonna do you're gonna have lose because
you you can have you know like I mean
you can understand that just by thinking
if it is your family you know if you and
your wife your family you have five
babies six maybe seven eight babies how
long can you sustain you don't wait you
know if you are not wealthy where does
the money come from you have to feed you
know your babies people
so anyway Chinese they there's a
population issue so they decided to have
you know one-child policy
you can have one only one child if you
have more you must pay heavy heavy taxes
something like that but now you're a few
years ago they reverse that because they
start to see is it's starting to have a
problem because we don't have people we
don't have young people anymore so they
try to reverse that but it's kind of
late because the Chinese young people
change in China they don't want children
just like the Western countries they you
know they they are not making babies so
when these things happens about
population you see we don't know what is
the answer we don't know like for
example back then 50 50 years ago 100
years ago there's the problem the
overpopulation problem is called Musil a
problem anyone remember the name
basically you know people started to
worry you know what happens when you
have too many people I mean the earth
cannot sustain it but so you know
there's a big war you know around the
globe you know trying to tell people to
not you know I mean it's a issue
population overpopulation issue and and
in fact this this is a problem for many
underdeveloped countries like Africa
they have a lot people they keep having
people Draenei they don't have
contraceptives and they are very
extremely poor now of course there are
other reasons corruption and you know
social structure problems to create you
know so there are many other problems
but but still they make a lot you know
they don't have they don't use they
don't have abortion they don't have
contraception so a lot of people it
really does create problems on the other
hand I mean basically like like 50 years
ago 100 years ago we don't know as I
mean the whole human you know beans you
know scientists we we cannot be sure you
know we don't know what will happen when
when there are more people so it's
unknown you know but now we know that at
least for the developed countries the
technology actually can advance so much
to the point that we don't need to worry
about population you know because you
know the population rises but but oh but
meanwhile we have genetic engineered
food you know almost like every every
crop every potato's fruits you know they
are all genetically engineered so that
you know you can produce ten times more
before you know so that kind of you know
so we don't see a problem but also
meanwhile people started to in developed
countries people start to not want we
have children and the effect of that is
actually we don't know you know we could
we you know you could be said that we
are already seeing many of the bad
effects you know the thing I would
consider the Millennials in social
justice is one of the symptoms we don't
know you know we don't we can't be know
we don't know for sure
you know what's causing what
people's so let's see okay lots of
comments so let me read the comments how
long I've been going thirteen people
watching so
looking for current developments it says
okay so partitions okay India will soon
have bigger population in China yeah
it looks like India China's population
growth has been stagnated the population
growth yeah has been stan stagnated
since when I don't remember but India
last time I check is still going because
I you know I've been looking at these
issues like since like 15 years ago
oops let's type English
you know I have you know I've been
studying this issue looking at this I
worried are you worried about this
population under the firmament so here's
a map you can see you know the the iCore
the red plaque you know human animals
like the like the Matrix movie you know
human animals in a sense is a virus you
you go it you know you grow and you wipe
out everything else you you wipe out the
animals insects whatever you destroy the
ecosystem so in a sense you know it's
like a virus you know or some kind of a
prank so this these are red flag so
China India and Europe it's interesting
you know America USA actually don't have
that many people I mean Europe is much
worse you see this red red plaque but in
USA is good and here is a population
growth by content easy so here is the
population over the you know the past
10,000 years you see it's only until you
know 2000 year 2000 let's see
ad oh this is 81 so this is actually
yeah those are PC so this is 80s so
beginning in like you know studying
around here 7 1700 that's basically when
that's when the Industrial Revolution
you know we start to have machines you
know basically it's it is technology
that changes society you know and we are
you know today with Google and other
fish intelligence and robotics and so on
it's it's a it's a it's a big change you
know we are entering into some kind of
new era so you see the population you
know is suddenly you know just in the
past 300 years
is shoot up to six billion and this
chart is back in 2003 I wrote this page
in 2003 you see this this chart is back
in 2003 but anyway today you know all
the industrial developed nations we are
not the population growth is actually
declining so people begin to encourage
people to make babies yeah but you know
the thing about future is that we nobody
can really say what will happen so Finch
say is just like Yandex and
Ronnie hi Ronnie Ronnie says visual
basic for applications use inside Emma's
office come in localized versions oh I
see interesting Finch says I'm
Australian but expat digital nomad okay
that's good
George says typing English is all muscle
memory though typing Chinese you have to
select no actually if you pick you know
type time in Chinese actually yeah it is
true you have to select but that's only
that happens only when you are typing
you are not familiar with it such as me
for example you know because because
okay for example let's let me type
Chinese okay so song one okay it picks
you know the reason it's you know for
four people in China they type it you
know so fast you like you almost you
don't have to choose because because of
the statistical you know the input
systems they use statistics to guess the
whole sentence so you actually don't
choose one character at a time you type
the pronunciation for the whole sentence
and the sentence the whole thing shows
hello from India hello
your name is in some kind of Indian
script
I cannot read and understand Satish
Oh Satish Oracle bone script let's see
yeah Chinese character so I have this
page about Chinese character styles from
ancient to today so that's that's over
COBOL and this is back in 1600 BC so you
know they have on Oracle on turtle
shells so these are oracle bone is so
called Oracle bone script which is
basically the first Chinese characters
then we have Browns what's so called
brown script you know the Oracle bone
script and I cannot read it no you know
you basically Chinese cannot read it you
have to you know you have to study in
order to read them but starting
beginning so the Browns Browns
inscription Brown script so code Brown
script
starting from 1600 BC to 771 BC this you
can actually read for example both of
this thing you know the some of these
things are very oh this this this code
Ron is 782 PC so it's almost like 3,000
years old I and and I can you know
understand most of it you know the
characters like like most Chinese you
don't have to have special training
and that's quite amazing because you
know you are literally literally reading
three thousand or 2,000 years old stuff
well actually I don't understand them
but you recognize I mean it doesn't you
you know some characters are still
pretty much the same but it doesn't take
much to I mean it doesn't differ much
from from today's Chinese for example
this is let me magnify for example this
character is King King this is me I
think anyway
yeah so anyway these are some of the old
Chinese you can find these on Wikipedia
like I mean you can find them you know
on Wikipedia so satish says we have
Hindu we programming languages in India
a bit for teaching purposes
it supports basic CC purrs first I see
Hindu e entirety of phoning human
speaking is discussing okay
okay let me maybe read the comment so
many now quickly I want to magnify can
magnify this my eyes are getting bad
mentality of fawning is disgusting Finch
says my aim Finch says my aim is truly
Mandarin in Hebrew so that I can in feel
infiltrate chat forums and get a feel of
the pose of the country's yeah that's
what I do
early doing that a bit with Russian yeah
that's a great way to know the people
you know what's actually happening what
the people actually say you know instead
of reading you know newspapers you know
because you know because usually they
are either you know controlled or from
government you know you know fake like
you go fake news or all from activists
you know they want to push some idea so
George says I'm I'm am unpopular at work
for saying we should use American
English in function names instead of
Australian English makes sense to me
since it's consistent with all the
libraries we use there's not much
difference right I mean I know there's
some difference in some words but but
for function names I mean does that
differ that much you know American
English versus Australian English so
George George you from Australia oh yeah
from perch I think so Finch says people
stuck in an english-speaking part of the
interweb missing out a lot of reality
yes yeah that's that's so true you know
really because yeah that's so much true
because because I can read Chinese so I
get it guy I get to see you know Chinese
you know China's take take on a world
everything you know but I don't read
other language but I mean yeah it is
true that you know suppose if you speak
Russian you actually see things you know
you don't see you know if you you know
seeing English only publications it's
actually so true you know because the
language barrier you when you once you
dig into the other language you see lots
of things
Haidee young Tony someone they can use
the language they know for function
names seem stupid yeah that kind of yeah
that's true you know so you know some of
these lead programmers and I mean some
of them are my acquaintances or friends
on Twitter you know you know and many of
them are kind of elite because I you
know I I wallow in the UNIX you know
world you know open source I and I am a
big Emacs user so so I am often
perceived as you know one of the hackers
so you know but but on the other hand
actually I'm actually my opinion is oh
it is done conformal you know
nonconformist I don't like those so yeah
so some of the Chinese you know they
when it when they when the question
comes up whether you should use Chinese
for function names you know some
function names some lead each you know
the Chinese we all say no because you
know because because they are they're
thought you know they are thinking they
are way of you know going up it's like
heavy digging through influenced by
English but by you know the Americans
for you know by Python community in USA
you know they follow the same path of
the elite you know among you know you
know UNIX or UNIX philosophy so some of
the Chinese we are like site site you
know UNIX philosophy you know because at
least you know lease fees also often can
see the like one of the elite you know
whenever lease per say something oh you
know everyone should you know look up to
them things like that so they would
recommend I mean there's this happened
before they recommend you know you
should just using
I did say disagree on that because
because you know you know consider how
many people are in China you know
there's one 1.4 billion you know like so
many and the Chinese is advancing so
fast you know because once you start to
Chinese people programmers they start to
use Chinese characters in function names
okay for example once that happens you
know one thing beats to another and very
soon you know you're gonna have Chinese
you're gonna have programming languages
that's totally Chinese invented in China
you know I'm American
you know agua but you know my blood is
Chinese so I have some you know
sympathies for you know Chinese so
that's the thing you know you know you
if you if you are you know for Chinese
people if you have the mentality now you
everything should be English only that
opportunity doesn't come up but they
never never thought of that they don't
you know they don't think much just like
the the the elite hacker types in
Western world they don't think they
don't think much they just they kind of
just follow whatever the pop the pop
whatever is more difficult what did
whatever is considered more difficult
like you know real men you know
programming languages UNIX and C and
stuff like that they don't actually
think about issues much hey in formatic
so how long I've been going I think I'm
kind of like I'm doing pretty I'm kind
of losing you know purpose or kind of
starting to ramble without coherence and
you know I
maybe we all pics awesome copyright fees
on his name good people here from when
oh I'm kind of lost track
Oh TP what so TP ok I think I'm I think
I'm tired and let's get myself some
drink this is apple juice I mean not
apple pie apple juice does it say
anywhere or you can see here so I'm
gonna get pepper juice you know I'm
getting tired because actually I'm about
to go to bed so let me yeah so you know
let me relax and not get it up tight and
my eyes you know when I get tired my
eyes start to cross so this way I can
actually read better so what is OTP set
of colors yeah it's very forum when
forum good people here just creating a
forum I I wanted to do that but I just
never got to like where hug like where
do I what tech do I use when Dionne says
when one of us decides to belay less
lazy probably Dion says maybe we will
have to pay chaos and copyright fees on
his name oh sorry forum that's great
sorry Frank rub anti-nato lists
anti-natal lists think the world should
have a zero charge
policy what does anti-natal list me
satish says little a to the combo but I
obviously disagree with Finch's
neo-colonial mentality of okay it's very
unlikely that India we are split in two
parts we are united by culture not
language yeah I think so I think that's
true yeah you could argue it has already
split Pakistan oh yes but not in the
future India has a bright future
Satya she must be blind to the events
okay don't argue too much okay guys go
easy it's all just you know for fun
Oh some people hate John G John cheese
so some people is using this Chinese
character language e language to make
cheat programs for in a gaming community
right yeah I believe the red parts refer
to density who makes sense for Europe
no not density those red are just like
people
like each is like no not in City
they are actually just people in this
map a red flag
oh do they say plague I think maybe it's
pronounced plague
Oh Sathish you're gonna go okay I think
that's it for today because I'm kind of
getting tired one name ID so what else
what's what else is new so we we began
to talk about yeah I just started to
talk to random today about you know we
talked about a Deon cool stream we
talked about video video versus text
text is like good for history for
recording for for technology for
condensing information video is kind of
natural however video is very extremely
time consuming you would be nice if we
have some kind of like like the bog I
mean the bog is the perfection you know
the poke each one of us know you know
like this this is like like a hive mind
you know we know like we don't even have
to communicate you already know what I
think I already know what you think it's
like you want one entity now second to
that okay this one entity in some sense
is the most efficient because these you
don't because you don't have like
separate individuals you only have one
user like together as one okay and okay
but but however this bee hive mind
violates one of the human animals nature
that is individualism you know when we
lost that like we're I'm not me it went
you know you and me are the same thing I
don't want that you don't want that you
know it's like a Haro
so but anyway so the book is the it's
kind of like you know it's supposed to
be the perfection but second to that you
know you'll be great if we have you know
like I can cut I can connect a pipe for
my head to your head then we communicate
at high speed you know communication so
we don't have to talk even we don't have
to read
because because talking is actually very
slow so if we have a like pipe
connection that's very efficient and
even if we can make it wireless you know
but however here's the thing you know we
don't understand - you know today even
with all the year AI going we don't
understand how you know we don't know
what is a soul you know we don't know
what is what is you know you what is
consciousness we don't actually know
that you know you know a philosophy you
know some people think that the human
consciousness is simply a emergent
phenomenon when when the computing power
the computation becomes complex enough
meaning that if you if your computer
means when winds winds you know too
powerful then then it automatically have
consciousness like without even you have
to program it so that's some some of the
people say wow other you know other you
know these people philosophers or
scientists or mathematicians they think
that machine can never ever have
consciousness like a human being and my
opinion of of this issue is that
actually so my opinion is we are machine
ever reach consciousness or it will
never reach consciousness so so what is
you guys opinion on this so that is the
question you know that's an interesting
question you know a lot of people talk
about that and my answer to that is
actually I don't know you know even
though I really want to say you know oh
I think you know I think this screen is
going to happen or that but actually
after all these years I I think you know
I cannot say which way it will be
Saiki Caesar makes sense so what is
psyche season let's look at
yeah exactly so Finch says the question
is what is consciousness
we humans are miserable at even defining
that unambiguously exactly you know we
can we cannot even define it pampies
season elementary particles have
elementary consciousness oh I never
heard of that psychoticism
so let's see so anyway I think that's it
for today because I started I am not
focused you know I am not getting
anywhere so okay that's it for today for
the top show thank you guys for coming I
hope to see you next time
if you have comments if you like to see
what topics next post in the comments
okay you know in the video you show up
or just type it here I'll talk about
next time and I think next time - maybe
maybe tomorrow I forgot who asked me
yesterday to talk about is that you D
young to talk about math in art like I
have article mathematical algorithmic
mathematical art I want to talk about
that so maybe next day yourself so see
you guys bye