hello welcome to another episode of
sound talk show so today's uh we don't
have a topic yet so these are going to
be the topic I posted in the YouTube you
know description box you can click go to
the link because I'll talk show topic
notes so pick one item from any of these
and paste it in the chat box okay and
then we'll talk about that otherwise I'm
gonna do I'm gonna do my stuff you know
I'm gonna do uh what's needed you know
I'm gonna work on my website so I need
to do a lot of work
so let me say again okay so pick a topic
uh of the uh you know here and uh we'll
do that okay so today's talk show let me
um so I'm gonna
topics topics guys Jesus you know I um
okay so Yasin says hi quick question
what do you think about Elixir as a
language God [ __ ] that's off topic can
you you know that's off topic
Elixir you know Elixir okay let me tell
you about that
um so again but I want you guys pick a
topic here okay so that's what we're
gonna
talk about yeah but anyway yeah that's a
good question because
I said that you know you can pick any
Topic in the first five minutes okay
Elixir Elixir you know I don't first of
all I don't know much about the Elixir
language
it's a functional programming language
uh based on erlen I think and uh
uh in JavaScript so yeah so let's see
Elixir so let's open that let's open
that
Elixir is a dynamic functional language
for building scalable maintainable
application selections on Earl and
virtual machine okay Olan is a
functional programming language known
for its a particular way of doing multi
concurrency you know running stuff in
parallel and uh you know so you have
thousands or ten thousand objects
they are all functional and they pass
messages to each other something like
that I don't know Orlando uh it'll be
interesting to learn but so many so I
don't know a lot so you know erla is one
of the earliest successful and
Commercial functional programming
language used by the telecommunication
Giant in no way in no way or somewhere
Scandinavia so it's a very success
successful commercial function of
programming language in fact you could
say we could say erlen is the first
commercially viable powerful you know
used in industry heavy you know industry
functional programming language because
most vast majority of functional
programming language are more more or
less academic toys like the skin disk
like Haskell most of them you know so
Airline is probably I would say the
first
used in industry what I mean by industry
I mean the Computing industry you know
Mega corporations they use it so early
so Elixir is a direct derivative of that
other land okay
and I believe it runs on basically it's
web-based you know uh so let's read
so these capabilities and elixir tooling
allows developers to be productive in
several domains such as web development
development yeah that's that's
essentially the the primary I suppose
the primary use of Elixir so Elixir is
uh to me
seems like a erlen a drift bringing a
land to web dev
you know airline in JavaScript
environment basically
so uh so so that is that so that's what
you know so that's what I don't know
Elixir okay so but that's basically what
it is
uh and for what you know it's um and
elixir so who did it who wrote it uh
it's
you know Elixir when you talk about
Elixir another language usually uh
mentioned in parallel is um
is uh m e l m that's another
functional programming language for the
web dev okay Elm
so
so what do I think of it
um
Elixir so Elixir is a functional
concurrent general purpose forming
language that runs on the beam virtual
machine machine which is also used to
implement erlan okay elix appears on top
of erlen and shares the same
abstractions for building distributed
fault tolerant applications yeah fault
tolerant is another major Salient point
of erlan system I don't know how it
works I I always wanted to learn but I
just never get to so meaning that you
you know you can have part of the system
down is your work you know it just spawn
thousands thousands millions of
what they what what object or processes
what processes whatever they call it so
that's
the nature of
um our land so it can you know tolerant
you know destruction much like internet
so uh Elixir also provides productive
tooling and an extensive design the
latter is supported by compile time meta
programming with macros and polymorphism
Via protocols okay
uh Unix is used by companies you know
here is the marketing part this this
part is written is contributed by The
Elixir phonetics you know they go to
Wikipedia and they started to say who is
using Elixir you know so Elixir is used
by companies such as ramp page Duty
don't know uh Discord okay breaks don't
know what about the Pinterest okay Mars
feature report and online universities
for building embedded systems the
community organization organizes yearly
events in the United States as well as
minor local events and conferences okay
so yeah so but I want to know who wrote
it okay
uh Jose vaderman let's magnify
yeah Nokia right uh Greg and dog hello
yeah that's right erlen I mean Earl and
is used by Nokia
is no no wait okay you are talking about
something else so anyway so yeah okay so
you are saying Elixir is used by Nokia
okay Nokia is kind of you know they've
been robbed robbed by Apple they're
being defeated by Apple
so Jose Valen is the creator of Helix
programming language or research and
development project created then
something something his score were to
enable higher extensibility
and productivity in the earlier and
virtual environment virtual machine
while keeping compatibility with
Airlines ecosystem
Elixir was aimed for large-scale blah
blah blah
Elixir uses features of Ruby Airline
closure what huh
okay so you so
um you know so Elixir may not be is the
question I want to know is elixir is
elixir derivative of our land
or is merely
or I mean or is it fairly very different
it's
but that it uses the erlan's virtual
environment does any notice you know
Yasin
so what do I think about it I don't I
don't have much opinion I mean my
opinion is that you know if you're gonna
whip you know well the yeah I think it's
great okay I would use it except that
you know the the vast majority of web
dev is Javascript and typescript
and also you so I mean
okay if if you want to use Elixir for
web dev you know suppose to your web dev
you know you you do web servers or front
end or back in
so that you have several choices and and
suppose you want a functional
programming you have several choices you
can use use JavaScript you know using
the functional programming features and
avoid all the
uh then then you know uh you know and
and and you probably want to use
typescript which is a superset of
JavaScript okay so that's the most
popular that's widely accepted so that's
JavaScript AS Plus type script okay then
you use maybe some Frameworks such as
um Dental uh view
um
you know uh uh Facebooks whatever uh
you know there's there are so many uh
Facebook so what's what's the name uh
Jesus
JavaScript framework Facebook
um suddenly I don't I forgot
anyway so
so if you want to what you uh do Dev web
dev and you want the functional
programming so there are several choices
the mainstream is Javascript plus
typescript that's one thing now Elixir
is another choice and the other one is l
m I suppose
okay these are all a functional
programming languages okay
uh actually you know if I started to
talk talk about about this they are
quite a lot so m is the choice also
functional then there is also pure
script
I'm not gonna go show it there's also
pure script okay derived from or
borrowed idea from Haskell okay pure
script M Elixir and um
then close that I hate these websites
that requires JavaScript you know this
this is a
not so good
Okay so
you have M okay let's show okay so
actually since we are talking about it
let's show pure script and let's show
all the uh you know
uh things okay so here's Wikipedia
here's a pure script it's kind of based
on the Haskell okay
all these are uh primarily I believe
primarily for doing web dev okay then
then you have
um then you have the okamo based called
um
uh
ml script uh they change they keep
changing your name book of script uh
let's we'll find it
reason yeah reason ml okay so uh very
confusing but but in the past two years
or so they Consolidated into one
programming language called reason and L
I think okay so hold on a second let me
find it
the reason ml the ml stands for meta
language
which is the language where or camel
camel or camel
F sharp they are all derived from so
they are one family so recent email is
basically or camel or email but in but
they changed the syntax so the syntax is
more familiar is the syntax is more like
JavaScript but the language is ocamo
okay
similarly for F sharp you know so here
it is reason
and among them I think reason I I'm more
more interested in Okay the reason ml
okay so let me summarize okay
so if you want to do web dev
and you don't want you know the
mainstream JavaScript with typescript
then and if you want functional
programming your choices are reason
based on camel or ml meta language okay
or you have pure script which is
someone you know based on uh heska okay
this is this is the most pure I believe
because it's just like Haskell you
cannot have mutability things like that
maybe I you know I know I I don't have
any experience with any of these okay so
your choice is reason pure script
okay and M
uh another one I don't know much about
but it's also functional
uh then you have uh Elixir okay
so what do I think about it you know any
of them well the the thing well the the
yeah I like them but there are so many
you know there are so many and the the
they all suffer from the unpopularity
kind of problem
because
if you are just doing your personal
project you know or toy programming or
learning yeah any one of this is great
but if you want to
uh you know if if you are going to
create something big
then you might have some
issues I mean it's like not that you
have issues I mean you can be successful
but it's
okay here's a way to put it okay if you
want a job you know let's say you just
came out of college you you want to be
employed
then
you know you try to study Elixir for you
know let's say two years or Elm or pure
script or Reason
you know your experience won't be
helpful when you look for a job
that's my point unless you are really
really good you became one of the master
then then you maybe there are five job
choices maybe they hire you maybe you
know
but for each job for one of these
language for each one of job you find
they are 100 more for JavaScript and
typescript
you know you have lots of options you
don't have to move to another another
state or country you know JavaScript in
typescript
so that is basically that is my opinion
about all these
now in my opinion any of these I would
any of these would be much better than
JavaScript and I would say much better
than typescript
JavaScript you know even though in the
past 10 years this incredible amount of
uh progress you know but but basically
they refuse
to create a new language meaning that
they they want to keep it 100 Backward
Compatible
therefore you have a huge amount of
trash you know a baggage in JavaScript
Watts lots of problems that will not go
away and you know you you program
JavaScript you can try to not use
certain operations that's bad you know
that's Asian from 1995.
yeah you can do that all that but still
there are huge amount of
fundamental uh problems baggage what's
you know confusion in JavaScript that
you cannot
avoid you can you know as for example
the type the the class system the the
you know the the instance of let me show
you a way okay so
very complex you know tremendously
complex and and bad you know the
Prototype key property which is you know
extremely confusing nobody can explain
okay I can tell you you know you read
this in detail the new operator the
instance of the property key Constructor
you know this and they have trash okay
and they they are array JavaScript array
is not a real array sometimes it becomes
objects all of a sudden if you delete
too many keys too many elements or and
then right you can also it's also object
it's hugely confusing okay JavaScript is
the worst language okay worst
and and what about typescript yeah
typescript edit typescript is a superset
of JavaScript okay so typescript is
truly a superset so any JavaScript is
also a typescript so but so what what
what does typescript do they just
basically they add a they add the
ability to
have types type checking so you can
declare types you know which is
essential when your code becomes a few
thousand lines you know or more than ten
thousand lines it becomes essential so
essentially all major corporations that
use JavaScript they are doing typescript
you know they are using typescript
so
so and types you know they are it's a
mainstream however typescript is 100
compatible with JavaScript you know it's
a superset and JavaScript is 100
compatible with the Asian you know
JavaScript in 1995 so it's a huge of
baggage in in typescript as well you
know it's just a [ __ ] it's a bag of [ __ ]
so that very bad JavaScript these you
know I I try to like it because of the
functional programming the functional
programming uh feature of just
JavaScript is is much better than python
in Python you can't do you know yeah but
JavaScript got lots of Watts so and and
typescript so that's a that's a big
problem
so any of these reason
this is this is one I'm most interested
okay so any of these I would
I would do them anytime better than
JavaScript you know reason reason email
or pure script or
Elm or
uh or Elixir so any of this is much
better than JavaScript
but the problem is you have limited uh
opportunities when you want to make
money out of it that that's a that's a
key issue and this I mean this is an
important issue if if all you do is just
a toy programming for a personal project
you don't you already have money you
don't care for a job that's fine you can
pick any of these but
but for most people making money is the
key you know
uh so that's my opinion whether to use
it you know that's that's my opinion
Campbell hey Campbell button can be a
button okay so I want to make a
correction you know my last video I did
a um
by the way let me you know pedal my
JavaScript in-depth tutorial so I spent
two three years writing this you know I
read all the JavaScript
specification several version of it from
cover to cover so I spent two or three
years writing this so this I would
consider it the best JavaScript in depth
anywhere on Earth
that's that's a bit you know uh Mega
megalomania thinking but honestly I
would say
my JavaScript in depth will be the top
three
resources on Earth doesn't matter it's
printed book or online okay and and in
fact
the Mozilla you know most of you
probably familiar with Mozilla Mozilla
is [ __ ] okay
well there are nuances Mozilla for
anything the latest happening Mozilla is
the best okay you cannot find it
anywhere not you know they are also yeah
let me talk about this JavaScript Books
Okay the best JavaScript books
um what are they okay so I can recommend
you know my own of course then
um then two or three okay uh let's go to
um
I can recommend only I can see that only
two or three that maybe
comparable in quality to my I would say
Okay so
uh let's go to Amazon let's see what um
okay so today's topic is just about
um
Oh wait [ __ ] this guy has a new version
Jesus let's have a look
I haven't checked for a few uh for for
three years okay so let me let me tell
you I know all about JavaScript Books
Okay so
he's
uh what the [ __ ]
so let me tell you some of these books
let me tell you my opinion react yeah
that that's a face that's a Facebook
thing you know the most popular
framework could be Act
uh I well this this is great to know
that uh they come up with a new version
the the guy who decided to rewrite it
I mean I wonder if he if the same author
or it's a new author with this you know
borrowing the old film of this if that's
the case then and I'm not you know you
wouldn't be sure about that
about this book okay so let's see David
Flanagan okay this is fantastic okay I
didn't know he came out with a new
edition wins this out
this is this is the best okay this is
the best JavaScript book I can tell you
right away
the I trust this guy this this David
Flanagan
he's a professional uh tutorial tutorial
writer you know you know
he's a professional programmer but he
also write tutorials you know he he's
working for uh Mozilla or before
somewhere before but anyway so I didn't
know there's a new version what date uh
what date is this
when did it when did it um
let's see
2020 oh I didn't know this so two years
ago he he decided
he gonna update you know so
this one okay
this one
is
one of the best okay I'm gonna tell you
top five JavaScript resource okay this
one is the best and it's it's good to
know he got a new version because I
because the last version is like
10 years ago 15 years ago which is super
outdated okay but I read
um
okay so let's copy let's also do this
you know so this is the great okay
uh let's just put it okay and I want to
show you so hold on a second so
um for example uh wait
so I put to today's talk show so later
on again you guys can go buy it you you
know buy for my links I make one dollar
or two
you know if you guys like my stuff pay
me okay donate you know go to my website
this is important I want to you know
because I'm you know if you like you
know my tutorial my teachings my talk
show you know go to my exotic.info and
patreon me five dollars or Amazon gift
card me
twenty dollars or PayPal okay
do that you know there's also Super Chat
you know on YouTube they they take like
40 30 or was it forty percent you know
uh very bad the YouTube
Okay so
so we let's summarize a bit what we
talked about and that that'll be it
maybe 10 more minutes okay
what do you think of
uh so what are the what what's the um
Helm uh elixir
Elm
Elm programming language and the pure
script
then then there is a reason ml
[Music]
okay that's the first thing we talked
about then JavaScript and typescript
okay then then uh we're gonna talk about
the best resources
for
JavaScript okay
paste tutorial
okay and of course I want to show
my website JavaScript in depth okay
uh okay that's one of the best top five
I would say okay if you ask me so if you
like my stuff you can pay
you know you'll get the entire website
downloaded in a zip file for JavaScript
including references to HTML to visual
CSS they are about
[Music]
um
let's see
go to diet they are about 900 pages okay
including CSS reference uh so JavaScript
then you have JavaScript reference you
know all the objects and their methods
you know object object then you have
um
array object and uh then you have set
map you know
then you have a tutorial for dome which
is which is the 90 percent
of what you actually do when you code
when you do web dev Dom you know
document object model or browser object
model this is the actual this is
what you actually do ninety percent of
time when you code JavaScript and this
is even more complex than JavaScript Dom
okay so I have a tutorial that teach you
how to create a you know website
interactive website without any um
framework okay no react no view no no
nothing no no no no any of those
libraries pure JavaScript building your
browser okay
so for example change CSS you know very
easy I just show you that you know make
it red or make it blue you can see that
you know uh how to change this how to
insert the node click me insert insert
hello hello you know so
and how to remove a nod
you know so fundamental you know using
pure browser you can do all this okay
and and then you know HTML input button
you can see it says you know
uh you know building a user interface
then you have some fancy ones such as
uh image rollover this is Asian this is
like 25 years ago they have this image
row
let me show you I want to show you uh
then there's a digital clock new window
the uh
fader element and fade fade okay and
fade fade
then you have
two tip
this is also interesting you can you
know Hoover and have two tips
so the technology required for this is
Javascript and CSS you need CSS because
see
actually how this works is that it's
actually a hack you use CSS to create
layers CSS can allow you to have layers
so then you use JavaScript to detect the
event of Hoover then you create a new
layer then show it when the Hoover is
outside of it you remove that layer so
that's how two tip is done essentially
your hack it's kind of yeah it's a hack
then then you have this uh
fun thing you might see this is also
Asian you know 25 20 years ago you have
this kind of thing
and let me show you one more okay then
there's this one
you will see it sometimes you know
sometimes it's an ad or a menu or
something that that follows your school
okay
so or using pure JavaScript no framework
no nothing and the code is the simplest
and tight the most tight possible so
that's part of all these are part of
Dome
and then you also have SVG tutorial
uh you know
that shows you how to how to write this
clock JavaScript plus SVG technology you
know so here is a complete SVG tutorial
and here's a code about 20 lines okay 30
lines to create this clock okay so that
that is my JavaScript tutorial so if you
like it you know you can buy it get the
entire thing
you know thank you
so one of my tutorial so let's go back
to so now let's go back to talk about
what are the best uh tutorials for
JavaScript okay
so first of all one of them I recommend
is this one
New Edition I trust it's great okay no I
don't have him this guy David Flanagan
in fact I have an article on him
if you go to saudi.info click on search
let's just say JavaScript and I have 10
500 pages on JavaScript okay so uh David
uh flat yeah so
I read this book I read this book uh
2013 okay from cover to cover okay and
I'm so very impressed okay this is the
best one so this you know so and I
explain why I explain why it is the best
okay and then
so let's copy that and put to the talk
show are you guys still here are you
guys still with me any comments
and then I give you some JavaScript
books review
um okay so this is the old you know
version edition JavaScript the
definitive guide
and meanwhile this is also fantastic
JavaScript the book The Good Parts by
this guy Douglas Crawford I've highly
respect okay both of them
this both of them this is you know both
of them are old
uh old more than more than 15 15 years
old okay so they are out they are not
useful today you you want the new
version but however
these two
are the these two are responsible
responsible for for making JavaScript
popular as you know in in both of them
fantastic okay the the the Douglas
Crawford
he is one of the you know the the main
leader the technical leader when Yahoo
was over you know uh during year 2000s
you know he so he's
he's
responsible responsible for spreading
the idea that JavaScript is one of the
best functional programming language
okay JavaScript the good parts very thin
book okay
so this are the best JavaScript books
these two nothing else okay don't I mean
you you might hear a lot of the opinions
about oh ninja or something [ __ ] okay
these two however
now they are outdated now they are
worthless because JavaScript has
basically has a facelift you know in the
past 10 years you know version every
year you have a new version so these two
books are useless today however each one
of them has a new version so we found a
new version for that one this one also
have a new edition so let me show you
JavaScript the good parts okay first of
all let's copy it here
uh
JavaScript books review 2018 okay
so now let's go to uh the good parts
JavaScript the good parts by Douglas
Crawford okay
uh the the best one of the top 10 expert
of JavaScript now he's got the new
version okay let me show you
um
so so this
this one is uh let me show you where is
it
uh
why is it not even showing here let's
click his name
he wrote a new book about four or five
years ago on JavaScript Okay so
Douglas covet
why is it clicking not work
what happened to
foreign
okay here
okay this one
how JavaScript works so he wrote a new
book about uh four years ago
I would also trust this one so this is a
kind of the new edition of the good
parts this is a new one okay I trust
this one so this I would consider one of
the top five JavaScript book
okay
uh what's his name how is this spelled
any comments questions on the right
notebook yeah
uh like
okay so that's true you know one is the
Rhino book New Edition and one is the
how JavaScript works and also of course
my then let me let me tell you about uh
the others okay
then we have
[Music]
um
this eloquent JavaScript okay this guy
maragin hover back
he is a JavaScript master
however this eloquent JavaScript is for
beginners
kind of for people who never programmed
before
so I trust this is a good book for those
people but not for if you already know a
language and also I don't like the
writing style
by the way this book is also free online
you know just search for name for the
name eloquent JavaScript you'll find it
you know it's I believe it's open source
even on his kit so it's free online it's
for absolute beginners who never
programmed you know anything and the
style of this book I don't like
so I you know so I don't like you know
and so what's the style his style is
storytelling you know each chapter he
tells you a elaborate story like nothing
nothing to do with programming you know
he make it like you know he's talking
you know the story yeah
that's the worst that's the worst
programming tutorial for me you know I
don't want I I want I want just the
relevant you know the thing I don't have
time to
you know if I want to read a story I
read a fiction I read a novel I read
Shakespeare you know I don't want the
story I don't want you know you telling
me a story in a programming context okay
but if you like that this and if you are
a pure beginner you know you don't know
any pro I mean before this is a good
book for you
okay
now this this book this book's writing
style is the in sharp contrast
to my JavaScript tutorial my JavaScript
tutorial is pure math okay
I tell you you know when you say math
people get fear you know people think oh
math I don't want it but actually it's a
most concise most concrete and most
um dense you know so each paragraph you
know so you have for beginners you can
read here then you have you know it
starts to get complex properties what's
a property every sentence counts
every sentence is in critical okay it
tells you exactly when you type this
what happens okay and it doesn't talk in
terms of
big computer science or patterns
programming patterns or idioms or you
should do it this way you know we all
dry principle do it only once a [ __ ]
[ __ ] or Unix philosophy okay there's no
philosophy it's just like mathematics
every sentence counts and almost every
paragraph
as an example okay every paragraph has a
code
standard loan code you can run in a
browser for example this part is tell
you telling you you know what's a
parental function okay
you know you can run right right away in
browser you know like you can copy it
uh you know in browser I also tell you
how to start the browser console you
paste it there
true you know it returns true every
every part independent you can run
you know every paragraph has a code that
demonstrates how it is the concept you
just learned so
JavaScript okay JavaScript in depth so
that is my style purely mathematical
indents and uh in sharp contrast to
to this guy telling a story like 1000
words 900 words are about a story about
something something like that okay
so I don't like this book and it's also
for beginners okay so we covered
actually we already covered two of the
best books I want to say you know one
one inside so there's there's another
okay so let me show you
um
yeah JavaScript so let me there I mean
they I know they are one or two more
books I that I can recommend
most gifted uh General script and jQuery
don't stop don't never use jQuery okay
do not use jQuery
because jQuery was invented in the 2000s
that's when JavaScript sucks
but since
um since uh
2016 or something I forgot the exact
date
um
there is a you know JavaScript started
to have a massive revision you know
um
yeah and uh and you don't need uh jQuery
anymore okay so let me put that out
there
you know so that's another book so um
so what are we
um
yeah and we we are trying to find
another top JavaScript book why is it
not listed here and see
quickly you know those are you know
quickly those are all
foreign
did they change the author this one I
read before I don't like it because he
he he's also expert but he kept talking
in terms of patents
uh is is this a new edition or
you know I don't like this book okay
this JavaScript for professional
JavaScript for web developer it's no
good
he he talks in terms of patterns like oh
this if you want you know a factory
pattern you do this idiotic you know
there's a lot of the JavaScript book but
a lot of them are just um
no good okay so you have to be very
careful buy just the ones I mentioned
okay
you know they are trying to make a buck
because JavaScript is the most popular
uh programming language language
JavaScript python
the top two most popular programming
language and also Java and C plus plus
okay so I don't I didn't find it here so
let me just type the name
you don't know JavaScript okay
that's that's the one
okay so this this book I also trust I
didn't read it but I also trust its
quality and correctness okay now it
begins this book now it becomes a series
of books
it began it began on GitHub as someone
trying to collect you know all the stack
Overflow by by okay Kyle Simpson okay so
it it begins to say you know collecting
all the
surprising things tips about JavaScript
you know it begins that now it becomes a
sick series of books I also trust this
one okay so if you like it you can you
can you can buy this one
you don't you don't know JavaScript
because the reason this become popular
because because first of all it's good
quality okay but you know there's the
title suggest you know you've been
coding JavaScript for let's say two
years but then when you read this book
or my book or you know you'll see oh I
didn't know that oh oh what what you
know that's a ray I can't believe it you
know that's a lot there's tons of things
like that in JavaScript that's why I use
it you know this book says you know with
the catchy uh title you don't know
JavaScript you know I don't care you
work at Google you know you don't know
[ __ ] okay you don't know JavaScript
so that's this book I can recommend
okay
so that's it about it today okay so
that's the few uh books um I can
recommend about JavaScript
uh oh yeah lastly let me talk about
Mozilla you know the Mozilla uh for
JavaScript you know because most people
they'll just say Mozilla is the best
that's idiots okay because they haven't
seen anything else because Mozilla is
free open source and free
you haven't seen anything else it yeah
Mozilla is the most the JavaScript
tutorial Mozilla let me show you okay so
if you just search for JavaScript
tutorial this turns by you know Indian
by the the [ __ ] idiotic W3 schools is
the worst okay lots of misinformation
but they they are popular because they
just teach you the one percent
you know the 10 of JavaScript that
everyone the beginner who never
programmed before but they heard that
programming can make a lot of money
that's what this tutorials are are okay
the mod and I don't know which one is
this the modern the you know they all
trying to make up money
I don't know that one JavaScript
utopia.net whatever tutorial Pawn is
another you know lots of scans and you
know they're trying to make money and
ads
uh JavaScript to show you for beginner
Guru 99 from idiots some idiots okay so
all this is crap okay Java Point Java
point is another uh commercial you know
tutorial website you know they they
started about 10 years ago okay here
here is the Mozilla okay
mosia's JavaScript is the worst okay if
you read it it's misleading okay
that's JavaScript is the worst of all of
all that I've talked about okay so
misleading [ __ ]
you learn it you you build up lots of
misleading information and data you have
to relearn okay Mozilla the writing
quality is also bad they don't know what
they you know this is open source open
source Wiki that's what they are Wiki
but they improved a lot about five years
ago because you know why because
apparently there's a Consortium you know
the behind the big companies Google
you know Firefox Microsoft Apple they
started to have it and you know and the
JavaScript Consortium or whatever you uh
you know they they are they have a
JavaScript spec every year you know I
mean the the people behind trying to
decide which feature they're gonna add
so anyway a group of industrial people
for web dev they collected they gathered
they decided you know JavaScript you
don't have a documentation
and the specs spec is impossible to read
you know it's not for programmers but
even for JavaScript compiler
creators it's this JavaScript spec is
not good okay
so anyway in JavaScript don't have a
doesn't have any document documentation
so that's a problem so these people
decided they're gonna
focus on one single JavaScript
documentation and they decided it's
gonna be Mozilla so Microsoft they used
to have their own JavaScript
documentation they removed it now if you
go there they just link to they just
tell you visit mozilla's JavaScript okay
so Apple they used to also have
JavaScript some tutorial they also it's
all gone okay so I mean in particular
Microsoft Microsoft has a one big chunk
of JavaScript tutorial okay that teaches
language and another you know tensor
pages about JavaScript reference you
know documenting all the object now it's
all good you know they they just linked
to the Mozilla now you know at first I
didn't know why I was thinking wait what
wow wow you know because I've been
observing you know the Microsoft
documentation on JavaScript for 15 years
you know one day I just realized hey hey
they just point to Mozilla huh how did
that happen because usually these
companies they don't you know they are
enemies to each other
you know so how come Microsoft you know
they Point their you know JavaScript to
Mozilla and Mozilla sucks you know
Mozilla JavaScript sucks then after two
years I realized I I found out because
there's some kind of you know Consortium
behind it they decided they want they
they want to push out one like the
documentation for JavaScript okay so
anyway Mercia JavaScript dark is the
worst okay
I haven't read it for a few years but I
don't think it's that good okay
but however the Mozilla JavaScript
reference okay especially on things that
happening at latest you know the the
last year because every year this new
version of JavaScript so those are
critical Mozilla nothing else you know
all these books you won't find because
they are you know they don't update as
often so but so if you are at The
Cutting Edge Edge of the browser you
know browser come up with new versions
every year you know in fact multiple
versions so there's a lot of changes to
their implementation and so on so
so if you are a professional JavaScript
Dev
Mozilla is critical okay
mozilla's JavaScript reference because
they'll tell you the latest CSS HTML or
JavaScript how they changed and and
which browser supported you know in you
know so Mozilla is good for that however
their JavaScript
uh tutorial is the worst now now look at
look at look at you know let me let me
let me dive into give you analysis how
they why is this worst okay JavaScript
Mozilla you know javascript.js is a
lightweight interpreted or just in time
compile programming language with first
class functions
the first sentence the most idiotic [ __ ]
you know incomprehensible
so it's a lightweight What What In what
way it's like lightweight in interpreted
oh so as opposed to compiled because you
know if you are a nerd then you
understand inter in interpreted versus
compiled you know technical jargon no
relevance to JavaScript programmers okay
and and just in time just in time they
are asked
you know those those are technical stuff
you know just in time compiled
programming language oh it's interpreted
then just in time compiled okay and with
first class functions the most idiotic
you know
Babbage babbling you know first first
class function what what does that mean
that that jargon came from the scheme
lisp Fanatics okay I'm not gonna explain
so and then it says well it's most well
known as the scripting language of web
pages many numbers and environments also
use it such as nodes
idiots okay so okay so that's it that's
my opinion about JavaScript and web dev
languages
okay
okay so uh let me just um
get these two um
okay so here is what we talked about
the different languages Elixir M pure
script reason ml JavaScript type script
which one to choose and then best
tutorials for JavaScript and why do I
think that way okay
uh George hello George why do you have
sound when you change tab that's
actually that's came from
um the that came from sticky keys
so it's not
so that so you hear the sound is because
the
sticky keys he sang and it makes a sound
whenever you have modifiers so when I
change tab it's actually I press this
key it's actually a macro so it actually
presses Ctrl shift tab
uh and because you know so it's pressing
Ctrl shift tab very fast but since I
have sticky song sticky keys that's why
it makes a sound you know
uh and actually I turned it down but I
guess you can still hear it
yeah you hear it from a speaker I guess
but if I turn this up
get ready okay
let's see I press Alt
you see that's uh that's the
sticky keys
you see any benefit to the beep okay so
that's it thank you guys for watching
what is this guy
so I've been talking for 60 minutes
exactly okay
uh I said I'm gonna buy it in future
once I learned JavaScript okay I
appreciate sharing your opinion it's a
good language but not popular indeed
okay I find this yeah combo pattern oh
yeah so let me make a quick uh
uh note about that okay so
what
go to talk show
so yesterday I mean two days I mean last
time I did a YouTube on auto format
email business code so Campbell button
write a auto format for emac Beast code
and in this tutorial I thought it's bad
but actually it's pretty good okay it's
it's pretty good so I'm gonna do a a new
video on this Auto format in in next
week or next two weeks you know I get to
you know there's there's a lot update
and so it's pretty good I think yeah I
think it's pretty good I'm gonna do
another video
so you for now you can just go to his
website uh you know just search for
emacs edisp Auto format ideas Man 42 so
um it's very good so this hopefully this
will revolutionize iMac this coding so
you no longer have to press tab you know
at each line you just press one key
it'll reformat your whole file in fast
okay
that's it for today thank you guys bye
oh there's the new
uh functional Language by Simon python
Jones who is famous for Haskell
and this function this language is
called verse calculus no I don't know I
didn't know that you know so so Nico 12
made a comment on my on one by one uh
my live show video about
about homotopy type Theory so apparently
decode 12 knows a lot about it yeah I'm
I still want to learn so it's too slow I
need to so much to do I need to learn
you know
um [ __ ] I probably uh or one of the
other you know the assistant proof
um
assisted assisted proof systems you know
programming language for doing math
proofs so
require also learning homotopy type
Theory and there are several languages I
know that is kind of the
let's say new or Haskell like you know
there's a Idris you know a few I don't
know much about them but yeah
okay bye