Good morning, everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Sandok
Show.
Today is 2019,
November 22nd, Friday,
6:
47 p.m. San Francisco time.
And good morning, welcome
Emily.
Good morning, Nabi.
So, we got five people watching and
two of them are in the chat.
So, Emily says, now Emily is a e is a
Emacs hacker and the Lisp hacker.
So, now since she's here, I'm thinking
maybe we should do some Emac Lisp.
And Nabi has a question. Nabi is
wondering whether Emacs Lisp, how is it
different from Lisp?
Uh well,
that's uh
that depends on what you mean. Like,
okay, so Emac Lisp So, in Lisp, so I can
explain that a little bit.
The Lisp family of languages, the
lineage of Lisp. So, let's see what does
uh Emily says.
From certain implementations, yes.
Emac Lisp has all the Emacs functions
for buffers, act building.
And I believe it's Lisp 1.5 based. So,
basically, variables and functions have
the same name space.
Yes, that is true.
Good morning. So, um
So, I am Let me give you
uh
you know, Emily probably already knows,
but let me let me talk about uh the Lisp
family of languages. Okay, well,
okay, let's talk about that a little
bit.
Then, good morning, Zumwelt.
Some topics you might cover, philosophy,
keyboard stuff, JavaScript, uh
millennium problems, your thoughts on C
and C++, okay.
Okay, in general, you just like
uh come in, just post one thing, like
one thing you want to ask instead of
like,
you know, like I I I got people
suggesting me suggesting to me topics,
you know, it's not like I don't have
topics. I mean I mean like I do have all
those topics, but like it's at the
moment you want one specific thing,
that's what I need, like if you I mean
it's more in particular, if you guys are
interested in one specific topic, then
uh
then, you know, we can
then the
my mouth starts to fly.
But but as opposed to like, oh, Sandok
needs a topic, then let's let's suggest
some general, you know,
uh
you know, that that that doesn't really
help.
So, anyway, so yeah, so let's go to so
Sandok Lee prolifer- proliferation
of languages. So, that is the topic.
Well, that is the article where I have
the Lisp lineage.
Okay, so here you can see a history
historical chart of Lisp families of
languages.
Uh so, in the beginning, you have Lisp 1
and 1.5, then Mac Lisp, then InterLisp,
then Lisp Machine Lisp, Scheme,
and Neo and Common Lisp and Lisp and so
on.
So, but in general, in today,
let's say from year 2000, okay, that's a
good time to begin for today's people.
Uh so, in general, you have Common Lisp,
okay, and Scheme
Lisp, okay, and then you have Emac Lisp,
okay, and then you have
in the past 10 years, you have Closure.
That's basically the four
that is still mostly used, okay.
Let me
repeat. Common Lisp,
Scheme Lisp,
Emac Lisp,
and Closure Lisp. Okay, these four.
That's relevant to today's people.
And Closure is industrial. Closure Lisp
is Java based on JVM. I talked about
Closure Lisp many times. So, in order to
run Closure, you have to start, you
know, you have to install the Java, the
Java Enterprise Edition, the Java
something Standard Edition, the Java
And the and then Closure is
intimately intertwined with Java.
And Closure Lisp is
by far
it's one of the Lisp that's different
from all the other Lisps. In in in fact,
you you could say it doesn't respect
much of the Lisp tradition.
So, in in many aspects, it dev- deviates
uh greatly. For example, you don't even
have cons anymore. You don't have, you
know, cons. You don't have vectors
versus Lisp.
Typically, in Common Lisp, Scheme Lisp,
Emac Lisp, you have vectors, you have
lists, you have But in Closure, you
don't have that anymore. You you have
instead of
instead of that, you have interfaces,
then you have
Anyway, Closure. So, but if you want to
get a job, if you want to eat,
if you want to put butter and bread on
your table,
Closure is the one
you need to go to, okay. Not Common
Lisp, no money no money there. Scheme
Lisp, no money there.
Emac Lisp,
you're going to be a hobo if you do Emac
Lisp, okay.
So, so Closure is your go-to language if
you want to
make a living
uh coding Lisp.
Okay, let me check check on myself. Am I
alive? Okay, I'm alive and I'm well.
Alive and seems I'm well. Okay, that's
good.
So, that's Closure Lisp. Now,
let's talk about Common Lisp, Scheme
Lisp, and Emac Lisp.
Uh let's first of all, let's talk about
Scheme Lisp. Scheme Lisp is
Now, Scheme Lisp has a few
branches, okay. The most basically, if
you want to
uh
there's Racket, okay. Racket
uh basically, just Racket. You know,
there's also GNU Guile, there's new
Lisp, you know,
you can ignore basically ignore all
that. So, in Scheme Lisp, basically, you
just have Scheme R
R6RS,
um
Scheme
R
R6RS, something like that, okay. That's
that's the name for the Scheme standard,
okay. They they call it
um
R6RS, yes, indeed. Every version. So,
before it's R4RS, then R5RS,
then R6RS. R6RS is the current Scheme
Lisp
st- standard.
Okay, and you can read the spec.
The full name of R R something RS is the
revised
report on the algorithmic language
Scheme. Uh idiotic name, but it's a
it that that name stuck, okay. That name
is um
is part became part of the code.
You know, you just say R6RS or it's kind
of a pun in the beginning because
I forgot what this based on the revised,
you know, report on the language Scheme.
Anyway,
so back in year 2K, back in 1999,
I read
um
like 60% of the R4RS Scheme spec,
you know, back then. So, this is 20
years ago. And now they have uh you
know,
the history of Scheme is one big topic
because you know, in the sense of
there's lots of war and fight, you know,
that like each each one
clawing each other's eyes out.
Bloody history of the Scheme language in
the past 20 years, you know, when
when R5
R6 uh R5RS, the Scheme standard came
out, the people fight, you know, there's
big issues, you know, like um
you know, if you guys are nerds, you
guys are familiar with the situation,
you know, people fight all over the
place. Hello, beautiful people. Good
morning.
Uh thank you for coming by. It's late in
Germany and UK and Emily and hello,
beautiful people. So, it's What time is
it there? Let's see. Let's see. 6:00.
It's 3:00 in the morning. 4:00 in the
morning.
And Emily is not sleepy yet. Good
morning, Alan.
Good morning to California. Good morning
to Irvine. Good morning to Florida. Good
morning to United Kingdom and good
morning to
uh not Germany, but it's the
Prague.
Check.
Check
uh Czech Republic.
So, anyway, Scheme Lisp, okay. Scheme
Lisp,
the two major branch of Scheme Lisp
relevant for today's people is
you have R6RS or you have the Racket
Racket Scheme, okay.
Racket Scheme. Uh let's go here, okay.
So, uh
There, you have the racket.
Scheme.
Um anyway, that's Scheme. If you do
Scheme, Scheme is pretty much used
limited to academia. So, if you are
you know, if you are a PhD student
living in poverty, or if you are a
professor, uh
that kind of, you know, you do Scheme.
Uh no way else. Is Scheme
Scheme is telekinesis in some remote
planet, okay, since 20 years ago and
they still are.
Nobody give a about Scheme.
Now, Common Lisp is dead.
Okay.
Except Emily. Emily is using it. Common
Lisp, you will go nowhere. Common Lisp
is dead. It's been dead for a while. It
um
So, Common Lisp
And and and and Common Lisp is crap,
okay. Common Lisp is crap. It's the
worst Lisp among
the Lisp among you know, between Common
Lisp, Scheme Lisp, or Closure.
Kind of, okay. I don't like Closure
because Closure is, you know, tied with
Java. So, it would be hard to
But, if you if you ask my opinion on the
language design itself, you know,
regardless of the environment, the
community, the people, and so on. Scheme
Lisp,
Closure is
Closure is very good, okay. Anyway, it's
it's hard to say because depends on what
you mean. So, anyway, Common Lisp is
dead, Scheme is dead. Now, there is
Emacs Lisp and Closure is good for if
you want to make money, you know,
you might have a chance. For each
Closure job, there are some Closure jobs
in San Francisco and, you know, there
are some.
But, for each Closure job, you have
1,000 Python jobs, 1,000 Ruby jobs,
1,000 GoLang jobs, 1,000 C++ jobs, okay.
That's that's the situation of Closure
Lisp.
Anyway, what about Emacs Lisp? Emacs
Lisp is
um it came from Mac Lisp, okay. Emacs
Lisp, the if you talk about the lineage,
it came from
Mac Lisp,
which
So,
for for today's people, it's kind of
uh
uh s-
share
many characteristics with Common Lisp,
okay. Not Scheme Lisp, but share with
many characteristics of Common Lisp.
But, however, Emacs Lisp is just a
scripting language. It's not a
full-featured programming language. It's
in fact, you compare to
you know, all the other Lisps, Closure,
Common Lisp, Scheme, you can write
real-world applications
for millions of people to use. In fact,
there are, you know, there are systems
written in Common Lisp still used today
and there are systems written in Scheme
Lisp
still used today, but
yes, they are. And there are systems
used in Closure in many companies today,
quite a few companies.
So, but for Emacs Lisp, there's no such
thing.
Emacs Lisp, for Emacs Lisp, it's it's
basically a
small scripting language. If you use
Emacs, you code in Emacs, you write
Emacs Lisp, that's it.
Uh don't listen to the Emacs phonetic
say, okay. Emacs, if you listen if you
do Emacs, you live in the Emacs
phonetic, the well of the Emacs
phonetics.
Then then you will hear you will begin
to believe, oh, Emacs Lisp, it's it's
used everywhere. It's used to make a
coffee machine. It's used to control two
doors. It's used to do IRC. It's you can
do chat. You can you can this all that
that crap, okay.
In real life, if you want to actually be
concerned concerned about the reality,
Emacs Lisp is nothing. It's it's
nothing. It's it's like uh nothing. Not
in terms of real-world applications.
If Emacs Lisp is score is 10, then
Common Lisp, Scheme Lisp, Closure, their
score will be 1,000, okay. So, Emacs
Lisp is nothing.
So, that is my opinion about
that topic.
What is this GNU Guile? Okay, GNU Guile,
well,
uh
you know,
Nabi, Nabi Young,
uh
you are being seduced into the dark
universe of the Lisp.
All these questions matters a
really.
Um but, okay, but if you want to know,
you know, so if you are, you know, I
know you know, you told us you are like
trying to get into, I mean,
you you working a game gaming company,
but you are you
you are a beginner programmer, so you
are trying to get into to become a real
programmer, something like that, right?
So,
so these questions, you know, doesn't,
you know,
you know, you just just study Python,
okay. Python, GoLang,
uh C++,
or or C, okay. You study one of those or
even Java.
Then then you good to go.
Uh Lisp is going nowhere, okay. Well, if
you want to hang out with us, yeah.
Lisp. Okay, so but the question about
GNU Guile, what is it? GNU Guile is a
implementation of Scheme, okay,
basically. It's uh so it's it's GNU
Guile is Scheme, basically. It's a
implementation of Scheme. And it's one
of the worst implementation of Scheme.
That is what GNU Guile is. Okay, I think
that's about the Lisp.
So, you know, I have tons of Lisp
articles and I I did two full video
about Lisp,
which is, you know, a kind of
So, I mean, for those people who are
interested in Lisp,
uh I would recommend watch those two
videos because
each one is like
uh 90 minutes.
And those are pretty good. So, that's if
you, you know, really are really
interested in Lisp. So, sorry.
There are two videos.
You know, I talk in depth about
uh Lisp. Let let let me just show it,
okay. So,
there is one, but they can't they are
kind of advanced. They are for
uh Lisp
fans, okay. So, one of them is this one.
Let's go to
uh more on YouTube. Let's go to YouTube.
Yeah. Wait.
So, anyway, so I
So, we end up talking about Lisp,
which is a topic I talk too often. I
wasn't
you know, the
it's
So, we are talking about Lisp, which is
a topic I talk too often.
Uh anyway, so I have two videos and
those are kind of for Lisp programmers.
That is, if you already program Lisp
for a year or two, then you might find
it interesting.
Uh so, one of them is this one, 2019
July 19th.
On Lisp syntax, S-expression,
meta-expression, Mathematica, and
meaning of sugar syntax.
Okay, so Emily, did you watch that one?
So, that's one of them. And the other
one is
Okay, this one Well, I actually I I did
so many so many Lisp YouTube videos, so
let's stop. But, usually
I'm addressing people who already
program Lisp.
Hold on a second.
So, anyway, I did a lot videos on on
Lisp and I also have a beginner
beginner's introduction to Emacs Lisp.
You can find it on my on my YouTube.
So, that's about Lisp. That's kind of
the non-technical intro to the Lisp
families.
Okay, I use Python and C# every day at
work. Okay, yeah, great.
Yes, Emacs Lisp, this is all new to me.
Okay, we avoid GNU Guile. Oh, yeah, GNU
Guile, you don't need to do it. Learn
Yeah, Emacs Lisp is kind of
um
Okay.
Anyway, so
this is is is this is this is this is a
talk show, okay.
Not not very serious stuff.
So, let's see what what what are people
saying. So, some topics you might So,
Zoom world, I don't know. Naming random
things off top of my head, okay. So,
Unix philosophy, okay, that talked about
that
uh too many times.
But, I use Emacs Lisp and I'm not a
hobo, so road. Okay, yeah, Emacs Emacs
is special.
Of course, you know, it's many of these
pro- coders, they also
you know, they do uh they have a job.
Uh
and okay, this
So, I was talking we were talking in
on YouTube about
national anthems. Okay, yep, in Germany
is the same time as in the country I'm
from.
Czech Republic.
Dobrý dobrý den. What does that mean,
dobrý den?
Punches for the feels.
Uh and you have 1 million job in
JavaScript. Yeah, indeed, resistance is
futile. You will be assimilated.
That's a perfect
That's a per- perfection. That's a bug
perfection.
Uh drawing the horde. What is this new
guy? Okay, so Okay, so
So, what is the next topic? Shall we
like what uh
Shall we do
random
or
you know, we we have lots of random
things on the chat. Fascinating stuff.
Panera Panera has coffee refills and
and Wi-Fi. Okay, that's a chain
restaurant in Florida area, I suppose.
Uh and you can see they make this food.
What is this thing?
This is kind of half sandwich, half
Subway. Okay, I cannot tell.
But it's like Mexican based.
Uh
and we were talking about national
anthems. Actually, I was talking about
national anthem anthems.
So, I was saying Russian anthem is
beautiful.
And China China's national anthem is
crap.
Taiwan's national anthem is even more
crap. It's worst It's the worst
tune in the in the universe.
And French's national anthem is
beautiful. Okay, French.
Um You know, how I know French national
anthem? Because back in 19
81 or so, 1978 or or something like
that. 19, you know,
you have video games, arcade video
games. And one of the game
they
They they they they begin by playing
this tune. And later on I learned that's
French French's national anthem.
There's a space, you know, space inva-
invader, you know, shooting game. Should
I bring that up? Should I actually find
that uh arcade video? So,
uh French national anthem, how does it
go?
Uh anyway,
and American's national anthem anthem,
the stars and stripes, it's pretty good.
Canadian is okay.
O Canada
da da da da da da
Then, United United Kingdom, God saves
the queen. God saves the queen.
Or something like that. Save or saves?
God saves. It must be saves or save.
Okay, this is So, God is considered
plural or something like that.
Or uncountable uncountable infinity.
God save the queen.
Okay, that tune I didn't, you know,
never get into me. I don't remember the
UK's national anthem, but Oh my god,
Russian.
Now, you have to look now. Let's hear
the Russian
national anthem.
Okay, dobrý dobrý den means good day and
is used as a greeting in Czech Republic.
Okay, dobrý den.
Okay, how do you Well, I have to look up
how do you pronounce that, dobrý den?
Config technical question, how do you
set up your direct directories of
miscellaneous script? Bash it is.
Um
Well, the
you I don't have a particular
system or anything like that. How do you
set up your directories of miscellaneous
script? Yeah, it's just over over the
place.
You know, those kind of things, every
time you try to organize
um
it tends to fall apart, you know, you
There's really no one way to organize
you know, like
I mean, I
you know, I think you are saying, you
know, what how do you organize all your
miscellaneous scripts?
I don't think there's a way. In general,
there is no way to organize your files.
Like each person, your mom, everyone,
you know, non-programmers, you have a
bunch of files. And then programmers,
you also have a bunch of files in your
life.
So, from what what I see,
more for most people, there's no just
there's no way just to organize it.
And so, therefore, today the most
popular way is like just random. You
just put in a directory.
You rely on, you know, starting like 10
years ago, you rely on the Apple
Spotlight search, which I never used. I
turned off, okay? So, the same thing
with Microsoft. They started to have
search box that will search all your
files on your system on the whole entire
hard disk. The way they do that Okay,
maybe we can talk about the history of
that. So, in the 1990s or early 2000,
yeah, 1990s and 2000s,
for a programmer,
you organize your files into directories
hierarchy. You you at least you try to,
okay?
Well, compared to back then compared to
today, you know, today you have 100
times more files. But anyway, back then
you you try to organize into hierarchy.
So, if you go to programmers forum, you
know, programmers make us,
they people tends to tell you how to try
how to do that, things like that.
And uh
and if you want, usually you use grep,
you know, the Unix tool grep
to find a particular word or phrase in
your files to find the file you want.
Now, this is in 1990s and and and uh
2000s.
Uh which is what I still do, you know?
So, I have script to find Okay, let me
show you. Well, I can use either I can
either use grep, you know, in shell,
grep uh grep for something that you
know, you Okay, so you need you need to
call this command start interactive or
brief, then type grep. Okay? So, now you
get this syntax, which is grep
recursively
or the idiotics
uh face. It
grep recursively r.
Then then f f for capital f is for
um
use the power syntax or use the power
regular expression, I think something
like that, okay? Then you type a string,
then   include
uh then star.html. That means you grep
for all files ending html. Then you give
a directory. So, this is the syntax to
find all strings in a directory. That's
a grep syntax.
Uh you can do Okay, you can do that.
So, let's change the directory to the
current directory and let's change, you
know, let's just grep Haskell. Let's see
what we found. Okay, you got you got
answers here.
Uh okay, switch here. So, you got
answers, you know, you got
They don't highlight it properly. So,
for example,
uh search Haskell. So, you got Haskell
Haskell, so that's the occurrence. So, I
So, in my talk show, apparently Haskell
is mentioned frequently.
And then let's do it again. I mean,
Haskell.
Okay. You see, in my talk show, Haskell
is mentioned frequently as a dramatic
word to diss the nerds.
Okay, not because I love Haskell. So,
every time I mention Haskell is is
representative
representation of the idiocy of the tech
geeky nerds.
Okay, that's one way to do it. Grep.
Then Okay, then you close this. Then you
can do I can do.
So,
the saw list mod, okay? So, I call it
the command is called
You can see it here. Saw find text,
okay?
So, I call it and type Haskell and press
enter and type a directory
directory path and type the file name
regular expression .html, okay?
Then there it is. Magnify.
It's the same result, but presented in a
different format. So, you can see in
this file
in this file I have
one mention of Haskell. And And in this
file
I have, you know, in this file I have
like several three mentions of Haskell.
So I can just
So that's occurrences of Haskell in
Microsoft talk show.
And that command C sharp find dot EL is
written in Lisp entirely, pure Lisp. So
you can use it on Windows, on Mac, on
Linux. It does not depend on the Unix
script tool.
Uh so actually I talked about this a few
times. So let's see. Um
So you can see the source code right
here. So here is the command
C sharp find text and here is the source
code.
And this package you can download on
Melpa. So you just go here.
That's my website for it.
And you can go there and you can
download on Melpa and you know, so so
that's done in Emacs Lisp. And then
I if I want to I can call this Go land
script. So type
uh find Go.
So this is a Go land script. And it's
187 lines. So I want to search So for
example, let's do the same thing. I want
to search Haskell.
Now this has the feature where you can
search for mul- multiple words or
regular expression at one in one shot.
So let's type Haskell there.
Uh
and I want to search in the directory
C sharp talk show directory. So let's
put the path here. So
uh C sharp talk show, copy the path,
close it.
Select all.
Paste.
And and okay, here's the path I want to
search. I want to search for this word
Haskell.
Okay, run it.
So this is Go land script running. So
here's the result.
Magnify. Go to the top.
It's not colored. Now let's call C sharp
output
C sharp find output mod.
Now so I have them colored just like the
output in my Emacs
uh find
C sharp find dot EL Emacs Lisp script.
So this is the output of Go land.
Uh so you see
So that's grep. That's
that's, you know, find the string.
That's how people used to find
a word in your thousands of files.
So this this way, this method is used
throughout 1990s and uh
2000s.
However, beginning around 2005
Apple began the Spotlight. Okay.
So that means you type any word, it just
it's kind of like grep but actually
better. Okay.
Uh let me go let me explain why it's
better. So you type a word, you can type
Haskell here. I don't want to do it, you
know, I I don't want to use the
I In fact, I turned it off. So anyway,
but you can
I don't want to do it. Okay, so cancel.
Cancel. So Mac began this first,
Spotlight. Then it came to Windows. So
on Windows you hit the Windows key, then
you can start to type something. That
searches your entire drive, something
like that.
How does the Apple do it? How does
Spotlight or Windows search do? Well,
they
unlike grep, okay? Grep is searching
real time. So it actually when you try
to search Haskell, it actually actually
opens every and each and every file to
see that word is in it, then
show the result.
But that is not the case with the
Spotlight.
What the Spotlight do is that first of
all, it
it
In short, it pre-greps everything,
pre-grep. So it searches, you know, all
your entire Every time you create a file
there's a a process in the background
that that runs that checks that that
you know, in in database
technology you say it index. It it index
your files. So what does that mean?
Basically, it read every file
you ever created
at the same time when you create them.
So you it reads a file and it
basically
index every word in the in the file.
Then it's kind of like a database. So it
organize, you know, it creates a
basically a kind of a a structure. So
for example, Haskell word
it creates a database kind of structure.
For example, the Haskell word appears in
this file, this file, this file, this
file. You know, it does this. This is
called indexing.
So it just do it in the background
without you even begin to use Spotlight.
So
then for example, the word Lisp appears
in this file, this this this this file,
you know, things like that. The word mom
appears in this this files. Okay, the
word something your your bedroom photos
appears in this this this files.
So it does this in the background,
index.
So when you actually want to search
something, you type it it it it shows
the result right away, like almost
instantaneously.
You you type Haskell, all the files that
contains the word shows
instantaneously. So it it's like So you
don't have to wait for it to open each
and every of your gigabytes of files.
So that is what this Spotlight
do.
You know, I'm simplifying things. It it
actually it is more going behind the
scenes because for example, Spotlight,
this kind of technology they will not um
they will not just search for text
files.
So for example, if you have a video
file, typically you also have keywords
and stuff.
And and what if you have HTML files?
You know, for for example, if you
if I search if I grep for HTML, if I
grep for the word title
then almost every
HTML file will contain it, you know.
But that may not be what I want because
you know, let's say for example, I
search for the word body. You know, I
want to find a document where I was
talking about, let's say, body parts.
Okay.
So I want to find a file. I want to find
I I remember last year I wrote something
about body, somebody something. Okay.
I want to find it. Yeah, and I remember
it's a HTML file. So if I do grep, you
know, like I did before, then every HTML
file will show up because every HTML
file contains the word body. You see.
Well, because body is part of the HTML
tag.
So that's that is that is a problem.
So but so in the Yuan Wang, oh, good
morning and good morning George. We
started to have you know, people from
different
region in the globe coming on. That's a
good thing. Good morning all these
people
uh from China and everywhere. You Where
are you guys from? China?
China and Taiwan or Japan or Perth in
Australia or
uh Monad. Okay, I actually I don't know
what is a Monad.
Not in a way I can do a explanation.
Yeah, Spotlight was Quicksilver,
exactly. It it is Quicksilver that began
this movement. Anyway, let's let's let
me finish the Spotlight
how they do things. So Spotlight, they
index your files. But when they index,
they don't just do a dumb, you know,
grep like just by words. They, for
example, they have a
For example, when they when when they
see when Spotlight indexer sees a HTML
file it will be smart enough to index
only
the content of the file. For example, in
this file HTML, I just index these
words. Not
not the tags, you know, not the tags,
not the JavaScript code.
You know, not the, you know, ad code,
things like that.
So similarly for image files, for PDF
files, for, you know,
PDF file is very complex, the format. So
for Word Microsoft Word files, for Excel
files, for image, movie files, audio
audio files, each one of them, you know,
you have like hundreds of different file
formats.
Uh so each one of them they have kind of
a spec, you know, they they have a way
to tell which part is actual content,
which part is, you know, the markup or
the meta info or things like that.
So so the Spotlight indexer
has a set of all these, you know,
complex file formats. So it understand,
you know, when it tries to index file,
it will know, okay, what to
actually index, what to ignore.
So it is actually a fairly complex
um
system, you know, because you have
literally you have to know hundreds of
file formats
on how to index them.
You know, that's Spotlight. So
Microsoft, I believe Microsoft kind of
just copied it. Well, I don't know, you
know, technically.
I mean, I don't mean they copy it the
code. I mean, they copy the idea. I
mean, the idea is not
very complex, you know.
Basically, when you want to do this
indexing all your files, basically, you
automatically think of this
you know, so so it begin
in Quicksilver. I don't think Well,
Quicksilver doesn't actually index
files, uh does it?
Anyway, the idea But anyway,
so
Spotlight on the Apple is the
I believe it's kind of the first or at
least the first
you know, file uh
global, you know, file system indexing
utility. Then it came to to Windows.
Then the Linux, of course, it
come to Linux, too.
Linux, the most innovative system.
Uh okay, yeah, that's about that.
Emily, Emily, are you still here?
Are you Are you like turned off?
What's your opinion on the career in
cybersecurity?
Jintian Zhongwen Jintian hao duo. Yeah,
Jintian bu shao. Saga, good morning.
Castle Woo. You know, I wanted to do a
Chinese version. Zhongwen
Sa Sa pinglun.
Sa Sa pinglun tianxia.
I wanted to do a Chinese, but for the
past 3 months or 4 months, I've been
stuck in a morning schedule
because of Bart.
Well, you know,
it's which is great, you know, I so
it so happens I spoke stuck with the
morning schedule and you know, uh and so
it's very convenient for European
peoples, but I noticed
you know, I noticed the Russian people,
Russian and many I used to have a lot
Australian for some reason, Australian
people, they
you don't see them anymore.
So yeah, I think, you know, I I might um
do variety of schedules, that would be
good.
Uh so Alan and uh
So actually, I just rambled to myself
for 40 minutes, I think. Yes, I'm you
know, I'm getting good at time. I can
guess how long I've been talking.
I mean, just like ramble for 40 minutes.
So is is am I doing something
interesting?
Uh and uh
Bart.
Well, Bart is probably going to complain
tomorrow.
Sa Sa, did you do that on purpose? You
Anyway, Bart.
Bart is great. Bart is great, okay.
Um
Anyway, you know, I uh so
So what?
So I was going to do
Okay, so
uh did I miss anything? Like anything I
wanted Okay, so I
I was talking about Spotlight and the
Microsoft search because I was talking
about how people organize files.
Yeah, so Alan was, you know, asking,
mentioning, you know, how do you
organize your miscellaneous script. Then
I generalized that question into how do
people organize their files? You know,
do do you put related related things
you know, in a directory? Like, for
example, about your personal love life,
everything in your directory. Or do you
put them in like videos are in one
directory, music is in one directory.
Like, how do you how do people do?
So my answer to that question
is from my observation,
there's no general solution. In fact,
if you look at what people do,
basically, it's just chaos.
Now, among programmers, I would say 90%
99% it's also chaos.
You know, you just put file wherever.
But there are like, I think, one in
1,000 one in 10,000 programmers,
you know, some of them like, possibly,
Emily, okay?
You So you you might have a system like
you stick to a some kind of your, you
know, system to organize your files. I
used to do that as well. And another
person I know to doing that is uh John
Wiegley, who is the current Emacs
maintainer, okay? John Wiegley. He is
very popular. He's on YouTube, you know,
he's very popular. You can see him.
So and he's also a Haskell coder and
he's also doing Coq, the proof as you
know, so-called assistant proof system,
you know, math.
So John Wiegley, he also is a person who
organized all his files in certain
strict manner according to, you know,
he's he's got his own system.
You know, I'm I'm kind I'm that type,
too. I used to do that, but
uh but but I I don't do it now because
many reasons.
Uh anyway, so
so we were talking about how people
organize organize files and uh then
then I started to talk about Spotlight
technology and Microsoft search. So
for vast majority of people, you know,
you just use that because that
that is actually more natural because
most people, you don't think for 100
hours to about how to organize things.
You just leave. You just leave and you
know, when you have a file, just put it
somewhere somewhere.
Um
Yeah, that's what I do. So at least
that's my answer to that
question.
Okay, that's one topic. I guess uh okay,
so you know, that's one
that's some one topic of my thoughts.
So let's see. Alan, hello beautiful
people and
uh
Nabi, can you explain what is monad is
on stream? No, I cannot because I don't
really know that well to really explain
it.
Um
I did flame it multiple times, but
you you can only go so far.
Monad. What is monad? Monad is something
the Haskell Haskellers
talk about every day nonstop.
Uh
So good morning, George. Uh
Yue Wang.
Bobby Hill.
Uh hello from Cole Mr. Lee. Bobby Hill,
where you from?
Castle Woo, good morning.
Yue Wang, China. So Yue Wang is from
China.
And uh Bobby Hill, what's your opinion
on a career in cybersecurity?
So cybersecurity or in Well,
in Well, in general,
people just say security. So what What
Where are you from, Bobby?
So security, you know, it's a kind of a
new profession starting around 2000s,
basically.
Uh I don't know much about it. So, you
know, yeah, of course, you can you can
make a living with that and cryptography
cryptoanalysis
and along with that, Bitcoin uh you
know, the lots of, you know, and uh
uh
And Bitcoin and uh what's that called?
The new technology where you
uh
chain. Blockchain. Blockchain.
So that's, you know, the emerging
technology and I think it's
I think, you know, Bitcoin,
cryptocurrency and things like that,
they are going to stay
uh for sure and they are going to
I think they are critical. I you know,
so I think they are pretty big.
And the security, you know, one of the
reasons security becomes big is because,
you know, it becomes a profession and
more than a profession,
it's big because hacking, because you
because security becomes becomes
basically more and more and more
important.
You know, you can hack into government
systems, company secret uh basically
the gist of that is money. It all comes
down to money.
You know, so you can
bank, for example, bank security, you
know, it's all related to that. That's
why security becomes bigger and bigger.
Now, security
is a general term. Okay, there's no
one definition. It's very broad. So
almost every everything becomes security
issue now.
You can call anything security.
Uh so it's kind of abused, you know, so
yeah, you can get a career in that, you
know, you study that.
Shen Bao, oh my god, another Chinese
guy.
Hi Ksa, what do you think of Andrew
Yang?
Andrew Yang.
You know, I don't really
You know, among the
he's okay, I guess. He's okay, but his
idea, okay, among the
United States presidential candidates
2020.
So you have, of course, you have Trump,
which is which is probably likely to
win.
Then you have the Democratic Party.
And uh it's kind of a mess, you know,
the Democratic Party with their social
justice
It's extreme mess, okay?
And so among these people, among the
candidate, my favorite
Okay, I I can say my favorite. I know I
know one I'm I can I will sanction I
approve for sure, absolutely. In fact,
not just I approve, I
I wholeheartedly heartily support is
uh
Gabbard, okay? Tulsi Gabbard.
She is a great person.
She is um
she she's she love her country, my
country, okay? She
she has, you know, she she's honest. She
has experience in military and in
government, you know, she's been
a senator or something in for Hawaii at
least for like 10 years or five or 10
years. And she's in the military serving
in the country, you know, for for 10
years or so. And she's pretty honest.
She is for the people, us.
And uh she is what you know, one of her
theme is to stop the war machine, you
know, America for reasons, okay? For
reasons it it's not
you cannot explain simply. America for
reasons is a country where we invade and
rob any other country, you know?
That's what we do. We we bomb them to
free them. That's what we do, you know?
Are they democracy? Oh, they are not
democracy, bomb them.
Grab their oil. That's what we do.
America. So Tulsi is trying to change
that, you know, stop spending billion
dollars to do that, you know, kill
600,000
people in Iraq. That's what we did. Iraq
war, 600,000
civilians dead. Who do they cry to?
You know, so that's that's America,
okay? And uh among Americans, you know,
in particular
white Americans. You know, when you talk
about America, it's pretty much you're
talking about white American, okay? Even
though technically oh, we have like 40%
blacks and and we are actually uh
multicultural. I'm Chinese, you know, we
are actually you know, multicultural is
crap, okay? Crap crap.
America you talk about America. You
know, like
you can ask, you know, one way to judge
what I you know, one way to
think whether I said what I said is true
is by simply asking foreign people like
all the people around outside America.
You ask them
what do you think about America?
Typically, you know,
you you you don't you know, they they're
basically they are thinking white
people. They don't think when when it
when they think America, they don't
think oh black or or Chinese or or or
some or Indian, you know, that's that's
not the case. It's just just white
people.
And today
the white people gang, the are
the social justice type of people, the
social justice and the Democratic Party
people, most you know, some at least
some of them. The extreme ones such as
the Elizabeth
the AOC
AOC the you know, they talk about
immigration and stuff. They talk about
race race every day. You know, they
and women women oh women we must help
women.
They talk about that so that they become
more and more powerful. That basically
that's it, okay?
They are the today.
Of course, on the other side you also
have, you know, hawks.
You you you used to be American
conservatives like George W. Bush.
But but today they they they has less
power.
Uh you know, the the most power power is
from the you know, the Google.
Basically, they are tied with Google,
Facebook, Twitter, they are all tied.
And with all the major publications, New
New York Times, New York Times,
uh
basically every
you know, news
publications.
They rule, they control, you know, the
thought flow. They start to do
censorship. It's kind of amazing, you
know, they you know, America imagine the
free speech, you know, freedom of
speech.
It's the
fundamental principle, the founding
principle, one of the founding principle
of America. And now the
Democratic the social justice
they
directly and explicitly say that they
don't want that. You know, they their
excuse is oh, we don't want we don't
want hate speech. We we want free speech
is good but we don't want hate speech.
The
They they they you know, I I think we
should
do what we can to eliminate those
people.
You know, so so that so that we get a
better society. That is
me, Chinese, Mexican, black people
poor people
including woman, okay? Woman the not not
the white, you know,
rich billion dollar white women, okay?
But but the poor people everyday woman.
We all get a better life. That's my
opinion.
Uh to
to not support and you know,
basically put criminals in jail. And I
believe those
many of today's, you know, Democratic
Party leaders are that that
are criminals.
That that is my opinion, okay? Political
opinion, okay? So
politics. So anyway, back to the topic
about the
about the so presidential candidates,
you know, we have several people. So
Tulsi Gabbard I support very much.
Uh she is basically the only one I truly
support because I I mean I truly
believe, you know, the all the all
things considered, you know, I want to
you know, that's typically I try to do.
I want I consider from all things, not
just you know, hot button topics or or
do you support abortion? Do you are you
pro-life or are you
you know, the pro-choice?
Stupid jargons, you know.
And or or are you pro pro pro pro racism
or you are you not pro racism? You know.
Political hot topic. Are you pro-gun or
are you not pro-gun? Do you think we
should kill people?
The idiocy of American
way, you know, it has become that and
worse.
So anyway, so all things considered,
Tuls- Tulsi Gabbard I've
I fully believe she is great, okay? She
is a great for for us, for people and
she will she's also great for the world,
okay?
Now, other candidates. Now,
Andrew Yang, okay? Andrew Yang
he I don't like I don't I don't find his
you know, his
ideas or
uh any any I don't find any interest in
whatever he does. You know, he's just
another candidate running for president
running for president. He think
you know, just like every candidate he
think he's got some better ideas but I
don't think so. He why okay, let me tell
you why.
Andrew Yang, his thing
you know, for
for his his marketing, his idea, his
his
you know, the the thing that he tries to
sell is is basically
you know, he's a nerd, okay? He's like
us. He's a programmer. He came from, you
know, the tech industry background, AI.
So in his brain, you know, I know nerds,
okay? I'm a nerd. I criticize nerds
often. So
so from what I see, you know, Andrew
Yang, his brain
it's got nothing. You know, he he's very
typical of technology tech nerds. He
thinks just like tech nerds thinks. Tech
nerds in my opinion don't know nothing
about society. Don't know how society
grows. Don't know what people do. They
don't know they don't know understand
nothing.
Okay, so Andrew Yang in my eyes is
exactly that. No different from from any
other Joe nerds among us, okay?
That's my opinion. So Andrew Yang, his
opinion, you know, I've seen his videos.
He talk about his ideas. He's you know,
his his his $1,000, you know,
free you know, his one of the his
selling point is that he wants to give
each person $1,000 a month.
He because he believes that AI the AI
technology will take jobs away. He
believes so therefore we should start to
move into the idea of this this idea of
free wage free wage. There's a term I
forgot what what was that. Basically,
the idea is that you know, sometimes in
the future every citizen nobody has to
work. You know, you just get money for
free. You you know,
because this the technology I mean at
least from a utopian point of view, the
technology is good enough so that it
provides food for everyone. Every you
know, nobody have to work. You just
well, you do things to better society in
some way. So but you don't have to for
basic needs like food, you don't have to
work anymore. That's the utopian idea.
So Andrew Yang, Andrew Yang is start to
you know, that start to push that idea
beginning by giving every person $1,000
a month.
Uh in in my opinion, it's idiotic, okay?
It's not and I don't think it's not
going to
um work. Well, I don't know for you
know, nobody know for sure, you know,
this kind of thing. No Nobody on Earth
can know this whether it will work well
for sure or not. Nobody, okay? I can
tell you for sure.
I can tell you does it you know, you
might watch some AI experts, some oh
academia professor on AI's, you know,
they they all have opinions, but
this kind of things nobody know for
sure. So, anyway, Andrew Yang, so his
idea, you know, his idea about how AI is
going to take over, therefore we need to
do something, we need to you know,
uh
try to do something so the automation
doesn't make the country chaotic. You
know, that's basically his idea. He's
he's you know, he's he's perception.
And to me, it's you know, that's
idiotic. That's typical nerd's
perception of the world.
I don't think, okay? Well, so you know,
so so that's that's my opinion about
Andrew Yang. I don't
you know, okay, maybe it will work, but
so I don't see nothing special. I don't
find Andrew Yang particularly
interesting to me, okay?
So,
but anyway, there are some other
lots of other Democratic candidates. I
think it's far far worse. Andrew Yang at
least is neutral in the in the sense
that he doesn't he's not a like evil or
bad person.
You know, he's not here to you know, I'm
going to secretly I'm going to become
very rich and control become the US
president and I'm going to you know,
become rich. He's not like that, okay?
Andrew Yang is at least I think honest,
you know, nerd like like a nerd, typical
nerd, okay? He had the I think he's kind
of
honest, okay? Uh as compared to many of
the
uh Democratic candidates like Elizabeth
and who are the others?
Okay, there's also Bernie, okay? Bernie
is kind of different, okay? Let me maybe
we can talk about that, but but it is a
bad and and the
Kamala Harris, okay? These are scumbags.
Kamala Harris, Elizabeth Beth something,
okay?
Uh what's his her name? Elizabeth.
Okay, I'm kind of like talking to
myself, you know, just like let me I I
need to get some feedback and see what
you guys are saying.
Uh
Okay, so so that's my opinion about
Andrew Yang. He's kind of a nerd. I
don't find his
ideals ideas very interesting, but at
least he's
he's okay. I think he's okay, okay?
If I don't have any particular candidate
candidates, then maybe you know, I I'll
vote for Andrew Yang. That's my opinion
about him. On the other hand, I must
mention there's the other some of the
other
uh Democratic Party candidate
candidates, Elizabeth
that uh Hunchapota, the Hunchapota.
Elizabeth, they these people these white
women, okay? They lie. Lie
through their mouth. Scumbags.
And then then you have the AOC, this
young girl, this young you know,
self-centric, you know,
lie and you know, creating drama just
just so that she can become more famous.
Then there's this Oh, yeah, Hillary.
Hillary is the
the worst criminal on in in in on Earth.
Hillary Clinton, the worst criminal on
Earth.
Then you have you know, the
Bulky Beto or something. A scumbag. This
I think he's from Texas.
Anyways, that is my opinion about those
candidates.
So, okay, so I you know, so that's a lot
politics.
Uh 10 people watching.
Uh okay, so what?
So, maybe that's it for today.
Oh, Yuan Wang Yuan Wang uh a you are a
security researcher, now. Okay.
Uh
Message deleted by Xardi.
What?
Why is the message deleted by Xardi?
Okay, I think I'm talking kind of loud.
Now it's 7:58.
George, why is why is your message is
deleted by Xardi?
That's
very
strange, okay?
Now, is someone hacking my Google
account?
George, why is all your messages says
message deleted by Xardi?
Are you guys seeing that?
Okay, so so uh Gasso Wu Gasso Wu where
from? Do you know about keyboard.io?
Yeah, of course. You haven't read my
blogs.
Uh
Yeah, you can use to control electrons
uh elections.
Okay, I think maybe that's it for today.
Neat books.
Neat books, that's how you call that
Andrew Yang
platform.
Uh Dems talking points, free stuff,
orange man bad, yeah.
Oppose the globalist neoliberal agenda.
Tulsi would be better, okay? I like
Tulsi, but
Okay, Andrew Yang what's uh Andrew Yang
was groomed as a rich lawyer person. I
see.
Has a tech utopian nerd leftist
platform.
Out of touch.
Uh so, George says
if I can't have Tulsi, I'll have Trump
for the entertainment value.
Uh but George, you are in Australia, so
you can't vote.
Uh speaking the truth. Glad Xardi isn't
racist voting for Yang just he's Asian.
Uh Democratic love race, gender, yeah.
That's the you know, the reason the
social justice things ideas rise, you
know, about race, gender is because
those kind of thing are
if you look at things, okay? Those are
the topic those are the subject matters
where you can
that's one of the way those are the
topics where you can get everyone
involved. That is a key thing why it
becomes, you know, why the Democratic
the social justice extreme extremist
become so much evolved around gender and
race. Because those are the
if you subject, you know, if you like
forget about politics, if you just think
about what kind of subject that I can
get everyone on Earth involved, that
would be gender and race, okay? Because
you know,
everyone has a gender and race and and
sex, basically.
When it comes to
uh you know,
you know, race race is a eternal
problem. So is gender, sex, okay? Forget
about the word gender, just say sex. Sex
is the proper word.
Race and sex is the eternal fundamental
of human animals. It's a problem that
you know, depends on perspective.
You know,
you may call it a problem or it's not a
problem. But it's the fundamental it is
like you it's something you cannot
escape. Like you know, like eating.
You know, you can stop eating, you know,
it's like eating food, you know, if you
don't do that, you you die. That is why
religion
always
revolve around eating. For example, in
religion you have oh, certain things you
cannot eat, certain day you cannot eat,
you are not not allowed to eat. And
whenever before you eat, you need to
pray, you know, this is
why why does religion has something to
do with eating often? Like different
religions often have to do that. Because
eating is a fundamental it's a core part
of
human animals. You cannot escape it.
Therefore, you know, just like race and
gender, okay, sex.
Therefore, eating so so if you can
tie your ideas or whatever to eating,
then
you get everyone involved, you know,
then you know
So, that is one way, religion becomes
revolved around, you know, you have
like, you know, this
uh uh you know, be pray before eating,
things like that. And uh something you
can you are not allowed to eat and some
other day you you may be allowed to eat
and and you have fasting, you know,
certain days you have to fast, things
like that. Because it controls
you know, eating is a fundamental
thing and and and uh as a consequence
it's a also fundamental desire.
You need you want to eat. Then comes
this certain thought that tells you, oh,
you you can only do certain certain you
it controls, you see, it meshes with
eating. So, it influences you. That is
why religion is
a lot religions, you know,
they evolve around eating.
In the same way, race and sex
it it it
it's the same uh the same same same
situation. You know, sex, nobody can
avoid.
Unless you are a monk, you know, which
is one in a million, you know, if if we
all become monks, we die, basically,
human race extinct, okay. So, but for
basically everyone, you have to have
sex.
You cannot stop it. You cannot help it.
And in fact, it's built in. It's built
in because
because those who don't care about sex,
who don't want sex, doesn't matter male
or female or or those people who are gay
or you know, doesn't matter what
whatever.
If you don't really care about sex, you
die. You Those people died long time
ago.
This is called evolution because you
don't reproduce. You you you die. So,
it's only those people in particular,
those people all the time.
Guys who all every girl,
they get more children. They So,
therefore, every man becomes like that.
Same thing for women, but a bit
different. Women, they want they need to
choose the guy who is the most powerful
so they can support their children.
Therefore,
women likes
basically.
Uh because, you know, women cannot, you
know, have one baby every every time
they have sex. They only can have one
per year, basically. So, that is uh so,
they have different strategies to
to
to increase, you know, to
uh to multiply
uh themselves. So, that is, you know,
this this So, sex, you know, gender,
that's
biological fundamental.
And race is similar, okay, race is kind
of similar. You know, when you think
about race, where does race come from?
Race came from sex, okay. Race is
intimately tied with sex.
I have sex with some girl, we have
children, we become a family. That's
race in the most smallest scale. You
have a race, okay. You have
you know, you married a guy, let's say,
you married a guy, you have a family.
Then you have a family. You you have you
have a unit of race. So, I want to
you know,
So, we but but
but we may have a conflict whenever
there's a food scarcity or when, you
know, things like that. So, that's race,
you know, so racial race issues is
fundamental. It's it's something not
that you cannot escape, okay.
Um
So, so, you know, if you want to get
every everyone
involved, you know,
sex, race, and food, that's kind of the
things that the subject matter you want
to tie into your propaganda or whatever
you want to say, marketing. So, that is
why and and race issue, okay,
these issues, sex, race, sex and race,
okay,
and even food,
they are not something that you that can
be solved, okay, it's not it's not it's
not something you can solve it for good
for for for for good.
Because it's
you know, it's because it's tied to your
DNA, okay, it's it's tied to your DNA.
So, again, it depends on how you look at
the problem. You know, if you go by
Eastern philosophy,
you know, Buddhism, you don't really
look at this problem as a problem. You
know, in life you don't For example, as
a human animal, you need it's necessary.
You eat every day.
You know, maybe it's it's necessary. You
cannot You know, you then then you might
think, oh, oh my god, I have to eat.
What? Um
My god, this is a problem. I don't
really, you know, why do we have to, you
know, have to eat? Why why is the
situation that we human have to eat? And
why is it that we have to become old?
Oh, this is a problem. We can't I cannot
deal with it.
See, it's a matter of perspective. If
you really think of that There there are
some people
basically psychological
uh psychologically sick people, they
do think too much like that and they
kind of perish. They become unhealthy.
So,
the world of things it it, you know,
whether it's a problem or not, you
don't, you know, you depends on your
perspective. So, if you want to
look at gender or or race as a problem,
then it it becomes worse and worse
problem. It becomes a real problem. You
know, it's
you know, so, that is what the social
justice can are doing. They are trying
to use that to
uh
sell themselves.
Okay, so, that's it for today, okay. So,
I'm not sure I'm going to be banned on
YouTube for this.
It is a possibility. Maybe no
monetization.
Uh
yeah.
And maybe that
I'm afraid, you know,
Oh, thank you, George,
for the uh
fist check Discord, okay. So, thank you,
George, for the super chat.
Let's check Discord. Oh, I need to play
this. I was going to play this.
Oh, thank you,
jeez. I have money, ching ching. I have
money coming.
Uh and who is that?
George, why is your uh
why is your
post all like
says deleted by X star?
I am people around the world we are
flooding the buckets. Naby Why would
they send a message? YouTube is weird.
Naby weird weird some. Why is X star
deleting my comments? Yeah, I don't
know. Uh
You have been placed in timeout by owner
of the video moderator.
Is it fixed now? Uh and uh
Naby Young, thank you, guys. So, let me
check, okay. Maybe I
bumped into it.
Wait. George, uh what?
Naby Young, we are testing how much
money takes to float message on top.
Okay, so,
let's see.
George, go to channel,
report, remove,
put in user put user Let let me try
this, okay.
Put user in timeout.
Okay, let's try it again.
Oh, I think I might maybe that's why.
Ah, sorry, George. It's happened again.
I think that's why. So,
so, this
Oh, so, you cannot post for the next 5
minutes. I think that's what what what
is this about, okay. So, when you put
somebody in timeout, that means
you prevent them for from posting for
the next 5 minutes.
Yeah, I think that's why.
Okay, I think that's it. Anything else?
Post, okay.
Type it or type in the Discord and uh I
think that's it for today.
Now Now, this video, will I get banned
by Google? Hmm.
I don't know.
Okay, so, but George, you are now in
timeout again for 5 minutes.
So, just wait for it to
clear, okay. Uh
I think that's it for today. Anything
else?
Thank you, Alan.
Rate you, fear mongers. Oh, hi with rate
to you.
Okay, I think let's avoid those
sensitive words because I really don't
want to be
uh you know, banned by Google. So, uh
Okay, that's it for today, I think.
Bye, guys. Hi, Michael Edwards. Pin on
comment above.
Okay, sorry, George. Um you know, that
for that time up, but uh
Okay, let's see how long I've been
talking now.
Uh
1 hour and 20 minutes. Let's wait for 2
minutes. 2 minutes and we close. Okay.
And meanwhile, there is this Russian
girl
who is playing the Russian anthem.
Beautiful. Wait, did I close it?
Good morning, Louise Hendrick Perez.
Hey, IPM. Hey, wow, I have a lot of
people today. So, I'm going to shut down
in in 5 minutes or so, in in 2 minutes
in 3 minutes.
So, let me play this Russian girl
playing Russian anthem.
Ciao.
Okay, I think that's it. I don't want to
play the whole thing in uh in case the
you know, the the copyright, you know,
Google copyright bot
gets on to me. So, thank you guys for
coming and that's it for today. Bye,
guys.
So, if you haven't already, join my
Discord. Okay, you can find my Discord
channel um
the URL everywhere on my YouTube, on my
uh Tsar Talk Show page. Just search for
Tsar D Discord. Bye, guys.