hi guys so today I'm going to show you
I'm going to play with Mac Mac's
annotation feature dictation not
annotation dictation feature where you
can just speak to the microphone and
your type whatever
for example let's see hi guys so today
I'm going to demonstrate there it is not
hello ladies
so this is fascinating
I tried voice recognition about ten
years ago how Microsoft Windows Vista
and it works but not so well but now it
works so well very well even with
Chinese accent it can correctly
understand what you are saying although
there is a problem though typically when
you speak common words like common
speech like everyday speech then it's
fine
but if you start to read academic papers
or journals poetry then it may not work
so well in other reason it works so well
is because phone because smartphone you
know all the people using smartphone
like Siri and Google ok Google and you
know Amazon has its thing echoing
whatever
oh well it just typed the whole thing in
one shot
so I was saying the problem the problem
is that if you read academic papers then
it may not work so well because because
you know okay let's see if it's working
so dictation then okay it's miss start
over start over test
edit cancel dictation you know there's a
problem with the command menu because
it's already cancelled and it still says
cancer dictation so now it's 844 so
let's do you know another 5 minutes or
so it's oh you know the menu is stuck
stupid Apple so anyway so this feature
you can find on the Mac you just go to
preferences and keyboards I think oh
yeah so keyboard you know keyboard and
the dictation the last time and you just
turn on and use yes using hands
dictation so that we are download you
know the dictionary the data files so
for it to process and you can say that
said about key shortcut to activate it
and supposedly you know if you don't
well if you don't download you know if
you don't turn on the enhanced dictation
so it doesn't download the data so what
happens is that whatever you say you'll
be sent to Apple I don't want that but
supposedly if you download the dictation
you know if you turn an enhanced
dictation you know which which downloads
the data files supposedly you know
whatever you speak is not saying to
Apple but you know who knows well
actually you can test that you can test
that by downloading the you know the
network monitoring software such as well
you know why don't we just turn this on
for now let's say okay start dictation
okay start dictation I am starting
dictation you see the Mack can also the
dictation feature can also understand
commands so if you want to you can have
it type commands I mean you can have it
you can use voice to control your Mack
okay my my headphone is telling it's
keeping being hit every time finish it
finishes the sentence so anyway so
Wireshark
I believe that's a name that's a
software name
so Y Shack is a network monitoring
software let's go to Wiki Wikipedia that
means Y Shack so if you install that he
can monitor you know your network
activity you know who is sending what
information but but it's somewhat
complicated to use I mean you have to
learn it and based and also you have to
understand tcp/ip and by the way I have
a tutorial so I like to share with you
you know I like you to check it out
programming
computer network tutorial so there it is
tcp/ip for beginner so if you never
studied you know if you never studied
tcp/ip you might read it you know spend
20 minutes so half an hour to read it
it's it actually gets more and more
complex near the bottom which I didn't
finish well because in near the bottom
I'm actually covering lots of other
things you know yeah you can study these
things this thing for 10 years you know
networking networking is pretty it's
pretty critical you know of other things
you study in programming for example
Emacs or programming languages those are
not important actually
but networking is you know it's most
critical its where the power lies
networking in database in and also other
artificial intelligence like machine
learning not programming languages not
Emacs you know yeah so anyway so back to
dictation so what else I want to say ok
let's try to read out this let's just
try to try to read out one more passage
so go back here okay now dictation he
started and I was just chatting randomly
about lots of things
the recent dictation software gets so
much better is because because
smartphone and iPhone and you know you
know I said that already
okay now if I wonder if I turn off you
know if I tell airplane mod will this
still work he should you know the reason
is because when you turn on airplane mod
what it does is that it turn off or
basically or networking or you know it
supposedly turn off the radio switch so
you there's no internet there's no Wi-Fi
there's no cellular you know it stops
receiving note you know sending signals
wireless signals but what if what if
your computer is wired that's the
interesting question I haven't looked
into
you know there's a issue with a
dictation because you see how it changes
the previous text and also period space
returned mule I know okay that's how you
do new line new line new line so let's
read out a passage from Wikipedia now
this will be harder to understand period
new line a link state routing protocol
is one of the two main classes of
routing protocols used in packet
switching networks for computer
communication period so that's pretty
good period
let's continue
period let's continue coma coma oh it
doesn't do coma so I have to find out
how to do how to use a dictation
this is the first time I'm using
dictation on the Mac so anyway I just
want to that's that's it for today's
video I just want to show you this
feature you know I'm trying to do video
every day and it's a good thing you know
I it's it's fun for me I mean I have
lots of ideas in the opinions I just
want to talk about talk about it I mean
even if even if nobody watches it is
just for myself and I enjoy doing that
so let me know what you think and if you
would like to see what I you know what
let me know what do you like to see and
yep see you