good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of sound talk
show
today is 2021
april 18th and today we are going to do
emacs this cody live coding
and today we are going to uh explore
the fuzzy matching in emac bisp
you know first imagine is like uh it's
very useful you'll see what it means
so it's going to be mostly about emac
emacs list coding and i'm going to
expand as we go
exploring first imagine you know there
are different kinds
i'm gonna explain okay so let's begin
and by the way today
i'm using my newly bought microphone
okay
this is uh you know so so now i got the
dedicated micro
so now i got so newly bought microphone
i got a dedicated mic
dedicated microphone so is my voice good
okay so uh okay let me show you the
microphone actually let's
take a minute uh just go to um
let me show you the microphone okay xali
keyboard
so you go to actually you go to
my keyboard blog search for saudi
keyboard blog and you can see
miscellaneous and i've done some
research on microphones
so you can see uh you know shopping
choices
and i end up buying this one uh pretty
cheap
35 or something and uh looks like it's
working
fantastic fife
uh dedicated microphone is much better
than uh headset
you know my headset has hum issue like
um
[Music]
screaming like fantastic good morning
but you haven't
you are not sleeping yet and good
morning is this one crazy okay
uh actually so we're gonna focus on emac
this today just imagine
so let me begin okay meanwhile let me
turn this
uh so you can watch my keyboard instead
you know since emacs coding you uh
it's it would be fun to just watch
at my keyboard my i type okay so
let's see okay
sec
okay so so yeah imagine coding so let's
begin okay
so i'm going i'm going to start okay so
on the
on the left window the pink window is
all the
command codes you can see whenever i
press a key
in emacs every keystroke
automatically becomes a command call so
if i move cursor by words you can see
it's actually calling forward word
and and you can also see the key i'm
pressing to do that
i'm using software keys and i'm using a
variable keyword
okay so now let's begin so first so you
can
if you are on youtube you can see the
topic this okay i have the topic this
prepared here
so let me show you what we are doing
okay so we are going to
uh write uh let me let me demonstrate
okay
so uh let's see emac this
so start an empty buffer and define a
function
uh and let's explain what does this
function do
okay um the function will be
select let's name it uh select
choices okay select choices and
uh
select from a list of choices
predefined choices
using and then
then insert them into buffer okay
that's what this function does and let's
put
today's date
okay that's what this does so let's
begin
so first of all what kind of choices do
we want
okay now when you write academic paper
there's
lots of repetitive kind of sentence
structures okay let me show you an
example
uh
okay let's let's just uh show you a
simple example okay
so here is a list of uh you know
sentences
uh if you are uh in academia and you are
writing a lot of you know
theses or report or publications
you there is a particular style of
writing
which is impersonal that is the style of
academic writing
and if you search online you search
online for academic phrases you'll find
tons of those kind of database
so here's an example you know this field
closely follows the paradigm of
something something
why do we consider to be a good way to
this has been widely adopted adopted in
the field of something something
this is more widely used at the time of
something something so
those are type of the academic style of
writing
so when you in you know if you are a
professor you may
you may find what we are doing today
useful uh
okay so let me show you so so these are
the choices first of all
i want to make each line uh you know i
want to quote each line
make make them into a uh
emac list list okay so let me show you
what
i do okay i press three keys so actually
let's undo uh let me show you okay
copy paste do that that
that that okay that command you can see
is called software lines okay
and now we have now we just say
list actually
okay copy that just paste here so we
have a list here
uh let's let's call them
phrases okay
uh let's put a variable here
so the variable is phrases and the value
will be
predefined these are phrases predefined
okay
so
so these are the choices we want um
want uh let user choose once user choose
one
it will be inserted to the buffer okay
so how do you write that uh let me show
you okay
let's say let's do some quickly
let's say let's do something quickly
messages
okay and we are going to say phrases
we're gonna print
phrases uh car phrases car just means
the first item okay
so that is the function that is that's
it so now we
evaluate the function then call it
meta x select choices by the way when
you do meta x you can see
in my mini buffer
sorry so you can see
in my mini buffer i'm using i do i'm
using the
you know one of the meta x what what is
it called
smash smacks right but anyway um
so you can see there is a uh it lets you
pick some choices for example if i type
saw
then it shows all the commands uh
starting with xr
so that's what you know this is similar
that's what we are doing today we are
trying to implement
something similar okay so let's call
meta x let's put the cursor at the
bottom
middle x then type select choices okay
enter
symbols values variable is void phrases
okay this error why is the arrow
oh oh oh oh yeah we we um
yeah because we you see this part needs
to be inside the
let okay so put it here yeah
uh yeah what so why is it all these oh
yeah so
actually so you know this nested
parentheses
this this is the indication of the
problem of nested parenthesis
syntax you know some some
minor issues i mean i mean the
disadvantage of nested parentheses
syntax
so sometimes you got confused which one
is uh inside which
yeah okay now now this is good okay
evaluate the buffer
put a cursor at the bottom call it
select choices
enter
you can see now you can see at the
bottom you see
it act you know it actually printed the
first uh
line that you know this field closely
follows something
okay if you have comments and questions
just post it okay
uh z trunk crazy
wanna see my pv face uh do you suggest
you i use stone emacs coming from
veeam okay i'm not gonna talk about that
because
uh different you know basically the
answer is different people have
different choices
you know it depends on the person so
anyway let me continue with this okay
so now we are going to write a you know
modify the code so that it lets the user
pick one of the choices uh actually i
need to go
faster because yeah we have a lot to do
okay so uh let me show you what to do
okay i do
read uh this is how you uh
okay i forgot what's the name okay so
what you do is
you go to casa emac list
okay so you go to xr emac list website
practical emac list then
you go down there is a section
about uh basics functions
but text editing buffer stream functions
both for rewrite file writing command
get purpose string work with lines get
user input okay click on that
prompt for file name prompt for
directory prompt for
string this is what we want okay read
string okay
that's the command we want okay so back
to here
so so actually in emacs you can say read
string but actually there's a better
version that is i do read string
so
uh what uh okay so i do
read i do read directory name i do read
buffer i do read file name i do read
buffer
uh what the
um wait there should be
i do read string
okay there is no such function
[Music]
oh actually i have an example of i do
right here so
oh i do completing read yeah okay so
here is the function we want copy it
back to
e-max buffer i do completing
read that's right
so here let's see the documentation
describe function so here is the full
syntax
copy and paste it here okay
and let's see now we don't need the
message part okay
delete that uh delete that i mean
comment it down i do
okay complete read okay let's uh
do this okay
prompt prompt will be
make a choice okay then the choices will
be
phrases okay then optional optional we
don't care about optional okay
so that's it
okay then then you need to set the
uh let's do a variable
user choice
okay user choice is a variable here
and now we're gonna set
user choice and that's gonna be this
line okay user choice that pretty fine
okay so now insert
user choice okay that's it
let's run it run our code move the
cursor to the bottom
call it select choices enter so now
watch okay so you see emacs now prompt
us with a bunch of choices now i'm going
to start to type
as i type it will start to narrow down
the choices
and this is the heart of fuzzy
matching first imagine because it first
imagine is a very useful
feature it lets you uh it saves a lot of
typing
because of all the choices for example
emacs commands
you you do not remember how exactly the
full name of the command but you do
remember some words or
you know part of the words in the
command name so you can just type that
you know and you'll be
able to show that as a selection and you
can pick it so
right now we have the similar situation
so let's say we want the third
um you know we want the the line that
says widely
adopted okay so i type watch what i type
okay
i d you see let me try it again
magnify okay let's let's do this
w okay as soon as you type w
then those sentences doesn't contain it
will be eliminated
so you see w okay i
d okay then let's say
let's type g okay now g is a word here
let's type g
okay now that that's the only selection
now enter that's what we want you so you
can see
it inserted uh that uh
phrase okay so we have completed
essentially this is the first part of
today's
uh uh you know the uh tutorial
these uh this is how you uh
use first imagine you know how how you
write a command
to have um first imagine feature to let
users select
a predefined list of things okay this
list of things can be anything it can be
sentences
it can be a list of command names and it
can be
you know uh whatever you know whatever
you it's a part of user interface
now uh okay questions now
you know now for our application
it you know we are going to have
actually potentially
a thousand uh phrases
so and each phrase may be
you know maybe a long sentence so that
means
our command the way we implement it
needs to be fast you know you cannot you
know if you have to
every time user calls the command it
waits for
you know one second or two seconds to do
it then that's no good okay
we need it to be fast thousands of
choices
okay so that's that's how you that's how
you write it
you know you can in fact copy this code
paste your emacs you need any file and
it'll work for you already okay now
let me show you um
you know like if you just search for
okay let me show you okay
academic phrases
okay you see there's a lot of people
searching for it because in academia
professors you know academia they
they want you know they they write a lot
of papers and it's very tedious to type
all these
uh let's see so you know i
seen this before so let's go to some of
the choices okay
i mean let me show you some of the
examples so here
is a page that lists academic phrases
sentences and vocabulary so you can see
you can see how many of them there are
you know you know they are grouped
by category okay
so lots of and this is just one of the
page there are like
a hundred more so
that's a point that's that's what i'm
saying you you potentially have hundred
choices okay
and by the way this this this uh
multiple choice
um user interface is uh truly extremely
useful i
also use it for a brief because i have
hundreds of briefs
but some of them i don't use very often
so i forgot
what exactly is a brief so i can you
know so
so i have a command that lets me select
on the fly which you believe i want
so very useful okay now the next thing
so
so this is what we are doing today now
the
the thing we want to talk about is about
fuzzy matching
because if you have thousands of choices
there are many type of first imaging now
in our case for example um
uh let's try to insert this line again
okay this has been widely adapted
in the field of so let's try it again
okay so
i'm gonna show you so select choices
let's magnify
okay so watch what i type okay so
we i'm going to type uh the first
character of
each word okay this has been
widely a adopted in
the you see so if you type the first
character of each word
that will work okay
but if you type the last character of
each word
it will also work let's try it again
uh let's say so it's gonna be s
s n y
d n you see that also works
so so the first imagine used here
let me try it again okay so let's see
let's search let's try the word has okay
you see there are two sentences i mean
two of the choices that contains the
word has
okay let's try it again call it
select choices yes and uh
h-a-s okay so we got
our two sentences now let's add one more
sentence
let's try add one more sentence
etch something uh let's say heart
the heart follows the brain of okay
let's make a cv sentence this heart
follows the brain up okay
now notice in this sentence there's no
such word has
has is not in this sentence okay
now we evaluate the buffer call command
again
now i'm going to type has h-a-s
okay uh it's not showing up
uh let's let's uh it's unexpected
let's try again h a s
okay i
this is not expected because what i'm
trying to
say is that
first imagine because i was trying to
get it to show
this line why because this line contains
h and a
and s okay let's try it again
this time let's type
h a t okay so if you type h
a t it works because it matches part of
the
word heart
so now let's try t h a
okay let's see what happens t h a try it
again
t try it again
select choices t
h a yeah so that's my point
uh th a will show up you know the
sentence because
t is in the first word
then h uh let's try again ths
you know so right now we are trying to
basically what we are doing is that we
are trying to find out
exactly what kind of first imaging i
mean how exactly
uh our text input
you know exactly what's the criteria how
how exactly it use
it uses our input to match the
selections
so let's say h
e let's say
h e o okay that works because
h-e-o is the second character of each
word
uh
okay but why is h-a-s does not work
h a s let's try again okay
h a
okay okay i
think i kind of see it
h a excludes the first choice
because uh
the character you type
i i don't understand why is it why why
does not
it includes the first choice
try it again
s
o l okay that works
h a
s okay that works okay so if you have
h h a
s that works but
h a s does not work
so what about t s
t right t
s t that should also turn up the first
sentence
t s t it does
so why is it h a s
does not work h a s well because
h between h and a there's an e
is that how so if we try
t i h
would that work t i h it should not
t i h it does
so why is it h why is it has does not
turn up the first
um i don't understand
uh i don't understand but i think we're
gonna move on okay
so now let's see the comments okay big
comments uh
okay you guys are chatting random
okay so now if you have questions for me
put my name to it okay
so now okay so now
i do not understand exactly how the
how the i do completing read is uh
the criteria it uses you know so we can
we can look
into we can look at that to see how it
is
uh uh to to find the answer okay so
describe function uh then we can see the
documentation
and we can we can go
to the source code okay
go to the source code
and we can see how it is implemented
so here it is i do read internal
this is the heart of the fuzzy matching
part
so let's go to i do read internal
okay actually there is some
uh i do read internally let's look into
it
okay search next make the prompt for i
do read internal
oh okay so they actually have
a programmers a documentation for
programmers
explaining how it works
here is a very briefly here is very
briefly how i do find file works
and here is the implementation okay
now okay so now this is actually the
heart
of i do mod so you see oh my god it's
okay it's few hundred lines let's see
how many uh
what is this yeah
345 lines
i do read internal this is the heart of
i do mod
345 lines so but exactly how it's
how it does the match so
let's search for rejects
oh it doesn't even use regular
expression amazing
i mean so this is my the first time i'm
i'm looking into
the i do internal
so it does not even use regular
expression
because i thought it's creating a
regular expression on the fly
so okay let's quickly find out exactly
how it is done so
i mean i'm interested i want to know
uh let me just look okay
so if require match is the neo
uh an existing file must be selected
okay so
uh require match
let's say let's search for scan okay
these matching lines scan
yeah i cannot i cannot see okay at least
matching line scan
do
wow so actually i'm surprised it's
um implementing its
own completion basically
yeah that's let's save it
uh i'm gonna study this offline
okay so that's so good guys
how many people are watching
five uh
so let's see
so okay so that's about i do
now let's look at helm okay so let's get
some let's
get start to do something interesting
so now we explain let's close
let's go back to our talk show page
now we have explained what we are doing
we
we wrote a function using i do
we explained the possible choices can be
a few thousands
and we we demonstrated what first
imagine
is now the point here is that there are
different type of fussy matching
that's the main topic of today so you
as we have seen the first imagine in i
do mod
essentially when you type something it
take them as uh you know it takes them
as a sequence
of characters and if that sequence
occurs in one of the choices
then you'll show it does not consider
you know space or
yeah so it's basically character based
sequence
match essentially
but so what is the problem but
but there are different type of first
imagine for example
in i do mod the word order i mean the
character sequence
order we user types is very critical
because if you type for example
you know you type the same character but
but reverse it won't work
for example for example the first line
the this heart follows the brain of okay
but if you type follows then followed by
heart
in it won't work okay let me show so
order is
important so i do
fuzzy matching let's let's do a demo
first
call it select choices so i'm going to
type
follows heart okay f o l
o s h e a r t
no match because there is no
sentence in the choices that contains
this exact order ordered sequence of
characters
so i do first imagine is
a character based
uh fuzzy matching and
all the matters okay
now let's explore other types
of fuzzy matching
in particular let's
look at helms mx
i know it does fuzzy
matching but word based
and oda does not matter
for example if you have a emac sometimes
a emacs command you forgot you know some
words in it but you forgot what's the
order for example
these matching lines or or
or uh match lines
list you know something like that you
don't remember the order
so so you know sometimes you want to
first imagine that ignores
order but consider each word
so for example in our case uh in our
case
you know sometimes you just want every
you know you you want to show a list of
phrases that contains
the word observed for example because
you do remember that that is the
sentence you want
so you you start to type observed
and if you use i do
then it may it may show many other
sentences that
actually do not contain the word
observed
because it's character based you know
the whole sentence contains the
characters o b
s e r v e d but there is no single word
that contains you know
match observed so such sentence we also
turn up
you don't want that you want a word
based fuzzy matching so let's let's
let's look into uh let's install helm
okay let's look so let's go to
uh let's go to my emacs let's see if i
have
helm installed okay melpa
search for helm so actually i have helm
installed
okay so
okay so let me show you what we are
doing so um
let's look at helm's implementation
of mx okay that's what we are doing
uh so first of all turn on helmet okay
so let's see helm
oh actually we don't we don't need to
turn on helmet we we can just directly
call helm
mx okay try it
yes yes yes okay so there we have it so
now we type
select
choices select
oh you see you see so
i helms meta x is you know it's first
imagine is very different from i do
for example the command we have written
let me show you okay first of all exit
so the command we've written is called
select choices
and we can call it by
okay for example we we try helmet x
and we type choices okay
and space select you see
it shows up because it ignores order
uh and also the space
character serves as a separator
but in i do's first imagine space
character is basically ignored
okay i believe so so
so helms first imagine um
is word-based and the
space serves as a separator and the word
order does not matter
okay so this is what we want so i'm
going to start to look into
uh i'm going to look into
how this is implemented okay helm mx
okay
so we write it down this is the command
okay let's describe function on it
uh now helmet helm mx is a automated
interactive compile this function in
there in helm commands helm commands
okay let's see
okay let's just go to the source code
open there we have it
magnify
okay so let's see how this works
um pre-configured helm for emax command
this is helm replacement of regular meta
x
uh unlike regular meta x
emax vanilla execute extended command
the prefix arcs if needed can be passed
after starting
helmets so okay uh when a prefix
argument is passed before starting
helmet x the first cu well in
helm mx session will
disable it
interesting a bit confusing
if you don't know what you know if you
uh i'm not
um you know the previous prefix arc
if you understand that i mean well i'm
not going to explain
because we got other things to do so you
can get help on each command by
persistent action okay so anyway
let's see how it is implemented
uh
okay so uh wait what
okay so first of all interactive okay
so
okay so the arc here the arc
here that's basically that's the prefix
arc
okay that's the argument for this
command
basically this part means
when user calls this function
interactively
how how does the function's argument
this
one gets a value and
that is defined i mean that's specified
by this
this code interactive so we can kind of
ignore that
uh because it yeah it's it's about and
you know
current prefix arc if you don't know
what that is just search for it i have
an article on that
but we don't we don't need to uh care
about that for now
so here is the main body of help okay
so if defining keyboard marker
or executing keyboard marco
then okay then do nothing basically just
call
this means just call the standard emax
meta x right yeah because when you're
defining a keyboard macro
the fancy interface usually interferes
with your recording
so if you are actually defining a
keyboard if you are in the middle of
doing that
you you know just do the just call the
regular meta x
otherwise here is the heart of help meta
x
so it says help me x read extended
command
hub array so let's so up array basically
is a basically is a vector it's a list
it's actually a vector it's a and you
know it's a list of all
emacs uh commands you know
so this is this this thing up array is
actually
contains uh contains a
few thousand items okay
more than one thousand for sure because
i've done i've you know i've seen it
before
so anyway so this this is the heart of
the
helmet x read okay let's search for that
okay and it is defined here let's see
how big
is this okay not too big now
narrow two region narrow to the function
so it's uh
60 lines let's see how it's implemented
okay here
i see the word flex flex matching is
another
um first imagine
uh method okay let's read the
documentation
read or exec okay so here's the command
name collection
predicate history okay read or execute
action on command name in collection or
history
okay uh when when this command is used
okay when something style is used
several actions those helm type commands
are used
and executed from here otherwise this
function returns the command as a symbol
okay helm completion is not provided
when executing or defining keyboard
markers
okay uh arc collection should be
an up array but can be any object
suitable for try completion okay
okay yeah so how is it done
how is the fuzzy matching done that's
the
thing we are interested
am i doing good
does feel good okay you guys are
chatting random
uh
do we do we actually have emacs people
here
[Laughter]
current viewers five six okay
anyway so let's back to helm let's see
how it implements the flex matching so
let's just search for flex
okay okay that only occurs one time
uh
how long have i been talking
46 minutes yeah
okay let's see how this works
it seems somewhat complex
because you know
actually we are not i don't think we are
looking at the heart of the
first imagine it's not here it's
probably some other function that
actually does that
how do i know because when you call helm
meta x
you know it actually it has a different
user interface
from the gnu emacs you see
it does not pop up a list of
options in the mini buffer instead
the mini buffer remains you know like
the mini buffer but
the list of choices is in in a separate
buffer
so and also the
list of choices has fancy
quantification in e-max terminology you
know fancy
color and font
so as you type for example as i type
uh let's say copy
you know then then it started to you
know it changes
the the
the choice is buffer and very elaborate
you can see syntax coloring
you know you can see command history
section he actually has several sections
kind of history section
emacs command section
okay yeah okay two sections so far
uh and all the words copy is highlighted
let's say cop
yeah so what if i type two
okay then you have command history
section emacs command
section
okay
okay what if i type gg okay
gg yeah so
one thing i noticed you know one thing
you notice here
is that the helm's first imaging system
you know whatever whatever you type the
characters you type
must be within a word and continuously
so that means when you type gg then
this sequence i mean then you know one
of the choices must contain
exactly gg uh with nothing in between
otherwise it doesn't you know count it
doesn't match
so that's why i say helms
fuzzy matching is kind of like it's like
substring of a word based
system and the order
a word does not matter
okay so so anyway helm has this you know
special interface
now we are trying to find out exactly
where is the code
that does the first imagine so it's a
bit complex because
because since it has to create generate
this
uh fancy interface
uh so there must be a part that does the
interface
and another part of the code that does
the
the uh uh first imaging okay
okay let's see the code let's start to
read the code this is
you know this is where i'm gonna be
quiet
because i need to read the code okay
helmet line display
okay mini buffer completion confirmed
predicate so these are a bunch of local
variables metadata metadata what is it
associate associate list
flex uh
completion style if so if it's not true
then then metadata equals to that
now what is metadata display sort
function
okay so basically okay candidate
sort candidate okay lots of
things so metadata
and what is the next source
okay so then you have emacs command
history
now these sources okay sources this is a
combination of
all the possible choices probably
okay and the lisp code here is a bit
advanced because you can see they are
using the spectic
backtick basically means
evaluate only part of a list
not every element in a list okay
so anyway sources is uh creating
a you know probably creating a list of
all the
input sources selections so now
you have prompt uh
prompt how meta x prefix argument
okay then and and something something
something something okay problem doesn't
it's not too important yeah basically
it's a
string to prompt user okay mini x
now helmets timer so they also have a
timer
uh fixbug add hell move selection after
hook
okay i don't know what that is i'm not
sure what the timer does
then add hook help move selection after
hook helm
move selection after
hook then you add the function hell meta
x
move selection after hook okay i'm not
sure
exactly what that means then add hook
helm before action hook okay something
something
then okay okay now it's now here is
probably
the main part of the
code okay let's see
when and sources and reverse history
when okay when that is true says sources
reverse sources okay that doesn't matter
it just reverse the order of the for
example command history
so that the more recent becomes on top
something like that
then okay so here is the heart oh my god
so
the heart the heart of this command is
very short
so so now i understand you know i can
see that
basically the entire the
entire thousands thousands of lines of
helm
is essentially based on this this single
command
helm read extended command yeah because
that's what helm does you know helm is a
emacs package that basically allows you
to call one single command
and that can be a file name can be
a search string can be a meta x you know
something like that helm you know one
single command
and you can just type and just match
you'll you'll you know
narrow down among file
file names or you know open file history
or command name
or command name history things like that
so you don't have to think about
oh am i going to opening a file or am i
going to call
uh emacs command or you know you just
start to type you just call one single
command and start to type
so i that's essentially the paradigm of
the helm package workflow something like
that okay more or less
so now i realized so the this command we
are looking
i think okay so far so i think it's
actually
kind of the the heart of help
and okay so then this command is
actually calling
here is very you know advanced emac this
code so here's the heart of this command
the code
unwind protect essentially what that
does
is uh something like um in case this
error
what to do you know it's it's rather
it's one of the uh deep
emac beast code usually you know
you don't you don't call this you know
okay so unwind protect so
program sitcom prefix ark neo
then call helm okay okay okay here is
the
yeah here's the part here's the heart of
the helm
so it's simply you see it's simply
called a helm command so helm command is
the
the master of the entire helm package is
this function helm
so it says sources okay and then prompt
okay then buffer
uh okay then history okay yeah so let's
so now okay now we understand we we want
to look into the source code of this
function help okay so so
expand narrow to region and that's
uh let's describe function on helm okay
so there it is the um
the documentation for the helm function
so helm
is an automated helmet is an auto
auto loaded compilies function helm in
helm el
helm key sources input
uh okay everything is optional
so actually we can actually
compile this function so it's not a
command you cannot actually call it
directly so let's try to call it
h e l h e h-e-e-l-m
yeah there's no search function by
itself this is a command
this is this is the engine of the helm
package uh so essentially
it you know it's probably the case that
every command you call in helm
will eventually call this command
okay so yeah so it says the main
function to execute
helm sources okay okay
so yeah so this is so we need to look
into this
uh function this is this is
the function we are looking for
uh so let's okay so let's
let's jump to the source code directly
okay
enter
so now let's see how many lines are
there uh
wow okay so let's see narrow to defend
okay 160 lines not many
and most of it is actually common lots
of comments so it's actually
50 lines of code so that means
the first imagine implementation
is actually in another command even
deeper
oh my god
we we've been talking so so so comments
hexa long time no see anime ziad
okay i forgot sorry
uh so you know anime join discord
you know so we can you know chat
okay so so how long have i been talking
today we've been going on
for uh one hour now
and right now we are looking at the
source code in of helm
to find out how it implements its
first imagine completion
and now we are looking at this function
this function is simply named helm
and that we believe the first image the
fuzzy matching
engine
is in one of the function this function
course
so we haven't found it yet so we need to
read
up on what this function okay let's read
up okay
let a bunch of local variables
uh fn fn is a function i think
helmness keyword p
okay let is a define a function
i mean a local variable fn
and fn what is fn condition
if helm alive true or something
then the function should be helm nest
oh okay got it now okay we
are closer
okay so now we are pretty now we are
closer to
finding the implementation of this
fuzzy matching using helm now yeah
so first of all it defines a local
variable fn
which is going to be a function you see
so the
possible choices of the function is
helmnest
or or again just helmet itself
or again or the helm internal so it
looks like
helm internal is the function we want
so we are diving another layer deeper
into help
okay so that is fn okay so that is fn
now it's magnified okay
now let's see what the code does so
if helm is alive something something
then then helm is a live internal
variable
uh okay something something uh
helm is alive if
if helm is alive
okay okay on buffer okay
yeah that we don't care okay so so if
helm is not alive
then oh okay so helm alive means
you are already calling helm for example
you know i'm calling helm so you see
right now i'm in a state of helm alive
that's what it means
yeah so this that's that's essentially
what this
part uh means so if helm is you know you
are already in helm
then error trying to run home within a
running home session yeah that's uh
so if so if helm is not alive then what
we do
so we do here so if keyword
car p list now i don't know what a
proper
p list is a property list okay keyword
so if it's a keyword possibilities
and and move not regular helm argument
is okay what whatever whatever
so if key if it's a keyword
then you do that otherwise you just do
that okay so
so here so fn
equals to helm internal yeah so here
helm internal so we advanced we made
progress
helm internal is now the function we
want to look for
helm internal should contain
the implementation of how
helm implements the first imagine okay
so let's describe function helm internal
okay
let's look at the inline dock okay helm
internal something something something
okay again similar
uh syntax arguments internal hem
function called by helm okay
uh yeah yeah yeah yeah so let's jump to
source code we
we we oops uh we
you know let's jump to source code
there it is helm internal
now narrow to defend let's see
how many lines is it
okay again 100 lines not too many so
it's
you know so apparently the helm's coding
style is very
um you know it uh modulized
you know it it it tries to you know for
each function you just have 100 lines
instead of you know a huge number of
lines
okay helm internal
okay the internal hem function called by
helm right
so so let's look at the code structure
what does it do
um now again our goal is to find
how helm implements first imagine okay
so let's see i don't know what you know
i'm just looking
advices uh helm nesting okay whatever
let's just scan let's scan
and see if there are some words about
pattern or regular expression or first
imagine
okay unwind protect
okay oh my god this is
okay you know there's a lot to look into
um
helm read from mini buffer prompt
input
okay so
so helm read from mini buffer so this is
where helm uh
you know when you type this function
lets you
type something that's how helm gets
input
uh so we are several layers down
and we still haven't seen it yet
so helm read from mini buffer so
uh helm log
advice remove bound advice removed
so actually so helm is actually fairly
complicated
package
helm allow mouse okay so i
so now looks like how read for mini
buffer
is the function we want to look
into yeah let's go up let's see what
else
okay yeah i'm that i'm guessing this is
the function we want to
look into so okay let's describe
function on that
let's see what it says helm read mini
buffer is a compile list function okay
uh read pattern with prompt prompt and
initial input
yeah okay but
but it doesn't return
anything you see does it return to
something
i don't think it returns anything
so anyway let's let's go to the source
code okay
go to the source code here is the code
oh okay so let's see how many lines are
there
okay
narrow to defend again 100 lines
each function is just 100 lines no more
okay we are diving uh three levels down
by now okay helm read from mini buffer
yeah again similar arguments
so we are trying to find the
how it implements first imagine
okay now finally helm read from
minibuffer right
prompt input okay uh
with helm buffer oh my god with helm
buffer
you know it defines it defines
its own with helm buffer
okay then okay i'm actually getting
tired
so any comments
no comments uh what's a font that's a
standard font that's a console
a console that's a windows standard font
okay for mono space for code
uh with helm buffer okay so that's
basically the whole thing
then if statement helps resume
p get current source okay
make more current line updates
pre-select okay so
so let's you know again we are looking
at helm's
uh formatting style you know helms
source code for imaging style now this
is
this deviates from the gnu e-max style
because for example i can show you in
gnu e-max style
okay for example if you look at um
you know you look at this block now i'm
gonna
i'm going to restyle it you'll see this
you see this
sequence of space will be good so let me
try okay
do it oh actually
wait
huh anyway never never mind
never mind back to uh back to the led
source process p okay helm log
timer neo helm log
then when source helm resume
help display mod line
okay so pattern now we're starting to
see
pattern here helm pattern reset helm
pattern in update
oh my god this is uh helm pattern helm
input helm pattern
okay so
there is a timer now i'm not sure what
the
what is timer doing here exactly
because i've seen timer mentioned
several times
okay i don't know you know i need to go
offline and uh
study this because right now i'm
probably getting pretty boring
for you guys uh yeah
uh am i still like alive yes i'm still
talking
um let's
let's um hold on a second let's
put my face
[Music]
uh
so yeah i think we're gonna stop
now it's taking a long time make sure we
stop
uh
we are trying to find how first imaging
is done in hell
and we dived into several levels of
nested you know
functions calling functions tracing
tracking the functions
um and still i'm not seeing it
uh because you know really because
that's the heart of the helm engine
uh i suppose
so we i still haven't seen the
you know the actual code for the fuzzy
matching but we are getting close
minibuffer we set up so read from mini
buffer so it's actually
calling
but you know it's actually calling this
emac this gnu emacs this command to read
from mini buffer
so what about input you know there's an
argument of
input here that's the user input so can
we
find it
you know so this argument is actually
not used anywhere
huh in the code
okay so the comment says enter now mini
buffer and wait for input
okay so here wait
what
so actually there's some comments here
maybe they are helpful
result reset helm pattern and update
display if no result found
with precedent value of the helm pattern
okay
okay helm pattern is probably what we
want to look into
okay so helm input and what about the
input
and okay over here it says enter now
mini buffer and wait for
input so
tab okay so
you know and so so from what i see now
helm is pretty you know helm's source
code
is fairly advanced
you know it's not just um a rapper
of emac beast or something you know it's
you know especially when you see this
kind of thing unwind
protect usually you don't call that when
you call that that means your code is
doing complex things
you want a way to you know if there's
some error
that's what a unwind protect does
normally you wouldn't call it you you
wouldn't call this
so a wine protect is in emacs version
19.
introduced or before yeah i think it's
way before yeah
you know uh because unwind protect you
know i might protect
you know here's a bit uh here's
a bit um on wine protect is actually
you know for my study of
exceptions you know in programming
there's let me let me just
let them talk for now a little bit you
know in programming there's a concept of
exceptions
you know and uh the meaning of
is very different in different languages
so you can go to wikipedia there's a
article on that
exceptions you know for example java you
know especially in oop languages
it's very common to see exceptions
meaning
basically it's a object oriented
method of errors you know of tracking
errors
you know error error handling you know
error handling is a very diff uh
complex uh issue uh different
there are so many different approaches
but anyway
in all languages you know today's
understanding of exceptions is basically
from op languages basically java
you can say java's model or it's also in
javascript and
also python you know exceptions
which is essentially
basically built in go tools you know
it's like mysterious go-to that's
so if you search for saudi exceptions or
history of exceptions saudi history
of exceptions you can find it let me
show you okay
let me jump
okay so here's the article why i hate
exceptions
and i have a quote from the golan
why does go not have exceptions
and you know i did some research on the
history of the exceptions so exceptions
is actually you know different languages
they are completely different you know
even your language has exceptions my
language has exceptions but they are
like different things
completely so it turns out from
from my study you know the first
exceptions
came from lisp okay this language and
uh and and the that exception is
entirely different from from java
or from java or python or javascript
you know it's you know throw and catch
is
uh it's it's also called the local exit
so anyway i do i vaguely recall an
unwind protec unwind protect
it's one of the earliest error han
error handling um approach okay
so you know in a sense this
it is indeed actually this is the
father of the error handling
concept exceptions okay but however this
you know the unwind protect and throw
and catch has nothing
absolutely nothing to do with java or
python or
javascript you know there are exceptions
so anyway that's a um that's a
digression about
unwind protect okay that's the error
handling thing
so back to the helm i don't know
uh so i haven't found what we're looking
for
we are looking for how helm the
engine of first imagine using helm so we
it's fairly complex okay helm is uh
it's a non-trivial actually non-trivial
package
okay so we haven't found it but however
we have some we we what we achieved is
some sense of
how helm is implemented you know the
helm structure so we can see
for example we have a helm read from
mini buffer
and the function that calls it is helm
internal and the function that calls
that is
helm okay and the function that calls
help meta x
yeah helm mx right so we we have a list
of hierarchy of functions
uh okay let's write them down okay and
and
that's probably that's it for today uh
so so if i let's see if i can remember
how meta x cause helm
cause
helm read for mini buffer i think
let's see
yeah okay so it's
helm internal okay
so we have this is what we have okay
yeah so so
so this is a sequence um
call stack okay helm mx calls helm
helm cos helm internal and helm internal
calls helm read for mini buffer
and and they're small but we are going
to stop
so so what we can do
is you know we want to implement our
function you know original function we
can actually make a different version
by just calling helm internal i think
that will work
okay let's try uh
let's try helm internal it's a function
we can call i think so
okay so if we call helm internal let's
call helm
read for mini buffer okay let's see
so here's the code helm read from mini
buffer
yeah we can let's try to call it okay
so we modify our code now
so here instead of using uh
you see instead of using i do complete
read
we use help okay let's see we use helm
complete read
okay let's see
helm read for mini buffer let's see what
happens okay i'm not sure you work
let's see let's see the uh
prompt input okay so let's try that okay
so select choices okay so evaluate the
uh
function okay then
move to the bottom code select choices
enter wrong number of arguments
okay yeah okay it needs seven arguments
and and we only give it two
okay so let's instead of hem read for
mini
buffer let's try
let's try helm internal okay let's see
okay evaluate the code call it
select choices okay
initial input should be a string or neo
okay so now let's try again
now let's just try helm
evaluate the function call
select choices initial input should be
your string or neo okay
yeah so we cannot call it we need to
okay that that's that's it for today we
close down
in minutes okay thank you okay bought in
z trunk crazy
good night uh guys uh bye guys