good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of sun talk
show
today is 2021
may 14th and welcome and
we are going to do xsa tv
so today's uh random okay if you have a
questions post in the type in the chat
box and video check audio check
that's good and let's go so we are going
to do random and
first of all i'm going to show you uh
you know so i'm going to basically do
some of the things i do every day
working on my website
and so you are going to show uh you are
going to see me working on
uh emacs okay on these all these links
uh you i'm gonna tell you what what i'm
going to do so there's going to be a lot
emacs
so i'm going to do that for 10 minutes
or something then we can also talk about
keyboards you know after 10 minutes
there's there's going to be more people
typically
then we're going to talk about keyboards
uh
ms your life yes then then i'm going to
talk about keyboards or
uh emacs or whatever random stuff okay
or math or mathematica
so if you have questions for me type it
this is the right moment okay
uh the right day okay so let me show you
what i
uh do okay so typically this is almost
like
my typical day so i have this folder you
can see
there is lots of uh photo
uh screenshots you know every two
hours or three hours i get up and walk
to and fro uh for half an hour or
or you know for half an hour every every
two hours or three
and i take notes with my surface tablet
actually let me show you
so i take notes with this surface
tablet
and you know i take notes and walk back
and forth
and then so and typically these notes
are just reviewing
of my website because i have six
thousand
pages you know written in the past uh
23 years and i take notes and you are
looking at
let me show you some for example uh
so what are these notes so for example
uh
let's show you okay so so this
image from twitter for example this i
might want to put on my
uh my blog because
okay actually there's a lot of things
i'm gonna show you and talk about
so for example i have a blog about
technology past and future and i thought
that screenshot would be interesting you
know this
this uh because this is the this is a
hardware from
sgi silicon graphics uh
i is for incorporated right yeah silicon
graphics incorporated
uh in fact you know once i started
talking it's gonna be non-stop
sgi logo okay silicon graphics is one of
the
most famous uh tech company
back in 1980s and 1990s is the most
known okay so you can see
i have actually their headquarter is
right here you know i can walk there
30 minutes so i took a photo of it of it
back in 2011 um
today this company is dead okay they
they were very famous famous for their
uh
graphics computer graphics uh technology
for example
open gl is from them you know you must
know opengl or web
gl that's from them and of course you
need those for
uh in video video games and of course
microsoft created their
uh what's the name i have got but anyway
sgi okay
silicon graphics uh
computer systems okay and and they're
you know they are very famous
and uh you know so they are you know
they also they
they make what's so called workstations
workstations is basically powerful
machine
of course today's iphone is more
powerful than than their station 20
years ago
but so and so they make they make
computer software they also make
computer hardware
and you know back then this is from
1980s to
to 1990s they they
they are dead around 2008 or something
you know they they shut down they
because um anyway so
so this photo from twitter is uh
a photo of their machine you know silent
their hardware they make software
their software is called irex irix
it's one of the unix you know back then
you know today's linux people you may
not know
so unix you know before linux
linux came up around 1992
uh but until you know begin 1992 also
but not until 1997
or 1990 you know in the late 1990s 1999
it became
starting to become popular but before
linux it's unix
so you have you have berkeley
bsd you know from berkeley university
bsd unix
and a t and t unix basically then you
have
then you have you know you have quite a
few basically from these two
major branches you have silicon graphics
irix i i i r i x
you have apple a u slash x
and that is from apple computer that's
right apple computer
au slash x you know look it up
so irix okay so let me show you
uh uh irix uh
okay i need to magnify my browser's
window
so let's go to i'm using by the way
by the way i'm using edge browser h you
know the microsoft edge browser because
today
the edge browser is actually more
trustworthy
than google chrome and so i started to
use edge browser
about two weeks ago and and you go to so
old space and settings
there's quite a lot of settings you know
but this is like
back in the 2000s uh browsers
it's like it lets you control lots of
things so for now
i want to oh why is room set to 90.
so i want to uh you know since i'm doing
a live stream
i wanted bigger font so microsoft edge
is
great okay so it turns out it's it's
great and one of the great feature
you know first of all it has lots of
settings it lets
nerds you know tech geekers like us to
trick
lots of things and one of the great
feature is the vertical tabs for example
i can switch
my tabs you know you can see on the side
left side you have vertical tabs
so these are most most of them are my
pages
uh most of them are about to do and
stuff
okay um yeah
so anyway so microsoft edge
browser it's great okay it's uh very
great it's very good
it's based on uh it's based on chrome
browser's engine you know the
bing so let me uh so back to the topic
let me show you irix okay irix unix
okay let's see wikipedia so there it is
i uh close that irix okay why is it so
small irix unix okay it's uh
one of the unix okay they don't have big
bigger pictures because back then the
screen is very small compared to today
so then they there is a ux
okay these are some of the unique unixes
okay aux okay they don't
um
okay they don't okay i want to show
apple unix okay there it is
okay a slash ux it's not a u slash x
okay this is from apple
computer i have not used aux but i have
used
irix so i have used irix
and then there is hp ux
that's uh unix from hp
okay so you can see and actually i used
one of these hardware
you know hp's hardware super computer
back in
2012 yes 1999
uh so anyway that's unique unixes
so back to yeah let's get back to what
i'm talking i was going to talk about so
there are some of unix's
then ibm has ibm has
aix okay so copy
new page paste then you have aix
that's unix from ibm and let's
ah i just closed it by mistake
reopen uh reopen yeah so
um so but let me show you unix
pestilence one of my page okay
unix is the worst technology
you know in a computing industry
beginning with unix everything becomes
crap
so if you ever wondered why is the web
technology also up
uh and c language that's because unix
okay this is uh opinion
you don't hear that much because all
those opinions are suppressed
uh because yeah
i have hundred over a hundred articles
on unix
uh it's all on my website so and this
this page for example is written in 2003
back then you don't have wikipedia 2003
that's when
wikipedia began in 2003 or 2000 uh
yeah around 2003 or 204 uh
but there's not much content so you know
internet back then is you know it's not
like today you don't
you rarely most most companies do not
even have a website
only a very handful of companies as a
website usually tech companies
so back then i was you know doing sys
admin so i com
compiled all the unix resources for
example this is a mean guide
for hp ux hp unix
and this is hp unix porting uh
center you know all the unix software
ported to uh
hp unix so if you are uh see me on
uh hp unix you can you know go to this
website and download mysql
python by the way i did this screenshot
in 2020
kind of late let's see if you if they
are still up
they are so but back then
mysql is not really that popular yet you
know this year around year 2000 well
yeah year 2000 mysql began to become
popular before mysql
is there there was msql
in fact you can find the o'reilly book
uh of that
so hp ux okay hp unix
then then then then the linux come up
okay
okay so anyway so i'm not so then you
have the bsd
daemon which is a fantastic
artwork you know i traced you know uh
anyway bstm
and then freebsd then open bsd then they
split
skism you know that's uh that's
that's the nature of humanity schism
and then you have apple it was rainbows
and then it's like okay so
yeah and around 2002 apple become
a unix called mac os x
that's supposed to mean mac os 10 but
they picked
x because to reflect the fact it's one
of the unix
because by tradition uh the unix name
they end with x unix operating systems
so and you can see on this page back in
what that is is back in 2002
apple ran this ad in all over the place
in time magazine and all that you know
so it says
sends other unix boxes to dev no
an ad from apple back in 2002 because
apple began
you know apple transition to uh you know
the
uh the unix kernel which is
kind of you know kind of a bit um
difficult to define because what is unix
you know unix there's a trademark
mark owned by this company then they
this is
it's a big drama okay what's the
company's name does anyone
know remember the unix sued
all the other linux and all the unixes
because it was a trademark
fasting for five dollars thank you
fasting
so do so fasting has a question do you
have virtualbox it would be nice if
you could do a review of lobs and
explain why you hate tidying windows
managers
while using one okay i don't have
virtualbox installed
and lobs i can tell you i can talk about
that
for an hour and but i never used it
you know i i can tell you what i think
of it
for for a certainty you know
you know let's not even virtualbox if i
if i install linux on my machine
hardware you know not emulation you know
i get uh
you know maybe i should buy another
machine and get money
to do my just just for doing my talk
show
so i run the linux box and i run labs
i can tell you my opinion of loves loves
before and after is going to be same
it's it's the worst possible
but
but but you are not sure because you
know how do i how do i
how do i know because i haven't used it
well i can you know
i well i can tell you but let me get
back to that okay because i'm gonna talk
for
10 hours just about that and i'm gonna
tell you the details
uh and at the end you'll be convinced
of the fact supposedly that
my opinion of lobs before i used it or
after i
use it will be the same okay you'll be
convinced of that that fact
after i talk you know about that topic
uh and that loves uh okay so so unix
okay so
okay we are digressing and further and
further away
i was going to show you um
i was going to show you my my normal day
daily activity you know so i walk around
i take screenshots and i take notes
so i'm showing you some of the notes i
take this screenshot because
this indigo hardware is from s uh
sgi you know silicon graphics computer
uh
and they you know so i want so i
you know i you know so i put this photo
on my website blog it you know
so that's one of the things so let me
show you some of the others okay
uh this is study of wufang language okay
uh
i you know you know i haven't coded
wufang language for about 15 years
but i began to about two months ago so i
you know i walk in back and forth and i
read
you know the documentation 1000 yeah
by now must be 2000 pages of
documentation
so i take notes and i tell you i mean
this is note to myself
i write down you know which function is
new for example
3d you know solid geometry so all these
are functions
that does geometry that that are related
to solid geometry
and i can tell you you know the point
and line
those are primitives uh those are all
primitives and some of them
anyway so some of these functions are
new in what year
that's what i you know notes to myself
so for those new ones i need to you know
study and look into
so i'm just showing you some of the my
random notes to myself this is
a screenshots usually with my
handwritten notes so this is another
uh interesting thing from for keyboard
because this
is the smallest trackball uh that's
usable
so uh from a japanese guy so i i'll blog
it on my keyboard blog
uh okay i i don't need to show my
keyword blog i don't
i don't think because i talked about
that so often
so so many interesting things okay uh
you just search for
saudi keyboard you'll find it so let's
go back let's go over this quickly so
again another wolfram language stuff
okay
and this is a mathematician conjecture
hypothesis
and he's on my channel sometimes are you
here justine
so uh actually i rambled all over the
place uh maybe i should begin to
um how long have i been been talking
i've been talking for
18 minutes oh my god
[Laughter]
who what are you guys saying not
nerdsville hello
what do you think about dragonfly bsd
okay i can tell you right off that i
i've used bsd
uh which one i don't remember this is so
this is back in
late 1990s to year 2002 okay
so i've used bsd i don't remember
exactly which branch was it you know
so back then you don't even have open
bsd you have
uh i forgot but it's schisms you know
the
the the nerds the open source you know
supposedly
to be the great spirit helping humanity
but they
when you get rid of money when you do
not allow money to go around
which is basically what open source and
free software foundation is
on the surface they say free beer versus
free speech oh we are not about
uh free beer we are actually about free
speech
something like that you know but
actually
if you remove if you don't if you if
free software all the open source stuff
if
it's not free if it's not free if it is
not free if you have to pay
to get linux or or whatever then
all the free software and open source
will die overnight
they will disappear overnight so this
open source and free software phonetics
they live in a lie you know they lie to
themselves oh
well actually uh free software
foundation actually we can you know sell
linux uh we can make money off it
but actually you cannot so they like you
know they they
especially in particular richard stowman
they use the free
you know free software foundation and
they he's he defend his
use of the word free by saying that oh
actually
free there's no good word in english to
mean free because
uh in latin this libra you know
therefore he used free software
foundation the free
here means freedom not you know not free
of money not
not you know uh you know but actually
but in reality in practice the word free
just means
you know you don't have to pay like free
pizza free beer okay
so he is abusing english in a sense you
know he's
richard stowman he's kind of semi
intentionally abusing the word
free to peddle his ideology that's what
happened that's what it is
so that's and open source is basically
the same okay open source is uh
robbing richard storkman's ideal you
know
they speak basically starting by the esr
guy
eric s raymond okay and another guy you
know
but but some of these guys becomes uh
you know back then they were
all over the place but these they mean
you know
come and go people died people died you
know after 20 years some of these
people you know the leaders founders of
open source
organization you know any anyway so
so yeah open source is uh basically
rob richard storman's ideal so and it
becomes everywhere and becomes now it
becomes the evil
empire google facebook uh twitter
they are open source they are all pro
open source they they contributed a ton
in fact without google without facebook
without
uh google and facebook
and without microsoft today if you if
microsoft google and facebook dies
tomorrow let's say god says you should
die yeah they are good
open source will immediately collapse
without these without these 100 1 000
lawyers one one million patents
commercial uh companies okay
so the open source is a open source and
free software foundation
it you know it's a giant lie
and you guys most of you guys you know
live under this line because
under this lie because you think oh it's
great
and uh and that gave us today's you know
the evil empire of google censorship and
all that and facebook you know
you like facebook right do you
uh you know i talked about this topic
too many times so let's not
um you know let's not repeat that okay
so
so thank you fasting for another five
dollars um
you haven't grown a beard yeah every
time you know let's look at
mirror let's look at myself you know
every time i have
you know i'm about to shave you know
basically every every three weeks i
shave it off
uh because i i don't think i look good
with
i never tried but the chinese you know
we don't have
we don't have the western you know the
the uh mutton chop
what's it called modern chops or
whatever uh so chinese you sh
so usually you might have a goatee but
you know like the
like the kung fu masters but
uh or sensei you know the japanese
sensei so but but i don't
i don't think i like that i'm gonna so
every every
three weeks i shave it off so uh
so i rambled over the place so um okay
so uh the the conversation always comes
down to uh
ranting again is the open source and
free software foundation like and google
and facebook the evil empires you know
you know how could how big is google you
only unimaginable you know it's the
biggest
uh organization in entire human
history the with the greatest power you
know they
they they have satellite they control
all information
basically all information of
entire humanity on earth seven billions
of people about to reach eight
uh they can you know they have power
they have rocket they have you know
uh lots of things okay so
anyway i want to uh you know because i
talk about
the open source topic uh hatred of them
too much
uh in lots of my videos so let's so
let's skip that i want to go back to
um i want to start to do some of the
coding things of my daily life daily
life okay
so this is uh so let's go back okay this
is a mathematician by the way this is
the stephen hawking
uh they he you know he was uh you know
he he is uh stefan
hawking is advisor of of justine justin
is a friend in canada he
sometimes shows up in my youtube channel
and he has some
uh congenital disease some problems
so anyway so he also became a
mathematician's
disgusting so i i so i take this
screenshot because you can find it
you can find the full size photo on my
discord
you know lots of interesting people so
join saudi discord okay
uh so he posted photo of seth uh
stephen hawking uh and himself so i
wanted to blog it
uh you know put on my website so i never
had a chance you know i never got
to so this is you know so this is
december 2019
and for some reason justin justin
abandoned
saudi discord he's got problems
justin uh but anyway so
my notes going back to my notes png
optimization so this is from wikipedia
so apparently
you have a png new
tool new command command line
tool to optimize optimize png
supposedly better than um then you know
the
opti png you know the
the you know the well-known tools uh
so anyway so i want to go ahead
you know lots of notes i've been
studying also i've been studying
powershell you can go to search for my
exotic powershell tutorial i've been
studying powershelf powershell is
fantastic a magnitude better than bash
or whatever the unix
sheet bag powershell okay and more
powerful than
more powerful simpler more consistent
and uh and
extremely better more better
documentation than the bash the unix two
bags the hack
that's what unix is everything unix
is just a
it's a giant spaghetti ball of hack
and bash is a bastion the unix two shell
two bags is a very good representation
of the crap the worst craft nature of
the unix philosophy
so okay so now we are back to some of
these pages
uh i want to show you my workflow okay
so actually let's do
a few minutes of this uh so you can see
these are my notes these are pages of my
articles
my blog so this page for example is
syntax
is lisp syntax readable is it readable
so i i know it's i write down move out
because this is in uh
in another article that's uh
that shouldn't be there so this this
part should be uh
should be a independent article you know
move it out so that's why
i said right so i'm going to do this i'm
going to show you the code you know how
do i call this
and this one for example uh javascript
you know
this is the list i need to make it a
definition list okay
okay and and lots of uh okay so i have
like
10 or so of these things uh so i was
going to do
so you can see right now in my sub
programming blog you can see
a bunch of articles with the number
there so this
this article for example concepts and
confusions of
prefix infix postfix and lisp notations
this article there's a 16 over there so
y16
that means in this article let's go to
it
there are 16 arrows uh
so so let me show you okay go down go
down go down go down
go down go down go down go down
you see those arrow characters there
are 16 error characters on this page
and why do i why is that significant
because
i started to reformat my html list
into a definition list which looks
better i'll show you in a moment okay
so the first step is to search
for all my pages of the
16 000 pages find a count
of all the arrows count so because when
error occurs
typically that means i have kind of a
list
that shows you know something then
explanation
you know so but in this page in this
case it's not
you know that's not it but i'm gonna
show you okay i'm gonna show you
in a moment so that is why so that is
why you see
you see these my notes you know uh
you know you see this is at least this
this
this page is you know i i need to change
to definition list so i'm gonna show you
okay
so actually let me show you uh so let me
show you this one apple pc keyboard
difference okay
let me start to um
okay open the open the file open in
browser
magnify so this page is about the
difference between apple and pc
keyboards okay so i go into detail
what's the difference the old key
you know apple apple keyboard has
command key and so on
so go down so you can see
i am talking about mac os x default
emacs
keybinding that's right in mac os 10 if
you open
text editor you know the yeah the
default text editor
it supports the basic emacs key bindings
so for example you can press ctrl f
to move forward by you know you can move
forward you know
so what i'm going to do with this so
default emacs keybinding i need to
change it okay so let me show you
so go back to emacs and show my uh
the pink window shows all my emacs
commands so search for
default emacs okay there it is on here
so
so this text block copy it
paste it and now call command
ul to dl html ul to dl
enter so separator arrow yes
remove separator yes damn
now you see they become that okay now go
back to browser
let's refresh okay look at this part
refresh
magnify so you see before
it looks like that but now it looks
better
so this is the html definition list okay
uh so what's the html definition list
you go to
exam code
html tutorial
definition list so this page explains
the full detail about what definition
list is basically it's like a dictionary
so when you
when you have a list where each item is
like you know a term
then something a term or something then
you can use
the definition is dl dtd that's very
useful
instead of just the ordered list or an
ordered list
so so okay so so back to the
html so i'm going to delete that
you know and refresh okay refresh
you can see that that is good now
i need to capitalize the first word of
each of the sentence
because that looks better so what i do
you go here press one key now look at
the pink window okay
boom and you can see
mmm you know the change part becomes
green
now go back to browser refresh
fantastic and beautiful and this all all
this due to the work
in emacs list so that command i just
called is
up case sentence it will find the proper
place to
capitalize and by the way also i
okay so so that is
an example okay so now if you go back to
browser magnify
go to the top okay so anyway never mind
so
that's a change so now let's go back to
my picture collection
my screenshot collection now you see
this page is done
so i need to delete it so i just press
uh
forward delete key deleted done
let me do another example okay now now
i'll do this fast okay so this is track
trackable exg okay so i know where that
is
so go to xrd keyboard blog
and open trackball exg
okay this page and search for
model number okay there it is you can
compare
model numbers and difference okay so you
can see it's right here
so do the same thing ul to d
i'll call it okay let me show you the
pink pink window so
coed yes uh separator is arrow
yes remove separator yes
okay now show in browser magnify
so that's this page this page is about
elecon electron
exg trackball
let's shrink okay so go down uh go down
go down go down go down go down
so there it is that's the now again i
need to capitalize each
uh the first letter of the sentence
so in this block
so now i press a key bam back to browser
refresh good
okay now go back to my screenshot now i
can delete this one
dd so okay so that's my
so i think you know i have a lot more so
i have a lot more but i think
let's stop you know because let's so
there are so many
other interesting things to talk about
so let's uh
you know there are a lot more i need to
uh do
so so now i'm going to look at comments
and answer the questions now fully
changing another five dollars fasting
thank you
uh then i'm gonna so so now i'm going to
read the comments
and uh answer the questions
okay uh yeah and uh
yeah we we touched on already several
topics
okay so let me drink my drink
today's drink is brought to you by
energy drink
so how long have i been talking non-stop
for 36 minutes the night
is young
so dragonfly bsd let me tell you about
dragonfly bsd
i know nothing about it but however i do
know
around 2006 also the bsd
schism split again you know you have
net bsd you have open bsd
you have free bsd yeah free freebsd is
the earliest okay
freebsd and uh net and
and the net bsd was the earliest
so you have two then sometimes later you
have open bsd because people don't agree
these nice open people gentle you know
you know they disagree you are wrong no
you are wrong
so split then sometimes around i think
2008 or something
dragonfly bsd uh
you know i i don't i you know
so so do i like bsd i never used it much
you know back in the year 19
1999 i used it you know just a bit
but so why do i you know i know a lot of
people
especially you guys you know they are
into the kernels you know they they us
you know we have a friend
who for some reason i don't know a good
friend who left
our group and his name
you know he left our group he's you know
he he he
he has his own group you know linux and
texas
technology what's his name uh
i forgot what's he you know there's a
lot of posting
you know there so but what's a
place where it's more polite talk okay
luis yeah
louise i don't know i don't know i don't
know why he left
my group but anyway so he
he's a bsd expert you know he's a young
guy and becoming you know
so many people so what i'm saying is
that many people when
it comes to linux you know operating
systems they are very
nerdy you know they they are you know
they study it they study the source code
and and
and for many of them and you guys
they make a distinction distinction
which is better you know
netbsd or openbsd or linux you know they
and also in our in our community
uh emily which is the most technical and
nice person in our group emily i i have
a video that
dedicated it to her she has done great
things let me
let me mention okay so you go to my
saudi keyboard blog
let me mention again uh actually i we i
did a video
that talks about her stuff exclusively
it's uh it's been a while last year i
think so
you go to fun then you'll see
this happy hacking emily this
server you know she's the one of the
she's
the pro the most technical person in our
group in
saudi discord she's always focused on
tech
you know maybe networking you know
technical details about networking
or the details about keyboard keyboard
switch
and also recently she's been getting
into
uh let me show you some of that okay let
me go slowly
uh happy hacking keyboard and you know
oscilloscope
and programming languages she's she's
into uh she codes
erlang she also codes you know she also
dug up taco you know she actually run
taco which is the father of emacs
she you know she dug it up you know she
you know there are places you can you
can run the emulator and she actually
tries it
and she take photo of the tickle manual
which which uh she gave me you know i
asked her permission to post on my
website
so i have actually a photo of taco
manual and she explained how it works
and she also get into the esoteric
languages you never heard of
you know like um yeah you know i don't
even
you know she actually again not not just
read about it oh there's taco oh
yeah taco is you know like dribbling you
know drama
talking about about it but she actually
took out the manuals and read it and
actually coded in your emulator
so emily that's our emily okay she's the
most
technical person uh in our group and
she's very focused she never talked
about
politics or drama you should never
get involved in that so she's fantastic
so she also uh invents her own writing
system
she also created her own keyboard layout
actually yes you know there are so many
keyboard layout anyway that's a whole
topic i talked
uh i talked too many times so she she
you know she's uh fantastic
and recently she's been you know so he
has m script her own writing system
and her actual writing handwriting of it
and she recently she got into a
steno machine okay let me show you uh
this is
good to show typewriters okay standalone
machine
uh where is it miscellaneous input okay
and okay so i have a lot of her stuff so
here
so here is the display inc phone so she
got a phone
you know she doesn't follow fashion and
facts
in fact she told me she never uh she
never read
hacker news she never read read it
she's also very young okay but unlike
the most nuts who's
you know uh you know uh wallowing hacker
news or the reddit in those kind of
places
like she doesn't know what those are she
doesn't know what's a bug
man she doesn't know all the slangs of
the you know internet
but she dive into deep on technical
things
very that's that's a good thing okay i
that's that's a model that's a behavior
we should follow
i recommend so anyway she you know she
bought display ink phone she doesn't
just oh
apple came out with a new phone let's
you know we need to buy it
we need to waiting like she she does
research and she bought this displaying
form this this
uh happened to be made in china and she
you know
here's her photo uh and there's a big
you know high resolution fantastic
resolution photo
of display inc phone okay uh
and she also bought a zoom
no yeah here the you know the tablet
books yeah books you can buy on amazon
if you like it go buy on amazon okay
currently unavailable
uh this must be available version
so anyway that's uh
e-paper you know display inc based
technology
uh tablet okay she also bought it and
she showed the differences
so that's emily okay and and okay so
let's go back to the topic i was going
to say so she also
recently she's been uh diving into steno
stenotype uh and she's telling you so if
you have a question about steno ask her
because she said so on saudi discourse
you can
oh you can contact her and ask her so
she got into
standard machines this is her photo this
is her machine and
and she is telling us about how the
different standard systems let me show
you okay
uh different standard systems how they
differ and so on so
that's emily so that that's a lot of
digression and how did we get into that
i was going to oh dragon bsd okay so bsd
so emily is also bsd uh fan
okay emily is also a very much bsd fan
and she has own
she had she built her own uh
pc with amd
raisin uh you know the the
the expensive one with 96 threads or 36
cpus something like that that she built
her own
and running bsd and uh
yeah so emily is into so dragon bsd
uh so back to my point so too many
people notes you know
you guys um you know look into the
operating system technology but to me
i never you know like to me that
you know for example in primary
languages i
am never interested in low-level
languages
such as c or c plus plus
and today the many a lot of you are into
rust
because it's low level so what does low
level mean
basically you have to deal with you know
you have concepts like
float int double loan
pointers or references or
garbage collection you know like you
have to manage it you know
so but to me programming i never i'm
never
interested in those kind of things i'm
interested in high level
kind of things for example haskell uh
mathematica you know and the proof
theory computational proof systems
uh so that's so and that's not typical
and you know i'm interested in math
languages if you watch lots of my video
you know
you all know i talked a lot about
programming languages
for example uh i like golan
very much i know a lot of people these
nuts this cc
plus unix and rust nuts they usually
bad mouth go land but to me golan is the
best language
because it's simple it doesn't you know
hack
it doesn't let you do hack you know
that's what unix people like
hack the that's what they do so
programming languages
i'm into high-level stuff math advanced
math
okay i'm not interested in memory
uh memory pointers pointer
arithmetics
you know in float declaration of
types
okay on on you
so then for operating systems
basically the same i'm use in when it
comes to operating systems
i'm interested in how do you use it to
the user you know
i'm interested in it in operating
systems to me
my opinion of it is usually about the
user interface about the api about how
well it is designed how well can i use
its shell how how good is the shell
design okay
so to me the bsd
the linux they are the same to me it's
the same
you just start the shell except i don't
like bsd
because the bsd shell you know they run
the seashell
c shell or the the the bsd version of
the shell
usually and i just i hate it
the glue version on linux for example on
linux
they you they typically by default you
you run the gnu
version of the unix two bags
uh and that's usually better okay
because for
every option you know fine for example
unix find grip
you know find grab orc set you know the
unix baggage
crap you know grew
back in 20 30 years ago they created
their version usually
it's a better version it's a you know
the free software version
of the comparable unix version because
unix was not free you know unix was
proprietary a tnt and so and and so on
but the ground version not just you know
a free software free free you know
quality and code free software
but it's also better designed because
you have the
better options uh you have more powerful
options
so so when when when when talking about
operating systems to me
i look at from the api point of view
just like
how i look at programming languages i
don't care about the
low level how it's implemented or
efficiency
oh of course i care about efficiency but
not the
the hack details so
to me when i look at operating systems
i'm i'm just concerned about how well
designed how can i
you know use it and so
mostly linux and bsd to me is the same
so sometimes i ask those you know bsd
nuts or
you know they they tell you different
opinions they talk about
uh they talk about paid pages or the
you know certain bsd features where it
lets you
have you know like pseudo you know root
and
yeah but i don't care about those
features so i care is that and i don't
even you know i don't know what i care
is
basically when it comes to unix systems
linux or bsd i care about the shell
that's why i care
shell you know what what shall are you
using and how good is it
how well is it designed designed other
things i don't care
basically so uh
so yeah so so that's my question about
the
uh bsd and stuff you know i i don't it
doesn't matter to me
now about labs okay uh some of you may
not know what is lobslops is the
created by this very famous guy luke
smith
okay luke smith he's a youtuber
okay okay let's
luke smith okay let's let's go to one of
his page because
he will be fun let's go to
uh youtube okay so we need to i guess we
need to
turn on javascript otherwise no candy
welcome back everyone
uh youtube
luke you know these these are luke
smith's videos
okay so first of all he's a pretty boy
you know that's a significant reason
he's popular okay
let me tell you when you do public
things like youtube you know being a
youtuber
your looks is significant in
uh in in
a significant uh criteria
for becoming popular okay you're
how beautiful you look now luke is a
beautiful boy okay
by the way i'm not gay okay if you are
gay that's fine i'm not gay okay
so dude here is luke smith you know he's
famous for
you know he talked about you know like
like me he's basically
uh we are in the same category we talk
about technology
and opinions you know linux but he
he he is focused on the meme things
the merlin millennial generation idiocy
you know each and every his video
is plastered with this meme
stuff oh my god jesus
okay so luke smith so he has opinions
about how to you know what
what's the best editor what's the best
operating system and so on
v-veemo uh e-max he's he's a vim user
and you know you know he has a lot of
opinions just like me
and you know so one of the things he
created the the
kind of a set of tools of installer okay
let's find the page there it is github
okay he
one is github page one is his uh home
page about it
so so here's a github
nukes auto writes bootstrapping scripts
l-a-r-b-s
[Laughter]
let's analyze this thing
okay now first of all it's the title i
mean that that's the name of the
his project okay l-a-r-b-s
luke's auto writes bootstrapping scripts
then you have this iconography
you know you have this logo
ugly
okay let me tell you so what do i think
of labs
when i see a project with this logo i
will never use it
that's it i i've already decided i know
what it's like
what kind of creature on this earth is
especially the millennial generations
these malenchen
idiots not including duke okay
you know he's he's certainly very smart
okay
and capable and uh and of course you
know
techni technically speaking he's doing
far better than me because i suffer
from hunger i used to not today but uh
so he's uh uh you know so what i'm
saying is that i'm not attacking duke
you know he's a great
a very smart guy and uh pretty
successful youtuber
as well but let me attack
this this this idea of
you know the millennial generation crap
and the eunuchs
philosophy you know these hacker nuts
anyway
he's not you know he so he's uh younger
of course he's maybe maybe uh 10 or 20
years younger than me anyway so
let me get to the point okay so i'm
saying back to la
lapse okay so first of all you have this
ugly extremely ugly
you know who creates that you know back
in the 1990s
nerds are not like this this is a
millennial
generation thing millennium merlen jen
which is a word i invented malenchen
okay no space
malanjin idiot they created this kind of
thing
they liked it and uh okay
and and then then look at the title
nukes auto writes bootstrapping scripts
you have the you have the word auto
right so what does the does rice
mean
rice that's right okay
you need to go to urban dictionary
uh there it is urban dictionary rice
let there be light rice
okay it says raise in race
inspired cosmetic enhancements
[Laughter]
race inspired cosmetic enhancements
parts put on cars to make them look fast
when they have no internal tuning and
are actually slow as hell okay
this is uh not a good explanation
idiotic
you know that's a again that's a
trademark of a million generation
crap including the urban dictionary
idiots idiocy you know these
people just go there and type their uh
type that what they think about
definitions okay okay i believe here is
the original meaning of rice okay
it's a etymology of the word rice
as used by the malayan you know part one
of the meaning you know right of course
it means what china man eats that's what
i eat
but then since the malayan it has new
meaning okay so
rice an automobile that has been
equipped
with gaudy unnecessary accessories
such as three inch high spoilers
loud and all repulsive paint job
and bodywork owners of such automobiles
feel that these accessories
make their car the best in the world
when in fact it is not
that's i believe that's what uh
you know the tech nerds rights came from
a borrower from this meaning
and this meaning is from
i'm not sure from where but i think it's
from black community
the the rappers you know i don't know
because the rappers like
like those kind of things so that's uh
so that's how you you know so you see me
talk that's how i view things that's how
i think about things
so i so what i see right i think about
etymology okay proper english
i think about shakespeare i'm not into
the melangen
means crap okay so rice the etymology of
rice i you know i can go i
if i have time i would go deeper so
what's the etymology
you know find out trace arrangement of
the
etymology of rights from a linguistic
point of view
linguistic you know human history not
the millennial generation
4chan this or that or urban dictionary
okay right so that's you know stupid
paint paint jobs and stupid things on
cars that's original mini
then the new mini is something about
race inspired cosmetic enhancements okay
so so i you know
the first i heard about the rice term is
about keyboards okay from keyboards
community
do it yourself so let me show you
another
sardi keyboard okay
let me show you about this thing by the
way am i am i still talking
i'm still talking and i'm still alive
and so i'm still
chi-ching fasting so many so many
thank you so people are still
uh yeah so a lot people now comments i
uh haven't had time to read them yet but
i've been talking non-stop 15 viewers
so i've been talking for how long
one hour okay let me let me continue
okay so
so we are talking about rice let me you
know then we go back to lobs
then then you know so
let me show you this thing okay so uh
let's
let's go to fun
and uh look at this
girl this the most beautiful girl and uh
one of the best thing that happened to
my
life okay ripster in real life you know
if you don't know rhys ripster is a
famous guy in keyboard community
you know in one of the earliest do it
yourself
you know even before do it yourself
becomes a thing you know
one of the earliest uh
experts who study all
aspects of computer keyboards
uh and collect them collect you know you
know before today's become a fashion
like on reddit
you know mechanical keyboard you know uh
uh
you know subreddit sub sub there s
these corporations you know the proper
word is room okay so reddit has a room
for mechanical keyboard not separated
and similarly on discord we have
different rooms not channels okay
rooms that's how i look at things okay
in contrast to the most hacker types or
the
new generation male engine okay so this
girl is
beautiful actually i know her
and and you know
okay so so she has
you know she's also on reddit by the way
and she has articles about rice okay
so that's why i i mentioned it you know
rice
rice rice keyboard you know uh
so that's about rice you know the
terminology of rice so let's go back
uh rice so labs okay luke's auto rice
auto rice so i have to think about
so basically it just means automatically
better okay essentially that's what like
kind of
what it means automatically super
fantastic
beautiful at least on the surface
bootstrapping scripts okay let's read
you know so
alan another illustrious member of our
group
alan but he's not too active
he's building boxes and part parts
not too active today alan told me about
love
first and yeah and also alan told me
about luke's but
i i know luke's before but alan you know
keep telling me about luke smith
so loves okay so let's see let's read
about
it a little bit and let me tell you what
i uh why
what i think okay but let me let's go
back to
let's see let's let me check the
comments quickly because i do
wants to cover the few questions then
then then then that's it
that's it oh actually actually i
have to go in
in five minutes actually yes
so labs okay let's talk about labs and
what else
uh so virtualbox
i might i probably won't going to
install it uh
yeah on my you know my gaming pc uh
or possibly
yeah i'm probably gonna install
virtualbox okay okay so
so let's see what's uh other questions
did you watch
israel doves
yes i have israel dove let me talk let
me tell you about that guy that guy is
an
idiot okay tell him to watch my video
okay
he's i'm sorry i disagree yeah
he's a friend he's a friend we are at
least
were friends we were friends we were you
know both emacs users
we on twitter we follow each other we
we were following each other okay and
then there is um
then then one day we stopped following
each other
you know kind of little quarrels because
uh because yeah
a little bit to do with politics okay
a little bit to do with politics so we
are not
so much of a friend anymore so i don't
want too bad mouth about him you know
what if he
if someone is a friend yeah we can again
again bad mouth about the guys so
but no we don't we we don't
talk you know we are not we still okay
we still friends but we stop
you know uh talking to
each other much but partly because
politics okay
and but you know he he
so did i watch his uh you know israel
dove's
response to your magic criticism you
know
i i don't even remember i watched it i
must have okay but the thing you know i
can tell you what happens just
just like my opinion about lobs even
without using it because i know i know
the guy very well you know
he is
he is you know first of all he's uh
he's kind of a nerd and hacker types
okay yeah we are emacs users okay
and uh let you know let's not talk about
politics let's just start
let's just talk about our opinions about
uh unix and you know emacs stuff
so you know so one thing so so here is
my criticism of his
he's thinking basically he he's the one
he's kind of the
in the unix philosophy type of people
okay idiot
extreme idiot to the extreme
incorrigible
you know those people they when it comes
to technology eunuchs and you know
unix philosophy they they are
incorrigible
doesn't matter what they what you say
just like religious people
you know some people believe in
christianity you know
i'm not going to go too much about
political things or religion
but but you do know that some people
are deeply into religion and when you
argue when you talk
about with them about god or something
it's impossible
to talk logically so
when it comes to uh unix things you know
technology it's impossible to talk to
the
because i have 20 years arguing with
this unix philosophy
idiots extreme idiots let me let me tell
you about one incident
so i did a video talking about the
truncation of lines
by the unix okay if you don't
know
unix unix operating system they
have the philosophical ideal idea
of everything is based on lines uh ascii
you know file stream pipe
you know what whatever the in file
system
the you know the fire hierarchy
you know it's all it's all uh and and
also uh what's a
socket you know it's all
uh socket type you know it's all
basically based on
uh text files you know so they
unix one of the unix kind of designs
everything is based on text files okay
that's my
alarm clock i have to go let me turn it
off
so i have to go in five minutes okay so
you know and i have a lot of articles
let me show you okay
uh
okay let me show you just show you some
of the articles unix philosophy
the idiot the the first item is
wikipedia
you know that's a that's kind of a
lie
it's like a code uh
you know but if you are into it you
wouldn't you don't know you know i
i i i did too many videos about it
okay um
so what is the proper word to find my
article without typing my name
sorry so i'm thinking
i want to find a way to find my so to
search
to to use search engine to find my
article but without typing my name
the nature of unix philosophy
okay type that the nature
of unix philosophy there you go so
unix philosophy is uh uh it's it's it's
it's um uh how do you say how do you say
it's a it's a
it doesn't it's a lie okay it's a it's a
meaningless
crap okay so anyway i want to show you
some of the other articles
so let's just open them all okay because
i have
1 000 more than 1 000 essays about unix
philosophy all things related to unix
philosophy
so this article back to unix pestilence
which i showed this before
so this article is on the unix file
systems case sensitivity
that's another huge topic uh
back then 20 years ago for all
throughout 1990s
unix idiocy uh okay here i found my
article so here is a collection of about
10 or 20 of them about unix okay
on unix file name character problem okay
the unix
idiocy extreme you know everything
that's wrong in computer
uh software industry uh i would claim
begin with the unix crap unix and c
language
they go hand in hand unix and c they
bootstrap
each other
so let me tell you okay so uh yeah so i
was talking about
there it is okay
unix rfc line truncation this is one of
the most
idiocy created by unix and
lingering even today it's a you know
unix philosophy
the thing unix and c has a massive
uh uh damage to
the computing industry even here today
why because
when you when you type something you
know when you are in your editor you
know for example in git commit
messages usually people say they say you
you need to truncate your lines for
example
for example so uh for example let me
show you this one okay here is a long
sentence
you know but if it's code or whatever
people say that you're
the idiots you know the hackers or the
you know they they have the idiom or
style guy they say
oh you cannot do that you you need to
cut
you know you need to truncate it like
that okay so and
each line must be less than 80
characters or 70 characters okay
you still have that convention all over
the place on git
you know on git messages on magic
of the emacs you know everywhere where
does that
truncate 80 character slang came from
that came from the
punch cards you know from 196 1970s
punch cards you have 80 horse the
idiocy of this
idiotic idiotic facts
and in unix the operating system unix
used to
truncate all your lines because for
example let's let's go to shell okay
okay i'm not on unix so i don't have the
uh ps okay so you can see here's the
powershell okay
uh powershell ps is the you know show
processes
you can do on linux you know just type
ps
and and on linux you type psa uwx okay
that shows you
uh doesn't work on powershell because
the options are different
so so so ps you know uh
these processes you know but sometimes
when you start the process
it's a long line so it's more than 80
characters on unix you're just silently
truncated so if you want to
find if you have a process of let's say
apache running
so you know you type ps let's let's
magnify okay i cannot magnify here
yeah i can but it's too much trouble so
let me just
let me just show you on emacs okay
so i need to go so in five minutes uh so
let's say
you know only on linux you type this
okay auww
x and uh uh and
you grab apache or grab something okay
because you want to find the process the
the
the process id for some uh
command you run okay that contains the
word apache or whatever
you know sometimes it's a shell script
and sometimes it's nes the shell script
is in
deep nested directories so the full or
the command line
lots of options is more than 80
characters okay
and when you do this on unix in
even up to year 2002
the unix operating system will silently
truncate
all the lines that's more than 80
characters so what the so when you
do this
you're trying to find the process you
run you know that contains some
some some word here okay
uh some word okay so let's say x y z so
you know for sure because you just
started the process that contains the
word x y z
in it but you learn this nothing shows
up because
it so happens the word x y z is beyond
80 characters
and and unix the ps and all the tr
silently truncated so so it doesn't show
it's a unix that's how unix
is
so truncate lines and in email you know
email so let me go back to show you my
articles
so email the unix
the crime unix is a crime you
know
uh you unix you know the email the
the how they called you know it's long
time ago i don't uh forgot
i don't remember the names you know the
email protocols they know that inbox
okay
inbox uh you know they email so
so unix they they have rfc
tells everyone that when you have an
email and you know you you need to
truncate your line here okay so where is
it
unix's plane uh plain text email fetish
okay where is it
uh ifc line truncation okay uh ifc
ifc2822
okay the unix tradition requires that
the return be inserted at
every 78 characters in email messages
unixes made this as a recommendation
into rfc
what does ifc stand for really
common
okay so unix because the operating
system
system is too idiotic to it cannot
it's incapable of handling long lines so
they truncated silently
and they force this into every other app
like
every other operating system they tell
them oh look at
ifc the standard you should truncate
your lines
unix that's what happens
so i actually did a video on this
already uh this is probably one hour
okay
one hour and 90 minutes okay 90 minutes
let's let's you know the you know 2019
may third unix philosophy truncate lines
closure
concurrency ai consciousness okay that's
a
two years ago 2019
so i did this video and uh back to the
israel dove guy and he you know he
he watched you know he watched it
[Laughter]
and he says you are all wrong oh my god
sally is wrong okay
okay oh i'm wrong okay so what's your
reason can you can you tell me
uh you know what's your reason
which part i was wrong then he
his response is like incredible idiocy
because
just like the way i have argued with the
unix people for 20 years you know they
call me a troll
i look at his reason his reason is no
reason
like did like i did i did 90 minutes
video
explaining the whole thing about unix
tranquility lines
and he don't like it flew by his head he
didn't get it oh he sees oh what he's
not talking about
that's heresy unix is the best solving
system
like he has no reason
uh that's that's so that's uh that's
that's yeah that's what i have to say
about that guy you know
yeah we are still i guess we are still
uh on good terms i well i don't know
maybe he's
he he watched this episode and he or he
oh
i don't i don't know so that's my uh
and yeah so that's my that's what i
think that's you know he's a unique sky
uh encourageable it's he's been too far
into it cannot be helped doesn't matter
how
you know how into what length you
explain things
okay i don't have time to read all the
comments uh so one more
so this fasting
thank you uh fuzzing and that's it oh
george
ching stop ranting you are late secretly
yeah so the thing um yeah actually i
gotta go yeah okay
so good it's uh the new language okay so
yeah i'm gonna go a shutdown in one
minute okay
wow today turned out into another to be
another
giant unix rent at least half of it
so i've been talking for how long um
one hour and 20 minutes okay
you know the unix incredible hum you
know that's that's perpetual
so so i have over 100 essays
uh about all the details of unix okay
and for example and here is one rob
pike what raw pack is one of the big
unix leader okay
on the origin of the unix start file
names you know
the unix have you know like yeah
like uh cd to a directory cd dot okay
cd dot dot you know let's let's
uh let's go to first of all
cd dot sorry info okay
uh what okay uh cd webcast v
dot info uh let's go comp okay
uh not underscore info
okay so i'm using powershell by the way
and you can do ls
or you can do da or you can use the full
name
get ch uh get child items
powershell is the greatest you know a
magnitude better than bash
okay so so so what i'm what's my point
so yeah i'm talking about the unix you
know you have uh
how you have the let me show you okay cd
dot dot
that that means one directory up that's
a unix convention
of course now it's so it's so popular
it's you know
it it it's adapted by powershell as well
so that's my point you see unix and see
they are a crime you know they are
their harm is not just temporary it's
not just oh
uh they design that way but okay you
have your opinions
they have their opinions maybe it's good
maybe you are wrong maybe i'm wrong
maybe i'm you know you are right
uh and you know that that's that's it
for
for that but it's not like that unix is
a cult
okay that's why it's a they have the
unix philosophy
meaning meaningless you know they
bread they
they bread this coat so that's what
that's why i say they have a
perpetual harm you know ever you know
lasting everlasting throughout computing
industry
so we talked about the line truncation
uh even today you know you can
you you go read style guides you know of
different languages
uh you know ruby ruby or git commit
messages or different languages you
and even in this they tell you if you
don't get you know you
if you have a long line they say oh you
cannot do that
stupid you know and you know they don't
understand you know they
these people they don't know they don't
understand you know like
anyway i gotta go so so and and
and and this you know the powershell
also adopted you know these two dots
anyway so then you have the dot dot
something file name config files you
know dot
emacs uh you know that's idiotic uh and
and and many okay uh so i have 100
articles on that
this unix code uh very harmful
thank you guys thank you for fuzzy
thank you thank you george uh that's it
bye
uh so we're gonna