seen you guys for a while for 10 days
welcome to another episode ofar talk
show uh there are a few things so most
today we're going to code iMac this
fantastic beautiful drawing generated by
Machine amazing amazing achievement of
humanity you know a machine can draw
this thousands of them per second uh
this is generated by gr you know the gr
on Twitter Elam musk X so um a month ago
or two we did a talk show about machine
uh generating images so today I'm going
to call emac this and some random some
some kind of announcement you know so
Twitter uh you know uh you know not
Twitter but Odyssey let me show you so
you go to kadi kadi uh doino code uh my
website for computing
math and uh then you go to the
programming blog so there is a
announcement made by Odyssey Odyssey is
a video and streaming platform so they
are saying that YouTube is making it
difficult for for copying syncing videos
you know YouTube so Odyssey video you
know I have a Odyssey
account so you go there here is my
Odyssey account so turn on
JavaScript if you are here say say hi
hello K and uh if you are watching
offline ski around so honestly I I have
a mirror of my uh live streams on
Odyssey
fantastic uh why do I have a mirror
because YouTube has become extremely
corrupt you know they do a lot of nasty
things uh well most most more
specifically censorship you know they
control what you are allowed or not
allowed to say so YouTube has become
extremely nasty and not just censor
censorship but because Google you know
because the whole censorship Google has
become degraded in quality you know
Google used to be the best quality
software in any software Google made
from about year 2000 to year 2010 okay
Google is the best you know their slogan
was do no evil and they are truly best
and we programmers promoted Google
because they they support you know open
source software they are truly good you
know and all the software by made by
Google are truly best quality but since
about 2010 they they removed you know do
no evil from their from their you know
corporate
um corporate um declaration you know
Manifesto things you know they so they
be and and then they become extremely
evil they they do all sort of nasty
things they create the APM protocol
which is
you know lot tons of nasty things I have
a Blog if you just search for Google
crimes Google crimes you'll see a
index uh okay let me show you
Google crimes okay let's stop this are
you guys watching me am I going is my
audio check video check I think I'm good
right comments guys did you change the F
of your emac uh yes and yes kind of I'm
using a right now I'm using a um you see
you press three keys so this this
variable peit mod that will change your
buffers font into a variable with or
also known as
um uh uh sense Ser F
okay so anyway I have articles search my
blog you'll find it how to and also uh
convenient commands to do
it
so so so I was saying you know Google
did a lot of things nasty so um so you
can
see Google crimes index you know
Google okay so where do you find that
Google CHMS there yeah well it's on
Hacker News so you click on Hacker News
then you click on you know this
on Google crime so here's my website uh
a list of
Google's kind of unlawful some of them
some of them are actually unlawful and
Google has been sued for it you know the
APM
scam they are trying to you know lots of
nasty things and Google J jamini you
know like you know the like ratio stuff
you know so Google has been
extremely nasty you know like unlawful
so that's why I I was trying to I was
thinking about switching to Odyssey
Odyssey is a alternative uh video
platform uh but it's not very popular
you know but other othery is kind of
this open source uh anyway you can look
into Odyssey okay so anyway Odyssey
announced that Google is STO thinking
you know Google's YouTube is stopped
stopping other video website from
automatically copy YouTube videos to
other
websites which you know which
is which is technque I mean it's not I
mean if you know I think that YouTube
has a right to do it because YouTube
It's a commercial you know software
server service you use it it's you know
they provideed you for free so they have
the right to say what kind of cannot be
done you know of of their of their
software obviously they don't want
competitors just simply be able to grab
whatever YouTube you know even if you
allow it so anyway Google is starting to
make it you know that's why we love
Google before Google YouTube when when
Google bought YouTube it's like you know
it's so much Freedom you can control
whatever you want you can even get paid
via Google ads you know
but it has going down you know it's it's
become so bad so Google is now starting
to do nasty things they don't they don't
publicly say it but however they they
try to do a lot of technical stuff so
that they prevent other websites such as
Odyssey from syncing YouTube videos so
here's the you know Odyssey made
announcement so it's likely you know in
in down the road swing in the future you
know Odyssey won't be able to copy
YouTube videos so that means when if you
want your video to be on Odyssey you
have to actually manually upload it
yourself which actually is a good thing
because that way it makes Odyssey kind
of independent not just like a backup of
YouTube
videos so um so anyway my my
announcement about my C live stream is
that I you know I'm thinking about you
know I might be switching to Odyssey or
uh alen's X also know as trator so today
actually just five minutes ago I did a
test live stream so you can kind of
listen to it uh test live
stream so I'm not sure which one I'm
going to use either Twitter or RC or
both or maybe if I talk about politics
then it's Twitter otherwise technique
Tech content it's othery or maybe
technical content remains on YouTube I'm
not sure yet but this probably going to
be some change and also when you do live
stream like the way I do it you know
every every live stream is like one hour
long and I just talk about things Rambo
a lot and usually when you do that you
don't get much views so you know it's
like two different kind of Styles when
you kind of do the live stream
talk or even lecture even if your uh
content is good it's not like
focused uh meanwhile if you load like
especially shorter videos focused on one
topic such as like Tik Tock you know
tits and ass of the white girls or the
YouTube shorts pry you know like the the
million views 10 million views like like
they are mostly just TT tits and ass of
girls especially white goes you know
that that is a that is you know that
that is actually what it
is uh but most people you know they
avoid saying it directly so anyway so
typically when you do a focused content
especially when it's short you have much
more viewership and you know Google's
algorithm actually control it that way
because Google wants money you know they
want ads money so they they so you you
tends to get into a situation
where uh for example let's go to YouTube
youtube.com Okay so you know you go to
YouTube and you see lots of these
brainless
Fox uh you know
uh you know like like the Zuma Fox with
their face and and shorts um so anyway
so so my point point is that when you do
a live stream the way I do it like a
live stream kind of just talking about
things you tends to have significant
fuel uh viewership also controlled you
know by algorithm like like 10 times so
even more than 10 times uh 50 times
less viewership so I have been thinking
really to do um pre-recorded
video you know maybe 10 minutes each or
20 minutes each but I'm not really
interested you know in doing that
because that when you do you know I
talked about this before several times
when you do a pre-recorded video like
vast majority of
YouTubers that means your inter you know
your interaction you you you you
basically more or less become reading a
script so it's less genuine less authent
authentic you know it's less of real
real human communication when you do
live it's more real human communication
like which happens in the past thousands
or million years of human communication
like your granddad telling a telling you
a story that's how you learn history
from your granddad how things were how
you know how things are you know you
learn things but today you you know in
modern society in the past let's say 30
years you don't get that much
anymore so you become this you know so
it's it's not so good and especially
America you know all everything is
capitalism commercialized marketing so
you got this all these
canned you know videos like you know
they they they prepare they read the
script they prepare and it's like
everything is so nice just focused on
one thing but it lost Humanity it lost
the human touch and uh half of that then
become fake phony like so-called
clickbait or or the Zoomer faces ah this
happened oh like like this you know what
the [ __ ] uh you know food and you know
so and and and look at this all the
girls girls the center of humanity look
at this you know showing tits and ass
and
whatnot so when you do a can video you
tend to lose the human touch so I I I
don't I don't really that's not my thing
I prefer just talking talking to you
guys you know like uh even without
preparation so so what now so that's
some you know so so going forward you
know I might be
using uh live stream on Twitter or
Odyssey I'm not sure yet which one I
have not tried live stream Odyssey yet
so anyway that's just some
uh
notification okay so now shall we start
to code emac this or maybe not maybe
just announcement
today so we talked for 15 15 minutes
um so how are you guys doing so okay
maybe not not coding emac this today
because you know I've been coding so
much emac this like focused emac this
coding in the past two years uh um
usually when you do that you know not
not many um people are that interested
so anyway so let's let me
yeah emac list coding okay so today I'm
supposed to write this
um generate a Sit map
which you know generate a s map in emac
list which I have done that you know I
did the last last live stream about that
before um so okay so let me show you the
page then we are not going to do it so
here's my goand
tutorial can you see it yes so goand
tutorial and then you know so check it
out if you like my work you know pay me
that's the you know put money uh where
your mouth is you know that's that's the
way to go you know pay me if you like
stuff you can find my links and stuff go
to you know on S code and at the bottom
on Amazon patreon or PayPal okay so go
back to the goand
tutorial cheers this is red why Trump
got elected that's another uh that's a
news that's amazing you know that's a
landslide uh and uh it you know the word
you know it's like a a heavy dark cloud
has been lifted around the
globe everyone is cheering you know the
stock went up the you know the the
Bitcoin went shot up to you know to to
to tremendous hate
anyway height so anyway goand tutorial
so you go to goand tutorial and you go
to examples you have uh generate sit map
so here's a code you can copy you can
run it it will generate So-Cal sitemap
you can look up what's a s map okay so I
I I I'm pretty sure I I did a live
stream on coding this or in emac thisp
so so let's not do the coding today
since I talked about the video
announcement and social stuff so the
other news is of course Trump um got
elected and it's a land slide it's just
you know it's just incredible
so I voted for the first time in my life
I became a American citizen in year 2000
exactly and uh I I I might have voted
once when when uh Arnold swasher you
know the Terminator guy is running for
California Governor that is around
204 and that is one election where I
looked into it a lot you know I spend
days look into the election you know USA
election so but I don't remember I
actually voted on on on year 2004 so so
so this year actually may be the first
time I ever voted as American citizen
and you can see I took a photo of it I
voted because the USA is on the verge of
collapsing okay the the because mostly
uh well because of the deep
State and uh and one important part of
it is the USA Democratic
party uh and look at this picture this
is a
girl she got her tits cut off because of
the democratic party okay and uh anyway
so I voted for the first time and and
here's another picture of the white
girls the center of humanity you know
they making a scene they are the
attention of
everyone young girls uh and then okay so
I voted here is a photo okay so here's a
photo of me I voted for the first time I
kind of scrambled that's on November
5th uh about five days ago so I I wasn't
sure I'm going to vote because in
California is controlled by De
Democratic party which is so-called a
blue state so you know this it's
unlikely becomes you know it won by
Trump VI are the
electo elector Electoral College you
know kind of complicated
system and it's it's kind of it's it's
not so good but anyway I voted on no
November 5th I wasn't sure I want to
vote I need you know I'm going to
because California is going to be not be
Trump anyway so my vote is kind of
wasted so but but I asked
people whether I should does it make a
difference uh so here is my question to
people uh where is it let me find it
okay so tury G
tury tury gabard she's one of the
greatest American okay tury
gabard greatest greatest
American and and that she has been put
on watch list by the by the very corrupt
[ __ ] Democratic party you
know she's the greatest American she
fight for America but she put you know
she she's she's been put on to a terror
terrorist watch list what a [ __ ] scum
the the bidden harary Clinton Nancy
Pelosi uh and Kamala Harris puppet you
know so that's why I
voted I vote for the California governor
gav new to go to jail and uh beiden in
Harris so anyway so so I was asking a
question and that post is um and by the
way here is a Trump's uh nce or
something you know another white
girl and uh
so so where where is my post let me find
that
okay yeah so here is the post of my my
voted
uh and uh and uh okay so go back and
uh yeah so here's my like my uh poll
about whether I should
vote you know let me explain so yes you
should vote help make America great
again or yes it's a citizen's Duty you
know yes you should vote but for a
different reason it's a citizen's duty
three no you should not vote because
it's helpless it's
rigged number four no you should not
vote because the Deep State runs by
itself president president who is the
president doesn't matter you know that's
also a kind of a popular
opinion uh which is kind of true also or
five no you should not vote because take
a dosm stance that's a Chinese
dosm do good but let the world take its
own course you know so I was thinking
should I Vote or not and so a lot of
people are you know for Trump you know
of course obviously because they follow
me so they saw the vote vote uh the poll
so they say yes you should vote for you
know make America great again which I
agree and then some people say yes you
should vote because it's a duty you know
that's kind of the tradition of America
you know why should you vote because uh
democracy you know you citizens elect
their leader leaders you
know and some some some some people
picked n it's really helpless you know
that's a lot of the foran well you know
my foran type of followers with anime
profile pictures uh then some people
yeah and then some people says yeah no
you know be a doist so you know the
doist meaning is that's that's kind of
the
Chinese one of the predominant
Chinese culture and philosophical
thought you know the Chinese I'm I'm a
Chinese blood obviously so and I was not
born in America so I
wasn't I didn't grew up in America I you
know I'm I lived in USA since I was year
uh 20 years old and uh I I lived in
Canada since I was 16 so I was born in
Taiwan you know
so for the first 16 years of my life
actually for the first 14 years of my
life I
was educated in Taiwan as a Chinese you
know so my thoughts
are half Chinese not like the American
bone CH
Chinese and uh then so and so so I I do
know you know certain Chinese point of
view so the you know one of the you know
one of the Chinese view is that you
don't really as a Chinese you you know
you don't really participate in like
politics okay the the thought is that
the PO the politicians or leaderships or
Kings or Emperors whatever the name goes
by um they should be good of course if
they are bad you you you you you
know you try you know they you you
Revolt you get them off but you but in
general you don't push for like you
don't get involved in in in in politics
I mean you can if you want to but I mean
it's just like the general thought that
most people you don't so I mean so this
is in contract you know so you you do
good you know you do whatever is good
but you let the nature takes its own
course you know you recommend you tell
other people to do good uh but the world
has you know kind of has its own ways of
running things in other words you be you
do not become a Fanatics like you know
like do go to the extreme so that's
that's kind of a Chinese Cultural um
thought so this is in sharp contrast to
Western the white men's kind of their
view their culture you know the Western
they they they for the past you know
2,000 years or more they are more
like obsessed about Justice and
democracy and repu public you know
so so obviously every person every
citizen needs to get involved you know
you need to express your view otherwise
you are you know it's a duty you it's
it's a thing you need to
do in contrast the Chinese culture dosm
or confusion ism is that your duty is
not about you know what's Justice your
duty is to respect your elders respect
your
parents when your parents get old you
provide for them that's your duty okay
but not the Western Society you know
like the Western Society your parents
you send them to the you know old old
people's houses you
know but the Western Society they focus
on the Justice Duty for democracy you
must participate you know you must
express your views about your you know
uh rulers so
anyway anyway so I voted okay and it
turns
out I didn't know you know like I didn't
know what who is going to win but it it
it turns out it became tremendous you
know
tremendous Landslide you know like and
the only States that's blue are those
States who which illegally made it made
it the case that you don't need you know
you don't need the voter ID to vote
basically so the only blue states are
the states that does not require a voter
ID which is which is kind of like
extremely corrupt you know by law by US
law every American understand you must
be American you you know in order to
vote you know you know because that's
you know we Americans you you know you
you you are for your country you don't
allow do you allow Chinese from China
communist to to to vote for USA
president or Russian or or or or or Iran
obviously not this is this is
America but the the blue the Democratic
run States
they specifically created espe
especially in California the new the G
you know the Gavin
Nome extreme criminal he put out a law
that
says you are not allowed to check vote
voter ID in California okay actually
there's a law about that
recently so it's extremely corrupt so
the only states that are still blue are
are these states who does that does not
require a voter
ID so extremely extreme
corrupt and then the trans you know the
cutting off the tits and dicks of
children and and and create a law like
in California that that that you are not
allowed you know if the school do not
have the you know they they they don't
they are not required to tell tell their
parents the the kids parents about
what's going on [ __ ] extremely
corrupt Gavin new and this this
Democratic party
scums made made me very angry okay and a
lot of people and Incredibly this
election American turns out to vote and
uh it became just Pro Trump
so so that's that's incredible that's
you know that's incredible and I you
know I I I I I wasn't expecting it it it
happened so right
now it's like every you know a lot of
people you know like obviously many of
us are very happy but meanwhile for me
for example the anger is still there
because because during the past 10 years
you are so much suppressed you know like
you you cannot on Twitter for example
during the Jack does Twitter you can you
cannot say
men are different from women you know an
obvious biological fact in fact they
have professors telling you that
biologically actually there's no
difference men are you know men and
women are are the same then you got the
men's in in female sports you know and
for a while they are saying women can
beat men but then until the trans came
up it it it turn turns out in all sports
the trans beats all the women like
record-breaking then they start to erase
the word women you know they don't call
it women they say you know like the
gender that can something you know they
can they say they they they say men can
get pregnant and all the commercials
they they show pregnant men in all the
news
magazines you know such a
degree the degree of Corruption of these
it's it's it's you know it's like incred
it's it's it's incredible degree but
America because but the Americans
especially the younger people the zumas
they don't know you know they grew up in
this you know in the past 10 years in
the in this environment you know so um
so anyway I think that's it for
today uh s sispa say sea are you are you
are are you the are you
the
says I think you are from that name
SE cheers red
wine so CA says thoughts on people
crying about not being able to kill
their own kids via abortion
oh yeah okay so the issue about abortion
so of course we all know in United
States it's you know it's
like I mean in America it's kind of City
usually so you have the you know the
repu Republican Party versus the
Democratic party and almost on every
issue is just like either it's one party
or the other I mean so like on any issue
the opinion is like whether you are
Republican or whether you are democratic
then you don't have to think about
anything on any issue is just like if
you are republ Republic then then on
abortion your opinion is this you know
so for example for
abortion the re for the Republicans they
call it poor life meaning that you know
the the the abortion should be illegal
with certain restrictions you know on
the other hand if you are the Democratic
you know um party abortion should be a a
women's Choice called poor choice you
know they they have these euphemisms you
know one is called Pro po Choice the
other is called poor life it's kind of
funny it's
interesting too because you you go into
the
Linguistics context because why you know
why you call it pro pro choice and po
life you know obviously the better more
communicative term is like pro-abortion
anti abortion right but no but but all
the political slogans they they they
have to use some kind of
euphemistic uh jargon to promote
their you know promote their their
their uh promote whatever the the take
on on issues so so for pro abortion they
call it pro life meaning that I mean
they call it po Choice meaning that
women should have the the the the the
vast amount of choice on decide whether
she going to abort her baby in fact to
the extreme case is that you know you
you can [ __ ] and if you got you know of
you know first of all you have condoms
and pills but if that fails you can
abort your baby anytime you want you
know that that's the extreme extreme
case for the Democratic party's view on
and on the other hand the
prolif is like is is anti-abortion and
the view is that mostly they are
associated with Christianity which is
the foundation of USA American you know
American
culture uh for good or bad okay but it's
a USA tradition okay so so the PO says
they are they are anti-abortion because
you should not so because babies are
sacred it's a life you you know you are
not supposed to just abort because via
technology you know you you can just
like [ __ ] around and [ __ ] be a
prostitute or be a a
[ __ ] and [ __ ] and then AO and so the
Christian they you know that's American
tradition so my view is that on abortion
I I think that my view is that hello
German
Molina my view on abortion is that this
you know some issue there is no right
answer okay there's no absolute right
answer for it so for me I think abortion
is kind of like that I'm so before
before two let's say before the rise of
social justice War year in 2000 in
2016 all my adult life I lived in
California which is very Lefty you know
state so I'm I'm I'm kind of influenced
by the left kind of view so so on
abortion let's say before 2016 my view
is that yeah sure why not you know
technology allow us to abort you
know what's wrong with that you know and
I'm not Christian you know I'm Chinese
most Chinese are not Christian and you
know I don't understand the Christian
things you know by now I understand some
you know like
666 you know the Christian oh you know
everything is God you know you you are
playing God or whatever but anyway so
I'm not a Christian I wasn't born a you
know I don't have touch with
Christianity I know a you know I have
some friends you know who are Christian
now but in general Christians things are
not you know it's kind of foreign to me
so I wasn't born with the idea that you
cannot like like like you cannot have
sex you cannot have [ __ ] you cannot
have [ __ ] yes
that's that's all like
Christians forbid those things in
General on the other hand the you know
so I thought abortion is fine you know
there's nothing wrong with
it but not today okay because today
after 2016 I started to see this this
all of a sudden this weird things like
this this this this extreme Fe you know
so so-called feminism like the man the
you know males are evil oh be the whole
society is corrupt because patriarchy
because men men are the [ __ ] scums
you know I started to see this and gay
gay should be the king of the world if
you are gay you are the you are the
greatest person on Earth and then if you
are trans you are the king you are the
super king of you know this [ __ ]
scums I started to see
this so then then so today my my opinion
about abortion is like [ __ ] ban
abortion okay [ __ ] this corrupt so-call
Democratic you know today's Democrat
Party hello Hank of flamio okay I think
that's it for today that's so that's my
opinion about abortion in summary I I
don't think there's a right correct you
know answer to that I mean it depends
you know if you really need it you
should have it you know because you know
there are some situations so for example
in rape or you know if you are very
young if you are 14 sometimes you need
you do need to have abortion that help
you in some way you know like depending
on person depend depending on family you
know whether you
can afford you know whether your family
is in a good you have a good family then
then your family can help you can take
care of it but on the other hand for
some girls it so happens it's
unavoidable it it's reality that you you
don't have a good family you know you
got kicked out you know you run you are
you know you run away from your family
then you got [ __ ] you know you got a
baby you need to abort it so in some
case it's good
well meanwhile you shouldn't abuse it
you you you should not think like oh I'm
just I'm just gonna be a [ __ ] and [ __ ]
over every day sleep with other people
and then if if if I forgot to use a
condom or fail or P or fail I'm just
going to abort you shouldn't abuse it
that way so that's my opinion about
abortion you know but but the thing is
in US say it becomes you know like like
just like just one you know Republican
or Democrat everything is like just
belong to one one view or another and
that applies to gun gun is another issue
I think it's kind of like abortion
there's no right answer and today I
support gun similar to abortion you know
before you know I was
thinking what you know you know well
first of all gun is a you know for
citizens to be allowed to own a gun is a
foundational culture of America okay you
have to respect that because different
countries they by by history by chances
they have different kind of the way how
they are formed in USA America it's a
it's a it's a right so-call you know by
the white man it's a right to have a gun
that's American culture that's a
foundational culture very important you
cannot you know you cannot you should
not dismiss it
okay but I thought you know what you
know you know maybe it's bad to to allow
everyone to own a gun yeah it's American
culture but you know but then you know
most people should you know you don't
need a gun you should have a peaceful
Society why you need a gun right that's
that was my thought as a California you
know before before
2016 but then so so then I started to
see the Democratic like the then the
mass m school shooting every every day
every other day school shooting why does
it happen because there's a problem
there's a problem people are not happy
created you got criminals created by
this corrupt Democratic party Fox that's
why they're school shooting okay then
the Democratic party want to control gun
like like especially on Twitter you see
you see the some of the you know like
like the Hop guy David hop a [ __ ]
scum you know like they they they they
they they they just want to say you know
you should not allow and the change of
gun emoji
that's spectacular change the gun emoji
into a water pistol so therefore you
reduce violence the [ __ ] lies by
these Democratic part party scums
okay so today I support guns okay I
support for Americans to own a gun you
know that's American tradition I very
much support it I want to [ __ ] these
corrupt
people okay that's it thank you guys for
watching I think that's been uh almost
an hour okay that's it for today
okay so if you like my videos support me
okay go to s. info patreon me PayPal me
Amazon gift card me okay Amazon gift
card means
something and I think that's it for
today and uh in summary I might started
to do videos on
Twitter uh on Twitter on Len X or
ay or on at
Odyssey and maybe I'll make some can
videos instead of live stream it you
know I'll see how it goes maybe I'll do
some maybe I'll I'll do political talk
shows on Twitter and uh maybe technical
on YouTube or maybe on I'll see how it
goes okay so yeah so today's topic is
like the USA election and
stuff tremendous you know you know
there's a lot to talk about um because
the USA election is not just USA because
it's Global because USA is
essentially up to up until now is is
basically controlling the direction of
the entire Earth okay by United
States essentially and especially in the
past you know in the past five years
it's also controlling the entire Western
Europe and um anyway
bye
guys we shut down shut down in a minute
one minute okay so let me
just go land tutorial copy the link uh
we shut
down in one
minute Google crims okay copy that
Google crims collection of Google crims
okay so
actually
cheers close
that Odyssey
copy paste ay
page close
that uh okay and
Twitter Len X