Good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Exon talk
show. Today we're going to call
JavaScript. I'm going to I hope to
explain the JavaScript iterators. So in
JavaScript you have iterators, then you
have iterables, then you have generator,
then you have generator functions. Very
complex. So I'm going to try to explain
that uh and uh ex you know explain my
work in the past uh few weeks uh lots of
work on JavaScript updating JavaScript
because they have a new version every
year new version every year since 2015
so they added features you know so you
got 2015 161 17 so I've been lagging
behind for like five years so I updated
a lot huge amount of it in last two
weeks and uh but today we're going to
try I'm going to try to uh I'm going to
try to do a good job explaining
iterators and
uh uh iterators iterate you know this
very complex iterators you got iterable
iterable object iterators and generators
and generator functions
uh then I'm going to try to explain why
they are bad I think they are bad in any
language they should be banned
from the perspective of programming
language design. Okay. And if you are
here, say hi. If you are watching
offline, play at 1.5 speed or faster
because I ramble. Um I hope I can get
focused on this these topics. So hello
Scott. Scott is a professional GPU
designer re writing in C++.
uh you
know highly respect
um yeah you know CPU GPU design you know
writing code um I don't even know what
it what it means Scott tried to explain
to me a few times but after a while I
forgot like so if you really want to
learn something you have to like work on
it you know you have to get into the
field otherwise you just forgot if you
just you know curious about
So okay so iterators so let's uh let's
so I start with um you know so I worked
on JavaScript a lot there's tremendous
things to add so so check out my website
okay so just search for JavaScript in
depth.info info and you will see my full
tutorial on JavaScript. The
most complicated language today well
less than C++. Okay, JavaScript is one
of is is like the top I would say top
three top four the most popular language
but also the most complicated. It's
tremendous baggage watts. Uh but C and
C++ is
worse in my opinion. JavaScript is got a
long way to go before you compare
compared to the [ __ ] pile of
C++ but JavaScript is up there. So and
you know since 2015 they made a lot
updates tremendous update. Um
uh so but by the way in a month ago on
April 28th episode 4 episode 649 I
explained um how JavaScript object
system works and why it sucks. So that's
a good one. Okay. So you can go check
out that object system. But today so so
JavaScript is very complex. So let's
look at the you know but since 2015 they
made a tremendous massive change like uh
adding features 2015 so finally like you
have a variable declaration that's local
before you cannot do that you know you
cannot have local variables so it's
tremendously like the worst language so
in 2015 they added you know local
variables let and constant then they
added a function arrow function because
for mostly for like functional
programming I mean it's convenient very
convenient they you know they added rest
parameters and default values for
function parameters very useful so
essentially they updated huge amount of
the language you know so it's JavaScript
today in terms of features um it's
comparable to other you know modern and
scripting languages such as Python, Ruby
or PHP.
PHP actually, you know, after the past
20 years, they improved a lot. PHP is
actually a good language
now. So anyway, JavaScript 2015, they
improved a lot. They added it's
basically like a complete new language.
Okay. So you can read um I detail you
know uh every each every every feature
added but but the thing is they did not
change it you know they insist that it
must be backward compatible. So that
means all the [ __ ] like the utter [ __ ]
in JavaScript in the past you know from
1995 to 2015 that's like 20 years all
the [ __ ] is still there. So when you
call JavaScript it's like you know
riding on a highway with lots of
potholes. So you have to be careful you
know oh you can't use this one because
that's oh lots of bad design you know
returning you know it automatically
converts something you know you can't
use so you have to use this one that
there there's like tens of it things
like that tons of it so you have to
avoid potholes you know when you code
JavaScript event you know then your code
is okay but but it's very comp
complicated okay so hello uh GNU and
Scott and Scott C++ with STL, you know,
creeping featurism to the point of ugly
readability. Yeah.
So you know we were talking about reduce
you know the the the functional
programming language reduce function and
I realized actually a few years ago it
is one of the most powerful you know the
you know reduce uh okay I'm starting to
digress but let you know let's talk
about that just for a moment. So reduce
is actually the most powerful functional
programming form analogous to the loop
because in reduce or sometimes it's
called fold in JavaScript you have
reduce so so let's go to JavaScript you
know so we can stay on topic uh
search reduce so you have array
prototype reduce then they added reduce
right few years ago so reduce you know
it works like like that so reduce is
a functional programming language
programming style form for any loop
whatsoever loop you can do you can use
reduce because why because basically it
just pass the state information to the
function in each loop so that's what I'm
saying then we were discussing on some
discord you know we we got some good
programmers here and uh so we started
argument and so
And someone showed me um let's see uh
someone showed me okay so let's magnify
uh god so control
plus yeah so we can magnify so let me so
reduce you know we talking about reduce
then someone showed me reduce in C++ and
you know one of the fascinating thing
okay we are digressing all over one of
the fascinating thing is that can reduce
work in parallel. So we get into
parallel computation you know it can if
the function is associative you know
it's starting to get complex you know so
this is a mathematical property of a
function if the function is associative
then reduce can kick into parallel
computation you know that needs to
explain you know but uh let's skip that
because I
want every time I start to do live
stream there's so many things to go into
so reduce can do parallelism and it
turns out in C++ it can be done you know
C++ so the guy showed me uh let's let's
go back so it's a few days ago so if you
haven't already joined Kasadi discord
uh the invitation link is on ksadi.info
info. Okay. So, Steve, you know, Steve
is a very uh meticulous guy. So, he
showed me the
C++ C++ reduce it can do parallel
computation. If you specify in the
argument, you know, so I I I I asked for
the documentation and I looked at the
documentation. Okay. Okay. I'm
digressing over, but let's just do it.
So the C++ uh Golang is 10 times faster
than JavaScript. There's lots of things
to talk about. C++ documentation is
incomprehensible. This is like the first
time I see C++
documentation. Okay, so you got reduce
you know imagine can you like can you
guys actually see it? Uh let's magnify.
Okay, let's magnify one more.
So you got it turns out you got this
template then you use less than equal
sign greater than equal sign as some
kind of parameter indicator. Okay. Then
you got this class class T class and uh
and and more and execution policy you
know t reduce parenthesis execution
policy
policy. What what the [ __ ] is that? So
in a parameter of a function or template
you got this execution policy policy.
Then look at this one fold left. So
apparently they they distinguish um
reduce and fold. You know someone in Kad
um you know in in Saudi discourse
someone mentioned you know actually they
make a distinction sometimes in some
languages they make a distinction
between reduce and fold but actually it
should be the same thing just different
languages use the different terms but
anyway to be specific you know so so C++
they have fold left and look at the
documentation okay so uh can you guys
see it you know this needs to be
magnified Right. Uh opening a new tab.
Okay. So
magnify you know. So in this
documentation they actually
put common syntax into the documentation
like this is not code. This is
documentation for this function. And
then you then you got common syntax like
this one says indirectly binary left
foldable. indirectly binary left
photoable and what uh and and then then
you got uh
wait okay then then you got like
um left fold then then you got like
contextual auto what what so so that's
so funny this is the first time I see
the C++ documentation okay but how do
you actually call it you you you know
the way you call it is that instead of a
list you you say list beginning and list
end because that way because for the C
C++ language you can reduce on part of
the array things like that so anyway so
reduce then I learned I didn't even know
what is C++ template you know so I asked
gu explained template
So C++ in my view is a circus language
you know like in Java al or um I know in
Java I know you know you know I know
basics of Java Java you don't have that
you can do all of these but you don't
have like templates and macros
like so it's like you know [ __ ] pile on
top of another beginning with Unix and E
in my opinion okay in my opinion Unix
and C they created all the damage huge
damage in computing industry in the past
30 years you know C and Unix like Unix
philosophy you know like bunch of
[ __ ] then they they they start with [ __ ]
then they they pile [ __ ] on top of it to
cover it up such as
C++ you know C is very popular oh but
it's got lots of problems Let's create,
you know, C++. We're going to fix, you
know, we're going to be backward
compatible and but we're going to fix
it. Pile piles of [ __ ] on top of
another. That's C and C++ in my
opinion. So I, you know, template. So I
learned about template and STL. Uh
yeah. Uh yeah. So I don't know anything
about it. So now let's go back. Okay,
let's digress enough. Let's go back to
um Yeah. So, lots of um additions to
JavaScript. Uh so you um JavaScript
Emacs. Yeah. So, this is latest edition
2025. It's not out yet. Every year uh in
June they publish the new additions but
but basically all the browsers already
implemented. So this is
JavaScript 2025. And the naming is
another
story, ECMAS script, EC ECMA 262, ECMAS
script. That's a complete [ __ ] You
know, this this these are the problems
of the coding industry. You know, why do
they like why you have the name ECMAS
script? Like well, that's because social
political reasons, you know, like then
what why does JavaScript suck? so much.
Why is it called JavaScript when it has
nothing to do with Java? Well, social
political
reasons. So in computing industry, we
are, you know, we have this all this all
this kind of [ __ ] All this kind of
[ __ ] ECMAScript and ECMA
262. Um, okay. So anyway, so that's
JavaScript features, you know. So check
it out. Okay. So there there are still a
few things I need to do. So you can I
mean okay I also have a um HTML history
timeline
because I watched HTML bone the birth of
HTML in
1993 you know when I just started to
learn you know coding wufan language
actually. So I learned HTML history. So
I watched the birth of HTML and
JavaScript and cookies and HTML 2 then
and
CSS1 then XML and
XHTML then today you got the
HTML 5 from what the [ __ ] group you know
that's another kind of political story.
Okay. So you know then you got Java uh
JavaScript version history. But anyway
check out okay check out JavaScript in
depth. That is
my tutorial which I spend I read you
know several versions of the JavaScript
specification the ECMAS script very
difficult to read and and could be
better but you know that's another story
you know like you read ECMAS script um
should I look at um no let you know
let's focus on you know the iterators
okay so but it it's very complex okay it
could be done much better, but I don't
understand why they don't, you know,
write it in a better
way. Um, yeah, that's another story to
talk about. Okay, JavaScript in depth.
Check it out. And if you like my stuff,
you can download the entire thing in a
zip
file. Okay, let me uh pedal my tutorial
a little bit. Okay. So, you can buy my
tutorial, you know, uh just pay me $30
35. So, you can use it as a reference
because it includes all the JavaScript
references as well. Object, class,
array, function. Then you got new things
like
symbol and set and map. Uh you know,
so that's my JavaScript tutorial. uh end
I have so actually this is not complete
you know so let me tell you
why why I wrote it you know what why I
think it's best I think this JavaScript
in depth is the best JavaScript
programming language tutorial and in
depth in English on earth okay better
than Mozilla you know the MD and you
know you guys you know everyone is
familiar MD and MTM used to sucks used
to suck so badly like mislead misleading
information because it's open source
then but about 10 years ago this uh deep
state they somehow made a made an
agreement so that they stopped all other
JavaScript tutorials such as for example
Microsoft they have their own JavaScript
tutorial but they killed it they all
focus on the Mosilla for for for reasons
I'm not too clear but but anyway they
all like pivoted just like one
JavaScript tutorial the Mozilla MDM
uh so let's show
it you know JavaScript Mozilla actually
let's search for
iterator so now it's known as MDM it
wasn't known as that it was known as
Mozilla something and now it's actually
much better much better than let's say
10 years ago okay but so This is the
kind of the JavaScript reference most of
people are familiar with uh and it's
very good and it's very update up to
date. I cannot compare to them today
actually because they are you know they
are done by like thousands of people. So
whenever you need the latest information
especially integration with DOM the
browser you know like whether this
feature is implemented in particular
browser or you know there's so much
complex comp complications so you have
to check MDN okay however MDM if you
read their
tutorial you know JavaScript tutorial to
this day mine is still better because I
tell
you in a way that's more um precise and
understandable and uh correct. Okay. So
you learn the good concepts from the
beginning. You don't learn the bad
concept. For example, let me tell you.
So properties you know JavaScript object
you got properties. So most people you
know you just write uh you know curly
braces a colon a value and comma and so
on you know property. So property is you
know object can have properties. Object
by definition is a collection of
properties actually plus some internal
behavior which is not talked about in
the JavaScript specification nor
mentioned on the MDM. Okay. So
JavaScript object the way the spec
define it is a collection of objects.
Okay, that's the way JavaScript
spec define it. Actually I have a local
copy. Uh I don't know if I removed it or
not. Uh let's search for uh search for
ECMA. Yeah. Uh wait, do I do I still
have a copy?
Uh yeah, I still have a copy. So, so
2011's spec
specification.
Uh yeah, so I actually took the time to
break them apart into several files by
chapter. So, you know, I reworked on
this. So, this is spec uh ECMA 262 5.1.
So, that's
2011. So, there's a spec. But anyway, so
then then there's 2015 spec, you know.
Um, so let's open it. Let's see. Uh,
hide show subtopics. Let's see. You
know, I actually worked so much on this.
Um, you know, so if you read the spec,
so let me show you the object. Okay, so
object definition, ordinary and exotic
object behaviors. Okay, that's like
technical detail. standard theoding
object, you know, it's like
incomprehensible. Okay,
so search for global. Okay, global
object. Uh let's go to the top. Let's
see. Proxy
uh operation on abstract operations.
Okay.
Next operations on iterator objects.
Okay. Uh, ordinary and exotic object
behaviors. Okay. Let's see. Building
function. Let's see. I want to look at
the section where they define what is
object. Uh, it's not this one. Anyway,
so so I have to think about where um
it's been a while. JavaScript script
basically they define it as a collection
of properties. Okay. A property is a key
and value
pair. Uh and
uh okay, but basically that's it. That's
how they define JavaScript object. But
actually that's not totally correct
because JavaScript objects such as
function date regular expression or map
set they are not just about collection
of pairs you know because for example a
function you have a function body for
array you have well array is kind of
collection of pairs because they don't
have real array uh then you got regular
expression you got a regular expression
you know body there and uh date for
example you got a date. So a collection
of you know JavaScript object is
actually just not just collection of key
value pairs also known as properties but
you got special internal data. Okay.
So okay so let's see if I can find the
official
documentation. Ah god search for OB.
Okay there. ECMAS script overview 4.21
objects.
Uh even though God this you know this is
how complicated it looks like. So even
though egg script includes syntax for
class definitions, eggmas script objects
are not fundamentally class-based such
as C++, small talk or Java. Instead of
instead object may be created in various
okay so that's not it. There is a place
where it defines um object. Okay there
object 4.33 member of the type object.
Note an object is a collection of
properties that has a single prototype
object. Okay, the prototype may be the
new value. Okay, so here basically let's
see if they have uh you know so anyway.
So here is their definition of object.
This definition is from the JavaScript
specific specification. It's actually
incorrect or rather impractical because
a function is
object and true it is a collection of
properties but is rarely used. Okay. And
it has a single prototype object meaning
it has a parent. You know a function you
create is the the parent is
function.prototype.
Okay. Okay. And the prototype may be
new. Okay, that's correct. But however,
you fail to say a function is not just a
collection of properties and you know it
because it has a function
body. You fail to say that. Same same
thing with regular expression or date
object or uh set or you know. So this is
actually you know this is what the spec
says but is actually not correct you
know.
So, so this is how I feel. You know,
what can you do? You know, you talk to
people, they don't they they don't
understand, you know, they how can you
possibly say the spec is
incorrect? But but is it can anyone
correct me? Am I incorrect somewhere
that this you know the object definition
from the spec is
incomplete? Okay. But you talk to
people, they don't understand. Okay.
That's that's kind of the situation of
the programming industry. Lots of things
you you know you dive deep you tell
people and they don't understand they
don't care. They they think you are
wrong and they don't care you know like
but like okay anyway that's about
JavaScript object. So where am I?
Um so let's go let's get back to so what
are we talking about eggmas script scope
close uh close so uh de block close so
we were going to talk about yeah okay so
my dev blog my javascript blog uh and
eggmas script new
features okay and eggmas script 2025
features so you got app array. So, okay.
So, actually now let's talk about how
these iterators works, shall we? It's
already 30
minutes. Do we have comments? Do we have
people watching? How many? Like 311.
Okay, great. Say hi. Okay, comment.
Okay. Scott says, "It'll be interesting
to compare JavaScript's iterators again
against C++ templates iterator
paradigm."
Uh I know C++ even if rarely used I know
uh nothing of JavaScript variant.
Okay. Oh okay. Iter. Okay. I cannot do I
I mean I know I can explain JavaScript
but I don't know nothing about C++
first. So I can I can't compare but I
can tell you about JavaScript
uh iterators. Okay. I think they are
slightly different actually because in
JavaScript. Okay. So let's talk about
iterators.
Okay. Okay. So let's talk about
iterators. So let me go through my
JavaScript in depth and find the proper
uh location for iterator iterators
because I have an article. Uh so there
it is iterable object. Okay. So the most
important about so the the the top few
concept about iterators in JavaScript is
you got iter iterable object okay that's
the most important that's the most
practical iterators it's more about
implementation details okay but the most
important thing is iterable object so
whenever you see a iterable object that
means you can use for loop for for of
loop or you can use spread operator or
you can use array from on them. So what
is iterable object? Iterable object is
like array. Okay, it's like a you know
just array except
that it's not a concrete array. Okay,
whenever a object is iterable, it's just
like array but every element is computed
at a time when you use it. Okay. So
that's the basic that's the basic
concept of iterable. Okay. In JavaScript
you also have that in
Python. I don't remember if in Python
they call iterable or um uh let let's
find out easily because let me digress a
little bit quickly find out. Okay. So in
Python you got uh okay so jump uh so
let's go to Python
uh you know I I think all these iterable
should be banned okay so but let's talk
about that later so in Python you also
got um function uh so function string
data types arithmetics boolean
conditional loop iteration so let's
write let's go to iterate the list um
innumerable uh enumerate Okay, very
confusing. You got you know iterable,
innumera, innumerable, all these jarens
each each language their definition
slightly different uh in each language.
Okay. So let's see
uh so I what I want to know is in Python
what is the name what is the equivalent
to JavaScript iterable. So if you guys
know say it. Okay, I know it. I have it
here
somewhere.
Uh okay. In JavaScript they are called
iterator. Okay. Officially okay. So
iterator in in in Python. Okay. In
iterator in Python is analogous to
JavaScript iterable. Okay. You know so
we getting into details. So in
JavaScript iterable is the most
important concept. basically it's mean
it basically just means infinite you
know it's like array but not
concrete okay so that's iterable in
JavaScript this is the thing you use you
know the the most important now so in
JavaScript they added a for loop which
is different from for loop okay so the
for loop is entirely different from for
loop because of the baggage you know to
the JavaScript
um fall in loop. Okay. So anyway, so
when you have a
iterable you can use for of loop to go
through it or you can use spread
operator which you know which make
it which which turns it into a array
basically. Okay. Or you can use array
from okay so I you know array from is
somewhere else array from turns the
iterable into a concrete array. Okay.
But if your in if if the iterable has
infinite items, that's one of the
feature of
iterable. Then then if you try to use
uh you know a spread operator of array
form then you got your crash you get
into infinite
recursion infinite loop. So you know
that's one of the bad things. So I don't
think you know I I I I think iterable or
iterator should be banned. Okay. So
anyway in JavaScript you got iterable.
Okay then you got a iterator. So why do
you have a iterator? So iterator
basically iterator is very complicated.
Okay iterator is there because in order
to implement the iterable
concept that's how the iterator thing is
created. Okay.
Now I will go to into tech technical
definitions in a
bit but if I do that it's very
complicated. Okay. So if you are very
advanced JavaScript programmers then you
want to know but but let's skip it for
now. Okay. So just know that iterator is
the underlying mechanism to make to make
the iterable concept work in JavaScript.
Okay. That's iterator. Then you got the
generator. Okay, so what is a generator?
Generator, the definition of generator
in JavaScript is that an object that's
both iterable and also iterator. Okay,
very complicated. You don't have to know
the details, but anyway, that's what it
is. So when your object is both iterable
object and is also an iterator, that
object is called generator.
Okay, this is why JavaScript sucks like
tremendous
tremendously. Then you got iterator gen
then you got generator function. So what
is generator function? Generator
function is a function basically it lets
you write generators. Okay. So because
if you want to write a
iterable manually it's very difficult.
You have
to anyway you you you have to create a
iterator and you in order to create an
iterator is like huge very
complicated and usually it something you
want something to be both iterable and
iterator. Why? Because it's just
JavaScript [ __ ] Okay, it's just
JavaScript [ __ ] for no other reason.
So, so usually you want a object to be
both iterable and iterator and that
thing is called generator. Okay, but
again you cannot just write it. You can
you you know you could you could write
it manually but very complicated. So you
have this new generator function you
know you just add a asterisk it allows
you to create
uh generator objects you know uh which
means it's iterable. Okay and also
iterator. Okay so that's that's the
basics. Okay. So that's that's the
basics. So iterable is the most
important you use every day. But then
the iterators and generators and uh you
know
iterator is a mechanism to create
iterable. Then you have generator means
it's both iterable and iterator. Then
you have generator function which lets
you create generators. Okay, that's how
it works. Now but how exactly it works?
Then you have to go to so-called
interface.
Okay. So in short, in order to create a
iterable, what does itable mean? Well,
if a object is a iterable, that just
means it has this property
symbol. Okay. Now, what is
symboliterator? That's another
complicated thing. Basically, that's uh
basically that's a random ID created on
the fly, but you can never see it. Okay,
but anyway. So for object to be iterable
all it takes it is is to conform
so-called conform to the iterable
interface. So what does it mean? It just
means you have the object must have a
property named
symbol. Okay you you can't see the value
of that property but but anyway that's
the value of this property s symbol.
Okay so you need to have that property.
then there's some special requirement
for that property. Okay, the value of
that
property must be a function. Okay, and
that function's return value must
conform to the iterator interface. Okay,
which means it's a object that has a
property of a string property next.
Okay, so so anyway, so so that's how it
works. That's that's the definition. If
you want to implement iterable or
iterator that's that's what it means. So
you got this interface okay so-called
interface in JavaScript that's another
very complic complicated thing. Now if
you go to Mosilla like we talked about
you know the Mosilla you know you know
the Mozilla you are familiar with they
they don't say interface they actually
call it protocol. So they say you know
for something to be a um iterable it
must conform to the iterable protocol.
Okay for something to be uh iterator it
must conform to the iterator protocol.
They don't use the word interface but I
looked up you know according to the
ECMAS script specification it's not
called interface it's called it's not
called protocol it's called interface.
Okay, that's another very complex
JavaScript [ __ ] involving the technical
matters also involving social issues,
you know. So, here is the JavaScript
ECMAS script specification for
um for 2025. Okay, so wait, this is
2024. But anyway, two uh 2024 because
2025 is not out yet. You see, so it says
the section it says iteration common
iteration
interfaces. Okay, the iterable interface
you see. So the iterable interface
includes the property described in table
77. Okay, so you know you got this. So
you got the you got the iterable
interface
uh which must have the symbol iterator
which they use this notation add add at
okay then you got iterator interface
then it must have the next string
property next and the value of that
property must be a function and that
function must conform to the iterator
result interface. Okay. But anyway, here
the point is that they call it
interface. But if you look at the
Mozilla
documentation, iterable, okay,
JavaScript iterable
uh just search for that. Okay, Mozilla.
You see they call it protocols, the
iteration protocol. Okay. So, so let me
tell you the details about this te
terminology and jarens which is a
complete science in programming. Okay.
So, you got two you know you you the
same concept the Mozilla documentation
call them protocols but the
specification call them interface. So
what's the situation? What's the deal?
Okay. So if you think about it, you see
the protocol is actually a better
terminology in the context of
JavaScript because in the spec in the in
the JavaScript spec they say interface
but interface is
actually because interface in common
understanding in particular particularly
in
Java Java and Goland they have a special
meaning usually they mean the functions
like the functions um so-cal signature
okay what kind of parameters are
required for the function that's called
interface often known as you know API
application programming interface so
when you use a function all you need to
know is what kind of parameters it
needs and what kind of things it return
okay that's called API interface That's
a common understanding of the term
interface in programming languages
especially in Java and Golan I know of
okay like they are defined technically
also in Typescript TypeScript Golan Java
that's a you know interface but in
JavaScript interface you know the
JavaScript spec their use of interface
is not that okay their interface means
the object must have a property certain
certain properties properties and the
properties value must be something.
Okay, that's a you know, so it does not
mean uh functions parameters and their
types. Okay, so that's but however
that's what you know that's what the
JavaScript spec uses the word
interface. So that is why in Mozilla
documentation they don't call it
interface they just say protocol. Why?
Because protocol is actually more
practical better term for JavaScript
because if you say interface they get
people get confused you know that's not
interface in Java in Golan in other
languages you know so they say protocol
protocol is kind of make making more
sense people might think of you know
HTTP protocol email protocol but anyway
protocol just means a kind of
specification makes better sense Okay.
So, Mosilla choose to use the word
protocol. So, there's, you know, there's
advantages and disadvantages. For one
thing, it's just incorrect. Okay.
Mozilla documentation, but you you
[ __ ] [ __ ] incorrect. That's what the
that's not what the spec says, you know.
So, they choose the word protocol
technically incorrect. Okay.
But however there's good reasons because
protocol is actually better understood
you know because then then you can say
the JavaScript the idiocy you know the
complete idiocy the JavaScript committee
the the
T3639 standard you know like right now
they have a comm committee T39 that's
called okay
uh like 36 or 39 let's say you know
there it is
TC39 ECMA uh
TC39 that's a committee that that tell
us what to do about JavaScript today.
Okay. So TC39 ECMA
262. So but this committee so the
question is why did this JavaScript
committee
idiots why did they use the interface
word when protocol is actually more
appropriate you know then that's another
thing to dig into
like so why is that I think um I think
actually
protocol I think that in a spec they
might already use the word protocol
let's let's search Okay. So that's when
my
um my uh you know my my local copy of
the JavaScript spec uh comes to use. So
search for protocol
uh is it C or
CA C. Okay. So let's search for it.
Let's see we'll find okay. So okay I
don't you know I cannot search here
because by default I made it to not to
ignore this
directory. Uh so let's go to uh my go
script. Okay search for protocol
and limit it to this directory. Copy the
directory. Okay.
Uh okay. Search for the word protocol
and uh limit it to this
directory. Copy and
uh okay so this is in Goland and if you
are curious about this Goland script you
can get it and for your own use find
stream uh in your
directory. Okay now run
it. Uh done. Uh so well okay so in
JavaScript specification
2025 they did not use the word
protocol. Okay double check. Did I use
the spe did I
uh Okay. So they did not use the word
protocol. Uh let's try something. Um
let's try something else to make sure my
script
works. Uh wait. Oh [ __ ] I have ignored
I have it ignored. So let's try
again. Oh, there it is.
So make it fine mod. So there it is.
So So indeed they use the word
protocol. Okay. Uni code format control
characters highle protocols. Okay. That
that is irrelevant. Let's go here. Open
function definition search for
protocol. Okay, so they do use the word
protocol. So note the next step throws a
type error to indicate that there was a
yield star protocol violation. Okay, so
in JavaScript spec they do use the
protocol. So maybe that's that is why
uh you know for the iterators they use
the word interface instead.
Okay, that's some technical detail.
Hello, F Hank. Ching Ching. Thank you,
Hank. Are you going to try a Fedora
atomic desktop? Not
likely. I, you know, first of all, I
need to switch to Linux, which is
anytime, any day soon. But I'm likely
uh I'm more likely to switch to the Mac
because Windows is like suck suck, you
know, sucks donkey
ass. Um
but I'm likely more likely to switch to
the Mac which involves you know changing
you know you know switching my disc uh
moving my files like me tedious but yeah
so what is atomic desktop find a fedora
atomic desktop to enhance your
experience you can find um the latest
version atomic desktop for fedora so
what does atomic signify does it mean
anything special or is just like a
jargon. Okay, you can you can tell me
about it. Yeah, I don't know.
So Scott says shouldn't be surprised you
that this is more of typical C++
reference guide readability.
Oh more of that typical okay so this is
okay so sky is saying that
um that is kind of more niche
documentation on the C++
templates. Okay.
So, so do we have um I think we kind of
covered we kind we kind of covered what
you know the iterator thing. So last 10
minutes is about this um this jargon
terminology issue protocol versus
interface. Why am I concerned?
Because first of all I'm writing my own
tutorial you
see and I claim my tutorial is better
than Mozilla so and more correct so so
that's the reason I have to be concerned
about which jargon am I to going to use
am I going to stick with the um the
spec you know coding interface or do I
like just use Mosilla
you know so for that question actually
Mosilla is better okay I should use
protocol instead of interface because
interface is just confusing that's not
what you know that's what not typically
programming understanding means it's not
an interface okay but for now I'm
choosing to stick with um the spec why
because just to
differentiate my tutorial
from the Mozilla or the common you know
the common zoomers you know the elite
hackers they are running you know they
are telling you what to do about
JavaScript I remain a little
idiosyncrasy of my tutorial okay
uh so okay we we talked about the jargon
we also talk about we we talked about
the definition of the uh we we we you
know the the meaning of
iterable and uh iterator and generator
in JavaScript. Okay, which is here.
Let's go to the page. Um
uh yeah. So actually I need to add that
here. So where is it? Python uh there.
Let's let's go there. Okay. So actually
it's already here somewhere. Iterator
interface. Okay. itterable object. So
let's add it to today's talk
show. Uh close that. Go to today's talk
show. Not that talk in today's talk
show. Show in browser. Uh yeah. So we
showed
um we explained how complicated it is.
We did that. We work on the new page.
Okay. Not yet. So you got the iterable
object. Go to the bottom. Then you got
the iterator
object. Okay. Add the link there. Then
you
got then you got the generator function.
Copy the file path. Close it. Close it.
Wait. Reopen it. Iterable. Close it. Go
back to my talk show.
then okay so we got another one
generator functions so let's open
generator function and interface okay so
copy that
uh go back to talk show generators then
you need copy the link paste it there
linkify make a list and combine the list
list okay so you got iterable able
object iterator generator generator of
function and interface we talked about
that
uh maybe that's it for today so it's one
hour fantastic anything else you
guys might have
um but today we didn't actually do any
code uh should we do any a little bit
code related to
iterable so let's
Good sir, Diego. Hey, you might like the
minimalism. Avoid Linux. Okay. Uh, it
uses OS3 to make it
immutable. OS3 to make it immutable.
Okay. Yeah, I'm not too familiar with
that, you know, but
um okay, I think that's it for today. Um
there could be one more thing that is
I'm going to show you these uh new
features. So in 2025 they added
map function they added for each
function they added I mean methods they
added filter methods they added every
sum find and more
okay so they added um they added let's
go to JavaScript
uh let's go to this page again so new
JavaScript
news and 2025 Okay, copy that. They
added all these functions. So, let's add
it to my um talk show
today. Okay, so they added these
functions and there are so I documented
them. Uh but there are a few more I
still need to document. So, you know, so
I'm thinking I can just work on one of
them. Should I? Should I? Should
I? You guys say something. Okay, maybe
that's it for today. Then
um you know I can show you know running
the code. So they so they added these
functions. These are functions from
array you know very useful you want to
map or for each or filter or every some
fine but they if you have a iterable you
cannot use those functions because you
know they are you know those are array
methods so it's very annoying so before
2025 you have to convert it to array
first or use for loop or use uh the
spread operator or convert to array use
array form. So I talked about array form
but I haven't shown uh the page. So let
me show you array form. Okay. So that's
the page. So copy that. Let me add it
here. So
um so array.comform allows you to
convert iterable to array first then you
can use map for each functions. But now
they added so that they added these
functions directly to the iterator
protocol prototype so that when you have
a iterable you can directly say map okay
let's run the code okay so let's do for
each okay so let let's not look at that
let's do it manually
um let's try okay so uh JavaScript so we
start the JavaScript first job is to
create a iterable now how do you create
the iterable. Well, array is already a
iterable. So, this this is this thing is
a iterable already. So, let's um
constant x iterable. Okay. So, remember
iterable is the thing you are um
concerned the most. Okay. Then print it
um that run it. You see you got that
this is array. Okay. Array is already
iterable uh iterable object. Okay.
That's a distinction. Very annoying.
very complex but anyway so when you have
a iterable you can directly now you can
directly uh map okay so let's uh let's
say dot for each
uh
what okay then an arrow function let's
say console log and you just want to
print it okay so yeah so let's comment
out let's run that there you have it one
two three
Oh, so you see, so this iterable, so how
do you know it's a iterable? Uh, so let
me let me let me explain.
Okay, array by default is a iterable
object.
Okay, now you can print it. Okay, let's
run it. Okay, so let's uh put the output
here there. Okay. Now, now directly use
the iterator method for each. Okay. And
uh run it. And uh let's
um let's copy the output here so it
makes
sense. So it's clear. Okay. Now, how do
we know it's a iterable? Okay.
How do we uh
God know
uh object
is an
iterable object. All you have to do is
you check on the symbol dot
um you can check O dang. Yeah, Dion.
Dion is saying something. Dion, go
[ __ ] come here. Watch my live
stream. Dion Dion is gonna like argue
with me about something. Yeah, that's
Yeah. So, what is this? So, I I was
going to say iterator should be banned.
Iterable iterator should be banned. And
Dion is no, you're
wrong. Okay. We I actually I haven't
explained why each robbo should be
banned but let's finish this first.
Okay. So you can check the So how do you
know? So how do you how do you find out
is if a object in JavaScript is
iterable? Okay. So what you do is
reflect has don't ask. Okay. Very
complicated. Reflect has. You want to
check if it has the property. Okay. So
you want to check it this
object whether it has the property
called
symbol iterator. Okay, there. Okay, so
you need to print it. So what you do is
console log and uh print it. Okay, now
purify the
code, evaluate it. You can see you got a
true. So this is how you find
out in a histic way how something is a
iterable. Okay, a iterable object
meaning that it conforms to the iterable
interface meaning that it must have a
property symbol iterator and the value
of that property must be a function. So
you can you know how do you know uh you
can say
iterable then you cannot use the dot you
have to use this syntax because
uh wait actually can you use the dot? No
another complication. Okay, that's why
JavaScript sucks. Like normally you just
dot something property but in this case
you cannot because symbol iterator is
one thing itself. It's iterator is a
property of the symbol object which
which is has a value then you are
checking you know then you want to check
if iterable has that property. So, so
this returns a function you can actually
call it you know adding a par then you
just print it. Okay. So for example I'm
showing you you know run it. So you got
this uh you see the return value is a
array iterator. Okay. So anyway then how
do you know if something is a iterator?
All you have to do is
to again you
check how to find out
uh you know I got uh this uh a brief how
to find how how
to find
out if uh I need to turn off a brief uh
but let's let's do it here.
How to find out if object is
iterator? Okay, so that is the key
thing. All you have to do is check for
the property next. Okay, this will
return false. That's
right. You can see force because
iterable is not a iterator. So instead,
but if
you if you um you see if
you have the iterable then you get the
property
symbol. The value of that property then
you call it that returns a thing it
which is an iterator. So this now will
return true. Okayify the code run it. So
you can see it's
true. Okay. So you know if you are you
know if you don't know check out my
JavaScript tutorial I have everything in
detail.
Um let's go to talk show. Uh you go to
iterator for example. Then you have test
if object is iterable or iterator or you
know or you can read about interface.
then you learn how to
check. Okay. Now go back to the code. So
what we are doing? So we are doing
um you know array is iterable and we are
coding for each method directly. Why
does it work? Because the because
this because it's actually very
complicated because this because
array object array is not just iterable
it's iterable it's also a iterator. So
array is actually a generator.
Okay. So because for example let me show
you um console log reflect has. Okay. We
want to check this array element then
you check for the symbol property
uh that will return true but also if you
check the next property it also return
true. So array is actually a iterable
and also a iterator which we can say
array is actually a generator. Okay. So
verify the code run
it. Uh actually false. Okay, I was
wrong. So it's not a it's a iterable but
it's not a iterator. Um, so why am I
uh
so iterate. So actually I don't know
what's going
on. Anyway, I think that's it for
today. So thank you guys for watching.
Bye
guys. So right now uh so we are what we
are doing we are demonstrating this for
each method for iterator. Okay. So and
we are using the for each method on the
array. Now
technically the for each
method requires a iterator to be the
parent. That is the for each method is a
method of
a oh [ __ ] I got it wrong. You know why
this
works? Even though array is not a
iterator because when we use for each
it's actually coding arrays methods.
Okay. So it's very annoying. So very you
know so very annoying. So let's not use
arrays. So we need to create our own uh
iterator object. Okay. So let's create
uh our own iterator
object. Okay, scratch that. Uh okay. So
but
um so what we going to do? So well let's
start from fresh. Okay. Create our own
iterable object so that it's not array
because array got a for each
method. Okay. So this in this case you
need to use a generator function. So uh
that means name that
um genf okay generator function then you
here the body says um
uh let's say let let it return one two
three. Okay. So one, two, three. That's
a array and you want to use four of.
Okay. So for a iterable there. So array
is a iterable. Okay. And for each key uh
let's say for each x what you want to do
is you want to yield x. Okay. Pify the
code.
That's that defines the generator
function. Okay. Then then what you say
is you say
um
my
iterable equals to the generator
function. Okay.
Constant you call the generator
function. So the generator
function
returns it returns actually a generator
which means it's uh iterable and also a
iterator. Okay. So this will let's call
it my
um okay this let's say X generator. So
this this x generator is a iterable and
is a also a iterator. So how do we know?
Let's use the test
here. Uh let's see. Hold on a second. So
copy cut remove
that. Okay. So how do we know is itable?
Okay. So so this this will be xgen.
Okay. And uh how do we know if object is
iterator? Let's see. Check is
iterator. Check is
iterable. Okay. And the check is
iterator. This will be xgen. Okay.
So let's remove that. Okay. So now the
code is just here. Run it. True, true,
true. Correct. So we we we define the
generator function. Then we call the
generator function which give us a
generator. Predify the code. Then we can
check the result. Generator is actually
a iterable and is also a iterator. Okay.
Now we can use the for each. Okay. So X
generator dot for each. Okay. Then
console log X. Okay. So now we run it.
Now we get one, two, three. Okay. That's
uh fantastic. Beautiful. Correct. And
that
concludes today's
talk. Let's double check. Define a
generator function. Call the generator.
Get a generator
object. Check the generator object is a
iterable. True. Check the generator
object is also iterator. Actually this
is wrong. Just just that. Okay. Run it.
True. Okay. Then check then call the for
each. Why is the for each available?
Because because if you say the generator
uh check the parent. Okay. So you want
to check whether the parent of generator
is is is the
iterator.prototype.
Okay. Uh okay. Uh iterator proto. Okay.
So you want to check the parent. Okay.
So reflect get prototype
of we want to get the prototype of that
generator and make check if it's equals
to iterator
prototype and print
it. Okay, let's make it com uh you know
motor line. Okay, this will return
true. Uh it returns false.
Uh it returns false because you have to
actually um you have to call the next
dot
wait
got yeah yeah you need to get the symbol
iterator symbol
So that will return true. Okay. Run it.
False. Okay. I'm now I'm now actually
now this is testing my understanding of
advanced JavaScript. So why is it
um Oh, you have to call it. This is very
confused. Yeah, call it false again. Ah,
[ __ ] Let's stop trial and error. Let's
just say exactly what is
it. Get prototype of
generator.
[Music]
Uh so that's a generator object
generator. So
generator
god. What is
that? Uh symbol iterator code.
Why don't you just
say object time? So you get the parent.
Anyway, that
um okay, I hope that's useful. Bye
guys. So that's what we talked about.
There is another item which is why
um why should we
ban the iterators concept or iter
iterator or iterable because
they you know I I think because they
makes the programming language very
complicated that's one reason because in
the JavaScript case it's very
complicated we know partly because the
you know JavaScript is a very bad
language. Okay, but what about in um
let's say in Python you know they call
it iterator. Well, I think it should be
banned because when you have iterator
things they they are still very
complicated because because then you
have a function that each time return
different things.
So, so it so another big reason is that
it violates functional programming
principle because your function is no
longer function. It has a state every
time it returns a different thing. Uh so
violates a functional programming
principle and then very complicated
because then because you you you you
have this kind of lazy
evaluation you it's hard to predict what
value it returns you know because it
keeps maintains a state okay so so I
think the iterator or iterable concept
should should should
um programming language should not have
it. You know, the reason they create
them, they say it's because save memory,
but rarely is the case when you need,
you know, 10,000 array
items. And if you actually do need some
kind of infinite list, I believe it's
much better just to use a loop, you
know, you just use a
loop. Okay, so that is my reason. So I
do not see why you need
um so so if you guys know you know if
you have a valid reason why you should
have iterators or iterable concept in
programming language let me know you
know give me solid uh examples
why you know um it's useful so I don't
know
myself is web assembly a better language
in JavaScript uh no not really because
web assembly is a very low language.
It's like assembly I was looking
into few days ago uh to keep myself
updated you know. So web assembly is
just like it's almost like assembly
language. So it's very very lowle
language but however it's used in
browsers. So you know you know web
assembly. So let's look at some code uh
you know it's just like very minimal uh
minimal um you know you know it's like
assembly language you don't have you
don't have loop you don't
have you don't have fancy you know you
don't have any convenient uh construct
you cannot write create a list kind of
like that do they have actually have
code I want to see some code yeah so
This this is what web web assembly looks
like. Okay.
Um you know so on the left is
coursely language code and uh in the
middle and on the right is the actual
you know the binary code it produces. So
web assembly is very low level.
So it's analogous to assembly language
in a programming language and the goal
why do they have a web assembly? So it's
like so that any programming language
can can compile to this web assembly. So
this web
assembly then compile to this this you
know like binary format. So so it can be
very fast almost just like C speed. Why?
Why you know how is it possible web
assembly become very fast? Because you
removed all the features of programming
language you know you don't allow list
you don't allow iterators you don't
allow array you you don't allow you know
very you know string format you don't
allow lots of
things. So when you don't allow them,
you become very minimal programming
language that close to the machine. So
so so the the goal of web assembly is
that it allows all other programming
languages
to compile
into web assembly so that it can run in
browser and why do people needs to do
that? So that people can you know run 3D
games in a browser. So that's the kind
of the purpose of web
assembly. So is it better language? They
are kind of in different levels. So you
can't really compare them. But I was
reading about
yesterday, you know, so far the vast
majority of actual web assembly code in
the world right now is all crypto scams.
like when you visit a site, they run web
assembly to to do crypto to use your
computing power to to mine bitcoins and
things like
that. So anyway, that's it. Bye
guys. Uh if you like my stuff, donate,
okay? Thank you, Hank. And also you guys
can go to my website, you know, uh you
can donate. Donate sudi.info, okay? go
to the bottom. Donate me big
time, you know. Uh, you know, you can
donate me Amazon gift card or PayPal or
Patreon me or buy my entire website for
300. Just 30 300. Okay, there are about
6,000 articles and you can get my
JavaScript in-depth in a zip file. Okay,
go to my JavaScript in-depth page and uh
go to uh here. Okay, go to Amazon gift
card Amazon gift card. Click the link or
PayPal. You have to use their link
because if you use the wrong link,
Amazon Germany or Amazon Japan, I won't
get it. I won't be able to get money.
So, use the link and use my email
address. Make sure my email address is
correct.
Okay. Okay.
Bye. Okay. Shut down. Let's see. Talk
show. Uh