good morning guys welcome to another
episode of our talk show hi guys so we
need the topic today so today's topic is
going to be JavaScript security or eMac
this regularly expression okay we can do
a Mac Lisp regular expression but eMac
this regular expression yeah we can do
that but JavaScript security what to
talk about that you see the word
security is very much abused because you
know what does it mean security you know
you know security problems in my biased
opinion or internets from the UNIX from
the UNIX philosophy from the Linux from
these hackers there there you came up
you know they it's from there you got
these hackers you know the rangin of the
hacker concepts and from there you know
from hackers to crackers you know they
they they love code up first occasion go
for those kind of thing you know and the
UNIX security yeah okay let's talk about
that security for example the UNIX
pestilence let's go through forming
block okay start up and hack the planet
and anti hack year to K okay let's go
there let's there is a the nature of
UNIX philosophy that that's not that why
software suck are you intelligent enough
to understand html5
the condition of industrial programmers
learn Lisp in ten days yeah why change
when it ain't broken you know this is
well and the bug reporting attitude
that's from you that's from open-source
ideology the fanaticism bug report
you know whenever you have something why
does it say live in 24 minutes I don't I
don't know 42 minutes I don't know so
anyway so you know I'm starting to get
into this topic but the JavaScript
security there is something I want to
show you jargons of software industry
what is scientific oh these are written
around 2000 to 2010 so there is a
article about UNIX pestilence let's see
I can find it where we can see how
secure is Unix you know when you talk
about UNIX or Linux Leena's came after
before it's Unix
that what's in hackers mind is that UNIX
is the most secure operating system you
know and they laugh at Microsoft you
know they'd be of course yeah Microsoft
virus every day more way every day
deserve that but actually the truth is
UNIX is the most insecure operating
system on earth let me show you okay
UNIX sovereignty so UNIX UNIX pestilence
you know I have so many articles that
over the 20 years they get you know they
get it's hard to find them
okay let's search for
pestilence
unikz pestilence okay
the free software that is okay so they
all go back to okay let's just go to my
directory oops
copy go to go to this page go to tired
go to pestilence okay
go through index go through you soft
three books this this page okay
the eunuchs pestilence this is written
in 2003 by the way this is that there is
this famous quote this this quote was
very popular throughout 1990s at least
so he says I liken starting ones
computing career with UNIX say as a
undergraduate to being born in East
Africa it is intolerably hot your body
is covered with lice and flies you are
more nourished and you suffer from
numerous curable diseases but as far as
you as far as young East African can
tell this is simply the natural
condition and they live within it by the
time they find out differently it's too
late they already think that the writing
of shell scripts is a natural act this
is a very popular quote in 1990s you
know when you know if you when you look
at UNIX history there is you know the
UNIX you know by the way it's on T
phases of Lisp you know back in those
days in 1970s or 80s that's beyond my
time I only began to study computers in
1990 and to use a computer in 1990 but
only in 1998 I began to do UNIX and get
into Emacs that but so 1970s and 1980s
you know there is a contention between
your flame war like religious war you
know like Emacs versus win so there's a
frame war between UNIX and ideas and you
know
least basically the Lisp programmers the
Lisp camp you know that that's very
contentious just like Perl vs. Python
Mac versus PC Common Lisp versus scheme
this you know each group flame each
other you know all day every day so you
know it's a it's a UNIX versus mo Tex
you know that the origin of the name is
a pun on mo Tex Mao mu l t IX okay let
me show you let me type it out so close
that close that close that let's go to
talk page close that so go to exalt
today's talk show page let's just paste
that and so there is mu l TI c x TI CX
okay mo tex is a operating system okay
so there's a wikipedia i don't know
nothing about this operating system
because it's you know before my time
it's really hard to understand and so
there's more textures i TS there's
several others basically they are
usually centered around artificial
intelligence research well probably not
exactly but we you know I don't know
this I'm not there so I don't know this
well so but when you when you try to
understand history before your time you
get concepts means mixed but anyway it
is true that basically there is the Lisp
camp and there is you know the motifs
camp
then there's UNIX they are they are
enemies okay
UNIX versus Lisp or UNIX versus Mott X
so these people more takes designers and
and they you know they don't like UNIX
and unix-like send see you know I like
to say UNIX and see they are they
put strapped it bootstrap it put
bootstrap strapping each other you know
see boots UNIX UNIX boots see we are the
fastest you know we are the that that's
the thing that's the
selling point they are fast fastest they
are the most brainless no design no
architecture no it extensibility no no
thought no thinking you know basically
the philosophy of Unix ok or see the
design of see everything you know
whenever you you design a language
you'll click create a software you know
Archie Tech whatever design whenever you
have a decision to make for the UNIX or
C philosophy it's easy very simple pick
whatever is the most easy to implement
and the fastest that is the UNIX
philosophy ok whenever you have a design
decision you know just pick whatever
it's a most easy to implement most
simple to with respect to implementation
you know easy to do like you don't know
anything you don't know nothing you just
so this is I can do it this way then
just do it that way and fast that is the
essence of the UNIX philosophy the UNIX
operating system the UNIX design see the
design of the C programming language ok
it's worse that's why I hate is so much
now again my my opinion is kind of
biased it's kind of so I'm saying things
this way that's kind of a traumatic but
you know you know but but you can say
this that's that's kind of this this
problem this unbiased way to say it but
you get the idea you know I'm just going
to say whatever you know just just like
the UNIX philosophy there's no
scientific basis cannot be verified
whatsoever you know they say UNIX
philosophy small is better you know the
KISS principle keep it simple and the
Eric Raymond guy you know that he's a
crackpot
that's UNIX philosophy you know there's
no basis whatsoever like like you know
in science in science you know when you
do science there's a common thought you
know there's a common principle very of
verifiability
in philosophy there's a school of
philosophy called analytic philosophy
meaning that you analyze well there's a
lot to it but basically meaning you
approach philosophy in a scientific way
so you analyze you know what it says for
example does God exist first of all you
you you try to state what exactly it
means scientifically so what does God
exist what does it means how can we
prove it or disapprove it by it first
first of all understanding you know how
can we so if this is a statement you
know whether it's true or false but but
you have to have a way you know what so
I can so this if this happens then we
know it's false you know you have to
have a solid verifiable way to falsify
it otherwise it's not science because
otherwise God or you know you can say
it's the exists or doesn't exist then
your reasoning changes you know because
this what does it actually mean
does does that mean you know you can see
someone who is God or does it mean
there's just you know like like you you
analyze you know the language that any
way that this school kind of a
scientific approach to philosophy is
called analytic philosophy it's one of
the founder is Bertrand Russell this
logician and the pacifists who is my
favorite author kind of my let's say top
top probably top one top top to the
Western author my favorite so in the
same way when people save UNIX
philosophy you know there are a bunch of
you know you know sayings about UNIX
philosophy decide it's not you know it's
just code slogans there's no way to
verify it because I know well I have I
know so much about this because anyway
so I was saying motives so let's go back
to securities ok UNIX security I do you
most people are thinking UNIX is the
most secure system but let me show you
this joke ok there's you can see you
know you study Unix
UNIX is actually the far the the least
secure of all almost of all operating
systems even compared to Microsoft and
key because Microsoft NT packing let's
say 1995 it's new you know it's got one
years old you know starting around 1995
also you know but UNIX has been around
you know in 1995 UNIX has been around
for 20 years so if you compare obviously
you know it's you have already 20 years
and you are so still so bad so very bad
and meanwhile the Microsoft NT is new on
the other hand let lets let's put
another perspective ok so one thing most
UNIX people will say ok look at
Microsoft operating system you have
viruses every day you know he threw out
today it's less you know today is more
secure you know but let's say since 1993
the first Windows version up to 2010 on
Windows you have variables every day you
know you go to you have variables from
Oz or vectors the so called vectors
you know you get various or more where
you know ransomware and oh these day and
it's very easy to get them even if you
are very careful because I used Windows
as my main system from from from 1990
from 2009 fought for two years two to
three years from around 2010 to 2012
something like that I gotta show you my
articles but ok so I got to show you my
article so many articles I to show Unix
let me just type it out UNIX break first
so I so that we don't forget and switch
to Windows from Mac okay that's such it
sorry switch Windows to Mac why I am
switching from Mac to Windows so this is
my article that details how why I
switched okay and so I I switch to
Windows for Mac in 2009 before that it's
nineteen years of Mac as my home system
you know I've been I've been doing UNIX
assisted means for Solaris since - since
1998 so I switched windows for from 2009
to 2010 I switched back they are
switched to Linux from 2009 to 2012 I
think then I switched to Linux for for
like three or four years then then my
experience of Linux is crap it's you
know because all these years you know
I've been wrong I haven't used Linux but
of course I you know you hear you know
for 10 years for 20 years Linux being
around you know they so so around 2010
no around 2000 year 2000 I was you know
system in for Solaris all these eunuchs
its gix I ryx you know Eric's from SGI's
Unix
let's say let's show this start to talk
about this SGI okay sorry
SGI let me show you some of the logos
SGI logo visualization SGI has the most
wonderful logo the the most where design
logo this is SGI SGI is Silicon Graphics
is one of the most back in 1990s is one
of the most respected and loved by
hackers they they are part of the UNIX
they create IREX which is one of
UNIX operating system I works you know
there are many UNIX is you this AIX from
IBM AIX hp-ux from hewlett-packard
Erik's from Silicon Graphics Silicon
Graphics is where most well known for
creating computer graphics you know
visual Hollywood visual effects you know
like they created Jurassic Park movie
the first one which is like it's a
revolutionary you know it's they are
most known for that for computer
graphics advancements but then they they
bankrupt because PCB came out PC becomes
more and more popular back then you have
you know all these UNIX is they run on
so-called workstations you call them
workstations ok you have a box like
sometimes pizza box they Co you can you
can find on the web there's are pictures
you search for SGI you know they have
hardware though those costs a lot money
you know ten thousand twenty thousand
dollars but then pc in 1990s then 2000
pc became cheaper and cheaper the intel
cpu replacing the you know silicon
graphics and all these unix is they they
use you know they use some Microsystems
chips and other other chips anyway so pc
took over and basically that bankrupt
SGI because all these cat software they
run on pc much cheaper you know like
three three hundred dollars you know
then but if you want to run on SGI it's
like ten thousand dollars things like
that so they bankrupt
you know SGI is also known for open open
that that the worst technology
what's the technology for computer
graphics you know that they released
opens they become open-source after they
went bankrupt you know that as I
mentioned before you know when when you
are bankrupt when your software has no
value you become open source that open
someone put someone say it in you guys
know I'm pretty sure you guys knows
bathroom you and CMOS say say it what's
a you know computer graphics as for game
programming games the low-level computer
graphics one of the worst technology
Satya CGI so let me copy that so we
digressed into SGI and yeah and SGI and
so let's go back to the unix breakfast
okay
the unix breakfast so yeah the unix
history you know debian you know the
open-source fighting which with each
other
directs x no direct sex is for microsoft
there is the open source version code i
can i can remember it you know yeah it's
okay
WebGL opengl yeah
opengl from silica yes IP IP me thank
you
opengl you know that's from Silicon
Graphics SGI you know they bankrupt
mainly released it becomes open source
they is it's not like oh we bankrupt
let's do it you know it's it when they
do that they always say oh we are we are
enthusiastic we support you know freedom
of humanity things like that we support
missus freedom of humanity therefore
today we are announcing that we are
releasing this oh you know Open GL to
the open source community oh yeah
everyone is like a product why they do
that because they bankrupt the you know
they have it's not
you know they failed there's no way to
make money they are bankrupt that's what
they do it same thing happened with same
thing happened with Java okay you know
Java is more complicated story something
happened with Java from the Sun
Microsystems one of the most evil
company you know people at that at that
time people hate Microsoft I don't
actually you know well you can say I'm
I'm always contrary but I don't see much
bad about Microsoft what I see is the
Sun Microsystems everything they do
they control Java they don't want Linux
to succeed you know Java you know
beginning with 1995 up to you know
they'd like it's all UNIX okay they
could easily make Java you know the
great language for Linux but they don't
want to because Linux is open source
they have no way to make money so they
tightly control Java so they make sure
that Java doesn't does not run well on
Linux okay that's what some echo system
did for for you know for a decade when
they are like raining the.com days so
Microsystems you know they want to sell
Java so that the Java runs on Solaris
you know the Sun Microsystems operating
system well and they wanted to run on
some Microsystems hardware you know they
say oh you know I have I have you know
back then I have you know I have you
know each each box is like $40,000 40
grand for Mini Mini server yeah the so
micro systems Evo and when then all
these companies some Microsystems next
do I have the there's a lot history here
okay net bsd next operating system is
also bankrupt you know this is by Steve
Jobs when he got kicked out from Apple
by John Sculley the me because there's a
fight
you know anyway Sun Microsystems Apple
you know
oh this company and Netscape of course
AOL miss scape failed because Microsoft
the browser they they are better than
the netscape browser in every way it's
faster it's more standard compliant it's
you know HTML and CSS
you know just begin you know to become
standardized they so Microsoft you know
back then they you know most UNIX people
will say oh Microsoft they do Evo they
create new they panned out the operating
system with their browser so that it it
wiped out you know the Netscape I don't
believe that that's false that's paid
that's just false from from my own
observations Microsoft Windows let let
me search ok let me show you
Microsoft hatred you know I got tons of
articles on those on Microsoft hatred so
they are like seven articles about all
this period of time from 1998 to around
2005 ok this one is written in 2002 it's
it's rich in response to eric nagging
you know the well-known common lisp
troll so you can read it in detail you
and so much so Microsoft hatred you know
they I detailed for example the you can
so this these are history ok so
Microsoft history Microsoft hatred
frequently asked questions from this
article you can see what are the
thinking you know every every
programmers in particular the UNIX
people you know they what they say about
Microsoft every day so I'm you know I'm
fighting with him I we taught you know
and Microsoft hatred and God yeah
communism that's and this what is
monopoly Apple Google Microsoft ok this
this is particularly interesting there
is a quote becomes viral that becomes
marrow in 2010 he says it's it's on
Twitter okay
welcome to the new decade Java is a
restricted platform Google is evil Apple
is a monopoly and micro are the
underdogs underdogs Microsoft other
underdogs this quote became viral you
know with millions millions of shares
mostly from you know programmers
especially the hacker types why because
it it means the bear it will stand true
because you see what they says you see
before 2010 everyone hates Microsoft you
know every everyone thinks Apple is a
good guys Google is a good guys you know
and Microsystems or
UNIX is a good guys but now in 2010 you
can see even even 10 years ago you know
2010 Apple you know Java is become Java
by the time it's already so - Oracle
yeah so Oracle is you know know the
hackers don't like Oracle I don't like
oconee the oil co is that is bad ok so
Java is now considered to be you know
not open source is it a bug story is
very complex it's like half open source
have not then at one time then lawsuit
then it's not open source installment
for example richard stallman one time
says you know Java is a trap you search
richard stallman java is a trap you can
find his his website on free software
foundation okay job Java is a trap then
around 2008 also it he reverted because
Java
did you know they started to okay
finally they are going to release it or
some free software sanctioned open
source you know if we software license
so then Richard Stallman posted an essay
saying oh we welcome now we will come
finally it's a great move we welcome
it's a microsystem so was it or go it
was Sun Microsystems I
before before some microsystem went
bankrupt okay some microsystem went
bankrupt around 2008 or so so richard
stallman reverted saying oh now we're
Java is great thank you for you know
service systems now I approve it you
know reaches oh man so you can see then
Google is evil you can see the
possession possession perception of
Google before 2010 you know it's a
company that does no evil
we helped it because it's grading every
way you know they they have a motto
motto in their company you know to know
Evo and and their software is just
fantastic in every way it really back
then then but but starting around 2010
that's about the right time you know
they they are becoming you know Evo
because they lie they they they they
control you know the web search engine
so that it only show their own products
and their website things like that and
lots of cases you know we reported by
the news media every day you know
because they say this but they actually
did they do that you know leaked
information or things like that is they
started to do all that kind of things
even you know starting around back
back in 2010 an apple is not monopoly
yeah that's a perception you know even
10 years ago because why because iPhone
you know the phone a Polk who made it
popular and they have tight control and
censorship you know they have you know
so-called Ward Carden you know they
don't allow anything that disagree with
them you know for example there's so
many bad stories about Apple food for is
for example one one thing they do is
that they for example today on Apple
they have ad blocks but they only block
googles ads you know cuoco sets their
own ads flows through our iPhone you
know that's what they do and back then
in 2010 they also do heavy censorship
you know they for example it's you know
you know on the web you know at one time
they been they been home for example and
Steve Jobs was famous for saying oh if
you want that go elsewhere something
like that and also they banned for
example this summer Kotra that you know
the Indian classic erotic you know how
to make love you know basically Kama
Sutra the Indian you know 2,000 years
old classic you know so Apple banded and
lots of other stories things like that
so Apple you know because they want to
why Apple do that but all these
companies they only they do what they do
there's only one simple reason that
cannot count all because they just want
to make money they don't care about you
know on the surface they say they care
about morality and ethics but actually
they don't you know they just say those
things
they have PR departments 1000 you know
employees speaking PR department in
lawyers in patent you know lawyers you
know and the PR department is an army
you know every day they just they
understand psychology they hire
psychologists you know so they can
create these logos and mantras and stuff
so that make you believe they are you
know doing good and swept away you know
ugly things they don't want you to hear
all these companies and Microsoft you
know back in 2010 ten years ago
Microsoft is like nobody is talking
about Microsoft you know they're just
like this because Microsoft they failed
they okay yeah Microsoft they they they
a browser failed you know for 10 years
the IE browser is the biggest you know
and they do nothing to it they you know
it's pretty lousy because they stopped
once they won the browser war in 2000
year 2000 they stopped updating anything
to it because they don't want they don't
want the web to grow they want their
operating system that's the that's the
bread and butter the web they have
nothing to do with it
well Google they they their bread and
butter is the web ads therefore Google
every day is pushing web technology you
know oh we open source
you know we push open WebGL you know the
the G the way the the graphic you know
they'd they push everything JavaScript
you know that's that's Google because
that's where Google's money came from an
Apple is pushing for the phone in a word
garden phone and Microsoft they failed
in their phone you know they are the
first to create you know the phone with
touch and start but but Microsoft is not
good marketing and and basically so
that's you see this quote this quote
went viral in in 2010 and from this you
can see you know you get you get thought
about history and there is Netscape okay
this here this story this essay is my my
story in my documentation of Netscape
the browser how they failed you know so
this is around 2002 from 2000 you know
from 2008 to 2002 you know netscape
browser you know it's the the web
becomes popular the boom town calm days
the web everything is you know Amazon
Amazon eBay Yahoo you know they become
popular and Microsoft they entered the
web late and they don't have nothing but
however so so they started to create the
IE browser you know for free you know
they all they try to and every version
since it began every version of
Microsoft ie browser is better than
Netscape in every aspect in memory usage
in speed in standard conformance back
then its HTML 3 okay I think it's HTML 3
and CSS just begins
PSSs began in 1997 or so okay CSS back
then CSS is a new concept you know not
many people embrace it yet
before CSS you have font on font font
attributes for example you write things
like for example let me show you so we
got a new paragraph you say font equals
to Arial for example so that's how you
do it and then you say I guess you say
color equals to easier color yeah I
think so
something like that colored red okay
that's how you do it there's no CSS and
CSS begin around around like let's make
it okay so CSS begin around you know
1997 or something like that the the
Specht
but it wasn't it took many years to for
it to become accepted you know because
when something began a technology began
usually nobody nobody is sure it's going
to survive or not you know some company
some company supported sanction it some
company doesn't it you know you don't
know yet so only on three or five years
later you'll see you know whether is
it's survival not so for example back
then another thing popular is VRML VRML
which is like a 3d system for the web
that died you know that back then around
2008 is hugely popular like everyday you
hear it on the web you have a plug-in
for VRML which is stand for virtual
reality virtual reality markup language
okay it's for the web so you supposedly
you can see you know 3d stuff on a web
that that failed for example but back
then for for
like four years five years it's
extremely popular and it's let's make
this okay so so you got these things and
VRML so so yeah CSS so so so from 1998
to around 2002 okay
when Netscape died all these years every
version of Microsoft ie
is better than Netscape in every way I
mean technically we're not talking about
politically but every technical detail I
have so I have a my own record of it you
know this is my opinion you can check
out our Netscape crap and the the famous
you know jamie zawinski
he also has a say for so finally
Netscape went bankrupt they got bought
out by AOL then they say they think oh
let's release it as open source you know
helps humanity anyway that they also
failed until four years later it became
Mozilla and they they rewrote everything
as they then become Firefox then Firefox
gradually became after you know four or
five years you know it gradually eats
into the Microsoft ie because and micro
Safari has no improvement since since
2002 my way no once Microsoft warned the
browser war they stopped updating
anything that's you know because that's
not the where they make money they don't
want the web to grow then every day you
hear on a web is how Microsoft is Evo
and this or that but I don't agree
because you know it's Microsoft browser
what it was you know better than
escaping every way and also is more it's
more standard compliant to W theses you
know HTML and CSS standard then escape
in
reversion you know but you know the me
the Microsoft hatred is kind of just the
Train you know just you know because a
particular because these UNIX people
they eat shrimpy everyone love to even
today you can see you know anyway so
let's go back to the security thing
there is the article there is the Arco I
want to show you how you know just like
an anecdotal story about how UNIX is the
most insecure obtains operating system
and by the way did here is a ad for
Microsoft back in year 2000 it's funny
so Microsoft created this ad in German
so better than you you have to tell us
what is what does it say actually I have
a translation here but anyway that's
that's Microsoft ad so let's go back so
let's go back there is the there is the
let me just post this okay my face
blocks part of the sentence okay so you
can see it here yeah okay
yeah so so let's go back to I want to go
back to that security thing okay so
okay I don't it's linked here somewhere
but the easiest way to find it is such
is to search for Saudi eunuchs break
first breakfast yet the the eunuchs way
okay
breakfast the eunuchs way wait the
eunuchs way first put the eunuchs way
okay this is this is the Oracle
you can so you can okay yeah just search
for fast fast food the eunuchs way so
you'll find it so let me get that
so let's I guess let me post the link
then copy URL paste it then make it the
make it title and then spam the chat
okay let's go spend the chat okay so
there is a problem with this chant
because it when you have a return it
like it doesn't respect the return it
merge them together but I suppose I
still walk so let's just post it so
these are the what you have to post one
by one I guess post enter back next cut
copy back post enter back next copy back
post enter back that's okay that's my
cell my articles oops
delete okay UNIX philosophy UNIX
philosophy fast-food the UNIX way now
this is a humor Gabey
is very funny Italy did you know I try
to find our engine of this this this
joke I think it's from 1984 and the
author might be pop peers but I cannot
be sure but you know you know it's very
funny
so the so now let me read the comments
then so actually I I kind of I I need to
go to take a piss love that drink here
so it's paste let me read the comments
quickly let me check me all the comments
address to me okay I'm gonna check all
the comments addressed to me right now
so what are we calling security what do
you say it means yeah so that you know
the concept of security especially since
ten years ago
it gets abused like everything is like
you just say security issues but like
what do you mean security you know I
have a big problem with the security
because computer computer languages
there is no security issue whatsoever
you see because computer language is
they they don't you know any security is
like just human it's like you hack
that's why anyway that topic it takes a
lot explanation because you know
security like what do you mean security
for example if you have a login system
let's say UNIX login system or web login
system that there is a security because
for example if I create a website I
create a login system but but every you
know but if I don't implement if I don't
understand stuff well you know I love
the implementation then any anyone can
easily bypass it
or if I you know if I use plain text you
know to log password and you know my
my connection to database is not
encrypted
you know the anyone can hack into it you
know anyone can simply listen to the
HTTP traffic then they know all the
passwords that is insecure that is
security issue and that the blame of
that is me the programmer because you
know I'm a lousy programmer I did that
that you know so if you have a password
that's that's a security issue but then
security is abuse you know like
everything you know every hacking
everything when someone can break into
your system or any or even Java on the
web javascript on the web is called
security it's not security like what do
you mean security if you're talking
about security every everything computer
programming everything is insecure
everything is security because you know
I go to your home if you don't have a
password on your system on your Mac or
Windows I can just use it that's
security that's that's not really
security because you choose not to you
know set up a password because you think
you know your your laptop is only used
by you and vast much by the way
vast majority of laptop users they don't
and on Windows for example they don't
have a password they don't turn it on
because most people they don't know that
what the heck is past what they don't
want it because once they have a
password they forgot they don't want it
you know most your mom and your parents
your grandpa you know anyone who is not
a programmer they don't want a password
that is why even on Linux many Linux
systems they start to create a system so
that there's no password by default
login system no password because this is
the way most people want to use
computers you know once you have a
passwords they don't
these too complex you know they I know
because you know since I wash dishes to
survive I know a lot of people working
in restaurant they are not programmers
they have no idea like what is a
programming they have no idea what is
this Google you know they barely heard
what is Google they don't know what is
web search you know they don't know
what's the meaning of a browser they
just use the phone they know press this
to talk to people you know press that oh
you know that that's what I know
and on the phone you know what's their
password their password is their phone
number most of them even don't have a
password yeah I mean they don't even
have that you know they're if they do
have a password their passwords their
phone number and there is no possible
way for you to convince them or tell
them because they that's they don't they
don't know you I mean you have to
realize the the degree that extend that
they don't you know they are not
programmers you have to realize how much
if you are a programmer you have to
realize how much you are well you are
living in a big bubble you don't
understand you don't understand how
normal people are working you know how
no more people are not programmers
non-technical people are actually are
you know except maybe your friends you
know that young people young people who
you know go to Instagram Facebook or
whatever all these social networks they
know okay they they know but most people
you know the vast majority they are not
programmers they are not tech they don't
they don't know and they don't want to
you don't they don't want the password
not even to mention Emacs like the Emacs
phonetics they say oh if you cannot
figure out what is maitake then you
should not use Emacs mataki most people
do not even know what the is ctrl
ctrl command key you know I know because
you have to you have to you know most
programmers we we live you know we each
person we have a lifestyle and we have
friends who are all in in this lifestyle
you know you don't talk to people walk
you know code you know for example in
America you say the coal miners the you
know the the people working at Walmart
the people working at McDonald's those
people you talk to those people they
don't know
what the can you tell me about
control Mehta control control my ass
don't even know what is a control key on
computer okay
so these are you know you Emacs phonetic
so all these programmers so Emacs
regular expression we probably that's
probably gonna be tomorrow then because
we don't have we already 50 minutes
what are calling security so I
appreciate the passion so Seema says I
appreciate the passion but what are we
coding secure how might we measure
exactly you know you have to define what
is security you know what is the value
proposition what is the what is the
value proposition about what similar
says about about the OpenGL or SGI what
is the value proportion yeah I forgot
what what do you mean by that
so comments okay okay one more comments
so iris says iris Kashia good morning
iris says I want to ask you something I
really like the Canisius advantage to
keyboard but it does not ship to my
country yeah that's too bad which one do
you recommend me as a similar as
possible okay so oh I just started then
by mistake notes I don't know what that
is okay so it's great notes so Kinesis
what's the alternative to Kinesis
advantage if you don't have if you
cannot buy it well there is a do do it
yourself keyboard there's a doctor these
are highly recommended but this one is
for do-it-yourself so you have to buy
parts you have to spend days to assemble
it you know you have to buy the
electronics the chips the key caps and
you have to 3d print
you know the the thing then you have to
assemble it there's an instruction on a
website and this is great this is this
is even better than Kinesis but
altogether you are going to spend
something like $400 USD I think he told
me because I met him he told me you know
it's even yeah you have to spend like
almost even more than more expensive
than Kinesis so you buy the parts and
you assemble ok so that's one option and
similarly there are these others you
know this oldest art do-it-yourself
this one is called tactile manual phone
dr. Manuel phone yeah so and this one is
also do it yourself but I don't have
experience on this tactile manual foam
you see their thumb keys is kind of
funky the idea of the thumb keys here is
that you press in what you know so the
idea is that they think the thumb you
know the natural movement is pressing
inward not not downwards so that's why
they created this you know inward inward
press for the thumb I'm not sure it's
good I never I never tried it actually
but I doubt it's you know I'm not sure
so anyway they are by the way this dr.
manuel foam and there is also
colloquialism this one is from japan it
becomes harder to get info because they
they also have a website they they sell
the parts but this one man you form is
from Japan so you have to kind of read
Japanese so you can do it but you know
it becomes hard and also this one is is
from Japan to do it yourself
but anyways and and there are all these
you know other people this one I I'm not
I don't think he has a website it's not
polished but you can but it sound way
that you can for example talk to him ask
him how he made it things like that any
all these are duties yourself the thing
is if you want this curved surface it
gets complex okay so and if you want to
buy a directory of course there's also
the motor on motor on is the other
alternative but it's even more expensive
it's like five hundred dollars and I am
it's this one is based on UK so I think
they so if you are UK or Europe maybe
they ship it there but although
otherwise I don't know but it's even
more expensive otherwise maybe you can
try eBay
you know eBay is oh oh you just have to
make do with others like none you know
some of the others this one is from
Japan also extremely expensive five
hundred dollars it's pretty good but
this one is five hundred dollars yeah
otherwise I think maybe the easiest way
I don't know like depending on where you
are so yeah so error errors like what
country are you are
and also let me mention if you buy from
China okay if you have opportunity to
visit China visitors Chen Chen Sheng
Jian is a city above Hong Kong okay like
one hour drive above Hong Kong City
sentient that's a big make make make are
topless you know that's a giant city
it's the most famous for the electronics
center of the of China or the world you
know but anyway if you buy keyboard or
anything electronics in China it's very
cheap okay it's five times cheaper than
any any anywhere else okay like the same
thing made it made in China you you buy
in China okay
now China they also have a website
called Taobao okay table our end and few
others for example Oh Alibaba okay for
example let's show how about calm they
have a few and you buy them like they
are five times cheaper the you know the
the ones made in China and the Chinese
brand but if you buy for example
Logitech oh you know Microsoft you know
the American brand then it's not cheaper
okay then in those cases you don't want
to buy from Taobao you rather buy from
Amazon you know elsewhere but but you go
through the Chinese you know table our
website I don't have a JavaScript on so
that's why it's not showing anything but
you they have tons you know hundreds of
varieties you know for example all this
all this keyboard varieties I show it
sound how about similar people have made
and many people build it then it they
sell it for example for example I see
this for example let's see Do It
Yourself for example I see this I can
make it myself
and I can sell it on Taobao and you know
and much cheaper you know so people
there are people doing that on Taobao
use
the tons of varieties or of all these
you know even far more than what I have
here for example look at this one this
one's spectacular this one this one is
on Taobao ok Aliexpress ok that's
another Chinese website Aliexpress I
don't have JavaScript on that's why it's
not showing but let's go - lets go to it
on Google Chrome ok 256 - $570 you know
it's you can buy it so but but anyway
let's go back to the design of things
this one is excellent I have seen no
other design like this why is it
excellent because it has one two three
four four knobs and wheels these knobs
like volume control in this wheels these
are great fantastic okay because these
knobs in quirós they allow they are the
best input system to control anything
any command that has forward and
backward or next previous or left right
or up and down or volume up you know up
down volume up/down squawk way up down
any kind of command that has say you
know opposing command in any of those
that needs to be a petition like you
want to repeat fast such as Patriot you
know you want to page up five times
kingdoms or score of ten times oh you
know next the next buffer previous
perform a step for example like like
what I'm doing you know you can hold
down you can hold down to like just like
you know go through them right now it's
loading that's why it's slow but
otherwise normally I can like fly
through them for example let's let me do
it now you know I gave again you know so
for this kind of and and also whenever
you have this kind of commands for
example page down page or another for
example backward word for
like I'm going backward paragraph oh
hold on I want to reverse direction
downward you know forward paragraph hold
on I want to reverse direction all these
commands you have tens of these pairs of
commands typically they are you know
typically they are they require
repetition like the the petal if you can
repeat them that's that would be
fantastic also often you want to reverse
direction for example forward oh wait I
want back what what I I pass I want
backward word Oh for example forward
right now I'm forwarding to the next
right bracket and backward you know any
of these commands you have tens of them
the best input physical input control
for them is is a wheel okay is a wheel
kind of thing we or knobs the wheel can
come in various forms for example for
example this where are we did we just
close it okay well for example you have
volume knobs or you have like this this
is like mask wheel yeah that's a base
control so anyway so you see this
Chinese one it's on Aliexpress
you can buy so I think this is you know
fantastic you just have two of them but
it's expensive but for example one we
when we so we were talking about Chinese
website right we were talking about
there are hundreds of varieties for
example you can see on the side you have
this programmable keypad you have this
forum programmable key back with a wheel
and also we are with a potent
combination you know only $75 this one
$56 USD if you go to Amazon you also
have that but it's like country $20 so
anyway so that's about Chinese made
stuff and Chinese website much cheaper
and by the way this is also this this
website right now because I
facing it through us you know I'm us I
mean us
California that's why it's actually more
isn't expensive but if you are actually
in China for example you buy it you know
you if you are in China you go to the
website they show the Chinese in you
know that maybe the the RMB the China
money but if you convert that to US
dollar it's like five times cheaper than
the US dollar prize shown here so the
best thing you want to do maybe you can
the best thing you can do if if you are
you know either visit China you know go
to China you know the the air the air
ticket is like 800 700 dollars something
like that $600 1/2 way I guess cheaper
when it's cheap then you can go to
online ask your Chinese friend to buy it
for you oh you visit China you know you
gotta change in you can buy physically
you know go to this engine but you do
have to watch out there are lots of
cheap you know bad quality things you
know you have to watch out there are
some people who introduced you you know
which is good which is back bad I'm like
on YouTube you might check you know
search for you know do some research
research search for what Chinese product
are they good are they bad you know
there are yeah there are there are scams
of course so if you don't speak Chinese
you there's something you are you want
to watch out as well so go to go to
China visited Chinese website or go to
China go buy you know go to the ancient
Chinese electronics Center oh if you are
also have China
you could try one of those indirect web
sites they anyway or as a Chinese friend
to buy it for you okay so for example
I'm in California I speak Chinese I
could buy for you you pay me I actually
I cannot do it
because I don't have a car I don't have
nothing I cannot I cannot move yeah st.
Jen and so david says tebah has fancy
keyboards but don't know if they ship to
Europe is Europe there is gearbest and
Aliexpress okay IRA says but would you
have enough precision to stop in the
world you want for actually I need to go
to bathroom quickly so so be right back
in one minute okay back in one minute
DeYoung good morning dear
Deon says my strongest hacker moves are
not working what is your strongest
hacker move so I got this shirt I don't
know what it is
GRS money oh I don't know what that is
it's a arcade or what garage I don't
know
it's from us my roommate gave it to me
so so it's C comments okay so okay so no
no common address to me and we okay so
any more questions we are you know we
are over one hour now so we could stop
anytime now I guess so if there is no
particular topic then then maybe that's
it for today let's go back to my talk
page so we can talk about Emacs regular
expression that we should we probably
reserved it for next time actually few
days ago last week or two weeks ago we
did we did I did a video or Emacs
regular expression yeah yeah so you know
I'm not sure what what am I doing with
my videos you know right now it's
becoming just like my daily chat it's
almost like you know it's typical
actually that's like what I do tip
typical of my stuff yes there's no there
is no goal there is no purpose there and
there's no schedule I'm just doing what
I you know whatever comes to
and do you know I liked like my blogs
you know you know this like lots of well
typically things that's of interest to
nerds Unicode keyboard programming math
and symbology Unicode symbols
programming symbols but but there's a
bit but usually there is no goal as you
know like as opposed to any people you
know like some people they teach
particular thing like Emacs you know
they focus on that or some people teach
JavaScript they focus on you know
educational or they teach math calculus
calculus trigonometry you know there's
this guy who became famous calculus
trigonometry trigonometry chemistry I
mean anyway for me it's almost like it's
like randoms of my topics sometimes
technical you know on these programming
languages or unicode programming
language design and sometimes it's it's
like politics YouTube and when you do
things like this usually yeah so I'm not
sure what am I going with my videos I'm
going to you know I'm doing with my
videos you know I've been doing videos
now almost every day for at least half a
year now and every video is like well
and most you have hundred 100 views that
means you know how you know how YouTube
councils as a view that's very
interesting because it's very complex
complicated and it's also highly
political you know because eating
involves money
it's like SEO you know there's a lot
drama and people talk about it you know
OVU You Tube change their view count
method again and also they kicked take
they try to keep it secret because
otherwise you know like I mentioned
before
you might you know yesterday or previous
talks this is a huge industry when you
know when it comes to web websites ads
you know there's lots of parties you
know they are all interested scammers
more where they do anything they can you
know people get into the industry they
do any thing they can to extract money
to get ads or things so this includes
YouTube you know like you go to youtube
there's tremendous amount of I would say
almost more than 50% of YouTube videos
they are created not by they are created
solely but by by parts by all means you
know all all things people possibly can
imagine they come up to to try to get
money you know to try to put on YouTube
ads from for example robotic voices for
example you go to youtube you'll see
today you'll see tons of news that's you
know let's be read out by robot you know
like for example for example what's the
current topic today hot topic like for
example gun control then they do they'll
have a you have tons of YouTube about
just Oh today you know machine voice you
know they didn't generate it
mechanically so you know people do that
then you also have all sorts of anyway
the the main point is that it's all
things all things imaginable like like
you cannot possibly imagine what kind of
ways they do it you cannot like you
cannot possibly even even imagine it
even if you try sit down think about it
for one hour why because they are
literally I don't know how much millions
or hundreds of thousands you know people
around the globe they are all trying to
do this because that's how you make
money you know they are so they have all
possible directions you know possibly
imagine imaginable subject you know they
are trying to do this so anyway when it
comes to Google YouTube view count so
that's very contingent
dangers and controversial topic because
and Google tries to keep it secret
because once you know you cannot tell if
you tell then all these you know you
know people will exploit it you know
they they will make their video becomes
you know 1 million views big so why is
is important because that number that
number has a tremendous impact on how
people decides to follow you yeah that
you know even though it's silly to you
know if you think about it that's really
silly you know because people wants to
follow popularity popular people you
know stars movie stars they want to know
what sure you are what shirt you are
wearing today like you know David Bowie
Space Oddity that's a great song you
know people want to know what should you
are wearing today you know what you wear
today is on the news millions people
want to talk about it oh you know with
especially if you are female then you
know that becomes a fashion you know so
anyway so YouTube viewcount that's you
know and and also where all these people
are trying to you know get you know
trying to explore it ads and so on
YouTube and Google itself is doing the
same
they are the evil but by themselves
because they are they are trying to make
money they are trying to control it the
the view count whatever algorithms you
know they use algorithms to control
everything they want to make sure so
that meanwhile they filter out well
basically what they want to make sure is
not really about filter out you know
these spare players or misinformation
that's what they say okay they say the
you know they are helping humanity to
filter out this bad information but
that's not the real true intentions what
they are really doing is that is they
want to maximize you know their ads
amount because this happened many
hence its being exposed for example for
few months ago like three months ago
they are like tens of thousands videos
each one is with millions of views that
explore its children like they have
contents that's you know cartoon you
know contents for children where where
the content is like spider-man doing
drugs you know spider-man vs. bad name
bad name bad man they on toilet
they drink each other's piss yeah
children's you know cartoon for children
and that's their content and they are
like each one is like ten million views
or something and there are several
accounts doing that extremely popular
and you think YouTube don't know that of
course they know but they don't they
don't do anything to it because that
makes me money makes them money until
this got exposed you know by team pool
by you know lots of people then they say
oh you know then they depend also counts
you know that's YouTube and this has
been you know and you don't know and
what most people don't know yeah and
because even if you follow news because
Twitter you know Facebook they control
information you know once you post they
limit how many people you know how when
you post about something they limit who
you who will see it you know they
control so but but if you are paying
attention to these community these kind
of happening then you know in the end
it's not just one person reported you
see it's like if you are in like it's
like Emacs
okay so modern societies each community
each news channel becomes very niche so
for example I'm Emacs I know a lot about
what's going on Emacs but other people
even programmers they don't know they
don't know they'd never they'd never
heard of what what what did we just
almond do yes
you know they don't know so anyways same
thing with these you know political
content topics but if you you know now
you know like now if you hear me now you
know you now you go to youtube you
search you search for children's video
you know spider-man you know controversy
then you see lots of reports in like
hundreds website all reporting it and
this is only one of the incident you
know YouTube this is a lot like every
month is this big and small every you
know things going on so YouTube you know
they they Google extremely evil okay
that I think that's about it you know
what can you do there's almost nothing
nothing you can do you know so you know
you think about modern society you
wonder whether it's getting better or
worse you know it's hard to say
and of course today there is happenings
with Hong Kong you probably heard of it
but if you are American I probably can
guess what's your opinion is you know
about Hong Kong it with basically China
is evil you know they did control they
are dictatorship they are controlling
informations therefore you support Hong
Kong yes please Hong Kong students you
look at all these millions of students
innocent civilians on the people all
they want is peace they all they want is
a little freedom you know you know
that's what they want and you have these
million people so in China this powerful
big dictatorship you know with police
beating people that's what you believe
that's what you hear and you know USA in
white countries you have this basically
left versus right you know the left is
the extreme left is about social justice
every day there's a big fight you know
Trump over no drop or anti Trump you
know big fight every day but when it
comes to China in Western countries
almost everywhere Greece China China is
the bad guy Hong Kong is good we all
want to support Chinese you know you
know the Hong Kong people we want
democracy we want overthrow the Chinese
government the Communists but that's
that's what you hear that's what you
believe of course I have a different
story to tell
but that's gonna be you another hour you
know but you know it's and you know so
what do you know about Chinese I mean do
you speak Chinese have you tried to talk
to Chinese people have you tried to a
hey wait hold on a second maybe maybe we
can I'm you know let me look into what's
the situation you know you never did
probably you never spend one minute to
look into because Chinese that's not of
your concern that's that's that's like
let's head hate Mitch micros
yeah that's a good thing I don't like
Microsoft God Microsoft did this this is
evil things yeah yeah Microsoft is so
evil you know you say it every day on
the web big why because we're the
Microsoft succeed Omega Microsoft went
to jail has nothing to do with your way
of fail you know well being
oh you cares yeah Microsoft is big evil
yeah they did evil isn't it they should
go to jail but did you ever spend you
know one hour to look into no same thing
with China you know but if you are
Chinese then you would be interested
then then you look into then there's
different opinions you start to see you
know different opinions it doesn't
matter it doesn't matter if you are in
China in Hong Kong in Taiwan you know if
you are Chinese you know or even outside
you but Chinese blood you you see you
start you you know you you you start to
see different opinions okay you you may
be you know with the Hong Kong or you
may be anti Hong Kong but you start to
see then it becomes a fight just like in
USA or white countries you have the left
group you know the social justice the
you know the anti-drug Trump oh you have
the right the Trump then you fight every
day you fight for information fake news
then you can reply to those fake news
then Twitter is trying to do censorship
and you know you do your fight okay so
that's I think that's it for today so if
you have any things you want me to
comment put my name to it then that's it
for today I think that's yeah thanks so
Thank You iris well for the question
about keyboard
deokman Indian burn a steak vas for me
so today today is today's rent again
East so the first 40 minutes is is
basically a rant and history of Unix
yeah unix netscape Microsoft kind of
history about those things about in Java
and you know in Mac Google Apple
basically history and again is the
mainstream views basically or somewhat
about human humanity human animals
behavior the you know the political
behavior of human animals somewhat
characterised via we are this you know
this Java is a trap Java war lease
versus Unix
whoa you know the motox versus UNIX
whoa-oh UNIX by the way though it came
from it's a it's a it's a parody of the
motives of renal system so you have more
tix then you mix people came up with
UNIX then then it's also it's also a
tasteless pun you know on a word UNIX
you know that's that's another reason I
hate this UNIX people UNIX philosophy
for people typically they are tasteless
you know they don't care they are this
they their personality is this kind of
happy-go-lucky oh I don't care you know
whatever you know let's have a beer you
know whatever kind of people now this is
supposed to reach a storm and for
example he's not that type he is not
this type of people he he for example
and on the other hand is on the extreme
he is rather very disciplined he
believed in this one thing he always
just like politically say about this is
he's his thing you know he doesn't you
know he's not like that you know and so
anyway so that's Unix the history of the
term UNIX so that's about it for today
so that first first hour is about that
then we talked about twenty minutes on
Kinesis versus alternatives and where to
buy keyboards in Chinese keyboards and
stuff okay so that's it for today thank
you guys for watching I can see I can
see that the Chinese state to be
defending yourself from being meant best
basa lized despite the fact there are
many things about a single-party system
to criticize well my opinion on China is
first of all I'd like to say of course
I'm biased
you know because because I'm you know
I'm Chinese blood and basically I
support China okay but as far as you
know my reasons you know okay with that
said you know my reason you know first
of all I mentioned this before when you
think about democracy you know when you
think about democracy what democracy the
way we believe in democracy
I'm a democracy is particularly us thing
USA okay American thing in the past you
know American is only 2200 years old
okay in a history of things
USA is only 200 years old okay they
don't have culture you really I mean
well if you want to trace it the u.s.
American thing they are based on Western
Western thought okay Western thought
which is Europe and and the core of it
came from Roman you know Roman Empire
and where does came from Roman Empire
their culture and thought is vastly
influenced from Greek culture Greek
mythology you know
so anyway that's weapons Western thought
but anyway back to the the thought of
democracy okay democracy freedom you
know that's Western especially
especially today when we talk about
democracy that's mostly Americans from
ci8 you know that's kind of with this
kind of out of shape you know Saudi it's
like you have to ask people what does it
what does it mean democracy what does it
mean exactly you know let's let's go
back to analytic philosophy what if I
try to divide everyone will have
different you know everyone who team
first of all you you ask you go to the
street ask those students okay in
college what ask them to give a
definition of democracy they cannot they
start you start to see they become
extremely seedy they like they have no
idea what they cannot possibly give a
coherent definition basically what they
will say Oh
individual freedom yeah freedom to
people freedom rules the country you
know vote voting systems that's that's
the most you get that's basically
something something along that lines
anyway so but anyway then you okay let's
let me let me get to the point okay so
even even if you assume democracy you
know meaning some kind of some sort of
democratic
ruling system meaning that you know
people vote and that's how you govern
okay so people vote then you have the
governors or you have presidents you
know basically people vote you know even
that so we even we suppose democracy
that that's what you guys want okay that
is questionable because if you actually
study united states system okay politics
you know you if you actually study it
you know it is far from voted by people
okay is kind of its kind of is but it's
kind of not the how the US government
runs you know the how the whole system
you the US system works is not
controlled by people at all okay far
from it you cannot you can control
nothing from it it let's put it this way
it's it's far from what people want okay
for example what's what's some of the
issues of government
okay the health system the foreign
policy the you know the how CIA is
watching you know look you know watching
private citizens security security
issues you know privacy issues you have
no control the most you can do is like
supposed to you you you elected a person
you like elected local government but
how you like you know you have all these
corporations the pharmacies that health
insurance companies the oil companies
Google for example they control
information massive this main PD and you
know you you you know assuming you are
trying you are interested and you look
into these issues then you realize you
know all these companies they spend
spent periods influence control people's
thought so if you watch TV you are no
more system sis if you are a normal
system everything you know it's not true
then you vote you know what are you
voting for everything you know it's like
you are voting for what they spend money
on that's what you are voting for so you
are so you are saying Oh democracy
therefore USA is great the curse of
democracy the you know you said you know
you said what you truly believe
on the other hand if you look at history
of the world doesn't matter we you know
what region you look at history of the
world or regions you know especially
Asia is democracy is a Western you know
the person of freedom justice personal
freedom that's a Western philosophy okay
that's a Western thought you know most
of you are probably Western people white
people okay you know that's what the
social justice term white people but
anyway you probably are Western okay but
east Eastern you know in India or in
Middle East or Russia or for example or
China you know the spaces especially
China you have more population in China
in throughout history than most Western
countries okay so if you want you know
trying you know China is more actually
the more center of the Western thought
but anyway let's talk about China that's
because that's what I know I don't know
about in Hindu much I don't know about
Middle East much okay although in India
and the Middle East is is also it's kind
of the cradle of this civilization as
well you know they say and also this is
Russia but anyway I know about China
okay that's a big part of human history
so in China which which is basically the
center that influenced Japan you know
this is in southern China or you know
like Korea Taiwan
you know vnm Singapore or these other
countries okay China basically that's
the the China culture is the source of
everything so in Chinese culture you
don't have you don't have democracy okay
I mean you don't have the thought of
personal freedom okay that's Western
thought you know I mean well you could
say you have that thought I mean but
it's not that's that's kind of a new
thought yeah I mean as far in what you
have instead
what you have is respect elders
respect your ancestor you know do no
evil
okay that's Buddhism do no evil like
don't do bad things okay that's evil
don't do bad things that kind of thing
okay that and you have you know so it's
a culture you know so you have these
kind of things as the foundation of
society society very different from
Western society also in China you have
you know so you have this hum harmony
you know how many like you'd like when
many Western like to talk about oh Tai
Chi o Tai Chi is the medicine Oh Jung oh
you know you know those kind of fuzzy
things Taoism you know that's the
Eastern culture you know where it's not
everything is not like Western you know
black and white if you you know needs to
be precise oh let's do physics oh the
logic from the Greek you know you cried
logic you know philosophy that doesn't
happen in China even China has you know
advanced math more advanced than Western
society okay but but but but how you
think about things doesn't go that way
you doesn't go by logic okay you don't
you go by logic you do the Chinese
philosophy kind of its kind of always
like roundabout you know like Tao and Yi
Jung and when I was younger I hated it I
love I love the Western philosophy I
love the in the individual of freedom
you know individuality I love that you
know Liberty you know in individual
freedom I love the physics the hard core
logic position in language you know like
English you know I love that and I love
the Greek philosophy you know I don't
mean while I don't like the Asian you
know the tradition of oh you know the e
and young you know the Taoism kind of
everything you know
the best thing to do is through nothing
kind of like this fuzzy
kind of run about philosophy
everything's like that you know that's
this when I was young that's that's why
you know I you know study English and
you know I know much about the Western
things but now I have a different view
it's kind of you have to respect the
eight that the the the ACM philosophy
because because even though it's not you
know because you can look at what
happens in society you know it's not
nice you know it's just different way of
thinking okay you don't you know so so
back to the topic so I was saying you
know democracy you know everyone is like
about democracy did this or that you
know what first of all what do you know
about it man democracy is yo defined and
and also if you look actually look at
democracy democracy countries they are
not necessarily better China and
elsewhere in history for a period of
time China has always been like not not
no democracy okay in fact you know
democracy is a new concept most of
history of humanity humanity there is no
such thing
democracy the Western propaganda based
by American democracy there's no such
thing okay most history of human animals
there is no such thing and there are
Wars they are bad times they are good
times but there are many period of times
they people live in harmony in peace
without the democracy okay and
look at the newer look at white
country's democracy yeah Americans wipe
out genocide wiped out the entire
genetic you know the American Indians
that's democracy if that's what you want
then then you have the German happenings
every why is you know the the social
justice guy is talking about every day
so so what is what what so so yeah what
so what is democracy that's that's
that's that's TV you watched too much TV
that's what happens and then then comes
open source yeah Liberty here are the
richest oh man the Liberty some do you
know it's like a communism mixed in with
communism share its share everything and
its get complex because today the social
justice people the left people they want
communism and then of course then the
right people they don't you know they
they are poor they are democracy and
also I mean they are also free market I
love free market okay I am anti but it's
complex you see all these politics a big
becomes very complex because you have
ABCD they are fighting with each other
you are pro a but for something you are
for B but a and B are enemies so when
that's chaos that's what chaos comes in
because that's when the world has
becomes rulers everyone is just to
whatever that been a benefit scheme
pushes pushes whatever ideology that
benefits the person the group that's
that's chaos you know Google is pushing
for whatever is good for Google Twitter
if the tech companies and all these in
China you know China you know so so so
far I've said you know kind of positive
things about China but of course China
has turned the Communist Party they have
done lots of bad things but that's not
my talk ok that's for you guys to talk
about that the point the important thing
is and nobody will listen to it is that
we need to talk about things and listen
to different opinions that's that's that
that would be a good thing ok that's it
for today so thank you guys for watching
bye
well let me read the comments for like
30 seconds but that's that would be it
so
because because I like to get the
comments in the YouTube video because
when he will say bye anyway that yeah
that's it that's it for today so bye
guys
I'm getting hungry and hot so I'm gonna
eat I'm gonna eat one turn Chinese I'm
gonna you know pretty good pretty cooked
you buy from the my roommate trade takes
me to their you buy that you know what
the Western cause dimpsons or wanton you
know three dollars a bag and you can you
know pull your them that's what I'm
gonna eat so tomorrow's talk is gonna be
Chinese food actually not well I don't
know what's tomorrow but actually I
think I should take a break yeah like I
said you know um you know I'm doing it
videos everyday it's like maybe 100
people watch a day at best
you know sometimes okay you know once in
a while every few months when video gets
700 people watching like like the last
video I did on personality test usually
then tactic none technical stuff that
one got 800 v8 800 views now becomes
somewhat popular 800 views because that
video I was talking about personality
test you know in personality disorder
you know that's none tech when you talk
about that I think that gets popular
yeah but I don't know what I'm doing
with my video I guess just everyday just
just random chat about things so
tomorrow what time tomorrow I don't know
I'm thinking okay let's maybe should we
keep talking tomorrow I don't know what
time so maybe I'll take a break tomorrow
so anyway so okay that's it bye okay do
a series on video teaching images from
there were two yeah maybe I should try
that okay anyway I don't know what time
tomorrow maybe not more maybe no video
tomorrow bye guys