Hello. Good morning, everyone. Welcome
to another episode of Sound Talk Show.
So, let's begin. So, today is Emacs.
It's everything about Emacs. It's about
Emacs color theme and the cycle hyphen
low line space command and change
default font command and the cycle fonts
command. So, it's all custom commands.
Let's So, let me begin demo. So, themes
is one of the thing that people love
because, you know, it's a no-brainer.
Everyone love to set up their color
themes. So, am I alive? Check video
check audio check. If you are watching
offline, play at 1.5 speed or higher
because I ramble and just like Joe
Rogan. And if you are watching live, say
hi. Say hi right now, okay?
So, color themes. So, let's begin. So,
video check audio check. I'm good. Yeah.
So, let's um yeah, color themes and
let's begin.
So, color So, first thing demo cycle
color themes. So, let's start a new
Emacs, okay? Press a key and it starts a
new Emacs. So, there is a new Emacs.
And by default, I don't use any themes.
All I do is set background color, okay?
So, you can see that.
Uh let's say red. Now it becomes red.
Now, let's magnify, okay? Let's set
background color uh white. Okay, that's
all I do. I set my background color to
honeydew. But, let's uh magnify the
font, okay? So, do it again. Set
background color and the honeydew,
that's what I use. So,
uh I got this question a lot. What theme
do you use? I just use a background.
Simple, the simplest possible. The more
ugly the user interface, the better.
Okay. So, set background color. So, you
know how to do that. And then, so let's
demonstrate themes. So, normally you
just go to uh customize
themes if you want a color theme in
Emacs. You see, custom- customize
themes, then you can have a several
selections. Uh you can have
Adwaita
face color similar to the default Gnome
3 3. Adveit- Adwaita. What whatever that
What does What the does that mean?
Adwaita. So, let's look up
Press press press
Press cuz I look up the web. Uh Adwaita
Wikipedia. What does it mean? From
Indian. Oh, Indian meaning one and only
in Sanskrit.
Sanskrit script, which is like 2 or
3,000 years old. Adwaita
also spelled something something was a
male Adabra giant tortoise that lived in
the
Alipore Zoological Gardens of Kolkata,
India. Okay? So, it's a creation fable.
Adwaita is a turtle. The Indian turtle.
It's turtles all the way down.
You know, Earth is flat. You got to
because we are all standing on a turtle.
Where does the turtle stand on? Well, it
there's another turtle underneath it.
And it's all the way down, my friends.
Adwaita. Oh, I see.
Learning something every day. So, but
how do you pronounce it? It didn't say
here. There's no IPA pronunciation. So,
I just assume Adwaita. But, wait.
Wait wait, don't tell me. Copy that.
Uh copy that new buffer, paste it. Press
press press press look up dictionary.
Uh Oh, it's not available. That word is
actually not available. So, press press
press press search the web. And there
must be somewhere
that tells us the pronunciation, okay?
So, let's try again. So, look up
dictionary,
um
I have a command that looks up all
dictionary, but I guess I deleted.
So, that command will look up, you know,
like five dictionaries. But, anyway.
So, anyway, so that's Twitter, my
Twitter. Join my Twitter for the
fantastic news, technical or otherwise,
like me juggling, okay? So, and that's
Wolfram language. So, where is my window
here?
Okay, so let's move that up. So, at
waiter.
Now, remember the command is customize
themes, okay?
Now, let's try deep blue, deeper blue,
okay? Stop. Now, let's start try dark
pharmacy, okay? Now, let's remove that.
Let's try Leuven dark, okay? So, that's
how you
get color themes in Emacs. Just call
customize themes.
Now,
but there's a idiocy of Emacs. You see
what Emacs does. So, remove the theme.
So, you can, for example, let's uh
Leuven.
Uh let's say cancel Leuven light blue,
okay? Now, in Emacs, oh, warning, light
blue theme is obsolete since Emacs 29,
okay? That's
Okay.
So,
So, customize themes, okay? But, in
Emacs, they got a idiocy
by the Emacs tech gigas, you know, they
tech nerds. They need to control
everything.
So, in Emacs, the themes are addictive.
That means multiple themes can be
combined. So, for example, I activate
the Leuven dark. Then I activate Luven.
Oh, it removes the other one.
Um
Well,
either used to be you can combine them
or uh you can combine them by uh by
Emacs code. Okay, anyway, forget about
that. Okay, so
custom themes. Now, what if you want to
cycle among themes, you know, like
sometimes you prefer the Manoch dark and
sometimes you prefer, let's say,
Mysterioso.
You want a command to switch between
them.
That's what we have here. So, sa cycle
theme. Okay, so that's space space Q.
So, do it.
So, I got the skin uh
theme. Right now, it's deep deeper blue.
Okay.
Space space Q.
Now, it's Adwaita, the turtle.
Space space Q. Now, it's dichromacy.
Space space Q. Now, back to deeper blue.
Fantastic.
Okay, that is the command.
And where can you get the command? You
can get it right here on xardi.info.
Just copy it and you have it. Okay? And
there's an old command that toggle theme
that just toggle between deeper blue and
no theme. But I don't I don't, you know,
I wrote this sa cycle theme today so
that supplants that
displaced that replaced this toggle
theme. Now, what's the proper word that
um
There is I think there I I thought there
is a proper word. So, let's switch to um
a bright theme because the dark theme is
sucks. The only good use of dark theme
is when
when it's at night and there is no light
in the room. So, everything is dark
because your girlfriend is sleeping in
the same room.
You don't want You don't want the shiny
screen, you know, shine you know,
lights up the whole room. That is the
only situation
you should use dark theme.
You know, this is a sensitive topic
because every time I say it, you know,
there's a lot of nerds will say, "Oh,
no, but I like dark theme." That's not
good, okay? Hurts your eyes. Trust me.
And I have 1,000 articles. Just search
for
1,000 1,000 articles.
Go to casouri.info.
Search
theme. So, you can see Emacs cycle color
theme, Emacs how to create your own
theme, Emacs in it set color theme. If
you want Emacs to start with some theme.
And the color theme gallery, this is all
the themes you have in Emacs.
Uh you know,
so I created a list, okay? So, go back.
Then you have CSS dark theme. How do you
do that? You cascading style sheet,
okay? Go back. You have is dark theme
good for your eyes? The answer is no.
Why? Because of science. And here's
reasons you can read about them. So,
casouri.info,
search and you know, search for the word
theme and you'll find all these
articles.
And PowerShell PowerShell toggle dark
theme.
That's a PowerShell command
I wrote, so you can Let's demo again.
Shift control scroll up. Wait. Shift
control scroll up. Shift control Wait.
Why didn't it scroll up?
Oh, no, it controls it controls
transparency.
What?
Let's see, shift O, okay.
Amazing, I learned a new thing. So,
shift control scroll
controls the Windows terminal's
transparency, okay?
Interesting.
By the way, transparency is another
another thing that's dramatic and it's
okay? You don't want anything to
be transparent, like turn it off
completely. Like it's this this is the
themes and the transparency is one of
the Linux idiots thing. They love it,
you know, they they are they are, you
know, custom settings
is the worst.
Impractical, okay? So, if you are here,
say hi, okay?
Wait. Let me double check. Am I like
alive and talking?
Do you want to
uh allow app to change your device? What
the
Why why do I get that?
Uncertain, no.
Okay.
Hi, you are alive. Hello ACP. Good to
see you.
So, back to the PowerShell. So, what are
we demonstrating? We were the Oh, yeah.
So, toggle PowerShell saw toggle.dark
theme.
So, you press that and every your
browser, your window, your system become
dark, okay? Do it again.
And go it go back. Now, some people
argue, you know, they love dark theme.
Why is it no good? Because one one of
the easy way you can tell is that when
you are watching other people's live
stream,
if I'm on if if I'm on dark theme, then
you'll find it right now, everything
becomes harder to read, okay?
You see, you you can you can you know,
you can check yourself. You see, you can
look at the window. Now, I switch to um
let's go back here.
Okay. Now, toggle white theme.
You know, so you can determine right now
which one is easier easier to see.
Okay.
So, let's go back to white. Okay. So,
close that uh we didn't close that yet.
Okay. So, that's PowerShell dark theme
and let's go back. So, this there's a
articles on dark theme. Okay. Anyway,
I just tell you it's no good. The only
situation you want to use it is when
your room
is completely dark. Someone is sleeping.
Okay.
Now, let's next command. Cycle hyphen
low line space. Okay. So, let's say
uh what is this page? Uh
some talk show can uh
What?
What is this page? So, if you uh
creating a new file,
for example, new file, you want to save
it. And what is this page?
And you can press a key
to have them using hyphen. Can you see
that? Press a key, then it become low
lines. You see at the bottom.
Press a key, it's all space again. Press
a key, hyphen. Press a key, low line.
Okay, cancel.
And you can do it here. Let's magnify.
By the way, the command I'm calling is
um can you see that?
Text scale adjust. Okay. So, you can
magnify. So,
So,
So, that is the
my current line. Press a key, hyphen.
Press a key, underscore. Press a key,
space.
Now, what if
press this
some
You know, what if you have uh
a line like that and your cursor is
here,
you can press a key, then only between
those quotes that get changed. Press the
key, low line, press the key, space.
See? Fantastic, wonderful command. Where
can you find it?
You can find it. This is cycle cycle
hyphen low line space and it's part of
soft light keys. Soft light keys is
free. You can find it. Just search with
the the name. And here's a URL. Open it.
Show in browser. So, you can grab the
code.
Okay?
Grab the code. You can have it.
So, close close. Okay, so that's demo of
the um cycle hyphen. Okay, so now let's
go back to soft talk show.
Uh so, we demonstrated that command.
Now, there is another command.
Uh
cycle
fonts. Wait. Okay, so anyway, so let's
go to the next. So,
change default font size by command.
Okay? So, let's see. So, where is my
other Emacs? So, my other Emacs is
here. Okay, we got this
dark theme going on.
So,
wait, did we demonstrate the cycle
theme? Yes, let's let's do uh
cycle
theme.
Okay?
Uh
I don't want deep blue blue. Let's do it
again. Fantastic. Okay? Now, this page
is not updated, so close it and call
customer customize theme again, so you
can see now it updates.
So, cycle cycle theme psycho color
themes
psycho hyphen low low line space, then
change default font size. You can grab
the code here. So, what does it do? So,
uh
Press press press. That's a change, you
know, that I have the key set. So, set
default font size. So, now I can say
uh let's say 30. Jeez, that's big.
Okay? And this will happen to all your
windows and frames, okay? Now,
Now, let's do it again. X set default
font size, okay? And now, let's say 18.
Now, it's normal. Now, if I'm not doing
live stream, usually this is the size I
go by.
But,
if you are doing live stream, remember
your size needs to be like almost two
times larger, otherwise people cannot
see it. So, let's do it again. Set
default font size 23. Good. Okay, let's
set default font size let's this time
30.
The bigger the font, then you can start
to see the beauty of the font of the
words. You can see.
Okay? Cancel. Now, next command.
Next command
uh X did you know that your chat is
quite delayed? I know that live stream
is normally lag behind the live chat,
but I think you might have slow mod.
Uh yes, something like that, you know,
it's something like that, you know, on
the YouTube.
I usually don't bother, you know, I you
I just use whatever default, but on
YouTube
um
like there there is a like
there's a there's a choice, but um
but I only have few, you know, few
people interact, so
So, anyway, so let's go to the next
item. And we And that's it for today.
So, today is pretty short. So, next one,
so you have set default font size.
Fantastic. Now, we can have also cycle
the font.
Okay? So, let's see.
X saw cycle font.
Do it.
Oh, Lucida Console 10.
You know, font is tied to the size. So,
let's cycle font again.
Current font is Cascadia Mono.
Cycle font again. Courier 10. Okay, but
now you cannot see it. So, let's go to
the command.
Uh and let's change it, okay? So,
describe function X saw cycle. Let's
magnify it first, okay?
Uh
X saw
set default font size. Let's say 30,
okay? Now,
Now,
describe function X saw cycle font.
Okay, go to it. Documentation, jump to
it. Open source code. Expand the window.
So, there it is.
Uh and
but you can set what kind of size you
want. So, let's change it here, okay?
Actually, let's copy this. Copy it. New.
Paste. Make it
X saw Emacs smart, okay?
Now,
let's put it here and prettify, so they
are closer to the left. Now, let's say
uh Courier 20, okay? Lucida Console 20.
Cascadia Mono 20. I'm not sure the
syntax is correct. Let's try it. Okay.
Now, eval the buffer. Now, Emacs know
it.
Now,
try it again.
X cycle font. Do it.
Uh Lucidia 10.
What?
Why did it not uh okay, so let's try
again. Okay, so let's
I thought I said it. So, oh.
Because this file is not saved. So, when
I run,
you know, the eval buffer, it does I
mean
it did Anyway, anyway, so let me run it
now. Okay, now it's run.
Now,
X cycle font.
It What?
Why is it that uh become smaller again?
Oh, uh Cascadia Mono 20. Okay, so now
evaluate this. Okay. Now, X cycle font.
Courier 20. Okay.
Do it again.
Lucidia Console 20. Do it again.
Uh Cascadia Mono 20. So, this let's make
it 25. Okay.
Let's Let's make them all
Uh let's make them all 25.
Now,
Okay, fantastic. Now, eval last sex.
Now, it's done. Now, let's set a key to
that X cycle font. So,
uh not kill buffer, uh
key map key map set.
Key map global set. That's what I want.
And what key do you want? Let's say
uh do we have F F6 is undefined, so
let's just use F6, okay? So, make it a
string
and F6. And what command do you want?
You want
counsel cycle font, okay? So, copy that
and
there, okay? Fantastic. Now, eval that
and eval that. Now, we can just press F6
to change the font. Now, let's see.
Do it.
Oh, wait.
Uh Courier 25, do it.
Lucida Console 25, do it.
Cascadia Mono 25, let's try it again.
Courier 20 Courier 25.
So, Courier needs to be like 30,
okay? Let's run it again.
Run.
Now, do it.
Cascadia Mono.
Courier 30.
Uh Courier needs to be 35.
Okay.
Lucida Lucida Console, okay?
Let's go to the top.
Courier 35.
Lucida Console.
Cascadia Mono, okay? Fantastic. Now, you
see Courier is like so small. Let's make
Courier like 40, actually.
Um do it. Go to the top. Now,
Cascadia Mono.
Uh font is not available. Courier 40.
What?
What about 36?
Courier 36.
Okay. Anyway.
So, that's the commands.
Cycle fonts by command. Okay? I think
that's it for today.
Is it good? Do you like it?
Does your function change the default
size for each existing buffer, too? No.
It is designed to just for the session.
Now, if you want to set in in a init
file, it's very easy to do. For example,
let's go to font. Okay? Go to one of the
cycle fonts by command. Scroll down.
Then you got a list of articles of
everything you want to know about font.
Okay? So, change font size, change
default Okay, change font size. Every
time you see this script emoji, that
means it's my custom command. Okay? So,
you can change font size on you how to
do it. And then you know, you have
several ways. You can use the menu. For
example, I go here.
Uh you you know, go to the
uh what is it? Options.
Options, then
you know, like nobody use
the graphical menu. Set default font.
Then you got you got this box. Then you
can pick. Okay? Then if you do this,
that will be saved to your init file.
But I But you know, you can just read my
article. I'll tell you the best way to
you know, which to which way to use. So.
Anyway, so change font size, then you
can get get character info. For example,
you want to know
what font am I currently using? You want
to know, you know, because maybe you are
on a Mac, on a Linux, on a new machine,
on your friend's machine, you don't
know. So, you can
put the cursor on any character.
Uh let's first of all, let's make it be
changing, okay? So, put the cursor on
any character, then call
describe-char.
Then this window pops up. You see, it
tells you the position. You are at
position 41. And the character is M, and
blah blah blah, category script Latin,
because this language this writing
system is Latin. That's why it's That's
what this script means. Then you got
syntax, that's Emacs syntax table, then
you got category, that's from Unicode.
You know, Unicode put each character
category uh
character into certain categories. Wait,
I believe that is this category of
Unicode or category of Emacs display? I
don't know. I rarely use that. To input
that character, type CX8 return 60.
You know. So, anyway, so that you got
the buffer code, that's a file encoding
that we are using UTF-8. Then finally,
you you can see this line, display by
this font. So, it's saying that right
now you are using
Half Spurs, one of the Linux technology.
All right, Lucida Console regular normal
normal mono 47 something something.
Okay? So, that's how you
can tell what exactly your the font you
are using. For example, let's go to this
Emacs. So, describe- char.
And
in this So, in this
window, I'm using Consolas, which is the
best which is the Windows default.
But here, it's Lucida Console.
Okay? I type so much I have hand pain
again. So, I think that's it for today.
So, uh
okay, so you were asking so this this is
called describe char, very fantastic
useful function, okay?
Uh then you can uh set font size, you
know, the everything about input methods
and Unicode.
Then here is back to font. How do you
toggle proportional font? That's another
topic.
Then you go to Unicode font for
programmer. How do you like you should
like all this you need to have the font
to begin with. So,
you know, I tell you which one is the
best, uh especially if you have a lot of
math symbols or technical symbols, like
Greek or set, subset, element of,
uh for all, not,
and
not
exist
implies
because, therefore, end of proof, you
know, summation, product, integral, um
partial derivative, you know, and uh
heart suits, playing cards suits,
uh and uh
you know, uh
stopwatch,
timer, you know, these user interface
symbols, cut and for the clipboard,
wheelchair, and the cultural symbols.
So,
to display that, you need a font. So, on
this page I tell you what are the best
fonts, okay?
Then then go down go down go down go
down find everything about font, cycle
font by command we demonstrated, and
there it is, Emacs init set up font.
So, click on that.
There's everything you want to know
about setting up fonts, so including one
of the ways via the
graphical user interface, which we
demonstrated before. So, if you call
that the
silver or you can do it manually, okay?
Just like that. Put this in your init
file.
Okay, so and there's quite a few more
things about font. Let's see, font for
yeah, Unicode symbols,
setting up and font for emoji, setting
up
If you don't do that, then every time
you open file that contains emoji, it
will take sometimes you kind of slow or
it does doesn't use the the font you
want. Okay, because they are different
There are so many There are quite a few
different fonts for emoji.
So, when you have several fonts for
emoji in Emacs, when you have a emoji,
which font does it use? That depends,
but you can specifically set it like
like here, okay?
Uh and there's a quite a lot more
articles, but okay, that's it.
Hello Hello farewell.
Fart whale Fart whale says, "Hello Mr.
Lee, new to Emacs and I've been loving
your content. Love the good mix of
topics in your live stream. Thank you."
Mwah.
You know, the online the online girls,
they are like
doing that all the time.
Girls thing.
So, that's it. If you guys like my
stuff, you need to donate, of course,
okay? Go to like my Xah Lee website,
xahlee.info.
Go all the way to the bottom. There are
7,000 articles for you to enjoy and you
can Patreon me a month, $10 something or
pay me 100 bucks if you work
in a professional job, Okay? PayPal me
Amazon gift card.
That's it.
Bye, guys.
Hello, Hank.
Hello, ACP.
That's good. Let's see. We talked for
how long?
Uh
Let me see about support soon.
Uh yeah, so let's see how long have we
been talking. Let's stop stream, okay?
32 33 minutes, okay?