good morning guys welcome to another
episode of sun talk show
fantastic we got a lot to do
so
today the main thing is going to be emac
this coding so check my live so video
check audio check uh good i'm good to go
so
the main thing today is gonna be emac
this coding so i'm going to code emaclis
and i'm going to give you a tutorial
you know as i go so those of you emacs
users
this is a good time
to ask you ask me questions and if you
want to learn lisp this is a good day
okay so
uh so i'm going to start to do it but
before we do anything the first 10
minutes let me show you
a website dark theme
many of you requested dark themes so now
my website you can see dark theme
okay so you can see
there are several articles you know the
you know dark theme uh
quite novel you know a novelty so if you
for example in on windows if your system
is
set to light then you got the light
theme
you know but if your system is set to um
set to dark
then the website automatically becomes
dark okay that's css magic let me show
you the magic css magic okay so you open
that so this is the line you want okay
so
this is the
line so
there is a new css
function or whatever property you call
it so prefer color theme doc
okay if that's
true then you want to set body
background color uh
you know background color black and
color white text color white
then you need to also change the link
color because otherwise it's blue which
is doesn't work with a
dark dark background it's you cannot see
it
so css magic okay talking about css
magic if you don't know web dev you can
learn from the ground up
in the most efficient way the css
introduction to css just search for xr
css
xrd css you'll find my tutorial okay
introduction to css fantastic dark theme
okay and okay so now so that's about css
so
let's copy that close that go to talk
show today
show in browser and we are going to
cover several other things let me go one
by one and we are going to code emac
list okay
uh dark theme so
dark theme visual css we already have it
so today's topics we talked about dark
theme so and
you know there are several problems i
need to fix okay so for example let me
show you so you know every two or three
hours i stand up and walk around
like this
hold on a second
so this is the surface tablet so you can
see and every few hours i walk around
back and forth like this
and this is the surface pen and i take
notes okay
to prevent ass rot
so this is
this is analogous to
to you using uh those of you using let
me show you my keyboard blog okay
because our keyboard blog
and you can see one of our friend
has bought a standing desk
so if you don't have standing desk you
can do walk around back and forth you
know with a tablet
tablet and do reading documentations
because you need to i need to read
documentation that's my obsession so
pop out chat so let's see what you guys
are saying okay
good morning
so if you have a question for me tag me
okay put my name to it
once you don't want pure background uh
you know i don't care about you know
when it comes to dark theme there's lots
of idiocies and fat in fact dark theme
is a fad okay it's not good for your
eyes in fact the
black text on white background is better
for your eyes
but for example you know before i did my
you know i i have lots of articles on
that but i'm not going to go into that
but you can see different you know
discord for example they choose uh you
know they don't want a pure black
background but i want pure black
background okay
so anyway so i'm so i walk around so one
of my friends get got the standing desk
you can you know go to my website and
buy it
and so i take notes so you see here are
the things i need to fix when i have a
dark theme so for example you go to so
first of all copy that
so on the pink window is all my emacs
command course
uh and keystrokes i'm using xr fly keys
and i'm using a vora keyboard so this is
ah i've got so many
uh basic things to go over so you can
see
so we talked about standing table and we
okay so
so you you go here then you can see my
keyboards okay so reviews kinesis
advantage 2 and ultimate hacking
keyboard on top that's that one
so i want to go over
you know i'm going all over the place i
don't if i don't follow a list or
something i get um
lost so let's let's talk about one thing
at a time so
so dark theme
css
standing deck desk and walk around
and i was going to say you see so these
are my notes right i take notes and i do
a screenshot then
i'm back here sitting on my power
station
then i
you know work on these things so for
example here are the things i you know
today's notes several things i did
uh i need to do
so for for example this one
let me show you some examples okay um
dutch so any of you are here to learn
lisp so if you are here to learn this
say it okay so we focus we get on to
writing the emac list tutorial
so there's a question from the german do
you have any tips tutorials regarding
implementing an emax major mod with
with a repo inferior lisp
no i don't have a tutorial for that for
example he's talking about uh let's go
to talk show page okay so show the pink
window and you can go drop into each
other so this lets you do
shell in
emac bisp and or you can go to the
standard shell
uh
you know so here is a standard shell
because i'm on windows so i don't have
the uh normally splash if you're on
linux so so you know he's talking about
how do you implement this kind of thing
the the
um
wait that's the issue yeah so how so
right now the second window is running
dos
uh and you can also learn in powershell
in fact
but i don't have the powershell
installed so how do you implement this
how do you write this i don't have a
tutorial for that okay
um yeah okay
of course i have a you know emac this
tutorial on writing a major mod
so those of you want to learn lisp begin
there
okay so
so so let's uh close each out close the
windows stars
kill it yes
and let's go back focus on the talk show
um i'm going to go over these things i
need to do i'm you know showing my
workflow
in emacs
so here is some of the typical problems
when you
have a dark theme for example the cg
svg clock doesn't look so nice and the
linux icon disappeared into the ether
you know in the pearl icon and the tcp
ip icon so if we go to the windows
uh settings and go to light theme now
you can see the svg clock
learn svg okay learn svg in one hour you
you'll know you'll learn how to write
this clock in javascript javascript so
and if you like my stuff okay all these
tutorials pay me
you know that's better than 1 000 thank
you
you know pay me paypal whatever uh or
uh google super super chat youtube
okay
so i'll buy my tutorials so let me uh
get back so you see so the svg clock
pearl icon linux icon
and if you go to dark theme they become
you know they disappear so there are
several
uh
lots of things you need to go over and
fix
and we are going to i'm going to fix
them some of them today okay so here's
my notes again
um
okay so let's do some fix the first
thing i want to fix is
the unicode okay so you go to start
website
then you go to the unicode
you go to emoji okay now you can change
you know you can use the emoji
font
or you can use the symbol font okay this
is not a good example let's go to
um
hands okay so emoji font
or
symbol font you see when you use symbol
font many of them become
disappears when you select it then you
can see you see
let's magnify okay so you can see the
full glory
so you need to fix that
so let's fix that okay copy the ui all
marker keys okay
switch to the last window then i mean
emax
show the ping window
open the link from the
clipboard so right now you are looking
at this page
this is the source code for that page
now go to the top
now turn on global highline mod so you
can see where my cursor is okay now go
to the css split the window
enter to open it
so the to fix this problem so emoji font
symbol font you see
so when you use symbol font
the color
should be white text color should be
white
so for example you can see
so you can see when there's a dark theme
the color here
white
okay but however for some reason the it
doesn't affect the emoji text that's a
problem so let's search for emoji
background color transparent okay this
is not probably that's probably not that
that's probably the problem
okay let's comment it out
refresh
oh okay that's why now
change to emoji change it to symbol now
it works
okay the reason it looks yellow is
because my unicode is marked up
using the mark
tag you can see there
and by default the mark tag
tag has a yellow background
so
so that is why you have to
okay so let's say background color white
okay
refresh
okay i'm not sure
okay now when you say you know
this doesn't look so good
uh so this is a css i need to fix
andre
cabrella thank you so much
thank you so if you have a question you
know that's a dedicated
payment for the question if you have a
question ask me okay
uh
yeah okay so
now we need to fix this problem i'm kind
of you know this is a issue that
i'm wondering if i should go through it
because or should we just start to code
emac this because today we are supposed
to do emac this
uh this problem is actually
a bit nasty
and probably not interesting to most
people about css
so how do you so how do you fix that so
if if we make the background white that
doesn't look so well because you know
you don't want this kind of thing happen
so
but if the
if the background you know if the theme
is light then that works fine
let's shrink uh
yeah it doesn't even i mean i don't want
that effect you see
can you see that
um
so
you know if it was transparent so when
it's transparent watch these okay
watch this
now if you refresh now that's better
transparent
now
however when it's transparent and it and
if you make it dark theme
so this is background color transparent
okay
and
make it dark theme
then you use the symbols font okay let's
go here symbols font so
when it's symbols font
it
it it sets the font to symbol font but
however why is the text not becoming
white
that's a problem because that's the
issue because for example if you go to
the top
you can see i mean
color white is the default
i mean color black is the default
okay color black is the default
but
color black is a default but if you go
to
but if we have a dark theme
then the color is white however it's not
it's not
effective
you know i think maybe i know why so
let's go back to the
okay let's go back to the emoji page
so showing browser here's the emoji page
search for javascript
so
the javascript that changes the font
when you click on that
is this javascript okay
this javascript
and you are looking at typescript
actually typescript is basically a
superset of javascript
so any javascript is also typescript
so we are looking at the javascript
typescript code
and we are looking at for example okay
let me show you okay some some some
tutorial about javascript and webdav so
okay so you can see
here
here is a button you see
it's a radio button
that
so this is the button id kind of unicode
font change 27
uh so search for that
okay go to the javascript
source code
search for that there it is you you find
several references
and here we set the event so that when
people click on it it does something
and
query select all change font okay so
here
is the function that actually
changes
so
what we want to check is whether it
changes any color in this source code
so let's search for color to see if
anything
there it is okay
[Music]
pop-up
style color dark red okay
that we don't want to change
and uh
background color silver that's fine
and set attribute new nonset attribute
style color dot green
what is that
function show info
function show info okay
uh where does the dark dark green come
from what is the show info hiding from
info oh
that's when you click on this show
character info that's the dark green so
for example let's go to food
you click on show character info
then it shows the
the unicode name and the unicode
code point id for the character
this is convenient feature so that
because it it lets you see the
everything and be able to search for
them
because otherwise you have to hoover
through each one so that's the show info
and green is fine okay so
so now
okay so toggle show info that's fine so
color dark green so
so no color is changed in this
file okay
so the problem is probably not caused by
this file so let's go back here
symbol
so
so let's go back to the css page
you know one easy way
one easy way to fix this let's just
this is getting boring so let's just fix
this quickly so unicode emoji so when
there is a dark theme you want the
background color to be black
and you want the color to be white
refresh
okay
i'm not going to do anything about this
let's
continue okay so consider that fixed
kind of
okay
copy it to my other sides
okay so next let's see what to do next
copy that
go to talk show
today's talk show
show in browser d that showing browser
close close close
okay
so here's some things we need to fix
and
there's more to fix
but that's that's it about that let's
get on to the next
topic
okay so i want to show you some
some uh recent
happenings with my keyboard okay so i
did a lot huge amount of work on
keyboard layout international keyboard
layout for example you have the canadian
layout canadian multi-lingual layout
then you have
german layout
and you have french layout french you
know french actually have several layout
and they recently in the past two years
that's the french government began a new
layout for french
you know so what i want to say is that
after you study all these layouts you
find that
there's a spanish spanish layout there's
a spanish layout for latin america like
mexico
uh argentina
and there's a spanish spanish layout for
spain in europe
they are different
you see but after you study all this
layout and especially uh for example
canadian french so french layout you
know so you have the french layout for
french people in france
then you have a
canadian french layout
you know for for the eastern part of
canadian quebec
then that's not enough then you have a
get back french canadian layout they are
they are different by a little bit they
are and and they are all inefficient
they are the most inefficient then they
are you know they are
the worst possible you know so after you
study you look at all the
international layouts you find that most
of them are just crap
and there's so many you know there's
there's fujikis there's
you know us international finnish
multilingual
dutch
belgium they speak the same language you
know just like you know the
but
and you might say oh well maybe because
they are you know
even though it's the same language but
their habit is different or something
not really you know so so this
okay so you see that's a thing i need to
fix
i uh with the dark layout so this is svg
right no this is png
okay so apparently this this png is
using a transparent background so that's
why
yeah so you see so lots of little things
you need to fix when you do the
dark theme kind of thing so anyway you
know esther estonian icelandic italian
you know icelandic for example their
language is like northern europe you
know like
the whole thing is crap you know the
keyboard layout is is just crap the
international you know each one of them
sucks donkey ass to the extreme to the
extreme
and and and besides that they they
create so many variations each one of
them is like useless idiotic
not even cons considering efficiency
uh reasons for example efficiency
meaning like borax you know you know
about work quality work comac i mean not
even consid considering efficiency all
those international layout they are just
idiotic extreme
same language then you have several
layouts then different region you know
maybe they have a special layout
and they don't improve anything at all
just because they just you know have a
layout just because they it's it's
theirs you know it's
individualistic
so okay let's that's enough about the
dark thing let's turn them back to the
light theme so we can proper properly
see
the things okay so
so yeah so that's the issue about
international layout so i have an
article specific you know dedicated to
that that's this one idiocy of keyboard
layouts quad z and other t and so on
you know that's what i found and the
issue is very complex different language
and sometimes you have you know
especially in europe you have several
countries but they speak the same
language
you know but but then um
so which layout should they use you know
very complex and they and
the most commonly used layouts
throughout these countries are just most
idiotic
and
and this also happened to the japanese
layout too you know japanese is
another totally different story because
you know the writing system you cannot
simply type it you have to use a input
system
so two days ago a few days ago i did a
talk show on how to input chinese
all the related things you you want to
know about chinese input methods okay
and
but anyway let's go back to japanese so
japanese input methods
so japanese you have the first of all
you need to learn about the input method
before you do that you need to learn
about the japanese writing system
because otherwise you are lost you don't
know what's going on so you need to be
somewhat familiar with the japanese info
inputs
the japanese language the japanese
writing system a little bit then you can
study
the japanese
input method like how how do you type
this kind of their writing system then
okay once you know this then you get you
get into the
the the the many varieties of japanese
keyboard layout
because once you have an input system
then you have different keyboard layout
you know they have different uh
they have actually different inputs uh
methods for japanese so that's
interesting but you know so get back to
my point is that the most popular
like if you just go to japan and the
most popular keyboard layout is
basically just the usa keyboard okay and
they use a input system the most popular
one of the you know among the other
different japanese input systems one of
them is most popular used by 99.9
percent of people
and that input method for japanese is
the most idiotic inefficient one
okay
so
this layout is happens you know
very interesting
you know there are many
efficient japanese input systems
but but very few use them you know nerds
typically yeah nerds like us you know
use them but most
people don't
so
that's interesting and this just like
the u.s situation you know the quality
most people use quality input system
right you know you know about quality
most people use quality which is very
one of the most inefficient system okay
so i think let's go back let's start to
code emac
shall we
okay so let's
so let's um
so yeah so recently you know in the past
few days i
spent a lot of time working on this
different
uh international input system it's it's
a very huge topic okay let me tell you
let me tell you the story how did i
start to do this
you know about 10 years ago i began to
write um
you know i i began to have a page
listing the different you know countries
keyboard layouts why
partly because of curiosity okay let me
show you
this article
so in in 2009 i began to do it you know
part of the reason is just curiosity
because back then i was i was doing the
ergo e-max project you know the ergo
e-max project
the ergo emax project
and uh
you know ergo e max you know which is an
efficient key binding system for emacs
so this
this this begins in 2007
okay
so around 2009 i started you know once
you do this you you're running into like
people will ask you people from
different countries or maybe you should
change this to something because they
their keyboard doesn't have that key
something like that so you started to
hear about international keyboards you
know like you know iceland italia you
know you start to know about them but i
have no idea what what's out there you
know i just know english i'm american
so
so um
so so you started to so i started to
look you know what what keyboard layouts
other countries use then then i started
to
see
they they suck donkey ass you know they
are so idiotic to the extreme
but there are many issues okay so so
first of all so you you started to you
know get a list of the different
countries keyboard layout that's one
thing
then in order to study efficiency let's
let's go to french okay
so for example here's french
now if you want to know some ideas so
i some idea about the efficiency of the
french layout what you need to know is
that what extra
um alphabet
they you know french language use that's
not in english
so for example let's go to german okay
so in german
in german you have these
these
four extra characters you know a oou
with a omelet you know how you call that
you know so those are called
you know i have a let me show you yeah
so let me just keep talking about this
let me explain the full glory so
so first of all you need to know about
that key you need to know about compose
key you need to know about old graph key
then you need to learn about that key
okay there's the example of that key
uh that key
that keys you know uh
do i have an actual physical keyboard
that shows that key yeah there is uh for
example this this for example this key
right here that's that key if you press
it it doesn't do anything
for example you press this key
it does nothing but
the next key you press
will become
that letter with the hat you know so
that's what that keys are so you need to
learn about that key
you need to learn about
old graph key you need to learn about
compose keys so this article explain
them in detail okay
then after that
if you want to know the efficiency of
french or germany layout then you have
to
learn
what extra characters those languages
contain
you know not in english not in latin
alphabet
so in the case of german you have these
um
you have these characters okay what are
the what what are the names of those
those are called
diacritic marks okay diacritic marks
look at this page diagratic marks each
one has a name so you have a cute accent
you have grave accent you have a this
hat is called circumflex and this
and this there's a two there are two
names for that that's a
diuresis or omelet okay so
german
language uses those okay
then you have cedella you have
uh
micron and others okay macron brave
brave and karen and tioda and tioda is
used in spanish and and you know you
started to get in to get into
linguistics
the orthography
of writing systems you know you have to
because you know
i was just unassuming doing a list of
you know firing country keyboards then
you have to start it to gradually know
these things
so and
it gets steep because for example these
are accent marks right but not the tioda
okay so the spanish
nino nino nina nina you know
that that means children
boys or girls you know
that character is not a accent that
that's part of the alphabet okay that's
one of the letter in spanish
so it's this is not a
diacritic this is a letter by itself
okay so
you know it's very interesting so
linguistics then
in a german case for example then you
have this character you know then you
dive into the so it's not just
linguistics but the history of the
german writing system that's where you
have to get dive into the history of the
german writing system but so apparently
this character
is it
or
chef chefs i don't know how to say them
sharp ex
you know this complex history so it's so
and in fact it turns out there's no
universal agreement among the german
people about what whether you should
have that or not have that you know
there's a like uncertain status
for example the capital you know capital
version of this letter
is basically never used so like only in
recent years like in the past decade
i believe you know you can read
wikipedia only in the past decade they
german government or something they
started to say oh actually we do need a
capital version of this data things like
that so it's
so very complex so you dive into
linguistics orthography and even the
history of it
then
if you want to access whether this
layout is efficient or not then you have
to have a statistics of the german
language you know just how just how
you know how often how often are these
characters used it turns out they are
not used much okay in the case of german
and but in french
you know
in french in uh french french language
language for example the
acute e this one is very
is free it is fairly frequently used for
example let's go to
let's go to uh french letter frequency
you know you know i started to study a
little bit these
oh actually
so you know actually the
acute e where is it here okay it's
actually not that much
used neither
so you started to you know so you need
to know the
letter frequency of each of these
languages that's what you started to get
into
okay
then it's um
then what else uh
german language yeah then statistics of
the letter frequency
then
very interesting okay so that's you know
that
then
then if you want to you know then i
started to look into the history for
example you know for the french keyboard
i know that they use um where is it okay
french
french keyboard you know there are
several versions there's a french asset
used in france there is you know
canadian french layout used in canada
then there's a quebec french then
there's a canadian multilingual layout
you know it's like
so many choices for nothing for
idiotically you know for nothing
canadian multi-lingual layout
that is for canadian who wants to type
french
english and french but
and and
and possibly other languages you know
so when you study this then you start to
know so you have to know for example so
what what exactly is the difference
of the french language between
the
people in france and people in quebec
for example you have to know because
otherwise you cannot judge you know
whether
it's justified to have a different
version of layout
so but basically i find that it's just
not necessary it's more just of a
history kind of thing then i started to
dig into so
so who
which
created the asset you know first of all
you have ascertained right which they
as a t layout basically they swap three
pairs of keys from croti
okay so
where do i say that okay let me see if i
can
french assetty so
i explained somewhere i forgot where
okay okay i know i remember where so
here okay
uh
yeah so one of the thing i learned is
that you know there's a chord z
layout and as a answer t so first thing
you might be wondering so why do they
quote z for example they swap
z and y
they swap these two letters so you
wonder why do they do that then you know
then you have to find out which language
uses this chord z layout
and basically my conclusion is that
there's like no
no good reason it's just
idiotic similarly for the azerty okay as
a tea this is not really good reason
you know if they
yeah so
that's interesting you know so
many of the interesting details
okay so uh let's what else let's go
let's go to
i already talked for 30 minutes let's
talk about let's do emacs then let's
start to do emacs
okay so let's go to talk show today's
talk show let's see if there's anything
i want to talk about so i did a new page
for windows logo key so this page is all
shortcuts involving the windows logo key
uh then
okay so for those of you using emacs
thanks to my friends you guys on saw
discord
uh who is this guy so
go to emacs
info i think info so he told me
you know so there's a
running emacs on android let's have the
glory look emacs in
android okay
so where do you download that so so what
you do is you so i updated
my page
uh you download
this
these um android operating system so you
download these turmerics
okay
then it's kind of a package
manager for android os so once you
download termix then you can install top
and all the unix stuff theme emacs and
stuff
okay so that's a tip for you emacs users
thanks to info okay so
what's the next thing what what else
okay so there's this keyboard from japan
from japan keyboard meet up a few years
ago you know this is
not a practical keyboard
uh
but it's interesting so
okay so anyway i let let's do emac this
okay so let's start
so what i want to do today is to write
the emac list code so let's do it
quickly i hope i can finish this in
in 20 minutes okay
write a emac so in fact it's in the talk
show
title okay
so
emacs list live coding so you want to
call this key so call this command so
let me show you what that command do so
for example i write a lot um
and where is it
let's clean up it this a little bit so
join
remove the white space okay
then
put that there put that there show in
browser so here are the things we talked
about and
we want to
code emac this yeah so
yeah so
so for example i write lots of tons of
pages about
keyboard shortcuts
so for example if you look at the source
code for this page let's open it
it looks like that okay so for example
let's go to the top
so you can see this one window tab
correspond to there you see
so but how do you so it's very tedious
so you know for example i want if i want
the windows for example this
this windows key for example i can
i can either do
is actually it's hard to do for example
window okay i'm using
html mod okay let me show you
here's a source code for html mod 4 000
lines almost 5 000 here's the top and
here's a home page you go to the page
showing browser
i did a video on that so if you like it
supported me support me okay buy it this
is one of the most complex
major mod i've done i've you know i have
so quite a few but this is one of the
most complex
lots of features
you are looking at me using it every day
you know right my 10 000 pages html
10 000 articles in 20 years
so
okay so let's copy that so go to okay so
wait copy
talk show
go to this talk show
okay so
make a link there so we have it
html mod then
i'm going to talk about
so for example the windows page how do
you
create that markup so in html mod you
press tab
then k
for key kbd
mark
uh tag okay so you got the key oh wait
let's do it again what
kbd
okay only it does only one character
okay that's idiotic undo you want to
select the word
tab
k
enter so you now you got that now
wrap a p tag around it
showing browser so you got now you got
the windows key
okay so how do you do that so but you
don't have this symbol so
so it's tedious it's fairly tedious so
what i do so i have a command so i just
say window okay then i call the command
watch the pink window you'll see my
command name and keystroke okay press
press
okay
so you got that okay i should have so
actually what i should do is type w-i-n
okay
press press so you got that
that's how you got that
so that command is this one
html keyboard shortcut markup
okay
so what if i want tab so tab
uh tab press two keys you gotta tab what
what about command cmd
press it you got a command okay so let's
um
clean this up
show in browser so you can see that's
what we added
but what if you want the window plus tab
you know for example windows tab windows
tab do does does this
kind of idiotic you know the window gui
is one of the worst because every time
you do that for example usually it's alt
tab okay
you see all tab is instantaneous okay
it's a bit digression or tap right but
what if you want it if you release the
old it goes away but what if you want it
to stay so you do
old control
tab okay then it stays there you see
then you can use arrows or whatever
okay this is this is good okay this is
better than old tab
anyway that that's another topic so but
however
since windows
vista or something that you have
window tab you know hold on window tab
so
it tries to emulate the mac basically so
you got this uh cancel do it again but
however it's extremely annoying like
every you know when mac does something
innovation it's fantastic it just works
but when windows tries to do it it sucks
donkey ass because every time you press
window tab
you see that you see the title take a
second to pop up very frustrating when
you actually work on you know computer
for several hours a day
it takes a second you know for the
titles to pop up then all the things
adjusted a bit so it's like
it your eyes
you know let's but
old control tab doesn't happen it's
instantaneous you know that's what you
want you want instantaneous
you know on a mac you also have this
animation but it just works it's just
it's beautiful and it works fine but on
windows
you know so all tab alt control tab it
works okay instantaneous and no no like
moving a little bit after you do it
but now but now windows tries to make it
you know
fancy window tab
animation then you have to wait a little
bit for them to adjust and then the
title pops up window idiocy
okay linux is worse by the way every
time i flame windows i have to add linux
is more far more worse because the
linux idiots
you can even install it
without spending a few months studying
you know computer science stuff
so anyway so the task the problem now is
that so there's this command i can
help me add this um
you know html stuff
but over the years i made a lot of
changes and now that command doesn't
work so well for example
windows tab okay
so i can do it in several ways w
dash
and you have
so w is agree for width for me so
i don't want with okay
w dash
tab okay
call the command
now you see the tab character is not
doesn't have the keyboard markup so
that's actually not good
but however let's say
w
dash t for example call the command
yeah it doesn't work so well so it's
quite tedious to write this so what i
want to do is fix it okay so for example
so let's call let's show the source code
of that command
describe key press the key
then you can see the short
source code so tab jump to it here's the
source code
so this code began
like 10 years ago but i don't have the
beginning version date this code began
10 years ago it went through every um
you know because in the past year i did
a lot of changes to my html mods so
right now the this function is kind of
um
not so good
it wasn't so good in the first place so
what i want to do is to rewrite it
but i i think i'm not going to do it
today because we already talked one hour
about other things
um
[Music]
rsi pen right here right now
too much typing
okay i think that's it for today
anything else
sadena is the greatest letter making
people misspelling words as ever so
so i can talk let's talk five more
minutes on something so any questions
for me about emacs or stuff let's talk
about keyboards maybe
so you see all these tabs are the things
i need to do
um
you know or review my old articles like
1000 articles
um
so here is the wikipedia on keyboard
layout you know wikipedia has grown and
grown like
you don't even know it behind you after
10 years it has grown so much much more
information and detail about many things
i learned a lot from wikipedia of course
not just you know on keyboard layout or
math and lots of other things
so
here is interesting it's a chromebook
photo of chromebook
and why is it interesting because you
can see uh what is it um
is it the that key or something or the
oh oh this
i believe it's actually it's a
old graph so you can see the old graph
key there
uh
but what is this
okay um
so anyway so wikipedia powershell
powershell my tutorial on powerful show
if you haven't learned
it yet learn it okay it's a powershell
is fantastic
you can see that's
powershell
so you can see i want to for example
here is let's delete okay so let me show
you again so i'm in this file this file
is html mod source code i want to go to
diode i just press two keys drop me to
the diode and highlight the current file
html mod
and you see all those uh great ones
those are backup files press the key
to delete them delete them yes okay so
all these are my packages
and what do i want to do
why am i talking about that yeah i
wanted to yeah powershell okay so
i'm using soft light keys another one my
package is free on my website so i pre
you know if i want to
show this directory in powershell i
press a key
you know now i'm in powershell in this
directory
uh
and and if you are on linux of course it
goes to bash on the mac same thing it
goes to z shell
so powershell okay exit
so what else
that's it for today
okay that yeah that's it for today so
uh be on a tivo is a efficient layout
for poochie keys you know my website is
kind of the first one to
to talk about this it's a designed by
one of the guy um
you know but then his website went down
so
they actually they have a link to my
website now
uh this so this wikipedia article is in
puji keys pojiki's version
yeah so here is link to my site
uh what else
let's see
so here is the mozilla reference on
you know i was looking at this when i
was trying to do the
dark thing
okay one hour talk thank you guys for
watching that's it for today
and thank you andre
bye guys
so i'm shutting down in a minute
delete
delete windows logo key shortcut shrink
dd
in browser tv close
show in browser so this is today's talk
show
close
uh
refresh what is this site html mode
we already have it close that
close that
okay undo
you know let me show you what i want to
do with this so if you go to you know
the index do it yourself keyboard
and if you scroll down
scroll down
you can see
it's here
you know but however
this is
there's a better place
to
you know there's a better index page to
play to place this keyboard and that
would be
under the fun section so you go to fun
so
on this index page
it's a bunch of interesting other teas
weird keyboard and you know
many interesting things for example
backlit
uh
keys keypads you know for example this
is this one is a classic this is the
oldest
used to sell for like two thousand or
three thousand dollars
this you know this is the granddaddy
back in 2000 year 2000 okay
optimus olympus
but
it turned they turned out they
never practical but this you know was
the first backlit you know a keyboard
not backlit with a
screen on each key
so this front section
you know so we have all these kind of
weird um keyboard this this one is a
art craft
keyboard dedicated each one cost you 300
dollars or 400 dollars you know it's
crafted crafted by a guy
to emulate retro feel
about
more than 10 years ago but they still
he's still around
so many interesting things okay so
one of the section on this
fun keyboard section is the
thousands keys keyboard with a thousand
keys
you know so this is hyper seven this is
this this one is loved on reddit all the
time by the least people or similar
or something like that you know hyper
seven
one thousand keys so this one is got 213
keys
not not good okay i wouldn't say it's
good at all i wouldn't i wouldn't use it
and then you have this keyboard monster
using the motrons one hand one-handed
keyboard
two of them
then you have this
keyboard this keyboard the way you use
it it's for disabled person the way you
use this keyboard is supposed to be like
this
use your mouth you know
so
but then this guy a friend he put them
together you know he he you know this uh
a friend on twitter so so his twitter
account is
you can see it
david core okay
there
so so this section is just a bunch of
keyboard with a thousand keys and look
at this one you know
so he's got one two three four five
you know he's got the motron keyboard
then he's got you know a motron keyboard
has
126 keys 126.
plus he's got one two three four five
six six
strips of the x keys
strip each one has about 12 keys so he
got six of them you know
seven actually
one thousand k so so this one thousand
keys keyboard means you press one button
and your launch nukes everything you do
is just one button press okay
so this so there is this one
kanji keyboard
okay
these are real keyboards but then you
know one of them is the most idiotic
that is
posted all the time i i don't
i don't find it funny okay this one this
is april fool's joke
uh
google's april fools
joke from japan japan's google you know
they
they did this
you know so a lot of people like it and
it's continuously posted
every year
but it's you know it's not interesting
at all okay that's it bye
and she's the most beautiful girl you
know you may know or may not know her
and
i happens to know her and she's the most
beautiful girl in the world
dentist
then no taking system yeah so that about
that note-taking system
that's you know that unpronounceable
name
in fact one of our member here
he's part of the author involved with
that system okay he posts here often
um
this guy
okay so he
he works with that he's the author of
some packages about that and
and you can find his website you know so
he's also on twitter
yeah there it is so that's him so you
can on twitter on medium and he's got a
github he's uh you know
so you can find
you know interesting so
so if you have any questions about that
system notating system you can ask him
he's the he's the expert
of course he's also a e-max user he
lives in emacs
bye