good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sound talk show good morning
everyone welcome to another episode of
excel talk show today is 2021st April
April 9th and today I'm going to do a
emac emacs list coding okay so I'm gonna
go quick this is a sub talk show live
stream extempo
I just decided to do this so nobody is
here three people two people so I'm just
going to start to code okay so today's
problem let me show you what is the
problem I'm going to code it's so let's
go to my emacs blog so you can see
what is the problem we are I'm trying to
solve okay
so you can see over here
uh
uh let me let me show you some some okay
so here is the article emacs undo redo
Saga okay uh I wrote this uh 10 years
ago and updated recently I did a video
talk a few days ago so what I want to do
is to write a emacs command such that
let me show you okay for example here's
a link
okay then let's go to that page
emacs blog go to the top section so can
you see my screen okay and on the pink
window is uh or every command I call is
shown on the pink window on the left
okay move Cruiser right backward by Char
backward by Char down up or by the
paragraph you so so you can see all the
commands I call in emacs and the
corresponding keys I'm using stuff like
this and I'm using vorac keyboard so
those keys correspond to vorac keys
but you know you can notice there's no
control key because something like Keys
is a moto mod so let me let me talk
about what is the problem if you have
comments questions a little bit posted
it okay and donate okay patreon me
donate
okay so what is the problem the problem
is for example this uh wait so wait uh
go to my emacs blog section so you can
see over this page
you know it says this is a link Emax and
do Saga and corresponding corresponding
to uh this link in the browser
right so the problem is sometimes I want
to move a block of text that involves a
link into another page for example
for example if I move this for example
okay so if I copy that okay
copy that split the window now go to my
programming blog show in browser
you can see this is my programming blog
and they are in a different directory
okay so let me show you again so
programming blog emacs block you can see
they um you know they are in different
domains so this is my local file system
but they are in different directory
so if I copy these uh you know these
emacs and do redo section and I want to
copy it and I want to move you know
sometimes I want to
create a new section paste it here
now go go back to the browser now look
if I refresh it's gonna show up here
okay refresh you see it shows up there
but however if I click it
it won't work because you moved a
so why does it not work because we moved
a relative link from One Directory
location to another
so obviously the relative link no longer
work so what I want is actually
I want to be I mean automatically I want
to be able to copy a block of text and
paste it in some other HTML page
and have emacs automatically fix the you
know all the relative links all the
local links okay that is the
uh what we want to do okay let's write
it out okay so let's go uh let's wait
okay so let's go to talk show Page open
my emacs bookmark so here's today's talk
show page you can see
uh and let's write it down
yeah so well it's already there so
so you can see
here's what we want to do write a emacs
man to copy current text block
but change all local links to full path
okay so so I separate the job into two
steps
so that it's easier for me to Live code
it and show you something useful you can
learn so
one of the tasks is write the emacs
command to copy current text block
however when you copy it the local links
should become full path instead of a
relative link now the second problem is
uh write the Emax command to change all
local links that's full path to relative
link
so in this way
in this way if I have for example a okay
let's let's go to my emacs block in this
way if I copy
you know so in this way I can let me
show you what I want to do so I you know
so this text block
I want it to become let me show you okay
I want it to become that okay so let me
show you
so the first job that I'm going to do
now live code is that given any region
I want to copy it but for any local link
like that it should be changed to full
path okay relative path to full path
that's what I want to write okay let's
begin
uh
let's begin okay so so let's begin
coding it so let's go to my abreve this
is my this is my emacs um kind of my
emacs in it let's just create a file
here
and magnify
and let's say okay so save it as
let's give a name
some uh
copy change relative link
so this actually HTML copy relative link
okay that should be that should be the
command name okay I mean
um
yeah okay so copy that save it paste it
dot El okay
now close it reopen magnify
uh
cut Define function and string back back
D for defined function press enter
I'm using SAR emacs this mod okay
sidechain now copy change relative link
okay dark string
let's write the doc string so go back to
talk show page I'm gonna I'm gonna need
to try to code this fast good morning
Cherry Ramis hello first time on stream
cheers from Brazil hey
uh so wait what are we doing so this is
the first task okay and uh this is
probably
the only thing I'll be able to do today
I I need to go in an hour so 15 minutes
and we should be able to uh do this so
write a emacs command
so this command will
copy context block
of HTML
HTML but
but change all local links to full path
okay that's what we want
version I always give you a version for
my commands Okay let's begin to write it
so first task is let's see the first
text is um
uh the first task is first of all find
the beginning selection point and end
selection Point okay the beginning I
mean the beginning region and end region
so
let's just say region okay let's start
from simple okay
so
P1 P2 and let's not use the dollar sign
so because let's go with the traditional
way
P1 P2 position 1 position 2 set q p one
position one region beginning okay good
set qp2 region end okay so now
predify it we got a region P1 and P2 are
the beginning and end of the region okay
so that that is you know use the select
the region and and we can work on it
so the next step is
um
oh my God this is not going to be easy
uh
live coding is always uh you know always
because I need to do it fast and in real
time and I need to explain why my code
so the next step is to find all the
link location okay you find you know
basically you find all the occurrences
occurrences of href let's write it down
find occurrence of href
grab the
grab the relative link
if it is
if it is relative link let's shrink a
little bit
shrink so if it's relay if it is
relative link
uh
grab it and okay just say change
it to full path okay
then
okay change it to full path
repeat for all HF href values okay so we
are trying to find this such a relative
link repeat for all
href values
then
then we want to copy that to the
emacs qrim basically copy that
yeah
then
okay let's not let's forget let's make
it simple let's just say that okay
find occurrence of href then if it's
relative link change it to full path
repeat for or
href values okay let's begin that's the
algorithm
outline okay
so let's start coding so uh first of all
narrow to region narrow to region
narrow to region will
make emacs think that's the only
content in a buffer ignore the rest of
it okay now whenever you do narrow to
region you you need to also say save
restriction okay
okay so here's our code and we're gonna
start
so first of all search forward
search forward for
for things like that
uh yeah so for
um
well
search for word
let's say that okay
now I'm assuming I'm working on my
you know I'm working on my own
HTML code because
in other people's HTML code you might
have a class here and or you might have
you know be like that but let's make it
simple so all my HTML links have this
kind of links have this form so let's
just search that this is just command
for me
so search for forward that then okay we
don't care option bound new
no Arrow
true we don't care if it cannot find it
you know if it cannot find it that means
we are done there's no local links okay
search for what uh that then
okay once you search for what emacs will
put the cruiser like somewhere here okay
then then you just grab this thing and
how do you do that you can do it by
uh
uh seeing it Point okay
thing
bounds of thing at Point okay let me let
me just let me do these bounds of thing
at Point
okay
so that is so we want a file name
wait before we now we need to actually
test if this is a local link or not so
in other words if it's uh starting with
HTTP such as that one we want to
ignore for now okay so
so how do you do that we can test
if the next few characters is http
okay let me show you how you do it okay
now
uh search for word then if if
that's not a word let's not worry about
the you know the the a you know let's
just assume for now all links are local
links okay let's assume
okay then we say pounds of thing of
points okay now we need to have another
variable
bounce okay
yeah let's just say
yeah
link
boundaries
ah
link begin end okay
the naming of things is one of the most
difficult thing okay set queue link
begin and
uh that's gonna that's what this
function is going to return so this is
going to be a file name remove the
remove okay then put it here
so
so link beginning and end then
then let's add more variables okay link
position one okay P1 okay link position
two okay
um
then we say set queue
link P1
equals to
car that okay
set Q
link
P2
equals to Cutter okay cutter
that okay so what does that mean so
so this boundary thing at Point
basically when your Cruiser is
on a file path okay then you can call
this command bound bounce of thing at
point it will find the beginning
position where where the file path
begins and you'll find it'll find the
end position of the fire path then it
will return them as a
conspire so basically it will return
something like this okay let me write it
cons
that's what it returns
so you can you know you can do describe
function on this and you can see
you know here's the full documentation
of the
of the of these function bounds
everything at Point
okay so let's see comments greetings
Buffalo meal this is emac session you
are not interested
morning guys scream uh we are nothing
here at least uh hey good morning zitron
crazy this trunk crazy and bought
bathroom you uh the pair
the con conspire the cons fair in
Germany
so okay so let's continue the code
so we now we have the uh positions
beginning and end and now we can extract
the beginning position
uh let's rename okay let's just rename
for the sake of so people can understand
it instead of instead of P1 P2 let's
just say link begin Link in
yeah so more people can understand what
that is
uh link
begin
position okay
and P2 is is going to be
link and position okay
so you can see the code now we you know
we start we start by
find the region beginning and region end
uh
am I am I am I doing good let's see
so we start by
we start by finding the regions
beginning and end that's that's these
two lines okay then we start to we want
to find the first occurrence of hif
that's that
and then we want to find the beginning
and end position of the link okay
that's these three lines okay now we are
good to go now let's see
um
yeah now let's do so what's next so once
once you have this
relative link you just want to turn it
into a full path how do you do that
there's a emacs command for that
file
full path no file creative link okay
file okay I don't remember so let's
so when when this happens I just go to
my emacs this tutorial okay so you just
go online go to emacs tutorial practical
emac list
and uh
right now you want to find a function
that
takes a relative path and return a full
path
so here okay file directory path magnify
okay so functions on directory uh
file path functions file name directory
file name number three file name
extension file name sense extension file
related name and expand file name that's
the one okay expand file name convert
file name to Absolute that's that's
right expand file name that's the
function we want so back to emac disp
it's 8 P.M there it's I was lucky to
find some like 8 P.M uh 8 P.M so where
are you
let's see let me digress a little bit
426 uh you are in
oh APM is just New York New York time
cherry
ronatus ramatis okay right 8pm is New
York let's see four five six seven no
I I don't I don't know maybe probably
probably New York
because there's no or maybe in maybe in
uh Nova Scotia
uh or Iceland probably not anyway so
back to the this code so what are we
uh practical emac this close that back
to the emac Beast code talk show close
that
oh yeah so we are back to the emac this
code so we want
so now we want let's see let's let's do
this okay let's
let's have a bigger window okay so now
expand file name okay that's the one we
want and uh
oh before we do that
we don't have the fire path yet
uh yeah we don't have the file path yet
let me let me show you
let's let me show you okay
now remember
okay hold on a second
okay we don't need it do you speak
remember remember we want to grab the
file path okay that's easy so how do you
do so because we have the beginning
position we have the end position so
what you do is
um
buffer substring no properties okay you
see okay that's right and given two
positions and the position is going to
be link begin
position right and the link and position
okay so this thing will return the
string that's the actual file path okay
so
um so let's name it okay set queue can
h i h i e f value okay
then
that's going to be that okay now this is
a new variable we want to add it
we want to add it to our you know these
are variables let's um
okay
predefy the code now let's go down
uh now okay let's let's
um
previous code and it's not to have too
many lines
yeah
indecision indecision okay so anyway so
now we have the current current
href value
which is you know which is which is this
string okay now the next thing to do is
um
the next thing to do is
is
um
yeah so we have current uh hif value
okay copy that we want to get the full
path Okay so
expand file name
that's good so we want to expand this
relative path okay optional relative
directory we don't need it because by
default it's relative to the current
directory so whatever this file is it's
relative to that directory so that's
good
so here is the full path okay
set
full path
equals to that okay so cut it put it
here make it pretty and here's a new
variable local variable we need to add
it to the top
there okay so now we got the full path
now we got the full path what do we do
next
now we
we need to
just replace the old relative path by
the full path okay so that's also easy
how do you do that
uh you do it by
uh
D for delete oh wait
there's no okay delete region okay
that's the command delete region
uh and you know you give two positions
so the position is going to be
link beginning and Link and position
okay copy that
here
okay delete region then
you just say insert
full path okay
purify so right now our code the whole
thing is pretty much complete okay it's
pretty much complete we first of all we
find you know user gives uh you know
first of all user gives a region
like a text block uh way for example
whatever however big region so we get
the P1 P2 is the region beginning and
region end then
then we uh
narrow to region
then we search for the first occurrence
of hif the link
then once we found it we get the
beginning position and end position of
the fire path
then we
then we grab it as a string
then we change it to full path then we
delete that region and insert the full
path so if we do it on this block of
text it should work
now this only works for the first
current occurrence we need to do a loop
so that it changes every uh you know
link so anyway but that you know this
seems great let's
um
let's let's let's begin to uh let's
evaluate this code let's see how we do
okay let me let me shrink let me get rid
of the Extra Spaces
okay evaluate the code now the code is
evaluated now let's go back to this
copy paste and let's work on this block
let's try it okay
so what's what is the command name so
let's try it selected call Meta X sound
HTML copy
change relative link
okay
do it oops
symbols value as variable is void P1
okay we got something okay yeah
obviously because the whole LED block
the whole let block of take of you know
we basically we mismatch the parent
because the whole LED block is this but
however our code is outside of it
outside of it so we need to move the
code inside the local variables cut
paste predified that's it
okay Eva the buffer now we try again
selected
meta X
HTML copy change relative link enter
okay your own type argument integer or
marker P Neo
what the
your own type of argument yeah okay
um
what uh
John type of argument integer or
uh why is that let's turn on let's call
the command
let's call the command toggle
emac this you know this command toggle
debug on Arrow
okay now let's try it again because now
if I do it again when this Arrow Emax
will pop up the full Arrow detail so do
it do it so there it is
uh debugger enter this error
um then it says
your own type and
okay magnified run type argument integer
or marker okay but for substring no
properties okay that's why so e-max this
when they when it is calling this
function bubbles so substrate no
properties
it's receiving two new arguments that is
the problem
so
so here you can see this line is the
problem why is it a problem let's try
again let's see
uh but for substring no properties link
begin position link and position did I
spell it incorrectly no I did it
correctly did I spell this incorrectly
no I it's spelled correctly
uh so link beginning position and Link
and position they are Neo
which is incorrect they shouldn't be
near so the problem is probably oh there
you see when we call this function
bounds of thing at point we are
wait what
okay here's uh here's what we need to do
okay let me I know I kind of know
I know an arrow already but I don't know
it's if that is all there is to it but
anyway you see we started to search
forward
okay let me let me let me let me show
you this okay let me go to the
yeah okay so so we started to search for
word
but before we do that we need to move
the cruiser to the beginning of the
region you see
so so first of all you need to say go to
go to char
region uh
buffer minimum okay
but Point minimum okay
that means move the cursor to the
beginning of the buffer okay
then we start to search okay
and actually we need to do a if
statement because what what if there is
uh nothing found you see
if it tries to search it and if there is
no local link like that there's no href
then you don't find it right
but however then we assume there we you
know we are assuming we found it because
we are starting to grab the file name so
so actually you need the if statement
so if you see a if statement if this
okay
put it here if that
then do something otherwise do nothing
in that case we can just say when okay
so when this is true
when search forward when you call the
search forward function it will return a
value that that that can be interpreted
is either true or false so when when
search is successful then you do these
things otherwise do nothing okay purify
uh let's try again so we fixed two
arrows
okay so we don't need that okay so right
okay
so now evaluate the buffer now go back
to this part
okay now select the region let's call it
again see what happens go ahead
do it
fantastic success
you can see it has changed you see
it was a relative link here
and now wait can you see it let me
scroll up okay
so it was a relative link there but now
it changed to a full path that is what
we want okay that is what we want we are
success
so I so uh now it's we I've been talking
for 40 minutes basically we can stop
here that is what
uh we have achieved obtained the goal
Today part of it anyway
which you know which is teaching you I
hope so I I hope I did some you know
basic
uh emac this practical tutorial you know
this is very practical because this is a
function I need you know like I talked
in the beginning of my video I need to
you know move a block of text of HTML
from one HTML file to another and I need
to get you know I need to get the
relative links fixed
so this is one of the steps you know I I
change a block of text of all the
relative links change them to full path
then then you know then I copy this or
cut it then I go to some other HTML file
I paste it there then I need another
command which is kind of reverse of this
you know it will just go through the
links and change all the full paths to
the relative link
so that is um I hope um
oh okay so there's a question what's the
difference between Chi and Qatar
okay that's about
um okay so let me explain okay
let's go to talk show okay uh
yeah yeah
let me just write it okay
what is the difference between
what's difference between yeah
I have a brief the problem is I forgot
what what is the brief
what's the difference between there it
is okay
but it's a bit difference between car
and cutter Okay so
in order to do to understand that you
need to understand e-max this I mean the
how least
is in lisp language Okay so
let me write it a list in this
is a is actually a nested con sales
what is a console
a cons uh concept okay so cons not con
so because
cell
is a
it is
this let's say it is okay code like this
cause
item one item two okay so this is a
concept you know you can do it in emac
list too so for example
cons
let's say three four okay const three
four and actually I can evaluate this
evaluate it you know let me show you the
uh let me show you the messages buffer
so you can see the message buffer Okay
so
so I go here now watch I'm gonna
evaluate this
evaluate and in the message buffer you
can see 3.4 that's uh that's a shorthand
notation
so what is the console you know just in
other languages you have array you know
think of it as a array a data structure
like array of two items okay so it's a
it's a couple
so in for example in Python you have
tuples you can have a tuple of two items
or type of three items and and so on so
account cell is basically just a tuple a
a array of two items and no more and no
less okay it's always it's a build in
data structure
in
email address in scheme disk and in
common lisp in fact it's it's kind of
the core of this idea okay so council is
a building data structure of two items
okay let me write it down it is a field
in data structure
of two items
no more and no less
can be thought of as python Turbo
okay
so
so in in emacs every list okay is
actually made of Concepts okay let me
explain
is actually made of Khan's cells
for example
for example let's say you have list one
two three
but
it is actually
two
but internally
it is actually
like this okay
so are you seeing this
yeah car encoder so yeah so so
internally it actually like this okay
let me show you cons uh
let's let me just do this okay let me
type it quickly so const one cons two
okay so you can see we have a list of
three elements one two three but
actually in e-mac B's and commonly and
skim this or racket this
actually
it is stored like a nested Concepts
so it actually looks like this
so uh
so you know I can you know we can
actually test it test it okay so for
example
uh let's say equal
uh list okay so list
one two three
versus
concept okay so you see that let's try
to evaluate it and see what uh emac says
okay so you can see here's a message
buffer
your print in that in over there okay so
let's see
evaluated
you see
he says true you see
so
so that is how
that's what con sales are
and this is a very very important
um thing you need to understand when you
code emac beasts not for beginners
because for beginners you don't you know
this is actually not important because
you can just you know you you know at
least it's just a list you can get the
first element and second element and so
on but however as you started to code
more and more this this is one of the
fundamental this is a very essential
fundamental thing you need to understand
a list data structure in lisp languages
actually do not have you know it's not
just by itself it's actually made of you
know made of cons cells
now
you might you might wonder why is that
you know in short it's just historical
okay that's just the way it is because
in order to implement it back in 40
years ago you have to use a linked list
data structure because for memory
efficiencies and so on so anyway
so that is why
you know in lisp you don't actually have
a you know list is not the fundamental
data structure every list is made of
Concepts and remember
the last concept
you know concept is a fixed
two items you know remember in the in
the deepest concept the second element
must be your Neo otherwise it's not it's
not really a proper list so called
properties okay so if you go to my emac
this tutorial
there is an explanation you know you
study
emac this space basic then you go down
you scroll down
you started you know as you have more
experience you started to learn least
data type
uh then you'll see explanations okay uh
listing vectors
yeah it's uh yeah so that's what console
is now once you understand console then
you want to understand car and cutter
okay
car and cutter
because
car and car basically just means return
the first element in a concept okay
return the first element new console
Qatar basically means return the second
element in a concept so that's what they
are
okay I think maybe that's it for today
I'm gonna uh random chat
uh for a few minutes five minutes and
we're gonna shut down
uh I miss most stream because of the
time zone differences yeah so I I
probably need to start to do some you
know live talk show in different time
zone what is the difference okay between
car and cutter so that's a full
explanation
and card Returns the first component of
a pair Qatar Returns the second
component exactly Alex
so Alex says do you think this list
implementation using cons sales is good
bad language design
it is a terrible terrible language
design it's an extremely lousy okay it
is in fact it's one of my complaints
about this for for about 20 years now
okay uh you know for example I can show
you my articles okay so you go to my
programming blog
you go down to this section
programming this let me show you this
image okay this image is funny
programming my list Reinventing Wheels
by using Marcos you know this this
person are phonetic this phonetics are
always talking thinking about macros
because they think this macros is the
best thing since sliced bread
you know I talked about this in terms of
my videos you you actually you should go
watch it because for example you see
here I have two videos that's full talk
about
about this about the nature about nature
of lisp about their history and so on
okay because that's one of my you know
I'm at least you know you could you
could say I'm a this expert for the you
know I've been coding this in the past
20 years not just emac in fact 30 years
emac beasts starting from 2005. so I
have 15 years of coding emac this but I
also code Mathematica which is
um which is kind of a variant of lisp I
mean code you know I did also I did also
did
four videos about Mathematica
uh you should actually you should watch
those ones I show on my website because
they are the you know what I consider
better my better live streams you know
where I talk about lots of things in a
condensed fashion each one is about an
hour
so if you are into the history of lisp
or if you are into Mathematica which is
a you can say it's a list but but very
kind of very different however shares
all the characteristics of lisp you can
watch them
so anyway back to uh lisp you know so
this article
I mean this section there's two videos
about this about this this syntax and so
on then you can see
this article which is dramatically
titled fundamental problems of lisp you
know this kind of title is so-called
click click clickbait today okay
fundamental problems of lisp
so in this article I give you two major
problems and one of them is the cons
okay
which we just explained uh let's see
where uh two sections
the cons okay so you scroll down you can
see the this cons so here is a
screenshot of emac lisp documentation
about what are con sales you know emac
this
so here is the emac this documentation
you know you can see they have a diagram
talking about how you know car and
cutter are nested so that they forms a
list okay
so anyway if you are interested go read
my article fundamental problems of this
you search it you'll find it
so why is it so you know two you know so
because this was invented uh 40 years
ago uh 1960s by Zhang magakathi right so
you know 40 years ago the hardware the
context of computation is very different
from today
so basically back then you have you
basically have to have costs in order to
make it fast in order you know it's a
implementation what I would say
implementation is a computer engineering
byproduct okay
but today for example in Python in Ruby
in every language in Python Ruby Golan
um I'm trying I'm trying to only list
the ones I really know okay
like I can solidly tell you
what still what's not in Python in Golan
in in Ruby in Mathematica in PHP Ruby
PHP in Java you don't have this like
what the can't sell what the I mean
why do you need why do you need like
what do you need to base your list on a
you know fixed two element thing why do
you need that you don't see that anymore
because you don't need it because the
cons sales was there because it was 40
years ago you know in order to do it you
know to make it fancy and so on you have
to have that but you don't have you
don't need that since you know 1990s
but however it's just history you know
that's that's you know just like unix
commands why is it this way or that way
uh you know you have lots of baggages in
programming languages so console is kind
of a fundamental it's kind of the
fundamental core
of this programming languages with one
exception
closure
remove that eliminated the concept so
enclosure closure you know which is uh
you know enclosure lisp they don't have
the concepts anymore they kicked that
out you know they don't we are not going
to have this crap that is why for some
of the common lisp fanatics
they don't consider closure to be at
least because it bothered them because
you know the common you know the the
traditional these phonetics they they
they are used to the concept of Concepts
lists are made of made up of Concepts
but closure just kicked it out
so so that that is some of the laws or
you know uh history about this okay
that's it for today
okay thank you guys so if you like my
emac this store stuff you know you go
buy buy my email list tutorials okay
thank you and patreon or PayPal donate
me thank you
so we we I'm gonna uh you know turn shut
down the stream in one minute and what
I'm going to do now is to copy
what we did today to my talk show page
so this is like
what I have to do in post talk show
so you can watch my walk here so let's
not
so that's today's talk show page
and paste it here
okay so let's make these
uh
let's make it a paragraph
okay wait
so you are looking at how I work on my
website
okay showing browser now you can see
magnify so we have just written what is
the difference between car and cutter
and so on
and uh
okay so I'm gonna
what's up but
but another great screen is about to end
thank you very much thank you Bart for
coming by
for being my loyal fan
uh okay let's um
uh cute question and answers okay Q
need to show the pink window so I
actually
okay so that and let's go to my emacs
blog let's see let's go to the dot El
so we so this is a bunch of cons so this
part copy it cut it we want to paste it
here so to illustrate you can see then
make it a emac this tree
and color by it and show in browser
so you can go to the bottom you can see
it you know this is the explanation
about con sales and car encoder
and that's just
um
make that
okay actually
okay make that and let me just uh add
no I forgot to show the pink window
can't be cut cut cut cut cut cut cut
paste show in browser
so now we have kind of a nice section
about what's the difference between car
and cutter what is the console
I showed explanation
and now we need to
oh yeah we need to grab then we need to
grab the list code here
which is the code we did today
uh where do I want it so copy the whole
thing go back to this page
so actually we did explain we did code
the first part but the second part would
be easy so let's put the code here
uh emac this paste it here
showing browser
you can see here's the code
then
predefy
wait I did something wrong
I did something wrong because oh yeah
it's good okay so here's the code we did
today
so we wanted to write a emacs command to
copy current text block but change all
local links to full path we did that but
you know but actually there's more to do
because we have assumed that every link
is a local link
so for me I need to you know after I go
off stream I need to modify so this
function becomes useful to myself
because you need to check if a link is
you know actually starting with HTTP if
that's the case that's not the local
link then your code will you know emacs
will say error you know uh something
went wrong because when you try to
convert it
convert it to full uh path it will fail
because you know the paths start with
HTTP it will say file cannot be found
so you need to check if it's you know
local link or not then you start to um
you know things I have to do so
so the second problem right the e-max
command to change your local links
that's full path to relative link
which is you know it's just like uh what
we did today is easy to do okay that's
it I hope you guys uh find it useful bye
copy oh yeah I need to copy the uh
you know I log I kind of log
so uh you know today's uh
people's chat
create a new file cut that paste it here
save close close and make a link make a
paragraph show in browser magnify and
you go down at the bottom you can see
today's talk show
messages you know some people get
nervous about this but guys you guys all
the chat is public okay
uh you know sometimes occasionally I get
people to tell me can you please delete
my chat because you know
if you really
you know care about that don't use the
real name or something you know I cannot
you know I I
um yeah
okay bye bye bye
go to obs
my Windows machine now it's fantastic
everything works fine
see GPU usage good memory usage
half of it 6 out of 16 so not even half
of it
GPU good
and stream