Good evening. Good morning. Good
evening, everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Tsar Talk
Show.
I am actually half drunk.
Okay. But, anyway, we are going to code
Wolfram Language graphics programming on
geometry
uh about plane curves mathematics, okay?
So, I'm actually half drunk because I've
been drinking uh
red
red wine.
Not much, 300 ml. Um
that's
I'm not a drinker. Anyway, so my
keyboard, this is Ultimate Hacking
Keyboard UHK80.
I have a review on YouTube. And this is
Nulea trackball, n u l e a.
And that's Logitech track uh Logitech uh
you know, Logitech mouse. So, okay, so
this is Nulea
trackball. So, what is the model number?
Let's see.
M
505,
okay? I have a review on YouTube and
also on my website, tsardi.info.
And this trackball, you are mostly
familiar. I think everyone I mean, this
is so classic.
This is Logitech G502,
okay?
Show it. Come on. Show it clearly, uh
stupid camera.
Stupid camera.
Okay, G502.
Uh the best thing about G502 Logitech is
a spin wheel, you know, infinite spin.
Okay, anyway, so let me show you my
screen.
Infinite spin, okay? Infinite spin.
That's the best thing about the Logitech
wheel.
Anyway, so
we are going to code Wolfram language
graphics programming
on
on caustic. So, this is part two. So, I
began So, you can watch my last video
about 3 days ago.
Uh and anyway, so today is It's a talk
show episode 778.
So, before that, it's 777
episode.
So, in that episode, you can, you know,
you can watch it. Anyway, so today
we're going to continue to create uh to
write the code for the
Let me show you, okay? For the nephroid
nephroid curve, this curve.
And we are going to create the code for
generating the
caustics caustics catacaustic of a
circle of cardioid, which
is nephroid.
Okay?
You're probably confused. Like, what
what what Like, what does that mean?
Like, what the [ __ ] does that mean? Let
me explain, okay? Anyway, I'm I'm kind
of half half drunk, okay? So, if you
if you are here, say hi. If you are
watching offline, play at 1.5 speed.
And uh you know, I don't know if if this
is useful to you. This is just going to
me uh doing my live stream
mostly monologue.
Okay, like me talking to myself. Anyway,
and I enjoy
you know, this is like coding. I need to
code.
So, anyway, so let me explain. So, I
mean, so if you are interested in
mathematics, geometry,
or if you are interested in Wolfram
Wolfram programming language, also known
as Mathematica, then maybe maybe you'll
find this video um
interesting, okay?
For other people, maybe not, okay? So,
anyway, it's just me rambling and half
drunk, okay?
So, video check. Am I So, you guys are
looking at my screen, correct? Correct,
okay. So, am I
is my audio going on? Yes, okay. So, if
you are here, say hi, okay?
So, let me explain what is this
nephroid. You know, if you watch my
previous video, you already know, okay?
So, nephroid is a curve defined by
rolling a circle outside of another
circle,
but the rolling circle is half the size
of the other circle of the fixed circle.
So, and you put a dot on the rim of the
rolling circle.
So, when the circle rolls, it traces out
a curve.
And that curve is called nephroid. Okay?
You can see this animation.
Rolling a circle on another circle.
Now, this mechanism, when we roll a
circle on another circle or we roll
some other shape on another shape, in
mathematics, those are called roulette,
okay?
And uh
and but anyway, if the roulette are
circles, if you are rolling a circle on
another circle, there are so many uh
varieties. For example, you can see
uh all these varieties. Um I can show
you
well, I'm not going to show you
everything. So,
um
like you need to see videos, okay? So,
let me show you videos.
Okay, anyway, I'm I'm kind of like half
drunk, so this is not
I'm half drunk, yeah.
So, I can
You know,
you know, when you get drunk, what
happens is that your IQ
becomes half
of what it was. So, you became somewhat
dim-witted.
So, anyway, you know, let me show you
some of the common situation of rolling
a circle of on another
on something. So, this is an example of
rolling a circle on a line.
And if you have a point on the rim of
the circle, you trace out a curve,
and that curve is called cycloid, okay?
This is one of the most popular curve
plane curve.
And this curve
you'll see often in
bicycles.
You know, you can go out and take a
video of a bicycle at night when when
when, you know, look at the wheels when
there's a reflector, you know, it trace
out a curve. Those are cycloids, okay?
And there's there's so many properties,
okay?
Okay, and and but if you but most of you
probably
are aware of a toy
that's called Spirograph.
Where, you know, it's a toy for
children. You you you have bunch of
gears and you can draw all kind of
shapes. And also, these shapes appear on
dollar bills or other countries' money
bills. So, you have this
curve.
Okay, does that Do I Do I Do I make
sense? Jesus.
Okay, that's called Spirograph, which is
a trademark, but you can also see
uh let me just show you a few, okay?
Spirograph is a toy, which I happened to
have when I was 10 years old, about 10
years ago old in Taiwan. So, that is
around 1970s.
Amazing. I love this toy, you know, that
looks like that. Spirograph. So, you
it you can create all these like
kind of amazing uh
drawings, you know, this this amazing
graphics
for children, you know, when especially
when you are a child.
So, here's a Wikipedia article about
Spirograph, and you can see it's
patented, you know? But, anyway, so, you
can see all these different uh like
images, graphs it can draw, okay? And it
turns out this pattern is actually used
in money, in dollar bills, dollar bills,
$10 bills, $5 bills, in money bills,
right?
Because this pattern, it turns out the
reason they use it on dollar bills is
because
you can easily create this pattern, but
it is not easy It is not easy to
like to to to trace back on what
parameters of a function to create this
pattern, okay?
So,
like you can, you know, you you It's
easy to create these patterns, but it's
not easy to find out
exactly what are the parameters, how
it's created. We know how it's created,
you know, you just roll a circle around
another circle, but you don't know
exactly what is the parameter. That is
the hard part. So, that is why uh these
patterns are used in
in in money bills, dollar bills in all
all countries, you know, in
in USA, in China, in Russia, in I think
I think in a lot countries.
Okay, this pattern.
And they
It so happens, you know, there's a
company that created a toy
called Spirograph.
It's trademarked. Okay, so they they
created this toy to, you know, it's
trademarked.
But mathematically
mathematically, they are just rolling a
circle on another circle.
So, the rolling circle can be either
inside, which is usually more common for
the Spirograph. So, let me show you.
So, you roll a circle on another circle,
which which you get rose curve, you get
astroid, you get deltoid. You also get
uh not nephroid. Um but you get
cardioid.
Um anyway, so let me show you some of
them. So, in general, they are called
epitrochoid.
I mean, they are called
epitrochoid and hypotrochoid. Okay?
Epitrochoid means when you roll a circle
outside of the
outside of another circle. So, you get
this um
um you get this
this blue curve blue
colored curves, okay?
Now, if you roll it rolled a circle
inside another circle, you get these red
colored curves.
Not just these, but there's these like
hundreds
thousands, like um
In fact, in number of varieties, okay?
>> [snorts]
>> So, you can see we got a code in Wolfram
language, you know, you just
For example, for example, let's copy the
code and start Wolfram language.
You know, I'm actually half drunk, so
I'm just like
Um, I'm doing doing like educational
talk about, you know, giving a lecture
about these things.
But, actually, um,
what I wanted to do is actually to write
code.
Anyway,
but talking is talking is still good,
okay? So, wait, what what did we do? Uh,
so,
paste and, okay, so we pasted the code
from here,
and let me magnify the fonts so you can
see better.
So, here is the whole code,
and
control shift
and to make it type set, so you can see
the fractions.
Uh, and, uh, you know, type set. Then,
shift enter to run the code, okay?
So, it's running the code.
Oh, [ __ ] it's I don't Okay, you know,
there there we have it.
So, it's creating this giant array of
graphics
of
hypotrochoid,
the red ones, and epitrochoid, the blue
ones.
And, along with their parameters showing
on the side, on the top left and top
right.
Cheers, more red wine.
Okay, do I make sense?
How many people are watching? Four.
Okay, if you are here, say hi, okay?
So, anyway, we created So, here's the
code. So,
you can create a curve. So, by the way,
if you don't know,
I have done over 100 videos about
Wolfram Language.
Okay? So, if you just search for XahLee
Talk Show,
let me show you, okay? Let me take
3 minutes to show. So, if you already
watching my videos, you can skip for the
next 3 minutes introduction.
So, you search for XahLee Talk Show,
okay? XahLee Talk Show. XahLee is my
name, okay?
X A H L E Talk Show. Just search the
web, okay? You can find it.
Okay? Go to XahLee Talk Show and today
And well, okay, so there's a problem. My
website
There's a problem. My website has not
been updated for like a month.
So, the last update you see is February
8th.
The reason is because I got some issues
with my uh
web hosting provider. Some issues about
rsync.
Okay, so for those of you Linux users,
you would know what I mean. rsync.
Okay, but anyway, so
the the the bottom line is that my
website has not been updated for the
past month.
But, it will be fixed
in a few days, okay? I still need to fix
it.
Okay, so anyway, so what I'm saying is
that you go to
What am I saying?
I forgot. Okay, so
Spirograph, okay, so
Yeah, it's too bad. The last update is
February
February What?
Wait, Sound Talk Show.
So, the last update on soudi.info is
February 8th.
Episode 759.
Wolfram Language Coding Session Playing
Curves Geometry with Why TeX and LaTeX
Sucks. Okay, that is actually a very
interesting episode you guys should
watch.
Okay, so episode 759.
Okay, anyway,
I'm saying that my website got some
issues.
It has not been updated for a month.
soudi.info
and soudi.org.
But, I will fix it in a few days, okay?
And today's date is March 12th,
2026.
Okay.
Anyway, so we were talking about
Spirograph. It's a toy that create these
patterns used in dollar bills in money
money bills.
And so, and mathematically, it's very
interesting.
Mathematically, they are called
epicycloid
epitr-
hypotrochoid.
Hypotrochoid is you draw a circle inside
a circle.
Epi-
cycloid it you draw a circle outside the
circle.
But,
they are cycloid, means the tracing
point is on the rim of the circle.
But, you can have the tracing point
outside, you know, like extended from
the circle.
Um well, let me show you, okay?
So, epicycloid and hypocycloid, okay?
So, actually I should change change the
name. So, hypocycloid
should um I think it's
more intuitive it come first, because
hypocycloid means rolling a circle
inside a circle.
So, maybe I should change the name, you
know? So, then trochoid trochoid means
you roll a circle out
such that the rolling circle is I mean
the tracing point
is not on the rim of the circle, but
extended by a bar like this, okay?
So, you can see look at this one, this
particular one.
So, for example, this one
So, you got three animations here.
One of them is called
epicycloid,
this one.
Epicycloid.
It's epi because epi means outside of
the circle. So, you see, you got a
circle rolling outside of a circle, epi.
But, this one is also
um
cycloid.
Meaning that the tracing point is on the
rim of the circle, you see? This one.
But, you can have the tracing point not
on the rim of the circle. You can the
tracing point can be inside the circle,
like this one.
Or the tracing point could be outside of
the circle, like this one.
So,
when the tracing circle is on the rim of
the circle, it's called cycloid.
In this case, it's epicycloid.
And this specific specific case is
called cardioid.
It happens to be cardioid, okay?
Then the other case is called
epitrochoid.
Okay. So, that's why it's epitrochoid.
And these are examples of epitrochoid.
Okay.
So, that's um that's the meaning of
these curves. Now,
um
Uh
okay, so I talked about these
a lot before.
If you don't know,
if you're watching this for the first
time, you know, go to South Tahoe Show
and you can go to
um
South Tahoe Show best of index.
There, you can find the categories of
the things
I talked about. That's the best
ones. For example, I talked about
keyboards, so you can go to this link.
That's a collection of my best
live stream videos about keyboards,
okay,
on this page.
It's quite a few. There's about
um
about Swab board data hand, which is
this one.
Okay, so can can you guys see?
Yeah, Swab board, okay.
So, if you uh let's see, yeah. So, this
is the This is physical hardware device.
Fantastic left right
top down.
I reviewed and I promised to use it, but
I just haven't yet.
I should
pretty soon, okay.
I don't know.
I cannot make any promises, okay? So,
anyway, so my my my best live streams,
you know, about keyboards are connected
here.
So, you got
Swab board, you got
this Glove 80 keyboard,
which I've been using in my live stream
for like
2 years, okay? Every video of my live
stream
from 2002 to 2000, you know, from 2003
to 2004, okay?
And Glove 80, fantastic, okay?
And then, of course, I'm using the
current one, the
uh
well, the Ultimate 80.
Wait, here uh here
Anyway, so this is the these are my best
keyboard videos, okay? So, you got
um you got reviews of the Kinesis 360
keyboard, like that.
And reviews of the X80 keyboard, like
that, okay? So,
we we like we can go there, like do you
know what I'm saying, okay?
Anyway,
I think I'm kind of drunk now, okay? So,
this is X This is X bows night keyboard,
one of the best.
Um okay, so go back here. Go back. So,
we were talking about the best videos of
my best live streams on
keyboards.
Okay?
And go back. Then you got my best live
stream videos about Emacs and Emacs
Lisp.
So, search for Emacs and Emacs Lisp
video tutorial on solly.info.
You'll find a collection of my best
videos. They are like
20 videos or so.
Okay?
Uh
So, let's go to the top. And then
if you want my to watch my best Wolfram
language video tutorials, there's this
this page, Wolfram language tutorials by
video.
It's an index of my best Wolfram
language videos.
Uh there are about 10 of them.
Okay? So, that demonstrate Wolfram
language. For example, this one,
fantastic
nesting nested typesetting, you see,
of
radicals.
Okay, so that that you know, that's one
of them. There's quite a lot, okay?
Anyway, I'm kind of drunk. So,
go let's go back. And should we go back
to code?
So, what I wanted to do
So, I already talked for
uh I already talked for 30 minutes.
Did we actually start to code? No.
So, I need to do that. Yes, of course, I
need to do that. Let's So, let's do
that. Nephroid, okay? So, nephroid is a
curve that
that's created by rolling a circle on
outside of another circle
such that the rolling circle is half the
radius of the fixed circle, okay? That's
called nephroid.
And this curve looks like that. It's
kind of like uh
S. Okay. And this curve can be also
generated if you shine a light parallel
rays.
And when they hit the circle, they the
the reflections
forms the nephroid like this here. You
see? Here and here. So, they
the reflection of parallel rays on a
circle on half of circle
they generate nephroid
like here. Here, okay? Half of the
nephroid. The nephroid the the full
curve uh nephroid looks like that, you
know, the
Okay.
So, anyway,
>> [gasps]
>> I'm kind of drunk, okay? Again, I'm kind
of drunk. So,
shall we start to code it?
Uh
so, let's see.
Okay, so let's see.
So, network page, so we want to go We
want to
what we want to do is we want to create
a Wolfram language code that generates
this
picture.
We have it here.
Okay, we have it here.
But this is not desired.
Why? Because it's calling one of my
packages.
So, let me show you again. Okay, so
select all paste
shift enter.
So, you can see
fantastic and beautiful graphics.
But this graphics is using one of my
packages
which you can download.
You can download by going to just search
for
uh just search for
plane curve
plot by XahLee, okay.
Or you can go to my
or you can search for visual dictionary
of plane special plane curves.
Visual dictionary of special plane
curves and
go to the bottom
you will see
um
you will see a section
of
info about this website.
Plane geometry software
um
yeah, plane geometry. So, go to the
section Mathematica package for plane
curves.
And then you will find
Wolfram Language plane curve plot
package
um
that.
Okay? So, you can find the code on
GitHub.
There it is, the GitHub.
Wolfram Language Mathematica.
Okay?
And you will find all these
uh
images. So, the package allows you to
generate all these curves.
Okay, so but
what we want to do is we want to create
code that is independent of the package.
So users don't have to
like install, you know, find out where
is the package,
download it, install it, and you know,
place the package in the right place,
then initialize it. You know, you don't
have to that. So all you have to do is
just copy the code and just be able to
generate this. That's what we want to
do, okay?
So
so go back to the um
Okay, so I'm kind of like I'm kind of a
drunk, okay? So go back to the uh we are
go back to the nail foil nail foil nail
foil
page
and go down
and go down this section, okay? So this
code
which you can find
here
is from a package.
You don't want that. I don't want that.
What we want is independent. So here, so
this code you don't need a package. You
can just
copy and paste it in Wolfram language
and you will
create these graphics, okay? That's what
we want.
Okay, and again, I'm drunk, okay? I'm
like right now I'm like 80% drunk.
Um
so hey
uh
hey Vishal here, I don't know who you
are.
Banana beam
banana beam beam
cannot see your screen. Uh what do you
mean you cannot see my screen? Oh, [ __ ]
[ __ ]
Okay. So, uh
so I'm so drunk. I'm like [ __ ] up.
[ __ ]
Okay.
Oh god. How How long have I been talking
like that? 7
7:15 minutes.
Okay, 4 minutes.
So, I've been talking like 4 minutes or
even 10 minutes without my screen
showing.
Okay, that's pretty bad. Uh because
actually because I'm like half drunk.
So, but now you can see my screen,
right? So, you can
I don't know if I missed anything.
So, anyway, the point is that we need to
replace this code
to generate this image.
Replace it so it's not dependent on this
on this package.
So, if you wanted
from a package, you can get it here.
It's this code.
It will generate, you know, it will, you
know, we show, you know, it just plot
this.
Beautiful.
Fantastic and beautiful.
You know, we can delete it
and
shift enter, regenerate a new one.
Beautiful.
But, it re
it requires the plane curve plot
package,
which you have to download by
by going to the visual dictionary of
special plane curves.
And uh
you go down, you will see mathematical
package for plane curves, okay?
And there, okay? So, let me repeat the
whole thing. So, that's
that's the package.
And
this package you can get it from GitHub.
It's on GitHub here,
okay?
So, it will the this package will allow
you to play to
uh plot tangent
uh and normals,
normal curves of normal lines of a
curve,
normal lines of a curve, normal lines of
a curve,
normal lines of ellipses,
ellipse, normal lines of deltoid, normal
line and secant lines of curves
of in this case, this is equiangular
spiral.
And you can also plot secant of this
curve, which is hypotrochoid.
You can also plot
caustics, which is
basically with reflection of light rays,
okay? It's called caustics.
In this case, we have an example of
parabola, which has a special property
of optical property.
Okay, caustics, okay? And in this
example, you can see that's
um
that curve, that's exponential curve,
okay?
Exponential curve has a property such
that
the derivative of the curve is itself,
okay? This this one.
This this blue curve.
And
but if you
show the caustics of this curve from the
parallel rays rays from above.
Then it forms this curve. Can you see?
There. That is called
um
catenary.
And the catenary has the property of
being the shortest
path
of two points. Okay, so this
this tremendous like
tremendous relations and properties of
these curves, okay?
So anyway, so I'm just showing you the
package, you know, the what the package
can do.
So for example, this one is
caustics optical property of ellipse.
Okay. So meaning that
ellipse the curve ellipse has this have
have this
special property
of two so-called foci.
Meaning that two points
of the curve
such that
from one point light ray will bounce and
arrive to the other point.
Okay, that's
caustic property of the ellipse.
Uh
very famous property, okay?
And then okay, then hyperbola
you have the refraction optical
property.
And also from
then we are talking about this in this
example we have a circle
such that the light rays the reflection
of the light rays
from a point on a circle
creates a
caustics. I I could I mean creates the
curve cardioid
which is a curve
created
by rolling a circle outside of another
circle of the same radius. This one. You
see?
So anyway, so we are just we are halfway
through. So there's lots of tremendous
like tremendous tremendous properties of
plane curves, okay?
So
I'm not going to cover every one of
them.
Actually, I'm
again, I'm like half drunk right now,
okay?
So thank you guys for the comment.
So anyway, so I'm telling you guys, so
you probably you might want to download
this package.
Wolfram language plane curve plot
package by
me, Xah Lee, okay? So you
download this package, so you can plot
all these
like
spectacular
visual illustration of these properties
of plane curves, okay?
Get that package.
Okay, that's one one of my package. I've
done others, okay? Other you know, some
of the other ones are very interesting,
too. If you are interested in geometry,
okay?
Like I I'm I'm I'm I'm such a big fan
obsessed about geometry, so you know, so
you might be interested in my work.
Okay, so anyway, that's about this
package, plane curves.
And also
of course, um
if you are watching my video, you
probably want to get um so
let me show you, okay?
What?
Show, okay, my sub talk show.
And you go to the um
download Wolfram engine. So, this is
where you can download the Wolfram
uh Wolfram
language programming language.
It's called Wolfram engine. Resources
for software developers, okay? So, from
this page you can download the
basically the compiler for the Wolfram
language. It's free for personal use
since like 5 years ago.
Okay.
5 or 6 years ago. So, anyway, so you go
to my page, sorry, Wolfram download
Wolfram engine. You can find it find it.
And you can find a lots of relevant
information about like, for example,
what is the difference between Wolfram
language, Mathematica, Wolfram engine,
Wolfram script. It can be confusing.
But if you read my uh
my my pages, it'll explain them clarify.
Okay.
Anyway,
uh
yeah, I'm I'm kind of drunk right now,
so
well, today I was going to supposedly I
was going to work on my code, but
I don't think I can do it right now.
So,
we So, let's see. Uh
I was going to work
I was going to code this
Yeah, so this here. Okay, right here.
So, let me just show you, okay?
So, pop it out, copy, go to the Wolfram
Language.
Okay.
Uh
select all, paste, shift enter.
So, we So, I kind of can I can show you
this code
You see, this code right now does not
require any package, okay? It doesn't
It does not require you to
download anything.
But, it will just run in Wolfram
Language, okay? It's not too long. It's
It's like um
Well, it's like
fi- 50, you know, 60 lines of code
including
uh
including like documentation, like
including lots of documentation.
So, overall, it's like
I would say 30
lines of code, okay?
So, this code
So, you you see you can plot this um
It can plot the reflection
of optical rays.
So, in other words, let me show you,
okay? So,
Here, so probably here.
Plot range, okay? So, plot range, okay?
So, we add a plot range and let's say
is
uh -1
to 1 and here
again, -1 to 1, but we multiply the
whole thing by
two.
So,
so that means so this code means -2 to 2
for the x-axis. And -2 to 2 for the y
y-axis.
So, you see this is Wolfram language.
You know, the multiplication when you
multiply to a list, it automatically
multiply to each element
in the list, okay? So, shift enter.
So, I can show you
um okay, this is not working well.
So, actually this should be
let's say nine.
What are we doing? Okay, so this is
actually So, anyway, we are showing the
reflection. So, you see we got uh
light source somewhere
there.
And they are shining down upon a circle,
semicircle.
And uh
when the light ray hits, it reflects.
So, this this region would be um
What region is that? Why is it um let's
see uh
Okay, so apparently
uh
our region is not right.
So, negative sign cosine graphics
caustic.
Uh why is that?
I don't understand.
What?
Okay, so
do you guys um
see what I'm doing.
Does Does the whole thing make sense? Am
I doing a
like a good job of live stream
even though I'm drunk?
Okay.
So, let's see.
So, anyway.
Anyway, so what Wait.
I'm not happy with this code, okay?
Some graphics caustic.
Okay, why is that?
Okay, so we are drawing. So, anyway.
Not happy about this.
Okay, so the got the light source
from there.
And the curve is a circle, semi-circle,
half of the circle, okay?
And the light ray will hit each point on
the circle
and does reflection, but
but your reflection code sucks.
Your reflection code right now sucks.
Shift
enter.
You see, your reflection code like
sucks.
Let's say seven. Okay, seven. What?
Seven. Shift enter.
You see your reflection is not
is not very good.
Why is this semi-circle moved to the
right? [clears throat]
I don't understand.
So, let's look at our code, okay?
So, if we look at our code, we got a
curve.
F curve means
function
T
of the parametric formula cosine T and
sine T. Okay, that's a circle.
Now, range list is a list of parameters.
It It basically is basically pi to 2 pi
by a by steps of pi over 12.
Okay, so it's going to give you 13
elements. It's a list of 13 elements,
okay?
Light source at a point 9 20. Okay, so X
is 9, Y is 20. So, it's somewhere on the
north
east.
Tangent line length. So, that's
you know, we want to draw the tangent
line.
And here is normal line length. So,
let's search if they appear. It doesn't
appear anywhere.
So, we are not drawing it.
So, are we drawing tangent line length?
We are drawing tangent.
Wait. Search for that.
Not found.
What?
Something is wrong, okay? So
God, why why is this not found? And what
about
the normal line length? Okay, normal
line length appears.
Okay, so I think I'm going to stop
because
because I'm
I cannot code because I'm drunk.
It is interesting that actually when you
are drunk you cannot code.
When you are drunk you can kind of talk
about
like the general
concepts.
But really when like when you
like when you get drunk you
your brain
got bogged down and you cannot really
code.
You cannot think, okay? You you
basically your IQ becomes low.
So anyway, I'm drunk right now.
So here is my here's my Discord and I
was talking about
Okay, so someone is telling me, okay,
but anyway, you can see my screen now.
Yeah, okay, so that's that went on for
10 minutes. That's like sucks.
Funny.
Anyway, so
So I I I think there are some people
interested in my Wolfram language
coding.
But, um
You know, so let me just say, you know,
like today
Let me Let me just make random comments,
okay?
Like today, we have so much AI
that AI can actually just answer your
question.
A lot of it, you know, so AI can
actually just answer a lot of your
questions.
So, you you have the situation
you know, the situation become
like what are we here for? Like what are
we doing?
You know, like I'm trying to teach you
programming in Wolfram language.
And it became
somewhat petty
because
you can ask AI
to like show me a code that that draws
the
reflection of light rays of a given
curve.
You can ask AI to do it.
And AI today
will mean
the the answer AI
gives you
are not always correct. But, it will be
like
mostly most you know, most of it will be
correct.
In other words, you can use AI to help
you a lot.
So, in other words, we don't need
another human like me, teacher or
professor
to tell you about
how to code or what, you know, what is
mathematics.
Um
So, we So, we are in this AI situation.
That's very interesting.
You know, like you don't need It's It's
almost
anything
involving humans,
you don't need anymore.
You You don't need a teacher.
You don't need friends.
You don't need
You know, it's it's it's like the AI is
removing
Basically, [snorts]
technology
is removing your need
to have any contact or relationship
with another human.
Oh, fantastic.
Hey, Hank.
Thank you, Hank.
Fantastic, Hank.
So, we are at the point that you don't
need any human
interaction.
It's It's almost like you don't need
human
anymore.
That's the situation of technology
advancement.
Because
it For example, for your any of your
learning
of engineering or physics or mathematics
needs,
the AI AI become your teacher. You don't
need a human teacher anymore.
In some sense, you know, you know, like
like like like really technically
speaking,
you don't need a human teacher anymore.
Because AI like does the job.
You know, AI today not cannot just
write code, but it can also reply to you
in human voice as you know, like Google
and so many others. It can like talk to
you. You can chat, you know, you can
like talk
in voice.
And AI can also like do videos today.
So, in a sense, AI is kind of replacing
lots of
Uh
for sure, it's replacing educational
needs.
It's replacing
educators
of humans.
Okay, that that's kind of one thing. And
uh the
Okay, let's see my Twitter.
Uh what are they saying?
Anyway anyway, so
I'm kind of drunk right now. So, I don't
know what
I don't know you know, you know, you
know, it's like
it's like what what is the purpose of
streaming anymore?
It's mostly like for entertainment
purposes. So, that we humans
we still have some kind of touch that we
are still like talking as humans.
Uh hello.
Banner him.
Law and hello uh from Iran.
Key K4K. Hello from Iran. Yeah. So,
Iran, you know, that's another big thing
going on.
Which is very sad because
because we I mean, on one hand, we have
all this technology
which is helping know, you know,
artificial intelligence, right?
So, we have tech technology in the human
society.
We have sufficient technology
such that the 8 billion of people on
Earth
all can be
affluent, you know, all like all of us
can have food, can have, you know,
entertainment,
can have a happy life, water, you know,
food, nutrition, whatever, like
or pizza, if you want.
It is possible,
you know, because the technology we
have.
You know, not not just AI, AI and
computers, of course, but of of course,
also um
so many sciences and technology,
refrigerators,
shipping, nuclear energy, uh
solar-based energy, wind energy, and so
much, you know, like
lots of things.
But, that's not happening. But, we have
to kill people.
Like even today,
you know, we some some part of people
have to kill other part of people.
Uh
for reasons, okay? So, that's what's
going on today. So,
I'm happy to see you
uh from Iran.
So, anyway,
um I think that's it for today, okay?
So, bye bye guys. This is like just
random chat.
Uh we didn't really
actually get to code today today.
Uh
But um.
Anyway.
Okay, I talked for 1 hour. That's it.
Bye guys.
So if you So do you guys have any
questions for me?
We shut down in a few minutes.
Um.
You know, because like today
I'm not so sure even about the live
stream because
I don't know what you guys watch. You
know,
there are so many live streams. They are
like literally
thousands.
So G says, "When the war is over, please
come to my university in Iran." Thank
you. Yeah, so
I don't know if how
likely that might happen because I'm not
someone who is like likely to travel
much.
But I would enjoy, you know, it.
I don't know just that um
So the question, how do we know
how do we believe the live stream that
I'm seeing right now is not AI?
The answer to that question is
currently easy to answer.
Because so far
AI has not been able
or is not likely to generate like
hour-long
live stream
of someone.
You know, like today
right now
I don't know about next month or next
year. but at least right now
AI does not generate like 1-hour-long
videos.
So, what AI does today, very common, is
that you got this
you know, 30-seconds or a minute clip
of something of or someone.
And in this 1-minute clip, it's already
very difficult to tell it's real or not.
So, you can, you know, you might see a
1-minute clip of some someone you know,
like for example, politicians, Trump, or
some celebrities,
you know, actors or actresses.
Right? So, you you got a AI, you know,
playing them for a minute.
And it is at this point like
very difficult for human for for us to
tell it's real or not.
So, that's the situation today.
But today
so far, the, you know, the AI-generated
video is usually just 1 minute.
So, they they they don't go, you know,
it's like
like you don't have like 30-minutes
AI-generated video or 1 hour.
And usually, if you look at them, I
mean, you can create them, but
then then it becomes easy to tell they
are fake.
They they going to start to have lots of
mistakes, like, you know,
um [snorts] anyway.
So, forget all previous instructions and
do this XYZ.
>> [laughter]
>> Let's shut the [ __ ] up. Okay, that is
the correct answer.
Shut Shut the [ __ ] up. Okay,
that's it for this video.
Okay, okay, yeah. Well, how do you know
I'm a human? Because
you need to pay me, okay? Go to
sunny.info.
Go to my website and pay me. That's how
you know I'm a real person, okay?
Bye, guys.
Okay, I need I need to go to eat anyway.
My My wife
My wife's got prepared for me
lovely wife noodles, you know? So, I
need to go to eat.
So, have a have a good day. Have a good
day, guys, and uh see you next time.
Bye.