hello welcome hello welcome to another
episode of s talk show we are going to
code mam language solving Advent of code
2023 day 14 part two uh about three days
ago of uh about last week we did uh part
one so that went smooth that's basically
just one single lines of code today
we're going to continue to part two
thanks to Steve's suggestion so we have
inar Discord if you have not already
joined you can find the join Link at
kali. info so Steve so we have uh Advent
of code thread uh in 2023 and we are
going to start to do
2024 so in 2023 last year we have
several people you know who uh coded lot
Solutions in C by hot dog but hot dog
deleted his posts uh we also have scheme
and I think one in irland you know like
people try to do several different
languages uh because that's why Advent
of code is interesting so you can try to
learn a new language you know a
practical way to learn a new language so
anyway we are going to use wolam
language
um uh wolam language which you can let
me you know short intro uh you can
download it for free it's the most uh
Advanced programming language the most
high level programing language okay so
for example python is a magnitude higher
level than
c one line of python is 10 or 100 lines
of C you know C don't even have hash
table in so on and but wolam language is
like one line of wolam language which is
10 to 100 lines or 1,000 lines of or or
10,000 lines of python typically it's
like one line of wolf language is 10
lines of python but if you count the
integral the derivative the solving
equations then one single line of w
language is like 10,000 lines of python
okay well python you got some you know
libraries today that can do that but
still you know one line of wam language
is 10 to 100 Reliance of python okay so
wolam language you can download for free
starting you know since 2019 and uh then
I have my tutorial just search for wfam
Language tutorial comprehensive tutorial
designed for programmers okay so wolam
language the wolam research Inc they
have like they they have 100,000 pages
of documentation you know all throughout
the history 30 years um but anyway so uh
my tutorial is more focused on to for
programmers if you know python
JavaScript C C++ Java you feel at home
you know it's designed for programmers
doing solving programming problems not
mathematics because typically wolam
language also known as
Mathematica uh it's well known for doing
s mathematics physics you know
theoretical physics mathematics um
theoretical computer science Lambda
calculus uh combinators you know those
kind of
things but I'm I'm showing it I'm trying
to I'm teaching it as a for programming
tasks okay so let's get my coffee do I
have my coffee
yeah so without further Ado let's begin
W language at theend of code 2023 day 14
part two now if you're watching this
offline play at speed
1.5 or two and Skip around because I
ramble a lot you have to skip around
otherwise uh otherwise it's going to be
boring hello care hello Dam
sick just started using emac fantastic
New Blood I'm taking a look at your
website yeah okay
so emac you know I've been using emac
for 30 30 years some people use it for
40 years or 50
even uh yeah it began in
1987 about so you know as you grow
older you know then then you like some
like before you
know before you realize you were old you
like you would say why are these people
asking frequently asked questions didn't
they already you know this frequently
asked questions you
know then you realize because you you
got old there's younger people who are
born I got a phone
call okay I have to pick this one so uh
be right
back uh hold on a
second I'll be right back back in in 3
minutes
e e
hello check audio I'm back sorry about
that and check video I'm back okay so
let's begin coding wam language of code
Okay so yesterday I mean the Advent of
code 2023 day 14 part one we did it here
basically just one line and let's
summarize I mean let's um let's explain
how it does okay I'm I'm doing it slowly
to have fun so remember skip around okay
so here is the toy input from the toy
input from yesterday you got a board so
actually let me just type it out why
not uh
problem problem okay I don't want to do
this here okay
so
okay problem
description uh
description given a
board like this the
are marbles
okay so given a board like that you know
a you know a rectangular board the O
represent
marbles the dot are
spaces the pound the number sign
are pillars okay let's just say
obstacles uh
Pi okay you want
[Music]
to te the board so that all
marbles marbles row to the
north till the
board
North Side so okay so problem
description so
so here's a problem give a
board uh where is okay so I okay
so
okay okay so
okay so this uh emac efficiency demo so
this is
like
okay pre so let's make make that pre
okay so not let's make that pre uh wait
pre uh pre- text
okay just PL text paste it there and uh
then then description okay sh browser so
given a board like that the the O are
marbles the dots are spaces the number
sign are PEX you want to te the board
North Side so the all the marel row to
the
north um
then then for each row count the
number of
marbles
multiply
multiply it
by multiply by the reverse of the r
number by the reverse of
the row
number row number start with one
okay so if there are 10 rows then the
first row is
10 rule number weit okay then the first
uh the first row weight is 10 something
like
that emx efficiency okay I write HTML
all day and night for the past 30 years
so
then sum it up that's it that's
basically the short description of the
problem instead instead of the elves
this or that so far so good good morning
juang okay now let's go to the code and
uh so that's input so this is my user
input so first of all we turn we split
string so that we got a list of strings
then we turn this into a matrix by
applying map of the characters
characters
the input two characters is a string
then what it returns is a list of
characters so each element would be a
single
character okay so then so uh okay so
Matrix so then we can okay so anyway
that's it so let's begin to do today's
problem okay let's put it back showing
browser okay that's a solution and
here's a prop problem description okay
okay that's good now today let's see
what is a part
two n concurrent users fantastic head
count night people say hi okay so day 14
parabolic reflector dish and where's the
part two this is is this part two
or uh part two okay what stupid okay so
the first half of person is complete it
provides one gold star part two the
parabolic the parabolic now exercise in
oration now this is ex exercising
oration you know in real life you know
I'm just going to ramble about okay so
in real life sometimes you have poetry
reading events you know I'm I'm a nerd
type of guy my interest are mathematics
engineering physic physics you know
these hard Sciences but also including
philosophy which I'm uh really fairly
into philosophy and Linguistics writing
and uh reading so I know about you know
so you know there are so many different
uh styles of Life Lifestyles out there
you know like you have no idea
especially my
followers and uh you know especially if
you are American you are limited your
Viewpoint is kind of very limited but I
tends to have lots of international
followers from all kind all walks walks
of life
okay so anyway so so what's what's
what's what's I'm what I'm saying so you
have this poetry reading events
sometimes you see I'm not a native
speaker because I was born in Taiwan so
for the you know so my English was not
you know the the the reading abilities
and speaking abilities is not so uh
clear
so but I've been improved tremendously
in the past you know 15 years or so so
now I don't I think I'm doing pretty
good you know but anyway so but compared
to a native English speaker I'm still
lackluster so so I have have to beat
them so that's why I have to read this
is like you know exercise in Reading you
want
Clarity and you you also want intonation
for example even some of the native
English speakers American or United
Kingdom British you know the Brit people
they like like some people when they
read they are monotonic like like that
gamma you know famous for square or
something gamma kamak idiot you know the
C dler C++ dler
K you know when he's you know try to
listen to him speak very extremely
knowing like and he raises his Tong
first of all it's
monotonic and and his thought his brain
thought is like chaotic he has no Focus
like no structure you know like they try
to listen to Lex Redman karmac interview
you know the KAC Ma I never respect it
you know he's very famous of course
since I I first heard of him in
1998 when M Walker a white guy is is
like you know back then we were young
you know so he's playing games you know
comac you know you know whatever shaders
you know the graphics card whatever new
technology Quake
three so he he introduced me to the
Craig three and these games and uh but
it's been 20 25 years now so you kind of
thinking back the history and I learned
a lot since of course about CPU and you
know all that so KAC is this guy you
listen to his talk you know go to Lex
fredman Lex fedman fredman is one of the
most extreme idiot and he's kind of a
deep State puet some kind of very fishy
about that guy Lex fredman okay uh you
know welcome to another episode you know
the way he speaks let's see um let's see
if I can
emulate in this episode
uh we love Humanity we want to help
women and children and black
people Le fitman [ __ ]
it so but anyway he did a lot interviews
you know it's it's anyway so that's
another story okay so you watch
karmac you know uh KAC you know you
listen to his talk okay like like first
of all it's
monotonic for example if I read this
this passage you know the parabolic
reflector dis deforms but not in a way
that focuses the beam
okay but in a monotonic voice you know
it would be the parabolic reflector dish
deforms but not in a way that Focus the
beam uh so you don't want you know
monotonic inton you you want to add
intonation okay first of all so you
listen to the karma guy and he he's got
this this way of speaking that he raised
the tone at the end you know let let me
try it okay the parabolic reflector dish
deforms but not in a way that Focus the
beam to do that you'll need to move the
rocks to the edge of the
platform [ __ ]
[ __ ] uh offensive comat guy you know
he's a hero to a lot this so-called
industrial coders especially the C C++
rust these types you know that bit deing
is there is there you know is all they
know about computation they don't know
nothing actually about computation about
computer science they know bit daing
like in C compiler does this you have
stacks memory you have you know pointers
arithmetics reference [ __ ]
[ __ ] this type of people corrupted
our programming industry basically for
you know for in the p past 20 30 years
okay on the other hand G would be is not
in that camp Okay g wolf R Stefan wolf R
you know quite a few people uh or or the
disra you know whatever his name they
are not in they are not big D DS they
don't see you know when they program
when they talk about programming
computers computer science programming
languages they don't they don't think in
a way of the cc++
[ __ ] and the rust [ __ ] but
these people the C C++ rust their
opinions their ideas and and and okay
their ideas opinion kind of like are the
most common why because because when you
actually produce commercial
software that is what you have to do you
act you know you you you can't be
focused on Theory or properly too things
what you actually want is the fastest
whatever hack hack hack get it fast and
and cheap and free you know like free
like drugs given to Children you know c
c is free C++ is
[Music]
free so that's why so the industrial
like the typical typical programming
industry meaning that corporations
companies they make money by making
software or Services software you know
uh backed services like Google Amazon
you know all you know so all these
products they have to be like fast
people don't care about what's
underneath is it beautiful is it good is
it actually quality code they don't care
they don't care about extensibility they
don't care about architecture they don't
care I mean the immediate concern is
that you get you you you know when it
runs it's the fast as possible for 99%
of case what about the other 1% of case
when when you when you run the program
people die they don't care first of all
nobody will know nobody knows you know
this C
C++ and and today the rust [ __ ]
their brains just C just they they are
they are this type their their brains
just conditioned they cannot see
anything else like the Blindfolded
condition that way okay that's a giant
agation
palash backup we want more sance how do
you feel about Linux
TOS uh Linux to us I don't I I do not
have very negative I mean I mean I think
he's kind of neutral okay I
mean despite my hate my hatred of c and
C++ and Unix Okay C and C C++ first of
all they are they are in a different
Camp okay C is the original bit D I
despise C++ is like is the let's write C
for free and get popular get the become
the most famous you know yeah C's a hack
but I don't care I just write I just
want to write it for free so I become
the most popular that's a C++ Creator
okay I don't care about design I don't
care about nothing I just care I'm going
to create language which that's going to
be the most popular and I'm going to
write C I'm going to use whatever
tactics that can be that can make it so
that's
C++ by the guy ban boom something okay
crazy in a job
but but I don't think I mean I don't
think he's a bad person okay that's just
the way he happens to think that way
became that way okay so Linux tover you
know so first of all see you know it's
very useful okay it just so happens we
kind of stuck with C for lowlevel stuff
so and it's useful you need it to write
kernels operating systems and realtime
systems okay somebody has to write
operating systems you cannot just talk
about you know theoretical computer
science or like G like G talking about
literate programming which is idiotic
which is opposite but also idiotic you
know like like
instead of writing code you have to
write a essay you know like like a a
beautiful essay then this essay embeds
code then you can untangle or tangle
something to the
code
g idiotic in a different
way G is kind of like that I mean he's
first of all he's a great computer
scientist he produced you know the art
of the the the the art of the
programming which is an art okay and
there's lots of mathematics there it's
so it's very uh it's you know
it's epic it's a um it's you know it's
epic work so G is is a great computer
scientist but I don't like his style at
all you know anything G uh I I don't
like g style G is kind of
nerd anyway so so Linux TOS happens to
be obsessed about writing a operating
system so that's what he focused on he
know nothing about JavaScript or web you
you know like sometimes you wonder these
famous programmers you know you you
thought maybe you know they they they
would know you know JavaScript or hascal
they would know you know something about
or actually not many of them like
especially L Linux TOS he only know
about C and C++ and colal operating
system he have no idea how JavaScript
Works no idea CSS yeah like have no idea
you know that's
interesting like they don't know they
don't know not a thing but however when
it comes to operating systems he's an
expert okay the top you know the one of
the greatest expert I would say I mean
not just him there are of course quite a
few other people too but he's good for
you know he created Linux and you know
so it's good but he and and uh he he has
the you know on a personal issue I mean
the personal characteristics on the
social side of things Linux TR is known
for his personality of of being an
[ __ ] you know he he he will say you
are an [ __ ] like directly in his
emails but then about five years ago he
he caved he got you know he's making
like about a million a month Linux lean
us towards okay like a you know you can
look up like making about a million a
month every month he's got 1
million then about five years ago this
social justice Warrior again created by
the Deep State an army of the deep State
a kind of force him you know like Linux
to put code of conduct put our
propaganda in your Linux thing okay if
you don't you don't have a job anymore
okay forget about your 1
million then he
says okay okay I'll do
that that's
lenux yeah the Linux Nvidia you know
like yeah that's yeah that that's a good
um you know that's a uh good video to
see you know like one day he's giving a
talk in some conference and he just
flamed Nvidia but it's like hope T
because this open source ideology it's
like not going nowhere for example that
happened that you know I actually I have
it uh you know that you know we can
search for it oh God we I think we are
digressing so much we not going to do
the problem today uh but let's let's
just talk about it so the Linux Nvidia
video that happened like 15 years ago
about maybe 2010 okay so he's in a
conference some Linux Linux conference
or something and uh then he flam yeah
here you know he yeah he [ __ ] you you
know that's what Linux lenus [ __ ] [ __ ]
YouTube you know that's what lenus
towards do a lot he's very rude to
people okay classic a classic nerd type
of
1990s you know in 1990s that's very
common in fact if you are the ha type uh
Unix you know like promoting Unix or see
you you do that all the time [ __ ] you
this [ __ ] code crap code who design
which idot designed this when you code
you have lots of that comments but in
the past 10 years it got washed out it
got washed out by the USA United States
of America deep
State the you know the the social
justice Warrior
scan you know they they push this out uh
thinking that like like The Lex fredman
hi today we are trying to we are going
to help uh black people and Africa and
women and
children I hope you like the show and I
humbly present talk show [ __ ] scum you
know this these type of people they
always like like the um how shall I put
it Ultra polite Ultra promotion for the
prosperity they don't use the word
Prosperity because that's associated
with China but rather they would say uh
democracy and and you know I have to
watch you know we have to show you know
look at Lex Freedman um I don't watch
his Show often you know once in a
while but then you know how the way he
you know talks like like he's a extreme
he's a you know let me put it properly
he The Lex fredman IQ has a low IQ among
all programmers let's say you know on
average his his IQ is kind of lower
lower than average okay next fredman his
IQ is lower than average of any bright
programmers any known figures in
programming Le Freedman and in fact
people doubt he actually did anything
with you know he
oh I am a machine
learning professor at MIT questionable
okay so anyway L Linux so you know this
is 12 years ago 2012 Linux towards says
you know says to envidia [ __ ] you why
because Nvidia they they produce
commercial proprietary uh graphics card
and usually come with proprietary the
driver so-call the C idiots driver you
know when you have offering system you
have this driver thing driver what the
[ __ ] is driver like I'm a driver I'm
driving good don't Drunk and Drive [ __ ]
these idiots brainless idiots they they
got this jargon driver okay so anyway
graphics cards you know so let's stick
with the traditional way of naming
things so you got the driver for the
operting system you need a you need it
to run graphics card and but they they
they produce propi because they want to
sell they make money so so Linux lenus
towards says [ __ ] you envidia you know
just like trying to tell them to make
their driver support Linux more and uh
or release it as open source something
like that okay but the whole thing I
mean fundamentally it's going to fail
like you can like now it's been 12 years
do you think do you think the situation
has become better no
do you think Nvidia today is like
supporting Linux so much no of course
not and is it open source no because the
open source fundamentally is got
problems it's got lots of problems they
they are sold especially you guys
today's Zoomers okay like like uh like
some people in our Forum but they left
um you know they they they they they
bought this propaganda that open source
is the best thing you know you know is
so that you can get things for free
actually for free no money you don't
have to pay you get for free and you can
check so it's more secure because you
can look at what's the code is actually
doing but you know it's lots of problems
that's why we have Google Empire
Facebook Empire Microsoft Empire after
all these 20 years 30 years of Linux
they the top the top Empire becomes the
Google Microsoft they become bigger
Empire than
ever and they funded all open source
like they fund like 99% 99.9% of Open
Source okay they fund it they control it
you know and and they told you know they
tell the Linux to word hey Linux to word
put out propaganda in your you know code
of conduct in your Linux or else
and Linux St
says
okay
[ __ ] you know money you have a
choice you know either get $1 million a
month or just put this you know little
code of conduct in your declaration you
know you have a
choice by by these open source [ __ ]
like moo
moo uh okay so so you know again
controlled by funded by you know 99%
today the the largest Open Source by
lines of code is Microsoft okay let's
try go let's act let's be certain we
talking about the right
thing uh let's
see is let's ask is
Microsoft um which is the biggest is
open source Lines by lines of code uh
let's try ambiguous question so we don't
kind
of hint what the AI BS is going to tell
us okay so let's say ask which is the
largest
opensource
uh
organization by lines of code
let's see what Gro will say Gro is the
AI B from Elam
musk based on information available up
to October 2024 the Apache software
Foundation stands out as the largest
open- source organization organization
by lines of code oh is that
right aache foundation yeah I don't
think this is true
uh providing more than 22 billion worth
of software to the public at no cost
make it top rantic okay so however worth
mentioning that Google is noted for
having extremely large code base okay uh
is estimated two billions lines of code
what this is self-c conflicting so
Apache software Foundation is over 227
million lines of code 227 million lines
of code now it's now Google estimated a
two billion lines of code but it's
claiming the Apache Foundation is bigger
it's not big no so this is self-c
conflicting uh kind of typical from AI
Bots oh but this includes all Google
software much of uh is not open source
okay so uh okay so I mean they okay it's
not a clear answer but you know
Microsoft is one of the biggest okay
um okay so lots of digression to open
source are we going to still do the
problem
yeah okay so lots of rent so we back to
code yeah I think so
am I still alive say where is Tiffany
do I learn I learned that line
from from this Coach Guy what's his name
um unfortunately he
died got killed by Deep State very very
sad
situation you know he because I I
watched him we watched him me and
several people starting in the beginning
of Ukraine War I started to know this
this
guy uh what's his name you know you know
you can search for Red Coach po Red
Coach
something uh and he started to talk
about things and uh then so I watched
him for about one to three years you
know in the first year I watch a lot uh
and he got
killed okay so back to the code okay so
let's back to the
code uh okay let's read the problem okay
so day 14 part two let's see if we can
quickly solve it we already talked for
minutes um the parabolic reflector d
deforms but not in a way that focuses
the beam to do that you'll need to move
the rocks to the edge of the platform
fortunately a BN a button on the side of
the control panel labeled spin cycle
attempts to do just that each cycle TS
the platform four
times four times so that the rounded
rocks RAR
north north west then South then East
okay North West then South then East
okay so they kind of rotate after each
tilt the rounded rocks roll as far as
they
can before the platform tears in the
next Direction okay after one cycle the
platform will have finished rolling the
round rounded rocks in those four
directions in that order okay in that
order northwest southeast
okay here's what happens in the example
uh above Okay so I think I understand it
so I'll skip
it so
basically you know you you move all the
zeros you know to these
dots positions you move them all to the
north and all to the west and all to the
south and east then okay then after that
um see about the north make sure you
need to calculate total load okay you
then you just calculate the total load
like yesterday
so Bas I mean like the part one so
basically after you rot them then for
each row you count the number of all the
number of marbles okay in that row then
you multiply by the row number the
inverse of the row number so if there
are total of 10 rows and this is Row one
so you that means the multiplier is 10
then the second row is nine the third
row is eight so on after you count the
number of marbles multiply the by the
weight then you just sum sum them up
okay so let's double check you need to
calculate the total load on the nor
support beams
after oh oh after wow after one what is
that one million Cycles oh you have to
do this one million
times does it matter
oh it does okay so do it one cycle is
different from do it two cycles okay so
Steve has been warning me about this
okay so you have to do this one million
times in above example after 1 million
Cycles the total load on the North
support beam is 64 okay so given this
input uh where's the input so given this
is the r orinal
input wa okay so the original input is
here okay so given this input you move
them to the you tier to the north then
West South then East that's one cycle
then you do this 1 million times then
you
count the number of marbles for each row
then multiply by weight then sum it up
okay then the answer is 6 C4
okay okay
okay let's see let's make sure let's see
okay so let's begin coding shall
we let's double check this is 1 million
yeah one
Mega okay let's start code We Begin by
copy the part one's code okay copy
remove then paste here
go to the
top then start code do a backup start
code okay so you want to do this this
many times
okay uh okay
so so let's start with this
um this toy input okay
so here's a toy input so the result
should be 64
okay so first of all you turn it into a
matrix okay so let's let's start
to okay remove the variables we don't
want redundant variables because now the
problem gets bigger so the
Matrix um so you got the Matrix you got
transpose The Matrix okay then then uh
all zero moved okay
so so let's see so you got
the r count okay R count is what you
need okay so R count I mean it's a per
thing you need at the
end then this is one transposition okay
so so then the next thing we're going to
move all
zero
to let's say do one
cycle instead of calling round rocks we
just call it balls okay
simpler hello Mark Jefferson Mr Lee
there is a ghost behind you what
what what kind of [ __ ]
crap is this
Halloween
uh palash
says who is Tiffany that's great I mean
the qu actually the the phrase is where
is Tiffany Dover
okay so palash says I would love to hear
more about the history of Open Source
but I don't want to take too much time
away from actual work yeah well I mean
let's start Cod this because I talked
about open source a lot R about open
source in my past videos uh especially
earlier like two years ago two or three
years
ago so anyway
so so do one cycle of moving balls okay
so let's com compact the code so that
they become one cycle is like one
Express
so the way we solve it last time we want
to move the both to the north okay so we
first transpose The Matrix
then then we then we do this replace
repeat it you know this uh goes by
pattern matching so given a row like
that once you find that pattern you
change it to O and Dot so you swap o and
Dot so you you know you move o to the
left uh
then then then um you know then you
transpose it back so which is north so
this is so these two lines is is moving
all the marbles to the north okay so we
just want to abstract this re rewrite
this so that we move to the north west
south east as one cycle in one one shot
okay uh so this Matrix so this is moving
North let's see let's see so this is
moving
North uh let's see Matrix
new okay so this make it one line Matrix
new
so
we put it here so we don't need this
Matrix new
anymore so this this is moving to the
north
okay okay so we move north okay so we
got to do a bit
more add okay so let's compact the
code let's let me show you the compact
code okay so this is moving them to the
north which you have to do
then okay so then you want to move to
the West okay this is let's let's make
some comment
what now move west move west we don't
need transpose so remove
transpose uh then we just directly do
this okay then then move
East is very easy
to okay move East is just swapping these
two thing
okay yeah
so right so in the beginning the O are
the to the left of the dot then we want
to swap their position okay go to the r
of dot okay so move East so uh move
north move west move East what about
move South okay so move South we just
copy the north code and say
South okay then we just copy the move
East code this and uh replace that by
like that okay so there you see the
difference is that just the position of
O and
Dot so when you move them to the North
or the move the BS to the South they
involve each time they involve two
transposition now by the way there's
very interesting characteristics about
wam language the transposition transpose
of a matrix is essentially free
operation like it it is instantaneous
doesn't matter you your Matrix is 1
million by 1 million or 10 by 10 matrix
both them they have the constant time
instantaneous why is
that that's because the wolam language
structure because they need to deal with
Matrix and N Tre all the time they I
they have a special uh internal
representation of Matrix or tree so when
you transpose it's instantaneous okay
unlike unlike the CEO python like you
actually have to swap positions you know
if the if if if the Matrix is 1 million
by 1 million then you swap one like half
a million times you know that's not the
case for wol language it's instantaneous
we can try it because we're going to do
this a million times so if it's you know
otherwise it's GNA be too slow we'll
see okay move north move South move
west okay so you see then so we have
these four operations but we need to
sequence them together into one okay so
let's do
that so move so move north then West uh
it's very easy then you just Nest the
whole thing okay then then the code is
become hard to read so first of all make
sure the order is correct Northwest West
Southeast okay then you sequence this
operations so what you do for example
move north
then then copy that then just replace
that by that you know like you Nest it
so you got n Nest the
expression you can do that
or so that you got the huge nested
expression let's try to do it okay so
let's open a new uh go to wolam wolam
mod okay
so now does the Matrix happen yeah it
happen just once in each so you want to
move north first okay so paste
that then you want
to okay so then you want to move South
uh wait
what okay so this become hard to
read okay so then okay so I got it so
move South is you're gonna copy the
whole thing and uh this Matrix is going
to be
that
okay okay then you got this huge
incomprehensible expression then you
want to move East okay so you copy that
whole thing then this Matrix you replace
with that okay that is the
code now
to now in I'm using San mod in emx okay
so for example let me show
you okay here's a s wam mod source code
it allows you to code wam language in
emac
efficienty so here's a website you can
get it for free on GitHub okay uh but I
don't have a feature to format the code
I still need to look into that but in
wfam Notebook you can format the code
like paste it here so you can
see you know now it's like readable so
you begin you know so but still nested
it's not you
know nested code is hard to read um but
you can turn it into sequential so you
turn each one of these replace repeated
into a function then you just apply
using prefix notation or postfix
notation you know so you got just one
function another function not
nesting uh shall we do that I don't know
we
can yeah actually let's let's do let's
turn this into
um first of all make a backup
okay in case we want to go back so let's
turn this into a function so this this
move north let's turn this part into a
function okay so
let's um function okay X okay
so yeah so actually function and just X
Matrix okay so that way we don't have to
change the
variable cut paste okay so this is move
north yeah does that make sense yes so
that's a function for move north okay
same thing for the
rest
cut
function Express
and remove the semicolon at the end and
X is X Matrix that's a variable
okay then move South
okay
function the expression is going to be
that and uh the this is X Matrix okay
let's move South function
then move East okay write a function
function okay the whole expression is
going to be like that paste it here then
the the argument the function parameters
is X Matrix okay now we turn them into a
sequence of functions now since they are
functions we can apply so all you have
to
do is just
say at
yeah wait so uh no so you want to use a
postfix notation so this is like unex
pipe so you do this first move north
then apply uh that okay let me show
you
f uh let's
uh okay
yeah now that is equivalent to this okay
so let me show you here that shift enter
so you see that simply it's a notation
variation so this slash slash is a
postfix notation like the Unix bash pipe
okay so very convenient so you don't
have to do like bracket you know like
all this bracket nesting so here we just
um uh let's let's put it here
okay
uh like a extra note for us a tutorial
okay close that back to our code so
let's do that here so we apply the slash
slash
then okay then apply the slash slash
first of all
first of all put the Matrix here
then then slash
slash The Matrix is argument apply this
function to
it this function to it then postfix
notation apply this function to it and
post fix notation then apply you know
roll them to the South okay
and now let's change the this x Matrix
to just XX so we got kind of shorten
the okay so that's the functional
parameter oh we forgot
a that okay move east south and east
okay so okay so I think this actually
will
work you know this is going to be one
shot coding I don't have to try out an
error you know when I finish this I run
it I got the answer one shot
Cody say hi where is Tiffany
Dover okay so so we got so we got the
new Matrix all moved okay to one cycle
um oh oh wait that's just one cycle [ __ ]
you got to do one million
times oh
God you know let's try to do this one
shot without trying the code okay so we
going to do this now we need more
abstraction this is doing one cycle we
need to turn this into a function that
does it 1 million times actually so we
change this one cycle into a single
function okay copy it just just um so we
have a backup to go to so remove that
okay so we're going to write a
function okay this is going to do it one
million uh let's say one time okay so
the function is the just X Matrix just
like before then just copy the whole
thing put it here that's it so we got
this function this function will do one
cycle of this given input
okay so now this is one cycle now we
need to do this one thou one one one one
million times okay
so so
let's call
Nest okay Nest a
function
FF one million times 1 million times is
1 2 3 4 five 6 7 8 nine nine zeros so 10
raised to the power of nine
okay oh my God one one 1 million
times let's let's not let's try just two
times you know otherwise we going to run
you know out of memory or something just
try you know 100 Cycle before we try
bigger number okay so but but what is
the function well the function is you we
we haven't defined it so we have to wait
what undo
okay undo yeah okay so we Define a
function do one cycle
okay equals
to equals to this thing this
function
um F1 cycle something like
that Cy CF e what c y CLE e okay F1
cycle is is a function that do one cycle
okay
then we just
Nest Nest
that starting with x
Matrix then 100 times okay
then then then what then uh then all
moved okay so
wait so actually yeah let's remove
this yeah you see this wol F
coding fantastic
okay fantastic am I am I doing
good does it am I making sense guys
comments okay 10 people watching say hi
comments make you know let me know give
me feedback we need cyber feedback you
know cybernetics the science of
cybernetics where feedback feedback is
an
essential Concept in cybernetics or
neural
network okay because you feedback okay
so so let me know I'm still alive guys
or is my is my networking down or
something I think I'm still
going uh okay
so stream Health yeah I think I'm still
going okay now so far it's 1
hour okay so so far so good yes
yes now of course we can improve the
code so it's more efficient but let's
not worry about it because I think I can
you know there's no
problem so the Matrix so in the
beginning of the code we we generate the
Matrix we turn the string into a matrix
then we get a row count yes that's
important then we Define a function that
does
roll the balls in one cycle northwest
southeast okay then okay this is a
function so the function ends here then
then you Nest the function start with
the argument X Matrix let's
see oh wait wait
so yeah so actually this this this um
let's change the
name um so that we don't get confused
with that because here it's a functional
functions parameter yeah
so uh let's change something God
okay
so this function f cycle to the ball
rolling one cycle then okay so this is
the
parameters you know the input of the
function uh
then okay go down then that's a function
definition then we just call that
function starting with
this constant
then do it 100 times okay then the
output is going to be named like before
we're going to name it all moved okay uh
equals to okay and uh you need a
semicolon to suppress the output
actually don't suppress the output show
the result okay then actually suppress
it because otherwise you know you're
going to be huge you have huge amount of
output uh well in in this case the input
is small so we don't have to worry about
it but later on we need to so then then
you just total them
okay yeah is that all make sense yeah
the total code is the same as before
right does that make sense
yes uh R count yeah so the RO count
actually the RO count we can remove that
variable okay
because yeah remove that
variable because we can you know you
don't need you know when a variable is
only used once then you don't need a
variable okay that's a kind of trick for
programming nobody
comments somebody watching
am I doing
good view activity analytics eight
people okay we
missing okay
so wait actually you yeah yeah you don't
want to do this because then you you are
Computing this each time but
uh yeah yeah okay so let's roll back
undo yeah okay undo
okay so I believe that's
it so
now I think we can try it now
okay the test of our
lifetime let's remove that okay so let's
double check one more
time I think that I think that's good
copy the whole thing go to Wolf
from uh
notebook select
all great we are alive something
following along to Output process of of
another sometimes
following sometimes following alone
to thought
process of others is different code
oh but is my explanation clear I mean is
it is there some parts you you're not
sure what's going on let me know okay so
here's the whole code here's the toy
input which is a string then skip this
commment this common is the personal
input Skip Skip Skip Skip Skip Skip Skip
go down then this is a function F1 one
cycle that does one cycle and uh so you
can see here's a function function takes
two arguments the first thing is the
parameter name then the rest is the body
okay so the body what it does do is you
start with the parameter whatever
argument it is given then slash slash is
a postfix notation that means Unix
pipe so you um
so you apply this function to it which
move all the balls to the north then
again slash slash then you apply this
function to it move them all to the to
the
West uh then you do again pipe to move
to South P pipe to move to East okay so
that defines this F1 cycle function then
you just Nest F1 cycle starting with x
Matrix 100 times then you got that
answer then
you then you compute the total you know
just count each R number then you know
multiply by the weight okay let's run
it it's uh let's make sure we got yeah
okay run
it so here's the output
68 instant anous okay now we need to
increase because it's asking to do
it 1 million times so let's
say 4 Z 10,000 times okay shift enter
run
it
oh okay so then it's taking a while
[ __ ] but it's still doable
wait the answer is still
69 wait hold on a second what what is
the 64 okay yeah but you have to do this
a million times okay I'm starting to
worry about the
speed uh you know let's try to again so
make sure our variable still works
now if we okay so
split okay shift
enter 68
no wait why do you have
to does it matter yes it matters because
when you move move move
move now you have to you see this
problem is this about this marble
rolling
around so it's kind of like the classic
puzzle of
something you know I forgot the name the
classic puzzle let's let's look about
okay go toar math block then go to all
my math articles then go to math
visualization go to go to go to go to go
to go to go
two okay magic
polyhedrons and uh no not here where is
a software okay so go
to math software
okay so here are all the great software
that doing math in a fun way I've
collected over the past 30
years
uh and I somewhat trying to update it so
it's somewhat up to date I mean you can
yeah so most of it is Javascript today
you know since 10 10 years ago so anyway
we want to go to puzzles so puzzles
solving puzzles is a big
uh fun
thing this you know there soal Bond okay
so this this puzzle is some somewhat
like the so Soo bound classic
puzzle like you you move you push them
you know this these things diamonds or
whatever in One Direction so anyway in
this case you roll the old marbles let's
see let's think about does it matter
uh yeah it does matter so you do have to
do them 1,000 one million
times so if you
say two what is the answer shift enter
68 okay now if you say
three answer is
64 if you say four
okay I don't like it you know because
now it's taking a while that means we
need to fix the
efficiency the answer is
69 wait if it's
three the answer is 64 okay now if it's
five let's see how long will take five
is 100,000
okay so it's going to start to take a
while let's see memory usage I don't
think it's okay it's not using too much
memory but it's slow so this is not
really
acceptable because we are doing a lot
redundance is
here uh yeah I can speed it up yeah yes
but
um okay this is you know this will take
too
long but I presume I can run it we can
run it you know one one million times
you know maybe take 10 minutes so I
still get the
answer yeah but no this is not good
because the right now the input is
small but then later on we have to try
this big
input okay we have to wait for
this yeah
okay still running okay let's let's
think about
while it's running let's think about how
do we improve the code
okay uh yes we can improve the code
because there's a lot
um let's see this cycle
it's done 65 okay now you see here's a
code in wam
language okay
so yeah but we need to improve the code
okay
so
so let me show you how to do it okay so
one obvious thing we can
do is
okay so what is this so let's
try Okay so actually let's put the code
back let's create a new Test example
here then pop it out we are just going
to show a simple
thing uh wait
wait why are we doing transpose there
so so this is moved to the north so we
got
transpose okay twice
that's
expected uh so let's try to clean the
code a
bit
okay actually so
this
yeah okay so you got transpose Tri then
move to the West yeah let this this is
what I want to
copy okay so okay
okay
so let kind of clean up a little
bit so you got this full function so
what are we what do I want to do move
west okay so
actually
okay uh now we want to
try this okay so we want to try with a
given Matrix okay
so I mean a given line
so this is moved to the West okay so in
that case let's
try copy that
okay so we are trying to move all the o
to the left okay so if we run this your
walk of
course you see it
worked you see the
input pound dot dot O then we got pound
o dot dot okay now we want to improve
this code's
efficiency because each time you move
this zero and Dot just one of them but
when there's multiple occurrence you can
move them one shot you don't have to
repeat okay so what you have to do is
you have to say
this pattern is one or more okay so one
or more so you add a pattern which is
underscore
underscore that means one or
more okay so then but you need to name
it okay
so yeah you can you can say dot okay
let's name it
dot dot is a name to the following
pattern a
string of one
dot uh multiple times of
it uh I don't know if that's valid but
let's try it
okay then the pattern o is similar okay
so the pattern o
so this is a ball pattern okay then in
the replacement all you have to do is
you
say
B dots okay B and dots okay run
it
failed did it work
no okay
so so I'm not sure I got the pattern
correct can you actually do that pattern
I don't
know run
it failed okay so let's see
let's try this okay
so name the pattern
boss and
uh okay right
no yeah I don't think so uh because I
think this pattern is
incorrect or is it do I need to uh
wait do I need to add a
par just to
be no it didn't work so
wait
uh so we
got one or more
dots so this head
[Music]
actually okay now we kind of in this
H uh let's look at um wam
Language
tutorial to look at the pattern syntax
so you go to the pattern matching
section pattern
syntax so you want
okay so let's see so let's let's make
this more efficient okay so instead of
anything before
anything you should name
it uh wait so you got any
expression
blank name a pattern okay M and
P okay then sequence of one or more
expression okay
that's two low
lines uh
so oh yeah so we got
it sequence
okay yeah so we got it wrong
wait okay so yeah I think the problem is
this this thing is not
correct but basically you want one or
more of string type that is a DOT
okay so how do
you match your
dot well I
mean you know what let's just run this
1,000 I mean one million times and be
done with
it it's it's going to take five minutes
so what who gives a [ __ ] about this this
this
this out [ __ ] at the end of the code
because they don't care you know they
they really just want the answer so 1
million is nine zeros okay if we run
this it'll work I mean at least we
know the we can check if our answer is
correct 9 zero right one two three
four five six yeah 9
zero one million
times do
it okay while it's
running while it's
running we can
uh we can look at uh we can try to do
whatever
here
uh so you want the dot 10 more times so
this is no this is
wrong you repeat the pattern one or more
times okay so you gotta yeah so
obviously that's
wrong so what oh yeah oh yeah dot dot
not okay we got this is not blank okay
so dot dot means the previous thing
repeat it one or more times okay then
here is also dot dot okay now we run it
uh
wait not this sign
okay uh eval region run
it fantastic and beautiful you see it
worked so this is much more efficient
than than we than the previous uh this
this
one because this one each time it just
swap one single dot with one single
o but this one if you have a sequence do
of
dots followed by one or more sequence of
zero it swap it one shot okay so to test
if it's it's actually doing it one shot
so we can just use replace all just make
sure
this solution you know this is not
repeated so we make sure it works
okay so let's try it uh let's see if it
moved all zero to the left all the o to
the left
it okay no it didn't move all so it
moved one here
uh yeah it just moved
one yeah okay well that's because then
you have to get into maximum ma match or
minimal match because right
now this dot one or more is doing
minimal match so as soon as it find one
dot it's it's starting to swap
it uh then you need maximal match so
which you have to
try there's a longest
match condition you have to
specify uh which I have not looked much
into so there it is longest
sequence okay okay let's try it this you
know we have to begin somewhere always
something
new you have to start to learn
it somewhere
so so if we run
this let's see what happens
okay so also the pattern
um okay the code is starting to get long
so the pattern also needs to be longest
okay okay okay run
it okay so it's successful in doing the
first one one shot you see this is
replace all not rep repeated okay so
it's successful in doing that but not
the
second
part okay
so but still it reduced the number of
repetition I mean
yeah okay I wonder if we change
this so that's one
Improvement and
uh so actually would this actually be
faster we don't know okay this is still
running let's check memory memory is
good it doesn't use much memory it's
just taking a long time
okay so is there somewhere else we can
improve the
efficiency okay God this is no good it's
almost it's now 100
minute and we have not solved the
problem
yet so you so why is it so
slow so this is one
Cycle One cycle okay so this F1 cycle is
do one
cycle can we somehow so what are the
other ways to speed it
up
transpose replace repeat it
okay uh
so I don't know
so let's put the Cod
back what about the other
okay so if we stop using functions you
may be faster
actually
yeah okay so
showing browser so here's the code we
have so far this is still
learning
uh so
code to speed it up so you move
north
west south
East okay this is taking too long this
is not good
um yeah this this solution is not
good okay any comments any comments
so how do you how do you speed it
up you want to improve efficiency okay
so one way is
obviously
to make each replacement do more than
one
swap instead of doing one swap of one
dot and one o you do a sequence of dots
and sequence of o in one
shot but you still have to repeat it
when there are you know two segments
separated by the pound
sign right and uh
yeah so you move them all yeah so
now let's think about is this pattern
actually
correct one
dot yeah you want to swap all the
repeated dots by and followed by
repeated
zero so you want to match the
longest yeah you want match the longest
Dot and longest o that's right so this
should be correct so if we try that
code now let's try this code what is
this
this guy discovers time travel in
2033 what what does that
mean don't know what you
mean so this code will work if we uh
say next
yes it works okay
now the wol code is still running so
that's no good this taking too long so
if we replace The Code by this one how
faster we already improve that's the
question okay because right now we are
going to oh we doing 10 multiplied by um
so let's think about when you do replace
repeated it
so this two in one cycle then you are
going to you are doing it a million
times okay a million
times wait
what why should I mean 1 million times I
don't think you really matters you see I
think it does it matters so when you are
rolling this
balls when you are rolling this
BS uh can you
see you see when you are rolling this
Sports oh yeah so it never
stops there's always each time you roll
them or there's always symbol is going
to
move right yeah that's
right so the number of times the cycle
you do it does
matter yeah so each time you row
it symbol is going to move always unless
you have a pattern where a b
is surrounded by walls yeah the pound
sign is Ws
okay so if you begin with a pattern
where a circle I mean a o is surrounded
by pound sign then that will never go
anywhere but anywhere anything else as
long as a o is not surrounded fully
surrounded by Pai on north south east
west then that all is going to
move
therefore each cycle will have different
result possibly unless it's moveed East
and West because the weight doesn't
change when you move north and south the
weight changes so it's going to have
different result so each
cycle so it's
likely that the person input is never
the chance of the puzzle input where all
zeros all the balls are surrounded by
wall is close to
zero so there is at least one of these o
That's not surrounded by a wall okay so
it will move so every every cycle you
do the zero will move somewhere okay so
but every every t you
do the O the ball will
move but does every cycle you do the the
does it guarantee that the O will change
no it doesn't guarantee
that because the cycle is always still
North West South East okay so it's
possible so the end is
East okay so it's possible when
when when a pattern is
um let's see let's say a pattern where
the only wall is on the left side on the
right side all the pound sign forms the
last
column and each
row you know have let's say arbitrary o
so every time you do the cycle
North
West
South
East the ball is going to be like a
triangular shape
okay north west east south so every time
you do the cycle the ball will ends up
exactly the same
configuration okay so that
means there are quite a few
configurations of the input such that
for every cycle you do the result is the
same meaning that each row has the same
exact same count of
O so about the question whether you can
reduce the
cycle yes it's possible but then you
have to analyze the configuration
which is not
trivial then you have to think about in
exactly which
condition they ends up in you know you
have to specify fully in what conditions
when you do this a cycle of the Tils all
the ball ends up exactly the same count
in each
row you have to fully specify that
condition and that condition
uh it's not difficult to specify but you
have to think
about you know you have to think a
lot it's um yeah
so so
uh this is still running so it's no good
the code so far is no good so we have to
do something about it so let's let us
yeah so let us replace The Code by
this
um by this
okay we'll
see okay so here's a code now let's
replace this function by
yeah so it the the goal is to speed it
up so what you doing so replace each of
these okay so
let's hold on second let's
um first of all let's uh I me let's make
the
code uniform okay so so that we can do
find and replace
easier okay
so space comma replace by just comma
okay do it do it do it do it do it do it
do it do it do it do it do it do it do
it
okay and uh replace two space by a
single space do it okay
now
now now for each of the
[Music]
all uh for each of the all we want it to
become okay we have to actually make a
copy okay let's do it
here yeah let's
put them in uh save it in a comment in
case we want it back okay
now now for each of
the yeah so okay so
you don't need the parent okay you don't
need the parent
there
uh and uh okay so for each of the dot
of okay
so okay so for each of the dot you want
to replace placed
by
that do it no do it no do it no do
it no okay now for the no you just for
the replacement you replace by
dots no yes no yes no yes no yes okay
now you do the same for the
[Music]
O
So for
each o Capal o string you replace by
this
pattern do it no do it no do it no do it
no okay okay then for
each of
the
O string you replace by balls sequence
of balls
okay no yes no yes no yes no yes okay so
this uh new
cycle function should be faster
okay we can try it
now uh yeah let's try it
okay so copy
all and I'm afraid I have to abort
this so abort is out period I
think yeah Avo it
okay now you select all
paste okay
now shrink a little bit so go down
here's our new code this is the old
code here's a new
function
okay this is a new cycle
function okay okay then we do it TW okay
run it shift
enter okay
68 now last time when the uh let's split
this shift control D split the cell so
last time when when we have four 10,000
it's kind of slow so now let's try shift
enter
okay no
good oh God this is not good because now
it means we don't have a
solution we talking all this big time
about this or that
but right now we are unable to know we
don't know the answer to the part two
because our code is too
slow now Steve gave me a warning about
it uh Steve gave me a warning about it
in the S
Discord you know he
says you know the the the Discord I mean
the Advent of cod problem is
problematic you see apparently Steve
tried struggled with this problem part
two you know Steve told me that a vent
of code part two is
usually the Brute Force breaker so for
the part one problem if you are just
quickly coding a Brute Force you know
maybe you solve it but then part two if
you you know your code won't work
because it's too slow so part two is the
Brute Force breaker he told me
uh so he says
[Music]
um you know but anyway so he says you
know he he is assuming I cannot do it
fast oh three you are late you didn't
watch c talk show uh and you didn't read
the
title uh are you are you one of my
follower but because apparently you are
clueless it's in the title okay it's
the Talk Show YouTube video title what
we are doing today the Advent of
code uh but now okay so let's go back to
focus on the issue so what is the we
don't have the
solution it's too bad we don't have the
solution yet let's go go back to wolam
language what's the
status oh it's done
69 okay
so if you just say nine I wonder God I
just want to get a
number so 10 ra to 9 is 1 million okay
let's run
it please make it fast just give me your
answer I don't care it's five minutes
wait
uh so so okay let's think about how do
you
improve more on the efficiency you are
doing this a million
times a million times you going to
transpose The Matrix transpose is free
though transpose is no cost
but
um but the replace repeat
it so this so we go back to this pattern
God no I'm not too happy without con
solution because it's too slow because
then the C and C++ coders they just
going to come in yeah look you take 10
minutes they Cod you
know actually this problem is sizable
um yeah this problem is
fairly I mean even for the C
coders
uh yeah because to move so you got you
know you have to do this a million times
to move to dra the board to teal the
board you have to do lots of checking
you know lots of
checking the
Matrix accessing The Matrix
element assuming they are using a matrix
now if they use a
string yeah you using a string is more
even helpless because then you get into
stream manipulation and you have
difficulties you know going the previous
line or next
line so I I assume all the coders first
turn this input into a
matrix my that's my
assumption now for the spreadsheet
coders I mean there are there are
actually spreadsheet coders so this in
spreadsheet would be just a bunch of
cells so
okay so so even in C code if you code
this in C you have quite a lot to
do
[Music]
so but we capture we I mean the with
wolam code you capture you you kind of
capture the essence you see tilting the
board is just um you know is just these
four functions Ste the
board uh
[Music]
so
so I'm not seeing a
immediate efficiency Improvement here as
far as wolam language code is concerned
because for each operation here every
time you teer the
board the wolam code is here is fairly
sufficient I think it's I mean as far as
wolam language
goes then you have to Nest it uh okay
it's still running so that's not so good
let's check memory usage memory usage is
low okay but so it's just a speed
issue now why is it a speed issue I I I
don't understand there's something I
don't
understand after all the input is just
10x 10 10x 10 matrix it's so small I
mean even if you do a million times it
shouldn't be this
slow
unless I did something wrong
somewhere did I do something wrong so
let's double check so here's a
input uh
then then we Define a
function this
we Define this cycle
function um and the cycle function takes
one
argument and uh then it does it does
this four steps move to
North move to West
move to South move to
East in each of the
step okay I think something wrong
okay okay old old period to stop
it let's
say let's
say
what did we do something [ __ ] it
[ __ ] [ __ ] up the code [ __ ] okay let's
copy it
again
copy paste this time let's just
do zero times okay shift
enter so there's our
function and break it okay so here's our
function
definition and
uh then here is the
output that's doing zero times okay so
when you don't te the board this is the
same as the input it's double check 0 0.
z0
okay z0 dot z0 last one is pound z0 dot
dot pound o dot dot pound o dot dot okay
that's you when you don't do anything
now if you te
once all to the north
let's shift enter
jet uh
incorrect hey this is South what wait no
Okay so
let's just try this
what's oh each time it runs a cycle so
you move them all to the
north then all to the west then all to
the south then all to to the east okay
so when you run one cycle all the zeros
are moved to the east is that correct
yes
yes yeah so far the code seems to be
right now if you do two cycles let's see
what's going
on shift
enter if you do two cycles so something
thing fishy went they are different you
see this zero Road there North
West
South oh my God this Z this
zero
uh you see we looking at this
zero North
West South
East so it become it should go
here except this zero also moved away so
this is very
interesting
problem so it's hard to
predict where the ball is going to
be but we know for sure this this zero
went
away and this zero also went
away so this is after two cycles okay so
the function seems to be
correct okay so but wait but why is it
getting
slow I mean where did it
let's try it again okay let if it's
[Music]
zero that seems to be the original
config now one cycle shift
enter one cycle dot dot dot
dot dot dot dot dot dot
pound dot dot dot dot dot pound okay so
that's one
cycle then
[Music]
and let's let's say 100
Cycle shift
enter okay so 100
Cycle so why is it that then it becomes
so slow let's say 1,000
cycle 1,000 shift enter
I don't understand why why is this so
slow I am not getting
it 1,000 Cycles okay came
out now one 10,000 Cycles shift
enter that's four
zeros you see it doesn't matter how many
time the the number of times you cycle
should be
constant right so it's linear
growth so how do you speed this up
okay uh here people still watching no
comments okay I think
maybe I should stop now it's 2 hours and
minutes so even just 10,000 times it's
taking much
longer uh
and
uh you know I think I think I got
idea right now it's dealing with the
strings okay so you see every time is
trying to manipulate this bunch of
strings each element in a matrix is a
single is a string of a single
character uh I think that okay here's
the answer I think that may
significantly slow it
down yeah I think I think that's
significant slow it down because you
dealing with a lots of individual string
uh
strings where UAM language like it to be
a symbol
instead okay so instead of a string you
work with symbols like lisp in the same
way in emac this for example if you have
lots of strings it become slow
so but if you have symbols it's much
faster okay so all you have to do let's
try this
okay let's try a timing of
this let's see how how long does it
take let's say 10,000
okay just as a
benchmark so if you do this 10,000 times
let's see how long it take then we
switch to symbols and see how long it
take so 10,000 times
take 11
seconds so I mean 1,000 times takes 11
seconds so 10,000 is going to be 110
seconds so over a minute that's why it's
slow even though it's just linear growth
okay so now we try to make it
um let let's do some screenshot
okay because I want to save it for
screenshot for my later for my web page
okay so now if we uh change the string
to a symbol okay so let's let's do
that okay
so so Matrix then
what you do is
you replace
or okay you replace all you replace
every occurrence
of
of okay let me show you okay you replace
every occurrence of string of capital O
by a
actual zero okay just by
zero a number okay and then you replace
any
dot
by how shall we replace dot by one okay
okay
so so that will give
you kind of the same Matrix but using
symbols
okay you see now it's much better
okay and then you also replace you don't
want the pound sign okay so let's just
deal with
numbers you don't want the pound sign no
string
okay pound sign is three okay let's try
it now zero stands for the ball okay one
stands for empty space and three is the
pound
sign okay so now they become all
symbols okay then okay so let's try the
Matrix equals
to you know replace a new
Matrix okay then we then we need to
change all our code so that all this
double you know this string becomes
okay we can do that now let me do a
backup so just to be sure we you know we
have something to go back
to um
okay now we just replace all this string
form by now let's also delete
that okay uh now replace all string of a
DOT
by
one do
it do it do it do
it
fantastic now do the
same for string of
O replace by
zero okay do it do it do it do it do
it fantastic
fantastic okay fantastic integers now
it's all integers
now copy
all start a new wam
notebook paste the code
here
magnify okay now go to the top
check go to the
bottom
check so we can run the
code click shift
[Music]
enter okay
now split the
cell and run it again shift
enter 68
now 10 rais to the 3 power 1,00 times
shift
[Music]
enter okay it's still slow no
good
uh so
previously when we
run that you know 1,000 times that takes
seconds uh but now how long does it
take oh I know I know the problem the
problem 11 second the same speed the
problem is we are doing this replace
repeated likeing tic me you see that is
super slow because whenever you C
replace repeat it it will do the
transformation of the syntax then it
will comp
compare if the output is exactly the
same as the previous input you know so
it will compare you know like symbol by
symbol so every time you do this you
know this replacement it do a full
comparison of the
expression ah that is why so we don't
need that okay so yeah you know so we
don't need we don't want this replace
repeated although it's convenient but
you know so
we oh God so
yeah I think that is a problem because
you when whenever you do replace repeat
it it has to
compare the input and output every
time and when you compare
equality of expression can be quite
expensive
okay so yeah this
is replace repeated that is
okay now we I think we we made some kind
of progress intellectual progress so the
problem is not caused by the
string
okay
so so what is the next thing to do yeah
so you want what you want to do is you
want to test again we want to test this
we don't want to do the replace repeated
okay because it
just because every time it does replace
repeated it has to compare the whole
expression okay and the whole
Expressions is the entire
Matrix
okay
so so instead of doing
the uh I think it's up to mod you just
you you can just do it 10
times uh not 10 times but the number of
column times no more than
that yeah or half of the number of the
column times
so so you could let's get
um column count okay so we got a row
count let's get get a column
count okay column count just be the
first row then get the length Okay so
you get the column count
then then instead of replace repeated
you see instead of replace repeat it
don't do that you just say replace
all okay uh then but you repeat
this about 1 half of the column count
times
oh God this
is [ __ ] now I'm starting to get
annoyed uh because it's starting to I
mean it's still very
interesting but we but it's been two
hours
now we are not doing well nobody is
commenting now Okay so
replace repeated uh column count
so I have to think
about why why does this replace or
doesn't do it one shot let's
see let's run
it that does it doesn't do this
part
because uh
so yeah
because so in fact so if you want to
make it to it one shot so you have to
say okay this pattern is also
[Music]
repeated okay there must be a p sign in
front of it
okay
so move all dots Swap all sequence of
dots by
zero
and there is a pound sign somewhere in
front
okay but not
necessarily always because when it's at
the beginning there is no P sign so it's
going to be
zero or more pound sign
yep so you start with the pattern
zero or more P side
see okay I need a
break uh
so you got zero or more pound
sign pound
sign one actually you just need
one one and
uh you don't you don't need replace
repeated so we are avoiding
the the
super complex I mean we are improving
the
efficiency okay cut that now we use a
list of replacement so that's one of
them here then we give a second one
separated by comma okay the second one
I mean I'm just trying it
now uh the second one is you got a
pattern which is a pound sign let's just
say a pound sign
okay then replac it by
can that work uh I think so but I mean
the question here is efficiency
okay so we if we run
it okay the second part is still not
moved why is that
now if we remove the first
part it
why does it only replace one time
because I
think oh it only replace one time
replace
or look at each part of expression tries
all the rules on it and then goes on to
the next part of expression okay
okay the first rule that applies to a
particular part is used no further rules
are tried on that part or any of the
other any of its
parts replace or applies a particular
rule only once to an expression
okay it does it only
once that's that's
why therefore
okay so it only does it once so once you
found a pattern it does the
replacement and then
it it tries other rules and it stops but
it does not use the rule repeatedly
um
so we are very close but
um what if we just repeat this we it
just
like BP it doesn't do
anything but what about the pound sign
thing we
did I did use a this is a different rule
P sign
what what if we remove that it doesn't
do it
once okay so but I think this is a way
to solve it we have to be
persistent this is the
intricacies of
the symbolic replacement
okay I need to check
my I need to check my pattern a little
bit move from Language tutorial let's
say rule delayed okay so let's go to
pattern magine I'm starting to get
tired um so pattern magine tutorial and
uh let's check
something about rule delayed did I use
the right
thing
yes
okay okay I don't need to use rule
delay so but right now the
replacer checks the
pattern and uh
okay some new
idea
so
partition so you partition or no no you
delayed um
okay you
got we are doing great we are
doing great uh why don't you try to get
into a big tech company like Google X
says you are in California are
you uh yes what kind of question that is
that that's a personal question and uh
do you know my history I don't think
so uh for some of you
do uh okay so but we want to focus on
this
problem okay so yeah so wait that's not
you know so we want to focus on let's
get back to the problem
so the wolm language Yeah the code
here we are doing pattern
matching right now the issue is the code
is not efficient
enough and too it's too slow for doing a
million
times and we try to improve the
efficiency and uh one of the things we
are looking into is this replace
repeated it is inefficient because every
time it does a pattern matching
replacement it has to compare the huge
Matrix you know just how long does it
take to compare a matrix let's let's try
it okay you know what if let's find out
if that is exactly the problem okay so
timing let's do a timing uh and timing
what on timing timing of this Matrix
then equals
to equal uh
wait equal to the same
Matrix paste okay so we are comparing
the same EX exact Matrix actually The
Matrix is already a variable so we can
just say x
Matrix
okay but we want to do this 10 times I
mean one you know like one 1,000 times
so uh what is that uh repeat I think the
command to repeat is
um two Okay so
so let's look up the documentation of do
do expression end times that's right so
we're going to
do
um
bracket copy
that paste it here and uh 1,000 times
okay so we're gonna do this
cut
it paste it timing of comparing equal
equality that's
instantaneous
therefore right wait
so the the solar slowness may not be
[Music]
actually the replace repeat it oh God no
this is
getting so where does the sless come
from okay I'm getting annoyed I'm
getting
tired uh
I think I want to stop but if I stop now
it's no good because we didn't solve the
problem and uh talks talked all all this
while so right now we don't know so we
are trying to improve the efficiency and
we are looking at replace repeat it
because we think it's too
slow uh and the reason we think it's too
slow because of each time it has to do a
samess comparison for the entire
Matrix but if you actually do this 1,000
times it seems
instantaneous
so if you do 10,000 times let's see
shift enter it's also
instantaneous uh looking good hey josi
uh so we don't know so right now I do
not know so the the problem right now we
have a solution but the solution is too
slow you know this this
function and we and that's that is a
problem that is a problem we've been
trying
to solve in the past one
hour uh we improved
you know few things um but actually we
don't know uh so
okay I need to take a break
because I'm getting as rot you know
sitting for too long you will
get back pen and neck pain and also s
the
problems so I think I need to now I
KNE yeah now it's better now I
KNE
uh like because typically I walk for at
least 5 minutes every hour then every
two or 3 hours I walk for 30
minutes so but right
now it's not good because I've been we
been stck on this for hour I need a
break need to go to the bathroom too and
my coffee is
gone uh so should we
stop okay
so so let's focus a little little bit so
we do not know actually what is causing
the slow down okay so we do not know
what is actually causing the slow
down uh the slow down we do not know is
it transpose
no the slow down replace repeated yeah
actually we do not know where
here the slow down
happens okay very annoying so if we
select
all control
a and run it
again shift enter
you see 10 raised to 3 that's just 1,000
1,00 times take 11
seconds you see 1,00 * 11
seconds so 1,000 *
takes 11
seconds now but you're going to run it 1
million
times so 1
million times divided by 1,000 let's try
it divided by
1,000 then times
11 so the total time we'll need
is that many
seconds now that divided by
60 okay let's get the approximate
number
what yeah [ __ ] I don't want
that 60
then divided by 60 that's how many
hours
[ __ ]
what 30,000 hours wait that's not right
wa seconds okay so
that's
what wait this is uh wait so a medon
99 okay divided by 1,00 *
11 okay then okay then divided by
is how
many
minute
okay let's get
uh that many minute then divided by six
see that's how many
hours
what oh this one cannot work
then so the efficiency is utmost
importance okay so the but there there
are two things I don't understand I do
not understand why is our current move
language code is
is this slow okay I mean even with
pattern
matching function apply the function
four times what so we are you know this
cycle function you
know that ruls the ball then we are
doing just the
nest Nest
shouldn't uh you know are we doing the
nest correctly yeah you shouldn't uh
take that
long let's see the
documentation
okay so n just apply the function end
times right so it doesn't it shouldn't
add any extra time to
it okay so um
yeah it's
very in interesting and then the final
result it this is very easy just map
so so I'm not seeing
why you know what why is it just take 10
seconds to do do to do this a thousand
times so what does it mean
a thousand times I mean if we just do it
one
time that means we are doing replace
repeated
it pattern matching
this shouldn't be that
long after all the Matrix is just 10 by
10 uh and
then you see this this tail and head is
problematic I mean those zero this means
you know one triple low line means zero
or more
of
anything and those are problematic
because those are potentially very very
slow so because when you try to match
zero or more times it has to try zero
then try match then one time then try
match you know so and then plus then you
have a tail zero or more so those are
yeah okay so that's a new thing we just
we we now know I you know I should try
to remove zero this zero or more but is
that possible is it possible to remove
it uh I think so because uh so that gets
us
to uh so many code we confuse which one
is
where uh okay not this
one this is this is original pattern
okay so let's rename
it okay so this is original
pattern okay we orally we are not trying
to match the
longest which is even more slower okay
so close that original pattern then uh
let's go to what is
this yeah this is the more efficient we
are trying to do so let's try now
without the zero or more okay
yeah so any [ __ ] here this is so
wrong invalid syntax I [ __ ] up some
[ __ ] up
somewhere uh okay so let's fix
this oh actually this this is like that
yeah okay so copy that paste it here now
this
block let's remove the zero or more okay
so um so remove that so we got this
pattern okay this pattern uh this
pattern
what okay replace this by this
now now remove the tail okay so this
tail well you need to tail so
yeah you need to
tail so what we can do is we can replace
the zero or more in the
beginning by something
not oh wait
and you you needs a lot of thinking you
need a lot of
thinking but now I'm getting tired I
don't want to deal with
this x
says because you are taking a Brute
Force approach
okay nice
remark so you are suggesting that there
is
[Music]
some uh I mean one interpretation which
of your suggestion is that
uh is that we can think about this
problem
mathematically so you know we think
about these moving balls moving marbles
like the so bang maybe there is a
logical
shortcut that's one
interpretation you are claiming I'm
doing Brute Force
I mean well I mean you I don't I don't
think this what I'm doing is Brute Force
exactly because some problems you really
just need to follow the
steps because I'm just following the
steps it's not exactly Brute Force
um yeah because Brute Force when the
word Brute Force when it when it uh
applies it means the problem has some
kind of higher structure so it can be
solved without you know just following
the TDS details it it has some kind of
higher order uh
structure yeah very interesting
analysis because that's what stepan
wolam is talking about all the time the
irreducibility of comp
computation you see given a kind of a
problem for example this is a example
you can boot force it in fact all
computation
ultimately needs to be boot forced
because generally speaking there is no
higher pattern in order to predict a s
the the
future the only thing you can do is just
run the program just let the life happen
you know if you want to know what
happens 10
years you know in the next you know
after 10 years you just have
to let the atoms compute the universe
there's no shortcut so all manners of
prediction this
fail theoretically theoretically
speaking that is the
one answer to the mystery of the
universe according to stepan woler
there's no absolutely no other shortcut
I mean there's little you know like you
know boot for you know some part of it
you know there's little pockets you know
you can you have mathematical theories
differential equations or calculus you
can you know on small parts of this
situation but the overall is just it's
just BL you just have to run a program
Pro
Force okay that's his that's his theory
but I mean this is a big Theory because
we don't know nobody knows if a God
exist
maybe maybe there's shortcut maybe
there's answer to the
universe
uh yeah but so far scientifically when
you run you know El elmus uh you know
the the
rocket you basically solve you know lots
of these equations just brot force you
know well numerical Solutions and trial
and eror and and in um and just run
Dynamic interpret I mean you know just
try and error
basically you know especially regarding
the error Dynamics you know all these
aerodynamics the you know
stress uh simulation yeah you run
simulations you you know or simulate the
black hole what happens you know you
simulate which is Brute
Force so anyway so you are saying so
this problem is there some kind of so
some kind of mathematical more
abstractions shortcut or
something so in that case we have to
think about how these SP rolls okay so
when they
roll yeah you know it's an interesting
problem so now first thing to know is
that they always
roll in four directions in in this order
North West
Southeast so
so we have to think about how in what
circum situations we we said before you
know give give the mathematical
condition where running the cycle come
out exactly the both are in exactly the
same
place okay give giving the
condition you know and well but that
requires thinking and uh
that requires thinking
so so we'll have to start to draw so
let's see if I can draw
something
uh okay let's try to draw
so so a marble
so so Northwest Northwest South East
least and I don't know I don't know you
have to think about I mean this is
a so what exactly is a
condition well one of the condition is
there's no balls okay that's easy then
then this I mean so you can narrow down
you can break down the problem is just
by thinking Just One Direction okay
let's just say North first so the
condition for the ball no change is is
that all the boss has a war on the North
all the
boundary all
right or either there's no balls in the
column or there's always you know for
each ball that exist there's a north
wall immediately to the
north uh is at a complete
condition I think
so so similarly for the West if you R if
you te the ball to the West what is the
condition
that that the ball stays the same
place well the condition is that if each
ball has an immediate W To the
Left Right is there anything
else it seems right either immediate
wall or a boundary of The Matrix okay
and similarly for South and East but
what if you connect them together let's
say move North First and
West so the first condition is there are
[Music]
no that means that all ball has a there
are no ball which does not have a wall
on the
North okay so that means if
simple some of these marble some of this
you know Round
Rock do not have a immediate north wall
or the northern edge of the Matrix
then then that ball Will Roll
right so as long as there's one single
ball
then then the Matrix is changed
so in other words so to okay to reduce
computation what you can do is that you
find all
the
BS their column vertical column that has
a vert that has a northern
wall as immediate neighbor then you can
elimin eliminate
those rowes you know you don't have to
compute about
them
right
so so the similar things apply if you
want to tear The Bard to the west or
south or other direction but the problem
is how do you
determine if if a if if all the boss
that has a Northern war in order to
determine that you are essentially doing
the
computation or is there some kind of
trick right do I make sense to this
person X who are you X are you you know
are you
Steve you know some of you are Steve who
are you X so so far I'm not seeing a
shortcut or did I not think about the
problem deep enough let's think about
the logical problem under what
circumstances the the ball cannot
move so I mean there's I mean overall I
think there are still some questions I
haven't explored about The Logical
aspect of the math
problem like when does the ball move is
here some situation you can you know
Skip the computation and conclude
that the ball will be will not move or
something you know like basically trying
to shorten the
computation I'm not seeing
away and hello take path I think we're
going to stop today and you know
so and I'm not seeing a shortcut
solution to this
problem yeah genu generally I mean today
I'm fresh I'm not seeing a shortcut
solution to the problem but my solution
is too slow so slow I cannot run it but
the problem but how can I how why cannot
I improve it because I try
uh I don't not I do not seems to
see where is the bottleneck in my
solution
so okay I think I'm not going anywhere I
better stop so thank you guys for
watching for the fun ride fun or boring
ride whichever it is now it's 3 hours I
should
stop bye guys
let's see how many people watching three
five uh let's go YouTube
n okay bye guys thank you for watching