good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of our talk show today is 2019
November 2nd saturday saturday no san
francisco time did I miss anything
okay so good morning guys so so good
morning guys we do not have a fixed
topic today and let's just talk about
random random stuff and but Bartholomew
kept asking me about Keith's lab part
says talk about Keith's lab tracking
feature planned then we moved I don't
know nothing about that the invar says
mother's ball says they tried to
introduce a tracking feature into get
lab then community backslash now they
cancelled it okay okay what do you want
me to say
so as like what do you want me to say I
don't know nothing about it kid lad
you know the question I wonder is how
did how does kid lab make money you know
since a year or two ago two years ago
Microsoft bought github then everyone
all the Nerds is like oh we need to
switch to Gil app gillip crap you know
the the kid oh yeah okay so here comes
another topic a torrent of topics about
the history of gitlab the history of the
repository you know a software version
of yz+ a websites you know before get
lab get lab I mean github before github
becomes the number one most popular
there were several competitors there's a
get like you don't even I don't even
remember the names now but there are at
least two
competitors they are head-to-head I mean
no one is more popular than the other so
you have given github you have what
what's the names guys you guys remember
I can remember and I can remember the
name if I try to think about it but
usually when I'm talking
my brain is have 50% gun so anyway
there's a good lab there is a beat
bucket yes
I mean github kid lab is new ok let's
forget about kid lab for the moment pit
bucket github there's another one
there's another one okay at least this
another one that's that's at least three
of them so around 2008 oh so did you
know do you have these several then then
you know it was one of my question why
did Kidz hub become the most popular you
know gradually over the years kid hub
becomes the one people go to the other
the others just went away you know is
your pit pocket is still there I think
it's not owned by Alexia's or selection
something bit bucket in fact I have my
entirety of my websites Alexian
Atlassian yeah that's the one alas Ian
they are still around I have all my
websites on there you know I'm using big
bucket I stopped I stopped updating
since about three years ago so my
website so you have 7,000 HTML files you
have all together including image files
you have like 30,000 files you know a
big thing all my websites sorry in folks
are the org charts some music you know
song big pocket why because it's free
it's free you cannot do so it's private
and it's free on bitbucket
it's free if you if you only have like
one or two users something like that you
can make it private
but on github you could you know if you
want it to be private you have to pay
right away so that that is why I was
using bitbucket you know to sync my
websites in case in case my TARDIS died
and I don't have money you know this is
few years ago I still don't have a you
know backup kind of so so I was hissing
bitbucket
this is like three years ago but I
stopped I haven't been logging into
stuff anyway so but I'm talking about
2008 also 2000 you know when this you
know kit itself begin around what 2005
or so so get begin 2005 and also back
then you have several competitors you
have mercury mercury you have you know
there are at least a total of three of
them you have mercury and you have the
another one the goon project is using
his sucks donkey ass is one of the worst
okay okay the history of and then you
have SVN before that you have CVS okay
okay there's a lot of topic to talk
about I mean the question is which one
I'm gonna focus what kind of thing am I
gonna focus on so you have CSV and okay
I actually have a tutorial of SVN now as
SVN to you guys we've you know if you
are young you probably don't know but
SVN is SVN is actually kind of new you
know subversion when you get old
everything's you know back then you this
is like the hip hipsters thing SVN it's
like the brand new thing everyone needs
to you need you need to switch to it
immediately guys you need to use a
subversion if you don't use subversion
you are idiot okay you need to switch to
it subversion this is you know the
subversion began around 2002 something
or actually 2000 2001 or something
subversion is
us to be the you know the the rewrite of
the CVS okay now CVS is another thing I
don't have a tutorial here I know CVS
inside out because that's what we were
using so CVS and before CVS you have
something else you know so this is
history of computing you know history
you don't you don't you don't know if
you are not there so you have CVS then
you have subversion CVS has got lots of
problems and terms of the UNIX
problems in CVS okay the UNIX philosophy
everything is wrong and then you have
subversion subversion supposed to be to
fix the CVS okay is try to complete me
right of CVS then okay then Lina's
towboats came up he created the get okay
now before so get what's new with get
that the new thing the new concept with
git is distributed you know it's
distributed its in its kind of entirely
new but however kit is not the first one
before get there is this one on Haskell
code I don't even remember the names now
does anyone remember the name there's a
Haskell versioning system written in
Haskell that is that is the first
distributed version control system I
should be able to remember the names
guys do you guys remember okay we need a
Haskell people here we need justing well
this is like ten years old okay ten
years ago so Haskell has one this is the
first distributed you know back then the
distributed idea is new so am I in my
life it would be okay I think oh by the
way Emacs conference is going on okay so
you guys can go watch that if you get
bored of my grant Emacs comfort
is happening right now like Emax
conference 2019 this year and they are
supposed to be all you know it's the
teleconferencing so it's not actual
actually live somewhere but it's all by
videos so what VCS what not VCS what is
VCS do you think there is any reason to
use SV and over Kip no SVN is like
already dead even though if it if it is
technically superior but I do
but even that you don't use it because
practically speaking instead nobody is
using it if you use it it's like you are
using you know name Julia this common
list okay nobody cares you know you are
out of the social structure so shoulder
but even technically it's not better
than gate because SVN SVN is not
distributed okay but you know it's just
sold so so back to my topic so you have
CVS you have sv n sv n is the new thing
okay then the leanest robots created kit
which is supposed to be ground up new
this the the new idea is actually the
distributed thing and he's a great coder
you know he's the C types three type of
low-level
Colonel fire system see you know the low
level memory memory stuff pointers that
dose of crap you know these these type
of people you know Lena Stovall is that
type of people you know the low level he
doesn't know he doesn't know anything
else you know some you know yeah he's
you know he only know the C he doesn't
know JavaScript like like like he has no
idea how what it is like you know he's
like that he just see so Linux travolt
created kit and but and but get the new
idea
distributed but however it's not a new
idea that because there is a has cow one
I need to find the Haskell one don't
anyone remember the name virtual control
system open-source she oh okay let's I
forgot the name okay let's just search
for it has cow version control system
you need to say distributed ok back then
this is the first one this is around
2006 doc there it is stock now doc now
doc is written doc you know Doc's is so
Doc's
can be forget ok it is the distributed
version control system written in
Haskell it's written by a professor who
is a physics you know physics professor
now this guy he's as apparent apparently
he's studying quantum mechanics
ok let's search for Sally talk because I
have an article on that da RCS there it
is ok you know this this is written in
2007 this is history
guys history by the way we have another
question from from Carrick who is asking
about programming languages we do not
get to that okay remind me if I didn't
so so so you have distributed
distributed revision control systems
Haskell dogs and math sacrilege okay so
talk is written in Haskell and it's
written by this physicist professor guy
okay so so there's interesting thing
going on okay here
this is open-source well it's not
you know it's not okay this Arco is
complaining about some human human
personality problem it's not really
about open source okay I take that back
anyway let's read it for a bit so but
let's remember where are we going so I'm
talking about so let's read it down
that's the best thing to read write down
what you are talking about version
control history
okay history of version control systems
CVS there's something before CVS on UNIX
I forgot the name ok but when I was in
doing UNIX system in 1998 CVS is the
predominant one there is like before CVS
there is something like patch you know
UNIX command line patch stuff so cvs cvs
subversion or SVN known as SVN then you
have haskell docks okay
first distribute it okay then you have
magnify
then you have git okay we are talking
about that then there are several topics
let's write it down what are we talking
about the story of docks by a quantum
mechanics physicist
how do you spell physicist
okay physicist okay wait is that right
physicist okay that's valid correctly
quantum mechanics you know this guy did
the story of human how do you say that
the story of let's just say arrogance
it's not arrogance exactly of Doc's by
quantum mechanic okay physically that's
a story a story of human arrogance of
dogs by a quantum mechanics physics
teasing mathematics okay he's a quantum
mechanics but mechanic physics and he's
like you know DC mathematics he thinks
he knows stuff and he wrote hero dogs
you know has cow he's a Haskell phonetic
no doubt and that you know that's a and
and in the story of open source okay
related to open source and the story of
open source okay
lots of dark issues you don't know you
don't hear it and you don't want to know
you open source fans you lovely open
source fans you don't know it because
you don't want to know and the story of
human arrogance of dogs okay it's not
arrogance but we will talk about that
then the history of web hosting sites of
version control system
okay so actually Doc's kit okay wait
wait so so you have CVS subversion Doc's
kit you have mercury and you have
another one you have at least two more
mercury and one insisted insisted by
Richard Stallman he you know it's
very bad about only two three years ago
about in 2016 or 2017 the Emacs finally
switched to get okay so what what is the
other one it's it's run by the company
that runs Rubin - so what what is a
company that runs open - what's what's
the company the the company behind that
was Ubuntu they anyone knows canonical
okay so I think yeah CAA owing SEO
canonical canonic canonical version
control system version control system
there is a one what what's the name I
forgot but let's look up good morning
Emily good morning to UK and good
morning to you German guys okay so it's
not here not like these days you cannot
find it anymore if you don't know the
name but let's go to Wikipedia version
control system this way we can see all
the other ones in history like they have
a list of version control systems I'm
sure so so let's see version control his
system's history structure graph
structure graph structure my ass
specialized strategies sauce management
model
SMUD of my ass these programmers they
don't know nothing they everytime when
whenever they have a chance they try to
introduce math joggins but they have no
idea what they're talking about like
graph distributed like the you know like
the keep kid people they like to say Oh
get is just a directed graph directed
graph yeah ass distributed revision
control integration branch and they have
at least I want the list of systems okay
least a version control software okay so
before CVS there is this RCS okay and
there is this s CCS those are before CVS
okay so these are 1990s
now the RCS and SC CS they are kind of
just a command line you know you you do
you do patch and diff kind of like that
I haven't used them but so okay so after
that this is 1990s so after that the CVS
is the actual kind of the first vo
version control system CVS okay CVS then
you have subversion which is kind of
rewrite of CVS Vesta I don't know then
okay proprietary okay I don't know about
proprietary stuff okay
you have a bunch of proprietary stuff
one that I know which is pretty famous
is the proprietary ones which one is it
used by Linux for a while I think
yes used by Linus Torvalds for a while
prepared everyone's I forgot what's the
name vote maybe I forgot
so distributed there it is stocks so you
can see Doc's here is the first one okay
yeah so there we have it
pasa pasa pasa
fahza a Z aar okay buzzer is Canonical's
you know they are trying to do it
and it's used by used by Emacs to2015 or
something you know by by 2015 Bazar is
long time dead like okay the the the
version control war you know it's like
browser war you know the so in in around
2005 you have kid you have darks you
have mercury you have Bazar and there's
another one big geek peak Kiva ok
bitkeeper okay so bitkeeper yeah big
Kiba is the actually okay bit Kiva is
proprietary but mokuba okay not mercury
Mercurio mercurial and mokuba oh and
guna arc okay so i I suppose we can put
Kuno Hawk here you know these new ones
is like nobody uses except a few like 10
pneumo phonetics free software phonetics
so you know you am on the open source
you have the open source then you have
the free software foundation they are at
war you know they they don't like each
other that they you know the in
particular the free software foundation
the richest demand camp despise the open
source I mean it's just the it's just a
war you know it's internal you don't you
don't talk about it much
these open source phonetics
they do society wrong so you know buzzes
so a so you have bossa and talks you
have Faso anyway the the most famous you
know back in around 2006 also the the
the version control system war is
actually what and get kit is not you
know more popular than the others so
it's it's like in a software industry we
still trying to find which one you know
there's no no one standard you know
everyone you know you use that I use
that you know some other one company use
others so it's a war you know it's
fighting it out eventually get get one
you know why did get wrong so anyway so
the history of version control system so
you have this punch okay and then let's
talk about why did get wrong okay now
nobody can say for sure because that's
kind of a social question but for my
opinion get warm because Lena Stowe
votes who is famous for Linux
that is why okay for no other reason not
necessarily because kid is technically
superior okay not necessarily in fact I
would not say it is it is technically
superior in several ways so but but
mercurial for example is easier to learn
and it was originally written it was a
deep in Python or Ruby alphabet which
was a Python Ruby guys Mercurio so
anyway get one but I wouldn't say
absolutely you know it's kitty is pretty
good technically but but in my opinion
it one in my opinion get one mostly
because the fame of leanness okay who
created Linux okay that that's it that's
because you know he's famous everyone
wants to know what shirt he's wearing
you know so he won't okay Mercurio is
written in Python okay yeah right Python
so anyway in the end get one and the
others just gradually died that died out
you know like like people you know
people you know like in open-source
community you have fanatics everywhere
you have Python fanatics Python almost
you know you must want you must write
everything in Python oh but no you must
run everything UV
ruby is the best better one then at
least profess phonetics you know they
they are like that nerds you know they
fight fight stuff all day day and night
in it so in a in the inversion control
so we are talking about version control
system war circa 2005 to 2010 I don't
you know something around there okay
eventually get won't get one okay but
when it's not too clear
you know it's written on a wall it is
gonna be the one for the future but they
ask you o makki real uses you know they
are still fighting it but you know at
the end this happens you know like for
example these programmers today it's
already dead you know but ten years ago
you co see some whispers they insist
this you know there's gonna be you know
see you around things like that so
anyway eventually get one and that's
because in my opinion why in my opinion
is simply simply because mostly because
Lena's he is the most famous you know
he's a hotshot he's a big-shot he's the
he's the talker he's saying you know
you he's saying you you know
Nvidia yeah have you guys seen the video
given an Nvidia you know the graphics
system the graphics card maker you know
the game for gamers no no no no you
Lina's well actually you know that's
that's that's that's not code for but
anyway you know you my complaints about
you know the open source you know the
talk activities and stuff you don't see
you know because when you see open
source you you think of the the the
goodness of humanity Oh everyone's
sharing no we must help each other we
must then they becomes we must help
women we must help blacks we must help
the poor they become social justice can
you know if you don't do what I say
go yourself I'm gonna I'm gonna
read you know you're gonna be fired
you're gonna be you know whatever that
becomes social justice scat social
justice warrior they have roots in the
opens open source fanaticism
they have you know the roots camp you
know in part okay
the reason social justice can rise there
are many quite a lot reasons political
and academia and but part of it in a
software industry it because open-source
mentality spread by the open-source
community by the way did you guys know
that the social just just is people they
are for communism does anyone not know
that have you guys seen you know the
riots in USA you know in Europe too but
I don't know much about Europe but in
USA and the USA politicians the
Democratic they are saying communism
socialism they antiva can can stir they
are flying communism flags the Russian
flags did you guys know or does anyone
not know that please raise your hand
okay yeah social justice communism from
Woburn sauce you know so so so that's
about the virtual version control system
war okay and get one okay so so that's
that now the next topic is the war the
next topic the history of web web hosts
inside servers a version control systems
war this is when you have kid hub github
and what's the others let's try to
remember the names so I can you know I
want to actually beat bucket okay so you
have github bitbucket then you have
Quito something does anyone remember
Quito github first okay so let's go to
Wikipedia again wikipedia has always
have these lists
so let's go to github gitlab gitlab is
new ok don't talk shut up kid lab is
like the latest craze kid lab that did
not exist I don't think in 2008 now now
we were talking about 2008 the history
of web hosting sites you know before
github wrong you know we were talking
about that kid hab kid lab was not there
I don't think so so we were talking
about O'Gill a biz kid no what what are
you talking about github ok let's let's
look at the HDD ZFS I don't know what
they are you talking about file systems
awkward so github let's go through we
want to go to the we want to go to the
oh this this cat this cat is a great
artwork you know this is a great example
of logo this is mascot this is great one
actually you know you look at the github
history you know the social justice war
do you guys know about this github you
know it's when it rose you know 2007 and
you know the you there's several
incidents of the social justice fighting
big news big and small every year like
part you know that did you know
open-source you know the talk politics
the fighting the crawling crawling each
other's out eyes out open source
you know because once you remove the
money then people cannot you know the
open source mentality is that we share
or we must share we must help each other
we must you know help each other then
once you remove the motivate motivation
for human survival that you are not
allowed to prosper money
you know you are not allowed to you must
share everything you own must share you
must not have properties that's
communism okay guys you know communism
you cannot have a car everything you own
is is public property that's the
ultimate sharing mentality ultimate we
share everything you should not have
everything by yourself your money is
mine okay your money give it to me open
source that's the ultimate open source
mentality super chat guys now I have now
thanks to Google now I have super chat
ok ok so we back to we are trying to
look for a list of the websites that
that that hosts the github and stuff a
scope license of repositories give
github enterprise there we have it
enterprise and now it's bought by
Microsoft and now everyone is like oh no
no no we cannot use it anymore let's
switch to get lab get lab every day get
lab this kid lab that and next year
get lab you know when google says Hankey
laughs yeah i'm gonna give you a billion
dollars you're gonna do this for us okay
by next year that so it's so 2020 then
everyone is they then they're gonna be
something something else you know the
open-source Oh panic oh my god keep
laughing spot out by Google what are we
gonna do we're gonna oh I'm gonna create
a new thing then every every every
open-source is nothing oh this this gift
kit lap new kid lab - everybody's
telling you you need to switch you need
to switch the open-source so what
do you guys think you know let me ask
you the open-source phonetics so what do
you guys think yeah
open-source so you have kid lab ok get
lab or whatever it's doing good right
it's too neat supposed to be good
so next year they're gonna put out by
Google whatever you know oh by Facebook
let's say they gonna do it you know so
you gonna do it you know if Google says
you know tomorrow says hey Bart I'm
gonna give you a million
you know because I like you and you're
gonna you're gonna stop so you're
gonna stop saying your things anymore
that's the same thing that's that's the
thing every why is that you know you can
just easily because that that is what
actually works that's not natural you
know there's nothing wrong with it you
know you create you work hard you create
gitlab then Google likes it Google wants
to buy it you know they are not putting
a gun on your head you know that's
illegal they ask you you know I'm gonna
give you a billion dollars you sell or
not it's up to you then then what you're
gonna do okay I work hard you know I
think I deserve it yeah I want to say oh
it I said it then tomorrow it's owned by
Google that's the story of kid hub kid
lab and everything else so what do you
think that you you you open source
phonetics office office software
phonetics what do you think of this so
you know yeah open source then then cook
about it he said then the next year you
can all the people he's gonna switch or
not what what you're gonna do I mean he
said it do you think something is wrong
they here oh you think this is this is
perfect
this is what it should be yeah every you
know kid lab they will be sold out you
know that already and you are fine so
next year when they are sold out then
you're gonna switch you know you're
gonna spend days to change switch all
your project toward the other one he
said you know you said normal is that
what you guys open-source phonetics free
software phonetics you think that's the
way it should be or what is what is it
what what is your answer like what is
your retort to my rant again it's open
source yeah ready says yeah yeah what oh
my god github so let's look at the the
that's let's look at let's look at the
list of the list of websites that host
the github thing okay so let's see
collaborative innovation network what
what the the mouse for common base
peer production
comparison okay there it is a list of
source code hosting facilities you know
just just say web web site not facility
facility my ass I'm a Superman I kind of
told my sentiment of today Matt okay so
mad so so so comparison so we are
talking about the history of web hosting
you know the web sites that host this
thing is this this version control
system so you have if SourceForge oh my
god sauce watch how could we forget you
you are the oldest granddaddy of the web
hosting open source stuff that reminds
me fresh meat
oh my god the history fresh meat now
Chris do you guys know what is fresh
meat like raise your hand does anyone
know what is fresh meat say it okay
fresh meat okay you guys don't know
history the history of you know history
you know history is something nobody
knows nobody cares you've at least
forgotten if it doesn't sound good to
you it's forgotten if it sounds good you
sound good to you you remember it you
know they say history is written by the
winners
fresh meat Pitt Buckhead okay github
these are all the popular ones fresh
meat fresh meat and SourceForge okay
and PTI okay I think I remember get here
I don't remember
and I'm talking about just some of the
popular ones I mean they are hundreds
there but I'm talking about some of the
you know popular whisk goo-goo-goo
Savannah that's the one that's why you
spiked new sucks donkey ass sucks the
incredible the most worst donkey ass you
know you look you go look at the goose
the website you know their websites like
from 1999 you know this is the one
not updated turns up you know
Louie look at this garbage you don't
know where to look you know it's a view
it so just was because nobody works on
here no money and you know this is this
is free software foundations answer to
the you know to the github gitlab you
know you should support this one you
should use this one try it try try it
doesn't work in every everywhere
and you you try to fire a bug report
then after not no response after ten
years like I did you know as after 10
years they send you thank you letters
thank you your burger vote from 10 years
ago I still receive it like just two
weeks three weeks ago
oven sauce good news semana okay
this this new this is this is good news
free software foundations a version of
it let's go back let's see what the
others Launchpad indeed Launchpad
Launchpad was you know popular back then
then SourceForge SourceForge is the
oldest okay so features so let's just
say this okay just these so the story of
human okay so so the history of hosting
websites and version control systems
okay so this is that
okay so you have this this this bunch
okay so actually let's make it one line
so the history of web hosting sites
version control systems whoa
fresh meat is the earliest okay you guys
don't know Emily so you know yeah the
SourceForge you know it's long story you
know a sad story of open souls you know
open sores phonetics you forget you
don't know it because you don't want you
know you only see the positive things
everything else to you is the troll you
don't you don't see you leaving a bubble
open source phonetics fresh meat is the
earliest it began around 2000 or 1999
it began alongside alongside of slash
dot now slash dot some of us may still
know is the earliest online forum for
hackers so you have slash dot you have
fresh meat then you have the fresh meat
okay and and in about ten years ago they
changed their name why
because social justice you know the so
you know like in back in 1999 okay
around there the thus you know the
program is stuff I've done by you know
hackers and you know basically nerds
like us okay we swear all the time you
know for now gradually the social
justice rose and you know the the the
it's it's seeing us that you know they
you it's become you know you you have to
use pelagic politically correct phrases
you cannot swear things like that so
fresh meat about ten years ago I forgot
when they change their name but let's go
to freshmeat calm let's see what what's
up there
they change their domain names but let's
just have a look see was a dato go
dotnet or dot-com I forgot so let's see
fresh meat dog okay that that's no good
so let's it says I need JavaScript I
don't want to turn JavaScript on
so fresh meat come let's see what I
think it's not net okay that's probably
a bad fish meat dotnet okay dotnet
become sauce forge so he got bought out
by sauce which apparently long story
okay
fresh meat was the first online you know
a kind of repository of software then
well when we talk about that not now
there's also Perl Sipan okay see parents
even earlier but that's kind of
different but because Sipan is only for
pearl so we are talking about on one
hand
fresh meat sauce Forge github bitbucket
get lab these are about general purpose
software so you can find any software
there on the other hand there are things
like programming programming language
library repositories so for example Perl
is the earliest you have C pad you guys
know C pan like when I talk about these
things many things people don't know
anymore
C pan is pearls you know you go there to
find o / libraries basically okay so you
have C pan pearl the earliest then you
have tech tech pan for la tech you know
tech lock take collection of all you
know tech stuff
then then Python started to you know
then you have a lot more Ruby yes
there's Java as there's Python has
there's you know every language has
there's you know online
repository of all the libraries for that
language so that's that thing but we
were talking about the general software
repository so fresh meat
is the earliest one you don't I you
cannot even see the website anymore
because apparently it looks like they
are they've been merged with the fourth
SourceForge
anyway ten years ago they change their
name because fresh meat you know it's
kind of like it's offensive you know
that the social just it's type of people
will say oh that's offensive
fresh me but it's that it was named
fresh meat because they that was you
know nerds nerds talk you know what why
fresh meat because it's fresh and meat
it media is food you know you want it
it's like good thing fresh meat
when meat is not fresh it's no good you
get sick so you want fresh meat you know
it's a it's it's an allergy it's how
language quotes language the new words
are always created by analogy
you know fresh meat so when when you say
fresh me it's like in software it's like
oh another great software you like a new
item you know everyday they have lots of
new software you know open open source
so so maybe ten years ago I mean around
ten ten or so years they change your
name because they had Africa what's the
name they changed but apparently it
looks like they they got bought out by
SourceForge now SourceForge is another
earliest one started around I don't know
year 2000 I mean about the same time as
fresh meat so SourceForge but but
because so SourceForge is the earliest
okay before get before get was even
amended you know SourceForge but because
it's often sauce they make no money so
they they are dying they dying they then
then they become spat you go there you
have ads everywhere then you have more
where you know because the site owners
they have no money either you have two
choices shut down completely shut down
no more sauce for geo get shut down oh
you started to take so you started to
take money from you know
you know question questionable
advertisers or some more websites you
know some spammy ads so you know you
started to do question question about
things because you have no choice or you
shut down your site you know so so you
started to have you know bad things you
know you you use it you know you know
bad bad ads spammed ads or so more where
links things like that so so that's the
story of SourceForge you know then you
know the people the open source fanatics
they started to hate it because they
they were spread like like you guys you
know they are started to tell everyone
oh don't use so so much because you know
this or that that's the story of
SourceForge you can see the stories and
you know hacker news on slash dot you
know you can see them you forgot you
know by tomorrow don't worry about
anything I say today by have a cookie
because spied tomorrow you won't
remember a thing
okay you won't remember a thing by
tomorrow you'll be back singing the
songs of open source always forgotten
you won't remember a thing
trust me so SourceForge you know so it
became spammy and it became bad then a
few years ago I don't know five years
ago three or four years ago apparently
SourceForge got sold you know someone
else sports SourceForge and they tried
to fix everything so they try to say
okay guys you know we are new now forget
about our also SourceForge we are now
New York come back to us we are
SourceForge that is today's SourceForge
you see here so let's let's let's go to
the source
forge ok let's go through let's see this
difference with okay so now they look
like that you see now it's this is very
modern
you know the JavaScript libraries
frameworks it looks like that sauce
Forge but you know so I don't know this
fresh meat is like
a part of source photo what what is it I
don't know but anyway but it retains
kind of the if you look at the you know
fresh meat tart sourceforge.net it kind
of retains the style of fresh meat you
know it looks like Slashdot you know
it's kind of the 1999 kind of remainder
style but SourceForge now it looks like
that so that's you know so fresh meat
and sauce watch are the earliest you
know get the earliest github then we
have feed pocket we have github we have
guna savannah we have launchpad now
these are new around let's say 2006 so
so at that time there is a wall there's
a you know the web hosting version
control system war each one tries to win
win because you know the more people use
your website you have more chance of
making money
so eventually github long why does kid
hop one I think mostly because you know
back then oh this website they support
they support any of several numbers of
version control systems for example big
bucket will say oh we support get we
support Mercurio we support bazaar we
support dogs you know things like that
usually not dark because talks the has
stalled ox is very small but anyway you
know they all try to support different
websites of all different others by the
way there's also I almost forgot this is
important there is Google code
google code my god it's forgotten now
it's history Google code remember Google
began their own web hosting website that
hosts software projects you know open
source ones basically and they also this
they support kit they support Mercurio
at least these two they also support
subversion yeah subversion
let's see if we can let me show you you
and I have a go Emacs hosted on Google
Code I have quite a few hosts you know
this one
now it's shut down you see wait and they
don't even show the there this is the
this was their logo now it's archived
because they shut it down you see this
is what it looks like Google code okay
Google code then Microsoft has also
created their own called Microsoft
multiplex or something okay was never
very popular I don't think so
it's course something does anyone
remember what's the Microsoft one it's
called Microsoft software hosting they
also shut down so well they bought
github of course but I think they shut
down before they bought github so I know
I don't know the name now but if you go
to Wikipedia you can you can find it I
think you can find it on Wikipedia
somewhere
somewhere here let's search for
Microsoft Azure DevOps services no
that's not the one there's another one
called something multiplex or something
anyone remember
okay anyway so that's a history of web
hosting websites now before we talk
about now actually I already finished a
subject you know I'm trying to give you
a history of that you know so but there
is this about quantum mechanics
mechanics sky where I wrote an article
this is someone interesting so let me
read it so this is 2007
now remember doc Haskell talks is the
first distributed version control system
before get okay so I say you know so you
have to when you read this article you
have to remember this is 2007 so when
you read it you get the sense of what
it's what it is like back in 2007 as
time goes by you know I don't I don't
even remember what's you know what what
what was it like you know like you don't
remember when when you were five years
old you know what is it like you know
you forgot when you were became adult so
anyway this is 2007 let me read it when
I first heard about distributed where
when I first heard about distributed
revision seat control system about two
years ago I heard of dogs which is
written in Haskell I was hugely excited
thinking about the function of
programming I loved and the no side
effect pure system I idolized and the
technology of human animal I rapture in
Davie I have no serious actual need to
use a revision control system in recent
years so I never really tried dogs no
actually no actively using any revision
system I just thought the newfangled
distributed tech in combination of
NASCAR was great about two months ago I
was updating a five years old a page I
wrote on UNIX tools the UNIX pestilence
tools in software
and I was trying to update myself on the
current state of the art of revision
systems
I read Wikipedia Docs in this passage
okay anyway that's kind of long and
that's my article is kind of long but
the the part I want to talk about is
this one so back then this guy David
Roundy Dave around II wrote talks okay
and he has a essay about theory or
patches as part of the docs
documentation theory or patches which is
no theory at all it's crap
it's these programmers you know he's a
he's a apparently he's a quantum
mechanics physicist and he's you know
he's thinking he's got a theory of
patches patching he theory my ass and
here's a quote he is here's what he says
I think a little background on the
author is in order I am a physicist and
I think like a physicist the proofs and
theorems given here are what I would
call physicists proofs and theorems
which is to say that while the proofs
may not be rigorous they are practical
and the theorems are intended to give
physical insight it would be great to
have a mathematician work on this but I
am NOT a mathematician and I don't care
for math this is what he says okay this
is full of himself whatever the word of
what a idiot
he's a physicist you know you know in in
the rearm of physicists or math
basically in hard sciences there is a
proof or there is no proof you don't say
oh this is a proof but this is not a
math proof because I'm a physicist
therefore my proof is physicist oriented
practical proof
[Laughter]
there's no such thing okay any physics
even even physicists any physics in in
academic community we are look at this
you cannot publish this if you published
no journal we all accept this paragraph
but this guy you know he's writing a you
know the documentation for Doc theory of
patches you know as part of the
documentation for Doc that's what he
says you know this crap then I flamed
him you know I flamed him on Haskell
oops you know when Haskell group spanned
me so so I say I say I love math I I
love math I respect math I'm nothing but
a menial menial servant to mathematics
who who is this David guy who proclaims
that he is no mathematician then
proceeded to tell us he doesn't care
about math then he went down about his
personal zeal for physics in particular
injecting the high D cracky quantum
mechanics with impunity so that that is
my flame you know I posted in in an IRC
Haskell community you know they they
tend to pan me the you know birthday
Pammy - right so you know after a few
years after a year or two I forgot when
I noticed you know you've got you go to
the docks
you know the docks documentation that
paragraph is removed okay you don't see
that paragraph anymore however you also
will not see any thanks thank you credit
to me you will not see it this happens a
lot in the open-source communities I
criticize you know I attack them they're
there because they are saying one plus
one equals two three I say go
yourself you are saying one plus one
equal to three and no and everyone is
spanning me you know everyone the open
source pockets they just spammy okay but
after a few years which they quietly
changed they change their stuff so
that's a story about that
this happening Haskell community so okay
that's a lot talk that's a lot vent so I
want to forget that the story of human
arrogance this is the story of not human
arrogance of mass sacrilege so so are
you guys still here you you guys tired
of my rents so close that showing
browser so that's today's topic so no
but why not
Python Mathematica for data science
actually okay great
I think you guys are still here so how
long have I been talking I've been
talking for let's go to let's see how
many people live scream 13 watching now
oh I actually I need to go to the videos
page and go to go through the live
stream control
let me take a break okay I need to take
a break and and let's see so I've been
talking for one hour but there is
another interesting topic about how do
you define language expressiveness and
things like that so who asked that que
quick are you see or hear Carrick if you
still here say it okay because you know
then we talk about that because
otherwise let me just answer the
comments and maybe that's it for today
okay Rick is the idea okay so let's so
let's talk about that
so we talked a lot so so let's see Emacs
conference so by the way so Emacs
conference is going young you guys can
go watch it you know it's I think it's
gonna be whole day today there are
several live talks by people if you go
to my Emacs website such such folks are
de Max okay actually go to my Emacs blog
you can see the video sorry Emacs well
video and website here is a website
Emacs conf
Tarak you can watch it so that's about
Emacs conference and so let's so next
topic is about which language to learn
okay so let me see yeah so I should go
top you know answer the first question
first
so Eric says from your website which
programming language is more powerful or
expressive but remain readable this one
is hard to say so I give so I give my
rank ordering and cut
carick says how do you got
expressiveness I'm curious
despite we'll be ranking high why do you
favor Golan not even Midway the scale
well so to answer that simply you know
that's just that ranking cannot be too
much I mean there is no laughter there's
no absolute ranking so I mean just take
it as a grain of salt that's what I'm
saying unless they are you know they are
like they they differ by several places
then in my opinion that one is better
than that one but if they are adjacent
you know because they because there is
no easy way there is no actually there's
no mathematical way to define there is
but anyway in practice there's no way to
say which language is more expressive
expressive than the other there's well
actually one article in academic journal
that tries to define expressiveness
mathematically but that Arco is written
by one of the guys from the scheme this
you know Rice University you know
whatever that scheme this group you know
who is creating racket this is about
2005 or so so he I think he's guys I
forgot that the guy which one is it
matheus or something so I mean so he
wrote a article in in one of the journal
that tries to define expressiveness
mathematically and that alko is like
incomprehensible I think I blog it I
blogged about it somewhere but it's this
is long ago ten years ago you'd take or
take some time to find it anyway so he
tried to define it's mathematically but
the article itself is incomprehensible
besides that it's not practical I
because I don't think you know I don't
think he's doing the the right of you
know he's
I don't think he's approaching the
problem correct fees but but okay here
so so anyway so he tried to do that and
I think he failed and it's an academic
paper so nobody actually read it
so he so here I have a blog where I
quickly written down in 2019 July 17th
about which language programming
language is easier to learn so I say
goal and Ruby PHP scheme Python eMac
this JavaScript Java closure Perl
okay Mahaska and then which language has
the best talk okay then I give my
opinion
then which programming language is most
popular okay then I give my opinion then
which foreign language is more powerful
or expressive okay then I give this the
foul the following rank so ruby greater
than scheme greater than Python greater
than Perl greater than PHP then
JavaScript closure goal and Java tengo
camel then Haskell the new Mac B's so
what what is this about so this is about
which language is more powerful or
expressive yeah so it's powerful or
expressive yeah it's it's actually hard
to say you know it because it depends on
what you mean how do you define what do
you mean by powerful and how do you mean
by expressive but however I give this
list because in general okay this is I
think this this is a good general
opinion about that question about which
language is more powerful
so I rank ruby the best then scheme then
python ruby scheme Python
it's about the same okay but I would say
Ruby your scheme is is more expressive
than Python because why because Python
do not allow do not fully support
functional programming because pythons
lambda lambda is the most fundamental
thing you need for functional
programming however in Python the lambda
is crippled you know you cannot get to
it too much with it so that is why I say
Ruby and scheme is greater than Python
for expressiveness because functional
programming is part of you know it's
part of expressive expressiveness again
the the the opinion depends you know
there is no absolute way because for
example if you like Opie then you may
not think scheme was better than Python
because scheme is mostly functional for
me okay
so my my my ranking is kind of biased
towards functional programming but
anyway I put Haskell like near the
bottom because why did I put Haskell
near the pad bottom actually I forgot
you know if I gonna write this again
Oh camo and Haskell would be wait okay
yeah so I think I had some yeah if I I
wouldn't write that you know ok maja and
Haskell would be better than JavaScript
for sure so you know this is just a fun
list you know don't worry too much about
that
so Carrick asked about that so Carrick
has so does that make sense or do you
have anything else specific or anything
you are thinking Carrick so Harry says
how do you catch expressiveness I'm
curious despite Ruby ranking hi why do
you favor goal and not even Midway this
scale okay : where is : o : is mid well
Midway uh yeah I don't remember you know
when I wrote that you know like this is
kind of part of so you might say it's
true okay so if I do this again you know
I have some general idea that won't
change but however some of the details I
would if I read it today I will change
it depends so you know we have to get
specific like what do you mean which
language is more powerful or expressive
so I put closure greater than : well
yeah it's hard to say you see closure is
the language that focus on immutability
a lot you know in functional programming
so everything is a function and the most
things are immutable the data structure
our image immutable but closure is
really fairly complex fairly complex to
understand not just because it's a lisp
you know it closure is is this place
different from all the other disks so
you know I know least where you know
closure is not difficult because it's
Lisp but rather because it has its they
have lots of things you know it intermix
with Java that makes it incomprehensible
you know it's using Chavez concept of
interface I mean it's it's intertwined
with Java
you know meanwhile when closure tries to
market to people closure says oh we are
functional
we are immutable you know pure
functional language and so on but
meanwhile when you actually use closure
it's intentionally and heavily
intertwined with Java and with Java
teep teep
like not just son superficially teeth
down and intentionally expose or Chavez
internal stuff like Chavez interface
Chavez object concept Chavez you know
object hierarchy Chavez interface
hierarchy you know intentionally
intertwined with Java
you know deeply that's that's what
closure is that and that is why closure
is no good I don't like Rocha because of
that otherwise you will be great
so anyway closure is supposed to be you
know very functional and immutability on
the other hand colon colon is very colon
is extremely simple it's like see okay
but it's like it's intended to replace
see verse verse so anyway yeah anyway
said that's what's my take on which
hickey I think which he which is I think
he's a great guy he's kind of funny he's
he's not funny guy okay he's just not
funny like he's a nut and you watch this
nut he fight you find it funny okay he
himself is not a funny guy you know he's
just this nerd with the glasses this you
know kosher let's see let's show me my
Allah goes why Crozier sucks
okay there are two articles
you should read one of them is why
Crozier is tense okay so you have this
rich Hickey guy this rich Hickey major
nerds okay actually we are about to end
because we talked for okay eighty
minutes not not too bad yet so rich
Hickey so you guys should read this
article
why Crozier is tense okay this this I
talked about so this article is about
why Crozier is very difficult to
understand language a language very
difficult to learn okay and I explain in
detail why that is why why is that okay
I explained that detail then so here is
rich Hickey you know this guy and then I
talked about this this one this article
you should also read Crozier's
popularity a tango with Java okay so
this this quote trapped in the Train
trapped in a Java train northbound is
closure southbound is Scala you know so
if you are a Java developer in the Java
industry you have nowhere to go because
Java is this you know Java is like
industrial enterprise language
everything you do in Java is very boring
you know it's everything everything
that's written in Java that's typically
tied to you know I would call enterprise
programming like database
you know database numbers and you know
before business typically very very
boring not scientific programming not
anything else is like enterprise thing
and and so you are trapped in Java and
then if you are trying to find a escape
route you have to two routes closure and
Scala so anyway in this are cockroaches
popularity or tango with Java I explain
why I explain why crow sure is popular
somewhat okay the any popularity closure
has it is Java you have to thank to okay
it is Java you nothing else because Java
is the most popular language the top
five most popular language of them all
Java C++ Python today okay PHP
JavaScript basically these five yeah
more or less
PHP JavaScript Java tsipras first Python
this five yeah the the the most popular
today Java Java is a big monster ok Java
you have the JVM so Java is that you
know he it has its own niche you know up
it's like an octopus enterprise
programming everything is a pain in Java
but closure is like kosher is like
living in this Java a GoSee ecosystem
you know closure is turning the Java
programmers you know like millions of
them because Java is very popular so
closure is telling them hey Java code us
come over here we are functional and
everything you know about Java we still
walk you know because we are on top of
JVM that's the attraction that's the
trap of closure that that is why I
realized you know because I was studying
studying studying closure because it's
Lisp you know I like least you know I
hate Java I despite y'all despise Java I
don't want nothing to do with Java in my
life ok so I you know I want closure but
it's written in JVM and I thought ok
well you know what can you do it you
know JVM is very popular right ok but I
got so I'll accept that but you know I
want to learn kosher you know you can
write you know another the entirely new
language on top of Jim here it's it's
just implemented on top of JVM ok so I
learned kosher but then I realized like
every every time you you want to learn
the details like the full thing is
tight with Java like it mentions
Java interface Java object when you want
to process strings you have to use Javas
string class you have to use the closure
syntax that cost that creates the Java
string syntax Java string class Java
string object when you want to do
regular expressions you have to create a
Java regular expression class not
closure
Java Java class so when you study
closure the everywhere is
intertwined
with Java yeah you know so I got I got
very frustrated you know so I looked
into detail I tried to find out why is
that why this you know then I realized
then it's like oh oh my god Wow yeah
that's why because Java is the most
popular language and closure is
piggyback on it - is there for closure
gets popular that's why okay that is why
and so that is it is in fact intentional
you know the rich Hickey which he is a
Java programmer okay he's the inter he's
this enterprise programmer so anyway so
so it's implicit because you know it
benefit him you know if this this
intertwining with Java get gets closer
more popular so you don't you know you
don't you don't you know you don't think
about you know cutting the tie you know
you're just good it's good for you good
for closure it gets you to grow so
that's like everywhere intertwine with
Java and and and for me no thank you
thank you
goodbye closure so that is that is that
okay that that is today it is some
extent so bob says that is the whole
point of closure so you know there are
some closure fans when they when they
see me talk they see it disagree you
know they still they like to live in
this bubble of closure when you do
closure I have a terraria okay I have a
closure tutorial and then you have to
install you know it's like it's like NPM
it's like JavaScript NPM you is you know
Java you know you have to install a
noggin lannigan is this to set you have
to install a structure you know Lanigan
java jars libraries like when you
install this one dependency it installs
ten other dependencies and each one has
a cache you know then you have a
directory of cash Java's java cache you
know class cash around few hundred you
know files there you know this it's a
it's like
the it's a complex okay it's a
kosher kosher is a complex you have
to install you know like in what do you
mean complex because in Python for
example Python : Ruby Python Cola and
Ruby you want to learn them you install
them you install them and you can start
coding right away not nothing else to
worry about you install download Ruby
then you can start to type 1 plus 1 or
whatever
same thing with Python same thing with :
ok you start to learn so that you start
to code right away that's not a case
with closure ok that's not the case with
Java when you want to learn Java for
example you go to their website you have
the Java Java development pack whatever
Java you know Java standard edition Java
Enterprise Edition Java the things Java
network you know that you have like 10
you you have to spend one hour to to
figure out west what to download ok
that's the Java let's see let's go to
Java download you have to spend one hour
to figure out what all these Java
jargons are you know let's go to let's
go to the Java first of all you see you
have to website download free Java then
you have Java SE you know what a is
SE se standard edition then you have
Java standard edition Java SE runtime
environment $8 C then you have Java SE
develop development kit 8 download so
which one you know so you have so
that that's that's a complexity ok SC
standard edition Enterprise Edition then
then you have the runtime environment
then you have development kit you know
like you know if you are a newbie if you
are new you don't know you know so what
do you mean like so which one like you
know you don't know
but let's let's go to the the website
you know it's pretty bad okay so Java so
once you download it whatever it is you
know you know you have two things you
have the run time which is eight JVM
then you have the compiler Java C okay
the compiler you have to install these
two things okay I think my roommate is
back let me check and close the door and
I think that's it for today and okay so
so Java is really complex
Simpson thing with closure okay because
closure runs on top of Java and before
so you download the Java first
you know closure is actually just a
library it's just a jar file of Java so
you download closure it's just a you
know Java fire but when you want to
write a project in closure you have to
install then again then again is this
this tool to manage you know the you
know it has a structure it's like you
know you check dependencies it checks to
you know checks a bunch of things
complex you spend one hour to learn
Lanigan mode one day few days you spend
few days to learn delegate before you
can even start to code closure okay then
Emacs Ida you know which allows you to
run closure in in Java it's you know
it's connected with you know you know
the the the demo Ghanaian stuff is kind
of okay so closure is very complex it's
intertwined with Java you know this is
in contrast to like I mentioned before
Python : Ruby and many other languages
PHP you can download and you can learn
it right away you can code it right away
not the case with closure okay so I
think that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
so Bart says that is a whole point of
closure so what did you smoke
when saying : is very simple it's like
see ya : is very simple what is simple
about CC is simple
it's a universally agreed see simple
Thank You Emily so anything else I kind
of told my sentiment today
okay kidnap in Python create a
proprietary VCS of people don't use it
open source kit so kidney suppose we see
open source
she'll homogeneous system there's any
way is there any reason to use SVN no
not today
SV angel is basically dead and nobody is
using it you know you will find a
handful of people of course but kit you
know just kit is a standard discord and
I don't know why you have a big thing
about this code but this code is just
fine you know they you know they have
you know they have like I think Natron
version like you know for example if you
want fancy emoji then you subscribe you
pay you know ten dollars a year or
something or ten dollars a month you
subscribe you pay them then then you
have the ability to stream like sync my
youtube in this code so people can watch
me on this code things like that so I
don't know why you have a big issue
about this code and you and I thought
and you play games right so this code is
really popular I don't know why you
don't have an account and you know I
haven't heard of much evil things they
did you know this code look up this
score I did I already did I looked
Wikipedia I mean you're it's you have to
tell me what's going on like be super
specific
you know you not not just oh is because
it's not open source or something you
know the thing is anyway so that's it
for today we talked about this too many
times
way people before anymore G even existed
like if you have an issue I asked you
before but you don't have answer I asked
you before like is there some particular
incident about this code that pisses you
off you know you think it's wrong you
know if you no say it
I asked you before you don't have like
you don't have anything like that and I
look I did check Wikipedia on this code
you know it's just it's just it's just
like every other companies you know if
you if you like the you know the the
what you know what I'm thinking you know
like if you really hate disco to the
degree that you refuse to use it then
you should like not use a phone at all
in the first place because that is far
more you know the kind of evil whatever
you don't want you know but you have to
use a phone well using a phone is kind
of necessary so that may not apply but
anyway so that's it for today let's see
okay one ninety minutes good bye guys i
I disconnect in one minute