good morning guys
I'm alive indeed so today I'm going to
talk about
welcome to the saw talk show by the way
it's 1 o'clock a.m. in the morning here
so I have to be quiet you know I live in
a small apartment it's a two-bedroom
apartment in California in Mountain View
now Mountain View is where Google's
headquarters is at and it's very
expensive here
and so my rent here is actually this
place is pretty cheap it's old apartment
building
it's 2020 2020 220 300 a month and I
have let's see one two three four I have
four roommates so I have to pay about
$800 a month and that pretty much makes
it even that is whatever income I have
just pay the rent so I'm gonna say hi
there
who are you say something so I'm going
to talk about random things I was
planning to talk about YouTube YouTube
videos I've been wanting to talk about
this for a while
oh three people hey guys hey break the
loop in formatic informatic hey guys
wait oh you guys are where are you guys
from like okay in this hour you guys are
in Europe right you know on YouTube and
elsewhere on the Internet most people
including geeks especially geeks you
know they use pseudonyms pseudonyms
handles you know they know Wow North
Africa oh wow so I would say California
hey we can meet up do we have we met
before break the loop Wow amazing we
have someone from North Africa well
we're in North Africa campaign I asked
informatics and how did you find me
okay so well you can you know you can
look up people here I mean this is
omoroca oh yeah yes I remember you said
that before
so African accent I don't know how
African African English yeah I don't
it's not in my memory how it sounds like
but my Roco okay I know that Morocco is
the most crowded city right you know I
grew up in Taiwan in Taiwan you know
where is Taiwan guys you know Taiwan is
a tiny island it's it's you know so this
is a you know XR talk show so let's do
you know let's just let's look at the
map you know random things so so here's
here's the China
here's China and it's let's zoom out so
you can see here's a globe and here is
China you know China is about the same
size as USA and Taiwan is here it's it's
you know very small let's shrink a
little bit you see okay so so here is
Japan here is Taiwan and if you look now
remember the sizes okay so China is
about do you speak Taiwanese in this big
job
they speak South Korea and let's go to
you as a the most powerful nation in the
world and by the way I'm a member I'm a
US citizen so USA is a speak so Taiwan
is like New Hampshire you know it's like
the the same size of Vermont or New
Hampshire or Maine that's yeah you know
so so let me yeah okay so let me tell
you where I came from so I I was born in
Taiwan here in in 1968 and when I was
fourteen that's around 1981 or 1982 I
through with my family we went to live
in Para why here hasn't shown here for
one year then okay that's far why that's
Spanish country so all this all this
continent they speak Spanish is except
Brazil Brazil speaks Portuguese which is
very similar to Spanish then so I live
in Paraguay for a year and we went to
live in Guatemala for half a year for
the malleus city I think and we were
also in Salvador for for one week I
think and at that time there was a war
it's around 1982 or something like that
I mean this always war in Salvador I
think okay so we live in Guatemala for
half a year then we flew
all the way to Montreal Montreal was a
beautiful beautiful CTA is a beautiful
city in Canada so in Montreal for a
while and in Vancouver for a while
Vancouver is all the way on the west
here and basically then my family went
home they flew back to Taiwan in I
stayed you know I'm the like 16 years
old and I just lived there by myself and
I was actually a illegal alien so I was
in my bank so I took a bus Greyhound bus
all the way from Vancouver to back to
Montreal and you know I just worked in
sweatshops sweatshops and bagel making
well you know the his sweater Factory
this Chinese sweater factory they make
clothing you know like buttons like when
you have a shirt for example they are
buttons right those buttons someone need
to put it down there and there's a
machine like you just put the button you
saw the pattern and other things like
you know the whole factory makes
clothing mostly women's women's clothing
because women's when you talk about
clothing
it's all women's stuff so I was in you
know cotton factory for a year or
something then I was also making bagels
you know there's a very popular mantra
is very famous for bagels I think mega
pay goes is the Jewish bread or
something
yeah I think it's a Jewish original
tradition let's see on a second let's go
to wait where's my bookmarks
hmm DuckDuckGo okay
you know dr. Koh has a problem because
right now I have JavaScript off anyway
let's not talk about that it's just
turned JavaScript on so let's go to
DuckDuckGo and bagels BHEL
so I was making this in a bakery whole
menu so anyway let's go back to the map
so in Montreal you know there's
something interesting Montreal is also
it's all different now
okay I'm gonna mention that I'm gonna
talk about that but when I was in
Montreal that is 1985 to 1989 it's very
you know in in Canada you know they are
two like factions or political divisions
so so on the Quebec province over here
they speak French they are French
ancestry most you know they speak French
and and the rest of the country is
English so they usually have like they
don't get along they fight but so Canada
is bilingual you know English in French
Canadian French so anyway in Montreal
it's a very sexually open city you know
they are you know from from like the
friend French culture so I remember
every in a Montreal downtown every few
blocks there's a strip club but anyway
but it's all changed now you know a
friend went to Montreal and I asked him
do you still see strip clubs now know
because you know Canada has turned it
into this social justice country like
most most white you know so-called white
countries like pretty bad USA I think it
began USA then in Canada and Australia
it's pretty bad and of course Europe but
anyway so in 1989 I came to California
here from Montreal and and basically I
lived here since
since so here is the California this
this is California this is San Francisco
and Los Angeles is down below here and
this is Hollywood you know all the
Hollywood stars here and this area San
Francisco this this area is called San
Francisco Bay Area and it's also known
as Silicon Valley so when you hear that
term that's here because all basically
all the online major mega corporations
began here and mostly are still here so
Google PayPal eBay basically everything
it's just just about a traitor you know
Twitter is over here in San Francisco
Google is right here Apple is right here
IBM is not here IBM well they have you
know branches here but their headquarter
is not here and Microsoft is also not
here Microsoft is in Seattle like above
so anyway that is the my story so let's
go back to let's shrink let's go back
and look at Europe now this area is
troubled water you know as American you
don't know what the [ __ ] is going on
there
you know vast majorities you know I am
kind of studious you know like most of
you guys so I read about things every
day but still you know Americans it mean
generally don't know [ __ ] they they
don't know anything outside of their
country in general yeah you know so
anyway so here's me know is so Morocco
okay
Morocco so I heard you know one day I
was looking up you know what are the
places that's most crowded in a word
some world Morocco I think it's like
number one or number two okay let's
let's check comments do you to your
roommates work in a software know my
roommates they are like they are Chinese
and they are mostly they are 60 years
old 60 close tools you know they are
pretty old except one guy which is their
son who is 30-something but basically
they they are they are basically
illiterate they don't speak English
first of all and they you know they are
blue-collar workers they work in
restaurant they cook cook they are cooks
in a restaurant so if you go to Chinese
restaurant you know oh yeah break the
loop some say yeah so you know if you go
to downtown you know Chinese any Chinese
restaurant here that that's where they
are you you know the reason I know them
they became my roommate is because I was
washing dishes few years ago it's pretty
sad but that you know I did that and I'm
still in kind of in that situation but
anyway so I was washing dishes but you
know the interesting thing about so
anyway so you know they are illiterate
like they don't they don't know what the
[ __ ] is internet you know they of course
they all have iPhones you know actually
yeah but they don't know what's going on
they just use it to talk to their
friends you know Chinese they they have
no idea did like for example they don't
know the difference between Wi-Fi or
cell phone
you know the cellular network like Nick
they don't they have no idea like you
just use the phone to talk to people
that's funny no so anyway so yeah they
are so what I mean by that I mean why do
I mention they are you
illiterate yet the interesting thing is
that because you know we are technical
people actually well technically we are
professionals
you know so-called professionals you
know we are white color but also we are
actually professionals as you know if
you know a program you are actually you
know classified as a professional
because it takes you know a college
education and you know I mean you know
that so so most of us you know most of
the white collar's in general you have
no idea what the blue-collar people's
life are like you know because you are
you are affluent you know you know you
are wealthy although you may not think
you are but you know actually you know
very wealthy so you you kind of live in
this enclosed word what how you see
things is not how people see things
especially I mean I'm talking about for
example in America so so white collar's
mostly are in big cities especially on
the east coast you know New York New
York California I mean Commerce is you
know big cities on the side and some
some big cities you know in the middle
but all the rest they are like like
cowboy itaú protank town you know they
are like just country towns they're just
like my house and in my house you just
see grass and cows and you know actually
that's true if you take the if you you
know I drove with a friend American
friend white guy from from from San
Francisco to to Philadelphia like ten
years ago
so and I've seen while I lived in
Illinois his chick chick chick
I lived in Illinois is for like half a
year and I live in Maryland for half a
year Maryland so but but mostly my life
is spending you know he mountain view in
this area modern views on say so anyway
let's go back Missy some comments let's
answer that how do we you when you came
to Union so so yeah I I was why I was in
Canada I was around 16 so I came to
California in 1989 where I was I think
19 or 20 yeah a bus from Vancouver to
Montreal is five days Greyhound bus it's
I think it's still five days I mean if
you go from San Francisco to New York
it's it's like four days of five days
my family I don't like to talk about my
family because my family is a problem
family you know my mom and dad they
fight you know like the well fight any
involving violence and my you know it's
very fairly complicated you know they
they got divorced and they remarried and
they divorced again and my mom's got
stats taped a new boyfriend you know my
stepdad and he is also no good guy and
so on and each invading my sister's my
sister and my brother basically my whole
family is almost like nobody gets along
with any each other so so that's the
situation not so crowded Morocco is not
so crowded now because in Taiwan it is
people here love crowdedness and hate
oxygen that's strange
okay so what okay so that's the map so
you know so many interesting things
going on so I was you know I I have
never been to China you know the
situation of Taiwan and China is that if
you don't know
it's basically so you have World War two
right World War two and the Japanese
basically invaded China so there's a big
huge bloody fight and but after that
then you have Chinese Civil War that's
very bloody you know Chinese Civil War
that's between the so called
nationalists versus the Communists and
in the end the National the National
List so that's how so my so my dad so I
so I'm part of that I was born in Taiwan
but my dad my you know my dad and my
granddad and my mom and my mom's parents
like in the Western countries you hear
Americans talk about NASA NASA all the
time like everything is not even thick
they don't talk about [ __ ] Japanese
everyday you know much because actually
Japan is kind of a friend to us but
anyway the Chinese and Japanese you know
the whole world who is very bloody and
chat you know Japanese has done things
you know similar to the Nazis and but
but that that was when I was born that's
already history so you know he's like
history moves on you when you are a new
generation you you know like what they
say time time heals everything so you
know so I don't know
you know in China and in Taiwan with
most people's you know they watch animes
you know Japanese enemies but still
there's you know you still the tension
um so anyway that that's the maps so
only forty millions have you visit
Taiwan well I went back to Taiwan in
2004 and lived there for half a year but
anyway so I was going to talk about okay
I kind of get you know so have been
talking for 23 minutes I kind of got
lost it but actually you know I have
huge amount of things to talk about you
know let's go to YouTube now I was going
to talk about YouTube shut up okay can
you guys hear it
if the YouTube is praying
can you guys hear it let's wait his
failure music let's see let's go here
okay great so you guys can hear it
because I was wondering you know because
you have to set it up here great so um
yeah I was going on talk about YouTube
stuff but should I or should I talk
about any other thing because you know
because like I have so many things to
you know to talk about like Emacs
programming let's see
so Emacs blog I want I need to write the
command to increase font globally okay
are you guys using Emacs by the way the
info Matic how did you find me
what were you guys following me because
of the because of my Emacs stuff
okay YouTube you know so this you know
if you know have you heard that you know
today every minute they are like they
are like thousands of hours of new
videos what you know thousands of hours
of new video every every minute so
there's so many things it's incredible
the annex Jones Alex Jones is a scumbag
you know I you know I watch people
especially public figures I watched him
and observe him so he's just a scumbag
he no well I don't know if that's a
topic yeah you know I don't know if you
guys heard of him it's kind of it's a
political topic you know he's a so but
if you haven't been paying attention
then it may not be interesting to you
but anyway so but anyway he say what
they call a conspiracy theorist he is
just a kook you know she just can lie
and create he just say fear-mongering
you know they like say you know oh
aliens here we are controlled by alien
and the FBI the government is like they
know that and they are supporting it and
stuff you know and it's you know the
thing is like is he making those things
up or we see you know what's his true
intention I mean as a person you look at
him you know that like so my I think
he's just yeah you know he know what
he's doing he is intentionally creating
this this garbage to so that a lot of
people you know he'll get followers and
you know make him rich and sell things
like there's like zero merit from of
anything coming from the mouth of Alex
Jones zero you know it's sad like
sometimes I see you know on Twitter and
sometimes I see other people
for example the anti left the anti
extreme left people what they call white
right-wing in USA you know so but I
found out you know one one of the person
went one girl when she's being
interviewed by Tim poor Tim cast she
says that she's actually a fan of Alex
Jones and she said that everything she
learned is from Alex Jones Infowars so
that's pretty sad that you see the thing
about the world is that it said almost
whatever you see use you say you you
kind of you will develop a following
follow you know a group that follows you
yeah I mean I mean yeah that's that's
true but I mean that's not a scientific
statement you know I mean so you know
don't take it literally but basically
any any person but but but you do not
just any person of course of course
you have to have certain charisma you
have to attract people for example the
Alex junk I of course he he doesn't look
like a prince you know like you know but
however he looks okay you know he looks
like a typical American you know the
typical white American let's say and he
he is able to talk you know a lot of
things and then stop you know and he is
able to you know you have to notice he
is able to articulate you know he's
conspicuously
things and you know he's got you know a
certain technique you know that it's
pretty that way
you know like so so so that's how he
attract you know his followers and also
the other thing is that in politics you
know some people follow you does not
necessarily mean that they like you or
they believe what you believe
you know they follow you because you
know there's a political banding you
know affiliation so because once you
become somewhat powerful they want to
join your forces like war you know when
you have war you know of you know ten
countries you want to join forces with
some other country even though you know
you don't like that guy but you join
forces because when you are small and
that's the same way you know the lgbtq
stuff that that's the same way because
you know you know the lesbian let's see
lesbian gay bi let's place me and gay
bisexual trans you know these four
groups they don't actually are not
together really you know they like like
you know bisexual you know you don't
really care about gays actually gays
don't really care about trans they don't
I mean there is no natural
attractiveness between each of these
groups of people you know gays and you
know bisexual lesbians you know I mean
lesbians they are interested you know
they are women who are interested in
women in case our guys interesting guy
you know
I mean if I'm a gay I'm not interested
in lesbian because you are women you
know in vice versa so you know similarly
for transient bisexual so you know but
they are you know cooped together you
know you have the face you know acronym
LGBTQ LGBTQ because
because politically putted political
bending you know you want to group these
together so you have more power you know
but now we are seeing problems you know
they are like it's getting out of hand
you know the trans people this feminists
they don't like the trends in the trans
don't like the feminists you know they
so anyway so that's you know Alex Jones
and okay so I so there's so many things
I wanna that's interesting you know I'm
not sure I want to talk about I mean I
don't want I don't need you know I'm not
like talking about YouTube just to talk
about politics I mean actually there's a
lot other things so this is actually um
okay let's look at the comment let's see
not sure if YouTube audio can be heard
what do you mean oh you use vim okay oh
yeah the Alex Jones guy hilarious yeah
he's you know he is so recently he he
did an interview with Joe Rogan yeah to
record someone created this account Joe
Rogan each University you know Joe Rogan
is kind of you know he's not in he's not
a intellectual you know I am a
intellectual you know because that's
what I'm interested you know in
philosophy and technology and you know
programming other feature intelligence
or all that kind of subjects but Joe
Rogan is not and his background is he's
a MMA fighter like mixed martial art
fighter that I mean so he's not you know
program engineer but he's rather idiotic
it's like you know but of course he he's
very famous he's a so-called talk talk
show host
you know the only stop talk talk shows
like they they don't know nothing like
they don't know [ __ ] they just talk like
a talk show so that's why I have any
talk show
but anyway so yeah so they are not you
know like this there was a Howard
something Howard Stern yeah you know I
remember you know when you know watching
a few Howard Stern you just talk [ __ ]
you know like random garbage you know
like you don't yes it's almost like you
don't you don't need any preparation you
don't need nothing you just talk you
know and you get interesting you know
celebrities to come on the show and talk
about things and in fact that's that's
actually most people's life
like you know most like vast majority of
people I mean we are programmers we are
you know programmers or engineers or
maybe scientists and and our interest at
least you know part of our life we spend
a lot of time studying rather very
technical details you know like science
Sciences in mathematics you know or
engineering how to how to get things to
work but that's not most people's in I
mean that's not most people's interest
you know we find programming very
interesting you know but for most people
that's the most boring thing you know
they just wanna you know they maybe they
go to bars you know the drink drink beer
or they go to dance clubs they go
shopping women go to shopping they you
know to vacations so so anyway so this
talk show host so so that's why they get
lots of views you know so so okay so
most people you know when they want to
hear you know they hear news every day
right on on TV about politics and so
they you know they like to you know talk
show talks about them you know which is
different from let's say different from
for me for example
from us let's say because for me for
example when I hear political news you
know every day there's some politics I
you know I tend to want to know okay so
so what is actually happening you know I
want you know start to like start to
read Wikipedia okay what countries are
where which you know their history you
know the economics that was so what's
the theory of economics what's the
statistics you know so kind of like you
know going into academic directional
philosophy direction you know so what
what is the proper no morality you know
that does for example democracy
his democracy good I mean is it
how much do you know about democracy
have you studied the history of
democracy you know things like that but
that's not most people they you know so
so yeah so I was watching a few very you
know there's so many very interesting
things on YouTube but I kind of lost
okay let me talk about this one girl
that's very she's very impressive here
so means so much beautiful people you
know this YouTube [ __ ] you know with
their with its algorithms controlling
what you want to see suggestions but
today most of it is bad like I don't
like it at all so actually the girl
Oh Karen she is extremely intelligent
she's one of the person I admire she
now this girl this girl she lived in
China so her her channel is talking
about China and because of course she
speaks Chinese there are a lot of people
you know Westerners who speak Chinese
now okay I just it's not even showing up
stupid oh and I rode off here so she had
a video that's extremely interesting so
I saw this one I think and also she's
beautiful she's from Eastern Europe or
something like that or middle Europe
[ __ ] this happened because of the
adblock
anyways
yeah this one I was watching this one
she's amazing so she's you know she's a
chess expert and she's beautiful
and she you know she gives she gave a
good presentation about chess
okay Emacs question yeah I'm a US
citizen I mentioned that before right
few minutes ago
oh you don't hear YouTube videos pain
okay let me try this
do you hear it No
so anyway let me stop that so anyway I
kind of lost on what YouTube I want to
talk about but anyway she's just you
know when I was reading when I was
watching this video and she's just
amazing you know so many young people
are there and they are it's amazing you
know you should just go out pursue what
whatever you want to do in your life
okay no YouTube okay now I have to so
okay so for family for family ask about
HTML mod so let me let me talk about
that quickly so I have a Emacs mod H
XHTML mod which is the one I'm using you
can see it in the malt line here let's
go okay second let's okay it's turn some
start command log mod okay so you can
see all my commands on this window and
so I have a I have written a mod it's
called some HTML mod and you it's on
github you can use and right now the
question is that it does not do indent
because for example if I press tab
you know the tab key is actually
assigned to insert some tag so there's
no indent but if I call intent for tab
command then I get this so anyway so my
my suggestion to you is that don't do
indent in HTML you know I never do
for for example I never do any intent
because HTML or XML is such that if you
actually do indent then you're gonna
what happens that you're gonna have lots
of indents basically if you look at all
the websites HTML source code they are
typically not intended because because
the whole thing is one nesting you know
starting with the starting with the body
tag you know for example let's copy this
file new file paste it home it cross
copy buffer new buffer pasted so this is
1,200 lines of HTML now let's put it in
HTML mod which is Emacs default HTML and
now I select all and press tab to indent
you see so this is the intended result
result you can you have lots of wasted
space actually you know my website is
actually does not use that much nesting
but you know for your HTML you may see
even more nesting so basically I
recommend don't indent you know just
only then and if you really want to you
know just go in 10 for tab command o
what you can do is that you can just
switch to HTML mod like you know switch
to HTML mod and then you do indent after
you done just close it and we reopen
your opening so HTML mod so yeah I
thought about you know maybe I should
had a indent function but
I'm not sure about that you know because
you shouldn't you should an indent you
know indenting is a problem in
programming actually I you know to me
I'd consider it a problem because
basically programmers the idea the
general conventional idea is that every
every you know the convention you know
the conventional agreement is that you
do intend on every line that's not good
you know like manually like each program
manually tries to indent every line you
know the editors usually help in some
way like when you press return it
doesn't intend for you but very often
like every few minutes you know a
programmer you know have to first about
indent manually they go you know you
know and you know coding format style
like where do you put your bracket
that's no good what should happen it
should be a
automated for example colon is a good
idea here so let's create a new buffer
let's let's say it's switch to go mod
okay and colon you say language from
Google and let's say it's the template
you see and let's say print that needs
to let's print one to 10 1 to 100 okay
not function okay so wait
okay let's just do four so for fringe we
don't need okay that it's ready it asked
me to save so let's run it
XX start go so it prints you know zero
to three and let's say i grab the whole
thing let's say I delete wait we face to
space by one space okay and let's say if
I do that
okay clean it it works now you know
Golan provides a tool that's bundled
with a language bundled with a compiler
that automatically indent that reformat
the whole thing in one shot including if
you have like a very long single line
for example let's call that command it's
called go format that that's a one press
Enter you see it does the whole thing
for you so what I you know this is ideal
this is the best so you know when you
code you don't have to worry about
indent just just coat the whole program
when you are done when you need to
publish it or something you press a
button and the whole thing is formatted
it can be you know ten thousand lines or
hundred thousand lines you do or the
formatting for you so the conventional
wisdom or the idea have you know
intending that's that's [ __ ] don't
you know that's you know I hope you know
don't do that
okay so getting used to yeah that's you
know getting used to is one issue
because humans you know habit is the
primary force of everything you know
because otherwise lots of things needs
to be changed you know like you even the
English language you know Chinese
language or French you know those
natural languages they are full of the
exceptions in you know problems in
pronunciation and so on and music
notation math notation the way we you
know the whole thing is like if you look
at from a scientific view if you want
efficiency you know we almost have to
change everything
you know but however you know one thing
we learn and you know is habit you know
have habit you know we face everything
first of all we have a habit then we go
from there
so change are slow usually very slow in
coming for example they say in
programming languages you know how fast
does programming languages turn around
usually it will take you know a few
generations you know so I think Steve
Jobs said something like that you know
he said like you know I forgot what's
the topic but anyways like he has he's
got some ideas right but people don't
want to you know dislike to new they
don't want to use it and he said
something like oh you just have to wait
them for them to die which is actually
true so for the intent you know so
things are changing slowly very slowly
you know in the past 50 years of
programming for example as functional
programming now it's becoming popular I
mean at least you know very commonplace
you know funky functional programming is
accepted you know but in 1990s know even
in mm know but today it's kind of
accepted Andy and why do we use
you know in many places functional
programming and and many other ideas you
know like changes slow and even Java you
know they introduced lambda remember
some five years old ago you know like
like you know but if if in 1990s if you
say we need lambda in Java you know
people like you you'll be beaten to
death
Oh functional programming that's easy at
the most fundamental and the most
important level is that you everything
you do you write a function without side
effect that's it okay first of all let's
focus on this and actually this is the
most important in the gist of functional
programming okay so functional
programming at the most fundamental
level and actually the horse of the most
practical level is just you try to for
any program you write any source code I
mean any you know any code you write you
try to make everything as a function
without side effect for example what do
you mean let me show you example so okay
let me just talk so what do you mean
function with without side effect that
means a function takes the argument and
it returns a value and that's it you
know every time given the same arguments
to the function the function will return
the same thing every time
no exceptions so that's that's
functional programming so what's an
example of the exception for example if
you have a function that changes value
of global variable then that's a
function with side effect because you
know every time you run a function even
though every time you give it a value of
3 as in
but the output may not be the same so
the idea of functional programming is
that you just you know you your program
works or function as functions like
every you give it an argument function
returns a value and you use the value as
a result that's how the whole program
runs now in contrast you know in C for
example you have you see you have many
many subroutines you don't call that
functions you call subroutines because
you know they have lots of side effects
for example you have subroutines that
returns void you know why do you want to
ever return above it because because you
are actually not using the return value
you know your main way of programming is
not the return value you are actually
you call a subroutine which is kind of
just a template that does something
that's your purpose of using the
subroutine not the return value um you
know in the functional programming on
the other hand is focused on every
function you know [ __ ] you call
functions function return things and you
can use that thing to do something else
so functional programming focus on
expressions okay so that's basically
okay writing file for database that gets
complicated you know so okay so so as
I'm saying functional programming at the
most basic and the most practical level
is just focused just just try to write
functions without side-effect okay
that's it now in many languages of
course you cannot do it and also you
know also also when you have files you
know writing to files opening files or
to database you cannot do it because I
mean you are talking to a database you
know the you know the you cannot you
know what do you mean no side effect and
what do you mean return value yeah I
mean you want to change something in
database you don't really you know the
function is not really returning some
thing for you so anyway so so yeah so
that's why it's you know it gets cited
slightly complicated and also so there's
the programming language Haskell you
probably have heard Haskell ma which
stands for meta language Oh camel camel
standard standard email and others
including this this this programming
language including eMac is is primarily
functional because everything is just
parenthesis function name and you know
and it returns something and you do
something with that so anyway so the
basic idea but it gets complicated so
then so you have Haskell which which is
more of an extreme example
so in Haskell you have more advanced
mathematical ideas that that tries to
capture you know so you can open an file
or deal with database but still they
have some mathematical way to maintain
the idea that function always return the
same thing given the same value I mean
you are still dealing with functions as
a unit so so that's that now Haskell is
the note that Haskell is kind of special
and extreme on the other hand almost
every other Haskell is almost the only
one the only functional language that
that that that tries to enforce the idea
that a function cannot have side side
effect at all they try to the language
enforces enforces it but however all the
languages Oh camel for example Oh cam Oh
F sharp F sharp is Microsoft's version
of Okemah
they all can they all have side effects
I mean they don't enforce it I mean you
ask how you kind of enforce it but so
actually the thing about Haskell is that
you know something I mean even though
the language according to ask our people
they actually
enforce it but it's kind of like they
changed the definition you know it's not
really that something you just you know
it's you know you just cannot do in some
certain perfect sense of functional you
know yeah you know but anyway so yeah so
also so you begin with the idea that you
try to write you try to compute
everything by expressions and functions
and rely on the return value
you know without without side effect
that's the fundamental and most
practical idea remember that in any
programming language you can always try
to go the functional style now that's
the most fundamental but once you start
to do that there are some other ideas
that comes up that become you you will
if you start to actually program
functional style style everyday you will
begin to learn actually actually you
will begin to discover there are several
things or concepts you know you just
notice okay
I'm not even you know giving you names
but you just start to notice that there
are certain things certain features you
want because you do this so often so you
know so so full functional programming
there are you know it begins to have its
some other features and ideas for
example you might have heard monad you
might have heard currying you might have
heard tail recursion or recursion you
might have heard referential
transparency so they are you know
subsequent ideas of functional
programming yeah but but basically you
know just focus on writing functions
without side effect
oh if you want to actually go to the
extreme you know you have to learn
Haskell
and by the way you know I always want to
flame ask our people cut edge to flame
them because because they are like the
the fad you know that it's like the Lisp
you know like the Hopi you know in the
past you know this is just a fad you
know like they are expert in Haskell but
what you hear about Haskell every day is
usually garbage you know it's it's trash
it's like poor people saying something
about power back then penny wait oh I've
been talking for a while or so so that
that's about to end so we end this soon
maybe a few more minutes so if you have
question type it and we will get to the
then you know yeah there's something
else I want to say about functional
programming oh yeah so Haskell okay has
cow is on the extreme end of functional
programming but note that has cow is not
it's not Bo an end or four point
functional programming not at all
Haskell is actually not a mathematical
first of all Haskell is not a math
language it is not it's not a language
that a true mathematician or logician
will actually like anyway I'm good
gaining offer by anyway so they are
other languages now there's called
[ __ ] coq it's nice let's just find it
[ __ ] and hydrous for example they are
these two languages that's build on top
of the ideas of Haskell so I dress is a
dress programming language okay here is
the I want to go to home page
yeah edges
okay so I mean you can look it up so
high dress it's kind of new a generation
after Haskell they are several I mean
they are several Hancock here's another
one
in this epic Graham I'm not sure what's
a program so this idris programming
language and there's [ __ ] what is this I
don't want to go here solo oh yeah here
so copies this is actually talk is
actually a mathematical proof system
actually they call it it's so called a
mathematical proof assistant so they
don't actually call it a proof system
but proof assistant so it's like a
programming language but not really so
it's you know it's not it's it you know
it's very different so but anyway it's
mostly useful building proofs and
there's a program actually I don't know
what a program exactly so so these heart
so Idris for example this this is very
new so it began in few years ago I think
so this is a new generation it's like
this is a next generation from a
scallion so anyway but these languages
they have they have very strong math
mathematical theories and that that can
get very complex I mean you will be
talking about symbolic logic and proof
systems
how common sense
how has going Hebrew means common sense
I didn't know but has cow the name has
cow came from that logician has cow so
let's let's look up has cow not jiton
and i remember there was an article like
ten years ago or more than ten years ago
this guy so he is a lot Jason you know
so Haskell borrowed his name but I
remembered like more than ten ten years
ago this article from ask our people
that they actually they interviewed the
family of Haskell curry this this
mathematician they interview the family
to ask them for permission to use the
name his name for the language so you
can look up you know you can look it up
you probably find the article also
translating okay I think that's it for
today for today's thank you for watching
today's episode of saw talk show so
thank you guys I want to mention this
you know I've been wanting you know I'm
okay I'm I'm you know so I I want to
mention so you know if you like my stuff
my videos you know I'm I'm well I'm
trying to make a buck you know or to you
know although I'm doing video I enjoy it
myself but so if you like my stuff you
know you know give me a few bucks you
know um I'm on patreon patreon and you
know you go to Amazon and you know send
me Amazon giftcard you know few bucks
and something or PayPal so that'd be
great if you like my things you know if
you think it's worthy so thank you guys
for watching and I'll see you next time
hey Israel dog you know you are the
email email sky right so I mean so he's
got the Emax Channel
so maybe we can do one together you know
sometimes you know I'm thinking it you
know stood a video together about Emacs
so see you guys
thanks good night