good morning everyone welcome to another
clan talk show today is June 9th 2019
today's topic is going to be let's see
so today's topic is going to be UNIX box
Emacs workflow demo add a new Unicode
phoenician page ok let's do that and you
know always feel free to ask questions
any comments opinions and also go to
this page and pick a topic so let me
prepare by reading this out here some
talk show pick a topic there and today
we're gonna talk about Phoenician
alphabet of Unicode ok
pick a topic posing comment ok let's
let's begin on that topic then ok we're
gonna go to Unicode now Phoenician
alphabet is one of the oldest alphabet
so let's go to let's view this in
browser good morning guys
and we are going to add so you see here
is my unicode page let's see so on the
Left panel is my order Emacs commands I
call you can see on the Left panel
good morning shown so shown do you have
any questions any particular topic
questions you know type it feel free to
post because today we're going to talk
about this we're gonna add this
Phoenician alphabet but this time for
more this one is basically half of it is
going to be a Emacs workflow demo so you
see how I work in Emacs and the other
party is gonna a little bit about
Phoenician alphabet which I don't know
nothing about but we are just going to
read Wikipedia page so let's see ok
great
phonation so Phoenician alphabet as far
as I know is the kind of the oldest
alphabet the oldest writing system that
we can call it a alphabet so we have
furnished okay let's go to Phoenicia
wait how is it pronounced there is a IPA
here international phonetic alphabet so
we can see how it is pronounced but
meanwhile while it's loading okay it's
loaded Phoenicia so it's pronounced
Phoenicia not not Phoenicia Phoenicia
you can see
it's still loading you can see the
there's an international of a bit there
and my god it's still loading
okay Phoenicia
Phoenicia from asian greek was a fella
so quick Salah Socratic Asian semantics
speaking Mediterranean civilization that
originated in the Levant
specifically in Lebanon in a West of in
a west of Fertile Crescent okay it's
super so here good morning hey Jack he
said did I pronounce a right Jack Jack
from France and hey good morning Andrew
so we got quite a few people active here
so if you have any questions pick a
topic okay you can see the topic and any
just any question you ask me we're gonna
first to do this Phoenician alphabet so
let me actually let me make sure we do
this in 15 minutes so we can finish this
in 15 minutes so you know so unicode so
let's see Phoenicia so Phoenicia
venetie venetie is a actually a haitian
country but what we want is the language
so let's see alphabet
connection we speak okay I have a little
bit cross-eyed so I'm going to cover one
of my eyes so I can see better right now
Phoenician alphabet yeah
wait is it like a pH a it's not
mentioned here
what okay let's go to saw talk show page
everything's so go to a new page search
Phoenician alphabet
so there it is Phoenician Phoenician
half a bed
and meanwhile it's loading let's go to
my unicode search page so I'm gonna take
this Phoenician so these are the
characters very interesting you know
they look exotic so what we are going to
do you see we have several Unicode
language pages here for example if you
scroll down you have Bengal eye Bengal
EO Bengal eye and you have a bunch of
others Bengal a Tibetan and let me show
you one more so I started to add these
you know all the world's languages you
know slowly one by one they are you know
hundreds so I started to add you know
one one you know some of them to my you
know go page and today what we want to
do is to add a page for Phoenician
alphabet so first of all go to the
Unicode my unicode web page which is
this page now let's let's pick runs okay
okay for some reason it's super slow why
is that what is causing it
CPU assistive control OBS
Oh BS from can we like
Phoenician alphabet drought control
carabiner photobooth at some of the
photobooth windows server activity good
or chrome help Google Chrome okay so
here is the rampage let's go to the top
and let's go to the top here let's put
let's go through my blog okay so that's
my blog and I'm going just to create a
new section paste it here
so that's Unicode run and we're gonna
add a Phoenician alphabet so how do you
spell Phoenician make sure Phoenicians
make sure we spell out correctly
copy it here then okay so here is how
it's spelled
finishing okay and lowercase it and
we're gonna Unicode Phoenician okay
and copy that let's put here remove the
underscore capitalize the title okay so
this page is empty so what so I have a
command here saw copy HTML by link so
what that will do is it will copy this
files content into whatever link is the
next file so it which is this one so if
I open this page now now it's got stuff
there and is it says the run Unicode you
know so we're gonna change this page so
we move the style let's see first of all
let's change the title so I'm I'm gonna
walk through this quickly change the
title update the dates remove that date
part then
remove that remove that remove delete
delete delete in fact there's a lot
things to delete here so we're gonna
delete that delete that delete delete
delete small to delete
okay showing browser that's what that's
what we want okay so we have a
Phoenician page right now it's empty
right now it's empty we're gonna start
to add stuff so here is Wikipedia
Phoenician alphabet code by convention
the throttle canal night half a bed for
inscriptions older than around 1050 BC
is the oldest verified alphabet in the
wider sense of the term alphabet okay so
we go back to my unicode page let's go
back to the Unicode page to the top and
let's type Phoenician and let's copy
these characters back to Emacs open this
Phoenician page and we're gonna add here
oh wait
Phoenician is not left to right is it
whenever there's left to right I hate it
because if like right now I move my
arrow to the left but now it's moving
right now for example now I moved my
arrow I press the right arrow key and
that happens okay and so if I put my
cursor here and now I press the right
arrow key okay so it goes right there
and okay so apparently there is a first
character there so let's look at the
unicode result page I must say I must
have a left-to-right marker here
somewhere maybe I don't see any
character that's left to right so so
here is the interesting problem these
Peaks basically I think what happened
there must be a character somewhere here
that says left to right so let me remove
the empty space this direction reverse
reverse though is very confusing so what
is this one Phoenicians word separator
so if I delete this character no I don't
want to delete a character okay show
space
live feed I don't want my feed okay
right Phoenicians is not left to right
by default is it let's see Phoenician
alphabet search for left 4 Phoenicians
was usually written right to left
though some texts alternate directions
yeah there's an interesting phenomenon
like in in old Asian summation scripts
they they write change direction like
from right to left then at the end they
change to left to right so it's like
it's like that like like that that is
called boustrophedon that's funny and
and that word means like I think that
what means a bool you know going ox you
know going around so you know apparently
some system or like that Asian systems
they don't have you know they they
haven't decided which direction to go
which is actually true for most of
things you know like almost everything
in every day in human life whatever you
see usually like there's no for example
English grammar there is no such thing
you know grandma there's no like you
know in the beginning people just get
together and talk eventually you have
writing systems you know after a
thousand years or so people started to
draw stuff you know carve stuff on the
stone or stuff or on bones then there is
no grammar you know like this is no
grammar but eventually you know the some
writers or philosophers they thought
about they look at the things and they
say oh there's a pattern let's you know
let's let's do grammar so then you have
Grandma so you know that this kind of
theory this kind of thinking where there
is no rule whatsoever it just you know
it kind of applies to everything I think
for my studies applies to everything
so the point is that you know a lot of
things you study today like grandma or
other rules usually usually we take it
we overestimate their importance like
there is no such thing
okay so we have not found out what's
going on here
you're very annoying so because we have
not found out why is not it's just copy
some of the characters okay let's copy
that too and new buffer paste magnify
okay so we we pasted just two characters
but still they are like left-to-right oh
I mean they are right to left
I'm sorry so that means apparently that
means Phoenician alphabet at least in
Unicode they are right to left which is
very annoying because the other
directions do not flow the way you
expected yeah so we let's try another
character maybe okay let's copy that
character new buffer magnify paste okay
yeah Phoenician is like right-to-left
that's very annoying because that means
we all have you know it's more difficult
to create a Unicode so what we're gonna
do now is to replace space by replace
space by
by noon line so I have this command saw
space to new line okay so that is done
finally okay let's look at that and now
we want to add this thing let's let me
show you okay this right to left is very
frustrating because all my command do
not work as expected
yeah we are having a problem here
so anyway but let's do a control you
wait let's do a insert a type here and
the crass will be big something okay
copy that
yeah this still it's still annoying
direction so go to the top then we're
gonna do we're gonna do a CSS font size
okay let's say fontsize to turn off show
space turn off show whitespace then
we're gonna delete that we're gonna
delete that delete that delete that show
in browser okay we got that but that's
not good enough because normally if if I
go to a Unicode say I go to plant I can
move my cursor there and there's a pop
up you can see the Unicode code point
and also the hexadecimal that is because
that is because I show you another page
and you will see you'll see why for
example let's go to the Unicode emoji
page so this is the emoji page and if
you go down you can see that each
Unicode magnify magnify each Unicode is
a smart up by this schmuck tag and then
my JavaScript will you know just process
those tags so what I need to do now is I
need for the for the Phoenician page for
each of these character to have a mark
okay oh yeah it looks okay so okay that
works so let's do that so the command I
code is this side Chi ml mark Unicode he
basically add the smoke tag with the
Unicode code point and the Unicode
character name you can find this command
inside Gmail mod it's on github so what
I'm going to do is actually wait
oh the left to right is gone for some
reason okay so what we're gonna do is im
using a Kinesis advantage to you can see
that is my keyboard and you can see that
you know if you go to my website sorry
you know just google such sorry keyboard
you'll find my review and video about
this keyboard and this keyboard is brown
cherries cherry MX brown switch so okay
back to this what we are going to do is
go into we're gonna start a keyboard
mark okay start key bamako move to the
right call the command stop keyboard
macro then select all these lines call
apply marco to region lines okay you see
in one shot we got all this markup done
now showing browser
it's excellent this is what we want now
we're gonna add that and we're gonna
show this
okay close that window so the next thing
to do is I'm going to add this
Phoenician Phoenician page to to the
panel on the left so we're at which
position should I add it
let's see Japanese Korean riebeck
Ethiopia let's add it before run below
high real guys okay so open Phoenician
page go down all the way down you can
see this bunch of this block of code we
want to replace so copy that
then I coxa find replace text paste that
okay enter then cancel the command we
cancel right now because we are going to
create a new text to replace which we
are going to do here so let's search for
drone
okay we are going to add above this line
so copy the file path
paste new line new line and make a list
remove that remove that so that's what
we want we want to add this line so
remove that and now we need to pick one
of the character that that gives people
an indication of the alphabet such as
you can see any one of this page has a
character that kinds of kind of
represents the script
so for Phoenicians which one should we
pick what do you guys think you know
usually you wanted to be typical for
example let's say let's say
critic how do you pronounce a critic the
Russian alphabet you know you want to
pick alphabet you want to pick a
character that kind of uniquely
identifies this alphabet but also
familiar to most people like when people
see this character they know oh that's
Russian you know you know if you can
find such a character that that is the
best and also if you can satisfy those
above two criteria the other another
criteria you want to have is that the
character should be dramatic
you know the more dramatic the better
you know so that like nobody we don't
know any of these languages so you know
you want some dramatic characters you
know so full Phoenician which character
should we pick let's let's just say for
now let's say that one okay and okay I
go back here put it here make it you
know I make these marks there so now
showing browser let's see how it looks
like there it is
hi rogue life then phoenician then run
hey good morning base so so we have done
we have added phoenician to this panel
but we need to add it for every any one
of this page you know for example this
astrology page there is you know we
still need to add it there so now copy
this copy run and linear copy these two
lines okay now let's do some find
replace text paste those two lines okay
enter then cancel okay now the replaced
text will be these three three lines so
let's cover it again start find replace
text up arrow then we got these two
lines now replace text by these three
lines okay in this directory yes Oh HTML
files right changes right changes fixed
case fixed case make backup
okay so it's all done oh these are you
know occurrences so now let's look at
the in browser let's go to an emoji
scroll down you can see that there it is
now let's try another page let's go to
linear be okay scroll down you can see
there it is Phoenician okay that is
basically that is done but usually what
I have what I have to do is that I have
to read you know this Wikipedia you know
spend spend few hours studying you know
reading about this Phoenician alphabet
then write something interesting about
it on my page you know so people get
some idea what this what is Phoenician
alphabet is about so for example its
begin by let's let's say I just paste
that
let's modify this definition of a bed
Phoenician alphabet is the oldest oldest
verified alphabet in the wider sense of
it of the term alphabet it is an
alphabet of abjad type consisting of 22
consonant consonant letters only living
vowel sounds implicit although certain
lady varieties uses mattress like
lection s for some vows okay we don't
care let's just say the phonetic
alphabet is the oldest oldest verified
alphabet in the widest sense of the term
okay let's just say that yeah
then we are done go to Isha its
translates to it again totally Shou
upload or sync this is so interactive a
breathe enter password okay we are done
uploading we have all these changes are
changed now if you go to sorry Unicode
you will see it so unicode on my website
so let's go to Unicode characters yes
let's scroll down there it is oh look at
that
different font it shows up like like
there it is this is Phoenician letter
10th okay so so that that is that so you
know Phoenician basically they they
became Greek then they they are like one
of the first alphabet and they
influenced they influenced quick
alphabet then Latin alphabet then
Cyrillic alphabet you know so you know
and also runic alphabet because you know
runic came from I don't remember but
anyway that's that's it about that so
what else guys that is that about this
unicode page so I I added this unicode
page which is great so on my blog I just
delete the Unicode run because we were
using that as a source to copy text form
but there's one more thing I need to do
I need to add that character here so
let's do that so copied open that and
search for T et okay
copy like copy that line close actually
I just want the character okay so
phoenician is definitely right-to-left
very annoying I always hated those so if
you paste it here
actually that should be part of the
title so open that change the title
paste the CAC there then close yes
save it copy the URL paste it here make
a link make a link make it a paragraph
that's it good
so now you can see there's a character
there Phoenician Phoenician character
then we're going to add it to my blog
XML atom feed so you can see this is
here new close it save and go to isha
again saw a brief interactive a brief
upload again so it's done so now if you
go to
if you go to my website you go to
programming blog you will see this link
you know this is new today so that is
done
ok so Andrew says I'm interested in
ergonomics but most ago keyboards and
track balls use the right thumb
extensively and my right thumb doesn't
have full mobility what would you
recommend most logo keyboards and track
balls use the write them extensively
well for track balls so let's let's go
to my web let's go to my keyboard page
so if you are right so it's like you
know it's like you are left-handed
there are several left-handed Mouse but
but they are few here and there not many
and so you can buy them let's just talk
about them so let's go to Mouse then we
will talk about trackball because track
track bow is kind of another solution
and it's a good solution so here is a
bunch of left-handed Mouse this one is
still on sale you know left left-handed
Mouse is not very popular of course
because not many people are left-handed
so some often they come and go like
sometimes they are not available this
one I'm not sure is still available you
can check so this one is still available
you know $89 don't don't ever buy
anything from razor raytracer just no
good they did because they they jack up
their prices because they market to
ignorin came us you know mostly they are
just spending tons of money on marketing
so usually i I would not buy a race
I would buy from Logitech and other
places so anyway so here's a bunch of
left-handed Mouse you can try or you can
try this one this one is ergonomic Mouse
there's a left-handed version okay but
it you know there are just a few of them
so you can try track boss track boss a
lot of them are ambidextrous like you
know you can get these these these these
through your works so so that basically
is the answer for the mouse pot now for
the key keyboard part they you know I
don't see how they are focusing on the
right thumb you know usually the
keyboard they are all symmetric so I'm
not sure what you mean
you know they focus on right them you
know yeah so but you know they basically
all the ergonomic keyboards they treat
the right hand and left hand symmetric
you know almost Oh bleep yeah so you
know if you have problems with the right
son then you know I guess just to talk
don't use the right thumb much you know
use you know yeah so does does that
answer the question well let me know
okay so pancreas no stays why do you
choose to have your notes in HTML you
don't feel that HTML with the text makes
it hard to extract the notes in the
future yeah I guess a lot of people ask
me that you know usually they want you
know a lot of people are oak mud fence
you know they are oak mud fence and but
basically you know I've been writing
HTML HTML raw since 1997 you know by
hand man
in the beginning I tie I literally type
every tag like this oops you know P oh I
I have some abbrevs so that's what
happens so basically I started to write
HTML manually in 1997 so I have like 20
you know 30 years of 25 years of writing
it and I'm using my own HTML mod like
right right now you can see this is a
for example let's let's do describe
describe variable okay then I typed
major mod now this is the way to find
out what is the current major mod you
just called this web variable and you
type major mod okay then okay I enter
then you will tell you that its value is
saw HTML mod so that that is what I'm
using and you can go to look at the code
you know so this is the the code for
thousand lines and I'm also using
javascript you know I have my own
JavaScript mod and CSS mod well because
I started to code Emacs Lisp in 2006 you
know in the beginning I don't have my
own mods but eventually you know one
thing leads to another you know I just
started to write them because you know
in Emacs is extensible you can either
spend the time to download and learn
another package or when you know eMac
this you can just create your own you
know it's not difficult so I have all my
you know own mods so to me typing notes
in HTML is more natural faster more
efficient and more flexible than using
oak mod you know yeah yeah a lot of
people you know ask me that and I talked
about this a couple of times you know
and people wants to you know because few
people you don't see people writing
Gmail manually they really feel but but
if you are used to I think it can be
actually more efficient and flexible in
it then Oakmont because when you HTML
like right now although it's difficult
to read but I press one button it's
showing browser this is far more easier
to read than any augment source you know
including images of course seeing
augment you can make Emacs show images
but you know there's a lot code to do
you know I can just view in browser and
if I want to you know show in Safari
then I have JavaScript on JavaScript
that does lots of things you cannot have
in Oakmont you know you can in Oakmont
you know you know like so I press one
button and and I mean browser but if you
are in OGG mode you have to export and
if you are writing your blog then you
have to cause you know hugo whatever you
know that generates generates the HTML
the HTML it generates usually it's very
extremely inefficient and you know lots
of crap you know I control everything
here every every letter character he's i
you know i typed myself so i have full
control of the CSS you know to detail
you know so if you are thinking so this
is not for everyone of course but if you
really love Emacs and you know ii Maglis
or you don't mind learning some I would
recommend I mean it you know it's it's a
good approach to write HTML directly
there is no issue with that in fact if
you do this long enough it will be more
efficient than Oakmont because another
way to look at this you know
oak Oak mod has oak mod has you know the
HTML mod the tours in HTML mod in duty
to dealing with HTML is like one
thousand ten thousand times
more than Oakmont that's a fact you know
so when you work with HTML directly you
really have a lot more power and options
than Oakmont okay so let me read more
question questions comments you can
always view trait X says you can always
use key mapping software to change the
key functionality away from the rights
lamp yeah yeah are you saying ACMA what
do you mean a comma a comma script is
the it is the official name for
JavaScript so Anjali says yeah but there
is not too many places for space
backspace tab enter something like the
oviducts other than the thumb clusters
okay Andrew you know if you have issues
with your right right thumb then you
know that's not a normal situation so I
guess so what I mean by that is that for
you any solutions you use is likely
necessarily not you know normal solution
provided by other people so you have to
you know make to I guess you know so one
option is you know I I always recommend
a programmable keypad so on for example
like this you know this page shows some
program programmable keypads I don't
know how that applies to you because you
know first of all if you are using oh go
you know ergonomic keyboards like oh go
dogs or these kind of stuff they are
already not normal you know they are
more advanced you know not no more like
normal people so you already got you
know like five or more
thump Keys you know no more keyboard you
only just just got one spacebar but now
if you are using open ami keyboard you
got five extra keys okay but you cannot
use the right side okay but still you
got 5x trust them the keys you know but
then you say yeah but you know it's
already a improvement you know what what
can you do you know so I guess that's
that so maybe you know maybe get a
program of programmable keypad yeah but
I don't know how you are using them I
mean what exactly you are trying to fix
you know so thank you thank you yes no I
have tried oak mod and doc quickie and I
was thinking about doing the these
static generated websites but I will try
your approach and see if there's a good
for me yeah so you could try it's not a
popular it's not very common but but if
you are using Emacs you know being
flexible Emacs and very customizable
yeah it's it's a good approach because I
you know because I've got people asking
me you know like people who wants to
suggest you know what why don't why
aren't you using oak mark come on oak
mark is the best of everything you know
and I keep telling them no you know my
own citizen system is more flexible and
more powerful and more efficient than
oak man you know that's that's adds
focus on stuff so I have my side tml
mark you could try they are specifically
designed if you are writing stuff ro you
know like today when you call JavaScript
you use frameworks right you know react
you know vous or whatever and the
JavaScript mods you know they they also
are cared for that many of them are you
know designed for that but my mods you
know so javascript much such about Jas
mod you know you can see here let me
show you like a few days ago someone
asked me about my web development set up
in Emacs so basically my answer is that
I'm just using my packages so here is
the CSS mod let's open that and stuff
like his CSS mod JavaScript mod HTML mod
you know I've been using them like it
might my HTML mod I've been using for
like seven years seven or eight so these
mods
what I'm saying is that this mod tends
to be designed for those people who only
have pure HTML you know not not mixed
coke not mixed you know a bag of
JavaScript CSS HTML together no but just
it's just pure valid HTML if you tends
to write that kind of thing this is very
good
okay excited to me mod same thing with
such of a squid mod if you write pure
JavaScript you know what you're doing
you are using Akmal script 2015 you know
the advanced but you are not using any
frameworks you know no jQuery no no
react no boo whatever no you know you
just new code in pure JavaScript this is
very good solution and actually you can
use this for typescript as well but let
me just also mention in in conjunction
you know I I almost don't use any
any other mods like in my Emacs let's go
to that Emacs so let's look at my my
packages ALPA so let's go to ALPA so
these are the met packages I've
installed actually I don't use them
company I don't I you know I the only
thing I use is let me show you what I
use
smacks I use smacks is the alternative
for meta X okay that's very good
so I use smacks and I use match it and I
use score mod now language mod is kind
of necessary otherwise you have to write
your own so I use go mod go mod match it
let's copy it and let me show you here
let me show you what I use okay
so snakes right match it right that's it
but the mud I use includes go mod okay
mama
this is okay mama company I don't use -
I don't use I hate these packages that
install any package that uses stash I
refuse to use okay I'm going to I'm
going to delete them - did it - Merline
delete delete L dock Eva delete f I
really despise this [ __ ] now G hub I'm
not sure which one which package
installed that you know I hate those
dependence packages key frequency is
very good okay and who is using these
memories maybe smacks is using it I
don't think so you know and in who who
put us here
I despise I truly despised this s and
this F and this - [ __ ] yeah you know
some somehow I have them because I
installed other things why snippet I
don't use anymore you know I haven't
used it for for more than five years
Tareq is all camera mod okay yeah and
you know let's delete them
you know sometimes I am tired my ice
goes cross so that is why we you see me
with a eyepatch I think I had this you
know when I was in my twenties even but
usually you cannot tell but but
sometimes you can tell so ok you were
saying Oakmont haha I thought you were
saying ACMA oh no oh cmon ok let's see
what else
how do i be in talking ok let's talk
maybe let's talk 10 minutes more yeah
let's do that
Phoenicians that is fantastic
Phoenicians let's summarize today's
speeds so you know every time I do a
video so I am let's go to a talk show
after I do a video usually I have to
look at the topics I talked about so
that I can kind of write up a summary
Phoenician alphabet we don't care about
that page anymore I need to read this
so that's homework you know that's what
I have to do and I write my webpages I
have to spend a few hours reading about
Phoenician alphabet and find anything
interesting I find it and also usually I
like to include some artifact like some
photo some ancient carvings or some
boxes or something you know so that
people can see they don't have it here
so I need to do some search so that for
example let me show you this one eunuch
oh let's repeat it that's I know why
it's repeated because
okay
do you have anything economic for your
eyes blue light filters no I don't have
anything like that in fact I need to
change my glasses this this class is
sucks I got them at Walmart the cheapest
one including eye exam it's like $300
okay so and I got these glasses this is
three years old and the glass is all
scratched up even though I didn't
scratch them I cannot show you because
the camera is not good enough to you
cannot see this patches but they begin
to have scratches but just by themselves
you know American grass is very bad in
China or Taiwan the grasses you get is
like it's it's it's about like six times
cheaper the qualities is is much better
you know it's like two times or three
times better
I mean they they don't even allow that
kind of grass material in USA the
doctors told me at Walmart so before
this I had a grass in Taiwan and I used
that for ten years no more than ten
years no problem but this one's got
problems so now let's refresh this page
you see that that is fixed now if you
look at the run page now run is amazing
okay so I wrote this JavaScript app you
can type English here and see it
converted to run half a bit
in real time so check it out okay you
can you can you can some secret
s ER CR et text here you can you can
type things here copy it and send it to
your friend you know to treat a hostile
you know tell them it's a encrypted text
so you can see this is run alphabet and
you hack you can you you have some
artifact some Asian stuff
let's go to let's maybe on a second
curse curse programmable keypads let's
talk about keyboards Arabia so today a
friend sent me this now this is a this
this is what called point-of-sale
keyboards now this is the type of
keyboard when you go to a store you know
the clerk checks checks out that's the
keyboard they use so on the back you can
see all these connectors all the ports
you ever need you know they so the you
know it's like a cash machine they can
they connect to the cash machine and and
it's programmable obviously because but
I don't think it's like a normal
keyboard you know for a normal computer
keyboard you program them so you have
keyboard mark words but for this one the
point-of-sale keyboard you know I
suppose you can press a key it sends
some special signal or something so I
don't know but apparently you can yeah I
mean so Amazon you can buy it but it's
not on Amazon right now it was like a
year or two ago yeah right now you
search for it oh there it is $128 okay
it's not very expensive so this is the
keyboard you can get this this is cool
why because then you have all these
macro keys 1000 macro keys so yeah if
you have some issues you can get this
keyboard and just anything you want to
do is just one single key press
apparently they also have a credit card
swiper here by anyway a friend you know
people are using this keyboard so this
this photo is for my friend on twitter
he sent it to me but today someone in
I'm not sure where this guys came from
Jonathan he sent me a photo okay and
look at this one let's magnify on the
left side you can see your sake so he
put a key with my my website logo they
are sake and also notice the key caps
are Braille they have you know the
Braille for the blind so you can see you
can feel the key caps and he's got a
bunch of other you know photos and stuff
this is great for dead that's Emacs of
course those pears I don't know what
they are
what are those pears and this I think
I've seen but I don't remember what that
is and this is what Albert our instance
or Edgar Allen Poe
looks like probably Edgar Allen Poe
maybe I don't know who that is this
looks familiar
is it Marx or is it some Russian writer
and you have Emacs into a no no no whose
that is now this I have seen this is a I
think possibly it's a the guy who
created Lisp that does anyone know
either that or the UNIX guys I forgot
I've seen this photo you know like you
can search it it's probably on Wikipedia
somewhere the PTO's now this is album
cover of The Beatles John Lennon maybe I
don't know who that is
this mr. Spock but anyway so he created
this thing that is a old old computer
code he told me code key to or something
anyway so this thing I don't know what
that is I think this is a most code
machine okay so that is that keyboard so
this is a point-of-sale keyboard which
is interesting because you have so many
keys I wouldn't buy it because you know
for me I need economic keyboards I
cannot type on the street keyboards so I
need to go get one you know I use that
this one so you
I recommend them then also get a keypad
programmable keypad that is my
recommendation because programmable
keypad gives you a lot function keys you
can just single key press to do things
okay I think that's it for today
anything else
that's it for today thank you for
watching bye