Hello guys, good morning. Good morning.
Welcome to another episode of Exar Talk
Show. We are going to code Emac this
today. Continued from last episode two
days ago. Emac this programming
language. The best programming language
for text processing best than pearl,
python, uh, woofam language, hascal, f
or camel. Best than any programming
language for the task of text
processing. Okay, which is a giant huge
task. Emac bisp. Uh, I have so much hand
pen. So, let me show you my keyboards
again. Glove 80. Fantastic keyboard.
Ultimate hacking keyboard. Fantastic.
Nia track ball. I have a Hoover to
activate Windows system. Fantastic. This
uh Logitech
405502. Got the spin wheel. That's the
best thing. Spin forever. Infinite
squirrel. Then uh then let me mention
this again. I got I type so much. I'm
going to become a
Uh the the the spot that hurts is right
here. Okay, let's see. Like right here
for me, left hand. So I'm going to start
to learn this again. No guarantees, but
this is uh the most advanced fancy input
device. This is called SWAR board. SV A
L B O A R D. Okay, it's got two pieces.
So, I did I have a review for each one
of them on YouTube. Now, let's begin
coding. If you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed. 1.5 speed.
Okay? Because I ramble. Otherwise, if
you are here, say hi. Love to see your
comments. Love to see your comments.
Okay. So, let's start to
code. Let's see how many of you are
watching. Three. Three is a crowd
include counting myself. Okay. I'm using
um I'm using Emacs the most efficient
editor showing browser. This is today's
talk show. Uh and I'm using SFY keys
which is uh efficient key binding system
for Emacs. There's a video you can watch
so you don't have to press control keys
or old keys or meta almost none. Okay.
So the most efficient so more efficient
than vim neo vim okay counting
keystrokes if you count keystrokes doing
the same thing keys is more efficient
than vim or neo vim or whatever okay
kafly keys that's what I'm using it's
you can download for free of course you
can watch a video download for free on
github uh it's also on gnu alpa and the
pink window shows all my commands and
call custom commands and keystrokes and
I'm using a vorac keyboard layout which
is which is uh close that okay uh
showing browser uh vorac keyboard layout
okay that's looks like that
uh most efficient you know so but so
should you switch to it or not that
depends okay there's lots of uh reasons
for most people no just get a
keyboard. If you type, you know, if you
type eight hours a day or something for
10 years, 20 years, if you are a
programmer or working with computers as
a professional, the first thing, the
first most important thing is to get a
keyboard
with linear light mechanical switches.
Okay, key switch guide. So, you can look
at my keyboard, you know. So get a
linear mechanical switch. That's the
most important. Okay. You can get one
any one of these or you can you know uh
follow me with these fancy keyboards.
Okay. So that's about keyboards. Now
let's talk about let's let's start to
code. Okay. So, so today's talk show now
the so it began you know we started um
continuation from two days ago which I
have to go so this code but before we do
that so what we have what we will uh
want to do is to add a ID uh to uh HTML
dive tag okay so for example you look at
this page JavaScript uh let's go to
JavaScript class, okay? JavaScript
tutorial on
kxali.info. kxi.info. Okay. Uh just go
there. Then you'll see a JavaScript
tutorial. JavaScript in depth. Then you
go down. You go to the let's say
strings. Okay. String
overview. JavaScript string. Fairly
complicated. You see because each
character is actually code unit code
unit from
UTF16. So it's not entirely a character
anyway. So you see this page you got
this topic box. Okay. Copy the URL. Go
to Emacs. Open this file. Showing
browser. You see that's a file. Go back
to Emacs. So you got you see this topic
box. Uh wait I don't want to delete. You
see topic box JavaScript string. Then
each ele then you got a list of items
showing browser go to the bottom you can
see that so that's so we were doing what
we want to do is that find all these
topic box among the 10,000 HTML and for
each one add a ID attribute
uh like this okay then random string so
if the topic box is the same for example
this one. So for each one of these
page change add the ID attribute to this
topic box for each one of these. Now
some other pages they'll be different.
So for example let's say let's go to um
JavaScript variable variable. Okay you
got a topic box but it's a different
topic. Okay.
So so for all these page they need an ID
of the same ID. Now for different topic
box you need a different ID. So you need
to go through 10,000 HTML files to add a
unique ID for this uh same topic. Okay,
that
was what we were doing two days ago but
we didn't complete but one of the key
thing is that you need this ID string.
Okay. But okay. So wait, but let's
digress. You see, because I want to
know because you know when you need to
add ID for example this, you know, you
you you want to avoid collision. So you
want to avoid collision. So you need to
know what is the you know the maximum
possible ID
values. Um and
uh okay let me let me do it. Uh let me
talk about this issue.
Okay. So show in browser close close
show in browser that's today's talk show
and we are talking about ID stream.
Okay. So uh so where so uh so we need to
add this make it
code code code cut that put here showing
browser. So we need to add that you see.
So let me
expand to each of the topic
box like
this. Okay, showing browser. You see
that's what we want to do. So but before
you write a code, you need to come up
with the ID. How do you get the ID? In
my case, I have a command. So let me
show you. Press, press, press. You see
you got an ID. Press press press press.
That command is insert insert random
string.
Okay. So you can go here is a source
code not too long but actually it call
random string. So go up here. So this is
random string. So what does it what are
the possible characters for random
string? They are a toz and zero to nine
uppercase and lower case but except
vowels. So you don't have a e i o u
upper or lower nor do you have l and l
you know uppercase l or lowerase l nor
do you have zero and one. So this why
because to avoid
ambiguity. But why do you so? Because L
and lower case lowerase L and one look
similar and uh zero looks similar to the
letter O. That's why you don't want
them. But what about vows? What about a
E? You know, but I is also similar to
one O L. But what about you capital I
for example? But what about A, E, and U?
Why do you want to remove them? Because
when you create a random string and when
there's a vow, you tends to form a
association of a word sometimes like
you know, you don't want that.
It's like it's pretty easy to have a
association with a word. So by removing
vows, you don't have that problem. Okay.
So and this code you can grab the code
if you want it yourself. So you got this
bunch of functions to insert random
string. You can insert a random number,
decimal number or random hexadimal
number or random string or um and or
then you have insert UU ID. Okay, let's
talk about that. Copy. So uh close. Let
me let me get uh to it. Okay. So, paste
that and uh insert random UID. Let me
demo. Okay. Copy that. Paste link them
both. Make a list. And uh this uh this
this make a text. Okay. Now, show in
browser. So, you got insert random UID
and insert random random string. You can
get the code and use them. Fantastic.
Thank you, Kasa. If you like my stuff,
donate, okay? Grab the code and donate.
100 bucks if you have a job. If you work
at Google or
something, put
999. Uh, by the way, someone wants to
buy my website, uh, you know, I sell for
$300, I send you a zip code. It's about
six It's about 6,000
unique files, essays, computer language
tutorials or
mathematics. So, but I haven't sent it
yet. Okay, I need to generate it. I make
sure, you know, make sure I generate a
new one. So, okay, you know, um, so wait
for
it. So, water says water says I tried to
switch to war. It almost broke my mind.
I got dizzy trying to practice. I gave
up. Yeah, it's not necessary. Okay. So,
I learned Vorac back in
1993 because I'm obsessed with
efficiency. You know, when I learned
about a quarty layout, it's like
up. Ju just, you know, the the why is
the letter arrange, you know, QWE TY as
SDF, you know, why is it that way? Oh,
because back then about 200 years ago
they want to avoid key jam. So they put
some frequent words in like different
places. So they avoid key jam but not
for making you type faster because if
you type fast they're going to jam they
going to make you slow actually specific
for that purpose. You know you go online
you read about it lot there's lots of
myth and conflict information. Some say
some say oh quarterty is actually not
designed to slow you down but actually
it
is the way our letter arrangement on
standard keyboard that's called quarti
because the first row is quer ty okay
invented some 200 years ago it is that
way
because in a sense it's because to
prevent people typing fast. Okay, that's
basically the bottom line. But you look
online, you you have thousands
conflicting info. Some say you are
wrong. No, you are wrong. Okay, ignore
them. So that's what we got. You know,
lots of histories like that. Like for
example, in programming languages, why
we have the Unix, you know, the
complicated bag of Because history
and C and all that history. Okay, we
can't just change it overnight because
we have habits, you know. You know, for
example, if you change the keyboard,
nobody knows how to type anymore. You're
going to relearn. You know, everyone, we
don't want to learn new things. We want,
you know, we want just to get on. So,
habit is a powerful force.
So, and you know the traditional math
notation, the traditional music
notation, you know, the five lines
musical staff, it's all kind of
convention and including English
language, you know, tons of bad
spelling, you know, I read it. I read
it, you know, and and lots of problems,
orthography, and lots of issues,
illogical, but we cannot change it. And
there's habit involved. So um yeah, so
there's so anyway on the keyboard. So
you got the quarty layout. I mean then
then you got a you got the vorac layout.
Okay. Let's talk about that a little
bit. So digress. Uh vorac layout. Okay.
So let me show you the page
uh
ergonomic keyboard layout. So it's this
this page is all the layouts that exist.
You see quot you see
borak you see quarty
is the bigger the circle the more
frequent is that key. Okay. Now if you
look at quarti you know it's all over
you you know but if you look at
vorac design all the most frequently
used keys are on your under your
fingers. Then you got comac. Then you
got QFM, you got workman. So you got a
lot of new ones. But the question is,
should you relearn any one of these new
uh for most people? No. Okay, it's not
worth it. Okay, that's my view. I talk
about
this almost every week for three years.
So, in my old tutorial, I mean in my old
videos, uh, let's say two or three years
ago, you'll see I talk about this almost
every week. Okay. So, but so let's not
um talk about that keyboard
uh stuff. So, that's about you know
keyboard layout and stuff and
efficiency. Now, back to the
uh random stream. Okay. So you have seen
I want to insert a random string you
know. So one of the common random string
in computer industry standard is called
UU ID. It stand for something like
universal
something ID. Okay. So we can insert
that. Let's see
uh the key insert a random string. Okay.
Random string. insert a random digit I
mean random number let's say I want 10
digit I mean let's say I want
nine digits of a decimal random decimal
number okay so press that nine then
press this wait I press it wrong press
nine universal argument nine
then there it is now selected
and uh call how
many call count words. So you got nine
characters you can see in the bottom
nine characters. Let's say I want 20
characters.
Okay. Uh press that key 20 uh wait press
that key 20 then press the key to insert
the random decimal number which is this.
You see now you got 20 digits. Same
thing with a random string. Now let's
say I want 20 digits. Okay, so universal
argument 20 then you got
20 random string. Okay, all the command
names you can see on the pink window.
Okay, so random string, random number.
What about random hexadimal? Okay, you
can do it like that. Okay, that that
that. What about 20 digits of it? Okay,
universal argument 20 that there you go.
Hexad decimal. Okay, 16 base number
system. So that's uh that are all these
commands.
Uh it's all here. Okay, so what about UU
ID? Okay, let's insert that. So I
believe the key is that uh no uh I
forgot what is a key. So you can press
show all keys and and search for UU ID.
There it is. Okay. Insert random UU ID.
Delete TZ. Okay. Delete
TZ. There it is. Delete TZ. Okay.
DTZ. Okay, this is a
standard random string called UU ID. So,
it's got
basically a specific format
of
32 digits of hexadisimal. Okay, that's
UID. Now, this is
uh London hexadismo.
Okay, let's uh comment it so make it
clear what we doing now. This
is
random decimal. Okay. And this is this
part
is random
string. Okay. Now put it back show in
browser. So we got some examples of
random string. Now there's a question
when you design a random ID such as in
YouTube. So if you notice every time you
go to YouTube there is this you know
random sequence of characters that's
their ID. That's basically each YouTube
video got this ID. So this is today's
talk
show you know. So this is recursive.
This is me talking right now. Okay.
Close it. So you you see YouTube got ID.
Similarly for uh Twitter every time you
make a post you see
there. There is this guy. This is
related to computer science. Our topic
today there's this guy Peter
Laden. I started to really dislike this
guy. He's dead by now. You know he's
like uh he died 20 years ago. He's a
computer scientist. Okay. Uh I started
to not like him because I learned he did
a great damage in programming language
syntax in
particularly in the functional
programming languages meta language ML
or Hascal or camel rust and python. you
know he he he created you know the
Python indentation syntax
that's partially came from this guy okay
and the ok camel's let the Hascal or
camel meta language they let something
also came from this guy and this guy is
kind of a troll okay the Peter Laden why
because he wrote the article the next
700 programming languages
you know, he's he's going to tell you
this thing, you know, I'm going to
create a syntax for the next 700
programming
languages. A grifter, okay, a clickbait
grifter. This guy, you know, seems a
smart guy, Peter Laden. I never heard of
him much because he didn't actually
create any language, but he's anyway,
he's a computer scientist. Okay. So, I
started to not like him. But back to our
topic. You see each
post got this ID. You see, copy that.
Okay.
So, you see
sample x.com ID. Okay. And uh and
today's talk show where where is it?
Here. Okay.
Then sample YouTube ID. You see? So
that's just for references purposes. So
we got ID. So but you when you design
your ID, you want to know how many
possible digits are there. I mean how
many possibilities are there? Because
you don't want collision. So for example
in the Twitter case
uh Twitter case that's really low. How
many how many digits is
that? Press press press press 19
characters. So it's only got 19
characters. So 19 characters is like um
that's not much. You're going to have
collision. That's interesting. Oh okay.
So each person by person. Okay. So for
each person you might have this many
poss possible posts.
So if you po uh post one message per
second, you know, for example, one
message per second. So 60
um let's let's let's do some random
coding and chat.
Okay,
60. So you got 24
hours each hour is 60 minutes. Each
minutes is 60 seconds. Okay, let's
compute
that. How many is
that? W language takes a while. So
that's that many. Okay. No, but but if
you do this
335 every day, you know, you do this
uh let's say one second per post for a
year.
Okay. What do you get? Show
me. Okay. So, you you only got that. So
if you do this for 10
years you know you then you just add
zero right that's not
much.
So okay let's show in browser. Okay
so show in browser. So
Twitter's let's see where is Twitter
Twitter's ID seems sufficient because if
you post one second per post for a year
you only get this much and Twitter ID is
like uh how many you know 19 digits. So
that's that's sufficient. If you post
one second per
post for 100 years you would not reach
the maximum of Twitter. But wait, but
these are random numbers. So you still
have possibility of collision because
these are not sequential. But
anyway, okay, that's so anyway that's
these are the issues about
identity
identifier about random identifier
design issues. Okay, random identifier
design and for that you can look into um
our article. Okay. So I digress so much.
Uh where is the
article? So we are talking about random
ID design. Okay. There it is. Okay. So
this article dive into detail
about what are the total
possibilities of a random
string design. You know if you are doing
YouTube, if if you are going to create a
YouTube website or Twitter or anything,
you need a like random string like how
many digits are you gonna have and also
what is your base. You see, you see one
thing interesting about YouTube is that
they used they include the underscore.
You see they also include
dash and you know you can you can see
they also include
vows. So there are 26 English letters
upper and lower case together is
possibilities plus 10 digits 0 to 9. So
52 + 10 62. So you got 62 based base
called radix. Okay, that's called
radix. Okay, 62. But in the YouTube case
then you also got underscore. Okay, they
also include underscore and dash. So you
got
um 62 + 2 64 base something like that.
Okay.
Then you want to know then depends on
how many digits you have total then you
can know what is the potential then you
have to think about how many videos each
person creates a day things like that
you have to
consider okay so that's about random uh
random string design okay design of
random let let me let me type it
okay new section
design of random
uh ID system of
random sequence of characters.
Okay. Then okay then then then then then
then move that down. Move that down.
Okay. And uh we want Okay. Cut. Let's
let me tell you what's going on. You'll
see. So we are talking
about Okay. So we got a new section now
cleaned up about design
of random sequence of characters for an
ID
system. So now we need to look at this
article.
So, so, so right now the question is if
I'm going to design an ID system for my
dive
tag, you know, I know my base, my radics
is um is uh is I think 50 you know 26
letters plus digits minus the vowels and
minus zero and one that's that's 48.
Okay. So I my radex is 48. So how many
digits do I need? That's the question
because I want to avoid collision. Okay.
So then so that's when you need to look
at this article. Okay. So for example my
uh why don't we why don't we just
compute it? Okay. So so so so that we
make this much more clear for those who
are later on watching this. Am I
good? It's interesting. So, uh um so
first of all, Juan says, "Do you think
Sufa is difficult?" You are talking
about Sufa, which is Chinese
calligraphy, which is the Chinese
tradition of use using a brush pen to
write Chinese characters. That's Chinese
calligraphy.
Aka Sufa, I want to make some uh for
women, for your
girlfriend. Yeah, you can do that. That
would be
fun. But Chinese
calligraphy
is is useless. It's kind of idiotic.
Okay. First first of all, Chinese
calligraphy. Now, if you are a white guy
or Western guy, if you are not Chinese,
then you don't know what I'm talking
about. Okay. But for Chinese and
Japanese or or or Korean, well, mostly
Chinese and Japanese still kind of do
it. It's a tradition. It's a cultural
tradition and art. Okay. And you kind of
also learn some kind of discipline
because every day. So have you guys seen
a Chinese click? You
know, you know, when I was in school
age, you know, 10 years old, you know, I
have to do this uh lots of Chinese have
to do this Chinese calligraphy. Okay, so
let me just show p
pictures. Uh so kind of like that that
okay this is how you do it. So you use a
brush pen basically you write Chinese
and you just keep doing it. So you kind
of de develop a style and and some of
them are beautiful. So there are many
kind of styles you know. So you that's
this these are called Chinese
calligraphy. So you see this is more
fancy one. There are many different
styles. Okay. Chinese calligraphy. So,
it's kind of similar to
uh to
English. Um let's see. Uh wait, uh let's
do a
screenshot. Do a massive screenshot. So,
let's digress and demo
calligraphy. Okay. So, snip as
um so it's like
similar similar
to
English. E N G L I S H English
uh
cursive. So, but in western tradition
you don't use a bush pen. So, what you
use is this um you use this um what's
the name of that pen? Ink. you know you
have to dip ink pen you know you have to
um I forgot you know but it's another
topic okay so okay so that's about
Chinese
calligraphy so it is a tradition okay so
wait uh save yes save okay it's a
tradition Chinese
tradition you know so you kind of learn
you know if you are Chinese or Japanese
you kind of learn tradition tradition.
That's how you learn your culture.
That's how you develop a sense of your
bloodline. Okay? Just like the western,
the white people, they have, you know,
their things like Rome
and But the question is, is this good?
No. Well, it's good in some way, but
it's useless. Okay. What you want to do
is rocket science, not calligraphy.
Okay? you doing Chinese calligraphy does
does not make China great. You doing
English um you know um
um cursive writing, the art of cursive
writing does not make America great
again. Okay, you want to do rocket
science, you want to do Emacs, you want
to do coding. Okay, that's the thing. So
is it good? Well, you can learn it, you
know, as a hobbit or, you know, that's
fine, but it's useless basically for
modern
society. So that so you want to show
that to your girlfriend. Yeah, you can
do
[Laughter]
that. So, uh, a says just use a
collision resistant ID package. No,
that's not good because because you just
shove the the problem into other people
and you rely on other people's solution,
you know. And what is the collision
resistant ID package? IDs are typically
assigned by the database. No need to
design ID. That's totally wrong. Where
do you think the database ID came from?
Somebody has to design it.
Thank you. Anything? And uh Okay, cool.
I'm personally here for programming
content. Okay, so okay, I'm back back to
back to
um you see we need to be poly math. You
see the other problem with coding is
just that you got lots of nerds. Then
you started to know nothing else about
society. You don't know you don't know
how society works. All you know is like
coding bits biting you know or
mathematics you know then but then you
became this
narrow you know you you lost you lost
the sense of humanity you lost the
purpose you lost the appreciation of
beauty you don't know why you are here
you know you ignored philosophy or you
know
arts so that's the other problem okay so
anyway let's go back to coding
Okay. So ID characters um design. So we
back to Yeah. So you can actually So for
example, so so one way
to to know to be safe is just based on
the UU ID. Okay. So UU ID is because UU
ID uh where is our
example? Uh where is it? Show it. So, UU
ID is
these 32
hex heximo um digits hexadimal digits 32
of them. So, whatever that should be
enough because UID is designed such that
if everyone every second create 10,000
UID is not likely to collide because the
the the numbers are too big. Okay. So,
so whatever you are designing you if you
make it to be the same number of
possibilities of UU ID then it's good.
Okay.
So, so we can see UU ID is 16 base.
Okay. So, 16 and how many how many of
them? 32 of them. Okay.
So, 32. So the total is is three follow
basically a number of 30 38 digits. Okay
that's like that's more than the atoms
in the universe something like that. So
system B if you base on just English
letters 26 of them then how many how
many uh you
need you need a lot. Okay, you need like
um let's
say okay you need about
28 27 to 28 number of digits. Okay, so
you kind of save five digits. So you see
what we want is that we want you know
the same number of possibilities but we
want to have smaller string as much as
possible. That's a desired uh thing. But
however the issue is that if you look at
you know if you read this article the
graph is
that if you just increase one more digit
that gives you a lot more possibilities
but if you increase the base they don't
grow much. Okay. So you so if you want
the more possibilities you need to
increase the number of digits. Okay. So
but but but what we going to do today is
something novel. We want to let's just
start to write EMAC this code.
Okay. So we want to do uh let's begin
write EMAC
code. Uh okay. So default
defa
insert random
Chinese cha. Okay. So we are going to
use Chinese characters for ID system
because Chinese characters they are
like depending on how you count there
are 3,000 common ones but if you count
all there are like 10 or 20,000 of it.
So one single Chinese random character
is like
already 10,000 possibilities. Okay. So
it's not like English r one English
random letter is one out of 26
possibilities but one random Chinese
character is you know like 10,000 uh
possibilities. Okay. Wait, go back. Uh
wait, where did we go? Yeah. Okay. Let's
write this.
Okay.
Um,
insert random Chinese char five of them.
Let's just say. Okay. Um, for now. Okay.
So, so first of all, what you need to
know is the the range of Chinese
characters in Unicode. Okay. Save it.
Um, so let let me show you. Chinese
characters unic code.info info you'll
find the unic code page then there is
the
Chinese okay there's some sample Chinese
characters okay copy
that close
that paste that okay then but what you
need to know is
um I need to know the unic code range I
don't know what it is so let's look up
Wikipedia Chinese encoding.
Uh, no. Big five. Okay. Convention. Uh,
unic code hand
unification. Okay. Open that
one. Guia. Okay. We don't care about
that. We want the unic code Chinese
encoding. Okay.
Uh, code page. No. So, let's go to this
page. Hand unification. Unicode.
Universal character set. character set
hand characters. Okay. Uh which is used
in Chinese characters used in also
Japan, Korea and Vietnamese. Okay. Uh
but what is the
range? Uh let's just search for unic
code hand block uh
CJK block. You'll find it directly.
There it is. Unicore block CJK stand for
Chinese Japanese Korea. Okay. So it's
from there it
is. So there are 20 of them. 20,000 of
them. Can you
see? Copy that.
Okay. So copy
that link
list. Okay. Uni code Chinese characters
block. And this is the range. Copy that.
Go to our code and paste that range.
Okay. There are there there are 20,000
of
it. Okay. So this is the range. Now I
want I need to know what is the decimal.
Okay. I don't want the uni code uh
format. So what is a decimal? You can do
in EMAC is that that
um yeah. Okay. So Eva wait not that. So
this should be pound sign x.
Okay there it is. This is a decimal.
Okay. And what about
this so you can look at the pink window
to see what I'm calling eval six. Okay.
this uh because you know this works
because this pound sign x means the
hexadimal input. Okay. So so that is
that. Okay. So the range is this to
this. Okay. So now we call
random random uh limit. Okay. So random
limit. So what we need to do is okay. So
let's
um
start and
um C start C end. Okay, something like
that. Okay, let's set it.
Yeah. Okay.
[Music]
So, C start
uh Okay, hold on a second. So, C start
will be just
that set that. Okay. and C end will
be
that. Okay.
Now,
okay. Now we got C start and C end. Then
random. I want the random number please.
Random number from
C
end minus CN minus C
start. Okay. And uh yeah create a random
then
plus then plus C start. Okay. So plus C
start there. Okay. So that gives you a
random character. Now if you
now it actually gives you a random
number. Okay. Now in Emacs a integer is
also means character. So you need to
turn this integer to a character. So
let's just say insert
um char ID. Okay. So char ID.
Wait. Set. What? What? What? What? What?
What? What? What? Set
set char ID that. Okay. Char ID equals
to that. Then
insert
insert chart to
string char ID. Okay. Purify the code.
That's it. That is the code. Okay. So,
evaluate the buffer.
Now meta xar insert random Chinese
chart. There we go. Fantastic. Now we
need to do this five times.
Okay.
So let's just quickly code it. Okay. Two
times two times
uh
five. I is a variable result. We don't
care. uh and uh delete that. And the
body will
be pg program that groups these two
together. Okay, copy
that. Paste predify the code. There it
is. Two times I from five times. Okay,
we don't actually care about the
variable. Do do it five times. generate
a try ID. In fact, we don't need this
variable. Okay, so try ID. Delete
it. Delete it. Delete it. Remove that.
Cut that. And just move the this thing
to here. Okay. And in fact, chart to
string, we don't need it. Let's just say
format. Okay. Because format 96 is uh
lowerase a. Try
it. No. Okay. So you need to say char
format
char. Uh no 95 I believe or is it 65?
Okay 65. This
asy code guessing. Okay. 65 is the ID
for capital A. There we have it. Okay.
So you can just say format C. Okay. So
let's do it. Do it. So format C. All we
have to do is just say format C and then
here you just give it a number there.
Okay. Then you don't need that. Then but
actually you need to say insert. Okay.
Pify the code. There it is. Pify. Remove
that. Pretty fine. Fantastic. Evaluate
the buffer now call. Do
it. Do it again. Do it again. Fantastic.
Okay.
Insert five of them. Okay. So, we got
the
code sample output. Okay. Put it back.
Syntax code show in browser. So today's
fruit is exploration of this function to
create uh insert random Chinese
characters. But how how many are there?
So let's see. We forgot to check how
many are there. So each letter is um so
wow let's check.
Okay. Okay. So this is my
calculator. Fantastic.
So we want
um yeah so that minus that okay we don't
care about that that
that print that that that
evaluate. So we got 20,000.
Wait. Oh. So you need that then times
five because you got five of it. Okay.
uh the others we don't care what what I
was doing you know this is my
calculator calculator pad okay I talked
about this so anyway run it so this you
got
10,000 okay so that's not
enough times five this is a power should
a power.
Yeah, fifth power. So that's why. So the
power in EMAC
is
explic basics string number arithmetics.
How do you do power exp? Okay. It's
always annoying when a programming
language don't have the correct for
power. Okay.
Exp. Wait, why is it exp
uh
what? Oh, wait. I'm in Python.
idiotic. In Python, the power is just
double double um
asterisk. Okay. Run it. F that. Okay,
that is what we looking for. This is
[Music]
the Okay.
So, save it. Close. Um, now let's create
a Python code. Paste it there. Pop out.
Comment. This is
possible. This is possibility
T possibility.
of five Chinese chars in uni
code CJK block
range. Okay, syntax correct show in
browser. So that's what we got and this
is fantastic. only five Chinese
characters and then you got this many
this many this many is even bigger than
Twitter's you know bigger than Twitter's
ID count you know where's Twitter you
see wait Twitter compare so copy that uh
Python let's say Twitter you see it's 10
three digits bigger than Twitter's so
this is sufficient this is
Beautiful. So, we got we got a fantastic
new ID design of Chinese characters,
just five of them. And usually when you
do this, because in
practice the Chinese, each Chinese knows
on average 3,000 characters to 5,000.
Five 5,000 is kind of tops just like
English. Okay. In English, when you read
a newspaper, you know, common college
educated people, you need 3,000
words. Same thing in Chinese. But
however, Chinese got, you know, 10,000
characters or more. So, so when you
create, you know, when you generate a
random character sequence of
Chinese, like most of the time, all the
words you don't know. Okay. Actually I
know some of them you know I I know like
half of them. I mean for average people
but the other half like you never seen
the world before. So anyway this is
fantastic fantastic new
uh ID design using
Chinese charts. Okay. Now what is what
are the possible flaws of this system?
Well, one for one thing you need uni
unic code
encoding you know which is very popular
today UTF8 and also you kind of need
Chinese font but which is also very
popular by default in Mac or in any
system you have Chinese font but however
using Chinese encoding um I
mean if you are dealing with ASI
low-level stuff you usually you don't
want that because then it involves
decoding the unic code. On the other
hand, if you just use ASKI characters
for random string, then any low-level
assembly, you know, even C language, you
know, they have libraries to to read
hexadimal, you know, they, you know,
they don't need to go through unic code
decoding.
But however if you are creating like in
a high level design
application this is pretty good very
short and uh and you have lots of
possibilities. So for example compared
to Twitter you got you know every time
you post you got these 19
digits or the YouTube you know like then
then you need capital some are capital
case some are lower case you know um
okay so that's kind
of I think that's a digression uh we did
but that's a good one talking about
the ID the uh character system. Okay,
that's a good digression. Uh as far as
the task about which we did about you
know adding the ID to the
dive that's not too interesting and we
did we did similar before you know we
did so many videos before but I might I
might do this offline or because I got
lots of other topics you know tomorrow I
I want to go back to wam language coding
lots of topics you know machine learning
lean proof system, F, you know,
programming, uh, lots of other things.
Okay, so I think that's it for today.
Thank you guys for
watching. Don't forget to donate to me.
Okay, so you can go to kasali.info.
kasali.info, my website for programming
stuff is called kasar code. Go to the
bottom, you PayPal me, Patreon me,
PayPal $100 uh, Amazon gift card.
Okay, thank you. Make me happy. Okay.
So, or you can if you want my you know
uh you know you can buy my entire Emac
Lisp and Emacs tutorial
uh for $30 something 32 you know I'll
send you the zip file so that you can
have a easy reference when you
[Music]
learn Emac this similarly I also have
one for JavaScript in depth you know for
for for Emacs list for example you go to
EMAC list then you go to um there buy
Emacs tutorial okay then
u mail to you or if you prefer
JavaScript if you are a webdev you know
I also have one for JavaScript in depth
this is actually more comprehensive than
my eag this tutorial so all the way down
you can see where to buy there by
I'll send you a copy so you can kind of
use it for reference. It's great for
reference because you click on the
JavaScript global reference. You got
object object which is a class object
class. Then you got object constructor
details. Then you got
object.prototype you know. So you got
object create object assign object get
prototype of these are static methods.
Then you go to object
prototype. Then these are uh the methods
you know then you know the the methods.
So you got a few of them you know has
own property is prototype prototype is
number. So but if you go back to u for
example
array you got array constructors fairly
complex array constructors then you got
array properties prototype. These are
static properties. Okay. Then but if you
go to prototype, these are dynamic
methods. This these are the used most
common. For example, push, pop, shift
and shift,
splice and contact, slice, you know, get
the keys and map for each filter, you
know, very uh frequently used. So this
is about my JavaScript tutorial the
reference section and regular expression
the entire documentation of regular
expression and so on. So for example
regular expression syntax very complex
topic okay and it's fully documented
documented and with lots of examples for
example you got this new unic code
property. So if you want to get unic
code let's say you want to grab all
emojis in a file then you need to use
this unic code regular expression you
know so I got examples for that too so
that's my uni uh JavaScript in depth
okay so check it out donate to me thank
you or if you want to like you know have
a local copy you can pay few bucks and
get anything else That's it for
today. So, let's go back. Let's see the
comments. And we shut
down. No comments. No comments. What the
AZ says, "If you create an app
today, would you design your own ID?
Would you also design the rest of the
database? And do you design ID for every
single table in the database feel like
re reinventing the wheel? Of course you
don't. Of course you don't.
You know in fact if you are industrial
coder professional
coders you don't need to know even
computer science algorithms because
hasht array uh sorting that's big
computer science or searching string how
do you implement regular expression you
don't need to know none of that you can
be a professional coder for Python or
even for machine learning and you don't
need to know about these things but
however I am a lot of time doing random
you know random programming technical
topics computer or uh science or
mathematics or theoretical computer
science and stuff pattern matching and
you know functional programming and
proof systems and type systems so
that's why I'm talking about this kind
of interesting topics about ID design
but in fact today you know today we
created this Chinese random ID in fact I
think that's useful
okay it will be I think it is I would
say 50% of chance okay
50% of chance that in five or 10 years
this will be popular okay because The
advantage of this is because you you
it's pretty short and you avoid a lot of
collision.
Okay. So this is actually a practical
application but I mean not practical
like you need it now but I think there's
a big potential you know down five or 10
years you you might see start to see you
might start to see IDs that comes in
this form okay just like a bunch of unic
code random Chinese
characters and and Chinese characters
among the uni code all the unic code
characters you know there are like I
don't know 30 thousands of them you know
Chinese is actually the most suitable
because when you talk about unic code
you could also let's try you know why
not let let's use all the emojis okay so
for example
uh where is it uh you know let's use all
the emojis uh for example
um you know so include all emojis and
why not let's also So include all um all
arrow keys you know so they there are
like 50 type of arrows or different uh
and also let's include all these exotic
alphabet desolate deseret which is um
phonetic based alphabet created by the
moments moments Christian kind of
Christian okay moments or let's include
include all the Greek letters,
okay? Or include the IPA phonetic
symbols, you know, for pronunciation.
Dad,
uh I iPod, iPad, iPad, you know,
phonetic symbols or let's include uh
historical or chemical symbols. You see
but the problem is if you include this
there are not many you know 50 100 they
don't give you this kind of bravity in
the Chinese characters and for the
Chinese characters there's no upper and
lower case that's very kind of nasty
thing because when you have upper case
and lower case for the same character
then you start to get into the
complexities of oh whether you know in
file in this file system it's um case
insensitive but in that language is case
sensitive you can have these complex
issues you see for example the YouTube
ID the YouTube ID they have some lower
case some capital
case but for some reason let's say you
need to save each YouTube video as a
file but in Mac and on Windows the file
system are not case sensitive by default
So the same ID sometimes
becomes you know they they act you know
the
same YouTube ID string they differ by
case so they meant to be different ID
but on a file system they become the
same file so that's a problem so so you
start to have you know you may get into
a problem so when but when you use
Chinese characters you don't have that
problem also another example so here is
squeeze For example, here's Greek and
variations. You have actually, you know,
this italic and bold. They are not
font. They are not font variations. They
are not, you know, style variation. They
are actual unic code
characters. So you can include Greeks,
you know, that would total of 100
characters, you know, or you can include
critic, you know, the Russian alphabet.
uh but or you can include Japanese uh
phonetic symbols the katakana and
stuff but one thing one problem is
Arabic you don't want that because
Arabic if you use these as random of
characters you they got they got right
to left problem
so you know so so some it's very um it's
not so good because either you stick
with right to left or left to right. You
if you mix them, it's not so good. Okay.
So, so that's, you know, my my uh random
comments about
that. Okay. Bye,
guys.
So, so Okay. So, bye.