good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh welcome welcome
all today is October 10th 10 o clock wow
what a coincidence in the morning San
Francisco time Thursday so today is
October 10th now October 10th is the
birthday of Taiwan the official name is
Republic of China that is the official
name of the country Taiwan the
government as a as a as a state you know
the proper term is called state in
English now the official name for the
China for the big China the giant China
the powerful which is a threat to us a
the official name of them is People's
Republic of China okay
People's Republic of China then the
Taiwanese Republic of China okay so so
October 10th is the you know watching so
in Taiwan we say I was born in Taiwan
and that is the you know so it's like
dry fourth of us a July fourth
you know the inter Independence Day but
however you see the China the big China
their birthday is also I think it's it's
October 11th or October 10th the same
day I don't remember but it's kind of
around the same and in China
you know in USA youth you know like last
year or something that or this year you
Trump has a parade you know you wrote
out tanks and missiles things like that
actually you in USA you don't see that
much okay I don't I don't remember
seeing that much in USA in my 30 years
in u.s.
since 1989 you don't see that in Canada
y-you don't see that but however you see
that in Taiwan every year this every
year when I was in Taiwan from 1968 I
was born in 1968 - and I left I left
Taiwan in 1984 so when I was a child as
far as I can tell you know every year
you have parade and also always they
include their military parade so you
have giant missiles you know giant
missiles and jet fighters very loud you
know firing into the sky every year okay
now this is time one every year Taiwan
remember time one is supported backed up
and important to USA because you know
it's a kind of like Japan you know we
say they are friends and in a way it's
pretty much controlled by USA you know
in USA we say we don't you know like
Russia
come on is e-tron crazy you know in USA
we worry about Oh Russia Russia is
meddling with our politics Russia is
meddling with our democracy meddling
with our election United States of
America we made out with every other
country on earth okay so let's start
today's talk show talk show welcome and
we I have actually prepared several
topics and but I think you guys have
some topics so let's talk about that
okay so magnify let me get prepared do I
look good oh my god do I look good is my
tie straight okay
I need to now I look better
no I need to put on a cease face yes I
see anger yes good okay
Santos show I've been talking for four
minutes
and let's look at the comments and I
have discord ready
the the software that bathroom you loves
okay so let's read the comments so
bathroom you says you have some topics
okay shoot
topics so need Nebo won't wanted me to
talk about Emacs we haven't done Emacs
for a while but you know
niebo type something specific like even
a general direction like you need to say
something because I've done Emacs you
know now and then every week I have
Emacs stuff so you know I could start
somewhere you know just pick a random
thing but it's it's you know but I don't
have anything in mind so it's always
better okay any of you you know type you
know if you want me to talk about Emacs
or you might be type something specific
like or anything you know I could you
know put the name of something
Emacs hooks right was it you who asked
about Emacs Emacs hooks yesterday nibel
I think it was you I missed the comments
but I saw it later so we I can I think
yeah so we can I can go through a
tutorial about what is hook in Emacs
okay like if you guys run out of
thoughts like you if you you want me to
talk about Emacs but you don't have
something in mind usually it's hard to
think about something at the time you
can just go to my Emacs website and
let's say sorry Emacs okay sorry max
such
then you go to practical Emax tutorial
then you click this yellow button to go
to the index home page then you see
exhaust Emacs sitemap you click on that
then this is a list of all topics on
this website so there are 760 articles
so you go here there is a random nice
button you click that and you hold down
the control key or command key then you
open them open whatever that comes you
know that interests you then you look at
them and you think this is interesting
or this reminds you of some other things
questions you have then get the uija or
just type it ok so that way I have a
direction you know I'm answering some
questions
you know feel you know do that do that
is better because otherwise I have
10,000 articles like which part of Emacs
I want to talk about I don't know ok so
that's about that so so if you want me
to if you have a questions about hook I
mean say it yeah it's always better if
you just say it so bathroom you say it's
number 13 chef software i seee
controversy i don't know what is the
chef software and Mattamy says Microsoft
says the value repair ability design
small repairable product I haven't heard
of that post the link bottom he first
link I don't know why your post links
doesn't show up something are you like
trolling over the place or like YouTube
censor you or something oh you can
always dissect the link you know what I
mean right it should be easy I don't see
I don't see why Google would censor that
for example here's a link you dissect it
into parts then this way
you will not be censored you know I
I don't see why you have this posting
link problem okay so I don't know what's
the chef software ID and what is IC e
controversy are they related or are they
different top topics I know the IC
controversy is about no borders the
American left extreme leftist they want
no borders they have this idea in recent
years of no borders it's like you know
if you have a home you have a house you
should not have doors you should allow
anyone to enter your home
same idea no borders that is the
American Left Party the Democratic Party
officially that is their position
rather it's not their position but it
just happens to be you know it's their
pasture it's their weaponized issue like
you this is issue
this is identification issue it's like
Emacs maitake you know you have to
mention we have to have metal key
otherwise you are not with us okay Emacs
must have meta key and that key must be
named meta not ought not something else
it must be named meta key then you are
with us otherwise you are not you don't
deserve to do to use Emacs same kind of
idea so my god oh my god let me think
about that enterprise management
software
so what enterprise management software
what is that I don't know what they say
it is shifts off we are you okay so
let's keep reading the comments you have
the feeling part of me says I have a
feeling that I use less new software
than you accept Linux yeah well you know
good new software
you know like depends on what you mean
well I guess I don't know but but anyway
the glue software are very specific you
know that for example there are many
open-source project and many software I
mean
is the organization they have some
specific software that is supposed to be
new software for example there is a
there is a software called
new plot ok new plot
ok let's search it it's it's one of the
circuits software ok so here is a new
plot now although the software has the
name renewing it but it's actually it's
it is actually not a new project ok so
you see it even says in Wikipedia it is
a program with a fairly long history
dating back to 1986 despite its name
this software is not part of new project
ok so you you have to remember be aware
that you know some software that's new
and old you know this is actually not a
new project and also many software in
open source Linux of with software
community sometimes they were at one
time part of new project you know
suppose I mean this is you know the
actually there is no precise definition
like what is good new project because
it's kind of mixed mixes around you know
sometimes so in history in the past 20
years 30 years some software a one time
doing for 10 years for example they are
supposedly part of the official group
project but then the leader doesn't like
which astro-man anymore or Richard
snowman doesn't like the guy anymore
they they fight and they they went their
separate
separate ways then you know the the
software now say so we are not done no
longer part of new you know this happens
now and then so it's you know it's the
ugly history of the open-source people
but usually the open-source fanatics yet
they don't talk about it and they don't
know about it you know because these
people these kind of stories you know
anything negative
do not get spread
by your church so father human says how
can I post a link if you can see it
dissect links are also censored
seriously I don't know I don't know
what's going on with your account I
posted a link it so this just yeah I
don't know what's going on it seemed
part you know I I think something wrong
with your account or what whatever you
are doing because when you dissected ink
it is impossible for Google algorithms
to even detect the link there are so
many ways you can dissect it you know
you can you can post a link not you can
post a link you can separate the words
and you can you know to watch 13 like we
talked about the other day or 13
he becomes you know that Google will not
be able to tell it's a link unless I
don't know what's yeah we we have seen
other people post links and if it's
sensor they should show up you know it
should show up I haven't you know I
don't I've never censored or anything
like that of anyone okay so let's see
what what is the other questions or
comments actually I want to get on
talking about today's things 17 14
minutes okay so many 17 people watching
so I don't know what you were talking
about about Microsoft chef software or
management software I mean what what
what enterprise management software that
we which one oh it's a link visible so I
mean they there are so many creative
ways to post the link and not be it not
be censored this is something you are
not doing correctly I'm pretty sure of
that easier side to such four V's
functions yes meow-meow you are not a
Emacs users who has skin that if you
want to know is zero site to such a
these functions you can find it in in
five minutes if that's if you really
have that question
Emacs see Emacs turn gentle gentle how
do you pronounce gentle gentle
so bottom you says recently I always
have to reload the page when your stream
starts if I don't reload it says the
stream starts in 15 minutes
oh I don't know what's going on are you
what browser are you using so the best
tips I can give you five days in you
actually sort of you of prefer switching
make your own parade and write an
article about it come on easy trunk
crazy I put out the thought out of my
head when you said America is measuring
with every other country on Earth okay I
forgot what say your opinion on the
chaff controversy what is the
controversy what Jesus what Jeff
software
oh okay so I guess these chef software
magnify magnify chef is a company in the
name of a configuration configuration
management tool writing in Ruby and Olin
it uses a pure Ruby domain-specific
language for writing system
configuration recipes chef is used to
streamline the task of configuration
configurating and maintaining a
company's servers and can integrate with
loud with cloud-based platforms such as
to automatically provision and configure
new machines yeah chef contains
solutions for both small and large scale
so what what what is the controversy oh
no no what is the controversy
so did Microsoft bot chef yeah keep
using open source and here are someone
buys it then the cycle starts again
okay so Jeff software is you know
configuration management you know
automation something like that they are
tons of it you know like I said before
technology is going exponentially now
you have to dive into that thought
exponentially means after a few years it
is impossible to even know you what you
are what is possible to know is like a
drop of water in ocean okay so you know
like we are looking at chef software you
know you think oh you don't one thing
new today but actually it's likely there
are 1000 such software that's that's
used use around the world right now you
just don't hear or know about it and
that's only one specific because because
you know a few years ago I I have a
friend who was doing you know he's a
test engineer
so there's a lot optimation he is
involved you know so I learned about it
is a huge turned I mean it's an industry
so
testing software testing is kind of a
field you know in software so there's a
huge industry that does that you know
you have lots of automation tours
auto-configuration
auto installed you know and they are a
lot and you never heard of so what's the
next painting my house postings I have
seen no one ever puts the link in chat
hey were just such for it Chevy is
pretty known it tries it I tried a sec
it does not work
Google doesn't like Firefox you know try
try Google comp no source code for Evo
developers no source code for Evo
developers pressure chef software to cut
ties with IC e oh okay I get it now I
think I heard of something like that so
chef is a open source I suppose
apache license yes and I suppose the IC
e you know the United States
what does IC stand for immigration I see
well anyway it's a it's a it's
organization government organization to
to work with immigration immigrants you
know visa and things like that and and
and you know so the American extreme
leftist such as antifa they don't want
you know they want no borders and stuff
so they so for some reason they found
out that this American government
organization ice is using chefs so they
don't want them to use it things like
that I don't know the details but the
details it's not important I don't think
it's something significant you have
these kind of things every day
okay so let me let me start to talk
about today's topic let's switch some
let's talk about some keyboard for less
serious less serious less serious less
seriousness less serious less business
yes okay so the first yeah so so I don't
know what chef software
okay so copy that
oh I didn't start saw start command log
mod okay so you see all my Emacs
commands on the left window okay and
let's close that reopen go here and
that's proposed oh right yeah III have
some topics I really want to talk about
first of all first first is the Emacs
block okay so I mean not Emacs block
Google censorship so Google has you know
there's a new scoop and comp dot Emacs
new school and Google basically censored
it so you go there you can no longer see
the new school you I mean you can no no
no longer access it you know google says
banned the content warning it says well
it says because there are lots of spam
so it's automatically spam or more where
things like that which is actually true
so Google says because of that they they
are banning this new scoop and now you
can only read it but you cannot post but
however you click continue to group it
it shows the same page so basically the
comp that Emacs new scoop is it's gone I
mean Google you can no longer view the
content 30 years 30 years of history
Google just wiped it out you know this
will never happen now let me talk about
bait
three about Google Groups around year
2001 or something like that around 2001
Google Google okay first of all what is
a new scoop new scoop is a old
technology just like today's you know
discord or IRC not not like I was like
discord of Reddit kind of like reddit
okay
kind of like reddit you go there post
messages you have many varieties of
topics comped out Emacs complement that
this come land that pearl come land that
you know this is and and also
non-technical like comp dot oh oh
start sex for example you know you have
like thousands of different topics you
go there you post things you know we
talk with people about that subject so
that's new scoop ok new scoop you can
you know you can just go to you
Wikipedia and see it okay so new scoop
for example lists of new scoops so
that's technology around around 1990s or
even earlier so I was a frequent use of
news group starting around nineteen
night starting around 1999 1998 to 2011
something like that okay okay I have now
since we started to talk about this I
have a tons of things to say about these
history things so you go to we we go to
again this network word anthropology
kind of a shot of history of new scoops
part of it is about that you kind of you
can see that many new scoops for example
such for okay deaths of new scoops for
example
death of new scoops okay this is this
happened this so I wrote this article in
2010 death of newsgroups
Microsoft is closing down their new
scoops see these are Co so this new
scoop is Microsoft dot Pollock dot
Windows dot PowerShell and they post you
know they they post this and I have a
link to Google Groups let's see if we
can access it so death of new scoops
let's see okay so oh yeah so I want to
visit that let me magnify a bit okay so
I want to visit this so I [ __ ] our
Google Chrome opening brass URL chrome
opening Chrome browser open linking
chrome okay and now let's click on this
Google Groups link let's see if it shows
up let's see if it's censored okay so we
can Co see it so so apparently
apparently they only close down the
compound Emacs one yeah so you see this
is what you see so if you click continue
to the group you get the same page no
topic available in this group you know
so the history of Google Groups is that
actually you can just read Wikipedia
okay Google Groups let's search for
Wikipedia there it is Wikipedia so so
back in 2001 the web became popular new
scoop is not on a web by the way new
scoop is a different technology you know
it's a different technology it's not on
the web it's not a website but you know
because since 1995 people you know the
web is going so it almost everything
begin to
to the web starting with email same
thing with the new scoop you know people
start to have you know websites that
that shows new scoop content so at the
time one of the most popular website
that shows new scoop content that allows
you to read and post new scoop is stage'
news okay this with this logo deja News
very popular everyone is using then okay
now you see he says this up hype was
acquired by Google in 2001 so Google
bought it basically Google say hey
here's few billion dollars there you go
now you belong to us Cuoco 2001 and back
then we were all cheering for it because
Google was a to no Evo company remember
this is 2001 you know so Google with
Google's great you know smart engineers
back then you know all the people at
Google are you know basically the best
engineers not today today they are go
crap so in so they goo about it and we
are all happy because Google is small
you know Google software is always the
best you know every design it just works
so that's back then you know and
Google's
you know Google's mantra Google's
principle back then was you know they
want to they want to help the world to
get information that is their goal you
know they have a phrase in chant about
that so we were happy because that's all
that's Google's business you know new
scoop is about information human history
you know yeah new school beginning 1980
is something I don't know exactly okay
you can read Wikipedia for detail but
anyway so Google about it and we are all
happy because now you have better search
better interface better everything
Google's bright engineers working on it
then
okay that's back then then as I
mentioned you know around to that by
2010 new scoop is kind of already is
dead
you know you know by 2007 2006 you know
new Scoob
start to win anyway because you started
to have for example reddit began around
what 2004 then you have hacker news and
your hacker news you know around about
that time think you have Wikipedia so
new Scoob kind of went away and you have
lots of other you know reddit you read
it is the big one forums you know it
kind of replays new scoops so new scoop
back in let's say 2006 they are still
fairly you know sizable number of users
but those people are basically the
hacker types okay yeah you guys hack
adepts in me kind of odd away already at
at that time the new school by 2005 then
the users of new scoop is already kind
of the older generation because younger
generation they just go to the web
reddit
yeah way that you go to Reddit do you go
to hacker news so that that is the story
about new scoops so by 2010 new scoop is
uh it's like 90 90 percent spam now you
guys know spam I hate you guys in the
same time you know the tech kickers they
are trying to fight spam I know because
you did you say issues the company I
work for GC okay you know you know
Google ya censorship is so bad because
because you your posts contain the word
hate that is why and also killed as you
know Google Evo so in my opinion I know
you I know you are a big open-source fan
but in my opinion the reason Google
become this way is part is is
significantly due to the open source and
free software fanaticism
that's that created this situation
that's my opinion I know you know many
of you do not agree that's fine so
anyway so Google the new scoops by 2010
is full of spam I know how do I know
because I was using
every day you go there you know 90% is
spent to the point that you know good
new scoops you know as a tech nerd yes
tech geek er you know we hacker types we
have like everyday we are chanting oh we
have this great filter you know
technology Bayesian theater you know by
there's program program you know he
wrote one time you know back then you
around 2005 or something he wrote you
know a spam filter
Pacey and you know that is one of those
chant joggins loved by these programmers
like like - like today's rust has cow
languages you know chant about it every
day
oh oh program created this Bayesian
filter you know you know anyway so tech
kickers the the way they fight spam is
by technology you know like spy versus
spy okay let me show let me show you spy
versus spy you know like if you you know
it's like in other words it's called
tech escalation you know you build a
bomb IP or the bigger bomb you know you
know so that you have spam and spam
spammers and the tech kickers you know
trying to fight the spam with tech you
know they you have spam farms you have
parts you have that then then the tech
kickers has spent theaters have kill
fire and you know in honey trap you know
they trying to find ideas okay this this
spam spy it's like like this you know
spy versus spy they think they obd each
other by technology so anyway so that's
the mindset of the tech kickers the the
tech you know UNIX philosophy buckets
but of course the so what so what
happens in the end of course the tech
geek are lost because they don't
understand reality spam or where it's
every day it's ten times hundred
speaker:today and in fact some of them
are part of Google part of Facebook book
you know spam more where and all that
very was you know the the Dallas Stars
attack and all that you know and they
and then today it's all controlled by a
few corporations you know they they have
you know anyway so so bye-bye 2010 new
scoop is filled of with with spam easy
to the point of unusable I mean I know
because I was using it so Emacs I was
you know you saw in this article I tell
I wrote about it you know 2010 Microsoft
declared that they are going not going
to use new scoop anymore this is 2010
for Microsoft okay and also you know so
I tell my story you know complain this
comp dot Emacs
you know I tell you what they are like
you know it's all spam ok spent [ __ ]
[ __ ] the take kickers [ __ ] that can
programmer nuts this okay so that is
about the death of new school ok and now
back to today's story now Google back
then in 2010
I mean 2001 we are so happy that Google
but you know Google about the didja
didja news you know Google is going to
make everything better
now the entirety of comp dot e max is
gun you cannot access it and maybe maybe
some of you are thinking oh that's just
a error you know maybe you know someone
can tell Google five cocoa fire bug
report guys you are open source coal
fire fire fire bug of report to Google
and you are thinking maybe Google will
correct it not not likely because Google
you see new scoop is already dead now
it's dead for ten years nobody uses new
scoop I mean they'll feel like
weird people even they maybe yet this
year use it but you see this these are
some of the new scoops are used often Oh
thought usage start English okay they
said then another one comp that land
that functional okay so apparently in
the function of programming group some
people are still posting poor Ruben
actually this guy recognized poor Ruben
I think he's a Emacs user I forgot
exactly what's you know so so Compton
thought land that lease you know these
are the use new scoops I use you see so
that's why it's in my favorite so you
can you can look at look at who is
posting now now this is spam okay you
can you can see by the way you see this
is this is spam after the filter after
the Google spam filter he showed up and
you can look at all the post are
basically by one person it was like that
even ten years ten years ago you see
every post is posted by robot Eric I can
he tilted his seal around oh my god
Kenny tilted Kenny Chilton is a old
Common Lisp code I would consider a
friend okay because he often supported
my opinions when when you know many of
the commonly Spurs are attacking me and
bar but pink of okay he's this this guy
bar bring cough he's a heavy Emacs user
his Emacs dev okay he's a Emacs
developer and he's I think I II my
opinion he's a great guy okay and he we
talked about a few times he showed me he
helped me
okay let me show you this machine
keyboards he he is a fan of history this
machine keyboards and pdp-10 machine
things like that so let me show you okay
so history let's go to cell keyboard
okay and actually let's go to PD there
it is stand the Stanford keyboard number
one zero nine nine by last spring cough
so he has article he has information
about the pdp-10 computer which is asian
computer and he's got photos you know
pdp-10 so very interesting you know he
he knows he knows stuff so we emailed a
few times but I think I also remember
him 10 years ago on his hoops so he and
also he is a Emacs death because in last
week he actually responded to some of my
Emacs spoke report that's that was for
fire ten years ago so he act act he took
them out and tried to you know walk on
them you know whether it's fixed or not
know fix you know things like that so he
so I think he's a great guy and I think
he's also actually I think he's done
quite a few things okay and did I get
his name right okay so for example let's
go to let's open a new buffer okay let's
go through : find this is my grave
script in Cola and basically I type his
name that's capitalized okay then I just
ran it such to all my website actually I
want to search to all my websites not
just that okay close cure process and do
it again okay let's wait for it to come
up it's searching 10,000
20,000 files so last spring cough so he
has done quite a few things so okay so
you see this these are some of the new
scoops come dot lan dot python you know
i haven't been using them for ten years
but you know some of the names I still
remember like I can write a who is who
of these new scoops you know the regular
characters like what they are like
what's their personality what they do
what's their you know and when you talk
about new scoop it's like drama all day
it's like just like just like in gaming
community came in communities or some
other programming college communities
elsewhere it's drama you know people
fight you know flame war originated from
new school okay the word the job and
fame war and you know things like that
all from new school so you know nobody
is using not many people are using news
group anymore so apparently it just
comped out Emacs is closed down
let's see another big Emacs new scoop is
no doubt Emacs start help let's have a
look who are posting now okay okay I
don't remember these people okay so we
were talking about new school big
history let's see how long I've been
talking so close these 42 minutes 20
people watching great say hi guys no
Google Talk you problem with our notice
Google kills product without notice yes
indeed yeah exactly the key word a lot
okay at least drop European on
repairability of hardware and how
important it is I don't know anything
about repairability of hardware like
what does I even mean I can guess you
know the bog the bog in Star Trek
they have repair repairable hardware in
fact their spaceships they have auto
repair automatically so if you shoot
their spaceship you know the bog cube
okay I need to show my websites
sorry Borg the book welcome to the bog
of Star Trek you will be a sim
assimilated resistance is futile
okay this is a bald spaceship and this
is the bog cream the bulk cream a
creature of fascination and and look the
moist glistening Sheen the softness of
organic carnality the tenderness of
maternal confidence a horror of sexual
irresistibility that is how they
depicted the pork cream making with mr.
data okay
and so so this is the bog you know the
book and so their ship you know they
have they have the greatest technology
they have auto repair and in fact our
science is you know the chemistry
material science actually we are it's I
mean in some sense that's possible we
have self repairing walls concrete you
know the scientists have you know you
you have seen news like that where you
know concrete house you know they you
know over the years because rain or
something they rot you know things like
that so but we have material such that I
don't know because of the chemistry
chemistry or something they say self
repair things
like that and also in software in our
industry in software we also have self
repair technology what is that get for
example let me show you a example self
repair let's say so let's go to diet
let's go to San talk-show let's go to
let's see what okay let's say this fire
ok this file so I so I open it so this
is March 8th ok 2019 March 8th ok I open
it I delete it
ok now refresh buffer you can see that
the fire is gone you know it's a it's a
backup now the actually that's DVD ok
delete now there is no longer ok this
part is done now there is no longer
March 8th ok now I need to repair it god
I lost now let's show the automatic
repair technology get check out do it
and the miraculous miraculously is back
right here
auto repair technology ok so oh my god
so we branch off so much fog auto repair
tech ok and the get ok
and that's copy that we talked about
that Star Trek ok close that space was a
spy okay let's talk we're me and it's
let's put that here ok actually I need
to show my website not other people's
website I need to show my website sorry
spice was a spy tech Akiko's vs.
spammers so this is the story of spy
versus spy look at he
you know you the white spy and the black
spy they are each they are trying to put
the other into the meat grinder that's I
was a spy and look at this one okay the
image is too small I need to get the
larger image that is the situation of
the tech nerds the hacker types you guys
okay the open source open source no
commercialism Ottoman stores everything
open source with some fire foundation
and we in the open source we need the
encryption we need distributed oh my god
we need to fight the spammers we need
that that's you guys
now we we know the end result after 30
years of it okay that's you know so I
wrote this article this is stated 2002
yeah yes early as 2002 that's you know
that's so did I mention program here
poor again not not here okay so so in
2006 addendum 2006 the worsening of
email spam okay that's nothing you know
today you have you have email spam
ization you don't even care about it
anymore
today you have far worse things going on
well so spy versus spy okay close that
now okay so this is yeah so this is loss
brink of guy
article about DP D the pdp-10 computer
it's a hardware I don't understand you
know but actually today you have
emulators so you can actually run it he
you know he showed me a little bit yeah
emulator so you can run that operating
system the t t PT PT p10 so supposedly
the C programming language is kind of
modeled
um on that machines hardware you know
the cease model of memory addresses
addresses things like that you know I
don't know see okay so I don't I cannot
give you any details so on this page is
this machine keyboards okay so beginning
this is the overview of the history of
lists machine keyboards where they came
from who created them things like that
and what year you know what do you how
they relate to a particular model of
list machine who makes list machines
things like that so you can see cell
keyboard actually I did a video about
this machine keyboards you might check
it out so in the beginning you have cell
cell keyboard then you have night
keyboard then you have the space-cadet
keyboard the most dramatic the most
popular today then you have symbolic
keyboard and so on okay so this machine
kibo and from these keyboards came the
Emacs key binding and the metal key okay
so you can see on the cells keyboard you
have the metal key beginning with the
cells keyboard meta you see that meta
and in fact you know today we have like
the window key we have the command key
we have control key web or key now
control key and and we also have Shift
key
all these are modifier keys meaning that
you have to hold it then you press
something then you release that key very
complicated okay but among these
modifier keys the shift key is the
earliest the granddaddy of all modifier
keys the shift key so why is it where
does it came from why should shift
because let's see let's go to keyboard
design because 200 years ago on a
mechanical keyboard you shift key
actually shifts the gears like you press
down the shift that kid over there you
press it down and
the gears the Levellers and stuff they
push all the columns to the left or to
the right you know it shifts the shift
gears shift like driving cars you have
to shift you know you hold it you so you
have to hold it
then the shifts then you can press
something they need it types capitulate
capital letters or something then you
release the shift that's how it works
but after 200 years computer keyboard
got invented ok the shift key ok after
200 years the computer keyboard came
around but people you don't need you
know you don't need to shift the gears
anymore but however the habit stuck you
know I want I need to have a shift key I
need to hold it down then press
something then release it because that's
my habit ok that's that is how the shift
key came jumped onto the computer
keyboard then as we were talking about
then so what about what is the history
of the others like the meta like the
meta control you know or you know or
today's window key each key has a
history ok control key came after the
shift control keys a second now I don't
know exactly what is a history from
teletype and unity I don't know exactly
what's the history but ok so so then you
have control key and what is control key
used not like today ok today you think
we think that control is for shortcuts
you know it's see you know if you don't
know history which is more vast majority
of people including programmers
including the hacker types they don't
know history ok but you can you can
spend a few hours to look into a history
of the these keys ok
even Wikipedia they don't have that much
detail they have a lot of detail I
learnt a lot from it but if you for
example if your question is what is a
history of a control key you go to
Wikipedia
it's it's spotty okay with respect to
that question what is the exact we
amended control key in the first place
it's spotty you have to go around
several key video articles then you have
to go through the links from it you know
then you know so anyway so control key
came second to shift now I don't know
exactly what's its history but basically
the it's a modifier just like shift Y
modifier because people are used to the
concept of modifiers like shifting gears
the way you hold it down first then you
press something then you release it very
idiotic it's you know in hints I in hand
side with respect to design that's
extreme idiotic the way that the
modifier works okay and it's also
extremely inefficient time consuming and
also hard to learn and also also it's a
repetitive strain injury inducing okay
never never press call keys now that's
another topic I have a lot of articles
about that but anyway you can try to
read my articles so in Emacs or in
Photoshop anyway try to never use key
combination the code you know like
modifier keys instead what you want is
key sequences you know like press
control release it okay don't you don't
need to hold it then press some other
key like today you have you can do that
with the shift key anyway I mean some of
you are building your own keyboards like
you know the you know so you can you can
do that you know you know what I'm
talking about right so don't use so
anyway back to the history of these
modifier keys so meta then you have so
okay so you have shift control but where
does lead for example on the Mac you
have the command key what is a history
of that on Windows you have the old key
where who invented like where does the
idea come you need an old key well what
does that come from okay
before we talk about that about those
the control key what what is control key
used nuts not shortcuts okay back then
you don't have shortcuts control key is
used to to send s key symbols okay okay
I haven't been reading comments he's
talking about the right to repair lie
can you fix your own stuff dingo
okay so ASCII characters let me tell you
about ASCII characters so here is the
table of ASCII characters you can see
the first you can see for example space
space is a invisible character then you
have the tab very popular in Python for
example the tab key that enters the you
know so you have the tab key which is a
key keyboard key then you have the tab
character which is a invisible character
now these characters are all part of
ASCII and you have Christ several other
invisible like so-called control
characters for example for example on
shell for example I can do LS right you
you know UNIX shell so okay so hold on a
second so let me move it here so you can
see yeah so you can do LS you know shell
LS dash L you know at least you know but
you can press ctrl T to exit it you know
can hold down ctrl T release then
release control you have must be in that
order but however that that is not a
shortcut okay
that's not a keyboard shortcut that
actually you are sending a signal to you
are actually sending this character let
me tell you ctrl T this one you see yo T
the ASCII character number for the name
of that character is end of transmission
you are actually so you are actually
typing that character and when the
terminal we see
gives that character that character then
it's it you know it means okay you are
turn with it you know exit so it's not
actually a shortcut you know you
actually send the signal across so
that's that's ASCII which is a critical
important history of programming and
also you have to know it well if you are
a programmer kind of when after two
years of programming you have to know
ASCII you know it's a good thing to know
ASCII well because stream they are all
related about bytes and asking about you
know these things okay so ASCII so that
is so that is the purpose the original
purpose okay I've been mixing around the
purpose of control key the history of
modifier keys began with shift actually
shifting gears okay then we have the
purpose of a control key then we have
then but okay so what the question is
what where does command key came from
where does Alt key came from well they
came from their granddaddy who got idea
it is this keyboard the cell keyboard
Stanford AI lab keyboard that created
this idea okay command key code key okay
the model basically modifiers okay that
that is our engine and also let me just
mention there's this guy who is very
much into keyboard he's a keyboard
historian you can that's the proper term
so he he is writing a book about
keyboards and typewriters so he's got a
Twitter you can follow him he is of a
German or engine this person
okay what okay so you and so okay so
let's go to Chrome because I don't have
JavaScript um so he is a German guy and
he write about he research a lot
keyboards he actually travel around to
go to museums or private collections
take photos because he is writing a book
about keyboards in history so he is a
great guy we have a huge amount of
things of interest in common okay
but however due to politics we don't
talk to each other anymore kind of like
that because he is kind of the social
justice type of people he hates Trump
for example
so because you know so he will see my
posts you know which is opposite of his
opinion and I will sometimes see the II
suppose you know about politics which i
think is you know evil so gradually we
don't talk to each other anymore but you
know I think he's a great guy politics
do that to people and the worst is when
civil war comes SIBO when civil when we
become so bad then you have civil war
that is when you stab your friends your
family you know you stab them and they
stop you and you have no choice it's not
like oh I don't want to do that if you
don't want to do that you die okay yeah
so that's about that guy so he's a
expert you know I don't know he's
writing a book on keyboards and you know
history I don't know what so current
status maybe it's already published so
we talked about space versus spy and so
we were talking about the keyboard
history of the keyboard the modifier
keys okay sales keyboard sale do I have
that link okay no copy back to Emacs and
post a link
okay somewhere later on after video I
have to you know reorganize make them in
order it's it takes hours like two hours
two to three hours to do it okay anyway
in this buffer we show the result of
searching for this guy
last spring cough okay now I call saw
find out put mud so that it's all
colored and you can jump around
occurrences and you can go to the file
and show in browser so a lot my articles
mentioned him because he has you know he
has helped me with some photos in stuff
so but besides keyboard he also does he
also has let's see if I can I was I
think okay oh these are about keyboards
you know who is a guy who created who
created use I might be confused him with
another guy so absurdly Emacs browser so
Emacs has a browser building called use
let's see
why is it not showing up my fate my page
there it is
oh go Emacs okay so Emacs has a browser
building actually I can view I can show
you for example in Emacs okay in Emacs I
MX eat of eww
enter you know they asked me to type a
URL so I typed this URL which is my own
website
this is how my website looks like in in
in Emacs this is Emacs everything is
written in Emacs Lisp this browser and
it it can also show images but it's not
really practical okay so hold on second
so let me paste that link so let's go
back to you so who wrote you the guy who
wrote you is okay so is this guy last
man named Ingebrigtsen okay that's
Norwegian or something Scandinavian name
I think so yeah both of them are named
laws so anyway so okay close that death
of new scoops we talked about death okay
close that close that close that
HTML markup function name what is this
about oh yeah this random articles on my
Emacs website how to learn Emacs it is
how to name your major mod okay so let
us let me take a break and let's see
read the comments
so I've been talking for one hour in six
minutes and that's okay that's about it
okay so actually today again we talked
about lots of things but there are some
things about some keyboards we didn't
talk we maybe will do next time okay so
for example let me show you I create
three we clear up this so that they are
now cream okay let me read the comments
so dingo says what are your thoughts on
this Blizzard Hong Kong drama have you
heard yeah I heard of it that's that's a
long topic to talk okay I it's it's it's
a lone topic it's a big topic and he's
also controversial because it's involves
politics it involves United States of
America it involves the meaning of
democracy you know basically I'm yeah
it's it's a difficult topic he's talking
about right to repay okay so no Google
cares okay any comments questions posted
now okay the list dropped your opinion
reliability okay
okay actually I don't I don't even see
comments no comments so good morning
idiot idiot
Addison way are you from what country so
Nybo now neighbor we what country are
you from again neighbor says actually
I'm learning a lot of Emax just by
watching you
if my expressions okay great it's on the
fly in the stream thinking of finances
okay so dingo says yeah about hong kong
that's a big topic i did a video about
my opinions of Hong Kong
basically the Hong Kong riot okay they
are in induced by USA you know USA has
this organization called CIA every year
they pay you know they pay rebels in all
countries around the world you know in
the Middle East in Hong Kong in China
and you know they pay they pay billions
literally billions and this is not all
conspiracy this is all open public
information on the website official
website itself this the organization
website that US government website
itself it's open public information day
they want to do that in the name of
democracy okay basically so USA has this
organization it used to be CIA but in
1970 so sometimes you know you know the
Congress you know they say oh this is
illegal you cannot you are not allowed
to do that
so in sewing so CIA created a new
organization called ng D okay let's
let's go through the official website
then it's on Wikipedia to you can you
know if you are interested ng D there it
is National Endowment for democracy in
the name of democracy okay so this
organization they take
taxpayers their tax dollars every year
billion literally billions I mean I I
have deep you know you can you know you
can spend time you know literally
billions of dollars every year from CIA
began with that in 1960s but anyway I
don't know when did this Oakes began 30
years ago every year you have few
billion dollars you distribute to around
the world who which country you put the
money to basically countries that that
we are benefit USA if their governments
become chaotic you know that's that's
the case now if there's a country a you
know a government if that country
doesn't matter they are the democratic
or not did this matter they are human
rights or whatever violation doesn't
matter if that country force it has no
benefit to USA for example some some
such countries in Africa no benefit to
us then this National Endowment for
democracy we are not give any money to
it okay so the the the democracy is just
the name it's a chant phrase it is kind
of lost meanings but anyway I know a lot
my friends American white people they
are like forward they are they are
forward they hear the word democracy old
and China is evil oh that country Middle
East Iraq I see both this is people that
evil they don't know nothing anyway so
this you have this organization that
pays speedy ins now when I say you know
when I say the number you did you know I
have to actually show you I rather not
okay because because then this becomes
very political I rather not you they
have at least every year you know you
can spend the time to look for if you
want to you'll find it they have at
least every day pay organizations like
for example in China they pay Tibet you
know they want to bet independence okay
they pay the Shanghai organized
organization for freedom okay for
whatever they then they pay Hong Kong
since see
1997 billion billion okay every year
they pay who they pay to they pay to any
organizations typically and also student
they train students okay
typically they pay anyone anybody
doesn't matter what to do as long as
they have the potential to [ __ ] the
government okay [ __ ] [ __ ] the country
[ __ ] the country up okay and it's Orton
in the name of democracy National
Endowment of democracy now if you are
white people you probably don't see what
I see because you know you don't you
don't care you know yeah you know it's
good for your country but but if you are
not why skiing then you see some problem
when when it comes to your country you
know maybe you came for I don't know
but since I have Chinese blood I see it
you know I see idea being USA for 30
years every news is about it's not it's
not fair okay it's not fair
news so this organization they pay money
to Hong Kong and and you know all the
Western media today it's happening you
know you have the French Yellow Jacket
riot it's been going on for a year now
for it ever month actually by today it's
most most a year already
violence you know they you know you see
it you you can see them if you go to
Twitter just type the hash hash tag
Yellow Jacket
okay you see tons of violent videos you
know the demonstrators thousands you
know fighting with the cops
but in US News you hear nothing about it
nothing zero why because it doesn't
benefit because the French government
are you know the friends okay friends
and also the rioters they complain
whatever they don't benefit you know
they don't you know so it's it's about
politics about benefits you know the
doesn't benefit us a you talk about
French Revolution doesn't benefit us a
so you don't hear news media nothing
because the rioters you know the the
French
I think poor lefty or something am I
wrong or something his name you know the
the day so he put more taxes on gone
gasps you know but meanwhile you know
much of Western countries are for the
green you know the green planet things
like that anyway so it's been going on
the violent you know burning cars
burning buildings breaking things Keo
and people oh yeah a few people dead few
people died of course then some people
got blinded by you know blind blinded
you know things like that but it's not
on a news no no way but Hong Kong same
kind of violence you know they you can
see our videos okay but it's news
everywhere if every major you know New
York Times is reported and they show
video and the story is basically oh my
god
China is so evil the the the evil empire
you know they are killing people they
are the Hong Kong the citizens they need
freedom but the China is like picking
them up and killing them and you know
and you see violent pictures of the cops
beating people but you all you have to
do is spend few minutes you go on
Twitter you spend few minutes and you
can watch all the viral and videos by
the by rioters okay they beat people
they beat citizens so a lot okay and
actually I am you know I'm posting you
know if you follow me on Twitter you can
see a lot of it so what can you do well
you know
okay so so Israel says what's better
than democracy well the point I know I
get that a lot
you know I get that that's you know a
lot so the the the the one way to look
at it okay one way to look at it is that
first of all it's just like open source
what first of all what is democracy for
what do you want democracy in the first
place what is your core I mean when we
want to do something some methodology
some philosophy or some criteria you
must have a core that these
methodologies are good for right so when
you say democracy you must have a co-op
typically the cause you want the people
the citizens to be happy right they they
must have freedom right they well
freedom is abstract they want comfort
okay I don't want to be beaten just
because I said the wrong opinion right
that's part of democracy right free
speech right free speech is not just a
chant phrase that means if I can say
something that's different I don't get
beaten I don't get kicked off kicked out
from Emax groups from the open source
community right that's what democracy is
for right so so what what if there's a
society that is not democracy but
however the people has all these course
new democracy wants better than your
democratic party what about that what
about that so I'm not a historian but I
I think it's fair to say if you look at
throughout history I had said this
before you know country's democracy is a
very recent jargon okay like within the
10th within the past hundred years
mostly spread by USA like you don't know
what it means anymore you just you know
obviously you know Iraq war so USA
started Iraq war 600,000 people dead
how many 600,000 you know that the
number can vary you could say oh it's
just actually not that many it's only
100,000 okay let's go with 100,000
civilians okay not counting soldiers
civilians you know 600,000 dead okay
went out hunt 100,000 okay how many you
know who do these people cry too wide
why did we why did we hit Iraq democracy
isn't that for democracy because the
Saddam Hussein is evil you know he could
torture people right yeah I think oh
yeah
dingo says I have to support Hong Kong
since China oppresses religious freedoms
no you you your brain stupid what you
don't know you don't know like did you
ever spend one hour not much 1 hour in
your life to actually dig information
like for example you go to a today's
with Western you know any in America
news you know China I saw evil spend one
hour not much just just one try to
research on the truth of the matter try
you start to find a different story now
if you keep doing that for one hour a
day in a month your opinion will be
changed the question is whether you are
willing to spend that one hour a day
what is a cause well originally is
because now if I talk about you know I
might be biased okay but you know you
listen listen you can check for your
truth yourself originally I try to be
fair okay because there is a Hong Kong
guy who went to Taiwan okay and raped a
girl or something raped a girl and
killed some someone or something like
that okay then then he went back to Hong
Kong okay so so but the the Hong Kong
law at the moment at the time you know
there is no no way to get the guy
because he something like that so that
that that is why it's about extradition
law okay so so so supposedly according
to Western media China wanted to have a
extradition law me
in that you know if you Hong Kong us you
know if someone did something really bad
then you know you can you can be sent to
China
okay and the door entrance because this
murderer you know he murdered someone
the girlfriend in Taiwan okay that's
that's our engine then well yeah I don't
know the details but but you know the
Western deserves anyway that that is
kind of the or engine okay in China
China is Pro is is no I'm not claiming
China is Pro Christian era T or Islam Oh
so of course I don't know okay I don't
know the details I mean we I don't know
I don't know what's the story about Pope
tried to point B shop in China okay I
don't know I think that's about it today
yeah Wow in 22 minutes
you know so I'm kind of unfortunate well
you can't you can say that I'm not you
know because well because that's my
that's my skin color you know I'm you
know so it's not but I'm also a US
citizen
you know I being my adult life is
spending u.s. you know I haven't been
I've never to China but you know I want
it to be fair you know so so if you look
at all the news media about China you
know it's just not it's not fair then
besides then you look at Iraq war Iraq
war and all the others it's just you
know USA is not we are not doing good
things okay that it that is a fact you
know today you have the turcica but
running for president president
presidential candidate to 2020 you know
she one of her main main thing is regime
change you know complaining about us
spent dis perience to do bad to other
things you know think about that
so does that mean does not does that
mean anything to you does that mean
anything to you
and no komoroske you know you must have
heard of that guy he's a he's the you
know where knowing programming because
of his komoroske hierarchy you know
language linguistics linguists you know
he's you know he created the komoroske
hierarchy okay which is related to
computer science and he is well no he's
actually almost the number one where non
quit criticize of us far in politics and
he has written books so here's our ago
okay komoroske hierarchy in a formal
languages of computer science and
linguistics the komoroske hierarchy is a
containment hierarchy of classes of
formal formal grammars okay so you can
actually see a picture you see that
picture regular language context
context-sensitive recursive innumerable
you know that's when you study passes
you learn about these things okay very
interesting very interesting and sick
and of great theoretical importance
especially in theoretical computer
science anyway so this guy is also the
way oh no it's almost the number one
creep criticize er of u.s. foreign
policy and he has wrote many books and
even today you can go to youtube you can
see his criticisms so if you actually
look at his you know study his books
he's writing you know the USA is the
greatest bully since let's say nineteen
fifty greatest bully you you you drop
other countries you do things you know
so do you guys are you guys do you not
know about this like do you have you
heard of it do you know have you guys
read none you know it's not he's just
only not the only one there's quite a
few ok of course the media don't report
it and as a US citizen we don't like to
talk about it because that's this that's
like are talking about bad things about
our own family you know we yeah you has
to do to pass things but it but but I
live happy I get more money you know you
don't talk about that much but so he has
written books so the equivalent you know
so do you guys know about this or you
haven't heard of it and if you know
about this if you have read books so the
other that then the other question is
you do you think he's lying you don't
believe it or you believe it I mean so
what's your take you know so I see some
of you you know up for USA so what did
what is your take about you know what
he's saying you think he's just a nut
job yeah and when we talk about you know
then you know then this you know Korean
War Vietnam War you know this is a lot
you know
Howard Zima exactly Howard Xing they
blame all both blame the US for all the
world's problems okay maybe maybe you
are right maybe yeah they did they are
actually in you know they could be
extreme but but I can you know I seen
since I'm Chinese I grew up in China you
know in Taiwan you know I was going to I
never been to China I can I can tell I
can tell how fail whether not fail us is
about when it comes to China it's just
it's totally out of question is unfair
why because it's simple to understand I
mean you don't have to take me because
I'm Chinese or biased oh you don't you
have to actually just think about in
general US you know Russia is the enemy
of USA so so you know you remember the
Cold War you fight Russia now who is
second to Russia China they are
communist us believe in capitalism
communist is a different you know
ideology so they are enemies so you USA
need ketchup Japan
to help get I want to help you know
whoever is the enemy of China you know
they they become US allies that's it's
that's politics this is simple politics
okay so that's it for today okay that's
it for today thank you guys for coming
90 minutes bye guys I'm gonna shut down
in 30 minutes
yeah I mean in one minute okay so I'm
done today
so today's drink is the black cherry
flavored energy drink and [ __ ] I don't I
don't have apple juice anymore so it's
gonna be tomato juice then
okay bye guys