hello everyone so I'm going to today I'm
going to show you I'm going to give you
a review of the Kinesis advantage to
keyboard now this is a fantastic
fantastic keyboard so the things I want
to show you okay okay maybe just show
you okay let's put the camera up so it's
like that it's it's like that it's super
light super light and study you can I
cannot pinned it right like I cannot
twist it this is the ergonomic keyboard
meaning that if you if you type on the
computer all day like eight hours a day
for four years so if you are writer
programmer then this is gonna be your
savior your Savior and this is gonna be
fantastic
so it's you know lets me do some typing
something water
once upon a time something and something
so so this is really good I have been
using this keyboard for almost two years
now since it came out this is advantage
to so let me show you from another angle
so like the normal you know desk angle
so I have my that's that's a keypad I
use it for programmer keypad and that's
a Logitech mouse so so let's see so this
is my like my desktop and I just put my
hands here the right hand and these are
the thumb keys so this is space space
inter control windows key page up page
down and you can see I have lots of
pictures on my website so you can just
search it sorry
keyboard and sorry such sorry
Canisius keyboard so in anyway so what
are the things I want to show you okay
what's the features whoops oh line me to
the back you can see my lousy camera so
anyway so you see these things are this
bath towel is folded they are my wrist
pads and and those are the best wrist
pads because most miss pads are too low
you need them to be high like Y like one
on the left and one right but I usually
when I'm not doing video these are like
over here so this is great comfort and
you can throw them you know wash them
every week or so and it's a lot cheaper
you know at our is just three dollars if
you buy a wrist pad that's like five
dollars in something and that you know
it's no good so anyway so okay so this
is special I mean this is for if you
really type a lot and this keyboard is
really for touch typist so if you do not
touch type that the normal way let me
put this if you do not touch type then
see then you know this may not be for
you well I have I have the paper here
okay
so yes sir so I have been using this for
almost two years now
but you said I'm a programmer and I am
also a heavy blogger so I write a lot
all right
everyday like typing and typing yeah so
if you do not touch type yeah then you
might want to learn oh you know this is
really designed for touch typist okay
how long does it get to use to this
actually I why my god this the first day
thanks to Kinesis they actually send me
one to review so I got it the first step
when it came out last year maybe two
years ago and and I was able to type it
like a pro the first day like I was able
to type first day no no mistakes well
because I have used one before auto
layout so let me show you what was so
what's the situation here so you see the
keys okay there are many curves right
but you can see one of the thing is that
the keys they are vertically aligned
like straight straight straight so so if
I put my fingers here you know it moves
up and down and up and down there's no
like normal keyboard they are not
straight they are like rented you know
in a weird way because that's the way
they are because in in 1800s
cold early nineteen hundreds the
mechanical typewriters they have to keep
the pass under it to be aligned like
equidistant anyway you so that's that's
why they are like that and we just you
know the scoot were stuck with the habit
yeah yeah so um the first day I was I
had no problem typing it but if you I
would say if you never use
a also orthogonal or grid layout before
then you might take you three weeks you
know if you type if you you know work
practice everyday like one hour you used
to use the keyboard hello he'll take you
maybe three weeks to get really good
without any mistakes but for me the
first layer I was taking out hi fine
so thumb keys why doesn't keys because
you know money like for example
backspace backspace normally
kibo is like here like you type enter
then backspace like it's you either use
your pinky or you like turn your wrist
to backspace that's that's not good so
on this keyboard the backspace is here
backspace you know like something and oh
I made a mistake TV yeah hold it TD so
in space is here enter is here you know
enter okay so one more thing about I'm
I'm a seein you know some so my my hands
are not well
standard kind of normal Asian sized
hands I don't know if you can see a
reference so or something but at least
I'm not the basketball stars you know
the most those guys got super sized
hands so so for me the thumb please this
key size is comfortable but but even
even those require some reach and that
so so you see these keys are absolutely
good and this requires actually a kind
of move you know the site and the other
keys or needs likes like stretch stretch
stretch so I would I would recommend
that that you know if you use this
keyboard you know you you don't you
don't stretch your
to do those keys that's not good you
want to like move your hand instead like
you know don't treat these keys as
something like you just like do it well
unless you have you know your hand is
big like you know your hand is naturally
sits here and you know okay so so that's
I think that's what I want to say about
this keyboard this video review I have
reviews on my website so there's lots of
you know written details on exactly have
this thing that's funny at first that's
a that's a phone like a phone jack home
plug that's for the foot pedal pedal
they also sell Kinesis foot pedal okay I
don't have it I don't use it because I
don't I usually I usually see sit with
my legs on the chair so I don't use foot
pedal but I could you know be nice so
anyway so it's super light and is it's
very well well built and this program
programmable functions like you can you
can swap control or control command or
Windows key to any key you want you know
all you have to do is just press this
and hold that then then type the keys
you want to change and type the other
key that you want it to be then then
press that again then there will be the
you know so you don't even need to like
your own gaming keyboards you have to
start the driver and you know do that
you don't have to do that you just also
you can record markers so okay so so
that would that's it for this video
review of the Kinesis a bandit advantage
- okay you need to see this this way
Kinesis advantage to keyboard I have the
model cutie I think yeah all the models
are the same my mother just means that
the keys are dual Abel
DQ I think I do labels so so nobody you
know you have let's see left hand he is
here asdf you know that's the normal
quality qw u rdy but beneath the key you
can see AO e u that's the borax so do a
label but any model have both qwerty and
boric building and you can switch them
you know to quote you they are just by
pressing one of these small function
keys those are mechanical keys by the
way these are mechanical keys okay
that's it for this review thank you for
watching