hello guys welcome to another episode of
talk show yay I'm alive
so obviously and actually I did another
one today earlier but it didn't didn't
come out I did it for 20 minutes so
there are people asking me when is my
schedule for livestream I don't have a
fan hijack I don't have a plan for where
I'm where I'm going to schedule because
usually if I do plan if I have a master
plan then you know usually it doesn't
work out but because I get you know I
get nervous when there's expectation and
and you know but I'm getting better
because I have been doing videos for
half a year now so I'm improving my
articulation I'm improving my topics and
I am improving lots of things and I'm
also learning you know the video
streaming technology and stuff the OBS
how to set up to YouTube and stuff like
today earlier today I just did 20
minutes and I think it's funny I was
smoking and and I did some music and
stuff that's very different but too bad
that it wasn't being broadcasted you
know why because I got the key wrong
anyway when you do a video YouTube
streaming or other streaming I suppose
you need a key and you need to put a key
on the your streaming software but I
think it actually it changes like you
know now in know and then I don't know
how how often hijack so do you guys have
do you have a question
so I'm going to talk about stuff and I'm
not sure what to talk about you know
it's best it's best when people are here
and ask me questions
okay let's go to my email hey max blog
so well yeah I was talking about smoking
audio today because I'm going to you
know I am going to quit smoking I
started smoking like six years ago okay
random talk KJ
okay hey hey guys hey Richie what's up
so have you been on my my son talk show
before
well the the format here is you guys
just ask any questions and I answer it
can be technical questions and it can be
other things by the way Jack do you
smoke you know smoking is a stigma you
know in USA in in the rich you know the
countries white people's countries like
New York and San and California you know
it wasn't always so but it has became
progressively so since you know in the
1990s you know you then suddenly
sometimes in the 1990s then you cannot
smoke in restaurant which is kind of
okay you cannot suit you know smoking in
restaurant and then you have a special
you know you have a special place in
restaurant you can smoke then that is
good you cannot smoke in restaurant all
then they banned smoking in bars that's
you know it's kind of funny like you
know you go to bars and you cannot smoke
what you know stupid thing that is then
is just getting progressively bad
however you know the you know the
politics so it's leftist you know the
Liberals you know I have always been
actually somewhat of a liberal and more
of a libertarian but today the politics
has
turned around completely but in general
you know in general the Liberals you
know they they don't want you to smoke
they you know they don't like cigarettes
however they like you know magic wanna
magic wanna smoke in California Indian
casino oh you can do that oh yeah I
think so
wait yo oh yeah you are you are in San
Jose right
hey cool we should meet up sometimes oh
wow man sometimes no money
oh yeah sometimes a pack a week jack a
pack a week oh that's not too much but
you are in China I mean you are a young
guy so anyway my I never smoked before
you know and I don't like it you know
okay so when I was like 17
Oh palm stream at home streams palm
streams is in way said near Los Angeles
hey web dog you are learning Borak great
that's fantastic
so I mean let me talk about smoking so
you know when I was like 17 know
something 16 in Montreal Canada and I
was a rebel kind of rebel so I smoked
and I was smoking you know for like half
you know a year maybe
you know for a year but then I you know
after that I never smoked and tio and
here maybe six years ago when I was 45
you know why you know two hours east
okay so you know because life is getting
bad you know life when when life is
going down you know I was you know I was
going to be a mathematician and a
millionaire you know that didn't happen
you know and I become so poor in life
life's bad
so I start to smoke you know how people
they cut themselves you know this
typically females you know like some
sometimes you can see on an int internet
like they they like to cut themselves so
my smoking is like kind of like that you
know it says it's a gradual you know
it's a self-destruction and gradually
but anyway in the past a month or so
I've been smoking too much
so anyway two years ago I quit like
completely code Turkey I quit you know I
don't think it's a problem for me to
quit me smoking it's it's it I don't
think I really have a physical or you
know biological addiction but rather
it's more of a psychological addict
addiction
so what topic is what we're going to
talk about today so so you are running
back so yeah Borak is great you know um
I'm not sure what I'm gonna talk about
but I think I want I'm going to smoke on
camera why not
okay let's do that oh why smoke I need
music I need to dance pop and stuff and
chicks and stuff
all right seven people are watching so
you know guys keep the comments coming
okay if you want me to talk about
technical subjects say so you know like
everything I do is dependent on your
comments like my life dependent depends
on your comments okay let me get my
lighter so you know for the past month
I've been smoking too much because like
to one pack every two days and and and
it's not good because you know you creep
ketucky oh well
seven to twenty two years old how old
are you now where are you located
we've dog so you see this is around the
core dude
25 times 25 great
oh my god you don't know how I wish to
be 25 so I'm going to quit actually I
was planning to smoke on screen and
because then that's a good way for me to
quit cigarette because I'm going to use
this thing vape you know these young
people started to do this vape thing I
think it's great because when I first
tried this it's so elegant because it's
all electronics you know it's all
electronic because I'm a I'm a geek
right you know I'm a nerd I'm a
programmer I'm into computer science and
machine why all the visual intelligence
or that and so comparatively you know
and I'm into efficiency you know
comparative well this well actually did
this a lot of traction about the good
old secret as well because you know what
it's fire you got fire here primitive
you got fire here very primitive and you
know sometimes you get tired of
technology you know the computers and
and and and and stuff so it's very basic
it's the primitive the the essential the
essence of human needs but on the other
hand this is really elegant because the
secret you gotta smell and if you are a
smoker okay you know you know maybe not
don't you know don't say the swear words
because scoobo is going to pammi you
know because
so if you have a question ask me you
know so I'm talking I was saying this is
attractive but because it's primitive
because high but when I supposed to use
this this is so elegant because when you
smoke a cigarette good ol cigarette it's
you know it's burning stuff and the
burning actually the damage to your
health is mostly due to burning it burns
and it creates some chemicals and this
electronic thing this way actually as
far as I've read it actually is harmless
I mean well you know I'm not you know
I'm not gonna talk about the regressive
liberals in California and New York New
York's people they of course they don't
they don't like it you know they think
oh this is another drug to the young
kids it's a [ __ ] now I'm gonna talk
about so anyway while I was smoking this
this is so elegant I'm if you haven't
seen it you know if you guys haven't see
it but you you guys probably have seen
you know the young people over over
and some of them below lots of smoke
like huge like you can see on YouTube
and they blow like all kind of colors
and rings and it looks like they have a
competition of that as well
and the this thing has progressed so
much that this thing has progressed so
much that they have you know it's you
know it's liquid Nick nicotine you know
they put nicotine as big quit and when
you when you suck on it it turns you
turns on there's a mechanism that turns
on and there's a battery inside the
battery burns the liquid so the liquid
evaporates that's how it works but this
thing is is like it's smell less I mean
there's no smell I mean although you can
see the smoke but it's actually vapor so
like if you are not a smoker you don't
smell a thing but with this cigarette
you know it it burns and if you are a
smoker people can smell people people
know far away from you from non-smokers
yeah babies baby better more longevity
but still it addictive yeah I guess
yeah because nicotine is addictive but
you know if we are going to talk about
the harmful effects you know there is
there's alcohol there is weed you know
people are doing that you know overs you
know I especially the fake libros you
know I you know so I never smoked
because you know since like 17 I never
smoked and and I don't like to smoke
because I am the I'm a super human I
mean I'm a Superman you know I'm going
to be the greatest mathematician and
also the greatest athlete you know doing
exports and all that you know and
everything so smoking I don't go for
smoking you know it's it doesn't do much
to me I mean some people I don't I don't
drink
and actually I don't smoke anything else
I don't I haven't haven't used drugs
except you know the except the weed you
know the marshal wanna and you know
maybe once every 20 years I've tried it
you know from from friends we are
smoking you know I mean smoking too much
and it's it doesn't really do me much
I'm doing it because it's a
self-destruction
it's a you know it's like those cutting
themselves so it's a it's purely of that
aspect I I kind of enjoyed smoking
yeah San Francisco the San Francisco
people the elite you know I came to
really hate them this especially not in
the past two years this is what's so
called you know regressive you know it
used to be progressive Richie wait
Richie to use do you vape tweed that's a
biggest press yeah you know the weed
I've tried it about like three years ago
I have a neighbor gave it to me
apparently some pure stuff you know I
haven't I have no idea what you know you
know the the the you know I'm you know
like not I'm not mad it's not my
lifestyle so I don't know nothing about
it but anyway he he gave me smoke i was
i was stoned
you know things yes things are literally
swaying I mean really and I became very
paranoid you know I become I was
thinking you know he's plotting on me
where I was stoned I went to Wikipedia I
tried to read the effects of the magic
wanna because I was for sure you know I
was certain that night that he is
you know he's plotting you know
something on me
yeah that's pretty wild but you know in
general I don't you know I don't like I
want my mind to be like always shop you
know it's general it's not my lifestyle
you see because actually my life style
is like I'm as ascetic okay let me
finish this one and our type and show
you I hope I spelled that correctly you
know one of one of a friend a white guy
one time he's a philosopher you know he
told me you know he says you know you
are ascetic and I didn't realize and I
see oh well yeah yeah actually that's
true
hey break the loop where did it go wrong
for you in your plan to become a
millionaire I never mentioned that you
know that went wrong Longwell million
aired you know when I was younger like
18 you know 17 when I was a teen I was
very ambitious ambitious due to my dad
you know my dad is kind of you know my
family is quite [ __ ] you know it's
it's a problem family my dad was my mom
and we married and they they have
physical violence in my my dad is a this
is back in Taiwan I was going to one by
the way where did you grow up in USA
were you born in USA Oh in in China's
some Oh somewhere so yeah so my family
it's pretty bad my dad dad is you can
you know in abusive you know in actually
America you know the America their
mentality is all [ __ ] up it was you
know it's it's [ __ ] up in the 90s when
a conservative are like ruling
everything and now it's
far worse since the past few years
because of the regressive liberals the
the social justice can you know I you
know they but anyway in California the
mentality you know it became so
protective you know Oh child abuse like
you cannot believe your child in a car
and you cannot leave dog in your car and
things like that you know by by by this
standard by this California standard
then basically everyone in China or
everyone in Taiwan is a criminal that's
true you know actually you know when
when at my era you know when I was a
child you know beating beating your kid
is like it's it's the right thing it's a
common it's normal it's you know
everyone does that everyone you know
majority of family and but anyway my
family is quite [ __ ] it's a special
case you know it's it's something you
know I you know it's not something you
know I want to talk about and but anyway
so I was ambitious and I wanted to but
anyway when I was young guy you know I
was you know the person you know
personality changes and things change I
mean it's it's not in a well it's just
for me I mean there's different people
different environment things happened
you know actually you know one thing I
noticed is that things change you know
that's actually true for a lot people I
mean not necessarily personality but
fortune and stuff you know you it
happens to let's say significant
percentage of population the fortunes
like son like many people you can become
so rich you know doing some period in
your lifetime and then you know then you
become like homeless at one point you
are the king of the world
literal literally you know you know
during Cultural Revolution or doing
other you know chaos you know
you know sometimes your French
Revolution you know one day you are the
king the next day you are you know
beheaded but that's I mean besides that
you know it also happens in everyday
life you can see people like I've got a
roommate you know he supposedly you know
he's like 60 something near 70 70 you
know supposedly he was very rich before
anyway the topic went yeah you know I
did so also you were born in South South
Korea okay great
they moved to Seattle when I was two
years old oh great then grew up in Los
Angeles cool
so anyway what are we talking about I
feel like having another cigarette then
you know but my plan you know I was
planning to like go on smoking online
here you know so I can quit you know
because as some kind of token you know
oh my god I'm smoking a lot but anyway
the California is the white people well
it is true the white people you know you
know in general they well you know what
I mean I mean the social justice scanned
those type of those people anyway that
you know the California is like that in
a text industries in general we shunned
from some smoking right you know this
rich wealthy people they tell people not
to smoke but you know and also two years
ago the California taxes so before a
pack of cigarette is like six dollars in
California I mean wow
I don't know in Los Angeles but in near
San Francisco in Mountain View here it's
six six dollars but two years ago or
have one year and a half ago
it becames like $1 and the the reason
you know they think you know they vote
for that way because they think oh so
it's more expensive so less people will
smoke but actually that's not true
you know the III was washing dishes
restaurant you know because you know as
I was watching dishes
and when you watch dishes you know when
you are a programmer you you never you
know all these programmers you know
[ __ ]
you never be in contact with the actual
blue label poor people but then you know
because you know many of those people
are not they are not some of them are
not even literate so anyway I went to
wash dishes so I met you know I know
their lives you know I met many of them
in fact all my roommates are you know
working in a restaurant you know when
you go to a Chinese restaurant you know
you see you know sometimes you go to the
back side you see the cooks you know
squatting over there smoking that's what
they are you know they are in many
chemists you know in many cases they are
illiterate I mean they don't speak
English okay they well they speak or
maybe some you know depends on you know
the people but in general they days days
they do not speak much English but more
so actually they are actually illiterate
they don't they don't read Chinese I
mean not in not absolutely but you know
a lot of them so anyway my roommates you
know they are they are you know they are
blue collars so that's you know they are
those you see when you go to a Chinese
restaurant you go to the back and you
see them squatting over there you know
that's how they are like and what what
was I going to say
oh yeah so I was going to say you know
they smoke you know they usually smoke
you know it's those people when you
increase you know money on on cigarette
it's those people you hit you know they
are not going to quit they are not going
to quit it's their life you know they
you know they are not like you you know
seeing the office you know talking about
you know go to Starbucks and have a sip
talking about the word politics oh this
is bad or that is good you know so
that's the situation and me too you know
I make like right now right now I make
$1,000 a month my rent here is
mm $2,200 a month and you know I don't
have money but but anyway so yeah so I
want to quit cigarette you know you know
this also the other thing is you know in
California it's a stigma so you don't
talk about it right I don't want to talk
about it you know I wasn't you know
talking about it because for example for
for one reason you know people say oh
look at that guy he's supposed to be
poor but he is smoking yeah yeah yeah
yeah yeah hey Daniel
lang Louise I smell cigarette for 15
years not too healthy that's true
yeah so let's talk about cigarette at
this another thing I want to say you
know the thing is you see the thing is
when you are doing find everything you
can look at things clearly and and you
can choose you know whether you want to
smoke or not and maybe you got money and
you smoke weeds you know you know or the
Hollywood stars they do drugs and you
know it's it's their leisure leisure
activity but for the poor people it's
not disha activity it's like their life
is so bad they'd like their smoke
smoking is their way you know their way
out of you know to ease the pain but
yeah what what was I saying yeah so
there's something I want to say I forgot
yeah so smoking is a stigma in this
liberal you know California and New York
you know I didn't know anything about
New York before because I never been
there but since 2016 you know the Trump
since Trump's you know since the Trump
you know elected since the mess you know
the social justice thing
Rose so I read a lot I spent like 30min
hung average you know statistically on
average I'm I spent maybe one
day and reading about all these you know
eruptions of you know angry social stuff
and I learned the New Yorkers are pretty
bad I don't want to be their fake oh
yeah my roommate smoke you know my um
both of my roommates okay it's like I
live with one two three four four
roommates you know and three of them are
male they are husband wife husband and
wife but anyway so they accept the young
youngest one who doesn't smoke but both
the other others smoke they work in
restaurant I am a very experienced
programmer thank you well not really
actually you know there's a difference
you know because I what I do like you've
seen on my website and you know I know
you know it looks like I know the
language languages it is true but
actually in terms of actually writing
software I'm not that good okay writing
software you know yeah because you know
I because you know I write you know for
the like all the you know the past ten
years
you know I study programming language
but languages which is completely
different thing from practitioner in
programming well I'm not saying one of
them is better okay but what I'm saying
is that if you are let's say average
programmer you work at some companies
you know even that Google you know
whatever
what do you do every day is code right
but but in general you don't match up
you don't actually know the programming
language in detail you don't you don't
like you like it's safe to say you know
if you you know anyone coded you know
JavaScript for five years you I asked
them a question they can answer you know
JavaScript they
and actually especially javascript
because javascript the syntax and
semantics is quite [ __ ] up it's very
complex
so in fact their code actually is just
wrong you know even a loop like often
you know it's just wrong but you know it
works then you got a team you know
testing team then you got you know you
know butts week fixing teaming you know
so life goes on so so you know so that's
a situation you know the average
programmers especially JavaScript you
know they they just write wrong the code
is just wrong and and also average
programmer let's say you know good
programmers you know let's say
above-average you know companies those
good ones you know let's say you know
the top 30% of the good programmers in
companies they so they are good and and
every day they just code you know they
can quickly
you know the key when you're working on
company typically what you want is
quickly just churn out code that that
reasonably you know does the job
you know satisfy whatever you know the
job and they you know they are good you
know and you know but still they are not
it's different from you know studying
your research on language or technology
or like when you're working in company
you they are they are like a thousand
things you know protocols and you know
spec for the course languages several
languages you know share whatever you
can't know them like you can't like most
of them actually most of the time most
of them are just new to new to you you
just have to do it you just have to you
know you maybe try to read some tutorial
and as soon as you know a little you
just coded in and and that's done you
passed you pass it on and you don't have
the mentality you don't have the need or
mentality to study anything in detail
and you don't have time because you got
this project and you you know put push
it out
and you got other things to do you know
you gotta you got meetings and so on and
you know maybe you know for some of them
you know maybe when you are off work you
know you try to study a little bit you
know maybe your github you know try to
write write your own program but in
general they you know it's not what they
do you know you are tired you're tired
of it you you wanna you know you you
watch TV or something on the other hand
you know like what the the things I
turned out to do you know like you know
study many languages design issues in
detail that's quite different so so I'm
going to smoke this oh wow I got 17
people watching that's the most number
of people watching is it is it because
I'm smoking so yeah so let's see what
conversation is going so I'm just gonna
keep smoking I'm gonna smoke myself to
death what a fascinating concept yes
in New York City's almost 20 dollars a
pack yeah I heard that
okay Ritchie says yeah one of my jobs in
the next two one always see them smoking
out back the mom boss is always ripping
someone a new one on the phone what job
are you are you a programmer
web dog says how am I making 1k in
Mountain View because I don't walk
basically that's that's why because I'm
not actually walking I haven't been
walking for like ten plus years so I
live a life well I'm a ascetic ascetic
you know that's what Oh sometimes I
think you know the right word to
describe it is a monk but not a typical
monk you see in shouting or whatever you
know you know but I'm a digital monk so
in other words my lifestyle is kind of
like a monk you leave a very basic
minimum life no pleasure and actually
the insome that kind that's that is you
know not just because partly because I'm
poor and I become that way but also
partly it's actually my personality
because I ascetic yeah Phyllis
philosophically you know they are like
when you read history there are many
people who are like that you know some
of the meaning is some famous people
like Gandhi you know that's that's a guy
everyone knows you know the Indian and
also sunshine some change the Chinese
what they call the Chinese father of
modern China there and there are others
you know they they live a Spartan you
know what what you call so basically no
pleasured and you know no fascia and
somehow that that somehow I'm like that
you know but I do that not for any you
know I'm not religious so some people
don't eat you know eat meat some people
don't drink wine because you know
religious reasons some people don't do
this or that because region that I am
NOT you know I eat meat any meat I eat
anything you know I and I enjoy you know
going to the restaurant you know I if
you give me some food I enjoy it but
however I do not
be quiet you know like like typically I
can eat I yeah and also my dark tired is
tends to be scientific so I'm basically
like you know you know the book the book
race in Star Trek or mr. data that's
kind of you know I always looked at the
book as the perfection of course in Star
Trek they they picture them as very ugly
and nasty and you know a you know a
threat to humanity but but however the
attraction about a book is not they
being ugly old or that kind of thing the
attraction of the book in Star Trek is
that they are these they are the kind of
people you know or race you know the
kind of people who focus purely on
function you know that the concept you
know functionality you know they say
there's a function in form right so the
book race is purely functional function
you concept you concentrate on function
alone and that's that's kind of my a lot
a lot my of my preferences
if we get basic income that's what I'm
gonna do it yeah but how you get basic
income I don't think you know that's I
don't think it will happen well and if
if if it happened the word is gonna be
chaotic it's like a power struggle so
okay let me read back some of the
comments let's see
no JAMA I hate it what's the worst
programming job you've had what is the
worst programming job I've had well the
other video I talked about it my
programming experience I don't I don't
remember if you are here or not so so
essentially I don't have much
programming job experience you know
except except back in about 1998 to 2002
so watch watch Andrew Young on Joe Rogan
youngin Oh what is that about Andrew
Young no I haven't I don't know who that
is
I'll check it out small business owner
janitorial oh great you know business
owner is is always great hi yujeong son
son he's all right you are you from
China
are you from China USA you know whenever
I see Chinese name I usually ask them
that because you know because people you
know Chinese people in China and Chinese
people in USA are very different
well it's but the Chinese people who
grew up in China and the Chinese people
who grew up in USA they are entirely
different you know the Chinese American
born Chinese is basically America you
know they are thought everything is just
you know it's almost indistinguishable
from white people so high so what city
what city in China oh yeah data is also
an interesting character you know I was
talking about that the other day the
schizoid
so my personality my personality is
schizoid now you can look up Wikipedia
about schizoid you know the full title
is schizoid personality disorder now
what that is is basically the
personality of loners now I'm going to
say you know I have a lot to say about
mr. data
you know mr. data is a kind of a
embodiment of schizoid personality
it's basically okay schizoid personality
is a personality without emotions okay
in real life I'm a schizoid you know I'm
a schizoid but I'm a mild one so I I do
have emotions of course but anyway the
schizoid type of people okay let me let
me tell you what it is it's basically
personality of loners people who like
prefer to be alone to do everything
alone by themselves and I'm kind of like
that and of course they are typically
introvert but usually you can you cannot
tell because in every other way they are
no more I mean like a like a schizoid
like right like I am you know I can if I
don't want you to know you wouldn't know
because you know like life is like like
I have full control of my emotions you
know you know so you know if you read
Wikipedia you know you get a lot of
information and they are a lot famous
people who are also schizoid you know
they can also be actors so they can give
a talk you know they can be a great
presenter but schizoid personality is a
personality that they just they do not
appreciate it they do not want they do
not value the person interpersonal
relationship and okay I'm gonna answer
the questions but let me finish about
ASCII soso skis or personality you know
you know go go read Wikipedia sometimes
let me finish the smoke and now type in
the out go to Wikipedia and I'll show
you
so ski so personality it's a personality
of loners and they and there are many
degrees of it as well you know if you
are you know each other
each of us have different personality
but if your personality is to such an
extreme degree that you are unable to
work in society function in society such
as getting married you know or find a
job or keep a you know long-term job
things like that or relationships then
they call it a personality disorder
you know they then they add the disorder
would to it you know that's a psychology
psychiatrists they that's their tongue
so anyway skis or personality is a
people who are you know loners and they
like they prefer to do things by
themselves they don't you know they
don't typically they don't make friends
like me you know I don't make friends
you know it's not because I don't want
to it's not it's not like you know you
know and you know it's not not it's it's
just naturally I don't I don't you know
you don't want to it's a personality
like same person I like you know some
people are in extrovert or whatever it's
just it's just a preference so you don't
make friends you end up not making
friends you know you like you don't you
don't make you know you can ski so
personality you can work in a
professional environment you can you
know workers or program or whatever jobs
you know you can I think you can you I
think there are even politicians who are
schizoid but where because to be a
politician you need to be social
typically the people who who who enjoy
social interactions or manipulating
other people they kind of thrive in in
the field of politics but schizoid you
know you don't so whatever yeah so
anyway schizoid so another thing about
schizoid is like you don't have much
emotion so you don't you know you don't
emotions it's not your thing which which
applies to me very much like when I see
you know let's say some accident happens
you know online some agree to us some
bad things happens you know and then
most people oh you know we're gonna pray
oh oh we you know we give them lit up
candles most people you know majority of
people they are like that old you know
they they feel they need to then then
often you know many of them may act
emotionally which is creates damage to
the whole society then you know they
become angry or whatever you know but
if you are a schizoid personality you
don't you don't feel the emotion you
like mr. data okay you don't you don't
feel it okay yeah I know this is bad I
know many people died I know and you
know okay and we try to solve it you
know so what can we do to you know solve
the problem you know to prevent that
from happening you know you know so so
you so it's like mr. data okay so when
you see things you don't you you don't
get you know emotions did you have like
full control of your emotions you don't
get you know the it's not like you are
helpless you know most people are
helpless to emotions it's it's
interesting because human humans are not
like machines you know if like a machine
you can say whatever to the machine the
machine is just just machine they don't
hear you I mean even if it has you know
some detectors it it doesn't do nothing
to the machine but for humans you can
say 13 certain things and and you you
can damage collapse the person you know
so that's you know what in large-scale
that's psychological warfare you know
you and also okay between persons you
can say something to your partner you
know your wife or girlfriend or your
husband you know you say hurtful things
and the other person combos you know but
if you look at the whole thing from a
physical point of view it's just a bunch
of sound waves and you destroy the
person that's true
you know you could say something put
someone so bad you know and they you
know but typically that's so schizoid
or not not like that you you know you
you know you like you can say anything
to me
I just perceive it I perceive it and I
react a code accordingly by logic you
know so in Star Trek there are several
interesting characters that's kind of
like attractive especially to nerds so
not so programmers tends to be like that
as well so no it's you know they are I
would say
more proportionally higher percentage of
schizoid among the programmers or
mathematicians you know many and also
many mathematicians they are they are
kind of you know like you imagine mad
scientists you know they are kind of
like that as well like hotel you know
the the Geico tell who who had a gödel's
incompleteness theorem so he sees like
that so anyway so back to the Star
Trek's key so it's so schizoid you know
it's a character without emotions but
and and often they also are sexual like
you know not me though very much into
girls oh my god anyway schizoid okay so
a lot of they a lot of them are sexual
so like anyway one of their
characteristics is that they don't have
emotion or they they they they have like
good control of their emotion you know
it's I mean all this is just natural
okay it's not like I want to be you know
I want to pretend to you know be someone
or something it's not like that and in
fact it's a situation that if I try you
know I really tried to make friends you
know establish relations I can't you
know because like packing when I was in
college you know if we have college I
went to a flea Hill Community College
you know I joined the swimming team you
know swimming team um so I joined the
swim team partly because you know I
think you know I so I can you know talk
to people more you know you have contact
with more people but it doesn't change
your thing you know I still don't don't
make friends you know it doesn't change
you know so anyway the skis away ok it's
the cause of the schizoid
it's anyway let's not get into that
basically this we don't know you know
there's no and and also all these
so-called personality disorders it's
it's kind of it's not really a disorder
and here
you really cannot function in society
then dance this good order for me you
could say I'm a normal you know it
depends on your point of view you know
if you look at me as someone very poor
and don't haven't been walking for ten
years then you know you might say yeah
you got a problem you know but here I'm
no more I can talk about things anyway
so back to the Star Trek so many of the
characters like the Vulcans you know the
Vulcan guy peace and prosper you know
and mr. data so they are kind of the
incarnation of the idea kind of like the
schizoid but what I want to say is that
you know a lot nerds or programmers so
you guys out there you know you look at
data and you wish you know I want to be
data you don't you don't want to be that
data because when you when you don't
have emotions like me okay I know it
because I am ski so when you don't have
emotions and you are in a social
situation a lot of things happen a lot
of things happened and not good for you
part not positive for you for example
well in Star Trek you know first of all
Star Trek is a show right whatever they
do they have to make you you have to
like it if you don't like it you don't
watch it they don't have a show anymore
so whatever whatever they do even
interesting ideas like mr. data or spark
or Romulans or whatever they have to
your audience you know they have to make
it so that it appears a appeal to you
you know you know so so they cannot go
pure you know they cannot go Jaco
you know on the other hand there's a
Jaco science you know I mean Jaco sci-fi
right you know Star Trek is not the hoc
or sci-fi you know how cool sci-fi is
more like more reality based science
fiction it's still science fiction but
it's kind of more dry while on the other
hand on Star Trek you have aliens you
have you know wars you know you
laser so you know topitos you know so
anyway Star Trek so mr. data and in
Spock so mr. data
so yeah the mr. data character you know
they try to show they try to portray to
you that okay we have this character
with which is without emotion and who is
trying to learn emotion and sometimes
you know some episode they'll make them
you know they will make it come out the
problem of no emotion like for example
there's someone will make a joke you
know counselor troi or whatever you know
counselor Troi and you know they make a
joke everyone is laughing but mr. the
data is like is that what human cause a
joke you know so it is trying to convey
to you the idea you know so you have
this this this and Roy who don't
understand emotion and and oh yeah it's
funny because you don't understand joke
in reality if you are really schizoid
like mr. data it's not gonna it's not
fun you know people when everyone is
laughing you are not laughing something
is wrong with with you you know they
they you know you know so in general the
person you know the seesaw is perceived
by others as as aloof and cold
emotionless you know aloof and cold and
you know remote so so I get that of
course you know people think I'm you
know roof and also because of so I'm
also asserted as ascetic you know as I
said before so I don't you know it's
it's almost like I don't it's almost
like you know like I avoid fresher you
know like intentionally and and you know
and a lot of people that happens to me a
lot you know online or elsewhere people
start to like when they interact with me
they start to go formal like like you
know they you know they become formal I
cannot blame them you know actually
that's not what I want I mean you know I
want you to be whatever you are I enjoy
that the more
if you are you know what I you know
whatever characters you know personality
you have if you interact me if you you
you feel at the East you know being
yourself
then the I enjoy I actually enjoy that
most but a lot of times people when I
intact you know I noticed you know and
when I interact with people they tend to
become formal like you know and I guess
I guess I know why because they observe
observe you know me and and that's how
they respond
you know that's natural you know because
they see me to be that way okay so let's
see what what comments and questions so
we got 18 people 16 people watching so
who are your people
come come out and say something say in
China so great to see you in Beijing
cool so I suppose you knew me from Emacs
so you are you max user right it's on
you each young second chance so that's
Chinese
Tony Chun I can type I can do you cannot
spell Chinese feeling well
huge yeah because yeah yeah I'm not very
familiar but I can type let's see I can
type let's try let me try it
let's see switch ping yeah so so this is
how you type Chinese guys for for those
English watches so you so there are many
input systems for time in Chinese one of
the most popular is called pinging let
me let me show you so
ping in so that's how you spell in
English so pinyin system is a phonetic
based system so it's based on sound so
if I know how a Chinese sounds I type it
using English piece based on English so
I type using an English alphabet
and the input system will show me a
bunch of choices and I press space you
know enter so for example some one so
there we have it enter so back to the
questions so I'm reading some questions
so would you be able to solve calculus
problems these days
yeah well I'm rusty I'm kind of rusty
but but I've been reading math in the
past two years
oh yeah I'd enjoy math so much you know
yeah and this yeah yeah but well if you
ask me your calculus for example if you
give me a derivative I can probably do
it if you give me an integral No do you
think China will overtake the US as the
biggest world power in the future I
don't know I mean it's it's you know who
knows now but how this you know what
I'll say is this is the social justice
scan if they keep going it will happen
it's already pretty bad you know the
China like when I read news today every
day it's China China you know they have
the biggest bridge they have the fastest
computer they have the highest whatever
that the vast fastest train you know
they have the highest buildings it's
it's all in China like almost everything
every day and sometimes you know I
follow the Chinese I started to follow
some of the Chinese you know Twitter
account from China they post all the
city you know pictures it's just amazing
so much of it you know but still I mean
us by you know as far as military power
is concerned if US is still quite far
ahead but however in terms of technology
you know all the technologies you know
Chinese is pretty you know well first of
all economically China I think is always
already beat
u.s. or was a second I don't know and us
is is like you know Oh China like bid in
debt to China billions of dollars or
something you know I don't know good
so yeah China is I mean it's just it's
like it's not it's just you know I'm
like I'm surprised by it you know and
also I feel good I feel happy because
I'm blood I'm you know I'm Chinese but
by blood I'm American citizen okay you
know for for people who who are grew up
you know in other countries and like
I've like me for example and you you
American you know your perspective you
know you you get more different
perspective than compared to say the
white American who just you know Google
being a you know USA so you know for me
I have some connection because Chinese
that's my blood that's my root so I you
know I pay attention I have some
connection I don't you know I wish China
you know doing well like for example my
parents you know you know they are
Chinese like hundred percent Chinese but
however I grew up in America well I grew
up in Canada in America and you know
when I was younger I was always I don't
like the Chinese philosophy that when I
was younger
I'm always much more interested in
Western philosophy
you know the logic the Greeks the risk
Toto the you know you know the Greek the
concrete the logical you know the
scientific way of thinking not these
days not well these days it's like mixed
you know I
but anyway so so I grew up you know you
know as when I you know it since I'm a
tote I grew up in Cal you know in in
Montreal Canada in California so
although you know back in the days like
in a 90 in the 90s you know I always
like despise well I don't despise but I
always make fun of American like like
because America America is like very a
monoculture what you might say
you know even today the social justice
they talk about multi culture but their
multi culture is like in the American
culture with you know funny CAD and
stuff that's that's their concept of
modern culture anyway America is mostly
monoculture you know these are good but
anyway you know III I used to make fun
you know but still but still I'm I'm
American you know and I like America you
know I this is this is this is my
country and technically as well you know
so you know I don't want America to do
bad you know I want you know America you
know we are the most powerful you know
we you know we're gonna send you a few
nukes you know and and free you guys
still you know yeah so so the best you
know the best thing is world peace you
know it's like yeah but that's getting
complicated yeah so because everyone you
know everyone wishes you know of course
everyone wishes to world peace
you know you wish what piece you know
but that doesn't happen just by wishing
especially the social justice can Fox
you know they they are incredibly evil
and not not just like not not just like
maybe they are you know maybe you don't
know maybe you know we it's debatable
but they are absolutely you know is
because this stays you you if you
actually try to read a new state they
they they lie they you know clearly lie
they try to get money they try to do
lots of things you know that not
something I really you know want to you
know that's not my main topic it but it
you know it's helpless you have to
because it's you you know it's a
actually you have to talk about it okay
I don't know what you guys you know your
political inclinations but today it's so
serious you know civil civil war is
about to begin
you know it's already you know it's not
like you know it's already your
there you know America you know you have
the divide so you have to you you you
kind of have to pay attention you know
you want to try to see you know how to
solve the problem you know try to talk
to people on the other side you know you
you want to try to do that because it's
getting really bad what do you think
about the recent news that rich people
paid money so their kids go to college
yeah that's a good example
you know this [ __ ] Hollywood you know
rich white people oh you know you you
you black black lives matter you know
black lives matter is started by white
lesbians you know oh yeah they talk
about do all these things you know but
they are at the top and they are the
most privileged and they st. you know
the yeah they bribe you know millions
we're talking about millions of dollars
they have so much money
you know put a few millions to the
Harvard oh you know whatever Stanford
you know University so they get their
kids they can you know they they are
sent you know Harvard graduate and these
people you know these days these PhDs
even PhDs they know nothing like not
just not just in journalism is okay I
don't know actually I don't know about
the sciences yeah maybe in the sciences
is not true but all the others like
social degrees you know these women
study since that you know III I didn't
intend to get into these topics because
you know Google you know soon you know
people is gonna report me and I get I'll
get banned you know there's so many
people get banned on YouTube to you know
since beginning about you know almost a
year ago
so do you think China will overtake okay
well let me talk about that you know
she's a she's Greek
you know she's Greek who okay I missed
some questions okay just like you math
Mecca Oh math America use a great by the
way is is that a legal copy because in
China you know many software is not
legal back then at least I don't know
what's the situation today in China do
they still copy like you know I know a
no AutoCAD for example like in China you
don't it's kind of funny like like in
USA you don't hear about AutoCAD that
much you know I mean even among the 3d
model people I don't think you still you
know I don't you know a lot of people
use others you know there are many but
in China it's like everything you know
you you almost hear everyone talking
about AutoCAD can even programmers you
know the tagua AutoCAD and auto lease
moto Lisp
is a list language you know a lisp
dialect a scooping language for AutoCAD
so in China talk about it that and I was
when you how come how come you guys all
know you know talking about AutoCAD why
is that why is this so popular in China
and I realized it's because in China
it's all copied you know is it's copied
version so everyone can get a copy free
and you know they teaching universities
I get I guess okay I don't know if it's
actually true but that's my guess
hey Gong ba we I'm just talking random
random stuff and I know
okay so Zen says and I know you when I
search something about math America oh
cool thanks yeah lip taught me and
staying here
can't constant okay oh the counselor
Troi is is that concentrate that's the
name the character's name is quick oh I
see yeah
in Brazil everyone also gets a free copy
oh okay
are you in Brazil Matthew a salsa it's
trivial to keychain for mathematica
really you know I always wondered you
know how they you know these pirate
people how do they actually do it
did you parent mathematica in early days
no I didn't I bought it you know back in
the early days 1992 I bought it of
course I don't actually I don't do you
know I don't do pirated yeah I almost
almost never it were basically never I
don't you know so you know Mathematica
they have student student version so
student I don't know how much is it
today but student version is something
like $200 you know but the professional
you know the the professional version is
like it was 1,000 something maybe it's
truth I don't know how much you know you
have to check the website but it's huge
like one thousand two thousand dollars
but however the student version or
hobbyist version they have a hobbyist
version you know but all the versions
are identical so it's not like crippled
all the versions are identical and and
by the way if you buy a Raspberry Pi
Mathematica is included in it so let's
go to my waist psych sorry dot info so
if you're gonna buy it buy it from my
website okay I'm gonna show you where so
you go to my website sorry dot info and
you go down and here is I have some
collection of articles about Mathematica
now this these are just some essays I've
written about Mathematica but they are
not a comprehensive tutorial and I
haven't coded Mathematica for actually
ten years but you know but anyway so I
have quite yeah quite a few articles
about math America but anyway yeah if
you are going to buy Mathematica ok
Mathematica is bundled free if you buy a
rasp rasp berry pie I think is show the
case yeah so if you want to buy it buy
it for my website
you know just click the link go to
Amazon and you know I make a few bucks
you know like 2% or something so yeah I
always wondered how they you know when
they pay with software how they do it
like but but you know I never looked
into and I have no idea how the entire
mechanism works how do you prevent
people from you know parroting you know
copying software yeah I suppose okay I
suppose when the software is installed
you know it checks your MAC address or
whatever your computer CPU whatever
identity you know ID then it mix that
and it creates a key something like that
and sends a key to the company then
something like that yeah
so okay so the comment died off I still
got 17 people now I've been talking for
one hour and 10 minutes now and today I
haven't I haven't talked much it's
almost like almost all rambling so I'm
looking to I'm going to quit I want to
quit because you know smoking you know
it doesn't do me you know smoking is my
slow self-destruction you know I want to
smoke because for no reason other than
the slow self-destruction you know I
have failed my life is a failure my life
is a failure you know you can say that
hey thank you thank you for coming by
break the loop we should which we should
do a meet up again sometimes bye
yeah I noticed so I have a patron so if
you guys like my talk you know go to
patron and be my patron hey Danny Oleg
no noise wait were you from I forgot
then you know you wrote you wrote a lot
of things I'm sorry I didn't get to
actually I didn't get to even read them
and you you you you coat you you posted
code to the self like ease pull request
I haven't got time to read them well
because you know I think you know I've
been doing videos but I haven't you know
got time to you know my emails has been
pile piled up so I'll get to it all Los
Angeles so you did that stuff like is
you did you
I noticed you you did a pull request
that use you Huskies or - okay hey high
five peace and prosper so so does that
actually work I mean I haven't looked
into I mean
but it would that that's a great thing
though because that's one of the things
I want to do to the cassava Keys
basically change the mechanism how it
swaps keys yeah so schizoid personality
that's this that's interesting so anyway
so I think how do guys you guys got
questions so I'm gonna smoke one more
smoke
I'm going to finish the FAP finish the
pack and and be done with it I guess
yeah I mean usual a lot I mean so I'm
gonna look into I want to be sure though
because you know because it's gonna take
me a lot time to read them code did you
read the code and also I'd you know
because that's a big thing I don't want
to just check it in like usually if
usually some other pool requests you
know I just checked in and you know
because it's little code but this one is
a big thing because if I check it in you
know then in my break you know other
people download it doesn't work because
there are many you see you might know
you may not know because when you you
know a lot of people use you know the
package in different situations so
there's also input systems you know some
Russian people that you have you know
they have to use Russian input systems
they have to constantly switch and also
in Emacs you know you have input systems
so you want to be sure that you know it
still works you know my sleeping hours
it's changes all the time you know I've
been trying to tell people this is a
hard thing one of the hard things to
convey to people like people get
surprised but literally it's just like I
don't have a schedule basically some
sometimes some period of weeks I sleep
during the daytime some some during the
night time so it's like that it's been
like that all my life basically so yeah
so literally I you know so I can so
basically if for example if you want to
like sometimes I need to talk to people
like schedule or meeting you know meet
people or something maybe for an
interview for example you know just you
know I have to like oh so so you know I
have a date
then III adjust to that date basically
but normally if anyone wants to talk to
me just tweeted me or anything
don't don't email though like but
because my email is like all piled up
like you I don't even want to read it
you know treated me like something
instantaneous and just it writes more
like one of two sentences
that's the best to get answers because
and that's typically the strategy for
getting other people's attention as well
you know just write something small so
they can respond right away then you
maybe try to talk more then you know if
you like like I mean in general if you
write a whole block you you know
especially like you know like like me
for example I tend to I want to like I
want to careful it we pray you know look
at the whole thing and reply but just
the prospect of you know oh this is a
big leap right and you know then I start
to like delay you know then then it
doesn't get read you know it just
doesn't get to be pride at all a lot of
people are like like that
okay cool yeah so yeah so I'll check it
out sometimes you know do let's say this
week sometimes you know because I and
also need to write code for I need to I
need to do this Python thing for the for
professor you know it should be easy but
I haven't been coding for I haven't been
coding Python for a while by the way hi
if you are watching so I think that's it
you know I feel like you know I feel
like I want to go on talking so this is
15 people watching but you know people
are keeping quiet so he say is that I
think that's it let's smoke the final
smoke the last cigarette the last meal
you know when you when you say these
kind of things you kind of have to be
joking because otherwise it's no good
you know otherwise people get alarmed
you know yeah don't worry about you know
that I have you know I have many I have
lots of things you know I want to talk
about you know lots of things about a
word about you know the thing about
video is that you know
like they are I mean there are seven
billions of people right I mean there
are 7 billions of people and most people
I mean if they are really different you
know there's so many different people
they take different lives they have
different lifestyles and you don't know
them you know like you can only I mean
normally I think there's there's a study
you know on average each person you can
make you can make meaningful friends at
most I forgot what's a figure like 50 or
100 you know like maybe 50 it's that's
the most you can make meaning meaningful
friends but anyway so I mean so I tend
to think a lot you know so you know all
these people you know medium perience of
people and their lifestyles you know
there's so many lifestyles you know
living and also you know there are party
people you know some people like they
especially I can imagine if you watch
movies you know sometimes to watch
movies you can imagine those there's
some party kind of people I mean they
are not you know a lot you know most
people are not programmers right yeah I
mean so I'm a programmer I'm a nerd and
so are most of you I suppose so our life
is mostly limited to the you know the
program you know yuppie life you know I
don't know if that's still wood today
you know in the office you know and
programmers you know yeah some
programmers they do party you know they
they go to parties and stuff but most of
us are not I guess you know that you
know you know we interested in math or
whatever science science and health
technology but outside you know this
outside it is also the people you know
especially like if you watch movies you
know you see also the people so what is
my point I mean well I don't have a
point
except you know I just you know it's
just something I think about you know
the it is and many people are
interesting yeah anyway it says that's
incoherence
so I smoke this cigarette and Dovie it
for today
programming our noemi's now yeah I kind
of you know I don't like I kind of I
don't like that yeah yeah just because
no means you know like yeah I remember
in the knighting I mean like 2010 maybe
around 2010 they start to have this bro
coders what they call what do they call
it you know like I mean they are not
nerds right I mean they they do their
stuff they and they of course they don't
know programming well they don't do for
anywhere else I mean and you know I read
recently on some some other programmers
yeah programmers I mean that's fine I
mean I mean there's nothing wrong with
that but but it's just it's just
different it's different culture this is
different people it's like different
people invading your space not well I
mean you know not not in any you know I
like you know these days you know in a
social justice situation you kind of
have to explain because if you don't
explain oh you are racist you know those
[ __ ]
so anyway programmers yeah you know yeah
you know I don't I don't like them
because they are you know they are
different personality you know I feel
comfortable when other people are nerds
you know because they understand me you
know I go you know like let's say I meet
people you know we talk you know and I
don't have no more things to talk about
like um like all my life you know when I
talk to people I can only talk about
science and technology and math or
philosophy or linguistics you know
academic subjects I you know I don't
have anything else to talk about I don't
have I don't they say I don't have a
life you know and also with me is that
I'm a schizoid and also so if I go to a
bar you know most people like when you
see TV shows you know the guys have
their you know you know whatever guys
night or whatever they go to buy and
guys enjoy each other
I enjoy that you know if I go to a PHA
you know the the the the number of times
I could go to a bar is like maybe once
every 10 years you know I go to a bar I
get very nervous it's like oh yeah I get
extremely nervous you know I cannot talk
I cannot function
you know I know to most people and even
a lot of you I know it's it's like
strange but that's just that's the
situation you know I can you know I can
relax you know I can you know sometimes
you know I can you know it's just a bar
you know you go there people have fun so
I go there but that's not just it's not
natural to me so I go there you know for
example they are passed right here right
so I go there I'm like I'm like a robot
you know I became robot what do I say
they what do I talk there I want to I
want to talk about that I want to talk
about philosophy you know that's what I
enjoy like right now you know I mean
doing what I'm doing
I mean train talking about Star Trek's
about science fiction about philosophy
of it you know you know either analysis
and all that mathematics I go through a
bar you know what I don't you know I
cannot you know they talk about jokes I
don't I don't I don't find it funny yeah
hey chokes it's not funny to me and my
jokes they don't understand you know
like you know programming like mr. data
jokes so that's so yeah programmers then
today they got well you know they got
you know you know let's not talk about
that
frameworks got more powerful yeah so
yeah so today you know you look at
today's programmers yeah you can see
online you know I talk to people you
know you talk to them they don't they
don't know they don't know programming I
mean what they doing you know the
JavaScript ten ten lines of code is a
library especially JavaScript the
JavaScript ecosystem because you know
why because the JavaScript you know it's
a kind of new language it became popular
around let's say 2008 so the people who
program JavaScript are mostly young
people let's say the Millennials I mean
that's a fitting you know actually that
that fits the period so that the the
people who are in JavaScript fields are
typically Millennials and the
Millennials as you know you know they
they don't know things you know they are
pretty ignorant and so they search in
JavaScript you know the people they like
ten lines it's a library and they they
have their ecosystem they have their
stuff you know it's like and you know
they don't know I mean not I mean a lot
a lot of them okay I mean well you know
like today you know every you know
program and become more popular and you
know you got more people and that's a
natural situation but of course there
are a lot great JavaScript programmers
you know it's you know a lot of them
great you know JavaScript programmers
yeah and frameworks you know for me
actually I don't know you know I don't
know I'm not very good I'm not I don't
you know I cannot code JavaScript like
most these people do although
technically is supposed to eat it's
easier but the way the way I call
JavaScript is like it's like back in
1999 you know III don't use frameworks
I don't like frameworks you know
well that's party you know it's not you
know okay part of the reason is because
I'm I'm the old generation I'm getting
old that is that is actually true my
ability to learn things my ability to
learn new things my ability to you know
absorb things is actually slower than
when I was younger it does happen so you
know the new technology I'm less capable
I'm less able to like you know absorb it
and just use it that is actually true
but on the other hand but that's not a
total reason so the other part of reason
is I'm is is that I I still hold you
know you want to be a programmer you
learn the fundamentals you learn the
algorithm you know mathematics I mean
you know like today's programmer they
talk about machine learning like oh yeah
they know machine Ani they didn't they
don't know [ __ ]
they don't even know calculus they don't
know algebra they don't know group
theory they don't know the basics but
they they are cribe and you know they
talk about machine learning oh this
isn't that he just used this library Oh
Google tensor oh you know but actually
you know they don't know [ __ ] and this
is scientifically true in the sense that
if the world crumbles down you know I
can for example I can write a framework
you know I can write a react I can you
know you give me time I can write react
from scratch I can write jQuery from
scratch okay you you ask me to be able
to have you know iPhone whatever I don't
know how to you know I'm not familiar
you know I cannot do that you know they
can do that but you know but you know if
you co-ceo me in a room I can create the
react I can create the features from
scratch I can you know do that they
cannot you know because they don't did
you know they don't know the you know
the fundamentals so that's what that
what I mean that they they don't know
things actually I mean when you actually
you know just
let's say you put five let's say you put
100 Millennials you know in a room see
you know seek secluded you know you ask
them to be out of project no not no
library is no framework no no nothing no
internet you put them together you know
after years see what they create on the
other hand you put a bunch of let's say
older generation programmers you know
you put you know hundred of them like
100 Millennials in one room 100 you know
older generation programmers let's say
let's say those from those no C or
Python or Perl ok or Lisp you know you
put them in one room after year I would
say and I would say it's likely you know
the the the older generation this you
know the see these guys they will create
they create things the Millennial people
I'm not sure I'm not sure they're gonna
do much so anyway that's it for today
thank you guys for coming by yeah that
that that that's that's it and so many
people coming by today great I'll see
you next time have a good day