hello guys welcome to another episode of
some talk show so today we are going to
code emac this emac Beast writing a
major mod python mod from from the
ground up from scratch okay and I'm just
going to begin and the keyboard you are
looking at
um is expose okay I have shown here you
just search for Sally keyboard and
you'll see my ergonomic keyboard reviews
and uh as you know I reviewed them and
today this one is exposed it's excellent
okay that's this one okay I'm going just
going to start to uh code so write a
major mod from the ground up for python
why do I want to write that because
let's start python okay the python mod
uh I don't like it
that is why so uh so you're gonna learn
from you know you can write your own mod
uh whatever new language or uh for
golang or for JavaScript you can write
your own so I'm gonna show you and if
you you know I'm so I'm gonna do this
live but you can find all the details
how to do it just by uh going to my
website sorry dot info emacs how to
write a major mod so you know syntax
current beginning with this one syntax
coloring font lock what does it do uh
you know how do you code it Define face
color comments color uh writing your
command to comment or uncommon
and keyboard completion you know you
want to complete names
you know so you can read them and you
can learn it so but I'm going to do a
live one but I actually I did this in
2001 so last year almost exactly a year
ago I did one write the major mod and
the last time a year ago this is uh
writing a major amount for go land
you know fantastic in fact if I code
Golan let's see
in in fact if I called Golan I'm using
my my own mod so you see so you can see
go you see
heck you know this is a Golan template
every Gold Line needs all these lines of
code uh you know so I can start to cook
let's say uh print
uh two plus three okay and I want to
format them very nicely I just press uh
tab F you see I can in fact let me Demo
okay
uh let's let's Munch all these together
and demonstrate the power of golan's go
format okay so you see the whole code is
not one line but I press the key
bam you know it reformat them and I run
it
you know when when you run go online for
the first time it it takes a while so
you see result is five uh two plus three
and now let's delete this and the unit
5 okay and now reformat again so you can
have arbitrary
complex code in big format okay anyway
let's go land so
um
and we are going to write python okay so
so right now I'm using the default
python mod how do you find out the mod
name of the current mod of course you
can look at the status bar the mod line
in emacs this line is called my line so
you know it says python but that's not
the technical name so if you want to
know what's the current mod you just say
major mod okay you want to say describe
function on
on this variable major mod so let's call
describe function and type major mod
it's already there press enter so now
you can see major mod is a variable
defined in somewhere and its value is
python mod so this string python Dash
mod that is the technical name
you know meaningful to the images
language of the major model okay so
right now I'm using my python mod let's
import this so what I want to do is say
import
yeah you see this is what I don't like
the about the python Mark let's restart
I want to say
import sys
okay but if I type that it's gonna it's
gonna transform my typing to something
else to another syntax I don't want so
let me type it slowly import okay space
then you see it changes it to form
something I don't want from something
but let's say sis okay and you see each
it makes you type in the mini buffer I
don't want to type in mini buffer you
know it's crammed
you know into a little space so okay
she's enter Then from this import a
function I don't I don't know what the
[ __ ] function name I want you know
identifier so let's press enter so
there's no completion
how the [ __ ] do I know what functions in
that package you know this is sucks so I
so I don't like the default mod
okay so let's go to python mod the swipe
function uh you know so python mod so
now you can see here is the python man
you can you can jump to the source code
okay we are in a source code and five
thousand seven seven thousand five
almost six thousand lines of code
uh okay let's let's start from scratch
let's just write out oh okay so pop this
back uh let's print
um
uh let's print uh this version I think
that's the how you print version you see
I got python 3.9 okay so let's let's
start to write let's begin to write the
python mod Okay so
start a new code block
block emac this that's right and pop it
out okay so
python mod okay
so okay so you know what we can do is
just copy paste
uh all the informations here so emac
based writing a major mod for syntax
calling there are many things involved
there are many features of a major mod
syntax coloring is the most primary
fundamental you know when you go to a
programming language the first thing you
want is syntax coloring
then
okay let me explain what what what are
the major elements what are the major
features of of using a major mod if you
have questions in
comments post it okay
I'm doing well thank you
so major Mart the first thing you want
is syntax coloring most of the time then
okay then front lock mod is related to
syntax coloring about details of it
Define phase is also detail
could a comment is also part of it
syntax coloring but there's a different
mechanism
so okay then what you want is you want a
command to comment and uncomment you see
that's part of the major mod because
every language has different Syntax for
common so comment and uncommon syntax
coding then you have keyword completion
okay now let's see so for example in
emacs so I want to say different I can
say d e and press tab you know I got all
the words in emac this so I can complete
so I can say F different okay that one
okay that's
keyword completion so you need that
you know so synex schooling
uh comment command comment and comment
keyword completion you want
then key map of course key map is you
know because in emacs everything is
keystrokes so you you need to know how
to create your own how to define you
know what key spine to what command Okay
key map then the other elements is a
brief template this is quick this is
fantastic okay this is like this one
this feature is actually
uh not often used in other major mods in
all the building mods in emacs for
whatever language they don't use this
much but I find this is the most useful
emac is a brief template for major mod
for example if I want to define a
function
um you know I can just say press D press
space it becomes different and press
space again it becomes the whole thing
and I can say insert I space
again you know it it creates the whole
syntax template for that function so
let's see something more uh more complex
let's say while loop okay press enter
you see I got this whole thing this
allows me to this is one of the idiom in
emacs it allows you to search and
replace
you know and if you don't want that you
can of course you can change it uh when
while okay so for example ylx
greater than okay so greater than x
let's say less than uh
less than lt space it becomes you know
the syntax so less than x less than 10
then you do something here
something let's say insert X
for example that's a while loop and you
can press tab two times it reformat the
whole thing for you so anyway formatting
that's another feature so anyway so the
brief template is a tremendous useful
then you have text properties that's
kind of the internal thing you need to
know over like overlay highlighting
that's another internal thing uh you
know usually part of major mod for
example I want to
highlight all the words let's go to a
big uh emac this code so you see this
file has a few thousand lines stuff like
keys I want to highlight all the um
let's go up
uh let's say I want to highlight all
functions that contains the word save
okay so I can
press that it calls highlight commander
and then I say save and enter it asks me
what color so high yellow okay so you
can see now all the words in the buffer
that contains the function names you
know contains the word save is all
colored this is extremely useful this is
um because when you work with code
sometimes you just want to see
where a certain function occur in a easy
in a very uh apparent manner
so you can see uh anyway so that's
highlight okay and and how do how does
it work you know you see this highlight
yellow how does it work well that works
by
that works by using the mechanism in
emacs called overlay highlighting so
there are two mechanisms to highlight
the word uh you know uh and I have
covered in the past
yeah I've covered this one in the past
so and look up doc that's another
feature you want in a major mod for
example in
so in for example right now in email
list emac this is Trivial because
emacs come with emac lisp so if you want
to have a function like look up the
documentation of the current function
you can just say describe function you
know it's oh you see so you can so right
now you are looking at the documentation
for the
both a file name function so you know it
says Returns the name of file buffer is
visiting O'Neill if not you know you can
look up any word for example interactive
describe function
interactive so you can see interactive
is you know a special form in C code in
csos code and blah blah blah
but if you are in another language
JavaScript PHP python Ruby
Golan C plus you know you can you need
to have a feature so that user can press
a button and it will take them to the
documentation for example let's go to
wolfam language you know wolfam language
let's say I want to list
all file names in your directory
recursively so what I can do is I can
just um file name here okay press tab
for completion okay that's the one I
want enter
and I got this
you know I that's that's how you get all
file names so so what what what does
this function do you know so I can press
a key
tab Edge
you know it goes to the browser the
appropriate location to show the
documentation of the current function
okay so that is a feature
you want to add to your major mod very
convenient
and very easy too you see you can see
it's only like 10 lines you know the so
the trick is you know you want to
you know spend time you want to you know
the a lot of people use emacs but they
never learned emac bisp
uh so you do want to
uh
sit set yourself a goal that you want to
maybe create a major amount let's say
some some programming language you work
most often so that that way we'll get
you started in learning emac bisp
because you don't actually need to
because there's a lot of packages
already thousands thousands of them but
oftentimes you need some feature it's
not there then also when you install
packages sometimes you are frustrated
because this package you know for
example might for example the python
close
for example on C go back to python okay
so let's go to meta X
python mod Okay so
you know I'm using python mod I want to
import something and need
[ __ ] change me to some other thing I
don't want that okay but if you don't
want that how do you fix it well you
have to look into
um
so how do I for example import
space so apparently it has some kind of
a trigger
so when you trigger when you press space
it looks looks at the
it's very annoying I don't I really
don't like this Behavior so when you
press space the python mod probably
looks up on the word before it and check
to see if it's some of the keyword if it
is then it calls a function
it then it delete that you know it
delete what you typed and it cause a
function you know import it deletes that
change it to form then call a function
then pop up and ask you a bunch of
questions idiotic so you can
for example let's go to python one okay
describe function
python mod okay so let's go to the so
here's a documentation the uh the
the dark string for python mod function
you know basically the documentation for
the major mod so let's go to the source
code and then we can look
look at uh where does it change
for example so for example if I want to
fix this problem
of python changing changing things so I
have to look at the source code
and in order to do this you have to know
IMAX so that's why that's why I'm saying
that you should set yourself a goal of
some you know small project that will
get you
stick to learning emac bisp and uh you
know iMac is very powerful if you are
emacs user if you know some images
so Peter mod and so I want to fix it you
know the the thing is oftentimes if you
know a lot emac Beast you know I've been
coding Mac this for 15 years so if you
know a lot emac this it would be faster
to fix the problem by just writing it
from scratch that's one that's why I
want to do it today you know right in
the python mod from scratch
instead of looking into
you know the python mod and see if there
is a
you know a variable a setting I can
change it to the way I like and let's
let's look at uh
let's look at the
least matching lines and let's look at
all the defined variables to see if
maybe there's some some of them
that can turn off that smart feature
uh I don't know let's see let's look for
the word smart okay it's not there let's
look for the word smart okay let's look
for the word Auto
you know
in the indentation okay this in you know
the default python mod indentation I
also don't like uh Auto load Auto or
something
okay I don't know so close that let's
look for the word import it must be
there somewhere because it's looking
it's changing my
my typing users typing of import uh
python skeleton I don't like it
skeleton is a
yeah so I don't like you know
you know once you know a language then
you develop your own style and ways and
certain things you just don't like I
don't like this a bunch of coding
skeletons to do things skeletons is a
package in emac building in here like
this that
helps you create templates basically
it's a template system
so how is it different from just using
emac lisp well the thing is the skeleton
package it kind of
helps you create templates you know for
example let's say
just like different you know help you
create templates without having to know
emac disp that is the that is a key for
the skeleton package
okay but I don't like it because I
compare to a brief we don't need it okay
in my opinion by the way that's why you
also have you know the com you know the
there's a lot completions yeah they kind
of or not necessary
so anyway so the reason I don't like the
skeleton is because you don't need it if
you know emac this they don't you know
they emac this by playing emac this is
much more powerful and uh
and uh and you know for what skeleton
can do without knowing lisp you can do
that with a brief
okay for what scale skeleton package can
do with a little emac this
then you can do that with emac this
itself without knowing to more than what
skeleton requires so skeleton package is
uh it's not too useful in my opinion and
it's it was created some 20 or 30 years
ago but why is that in Python mod it's
using skeleton you know it looks like
you know just by facing judging by the
naming of things so let's look at what
exactly it's using
python skeleton class oh maybe it's not
okay I was wrong so I cannot find a name
of that
um skeleton definition okay there it is
oh yeah
yeah it's using skeleton no good you see
you see here python skeleton Define you
see these things strings that's a
template that's the template Syntax for
us for the skeleton package
you know it's trying to
the goal you know it's trying to
think that you know you don't have to to
know too much least because you see it's
all just a bunch of strings but it
allows you to insert templates but it's
not good
because if you learn skeleton
you see you you still have some some
lists you see this part is the actual
kind of
code
uh so anyway so let's look at the
skeleton and we are digressing of course
we are digressing a lot
so there it is Define macro okay again I
don't like macro so another random
comment to you these people you know if
you are beginner
never ever
when you called emac this or any other I
would say otherly skim these companies
never use the macro feature you know
because the way when you hear about
people talking about this why it is so
good
these phonetics will say oh it's this
macro you know in there
opinion in their you know is is is like
the macro is the god of God feature of
languages but actually this Marco is one
of the circus okay
and then people start because of the the
this fat just like oop you know you in
oop you have you know people insist
everything must be your object you know
so so oftentimes for example in Python
you have lots of python code that's oop
but it's just bloat you know you can do
it with one single function but in op
it's
10 classes in what what not [ __ ] you
know it so in some sense sometimes
sometimes it's blowed bloat and that
happens when you have a coat like thing
you know oops the best thing therefore
everything must be op therefore this
single function I'm going to change it
into a op model it's EDS idiocy in the
same way in lisp code
you know there's a lot um
I don't know a second my
my alarm clock
so in this code there is this there is
this fantasy this code that oh this
Marco is the best thing you need to
Marco so that's why you are looking you
are seeing a marker so this so This
python mod
is trying to Define your macro based on
the skeleton package let's look at let
me show you the skeleton package okay
uh
okay anyway it must be on top so you can
just see require you search for require
USC skeleton uh where is it
s-k-e-l-e
okay
okay they didn't even what
you can see color [ __ ] shell
is surprised if uh so who who wrote this
Fabian e Galina I don't know who he is
and he's got the GitHub so I look
Okay so
you know usually I look you know I look
who wrote them and why and you know look
at the history of things
you know today I'm kind of
distracted into other things because I
meant to write a python uh major mod
from the scratch
but again
like I said I have already done this
last year so you can you know if you
really want to
learn about how to write a major mod
from scratch you can look at last year's
video or just look at my um
you know tutorial already written
so what are we doing now so this guy
wrote python so right now we want to
find the skeleton why s-k-e-l-e-t
[Music]
Okay so
so skeletons so skeletons are provided
for simple inserting of things like
class Definition for import if why okay
so now I'm guessing it is this Skeleton
thing that's [ __ ] up
things when I type import you know it's
trying to be smart okay these skeletons
are integrated with a brief okay if you
have a pre-mod activated in Python
skeleton Auto insert is set to true then
whenever you type the name of any of
those defined hit space they will
automatically expand okay as an
alternative you can use the defined
skeleton command python skirt okay
so I don't know so I don't know where
the
so I think they are they implemented
skeleton by themselves without using the
skeletons package is that true
yeah so but you see these are templates
these are templates which I
which I think is no good
you see
you see this this line probably this
part is [ __ ] up my typing of import
you know why why do they do that because
python is one of the language that has a
code
so meaning that
you know they they want to tell you how
your code should be
your code style they they have a
uh passion or Obsession of how your
coding style should be in python or how
you code things so according to them you
should use import I mean you should use
the phone
instead of the import something
um syntax let me let me show you
so um
you know python is one of the worst
language one today is is is actually the
worst a month because there are so many
new languages which with great features
colon and
Ruby is much better than Python and
Ruby's even older than python by by uh
half a year or something
or maybe the other way around uh Ruby is
much better much more elegant much more
consistent and much more
thirst in Python and much more
understandable Ruby okay
the the only reason why so why is pet
you know python today is one of the most
popular language among the top three
also why because Google for two reasons
one is in around 2000 year 2000 Google
made it popular because Google choose it
as their in-house scripting language to
year 2000 okay
that is the time when programmers
started to hear about python oh python
Google is using it or therefore you know
I'm gonna use it to Google 2000 year
2000. then
year 2008 or so Ruby became extremely
popular because Ruby on Rails oh in year
2008 that's like Ruby on Rails then
python the language that pylon language
truly sucks okay it's falling out you
know for it's getting less lit and less
popular
but then around 2010 Google once again
because the machine learning the neural
networks Google is pumping up pumping
out python code you know
python because python is too slow it can
actually do any machine learning code
those codes are better in C's C plus
plus but python is just the front end
you know the the interface
so Google is pumping doing lots of
machine learning you know Google is
advertising their power you know and so
on you know and well and Google is using
python for this scripting language so
they all their libraries the front end
is you know python so this this is why
this is the second time python becomes
popular
you know that essentially that's the
only reason this pattern is truly sucky
the worst and the guide of van Rossum
among all programming language creators
I studied I looked into you know Wolfram
language step from Wolfram this you know
the McCarthy this uh Gola and Rob Pike
and Ken Thompson I think but Rob Pike
you know which is a Unix phonetics
you know of all the perimeter you know
Pearl Larry War which uh which is a
crack part you know about the
programming language
in JavaScript JavaScript by the um
Ike you know Brenda Brenda Brendan Ike
JavaScript
you look at all the creators of
programming languages you look at their
you know you you try to look into their
IQ
or how much do they know in Java you
know Java is from Gosling you know who
is very smart and wrote one of the first
emacs
you look at so of all these people guide
over Anderson is the most idiotic the
most low IQ among them all in my
judgment okay
but then but but he but among them you
know the different people have different
personalities some are talkative you
know they're talking all the time or
giving confidences you know they are
under the Limelight all the time such as
Richard Stoneman you know why are some
are just quiet they don't talk too much
TCR for example the creator of TCR
language today is kind of died out TCL
but back in year 2000 is a very popular
uh and
um you know alongside Pearl TCL so the
guy who created TCL his kind of academic
that academic guy he's not you know like
talking drama all the time like jwz
[ __ ] Jamie zielinski [ __ ] who is
famous for you know hacker you know
creating the Netscape you know for the
Unix version you know he talked he
babbles all the time you know but then
dramatically and also lead us to word
you know he created Linux he's also the
dramatic guy you know he's like flaming
you you are idiot that you know the you
know Linux covered
but but some of the you know language
created they are more quiet Rob Pike for
example who created lots of utf-8 he
created utf-8 uh last week I did a video
on unicode watch that okay so rap hike
he created utf-8 and lots of Unix things
and and and plan Nai and he also and he
basically also created
um go land with other with another guy I
forgot Ken Thompson I think or maybe
another I I forgot but anyway so rap
hack is also one of the
uh chatty guy and dramatic dramatic he
write a lot you know like me you know
I'm you can you can class it by me as
one of the more chatty and dramatic
but anyway my I was going to say the um
of all the programming language creators
I know the guy kidovan rosam is most the
most slow IQ okay
but but he also have a personality that
he think he's the he's the best designer
you know he he created python he want to
revolutionize Revolution
uh
nice the agent programming education you
know he in his vision python 3000 he won
everyone every school to use Python
worst language the reason I learned
python is because in in 2006 you know
Pearl is the reigning language for
scripting you know priorities everywhere
and pearl is just a Unix code very
strong code you know more than one thing
to do it you know the postmodern the
first post-modern language Pro you know
full of Unix code in crap so I thought
pattern is better
but python is kind of opposite but not
but it's like it's a trap okay it's it's
got this
as if aggressive it's a passive
aggressive coat Python and the python
people you know of course because of
Guido and rosam you know they are all
kind of
telling you what to do but in in some uh
you know
implicit way like you should do it this
way or that way so anyway python
so we we were talking about that because
we were talking about the import syntax
the most most idiotic design okay filled
with it either let me show you the
import okay the import situation
so there it is import module okay so we
import uh
recently I updated this function this
section so you see uh
yeah so you see so you have
two Syntax for you know more than you
have two you know primarily two syntax
to import some modules so one is just
import module name then the other one is
form module name import name keyword you
know function name one two three
[ __ ] IDI ID idiotic [ __ ] python
this so why so first so first of all you
see
and there are other ways okay but
anyways so these two major way why is it
not good because you can see first of
all you have two two different syntax
you know these two syntax are not the
same thing it's not like one is just
part of the other no they are like two
completely statement completely
different statements
that are basically doing about the same
thing
yet
one of the you know part of the
statement of the you know this one is
appears happens as part of the syntax of
the other completely different statement
so you see
let me explain this one okay because
when I you know syntax is one of the
thing I focus the most is in programming
languages in my study of programming
languages and syntax is more important
than semantics you know some some some
computer scientists idiots they write a
book they say oh syntax is not important
it's a cement that those are idiots okay
so let me explain why this python import
syntax is sucks okay
you see first of all you have import
something that's a syntax meaning that
that's something you type it has a
meaning to the Python language okay
import uh then something match your name
okay
now now now look at this syntax firm
module name import name one name two now
you can see the import something happens
exactly here to put in in two places you
know import something that has a meaning
but then but then this forms something
import something the second part import
something happened there
but here
their meaning is completely different
okay in the first
example I mean in the first syntax the
import something the argument or you
know it import is not a function so
technically it's not correct to call it
an argument
but you know it's a statement so import
something that thing
what you call is non-terminal in in
passing context
so this is an internal module name is it
should be your module name but in the
alternative syntax this Imports
something those names are not module
names okay those those names are
identifiers or function and variable
names in the module okay so in the asset
you have a problem what is the problem
it's confusing
because if if you are a programming you
know you see exactly the same thing
import something input ABC in one place
the ABC means one thing the in the other
place it means something else okay
so that's why
this design is just idiotic
who do you blame Guido Von Rossum idiot
and by the way it's let me get to
political political stuff you know Guido
Von Rosen also joined the social justice
Warrior again you know there's a video
of him talking about oh I'm not going to
teach programming to any males I'm going
to exclusively teaching girls Mentor you
know I'm gonna just Mentor women because
this that [ __ ]
not not a good
uh not a good thing to do okay so
but I don't think kidama and rosam is
not a bad person okay I don't think he's
a he's a bad person and even as a social
justice Warrior I don't think he's not
really doing something harmful meanwhile
there's a lot of them doing very bad
things but
I'm not going to talk about that
here and but anyway so man I don't I
don't think he's a
I don't
he he doesn't have a heist status in my
in my mind okay to me
uh so anyway let's back to the you know
technical thing uh syntax so he created
this you know but then you see
these two are different because one is
just importing of module okay the other
one is let's use select the names but
stupid stupid syntax you know
and it's you know he likes to you know
the Python language look look at the way
this this syntax is designed you know
it's like English you know almost like
firm a module name they import
it's idiot okay just idiot you see then
you can see this you know this part it
allows you to use the asterisk
and now if you do this then it's it's
what's the difference between that and
this you know I'm not sure even there's
a technical difference
uh maybe maybe there is but it's just
idiotic so anyway so we digressed a lot
and uh
uh maybe we are not going to write a
python mod from from scratch today
let's see where we want to go yeah so we
were talking about the skeleton
Skeleton thing
okay so I think the python mod this
major mod written by this guy he
actually created his own skeleton
without using the skeleton package uh if
you let me show you what I mean so in
emacs lisp you have a skeleton package
you can see it by let's see
by calling a purpose okay so let's see
propose you call Meta x a purpose
command then you type skeleton
okay so you can see okay that's not what
we want okay so here this one
yeah so you see here is a package
skeleton.el so let's go to the directory
you know this package
skeleton.el is part of emacs
okay and you open it and this is the
package 600 lines that
that lets you define templates
without knowing too much emac bisp
that's what we were talking about but
the python mod is also using skeleton
but the issue is I don't think it's
actually using
you know the package but it's
it's emulating it's doing it's doing
what's skeleton is
doing but the guy created it himself
something like maybe
so let's see skeleton read and okay
anyway
so lots of digression uh I think we are
not going to code it because to code
that to code the python mod from scratch
we'll take half an hour
um but we can
yeah if I start from if I do it right
now even if I do them the fastest as I
can it will take 20
minutes yeah so let's not do it we can
do it another day
okay I'm gonna going to read comments
and that will be it for today
uh hello immortality
Christian sample
okay
what's going on
magnify
uh
uh so look like Ludwig a question so
Marcus can grow into too many categories
in a workflow
I'm
not sure what you mean
[Music]
um
okay that's it for today as for the
keyboard you know so
let's let's just talk random then let's
turn your fantastic keyboard let me show
you can you see
yeah so we have color red and let's
change it to that's it for today so I'm
gonna do some random
green
now because I got the lousy camera so I
got two
forty dollars so this large attack
eighty dollars idiot [ __ ] you know this
stupid camera so you cannot see well I
need to buy so donate okay time to
donate buy me a camera Amazon go to my
Amazon
right and you know send me a gift card
and you can see
foam
yeah so let's let me let me let's talk
let me talk about some keyboard a little
bit so um
and what are we doing so pop this back
so sorry first walk sorry info
so go to my website sorry.info and you
can donate all the way to the bottom
donate patreon Amazon gift card PayPal
okay and we are going to yeah about
keyboard
so
you know I'm not giving up Kinesis
advantage
I'm using X but both are great okay uh
the
Kinesis Advantage you know these two are
my top favorite
uh but I've been using the Kinesis
Advantage for like four years five years
so I mean so for a change I'm using the
expose uh
and it so happens my Kinesis advantage
it has a
Cherry MX
silent red
switch meaning it's linear okay it's
linear and Light which is great however
my expose it's got a gatron red get one
red and it's even lighter you know it's
linear and even lighter much
significantly so so I prefer the X you
know the the gator and Ketone red switch
is much more you know because when if I
have to type a lot this this lighter
linear switches
much more you know the the Cherry MX red
silent is already very good but this one
is even lighter so for a change you know
I just want to
you know change my keyboard for a while
con keyboard you know that's that's one
of those 40 it's crap okay that's it for
today
um yeah yeah I think so
let's see
no I don't miss making mistakes if they
are like no
okay that's it for today bye guys