good morning guys welcome to another
episode of South Park show I am your
host sunny and we are going to talk
about interesting things okay
and first of all let's put on the date
so here's my Emax and i'm gonna talk
about some talk-show date April 1st so
today's April Fool's well the idiotic
thing ok I'm going to show you actually
I'm going to show you my food you know I
just went I'm like 2 minutes 3 minutes
late
I just went to shop with my roommate and
I mean let me say start now start now
copy paste and good for master done
master been mastered is the most idiotic
name you know the open source geeks you
know if you want to be popular
don't use such stupid name ok you know
like you cannot spare it you say he's
like you know um okay me post nice first
stop now and let's see how many people
are watching 1 people watching yeah and
then he starts youtube not YouTube but
Safari but because I'm going to log on
to my Twitter account to announce I'm
alive you see so I let me show you let
me give you a view to a kill now this is
my abort
ok you can see those are my that's my my
bed quarters
and that's all miss okay that's miss
miss ten years worth of miss you know
recently I read on Twitter someone wrote
about ADHD you know that you know like a
HDD or what whatever has syndrome and
okay look now this is a packrat
situation this is a you know you are
looking at someone who's got serious
problems yes okay so let me show you so
I went to with my roommate and you can
see I got food these are my rations you
know got bananas and got three cartons
of you know juice and this is apple
juice oh this is my lifeblood this is
like you know me know the energy drink
the power drink for sustenance so I got
a bunch of things for sustenance you see
and and there is the grape juice grape
juice you cannot do without grape juice
okay and by the way I don't drink any
sugar to drink so all my food I never
drink sugar you know like Coke UNICEF
and you don't want to drink when you buy
juice always buy that that's a hundred
percent juice you know know know that
you know what a they call it the the
kind of sugar they use so this wanna
meet Bronson
and I got this hat today and some some
like Salvation Army kind of still with
my roommate so they went and then I went
it's like cheap so I just got it you
know why because once you get that your
head is cold
hey green deck from Russia echo again
you know this problem you know OBS
okay now it's better
yeah the OBS I should oops
now that's energy drink okay this is the
lifeblood of things actually I still
have some here let's put it here
how is going green debt hey PO whoa
buckets
sounds awful sounds better now so today
we're gonna talk about a bunch of things
you know I noticed so there's one more
item I want to show you now look you see
that that's pizza that's pizza you see
great pizza three three dollars each and
you just put them in oven for like 20
minutes and it's good
wonderful pizza cheap pizza so how is in
Russia I mean is Russia in that city
cheetahs something something bug is that
expensive or you know comparatively in
Russia he said expensive to live in
Russia
so now you have seen my rations for my
sustenance and now it's time to put
money in my bank account
Casali keep headstart index okay oh
these are good things you know you go by
them
you okay by them then you go here and
you go to my blog actually just go to
Saudi dot info and of course you got my
paypal you got my patreon you got my
Amazon and put money there okay because
that's good
it's good for me it's good for you it's
good for Humanity you know okay what's
the next topic will be show food I
already showed you my food
pay me yes I said that in talk show
focus on one topic and possibly twice a
day yeah so I was thinking you know so
I'm doing video and I've been doing for
like three months now every day almost
and you know you learn you you learn you
learn many experiences you know how to
do a live stream you learn how to you
learn you learn your oration skills you
know now if you are younger you know
Millennials you probably are ignorant
you know you don't know what this
oration you know the ovation is the art
of talking okay so you got you know
Asian many aspects you want to improve
your articulation now articulation this
just does not just mean the you know
crea pronunciation but also the ability
to or the how you you know if you have
complex ideas you want to be able to
like express them you know speak them
clearly but also you you want to be able
to capture the idea use you know of you
know
you know few words with clarity that it
that is what articulation is about and
then you want your articulation so you
know a lot of things about doing video
about you know for example what topics
you go you know whether you how do you
do like you know when you start to do
things you know you learn things for
example many open-source fans you know
they in their life they've never opened
the business you know but they have all
sort of opinions about how how's the
society should be how Internet should be
you know that's a typical open source
and how economy you know how to make
money and so on but anyway so so yeah so
like you know I've been talking a lot
and I'm thinking you know I'm gonna you
know I'm gonna do more focused you know
possibly we don't I don't know for sure
but you know I tend to like you know do
as you go go as you do you know instead
of like a master plan because whenever I
do master plan usually it fails because
when I have a master plan because I'm
very ambitious you know I'm very I'm
highly extremely competitive and the
reason of that is it's rather from from
my childhood from the way I was grew up
you know in other words you could say
you know my parents I never got you know
love or you know confidence for my
parents you know which is in sharp
contrast to America you know in America
education you know typically the parents
are like always encourage your children
you know oh can you please you know do
this oh oh you are beautiful
oh this valley is great oh that's great
achievement that's typical American
education that's supposed to be the idea
you know other parents do that
you know they talk to your to your kids
as if like talking to you know close
friends you know stranger friends you
know you like you know please and do
that on the other hand you know in China
you know
in in taiwan in chinese we you don't
talk to your kids with all the priests
and and and you know that those polite
words you know you don't almost never
you know i you know they they've got my
roommates are cooking and the alarm went
off I guess take too much smoke so in
China you know the culture is different
of course and you don't you know it's
kind of strange to see you know parents
talking to the kids with you know fries
and you know the kind of almost like
negotiation in a business meeting you
know you just tell your kid what to do I
mean not like you you know you know you
just they are your children you teach
them you tell them no don't do this
oh you know do that oh that's great you
know of course you you know you know
with encouragement sometimes in stuff
but anyway the point is it's very
different from the American Way okay but
they also also the other important
actually this is the most critical thing
first of all every culture is different
okay that's obvious you know obvious you
know you have you know a different
culture of different ways up to bring up
their children but the thing about
American is that now this is similar to
the open source can you know the the
elite hacker types okay the thing about
American culture the American side they
they do it that they away but more
importantly they think it is the only
way I mean for the whole world I give
you don't do this where you are wrong
you are like you are an ethical you are
criminal you know it's like you look at
the Americans controversial or sensitive
sensitivity you know the topics
political sensitive topics for example
democracy and others rather I'd rather
not mention but you take those topics
okay
then you look at other words they are
entirely different you know
you know you look at Japan Russia you
look at you know China you know none
non-western no no white with some people
okay you look at different countries not
entirely different you know from your
you know you're like very narrow
prescribe you know certain views about
any you know hot political buttons in
USA yeah that's that's my brand about
USA hi Nicholas
now Nicholas is from Hong Kong hi hi
there hi to Hong Kong Sangha and okay
we're Moscow is expensive but in the
rest of country many people in Russia
live for less than $300 a month
Wow in Yuka stop touring bug it's like
50 50 I see green Texas you can create a
different scene for a full scene full
screen camera and switch live with OBS
yeah I guess I can I just never explode
it like you know just click here and
your switch to you know different either
full screen of myself or something right
yeah I need to explore obvious you know
we're starting with meeting the manuals
but I haven't done so yet oh by the way
since we're talking about culture I
think we are going to have a guest a
guest his name is Israel and I think
we're gonna have it tomorrow
and he's gonna just join me and we're
gonna talk about Cairo like he's gonna
introduce us culture in you know coach
Coach culture around maybe Middle East
I'm not too sure but he's gonna talk
about that
so tomorrow hopefully right now we are
working out how to actually do it you
know on a technical aspect because you
know this is my I don't know about
livestreaming much so you know so far
I've just used to these you know I go to
youtube I click you know live stream
then I go to OBS I click on start
streaming and there we have it streaming
live and but now we he he is going to
join me
so audios in audio so he suggested some
software I have to like install and
looking to create account maybe then you
know he's gonna talk we're gonna talk
and you know you know also meanwhile
stream it
so that's tomorrow I think it's from
tomorrow 11 3rd 11 o'clock or 11:30 a.m.
in the morning San Francisco time
actually I need to check the time to
make sure but anyway I think you know
you know yeah you know nothing on my
Twitter in the master then and let's see
how it goes so by the way he is he is
also an Emacs user and he is he is you
know he has done some Emacs videos I
don't remember the name right now the
Emacs lessons but I don't want to search
it now but anyway so you you you know if
you have seen my videos he has been here
a few times you probably know but he'll
be here tomorrow we'll see okay oh do ya
someone asked me for a audio only
version do you guys like do you guys
want a audio only version because yeah
someone named the wheel William asked me
for it so yeah he does Emacs is great
yeah okay this is a real guy he has a
video YouTube channel called Emacs is
great so you
you guys might check it out so yeah good
thank you
Thank You green Derek so let's go to
YouTube YouTube
YouTube the modern TV YouTube is a TV of
the Millennials yeah well this is
becoming so because every video they
have when we start watch your video they
have a logo ooh you know India India see
inside like everything is commercialized
of course you know then you know anyway
so Emacs is great so this guy Israel
Doug or Israel Tov oops okay so he's got
you know he's producing videos like
frequency okay let's go to his channel
okay and you can see her brew that would
be interesting so tomorrow I'm going to
do it whoops I don't want to quick oh no
tomorrow I'm going to do a holy
okay tomorrow I'm going to do a her brew
page for my Unicode page so we cannot
discuss maybe there's interesting things
about her brew okay so that's that's him
and let's go back to the next topic by
the way as usual if you guys have any
comments any thoughts any opinions type
it keep the comments going because that
keeps the channel that keeps the video
interesting okay so next I think I'm
going to do this Amazon page actually I
mentioned this before how long I been
going so I've been talking for 19
minutes okay so the next one is gonna be
Emacs and keyboard oh so we can do a
Emacs and keyboard which is adding a
keyboard to my keyboard blog or I can
demonstrate the Emacs sir HTML lines to
list
or you can do a this page now this page
is a web crawler in Python and it's in
Python - I'm good I need to convert it
to Python 3 so we can do that so what do
you guys think which one do you like to
see so one of them is okay let me show
you this one so three choices I give you
multiple choices three choices one is
this this is a this is a great
programmable keyboard I'm going to add
this page as one of my keyboard review
page on this keyboard so you're gonna
see how I use Emacs you know it's kind
of like a Emacs demo and maybe a little
bit I'll talk about a little bit
keyboard if you like you know ask me
questions so that oh I can do another
page we can do another thing like oops
like like this okay
something something else okay let me
start saw start command log mod okay now
you can see all my Emacs commands on the
Left panel okay now look watch I do
I call this command and look at these
two lines okay now watch wait I'm I've
been fine okay look watch ting instant
you see something in something else now
view in browser easy it's these two
items let's add a H showing because you
can see you see so I just pressed
basically I press let's see I press I
press two keys and it becomes a list so
the command is called line to list so I
can demo you know do a demo
I mean I'm gonna show you some emag
based code code you know how I do that
and maybe possibly
teach you some eMac this so that's the
other thing and another thing is just a
convert Python 2 to 3 so which one you
like the Emacs demo for keyboard
okay green decks got it okay so so
that's the looking back see what
everything is interesting okay I'm I'm
gonna try to do this quick you know
instead of like you know like all right
sometimes I watch my old videos I kind
of like dragging on you know talking too
much and repetitive so I am getting
better not to be like that so let's go
to my keyboard block this is my keyboard
blog and you can see my keyboard block
sofa so I'm going to you know I just
copy the URL and I put the link here and
press a button and it's wait wait wait
let me do it again
okay so you see that empty paste link of
I that's it okay so now show you in
browser now of course that's that's just
by I'm at by it Amazon it's not good
enough so I need to click on that click
on that and I'm gonna right click save
image as
okay I'm gonna save it as TG okay say
okay it's saved to my download folder
okay close it actually let's see
anything else interesting you can
connect you can connect the keypad plug
and play and the 104 key keyboard with
the same computer at the same time that
we are not interfere okay that's that
that's the program above the the
programmability that's pretty good
I think they improved their software
because it's different from what I've
seen last time yeah so I would recommend
this keyboard actually because I have a
version is kind of sitting there
and it's dirty you know one thing I want
about program oh okay one thing let's
talk about app or mobile keyboard a
little bit now when you buy a keyboard
you want it to be programmable okay and
you want it to
okay let's do the web color leap after
this so you want to buy a keyboard
that's programmable okay meaning that
with memory with memory on the keyboard
so that you can plug it into any
computer any operating system then your
pre programmed keys is there let's go to
casali info not info okay and let's go
to keyboard yeah so I have some ID you
know PC keyboard keypads okay click on
keypads and you can see the keypads I
recommend and there are lots of info
about how to buy a keypad you know go
ahead and read that if you like now yeah
so first of all you want a programmable
keyboard with memory on it then the
other question is how what are the ways
you know how do you program the keyboard
now depending on our keyboard there are
many different ways for example one of
the ways for example oh go ducks now to
program or go ducks keyboard you need to
go to a website then you see okay let me
show you a other codn't
design okay click on design and there
are several articles somewhere okay this
page about about the different ways to
program a keyboard now first of all they
are different firmware capabilities no
or programmable keyboard you know maybe
a keypad or keyboard they have you know
they all say programmable they all say
they are programmable keyboard but
actually the capability you know just
exactly what kind of key you can program
actually differ quite a lot among
among different programmable keyboards
you know from logitech from or ago dogs
which runs the q q MX
open-source software or from keyboard
i/o or from Kinesis Kinesis which is the
one so so different so they are
different programmable keyboards that
yeah let me show you my connected
kinases so you see that's my see if I
you know I've showed this many times but
you know for those of you new you know
to my desktop so it looks like that
so Kinesis is also programmable but the
point is different programmable
keyboards the programmability what kind
of key you can program is actually quite
different so i give you some examples of
the differences then or the Kokee that's
one thing then how you program the
keyboard is actually also quite
different now okay first of all i talk
about the advantage of somewhere you
know programmable keyboard over a Priyan
system key mapping you know you can you
know there are many software mac on
linux you know windows autohotkey on the
Mac is carabiner on Linux you have you
know you know for example if you go here
you can see Linux so this panel is all
about how do you program program
keyboards using your operating system
but those are no good compared to the
programmable keyboard firmware okay
that's why you want to buy a keyboard
that's programmable not you know if you
don't have a program about keyboard you
want to program keys you can use the
operating system you know but it's
usually you spend hours you know on a
Mac or Windows you know different
software or Linux is worse cost you
spend hours you know to
to try to get the right syntax you know
2zv works and even if you know it does
not work hundred percent like sometimes
some programs is in root privilege for
example on Windows then the key doesn't
work or when the system boots up you are
in terminal you know virtual terminal
the key to a programmable the key you
program doesn't work so programming are
not always you know via always software
is second second rate okay you do you
you you don't want to do that if you can
you want a program about keyboard first
so that's why you know I recommend so
that that's what I'm talking about
advantage of firmware over up green
system key mapping okay now
the the issue I'm going to touch is
anyway there are different methods to
program the keys so example if you buy a
boat or go ducks you you want to program
the keys what do you do you go to the
website you go to the you know one of
the go ducks website you you know you
drag keys around I have a window yeah
here it is
you know here's a go ducks this one is
from infinity aqueducts infinity you
know so you go to the website you drag
the keys around you know just you know
to programming keys then you click Save
it will actually save a binary you know
to your system then you have to download
I think you have to download the
firmware updater then on your operating
system you click you launch the firmware
updater you then you click update then
you select the binary file you just
download it you just created then you
say go then
then it's update it you know so it's
it's not good you know because I have
one keyboard that's like that
oh the truly economic keyboard is like
that I have it here to do economic some
somewhere you can find in the economic
let's just go there ergonomic keyboards
ergonomic egoistic then surely this one
you know I have this one I still do so
this one back then the you know -
updated from where it's like it's like
the docks it's not convenient because
you have to go to the website and do
things then download you know a binary
then launch the updater firmware updater
you know then you know choose the you
know it's not good the the best way a
feature for programmable keyboard is its
so-called driverless ok it's called
tribal s or on-the-fly programmability
for example my Kinesis is like that so
if i want to program the keys for
example if i want to program the keys i
just press here i just hold down this
button depending on if I want to just
map one key or if I want to do a macro
if I want to program a marker I press
that and you know and press that then I
just press keys then we am done I press
that again then then it's set in the
firmware you know so you know so that's
about you know programmability you know
you can check out my website that you
are out there and now let's go back to
that Amazon model okay four layers
customer configuration so this this
keyboard as far as I know it does not
have driverless programming so if when
you want to prep when you want to
program this keyboard you have to launch
their software's usually core driver
software you know you don't your
software then you you know click around
then say save then it's saved in the
keyboard memory so it's not you know
it's the it's not the best okay but but
it's it's it's reasonably good
so let's go back to my my blog now
remember I need to write a page about
these right now remember I just saved a
picture before now I can call this
command look at the left panel okay
that's some move image file let's say I
choose a directory okay
and that's my file name and this is
called what's the name what should I
name it kulit wrong one-handed Marco
okay so I'm gonna name it KO e KO le RTO
and keypad okay let's say our GP key bad
okay so now look at the look at my blog
whoa look isn't that beautiful
be so wonderful careful colorful
and logical okay then put the Amazon
link here and let's make it good there
it is basically that that's how I do it
that that's the that's essential
you know but usually you know if I'm you
know what usually I have to do is I go
to my keypad page and I have to actually
put a here so you know let's do that so
copy that copy that whoops copy the URL
switch back to Emacs hey sir you are
here make a link make a paragraph cut
this block go back to the link location
open it and go pitch down depends on
where do I want to put it it's like okay
I probably gonna put above this okay and
it's such for smart y'all okay for the
cruiser there paste it
cut this and do move one block up pace
it and the change it to Kol Oh yeaaaah
tio and okay and view in browser page
down page down you see that's good that
that's good
now I need to update the date now this
phase is last updated on 2018 1012 Ted
October 29th now look at my left panel
look one two three Fiji's and it's
because ha Southside update article
timestamp now looking browser 2019 April
1st good and this is this is not April
1st joke so that is it for this topic or
one more thing one more thing is I just
go to Esau ok let me show this go to
Esau are interactive a brief then
it give me a bunch of choices each one
of them is a or brief so I just pick the
first one I think now it expands to that
enter
then you know I noticed if you if I say
the word if I say this word if I say
this word Google we are actually stop
streaming for like two seconds or so I
noticed that you know let me try that
again
I mean you know let's try that so if to
see if Google actually take that few
second away for example I'm going to say
this was okay I'm going to say okay I'm
going to say these phrase and you guys
tell me if you cannot you can hear it oh
you know you you know oh it it oh if
there's some cut of two seconds okay I'm
going to type my password okay so okay
close that so did you guys actually here
I mean here did Google cut out a few
seconds or something hey George hey
Danielle
George George where are you from George
I forgot oh you are from Australia
so John John someone he said love white
missile away a slot on in tera is about
zone so that's that's about key ball
it's so is there any questions about
keyboard let me know okay so let's see
how many people are six watching and
let's go to the next topic then save
that and let's go to the next topic
let's do okay let's do the Python one
then guys are you here type something
guys
let's see
hello hello
okay let's shall we do the next one to
the Python then converting Python to a
web crawler
oh my god is stuck am I stuck
hello guys say something say something
say something say say like something to
let me know let me know I'm like alive
and self how asdf that's great hey
Michael
so I guess okay so next topic we're
gonna do Python so Danielle says I have
a I have a 120 Kucera
$120 kasi RGB Cherry MX keyboard
and RGB was amusing for like five
million so okay so yeah you know I
noticed that there is like a 10 second
delay almost a five-second delay the
moment I say something and the moment I
see myself you know video yeah anyway so
um so did you guys hear when I talked
about
this
so anyway so let's do it the Python then
web crawler so this is a Python web
crawler and I'm going to I need to
convert it to Python 3 so first of all
so so this is my blog and you know it's
like it's like 50 lines so the code is
here and now look at I press one key and
it moves the code there but okay before
I do that and do I'm going to update the
date the date is the date is here I'm
going to go command update the date also
makes a backup then I press one key and
it moves the Python code to a window
here okay and let's try it it won't run
because I don't have the library I don't
have the library beautifulsoup installed
but let's just run it anyway let's see
run yeah no match your name the
beautiful soup you know you know Python
is very fairly you know it's kind of
annoying so so I do have okay does
anyone know how to install beautiful
soup like quickly I mean because I used
you know the Python you know installing
module is very confusing
hey Israel that's a guy we talked about
earlier he's gonna join me tomorrow and
talk about culture so do we have do we
have Python programmers
oh okay so let's
pick well let's see hold on a second
yeah there's you know Python virtual
environment you know so I wrote this
article like in 2014 and the different
method you know installation of module
is very confusing I think it's still
kind of so today
so there's PIP there's easy install as
far as I know easy install is kind of
long outdated it's a mess you know so
people don't use that
however easy install is already
installed on my Mac you know it's like
default you know it's that's that's no
good you know you should Python
shouldn't do that
so pip let's see if I have pip installed
which hip okay so I have PP installed so
how do I install it helped I just type
install how big ok ok let me try that
then God pip help is stuck ok so finally
pip install
so Israel you program in Python so let's
try night seems like Israel know what
he's doing okay I'm gonna let this now
if it crashes my up in system I blame
you okay okay let's do it
do it actually I mean I should have I
should have installed to my local
directory requirement already satisfied
beautiful soup for in yeah well I
have you see I have I have installed in
Python 3 let's forget about it then it's
just let's just try to convert this into
go back to my let's just try to convert
it into Python 3 okay so wait a second
so first of all I this to Python 3 okay
but what will happen is that when I move
this file into a fire itself it will
actually name the temp file as py 3 dot
py 3 and the and you see you see I moved
it out and when when the file name ends
in py 3 and when I run the file he'll
run you'll use Python 3 so that's why
you know that's one of the effect of
abusing the class Python 3 I mean this
is this is such t ml Mart so it's just
my own mod my own design so we are in
Python
let's do Python 3 so let's remove that
you don't need coding okay let's just
run it let's see if it works
run syntax error invalid ok obviously
because print any print statement now
needs to have
parentheses okay
now let's run it again but no much
you're named you are our lip oh my god
that's gonna be no matter named URL
live and I am using it yeah so what
did you are our live - change - oh God
so I don't think I can actually do this
smoothly because you know I I don't you
know because you know I don't code
Python every day so if you don't code it
you know for the past month you forgot
you have you know every time you do
something you have to kind of like spend
a lot of time to look into the dark and
stuff so Python - let's see No - our
live tomorrow has been split across
several modules in Python 3 named you
our Libya requests and you are our lips
arrow okay so two - three - okay so so
let's try - let's try the Python 2 to 3
tool now let me read the comments first
so Israel mostly program in PHP ok but
have done some Python I quit using Mac
because they missed a pip and couldn't
use it right hmm I mean I wouldn't blame
on the Mac for this particular case but
you know Apple is evil in many other
ways like thousands patents and
intentionally make your you know iPhone
slow whenever they have a new version so
that you know that's there's actually
illegal they are being sued for it in
Debian you can use people for Python 3
okay yeah so the neo says in other words
run a command in your console not in a
Python interpreter
what do you mean they lock they lock
down sudo well I mean I think that's a
good thing actually because you don't
want to install you know generally you
know I agree you know the opinion is
that you don't want to install whatever
Python or Perl you know whatever in the
system like use a user being okay in
UNIX you know the tradition of UNIX is
that you know when you have UNIX all the
binaries are in user ping or s ping okay
now SP is kind of a system critical
binary programs okay now user slash bin
is typically your perl your bash you
know the the the the big version of bash
your you know perl python and that's
usually in user ping now when you want
to install some other software let's say
:
that tradish traditionally on UNIX or
Linux is installed in user local pin so
the user local being you still need root
privilege to install things there but
that directories is intended to be you
know the user install software now this
this way is actually becoming out of
fashion since maybe ten years ago
because you see on each boot you know
privilege to install things here there
you know user local bean so instead
instead many many programs these days I
mean the the way to do it is that you
install whatever you personally install
in your personal directory you know in
your home directory so that's the way
that you the UNIX or Linux evolved you
know so but in Python when you use pips
or you know at least when you use you
know easiest or they still do the old
way you know they install to the user
local peeing or something
that okay yeah and I know as I see what
you're saying
Israel okay but anyway so let's get back
to Python so let's go to my my tutorial
I have a page about differences between
Python 2 and Python 3 and at the bottom
I talked about how to use the program 2
to 3 that convert it okay and we can try
to use that so let's go to Isha which
one second okay
Bryn show the window which two two three
okay
it's there now let's try to run it
two two three that wait a minute
whatever okay let's see what it did
original refactored you know the another
thing very annoying about Python is that
Python the guy dog person
he wants to pad you know theater in
lambda you know so where if your if your
code uses you know maps something lambda
you know - at least he it tries to
convert it to using a list comprehension
you know I don't want there you know I
don't want you to tell me you know which
way I supposed to be the better way you
know but but Python two to three does
that I noticed so anyway so so what did
it change so it says okay so this one is
changed to this one good I can accept
so let me magnify so this line is
changed to this line okay I can accept
and this line is changed
this line okay I can accept the Python
it iterate items each items is
deprecated
it's just items the I despise iterators
okay I talked about this in few few last
week or some few days ago about it
actually I never actually talked about
this specific issue about iterators you
know the concept of iterators and
generators in programming languages I
hate them okay and typically they are
they are they came from the Opie
background object-oriented programming
languages it's almost always is the Opie
languages like Java and Python has them
okay in functional languages you don't
have them why because it's stupid you
know but wiring or people because you
know because your language is lousy well
to put it nicely because you know that's
that's the oo P way of kind of thinking
then you need iterator so-called
iterators and generators very idiotic
idea
they are idiotic because they are not
they are like I what what I call
computer engineering side effect you
know it's like mathematically as a
programmer who whose job is to specify
algorithms the concept of iterators and
generators that only exist they are just
like int float turbo you know kind of
like reference kind of the byproduct of
computer engineering and and it's from
this stupid compilers C C++ programmers
they force this these available ideas
unto us programmers that that's what
they are it's controversial of course my
opinion this is controversial you may
not agree but maybe next stage morrow we
are are discuss this in depth you know
the iterator is constant
eateries iterators generators they are
stupid concept in this in the same way
as the concept of int float long double
those changes every five years you know
after five years oh we don't need you
know there's no longer turbo because
everything is already a double you know
if first of all you'll notice the
stupidity of this name stubble
why turbo because because you know
originally you have like one bite now
you have two bites so it's like turbo
you know but but it it refers to a type
of integer you know anyway and long and
you know and float when I what the
float what a float the boat like a
banana like a banana boat you float this
stupid programmers okay idiotic moronic
you know you so so this issue so so
these concepts are byproduct of computer
engineering but also another issue is
related to named me
you see naming or jargons is critical in
communication but these people stupid
hacker types they always have the worst
name possible one and the one of the
prime example is this float no turbo
long you know I mean you know look at
think about it there so if you tell
someone okay I have a type double if
he'd never studied for I mean angry
that's the see I mean what does it mean
turbo I mean why wait what what double
you know so that says again any anyway
so that's another topic so okay I
started to rent which is good because
because because you know I'm doing my
talk show and so why you know what what
does it make my talk show
you know valuable to at least some
people like you guys you know because I
have certain opinions that is not usual
you know that's you know that this
opinion czar not what you see every day
because if you I'm talking about things
you
do you know every day why are you here
right so sometimes I you know get into a
rant talking about some some things
that's you know I I feel you know the
different ideas that I don't see you
know elsewhere so yeah so let but let me
point out my some of my articles on
these issues you you know you you see
I'm like you know doing some advertising
advertisement for myself so if you look
at programming my programming block on
the side panel there's a panel about
jargons okay and it's open that and
there is a panel about semantic noodle
open that now if you go to chuggins page
is a collection of articles related to
naming and joggins you know and the
semantic noodle is collection of essays
about semantic related issues in
programming language and the and I
mentioned iterators okay high TEI okay
here's the article iterators enumerator
you know i yeah one thing i forgot to
mention is enumerator they almost always
exist only okie languages such as Java
in Java Java JavaScript to today and
Python you know its new in JavaScript
but anyway so this so on the surface you
know you know like I have this opinion
and someone challenged me you know
someone disagree and they challenged
challenged me they say iterators they
are great I mean they are just an
abstraction
you know programmers call abstraction
because abstraction you know so instead
of dealing with indexes of at least you
know you have iterators which is an
object so in some sense it's good
because it abstract away you know the
actual indexes you know so you have
these small pure
thing you to work with called iterators
so what do I say to that I thought about
it and I wrote out my reasons you know
why you know I'm trying to resolve kind
of a paradox or conflict you know like
why on my hand I think either is a
iterator is stupid but on the other hand
this idea of abstraction which is in
general generally good so it seems this
you know so it seems I'm in conflict
with myself so I'm trying to resolve it
and and the result of the is this
article basically basically what I'm
saying is that of course not all
abstractions are good you know you can
oh you can create abstractions for
anything like right now you know like
you know you can do obscure abstraction
for anything so not not all of them are
good and so the erasers I think they are
just wrong ones
so that's that so let's go back to the
Python 3 and it has changed my way did
it did it change okay it didn't change
actually fine down to two three what
what's the do I need option to say to
save I'm gonna read the comments seeing
of it so
okay let me read a comment I need to run
Python to do three and make it save to a
file
Oh W okay here so let's do that
right
okay I think that's great
he changed my foul its Rena seve a waltz
it's just done yet
what no modulename beautiful soup wait
what
I have beautiful through be installed
what's going on beautiful soup for maybe
okay let me read the comments w thank
you Israel okay so let's see so it's
awesome system so no peeps in so by
default to home OPP installed to the
home directory by default okay good to
know thank you
so the now says lots of open source
packages assume Python assume Python
refers to Python - yeah you know the
Python you know that like almost every
decision that I find them I can call
command to run this program but you
cannot tell it's Python two or three
I mean if theoretically it's possible if
you try to pass the file then you know
but but even mathematically you know you
can have a program that sports Python
two in Python 3 so it's actually useful
to have a different league you know
probably originated from this guy
doorguy you know because he wants you to
think there's only one Python
you know he he tries to like kind of
force some some type of ideology onto
you he want to maintain
like there's only one Python and all of
you should immediately you know switch
through Python three you know so every
decision you know everything in Python
is like that so I did talk about Python
you know in my past few weeks ago a week
or two ago like the whole hour is about
Python you know a guide oh those of you
might check out so anyway so let's see
yeah so for the record I do not agree so
Israel do not agree about iterators I
think that's a issue maybe you can
debate about that yeah so Danielle says
just call the script using something
like Python 2.7
yeah I think people want you for the
rent
okay iterators are generalization okay
teneo says iterators are a
generalization of the ETA r a sham
mechanism available but let's take
javascript an integrator is an object
with a darling yeah exactly yeah but I
don't think it's good you know actually
you know like if we talk about this I
mean it's because I mean I you know I
this is a controversial topic about a
computer language design you know the
issue about you know whether iterator is
a good concept you know III think it's
no good so I mean but please so it's
it's a debatable topic so I don't think
you know there's absolute correct answer
I mean even with this I mean like even
if we discuss it
there are many contexts like what do you
assume you know I mean you go you know
this many you know the other thing is
many design questions old questions in
general there's simply no one correct
answer I mean there are different
approaches or you know like most often
people assume there's like one correct
answer
you know yeah so I'm just giving you
different my opinions you know iterators
so anyway so let's run this and it says
beautiful sube is not installed this is
not correct
let's open a new file let's set to
python mod let's save it as X X dot py 3
and let's delete everything except
okay let's run this beautiful soup is
not installed but I think it is let's
see which pi3 okay
it's sing on a contra directory so go to
the directory go up a directory okay now
I need to print out the packages I have
installed and I have a tutorial here how
to do that please modules this modules
so list or available modules let's try
that curse curse curse and go back
vennett and this is a know another know
anything please wait a moment while I
gather a list of all available modules
you know I'm programming Perl in Ruby in
Mathematica the emag I've never seen a
closure and you know scheme list racket
I've never seen a program that tells me
when I want to list modules it tells me
please wait
it only happens in Python you know
what's going on but you know I so I
don't understand why
I Python colonel
it's still running god this is taking
you know so does anyone know why is that
when you do these modules Python takes
forever I mean I never heard any other
languages to do that
yeah generators and iterators yeah
you're interesting so does any one know
why paidamma Josey always like take a
long time to list and I got a bunch of
oh my god I just installed on a contra
thing and I ran it last time I don't
remember it's you know
oh this okay I don't I don't I try to
such beautiful soup it's not there but
okay so I don't think it's the reading
module documentation and this modules
function variable names using module
he's immature
import function names for module default
module module search path let's do that
I want to print the module search path
okay let's go back here
okay so soup there it is beautiful soup
soup
so why why is it
okay so beautiful soup is not there any
I mean it's not
ayyyy Oh si I don't know what is that
side packages leaps dynamic load okay
soup beautiful okay it's not there okay
so the problem I think is with beautiful
soup I thought it's already installed
okay I guess I possible so any
suggestions on what to do beautiful soup
okay and so far we have found these are
my load path for modules and let's try
to print the modules again see what they
are this is gonna take a long time again
okay that's I'm not
wait this is this is strange because I
just installed on a contra 3 and that
the whole thing is like - chica bites
it's supposed to have everything
included I'm pretty sure beautiful soup
is part of it on a contra you know it's
got to G guard
you know 2.5 gigabytes so why what why
not it's not there
beautiful soup for okay they change the
name is that true let's go get
now the Python module name is there a
convention for capitalization
let's just try that
okay let's copy that paste it save that
then let's run this let's just try
different things no this is this is
trial and error coding
yeah
this is no good
okay Thank You Israel
[Laughter]
you know okay I am gonna grant again you
know come you come you know I'm gonna
rent again
you know the Python Python has these
syntax okay from something imposed
something where um let me just rent
let's see if that works let me just run
it or not okay thank you Israel it works
I'm gonna rant about these syntax form
something import something okay
yeah let's let's do that yeah I'm gonna
advance you know it's rent so you see
Python has let me just see spin so
Python is this syntax this for example
compare compare from let's say FF Lib
okay let's say X Y Z versus Python mod
okay versus import okay let's say these
two statements you know when you import
the XYZ let's just say X okay when you
import X this this part is the variable
that the library is named okay now when
you have this syntax if something for
from something in for something this
variable well I got confused yeah so so
when you have this syntax from something
let me write it this way I think that
that's that from something in for
something the import something has
different semantics then the import
something there you see what I mean so
that means when given a piece of syntax
like a piece of string like this one
like the first line depending on where
you put it depending on the adjacent
string
the meaning changed you know that's what
I call context-dependent
semantics I don't you know yeah I don't
think it's a good thing it's a bad thing
so I I try to avoid so that's one of the
rent rent related to this issue but
anyway this worked thank you
Israel so let's get back to let's get
going with the let's get going with the
this but also you know since this works
in I mean what way why should we do the
any anyway let's do it let's run it it's
walking finally it's working so that
concludes you know the the the the main
thing I'm doing today I mean the you
know one of the topics so finally it's
works but why is it so so it's finished
oh looks like now github started to it
stops you from calling out the github
because I don't remember I have put a
stop to this let's try it again so I
think github process one you are while
true yeah I think github maybe try to
prevent people from calling now
where's my Cola okay here so now let's
put the code back show in browser okay
back to me max syntax color it showing
browser okay that's it that's a that's
it for this but offline I'm going to
walk out some of the details like you
know refactor cling of the code and make
it you know make it quo like it used to
you know sin you know we turn a bunch of
links you know it's that's what quoted
us but I think maybe github you know
figure out maybe to see if maybe github
did something to prevent quoting so that
that's it for the you know two to three
conversion you skip map hot github yeah
well I mean that's the open source you
know issue right I mean yeah if you are
a big fan of open source you want to use
key lab but but github yeah that's
that's an entire new topic what about
the thing is it's just not practical you
know a lot of things are github you know
now you see so I mean if I take your
suggestion then I'm going to spend a few
hours I mean literally it's gonna be
like almost a whole day to put my stuff
to give up then I have to tell all the
people how I you know it's gonna take
like a full time one day more than one
day I'm gonna update all my Emacs
repository then I have to tell friends
you know things change
then people is gonna ask me you know
because I used to where's your link you
know I have to talk about it then the
thing is then the next year kidnap is
you know powered by Microsoft you know
it happens all the time because when
there's money if you are the author of
key lab tomorrow microsoft says hey
we're gonna give you ten millions you
know you're gonna do it you know because
you know that's your food you know
then then Kela becomes you know
something else then oh you know the
cycle happens over again you know this
happens in the past you know thirty
years yeah but you know I actually I
don't you skip much I mean I don't use
all the tools in details I only just you
know you know use it very simply so I
hope that okay that's it so so the first
Nicholas so I hope that's fun to watch
to see is it good
are you still here Nicholas so maybe
that's it for today yeah we been talking
over so Israel again I shall see you
tomorrow and let me I'm going to try the
software like England our I'm going to
try the software you suggest it and
hopefully tomorrow I'll have you on the
show you know we talked about a little
bit culture around where you live
something like that probably yeah
and I'll see you guys tomorrow
I think maybe I'll go have a pizza okay
yeah we'll walk it out Israel so thank
you guys for coming see you tomorrow bye