Hello guys. Hello guys. Good morning
everyone. Welcome to another episode of
talk show. My keyboards this is UHK80
ultimate hacking keyboard. This is Nia
track ballboard. Okay we are going to do
uh advent of code. Okay, let let's
switch uh to my um
my browser and my code my Emacs code.
So, we are going to do advent of code
day 7 part two. In the past month, we
have done advent of code 2025. Lots of
them. Uh check out my YouTube. And so,
last time about two days ago, we did day
seven. And so today is part two. So you
got this um beam from the above then
they got split. The last time the
problem was to find out how many times
it splitted. Okay. So this is the input
and today. So so and let's go to today.
Advent of code. Okay. Advent of code
2025 day seven part two in wufam
language. So let's start wuam language.
If you don't know already wuam language
is the most advanced programming
language by a magnitude it is a term
rewriting system very different from all
other languages even has lisp. Okay. So
there it is. Wuam language. Uh start a
new notebook. Evaluate three. Shift
enter to start the kernel. Kernel is the
engine. So Wuam language has a kernel
and uh the the and the front end. So
it's different from all the languages.
So you have two parts. The kernel is the
engine. It does all the computation. the
front end which is you have notebook or
you can run it in terminal uh woof
script.
So that's a front end every time you
evaluate something it sends the input to
the kernel and the kernel send back the
output then the the front end display
it. So this is like how wam language
works.
So you can see start kernel quit kernel
you can have actually you know hundreds
of kernels parallel computation and
things like that.
So wam language we we did a lot intro
okay just go to one one of my website
kasali.info info. Okay, I'm language for
programmer. There are hundreds of
articles and full tutorial and videos
we've done before
uh for example, you know, so lots of it.
Okay, so we just going to go back go
back uh and and also download. Okay,
search for wam language for
programmers.info
my name. Then you'll find the download
link on wam language uh wam research
website developer wufam.com. Okay. Uh so
you can download it for free for
personal use.
Uh read their license agreement. Okay.
Good morning. Good morning Cortez. Hello
Cortez. Hello to your country. Lovely.
Um so language. So uh yeah code. Yeah,
let's start coding. Do we have
everything? Yes,
[clears throat]
so play at speed two. Okay, this is
probably boring for most of you guys. Uh
but if you like to learn something about
wam language, you might learn something
here. Okay. Uh yeah, we need to go to
advent of code uh day seven. Okay. So
day seven
uh do we have part two? So let's see
part two. Okay. So we need to copy it
part two. Okay. Let's just copy and read
it in Emacs because at advand of a code
they have lousy website design. That's
my discord by the way. Uh so advant of
code you go to their website you see
they are fixed layout
so if you have large font you then you
have to scroll right left very bad okay
advent of code so let's go to so here's
today's uh page search for txt so uh
advent of code problem description and
now we're just going to uh part two
Okay, good.
And uh paste it here. Okay, let's see.
[clears throat]
Okay. Uh
now the Emacs right now cuts the word in
the middle of the word. So I don't want
that. So I want to set a um word wrap. I
want to I want it to wrap at the
boundary of word.
So I forgot what's the command. So let's
search for it. Uh insert word toggle
word wrap. Okay. Space
space and space edge. Okay. Now that's
much better. So with your analysis of
the manifold complete, you begin fixing
the teleporter. However, as you open the
slide of the teleporters to replace the
broken manifold, you are surprised to
discover that it isn't classical
manifold. It's a quantum tac manifold.
Jesus.
[laughter]
Okay. Quantum tachio manifold. With a
quantum tacium manifold, only a single
tachium particle is sent through the
manifold. Okay? They don't split. So
it's quantum. So you have a beam. Now
remember, you have a beam going down
from above.
Then when it
collide with one of the correct
character, it split into two. Okay? But
now it doesn't split. So with quantum
tachium manifold only a single tachium
particle is sent through the manifold. A
tachium particle takes both left and
right path of each splitter encountered.
Okay. They they still split. Since this
is impossible the manual recommends the
many words interpretation of quantum
tachian splitting. Each time a particle
reaches a splitter, it's actually time
itself which splits.
It's actually time itself which splits.
What does that mean? This is um
it's actually time itself. This is
nonsensical English. Now is it correct
grammar? It's actually time. It's
actually
time itself which splits. Okay. Don't
know in one timeline the particle went
left and in another in the other
timeline the particle went right. Okay.
To fix the manifold, what you really
need to know is the number of timeline
active
after a single particle completes all of
its possible journeys through the
manifold.
>> [clears throat]
>> To fix the manifold, what you really
need to know is the number of timelines
active
after a single particle completes all of
its possible journeys through the
manifold. Okay. So let's consider just
one particle beam.
So number of timelines
active
What does that mean? The in the above
example, there are many timelines. Okay,
for instance, there's the timeline where
the particle always went left. Okay, so
you got into a multiverse situation.
Something like that.
Let's go faceless. Hello. So, it's
probably going to slow, you know, I'm
going to try to be fast because I don't
know in two hours. I hope I hope less
than two. I hope one hour I can finish.
Okay. I really need to get going. Okay.
So, so the above. So, there are many
timelines. For instance, there's a
timeline where the particle always went
left. Okay. So, it went left. Okay.
Yeah. Yeah.
Made sense. Yeah. Or there's a timeline
timeline
where the particle alternated going left
and right at each splitter. Okay. So it
went left then it went right. Okay.
Okay. Or there's a timeline where the
particle ends up at the same point as
the alternating timeline
but takes a totally different path to
get there.
Okay. So basically in this example it
went left and left and left and right
and right and left and right. ends up at
the same position. [sighs]
In this example, in total, the particle
ends up on on 40 different timelines.
[clears throat]
What what does it mean? 40 different
timelines.
Uh
so it means the
so every time you encounter a splitter
you have a choice of left and right.
So are you saying just how many
encounters of the
splitter?
Total possible encounter of the
splitter. Is that right?
Apply the many apply the many words
interpretation of quantum tachion
splitting to your manifold diagram. In
total, how many different timelines
would a single tachium particle ends up
on?
Now, what does it mean the timeline? You
seems
there's a confusion between timeline and
position
with a single takian particle ends up
on. So
in this example in the given input
simple example input it's saying that
basically the answer is 40.
Okay, it's saying basically for this
input the answer is 40. Now where does
that number come from?
Okay. So let's let's let's read what
does it mean timeline.
Have you guys done this problem?
So we need to read again. So
okay. So what the
quantum tachon quantum tachon manifold
single tachium particle is sent through
the manifold.
Okay.
So it does not split.
A tacium particle takes both the left
and right path of each splitter
encountered.
But since this is impossible, the manual
recommends the many words interpretation
of quantum tachon splitting. Each time a
particle reaches a splitter, it's
actually
it's actually time itself which splits.
idiotic
twisted
semantics.
time itself which splits.
Does does that mean time like the here
the word time does that it records the
time it happens
and then which split or does that mean
it records which way it went through
like multiple
meanings
and actually it's actually as if nerd
speaking it's actually time itself
time itself means you record what time
it occurred
and which split. So it measures the time
it occurred and it also measures which
way it went.
Doesn't make sense.
In one timeline the particle went left
and in another timeline the particle
went uh right.
In the above example, there are many
timelines. For instance, there's a
timeline where the particle always went
left.
Okay. So, I think
Okay. So, okay. So his word in this
advent of code the word the timeline you
should read that as in one universe
situation like of the multiverse like
one of the possibility
they call it timeline perhaps this is in
sync with the multiverse
science fiction or something they call
it timeline so a timeline is basically
ically just one of the possible universe
I suppose that's what it means then if
so then then it makes sense so this is
one of the possible situation this one
okay
so let's see for instance there's a
timeline where the particle always went
left okay or there's a timeline where
the particle alternate going left and
right or there's a timeline the particle
ends up at the same starting position
ition. Okay.
So he is saying that in this example
he's saying that given this input there
are total of 40 possible universe.
Okay.
40 possible universe.
>> [clears throat]
>> Okay. Apply the many words
interpretation of quantum tachons
splitting to your manifold diagram. In
total, how many different timelines
would a single tachon? Okay, I
understand the problem.
Okay, save it. Close it.
Uh shall we start to code? I guess uh so
far I have no clue what is going on. I
mean I know I understand the problem but
but I have no clue.
Okay. So let's uh today's talk show day
seven. No
today talk show day seven part two.
Okay. and start. Um,
you got
you got a uh input something like that.
Okay. So
it's it's um so I don't know.
So this is our input.
So every time it encounters a splitter
you have two possible positions.
Remember the problem is to count how
many total possible universe. So every
time you encounter a splitter you have
two possible positions.
God this requires thinking this problem.
So
here you got you know
so you want to ask the question is how
many possible universe okay let let's
write some description
analysis of the problem Okay,
got a beam.
Okay, now they don't call it beam. They
call it particle instead because of the
quantum mechanics. The beam, the light
beam versus particle duality, something
like that. I don't understand. Few
people do. So B. So you got a particle.
Uh
I don't have a shortcut for that. That
that needs to be fixed.
Particle. Okay. Article. God. That needs
to be fixed. Okay. You got a particle
[sighs]
at the top.
It flows down each time it encounters
a splitter.
It may
move to the left or right. Okay,
something like that.
The question asks
how many total
possibilities
in the end basically.
So let's think about one situation. So
So okay. So now let's write as we go.
Write my thoughts.
So in each instance
this is problem analysis. Okay. This is
how I my brain works
so to speak.
Each in each instance
a particle. Okay. So let's fix the
particle thing. Okay. OPQR.
So you need a word for particle because
it is used in physics. particle and in
fixed physics academic scientific
subject
which I write a lot about. So I want a
brief for it.
Spell check particles. Is that correct?
Yes. So we got a brief eval. Evalow it.
Close it. Now you got article. Okay.
Fantastic. So in each instance a
particle
um
in of time
there
may be n particles. Okay, this is
important
and each has a position.
Okay.
In each instance of time of time there
may be um let's see
now let's
focus on a single article.
When it runs into a splitter,
it
may go left or right. So that means it
adds two possibility
to the existing number of possibility.
Okay.
So you begin so you begin with a number
of possibilities
with a state
number uh
okay you need to name that state in the
code. So what's a short name?
Uh so according to the advent of code
they would call it
number of timelines
but I don't want that because it's
confusing with time which is confusing
with time and space continum
which is
physics. Okay.
So
there's my pen. So so we begin with a
state number of possibilities. Okay.
Then
then we need another state and uh this
would be
number of particles
and their positions.
Okay, we need that.
So as the beam go down, we start with
number of possibilities. So when it
begin is it zero? Yeah, zero. Okay,
let's use a mix of programming language
syntax here. Okay. Start with zero and
uh and uh so
uh position is equals to five something
like that. Okay. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8
starting position. Okay.
Then so we got two states now. These two
states. Okay.
Now each time the particle goes down,
you change the position and you change
the
state. Uh I mean you change the number
of possibilities you add
like one two then here one two one two
so
in each
row flow in each flow. Okay. In each
flow
of a row, this always
this may increment
and always by just two.
Is that right?
Number of possibilities.
No.
So we do we count so the number of
positions. So you see this complicated
scenario because according to the story
you only deal with one particle
but what we are doing uh is that we may
track several particles
several particles and they may they
split. Okay, they may split.
So they may just go down or they may
split.
Okay, go down or they may split. Okay,
so
so basically in each time you go to the
next row,
you find the new positions of the
particle. So several particles. So you
are tracking all possibilities in one
shot. And every time you encounter a
collision,
you increase for each collision, you
increase the number of possibilities by
two.
I believe that's it.
Okay. I believe that's it.
Is there a people here? Six people.
Okay. Is that right? Yeah. Okay. Say
something. Okay. I think let's start to
code. Show in browser.
analysis of the problem. Okay, this is
our preliminary thought and so far
since we already have code from last
time I don't think this is too
difficult. Okay, but who knows maybe we
we we maybe our analysis turned out
wrong or something. Um but I think it's
correct. Okay, so let's think about to
make sure. So we begin with a state
number of possibilities start with zero.
In each row, in each flow of a row,
basically we go through the rows. We
loop the function or the function
through the rows.
So this may increase. So this may not
increment. Okay, wait.
um
uh
increase and always increase by two.
Okay.
per
per collision
uh
by two per collision. Okay.
Yeah.
Then we need another state number of
particles and their positions like last
time. Okay.
Then the algorithm,
the argo is just
write a function
and loop it through the
rows and
update the states.
The final solution is
the solution is
number of possibilities. Okay.
Yeah.
Okay. Let's begin. Let's begin it.
Okay. So, let's start code. The first
thing is to turn it into a uh uh uh row
and matrix. This is last time. No, we
don't I don't want that code. I mean I
want a different code
solution code. Yeah. So uh
yeah. So that that was like example. So
what I want is this.
Okay. So first of all we turn it into a
matrix
string into matrix and turn the dot into
zero and uh the splitters into one.
Okay. And total split this is a
variable. This is a state we need to
change.
So before we are tracking the total
number of split each time it splits into
two.
So how how how are the problem
different?
So last time total split is 21
uh and the final state is nice. So it's
interesting I mean the final number of
beams is nine
but now so how is total split different?
So every time you split
so every time there's a collision
you increase the total split. Yes. You
see,
every time there's a collision, you
increase the total speed. But today, you
just
times two. Is that right?
I hope it's not that trivial. Let's see.
Collision collide list.
Yeah, collide list is a list of
positions
that collide happens. So the length of
collide list is basically the number of
them and you just multiply this by two.
Would that uh do it?
Yeah. Because each time whenever it
collides it has two possibilities. So
two
times
would that would that be that trivial?
40. Let's see if it's 40. run it.
If it came out 40, we solve this in in
one second. [laughter]
42. Let's see what is the Okay, it says
[clears throat]
40 different timelines.
Okay, but my answer says 42.
So there is something
something wrong with the logic. Let's
think about what is it. So last time we
wanted to track the number of
collisions.
So the beam split into two. But this
time
So how is it? Oh
god.
You see this is really kind of tricky.
So you see the trick in this problem
part two [clears throat]
is about in interpretation
because every time you only deal with
one single beam so you are going into
multiverse situation. So when you have
two beams that merge.
Okay. So God, you need to think about
this problem. Uh
this is like a thinking problem. Now
it's not a coding problem. It's thinking
problem.
Do you guys know what I mean? Do I make
sense?
This analysis of the problem.
Okay. So, so what what is the difference
between collision and uh and the
multiverse?
So when you collide you split into two
two possibilities you add it but however
you see let's say the in this rows in
this situation
you got two splitters
so let's say you know you got two beams
above above them so here you got
so let's look at example okay so Let's
see.
Put it back. Okay. Let's see your
example.
So, let's see if you have a beam,
right? You got the beam.
Oops. What?
Wrong key. Okay. So let's say you got
that situation
then
uh what
then what you have is um
then
if if you have multiple beans going at
the same time then you got that
situation.
Now in the previous problem you count
total number of collisions. So that's so
that's one two you added two collisions.
Okay. But but this time you are counting
the possible multiverse.
So this beam if we track this beam this
particle it has two multiverse.
And if we track this particle, it has
two multiverse,
right? So what what so we have to
understand what the
so in total do we have like three
multiverse or four
So when when the multiverse position is
the same, they don't count. Okay. So
when the it's the same, they don't
count.
So let's see. Collision. Collision.
So when the multiverse
is in the same state, do they count?
They don't count. I I think they don't
count because otherwise our code would
be correct.
So that means every time you collide
then you have new positions of the
particle.
You want to count
Oh, you want to count the new positions
of the particle,
new possible positions of the particle.
Okay, that's what you count. So, instead
of total here,
let's go back. Let's I think maybe we
solved it by trial and error. We just
like
you know like um so this is the
important state. So it was total split.
So we multiply by two that's uh for each
collision we counted twice. That's not
right because
we want to count only the new the number
of new positions.
Okay. So this total split let's change
the name let's change it to uh
total state total universe. Okay. So
change like like um
total total multiverse.
Does that make sense? May maybe not.
Total.
So the total multiverse would be not not
just times two but the number of new
positions.
So what is the number of new positions?
That would be
our code is fantastic because we can
just use this code. Let's see.
This this is the total number of
positions. Okay.
Returns a new beam state.
Okay. So this this is the um this is the
thing.
Okay. So now let's write a uh width
and see
beam state
row state I mean row so what we do is we
write the new function
If
collide is zero, no collision, then
nothing happens, right? That's right.
But if some collision happened, then you
want
this thing.
New beam state equals to that that that
that that. Okay. Then
you will return the new beam state. But
meanwhile
you want to
um
you want to say total multiverse equals
to total total multiverse plus the
number of new beam state.
What? Yeah. Wait.
Yeah.
Okay. So that is the side effect. So we
don't want this anymore. That's uh
that's a number of collisions. Okay.
Okay. If we do this um can we just run
it? Yes, I think so. So let's just run
it. Okay. So let's see. Make sure one
more time with
new beam state. Yes. Yes. Yes. Just run
it.
40. Beautiful.
[laughter]
Fantastic code from last time. Helps.
So, put it back. Syntax color. And uh
this this is a example of um
let's uh yeah that those are thinking
examples. Okay. So let's do it.
So let's see analysis of the problem
and blah blah blah and we thought about
that that and here is a solution.
solution needs to have a its own
uh input.
Okay,
that should be code. Okay, don't want
text. So, and here and create a new
section
solution
paste. Okay,
fantastic. And our answer is 40. Now,
does it work for our personal input?
The toy input solution is 40. That's
correct. Okay, let's try our personal
input. Paste.
Pop it out. and uh search for text
at the end of code day seven input.
Copy. Close.
Go to our code. Close. Go to our code
there. Select or paste.
Uh make sure it's Yeah. Run it.
So, our answer is 3158.
Is it correct? I'm pretty I'm I'm 99%
confident. Okay. Paste it. Submit.
That's not the right answer. Your answer
is too low. Oh
God,
[laughter] my answer is too low. It
says,
"Yeah, but it works on the personal
input." Let's see. Uh, let's try the
personal input again. It
says 40.
Now, what is the nine? Nine is a new
state. Okay. The total number of
particles in the end is nine.
But uh
okay this uh god
but our new pos
if we work on the personal input then it
is wrong.
What why is that
total multiverse?
Okay, you got B185
and you got 87 there. Okay, you can copy
it and go to wir language select or
paste
is a code and you can shift enter
and the wir language says it prints all
the output the debugging information.
Um
then at the end it says 3158
and at the end of code says it's
incorrect.
Uh so
so something is wrong.
What is uh wrong with our analysis?
beams split. So when they split,
you count the position, right? You count
it. We count the length the
length of the beam state.
Multiverse total multiverse equals to
total multiverse plus
length of the new beam state.
So new beam state. So before so look at
this line
it's got two particles. Now it's got
three.
So this two this two. So
yeah,
so so okay so two two
so the new number of state is three
I mean the the possible multiverse let's
see one two one two when the multiverse
is the same they don't
do they count.
You don't they don't count, right?
Because otherwise it's just double the
collision.
Okay. I'm I'm kind of not
excited to work on this because
it requires me to think like I just have
to think about this problem.
Uh, it's interesting though, but
probably very boring for you guys. Is
that right? Okay, nobody's here now.
Uh
or there's a timeline where the particle
ends up at the same point as the
alternating timeline
but takes a totally different path to
get there.
Oh, okay. So you want to count the total
possibilities in the end.
Right? No. What? 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11
12 13 14 15.
No. No. That cannot be right because
there are only 15 total space. So your
answer cannot be 40.
You know the particles ends up on 40
different timelines.
The article ends up on 40 different
timeline timelines.
You see I don't understand the problem.
Oh, so the the question is you want to
check how many total path
is it? The multiverse. The
question is just how many total path
how many total possible path.
So the question
okay I think okay
uh
okay now I think the question is about
how many total
possible
path
from top to bottom.
Okay, I think that is the question
instead of the multi-verse
and timeline
The question is simply how many to how
many possible path
each one is a path. How many total
possible path?
So the question
so the code will be very different from
part one. The question is simply how
many total possible path. Does that make
sense? Make sure that is the right
understanding.
So
yeah. So but they call it timeline.
Okay. They call it timeline.
Each multiverse, each universe, possible
universe is one timeline.
But
we can think of this is just one
universe. It's just how many total
different path
it is possible. Okay. So if we if that
is the problem then what you do
and then what you do is use um so we
don't have a nice picture like that.
Okay. So if that's a problem, if the
problem is just how many possible path,
then how do you do? What do you do? So
you
you go down, go down,
go down possible path.
So again you have a accumulated
state. Okay, you begin with a zero, you
add to that each each time you go down a
row. Okay, so when you encounter a
collision,
you have left and right choices. So you
increase that by two.
Okay. And if there's no collision, then
nothing happens. Okay?
Is that right? If there's no collision
uh you don't do you increase the path
no. So only when you encounter a
collision
then you have
two possible uh path.
So again every time you have a collision
your possible path choices
increase by two. Okay.
So, what do what if you have here
increase by two?
But okay, here's the thing. Whenever
there is a merge
you see whenever so you see these two
obstacles these two splitters
it split two beams into three.
However the middle one is merged. So
whenever there is a merge you want to
decrease
the
possible path by one. Okay.
So whenever you encounter a splitter you
increase the possible path by two. But
whenever there is a merge, you decrease
the possible path by what?
Something like that. I think I think I
think that's
okay. We try this.
When a article encounter is splitter
increase
possible path by two. But when
there is a particle merge
decrease
by one. Okay, that's what we do. Okay,
now let's just go to our code.
Uh, let's go to the short code code. So,
cut.
So, instead of total multiverse, it's
just say total path.
Okay. So this time you
total path you don't want that. Okay.
You want it to be
let's see
color that cur that color that okay so
you got uh collide list there so
two times
x collide list whenever Whenever you
have a collision, you increase it by
two. But however, whenever you have a um
you have a merge. Let's see. New beam
position. Let's see
new beam position. One, two, three.
Let's look at the old picture. The old
picture kind of helps
wait
the Okay, you basically all you do is
you take the pos the count of the new
number of beans
minus the previous count. That's it.
That's a that's a new possibility you
added.
That's it.
Okay.
So, so don't do this. Don't do this
increase. You just all you have to do is
take that out. Uh total path. Take this
out. Here is your witch. And here you
add a statement
like side effect
where you say the length of the X new
beam total count of that minus
the length of
previous beam state.
Okay. So that's your total path.
Fantastic.
Just run it. 40 please.
Now
wait. You you you do have to increase by
two. Okay. Wait.
Okay. Hold on a second. Where's the
color list? Okay.
Okay. So,
so two times that
then minus then min two times that. And
you want to um
total
number of path.
So let's focus on this line that will
help. Okay.
So suppose over here it's zero. Now in
this new row
it became
well over here it's let's say three. So
this here is
Oh my god, there is problem. One, two,
three, four.
Two, three, four.
New number positions.
Basically, you just count new number
positions.
Is that right? Do you just count new
number of positions?
Oh god, this needs to think. Uh,
well, you can't you can't just trial out
and error. You really just have to think
about the problem. So, I don't feel like
continuing
because
it's boring and you just watch me do
nothing.
Um, so what about if you pretend to be
the top
math Olympiad competitor, you know, like
figure out like this instantaneously?
Can I do that?
Yeah, that that takes uh kind of
mentality and concentration though.
I can try
So you want a total of possible path
to
so you got a number of total paths And
no one you got two
three four.
So that you you want okay so you want to
know
the new position
basically the number of new positions
Oh god.
You have to, you know, to really, you
really need to
like if I imagine I'm a math Olympian
like purely like just focus all your
might on this like quickly try to can
you see a what is the solution?
Yeah, you can. But that takes I don't
know if I can but I can try it. But that
takes tremendous amount of concentration
and I can't do YouTube you know. Well
what about meanwhile while you are like
online live stream can you try to do
that?
Yeah, but yeah, I could I could I could
try that gradually, but but
uh not prepared because I got, you know,
doing live stream and distractions.
So So let's think about this again. So
you know, it's just be very boring. It's
just because I you know this needs to
think
like how many people how many other
people like today
how many people are still doing uh adv
of code I mean 2025 I mean how many
people did it
are they and how much time they spend on
this it would be interesting to look u
But
okay. So, but um okay, let let me just
think about this a bit more.
You know a dumb solution is that you
just
you just keep you know each possibility
you keep it in a state. So you you
basically just brute force count all
possible like at the end you have you
know let's say hundreds of different
path from top to bottom
then you just compare remove the
duplicate then that's how you get okay
so that's a brute force way and in this
problem the the input is not too large I
think it can be done brute force way the
input is you know uh thousand let's say
so you have lots of combinatorial so it
maybe it's not
maybe it'll take too long okay I mean so
one way brute force is just you you just
do one path at a time
[sighs]
so but if you want to do them all at a
time can you like.
Okay. So,
when it's go down.
One, two, three, four.
So is it is it not just add the uh
like I don't understand
Is he not just And
I think um let's do this.
Okay, so let's do this. It's just
I don't know if that works, but let's
just try it. 29.
So, 29 is not correct.
Uh,
no.
something. Okay.
Okay,
I'll be back. Be back in five minutes.
Okay, let's see.
Okay. Not good. Not good. Not good.
Okay.
Be back in five minutes.
I probably going to quit.
Not walking.
[clears throat]
Let's try this quickly. I think um let's
try this. It should be just that.
Wait, is it just a new beam state? Okay,
so maybe that. Come on.
40.
[laughter]
So simple. Maybe that's the answer.
God. Okay, put this back carefully.
Now
cut, paste,
and paste
and uh and cut this
uh user input.
Paste there. Okay. And remove that. And
now run this custom input.
Okay,
run it.
3158.
That's the number I gave. It says it's
wrong.
Oh god.
Okay, I think I'm going to quit then.
It's not correct, man.
Why is it? I I don't know. But uh
each pass.
So remember, you do one thing at a time,
one particle.
So one particle at a time.
So when the particle got
you two new possibilities.
Okay. So whenever there is a collision
you got two new possibility
for each
but for each.
So
Stop this. It's I mean this is not going
to work out. I I
[snorts and clears throat]
Okay. Uh
where should I stop?
I don't know. Um,
I can stop it,
declare it a failure,
then I'm probably going to think about
it,
lie in bed or something. Then tomorrow
or or after tomorrow,
I'll do a live stream and finish coding
it. The problem is not coding. The
problem is thinking about the problem.
uh
like it's a bit it's a bit you know you
have to think about a problem it's not
even in the algorithm stage yet
once you know exactly
I mean we we we already understand the
problem the problem is like find all
possible path
right it seems trivial
uh but we don't No,
we don't have like approach yet.
Okay.
So, if I stop now, I declare a failure,
then you know, think about it, then come
back or
I can try to persist.
It might take one more hour
or even longer. But I can't, you know, I
can't stay longer though. I have to go.
My wife's coming back.
So if I persist,
you know, it might take half an hour.
Uh could possibly just 15 minutes. I
don't know. Could be an hour or more.
Then what uh benefit do I get? I mean
then I persisted, right? So this video
is going to be like 3 hours and
eventually I solved it.
Uh, so which way
should I be?
I think
I should quit
because it doesn't, you know, if I push,
you know, yeah, I can do it, you know, I
can probably
if I continue to for another two hours.
So I can continue to do that just so
that this video, you know, looks good.
I finished it in one shot, but
that doesn't do much, you know. Uh so I
think it's better
to stop.
Yeah. Then think about the problem. Then
come back, then give a nice summary.
Then just quickly finish it or leave it
unfinished
like we did. We we got some of the
problem like day three part two
unfinished.
Uh
kind of very annoying. And day five part
two. Okay. Yeah, I think I should quit
then.
Okay, bye guys. Bye guys.
Okay, so in summary, we didn't solve
this problem. In summary,
this problem seems to require more
thinking. We don't know. I don't know
what's going on. So, we didn't solve it.
We s we we have a solution for the p for
the example simple input. But when we
run that in our in our code, it fails.
Now, is that because
uh
is it possible uh new
uh input got screwed up or something,
you know? So it's so it's kind of
annoying that it gives the correct
answer on the
sample input but not on the personal
input.
Okay, bye.