today we are going to talk about these
topics these so you see a list of items
and anything you want to talk about you
just type it in a chat like type the
numbers I see it and we all have a go so
these these are the topics and just type
in a chat okay let me make some changes
well there's no need to make changes
just type in the chat and let's go
okay this window this window this window
0 watching again people come on
German 30 so so let's see the topics
okay we're gonna talk about Python tips
okay let's just start with that Python
tips and a contra you know if you are a
Python programmer you probably already
know but many of you are not you know
Python programmers so recently I inch I
installed this on a contra thing which
is like 2.6 bytes let's see and
Contra Python you know that's what a
stupid name that is you know it refers
to some kind of a type of Python some
species or something but okay anaconda
distribution but also it refers you know
some pop stars
black girl has you know a song of that
name and it's basically just showing ass
showing asses you know very degenerate
and I'll now come dry you know what what
a stupid name but anyway here's this is
a Python distribution it's a huge one
you know I downloaded the other day and
it's 2.6 megabytes in you know but it
does include everything you know Python
these days is kind of associated with
machine learning and wealth in data
mining and and associated with that is
statistics in math so you know Python
community you have all these kind of
thing tensorflow is google's AI engine a
library Jupiter is kind of a notebook
copied from Mathematica
let's see Jupiter Jupiter yeah let me
show you Mathematica well I talked about
that quite a few times so this is this
is Mathematica this is this is what
notebook looks like back in 1990 you
know this is a notebook so it became
popular these days you know from Jupiter
because they basically they implement
web-based interface the Jupiter Jupiter
notebook this is Mathematica notebook
you can see the Mathematica you can
include graphics animations and stuff so
let's see how many people are watching
hey guys so today's topic hey Alex
today's topic is going to be it's going
to be any one of these so pick a topic
and we'll talk about that just type type
the topic in the comment you know type
the number or type the topic
so I was talking about Ana contra an
account there is a Python distribution
it's huge it basically it includes
everything you know it includes numpy is
a numerical computation engine for
Python sigh PI you know I haven't used
any of these ciphers you know for
scientific computation and and they are
all Python packages what is pent pandas
by the way what are the others pandas
tasks
bokun hopeful view data shader and all
these I don't I don't know what they are
I only know tensorflow sigh pi numpy
Jupiter and I actually have not used any
of them so we do we have Python
programmers here say something say
something your comments direct the show
you know you tell me something you
comment on your opinions you come and
you pick a topic so anyway I was saying
on a contra ok yeah and I'll come Oh an
accountant not job and somehow I picked
up the R for some reason and I'll come
dad yeah so you know I think these are
more for the you know machine learning
kind of people I mean the scientific
tasks you know scientific programming
not really for industrial coding for
Python for example writing writing a web
server you know what
creating a website and so on but I mean
Python is these days used a lot for
machine learning for AI because of
Google you know essentially Google
single-handed you know the history of
Python is interesting well everything is
interesting but the history of Python is
that again pick a topic ok just type
type in a comment
I'll talk about it the history of Python
is that back in 2000 okay 1995 - let's
say 2000 back in 2000 the web is
becoming popular you'd begin to have you
know you you have eBay you have search
engines Google is not the popular one
year was Yahoo and hotpot and you know
some others you know back so back in
2000 the most popular languages are Java
and Perl these are the two top ones Java
Perl CC press basically these four are
the top four and impacting it's not like
today where when you you know working a
company you have to use lots of tools
and lots of languages usually more than
more than two languages but back then
each program you essentially in a job
you only use one language you know you
if you are a C programmer you just you
know to see your C++ or Java or Perl you
know yeah maybe pro and you know Java or
poor important C and so that's back then
so Perl
it's the most popular high-level
language it's like you know the the
thinking was I I mean it's going to be
Java and Pro is going to be the last
language you know the Java has a slogan
you know write once run everywhere and
today that is JavaScript that is
actually true for JavaScript but anyway
so pro is the only language essentially
almost the only high-level language and
Ruby and Python they were born later
than Perl they were like one year I mean
that invention we're talking about that
the date it's like the first version is
published so Perl pearl was there first
then after year or two you have Python
and Ruby but anyway they Python Ruby
didn't get popular Perl becomes you know
it's like I mean it's used in the whole
industry like nineteen nineteen ninety
five percent you know everyone yeah I
mean it's a that's the common that's
you know situation so pearl but however
pearl has a major problem because pearl
you know if you ever coded in Pearl you
know that pearl community and I mean the
Pearl language is very its syntax OOP
I think the syntax OOP originated from
Pearl was something like but anyway
pearl is like the most well known syntax
OOP they and the lab reward the guy who
created pearl he is a kind of a nut job
kind of type of guy he likes to create
sophistries you know he quotes slogans
you know laziness is the virtue of
programmers and so on you know he hung
up slogans every day and every program
attaches you know those slogans in their
signature you know back then there's a
signature I don't know if you guys still
know that like basically whenever you
post something online you have like you
know at the end you have like for
example Kasauli and then some funny
quote then your website you know that's
a signature you know so every yoke if
you look at back the web you know online
new scoops you'll see everyone has that
and then usually you have some Sun
Maxim's unquote some you know wisdom
like you know sometimes often it's for
example just another pearl hacker you'll
see that many way pearl is widely
popular and it's supposed to be like the
last language you know there's a core so
called you know swiss army of light
knife you know that's that's also a very
popular concept back then among
programmers like today's hacker news you
know today you go to hack a new so you
know dreaded you have this jog and
slogan oh machine learning oh you know
we need to do machine learning oh yeah
and you know date hot date data mining
you know the kind of so bad thing
it was perl you know and with you know a
whole bunch of jargons and every poor I
mean people are not like people are
serious like the average programmers
they think this is true I mean they
think this is a truth so anyway pearl
but Perl the problem with Pro is that
the syntax is
very complex I mean and actually that is
nature that is the library was the
intention he you know when when he
talked about pearls features you know
one of the thing he wants to mention is
like is that that person taxes like
English okay you know so you know pearl
you have lots of exceptions and lots of
you know weird things and he defended by
saying you know look at English you know
that's that's natural that's you know so
anyway Pearl's got this issue you know
very complex syntax so apparently a lot
of people you know just don't like that
you know even though they they don't you
don't see them you don't hear them often
because because all the online things
are wiped out by pearl people you know
because they are popular they spread is
you know programmer the virtue of
grammar is laziness and so so and so on
actually well since we are talking about
this concept yeah
pro is another topic you know it's it's
going to be how as I was talking on
pearl I was going to show you a book
signed by Larry war I know I went to the
conference Linux conference in 1999 so
back then you know open source just
began so Linux
leanness and Eric Tremont and Richard
Stallman in that reward they are they
are like the top figures and and also
the Java Java guy java guy Gosling
Gosling Gosling you know who created
Java
he also wrote Emacs by the way though
one of the earliest Emacs version anyway
so these people
yeah these four people you know are very
popular like they give they give talks
in conferences you know everywhere so I
went there and I have a book signed by
him
actually let's let's have have a look
sorry / books keep the comments got
coming guys
so sorry book so back then you know /
was my my I use pearl one of the
language that I know very well I read I
read okay I wrote this article / books
of survey I read all of them some of
them more than one time so and also the
/ documentation like / doc something I
read the entirety like you know a few
times so this book by the way at the
time I was carrying the book mastering
regular expressions it's published by
alrighty back then is also one of the
most famous popular book so I went there
and and I had him sign it you know -
brain power
Larry war you know there's more than one
way to do it yeah that's the most
popular slogan of Pearl you know the you
know so the people spread these things
and you can see that programmers do that
today as well like today
what are today's jargons you know
today's dragons are okay a few years
back then you have kiss you know like
keep it simple stupid and then you have
dry like don't repeat yourself you know
like this this this a you know
these are just you know slogans you know
always associated with the elite hacker
types okay let me read some comments so
I can see where I'm going
panda is for data analysis gives you
stuff similar to our oh okay great thank
you
I see pandas and when I'm using oak
pebble I also never needed Python
notebooks and I still want wonder if I
would ever need it oh yeah yeah oak
babble yeah indeed yeah since your if
you are using oak Mart and you know in
emacs
you don't need Python notebooks but
however oak Mart it's not so easy to
include you know images right and and
also animation that would be hard I
think
I mean wow that's the nature of Emax
because you have to you know you have to
know some Lisp and you have to like find
how to do this or that I mean on the
other hand I mean just just for
comparison for those who don't know you
know the Python notebook notebook is
like it's almost like IDE you know like
you don't have to be your hacker you
don't have to look oh how do you you
know what are the commands you know you
just open it and you know you can just
start to use it and and it can include
images and animation and headers you
know headers and subsections and so on
but yeah Oh glob Oh glob Oh glob oh it's
great so Alex Alex says I've been
performer until 2000 well okay you are
one of the early early guys like me so
we had problems with memory leaks in mod
Pro yeah that's I haven't heard that
word for a long time oh my god that
brings back memories smart oh you Apache
I remember I was doing you know I was
assisted me on Solaris and Apache is one
of the worst software in a world and
also Apache documentation is is the
worst period of ordered documentation in
the world Apache Apache documentation
and UNIX man pages is so alike alex says
another thing is code was not so easy to
read exactly Python was much better in
both and we switched and happy with that
yeah exactly so so back to Peru so I was
saying you know Perl syntax is pretty
pretty bad you know and so that's when
so Google Google began around that time
year 2000 I think it's technically in
1998 or something 1999 or something I
don't know but it became too you know
public became to be aware of Google
search engine back in around 2000 and
you know of course Google they need a
language right so they choose they
choose Java they choose Linux for
servers why because it's free
actually that's so that's essentially
the moon the most important reason
because it's free otherwise they have to
pay you know Microsoft you know that's a
lot money
so anyway Google choose Java job they
choose Java partly because the Larry
Page what's he like other guys Sergey
you know sir go and marry like they are
Stanford students and you know they were
learning Java you know that bad thing it
was also popular job I was taught in
universities so you know they know Java
so now obviously that's probably not the
only reason Google choose Java but as
their you know company's main language
but but also but but at least it's one
of the reason you know because you know
I started a company and I know this
language and I'm going to use it you
know so anyway Google choose Java and
Linux in and the other languages they
choose Python they choose Python instead
instead of Perl because apparently
because you know the Perl syntax is just
intolerable so it at that time job Java
is not well known I mean it's not you
know it's known in some subcultures but
you know it's not in white we know among
programmers but because of Google you
know Google becomes very big you know
they're around 2000 2001 you know they
they become very big then and of course
programmers always want to know what
language are you using you know so and
they are using Python so because of
Google's choices of Python that made
Python popular that that is a beginning
of the popularity of Python Python
becomes mainstream you know that's how
it became mainstream but but then even
up to 2005 you know in an industry Perl
is still there you know on the top
because because you know Pro is like you
know used every everywhere like the
that's the language I mean that's the
most people you know programmers who
consider that's the last line you know
the the the only the best you know
high-level language but anyway so as
time goes on the Perl kind of just died
for four reason that's hard to describe
in one sentence I think you know for
just like it's it's it's quite
fascinating and and and you know
surprising as well because you have this
language that's you know everywhere
spread by all these programmers you need
programmers UNIX UNIX hackers you know
UNIX philosophy and so on and then it
was you know on the top like almost like
you think there's no possibility for it
to go away but it went away
so anyway Perl so Python became popular
around let's say oops a pet Python
surpassed
Perl around 2006 in the industry for
example like if you look at job listings
around that time that's the time when
Python there are more Python you know
requirements than Pro and Ruby became
popular around 2008 or something because
of the ruby unveil that like one night
overnight shots Ruby to the roof you
know so everyone is like everyone is
talking about Ruby on Rails we need to
do this you know we need to use Ruby on
Rails Ruby Ruby on Rails is a framework
for the web that kind of that's kind of
like the first one that packages
everything makes everything easy
so anyway Ruby on Rails then then also
around and after year to Java JavaScript
you know Rose JavaScript was primarily
because not jeaious you know not yes
it's also very interesting not sure is
that it's well what the interesting
because it's started by a guy who is
actually not a professional programmer
he is actually a professional
mathematician
on a field about kr jeepers I think I
mean very esoteric field
of math I mean he's he was a postdoc or
a PhD student I forgot which but so he
you know he's not a programmer I mean
not not the professional programmers but
he's a mathematician you know
mathematician math subjects I extremely
dry like like for any PhD math students
the thing they study nobody can
understand now this is in sharp contrast
to physics
I mean physics okay it's also very
difficult you know you you spend many
years to study but however the physics
you know you can kind of convey what you
are studying to average people you know
okay so you have the universe you know
you have atoms we are still I'm studying
you know how they interact and things
like that but not in math when you had
peered at massive a master's degree of
math or you know PhD you cannot explain
you cannot really explain to you know
the average person what you are studying
because if you explain it you know you
cannot basically you cannot convey the
essence what you are studying because in
order to do so you you it will take like
few hours to actually explain to them so
that they actually understand have some
sense what you are studying it will take
you know few hours I was you know to
talk to someone on a streak you know
about the math anyway so this guy
mathematician so he started you know
he's he's very so so talented you know
so he basically within one year he
created you know the not Jas you know
and he he became he is a very uh you
know very talented he he can program you
know he created notches so that that's
how Java squid became popular but of
course that's not the only reason but
that's the one of the main reason like
milestone because of the not jeaious so
anyway the pearl so Python become
popular
because of Google then you know Ruby
because of the Ruby on Rails around 2008
and JavaScript became popular because
not yes and also because phone iPhone
you know iPhone from Apple around that
time and iPhone you know the smartphone
is began to wipe out everything else you
know wipe out laptops you know desktops
because that's because app for average
people that's what you want that's what
you need you know average people
non-programmers you know working in the
restaurant or whatever's hospitals they
are not going to you know like
programming or even like you buy a
laptop you know browsers you know a
menus and you know you commence you know
they don't don't that Fung is you know
what they want so form becomes you know
worldwide popular and form is Fong is
well one of the primary things that
drives phone is the internet you know
Wow also the city will network but the
Internet and the and on the Internet of
course javascript is the language you
use so that's how how also they prepare
it prepared JavaScript you know to start
them so anyway that's how some of these
languages you know became popular but
the other thing I want to say is that
Python so you see so so around that time
so python has many competitors you know
you have Ruby who became extremely
popular because Ruby on Rails and
JavaScript but so python is kind of you
know hanging there but then but then
like you know five years ago ten years
ago around 2010 let's say Google again
Google pushed Java Python again because
why machine learning so you know like
you know around 2010 or so you know
machine the concept of machine learning
and data data mining okay data mine is
their first you know became popular they
are mining what does I mean because
companies like Google or Facebook or you
know Twitter they have massive amount of
data you know they want to they want
process and find find your inclination
Nations find what you like what you
don't like so making advertise so they
have these data mining they just you
know using statistical statistics you
know to to come up see what you like and
who you know who should they suggest to
be your friends like if you go to
Twitter or other social networks you
know you see suggestions and things like
that so data mining you know becomes the
craze you know every program is talking
about oh we need data mining you know
then there after a few years the AI
became popular of Google's you know a I
like tensor flow and so but because
Google is using Python you know python
is one of the Google's primary language
therefore Python you know becomes
associated with data mining and you know
a I so for this reason this is this is
my perception okay it's you know it's
just I mean this is my perception so for
this reason data mining and AI and
because scoobo is using Python so they
created two O's in Python to fourfold
you know these tasks then that spread
you know that's spread so everyone so
that that prepared you know made Python
you know popular you know so so that's
how I see you know this on a contra you
know or these things
Jupiter's you know none piece I PI you
know they made Python popular the
attention flow you know the AI you know
the a I think Google created you know
when you want to do a you need to do a
huge amount of computation Python cannot
handle it so so what did those
computations you know they are turning
see your tsipras first at Google you
know I don't know maybe Java but
probably see first press you know the
heart of your neural networks or
whatever technology they use for other
visual intelligence but however the
interface to those engines is Python you
know Python you know Python is a stroll
language you know I mean compared to you
know the a low level you have C C++ :
Java you know they are kind of maybe not
Java but they are kind of fast because
they are low label but higher level you
have Python Ruby JavaScript panel Ruby
JavaScript pearl and and in bunch of
others they are like 5 times slower in
general then then see also : for example
so so that's so that's why the interface
to AI is like Python so that's due to
Google how it make became popular so
let's read some comments being bar so
high order per by mark Dominus so normal
says higher order pearl by mark Dominus
is a good one for your list available
free at this website
yeah but you know I don't like Perl you
know I'm glad it's good I don't want to
dig into I don't want to former pro I
mean you you can of course I mean each
person is different so I think I've seen
that book you know I don't know anyway
so yeah I have a you know here I have a
survey of Perl books you know I read all
of them like you know word for word so
this is this is around 2002 so you know
learning Pro you know lots of history
you know and also many of these people
have you know they disappeared you know
for example this this per book per the
programmers companion 1997 by Nico
Chapman then the guy disappeared you
know after a few years you know
disappeared the learning Perot is very
extremely popular learn imperiled by
this guy controversial guy Randall
Schwartz he back then he was a household
name among programmers but anyway so the
years you know the per books I've
surveyed
okay so anyway pearl are not contra you
know I'm just throwing out on a onaconda
you know so that well I mean if you are
not a Python program it's you know I'm
just doing maybe it's useful to you so
it's like 22.6 g-got bites you know I've
never download a software that huge you
know the biggest is maybe a browser you
know a few hundred megabytes maybe but
you know this is 2.6 gigabyte and it
includes all these things anyway so
that's on a contra
so that's Perl and so we covered on our
contra history of languages you know how
they became popular so so one thing led
to another that's how my rambling is
doing so okay any of these topic pick
pick one what's the next topic we should
talk about then you check the comments
so here is the topics and see the
comments today's AI is artificial
instinct not intelligence how is that
what do you mean yeah what do you mean
okay
alex says does not Google again
introduced go and so they switch to it
yeah Google you know Google the people
at Google Rob Pike and Thompson by the
way thanks to Scott who mentioned that
you know anyway so Google the Rob Pike
and Thompson is something or something
Thompson he created the go language its
intended to replace see prosperous you
know so I that's that's my favorite
language now and sorry sorry : so you
can check out my tutorial so : is my
favorite language
and anyway so so : is my favorite
language and it's very good yeah so
Google created it and originally its
intended intended as a replacement of C
or C++ primarily c plus for us but
however you know it was amended about 10
years ago but today it's very very
popular it's the extremely popular in
the industry Golan so it it does replace
some C+ for us but also many Python
programmers you know switch to Golan and
also Google wrote a tool that that
converts 5 1 to 2 : anyway so yeah
exactly they have a goat translator -
for that converts 5 down to : so let me
look around 3 adoptions so if you so
every few years I check Python 3
adoption parent 3 is kind of failure
right now it's used about 40% in an
industry it's but anyway Google created
this tool grumpy and they created this
image that was funny
so Python functional number two what do
you mean so okay no man say snowman says
complex numbers would be interesting
oh I remember is they have real and
imaginary part okay let's talk about
complex numbers
why : is your favorite right now okay
unique so that intelligence understand
itself okay here's another comment for
Chari
he says intelligence understands itself
but instinct just something
automatically for example we don't know
how we recognize faces exactly so let me
yeah I'll go through the answer the
question so so the you know the today
the most part you know in artificial
intelligence they are several techniques
to you know programming takes techniques
to achieve that so for example you have
you have evolutionary programming which
is you you wrote several programs and
they running an environment they compete
with each other and the ones who satisfy
some score get higher score that
algorithm wins you know evolution nary
evolutionary algorithm no that's not the
proper term but something like that but
anyway so you know it's it's based on
the evolution concept you know you know
programs compete algorithms compete with
themselves and the winner
whoever wins you know they have a score
criteria whoever wins that algorithm
survives and that algorithm competes
with other algorithms so eventually
you'll find one algorithm algorithm
that's the best for the task
you know that's evolution evolutionary
algorithms of programming isn't that's
not the right name but what what what
was the right name for that guys
evolutionary programming but anyway
there are two things they are quite
they're separate evolution or genetic
genetic programming
yeah genetic programming and evolution
algorithm they are actually two
different things but it's based on idea
of you know evolution you know biology
so that's one techniques technique for
AI another technique I'm not expert on
AI by the way I just want to mention
these are some of the things I know so
you have you know genetic programming
evolutionary algorithm then you have so
what one of the most popular today is
neural networks so neural networks you
know so Google two years ago they
they're go their software offers zero
called alpha zero they teach the world's
best go players by far like no no human
can beat the machine now Google's alpha
0 alpha 0 is a go playing software go is
a aged agent game kind of like chess but
not really but you know it's a is what
what is called zero sum full information
game it's something like that something
like that so anyway so so go so Google
created the alphago and that beats the
word champion you know go is you know
it's supposed to be the milestone the
measure of whether we have artificial
intelligence you know if a machine can
play go and beat humans then we say you
know we have you know artificial
intelligences here you know for for the
past 30 years there was well that there
was one of the you know criteria to know
whether we have artificial intelligence
so anyway Google did it and the method
you know the AI admitted they use this
neural networks neural networks you know
but there is a major problem with neural
networks
the problem with neural networks is that
you know so okay you have you have this
software you know it can it can
recognize people's faces
again and it can it can let's say
translate languages not really but you
know like today's translation is pretty
bad but anyway and it can beat human
being you know human animals in Ingo you
know in a game of Go
however the problem the major problem
with newer works is that you cannot find
out how it does it okay so for example
if you let's talk this say chess let's
not you know say go because go a lot of
people don't know what that is let's say
chess if you write a program to play
chess now you are in control of the
algorithms right so if your chest if
your chess software became the world
champion you know exactly how it wins
because you wrote the program at each
step you know you look at you know all
the ways you know which way is better
and you kind of you can learn from your
software you know if your software beats
all the humans you you learn you know
how so I mean in a sense you learn when
you solve a problem using the software
and when the software is is successful
then you learn something about the
nature of the problem because because if
it's a math problem you you kind of
learned some theorem because your
program does this and that that became
the right thing then you learn something
about the the problem you know we can
call it a theory you know you understand
the problem but however the the neural
network is not like that at all you know
the neural network it can beat humans
you know in chess or whatever but you
know nothing it there's nothing it can
tell you you know what a why is such a
move better than others in chess like
nothing zero absolutely not nothing
because the way neural network works is
like it imitates you know the human
brain by the way again I don't know much
about neural networks and I've never
written programming is that I never
actually study that neural networks but
anyway that that's a nature that's
raishin so I want to show you an article
why is that every time neuro-networks
sorry new neural networks so I have
written this article artificial neural
networks is nasty and I explained my
view idea you know if you are interested
you can read about it so I mean the gist
is that neuro what networks you can not
you can not learn anything from it it's
just a machine it's you know doing it
it's things so yeah that's that's
genetic algorithms that's right okay let
me answer the other question why is :
your favorite language now I mentioned
that I talked about that a few times in
my past livestream but but basically
okay for two main reasons I'll be just
I'll be just quick one is that one is
that the language is very simple I mean
you can learn the whole thing in one day
seriously I don't mean you know I don't
I don't mean it was a hyperbole I mean
you guys most of you guys all of you are
programmers right you probably have a
few years of experience and you probably
know more than one language you know
maybe some language you know more in
some days for example if you go learn
Haskell that's extremely difficult you
know it takes you month you know and you
don't quite get it
if you learn closure it's probably kind
of a similar situation you know you take
a lot of time and different new concepts
you know and so on goal and you can
learn in one day the entire language
okay I'm serious about this you know
maybe two days or three days you know
you take one hour a day and you can you
know learning study goal and you know
for a week you learn you're understand
not just learn but but understand the
whole language completely because it's
very simple now you can read my tutorial
you know
of course I recommend it you know start
with my tutorial and go from there
so you can you can so it's extremely
simple and it's also statists statically
typed so it's just kind of strongly
typed language like C or C++ or Java but
however it has also type inference
meaning that type int type inference
meaning that you most of the time you
don't have to worry about types okay
it's just like when you program in
JavaScript or Python or Ruby okay and
also it's it's fast I mean that's by
design it's as fast as C++ you know or C
you know so it's it's it's five times
fast faster than any other item Ruby
JavaScript five times a beast so it's
extremely simple its stat and it's
extremely fast and you know and but okay
these two are not sufficient there's one
more most important thing most languages
you know when they are very good you
like it very much they they are usually
academic languages like nobody uses you
know if you you have some subculture
like scheme you know racket or scheme
this you know they are they like that
but in an industry you know it's nobody
a few people know it's like Haskell you
know you have a subculture but it's not
mainstream : is mainstream I mean if you
want to chop : : you know it's it's
hugely popular you know it's widely
adopted so that is the reason I like :
and every design you know in when you
learn a language on their homepage
usually they have like philosophy you
know they they tell you why we created
this language why do we need another
language you know okay why this language
why my language is better than others
and I you know what features is my
language oh I have like polymorphism I
have static typing and so on you know
jargons
but anyway so so :
Blagh you know I think Rob Michael yeah
I think he or maybe others he there's an
article about you know it discusses the
philosophy the design ok the design of
Golan and basically every item I agree
let's see so if I go to my programming
blog
sorry info and I scroll down all the way
down to the bottom and go to blog
archive I have a article about that I'm
not sure with what date but it's
probably here or here or here ok not
here
anyway so back then a few months ago
maybe four months ago I about I I list
III point out the article so you can go
to it and I gave the reasons at least
the reasons they they tell you about the
design of goal line why make you know
what's the why they design it that way I
mean you know they have like a list of
reasons you know these the problems they
want to solve and date for them they
don't they don't see it in other
languages you know things like that
and basically I agree with every one of
them you know very almost yeah every one
of them very much and I surprised myself
because I didn't like the Rob Pike guy
because I think he's a UNIX you know
UNIX head I never liked him but but that
changed after I learned about Golan and
everything changed so that's about Golan
so let me answer another question let's
go back to so how long have I been
talking 48 minutes let's go to okay
maybe let's talk about complex numbers
and after that there'll be it for for
today
okay let's talk about complex numbers so
I'm going to give you an introduction on
complex numbers
now I'm not a well I mean I assume most
of you guys are not mathematicians I
mean you guys are programmers so so for
that I can give you an introduction to
complex numbers I mean what I'm going to
talk about complex numbers is pretty
basic so I mean even for mathematicians
I can talk about that because it's not
it's not very advanced math it's it's
it's something simple so complex numbers
so actually let's go to XRD complex
numbers so I'm just going to give you an
introduction understanding complex
numbers this article exactly I also have
come I also have articles on how you do
complex numbers in Python and in Java
and also in Ruby okay so here is Java
here is Python here is Java Java doesn't
have complex numbers building but python
does and also Ruby does so sorry Ruby
complex numbers
so I mean you can look at you know if
you if you if you maybe after after I
talk about complex numbers then you can
try to you know code something about
complex numbers but anyway these two
articles ruby complex numbers complex
numbers in ruby and complex numbers in
python you compare them and you can see
which is the better language okay I am
NOT going to tell you which now but but
if you are like interested in language
design you know you can like compare
this to Allah go and you get church you
know which one you you know to you is a
better language anyway so understanding
complex numbers okay what I want to say
about complex numbers you know most most
of the time complex numbers is taught
you know so you have a number imaginary
numbers so code such that you know like
such that its value is the square root
of negative one okay
what do you mean square root of negative
one so okay I don't know if you guys are
familiar with it because Nick so when
you multiply a number by itself you
square a number and if that number is
negative the result is always positive
because two negative numbers when you
multiply it becomes positive so any
number squared doesn't matter its
negative or positive
the result is a positive number but
however if you have like square root of
negative one so square root is a reverse
of squared so so when you say square
root of negative one you are saying you
are saying there is a number such that
when it multiplied itself it the answer
is negative one you know that doesn't
make sense
you know it's impossible there is no
number that every you know neck every
number squared
is a positive number you cannot have you
know Brazil cannot be a negative number
so so anyway that's that is why people
call it imaginary number because you
know at the beginning in the history of
mathematics you know people you know you
I find it this weird you find this weird
peak and all mathematicians you know the
greatest mathematicians find it weird -
that is a history of imaginary numbers
like like back then mathematicians you
know don't accept this you know like
this when they see this this is voodoo
you know they they fight I mean like if
they are like political factions they
fiercely fight each other you know they
know fire you if you believe you know if
you are in this school that's cool you
know like fight you'd like just like
today's politics you know you have
different parties and so on
anyway complex number so but where does
it came from I mean how it where does it
came from who you know who like out of
his mind created this concept you know
where you have a square root of negative
one
yeah you know so it is not it's not like
someone you know a nutjob who who
thought of this the the reason this came
up is actually it's actually it happens
yeah I mean it came up in the process of
solving higher higher degree polynomials
okay what does I mean so when you solve
a polynomial let me write it out so
polynomials like X x squared plus you
know X maybe maybe let's say 3x equals
to 5 let's say okay that's that's a
polynomial you want to you want to solve
for X what is X okay in a more complex
examples you have you know X third power
let's say let's say that you know four
times x third power minus x squared
first
first three X equals to five you want to
find out what is X so this this is this
is called a third power polynomial and
and there are more powers like fourth
power fifth power and so on
you want to solve these equations you
know back in this is around 1700s you
know mathematicians you know the
greatest top mathematicians all trying
to solve this now for the folio fathers
second-degree case we already have a
formula you know the formula is
something like it's called quadratic
formula Q you old let's say Q qadr iti
think you can look it up but it's like
negative B plus or minus square root of
2 AC divided by a negative B something
like that let's look at it up let's look
it up there it is quadratic formula so
they magnify so yeah that's a formula so
whenever you see a way whenever you see
a second-degree polynomial and you know
this is a this is B plus C you know ABC
are just some numbers some constant
numbers whenever you have a
second-degree polynomial you can just
plug in you can just use this formula so
x equals two so the solution is you know
x equals two these negative P plus minus
square root of b plus b square minus 4ac
the whole thing divided by 2a yeah so
that's a that's this solution is called
closed form formula for second-degree
polynomials any so mathematicians you
know they want to know okay that's great
that's so you know it's fantastic you
know you don't even have to solve it
whenever you see this form you just you
the answer is right here you have
formula you have a closed-form formula
so they want to do the same for third
degree polynomials and they want to do
the same for let's say fourth degree
polynomials you know they want to you
know then they want to do the same for
fifth degree polynomials would you know
that's the next step step you know so so
people have came up with a formula for
third degree polynomial it's fairly
complex like you have many verticals you
know square root or you know fairly
complex and people also have solution
closed-form formulas for fourth degree
but however for fifth degree nobody ever
found a solution okay that's another
history but by itself okay that's a
that's a major chapter of math history
and if you are curious the that chapter
the name of that chapter math history is
called quintic solving the quintic
equation so you can look it up if you
want after after the show so anyway but
what I'm going to get into is that when
people when mathematicians there's this
guy he tried to find a closed-form
formula for the third degree polynomial
he then then this came up this square
root of negative one
it came up you know it's not like you
know it's not like he just dreamed
dreamed it up when when people are
trying to solve solve this third degree
polynomial as the formula you know you
manipulate you know the formula then
then you the solution involves this the
solution give us this thing so that
that's that is the origin yes that is
the engine the first time ever the
square root of negative one came up so
all the mathematicians are puzzled at
the time you know nobody you know when
you know it's like math you
a huge history you know it's like in
physics you have you know in philosophy
you know a few thousand years ago we
have questions like what is the meaning
of life you know what what is the size
of the universe you know we have lots of
philosophical questions like that you
know and in physics you know what what
is the you know size of the universe but
in math you know of Kathi's also you
know it's it's the you have this
mysterious I mean nobody really
understand you know what's going on in
math you know I mean different era
you have different problems you know
people don't understand so today we have
you know current today we have some set
of problems that is personal to us but
back then this is one of them so this
guy tried to solve the you know 30
polynomial and you know then you got
this square root of negative one thing
so all the mathematicians don't
understand it and many basically most of
them all of them basically they rejected
reject you know they okay that's this
garbage you know it may say makes sense
you know because this there cannot be a
number whose you know Square is negative
one it's impossible so they just
rejected but okay so that's the
beginning that's the beginning of the
imaginary number then it's not after you
know maybe 50 years or 100 years then
mathematicians began to understand
understand this situation why it happens
let's see if I can explain you know
where am I going about this so anyway
let me read the comments a bit and I
think we're gonna wrap it up pretty soon
true so okay so so keep the comments
coming okay so if you have you know let
me know how am i doing so yeah we let's
get back to okay so this is the
beginning of the imaginary number now
today when you learn in math let's say
in high school when people say when when
people when teachers teach you about
imaginary numbers you know typically
what they do is that they say you know
imaginary number is just a number such
that such that such that you know
x-squared equals to 1 that's the
Imaginarium that's oh yeah yeah okay let
me rephrase you know the teachers tell
you that the reason imaginary number
exists because mathematicians is trying
to solve equations such as x squared
equals to negative one that is not true
okay
that's a that that is not true I mean
the reason I mean you can look look it
up you can look up Wikipedia you explain
that history of complex numbers so but
however this way of explaining imaginary
number is very simple and could be
convenient you know it kind of you know
it kind of get the point across
because it is a number that equal you
know squared equals negative 1 however
this is not the origin this is how this
is not how imaginary number came up
it came up because you know when people
are trying to solve 3rd degree
polynomials by anyway so let's get back
to this so so when this when squared
root negative 1 came of mathematicians
do not accept it but okay but even ok
you know because math is a mystery
nobody understand you know the whole
thing white numbers works why you know
what is infinity you know there are many
current math problems for example of the
Continuum Hypothesis you know i can type
it you know if you look at that view you
get that okay that is one of the current
thing we don't really understand the
details okay mathematicians but you can
look it up you you will need actually
like four years of math you know major
to to actually understand it but but you
know but you can look it up you know
just for curiosity's sake but anyway so
back to the yeah when so when square
root equals negative one can Bob nobody
you understand it no people rejected and
but after 50 years or maybe a hundred
years mathematicians began to understand
it but okay so let me put it this way so
there there is a few mathematicians you
know some publish their results some
didn't publish but a few mathematicians
began they came up with a way they came
up with a way to express the imaginary
numbers without without this concept of
square root equals to negative one
without it you know they came up with a
way to explain comp you know the
imaginary number without involving
without having anything to do with
square root okay and that is what I'm
going to explain okay so first of all
first of all so a complex number so we
first of all we have
so this is the imaginary number usually
okay usually regionals I so it's called
imaginary then
okay so this this is the complex number
so complex number is is just a number
wait wait yes so complex number so so
you have imaginary number and complex
number is any number of this form it's
it's a real number a and B are real
numbers and P is a numbers multiplied by
I which is a complex number so in other
words the work in other words a complex
number is so complex a complex number is
that you know that form so that's a
complex number but but what is the
explanation without a square root of
number I so let me explain that and
we'll be done it will be take another
five minutes five minutes or ten minutes
and then we'll be done okay here's
here's the interesting thing let's see
if I can you know I got this pen this
tablet let me see if I can use it to
draw this tablet let's see yeah so so
this this pen tablet thing so by the way
if you like it if you you know yeah let
me mention if you like my videos go to
saudi dot info put some monies put some
money in my bank account okay if you
like my videos you know do that
so let's go to keyboard and
miscellaneous so I got this thing so
here's some of my recommendations now
you can look around and if you like it
buy it for my website so I'm going to
show you if I can
is slow
why is it not yet done so let's see
comments
so toastin hi toastin Torsen says math
is mysterious and complex but with some
imaginary but with some imaginary
entities you can get to the root of even
negative numbers X oh no excellent
oh no app for quick writing on tablet oh
I'll check it out thank you
so let's see if I can do this okay so
that works actually so I'm going to draw
I'm going to draw some mathematics this
is my this is the first time I'm going
to do that and and this is exactly what
I need with the pen so I'm getting some
use of this paint applet okay math
express why is it so big so
oh yeah size
and it's okay so let's open another one
so okay complex numbers so let's do that
so we have let's go here so okay so
we're gonna explain complex numbers with
without square root of I and the the way
to do that is via geometry so you guys
knows vectors right so vectors you have
this you have this X you have Y so okay
I'm going to explain complex numbers
without the square root of I and in fact
what I'm about to explain that is how
mathematicians first understand complex
numbers once they see this explanation
of complex numbers all mathematicians
began to accept complex numbers because
in this way of of interpretation of
complex numbers
you don't need square root of negative
one and you know and and it's pure logic
you know it's pure logical you know so
you don't you don't you don't have this
imaginary you know thing anymore
so let me let me start that so complex
number is a pair of numbers two numbers
a and B okay just to pair them numbers
and what what is a and B a and B are
just real numbers like one two three
four five you know or negative 1 2 3 4 5
or negative 1.1 or 5 over 3 you know
there are just real numbers so a complex
number is a pair of numbers ok this is
getting too elaborate
yeah nay I have to magnify that let's
forget that anyway so it's not get too
complicated so complex number is just a
pair of numbers and a pair of real
numbers now on on you can you know you
can plot it on the axis so we here is
for example this one see it's not
working anymore
I don't know what's going on so let's
select that
DVD
what's going on
yeah I cannot draw it anymore so I don't
know so anyway it's you guys familiar
with vectors so it's like vectors so
it's you just got two numbers a and B so
complex number is a pair of numbers and
I'll just explain by you know gestures
so and so you define two operators so
let me just type it here complex number
is okay now a geometric and logical
explanation of complex numbers sense
square okay okay complex number is a
pair of numbers we write a B okay a a
and B just real numbers now we define
two operations on them one addition to
multiplication okay so far so good
am i doing good
so we define two operations on contract
numbers addition is defined like this so
a B is a complex number and C T equals 2
this is easy a plus C B first e great is
it good
okay now multiplication
multiplication is defined like this now
the formula is a little bit complicated
so I'll have to look up
[Music]
[Applause]
multiplication of complex numbers is
defined by here
so I'm gonna okay that is that that is
it so you okay so let me write this in
for ABC T multiplied you know so a B is
a complex number and C D is a complex
number and you simply just define it
define it this way so the first part
will be AC minus PD and the ad plus BC
that is it that is it my friends so what
do you mean that is that is it how does
it you know how does it connect to the
negative one well actually I should
explain that because if I don't it's not
completely explanation so so far so good
type good type good let me know so I can
you know I can feel good and go on so so
yeah so addition is this and
multiplication is this okay so let's see
explain why you know why why are we
doing this I mean how is this has
anything to do with you know the
arranger negative square root of
negative one
let's see okay so the next X but okay
first of all this is it I mean that that
is or to complex numbers complex numbers
is just you know it's just a pair of
numbers and you define addition and
multiplication okay but so far it seems
puzzling but why are you just you know
the blue give you you know define is two
things how does it connect to the
negative the square root of negative one
so it's like this so remember before you
know before the geometry interpretation
name is before the geometry
interpretation we have complex numbers
like this like this so we write it that
so we have complex numbers like this and
we can do the normal addition and
multiplication with it for example for
example let's do that
for example so this a B is a plus oops
so that's one complex number and
see do you begin to see so this is this
is equals to
you see so a plus p1 is one complex
number and see first e1 is another
complex number and the result is you
know you just you just use no more no
more addition you know and you get no
more addition and multiplication rules
and you get this new number and phone
for for example addition multiplication
we have we have let's see so
multiplication we have two complex
numbers 1 & 2 and we we so what we get
is for example so we when you multiply
two numbers we get so this is okay so
this is multiply we use multiplication
rules so you a so this is equals through
a times C a times C first a let's let's
just drop back a times D I firs CB I
plus plus B the I squared which equals
to the BDI squared because I squared is
negative one so BD I squared is negative
one so that equals to just
and that equals two
then you collect the terms and that
equals through that so you can see by
algebra you know by square root you know
if we define complex imaginary or square
root of negative one and we apply the
normal addition rule and multiplication
vacation rule it looks like this you
know it looks like this okay so I think
that's it so it looks like this but now
you can see the the this multiplication
is is just like that
Oh exactly
I'm so glad I kind of like actually
worked it out on my own so so are you
guys are you guys still here say
something
so anyway actually we are done so yeah
we are done but so you see you can see
that now the the the geometric
interpretation without negative square
root of 1 I mean Nick square root of
negative 1 we thought that at all we
simply define complex numbers as just a
pair of numbers then we define audition
and we define audition like that and we
define multiplication like that you know
just by pure logic you know without the
reason you know which let's just let's
say you know we just define it like that
then we can work with these numbers you
know as complex numbers
now now now before this geometric
interpretation we if we have complex
numbers of square root of negative 1
which is this I and we apply the normal
addition rule and the normal
multiplication rule we get you know we
get this and we get this but now if you
compare these
you know addition and multiplication to
the geometric interpretation they are
identical so so you see in this way you
never even mentioned squared you know
you never even mentioned the concept of
some you know imaginary things you know
square root of negative one like you use
you kind of just PI past it you know you
there's no concept of you know there's
no concept of square root of negative
one this is like pure logic you know
pure logic you know and you have this
you know so in other words we say that
you you simply created a new system a
new number system which we call complex
numbers you know new system we call
complex numbers and we simply define
multiplication and addition this way but
you can see that it is actually
compatible with you know the arrangin of
complex numbers where you have this
thing I which is like the you know
square root of negative 1 so ok so
that's it about complex numbers any
questions any questions that's it for
today thank you guys for coming
I'll see you guys next time
bye