hi guys so I'm going to show you today a
command let's see let's go to my blog
this command is to turn lines into HTML
list so let's go to let me show you here
so a new section a new section so
suppose I have few lines CAD dogs and I
want to turn them into a wrist so I have
like that so that that is the command
HTML lines to list and you can get that
at I don't have a web page for it but
it's in my HTML mod HTML HTML mod you
can get this package at at this location
but so so that's very nice you know you
can turn any line to to HTML list and if
you want you can if you do it with
prefix like universal argument like
control you then you call the command
then you get a order list well let's
look at browser wait let's forget the
browser you see that's the ordered list
and no more or less like this
okay and today I wrote a new command I
what I want is the definition list so a
definition based looks like but actually
it's easier if I just show you
so for example let's say I have some
examples honest I can show you somewhere
here yeah this is the definition list
you have te l for definition list and dt
is the the word you want to define and
DD is the definition what if whatever
you want so and the result looks like
that this list is useful if you write
programming languages like functions for
example let's see okay let me go through
my web blog so TV that web blog so
here's all the things I want to do
convert able to HTML for example this
file so this file this page is talking
about HTML time tag that's a new tag in
HTML 5 and you can see here I'm using a
table to explain you know the syntax and
and the meaning so so this is for the
attribute daytime but anyway let's yeah
let's try another example
okay here so so so this page is html5
complete list of html5 tags so I'm using
lots of tables here you can see they are
all tables but in this case actually the
best format is probably definition based
you know the problem that the problem
with table is that they look nice in a
browser but however on a cell phone now
you know smartphone is so popular you
know if you want your webpages to show
in Google search result sometimes table
format Google will complain you know
that's not readable on a smart phone so
I like to turn this into a definition is
so let's do that let's let's for example
let's do that make a backup okay copy
that and copy it here let's just
manually do it for example remove the
table now to region and change to first
of all let's get the
lines to DT such failed oh hey there's a
mistake I need to because you see I'm
trying to turn this line to to to that
in show you let me show you so I'm
trying to well I'm trying to turn that
line to to this but the problem is it
requires a space I don't want it to be
space so basically what okay let me show
you go to the new window okay that's a
command let me do describe function and
jump to the fire okay that that's not
right it's not actually you see this is
the code I just wrote like a few minutes
ago
but now I already committed to my HTML
mod so let's let's look at the version
in HTML mod so let's see that's my
shortcut for HTML mod then you can I can
just jump to the code so such for 2dt
to DL to TL okay there it is
so I want to evaluate here so so you see
this line will become that however
there's a problem you see if I don't
have the space there you will not work
like right now
he will not work so that's a mistake so
it should not require space so what I
need to do is just a that evaluate
now let's try it yeah that's good
so anyway what I'm trying to say is okay
so I'm I'm going to turn this table to
the DT format let's do that Naruto
region was that so I want a deal deal at
the end then I want to change that to DT
yes and change that to DT definition
this DL wait so many mistakes
yeah
yes changeable then I want to change the
ending this part to DT yes change oh
then I want to change this part to PT
and beginning of DP that's right so now
it's done expand window showing browser
you see now it looks like that it does
not necessarily looks better I mean I
think the table looks better but however
however the DT is probably the way to go
I have to think about it you know
whether I'm gonna do this but I mean the
point is now I have the command now I
have this command that allows me to to
to write this definition based if I want
so let's show an example
so the command name is HTML lines - DL
and and if you just call it here for
each line you will use the first period
as the separator between definition and
between the word to define in the
definition however if you call a
universal
argument first that is you press control
you let me show it here so control you
then you call the command such Team
Alliance - DL then he will ask you what
for a character to be used as a
separator so let's do that in this case
I wanted to be well actually this is
this is no little bits I want to
separate the character to be your arrow
let's say so how so let me do some
manipulation first replace that by let's
say arrow do it do it do it
no no yes no no yes no yes yes okay
there's a mistake here should be yes
okay now I know I wanna call the command
so control you then call the command
- - DL yes then give a character arrow
yes you see now now it's doing that so
now I expand widen you know narrow to
region widened so now that's good
now I'm using those brackets so that I
can I mean that's what I can change them
to the code tag like like that there so
show in browser again
so you see so anyway so that that is the
come
and such TM airlines - dia so you can
find the command in in my mod in this
mod and and from this URL okay that's
all I want to show you today and so I've
been doing a few videos since a month or
two ago so if you like me to see if you
like to watch anything you may make a
comment you know let me know what you
like to see you know you know you can
treat me thank you for watching bye