hello welcome to another episode of sant
talk show s talk show is a variety show
mostly focusing on programming and nerd
stuff so I talk about programming
languages in particular emac lisp and
wolam language and uh it also may
include JavaScript python goand and a
bunch of others programming language
design algorithms artificial
intelligence
Wikipedia information technology you
know this kind of thing nerds of in
interest to nerds in particular my
interest if you are watching offline
feel free to skip around so because I
talk you know random randomish and today
we are going to code we are going to
code Advent of code what is going on
with that advent of code okay so
continue Advent of a code in wo family
language okay let me talk about my
keyboards and let's begin so this is
glove 80 fantastic keyboard my main this
is Ultimate hacking keyboard also
fantastic I use it for as a Marco keypad
60 key Mar fantastic nulia nulia tracko
uh Logitech mouse and I must mention
this again I have not uh you know been
using it yet so this is sve board SV a l
b o a r d this is the most advanced
input device it's a keyboard okay so you
know a b CDE e FG quy and vorak and and
there's a pointer so this is called SV a
l b o a r d SW board there's two of them
one for left hand one for right hand
hold on and I will be using it every day
okay so that's my keyboards and uh I
have reviews just for search for it
you'll find it on YouTube and all over
on my
website. info okay today Advent of code
2023 other people finished in 2023 I
finish next year so previously we've
done up to problem nine day nine and day
10 I skipped because I was tired that
day and this is kind of day 10 is
tedious problem so we're going to do day
okay let's just begin okay let's uh
let's talking and begin coding okay am I
ready yes got coffee yes coffee
here Advent of code 2023 problem 11 okay
day 11 okay let's begin uh let's so
let's start to make we're going to code
in wolam language let's start wolam
language wolam language now version 14
fantastic the most powerful symbolic
language on earth a magnitude higher
level than hascar closure lisp uh or
camel F all the all the fan you know all
the
languages uh so Wan language okay so
start a new uh new like a notebook
buffer so three
enter three shift enter to evaluate
fantastic let's magnify one more okay so
let's read the problem day
11 okay so day 11 let's look let's try
to do this quickly instead of like
um you know slowly reading everything so
you got problem input looks like that
some kind of maze kind of thing so
Advent of code they like to do that okay
so you continue following sign following
signs for hot springs and eventually
came across a
Observatory the elf within turns out to
be a researcher studying cosmotic cos
Cosmic expansion using the giant
telescope here he doesn't know anything
about the missing machine parts he's
only visiting for This research project
however he confirms that the hot springs
are the next closest area likely to have
people he will even take take you
straight there once he's done with
today's observation analysis okay edotic
elf maybe you can help him with the
analysis to speed things up of course
the researcher has collected a bunch of
data and compiled the data into a single
Giant image that's your person input
critical part the image includes empty
spaces represented by a DOT and galaxies
represented by a pound sign for example
okay so a DOT is empty space a pound
sign is Galaxy okay so you got the input
like that the researcher is trying to
figure out the sum of the length of the
shortest
path between every pair of galaxies oh
combinatorial
problem so between every two pound sign
you have a distance okay
and
uh sum of the length of the shortest
path between every pair so every pair
you have a path in between them that is
and then you have a length of that path
so you have variety of a path between a
given pair of galaxies but you want the
shortest of course in this case it's
called taxi cap distance or Manon
distance because supposedly manhon the
city near New York is kind of like a all
squares you know it's great so instead
of going like curved line you just go up
you can only go up down up down each
time by one unit of distance so that way
of measuring this distance is called
manhatton distance or taxi cab geometry
something like that okay you can look up
on Wikipedia so anyway shortest path
between every pair of G is there's the
shortest path and measured you know
given by a length that's a number and um
the researcher is trying to figure out
the sum of the
lengths okay so you have a pair you have
a bunch of dots each City each Galaxy
let's just say it's a DOT okay a Vertex
so you have a bunch of them you want you
want to get a list of all the possible
pairs all the doesn't matter okay now
for each pair you got a distance that's
the you know the taxi cap this distance
okay then you want to find out the sum
okay you want to find the sum of them
all problem understood I
believe now how however there's a catch
oh there's a catch you [ __ ] elf the
universe expanded in the time it took
the light from those galaxies to reach
the opposite vory due to due to
something involving gravitational
effects only some space expands in fact
the result is that any row or column
that contains no galaxies should all
actually be twice a speed oh there's a
trick so if you have a row or if you
have a column such so for example this
row where there's no galaxies then any
anything passing through that counts as
two distance okay okay uh
idiotic okay these rows and columns need
to be twice as big the result of cosmic
expansion therefore looks like this okay
so the first step is you expand the
universe something
maybe equipped with this expanded
universe the shortest path between every
pair of galaxies can be found it can
help to assign every Galaxy a unique
number okay now it's giving a number
instead instead of the pound sign or the
number sign or the octat Trope that's
the name of that
symbol in these n galaxies there are 36
pairs how do you know
because combination you know because 9 *
8 let's
say wait what so this nine galaxies
uh oh yeah then order doesn't matter so
8 * 9 is 72 72 divided by two because
order doesn't matter you got 36 pairs
correct only count each pair once or the
within the pair doesn't matter of course
shut the [ __ ] up for each pair find any
shortest path between two galaxies for
each pair find any shortest path between
the two galaxies using only steps that
move up and down of course yeah that's
taxi cap gometry or uh write exactly one
dot or one pound at a
time oh so but so but one there's a
question can you when you pass through
another you know galaxy do you do you
have to go around or you can directly
pass when you count the
distance apparently you can just pass
through yeah okay the shortest path
between two galaxies is allowed to pass
through is allowed to pass through
another galaxy and preent even before I
read the problem I knew for example here
is one of the shortest path between
galaxies 5 and N uh five and N now why
do they okay why do they draw two uh
oh actually it's just one okay so this
path has length n because it takes a
minimum of nine steps to get from Galaxy
5 to Galaxy 9 let's let's try count 1 2
3 4 5 6 78 okay so you have you know you
have eight pound symbols plus one you
know because the last step the eight
locations
marked number sign plus the step onto
Galaxy 9 itself yeah so here are some
other example show this path length
Okay okay so yeah okay so in this
example after explaining the universe
the sum of the shortest path between all
36 pairs of galaxies is
374 okay you want to find the sum okay
expand the universe then find the length
of the shortest path between every pair
of galaxies what is the sum of these
lengths okay that is a
problem uh okay this problem seem
slightly
complicated am I like alive is there any
disturbances in the universe such that
my live stream is actually not live
let's double check yeah it's live if you
are here say something okay okay so this
problem is slightly complicated let's
get to work okay let's stop talking
because uh because normally I'm too
slow uh you know talking so let's
let's just get some of the input um
let's see so for of course you need the
input and you need the to input so here
is the to input so now okay so let's
[Music]
see
uh okay so here is a to
input okay then uh let's see my personal
input does it do they use at you know
what kind of symbol do they use get your
person input okay copy and the new per
first save let's save it XX today's date
Advent of code a. text okay now make a
backup now expand the window okay they
use the pound sign for the galaxies okay
uh okay
so so first of all you need to expand
the universe okay so this is
this is my input
okay and here's a sample input so
uh so we can actually start to work on
this problem yes because I know all
the specifications of the problem so
should should we write it down first so
given uh let's write it down because
that is my habit and it's a good habit
when you actually work in real life in
in a job
uh because I'm not the hacking type like
the Unix and C idiots they don't they
don't they don't think they just start
to do something you know they like they
typically that's what they do start
to [ __ ] I despise
those C and C++ and the Unix the system
me this type of people okay I'm
a engineer programmer I'm a
mathematician
so let's you know let's start to write
the problem so uh
problem given a text
input
uh
each CH is either a DOT or a pound
sign uh you want to
first double the row that's all dots
okay and
uh and
double any column that is all dots okay
that's what you have to do so problem
specification okay so that you expand
the universe
then then
okay so the goal is to get the sum of
all the distance so you need to start to
identify you see you need a way to
identify each of these Galaxy
locations
um well you can use a coordinate
coordinate system or you can just use
you know 1 2 3 4 by order top down left
to right or you can use is a b c d so it
seems 1 2 3 4 is
easiest uh but but then okay then so you
need to
identify uh you need
to find find a way to
identify
the
galaxies
okay and
then then given two galaxies
you need to measure their distance now
how do you do that okay Wen language can
easily do
it
uh because because uh
wait oh wait so there's actually very
simple if you
allow passing through any other galaxies
then all you then then then the distance
between any two galaxies is just the sum
of their coordinate difference x- axis
and y AIS you know instead of doing any
of zigzag all you have to do is just is
just compute how many in the column how
how many in the row
okay okay so
yeah you see right now the problem is
how do you codify
this so anyway you so so first of all
you
identify you need a way to identify all
the galaxies
okay okay so the easiest way is actually
by coordinate
because because you need to compute this
distance later so once you have
coordinate it's much easier to compute
the
distance right
so for each of these galaxies you need
to give it a coordinate like cartisian
coordinate so which is identified by two
numbers x coordinate and y coordinate uh
and also you need to devise like where
do you consider is orine okay so
typically orine is the
bottom so
so basically
to to get the coordinate for each Galaxy
all you have to do is you count at what
column it is that is the x axis column
number then the line number is the Y AIS
okay now that is assuming the code note
is at the at the top left and the Y AIS
goes downwards
positive okay but anyway that's how you
get a coordinate does it matter I mean
like traditionally in mathematics the y
axis up direction is
positive okay but usually in computer
Graphics the y- AIS up direction is
negative you know in computer Graphics
usually the corner the orine is on the
top left so the more down the more
negative I mean the more positive it
gets so it's the reverse of the
traditional math so which way should we
do I mean in this case it's probably
easier just to count down you know so
the first row is
just one or zero so second row is
y equals to two third row y equals to 3
so so any in other words any of the
Galaxy is identified by the column
number first then the row number okay
wait there are many ways to do
this okay you don't have to go into math
cordin you can just say row number and
column number okay same thing so let's
do the row number and column number so
you have row number and column column
number okay then then the distance is
okay so let's write it
down for
each symbol pound symbol uh
okay for each pound symbol it is
identified by row number and column
number okay fantastic row start at one
column
start at one not zero because zero is
the E from this C Java C++ idiots you
know they they they created this zero
convention which is very edotic it's
more conversent to do deal with zero
okay uh I have arle on that why does
array you know start with zero or
what so physics default emac key binding
whe [ __ ] up your fingers that's true
okay now let's focus on today's problem
so you identify each of the galaxies by
row number then by column number okay
here we documented the problem then
what's next then the distance between
them is just
um uh let's
see let the difference
okay let's just write it down
okay let's sum them all together
so the
distance
between two
galaxies is the
diff let's just say let's just write in
the rule number
numbers plus okay so something like that
diff column
number so difference between row number
and column number and plus one I think
so I believe that is that
okay so difference row number plus
difference column number okay let's
try so this the column difference is
zero and a row is one two three 1 2 3 4
five so the second one is
five the first one is column one 5 - 1
is 4 okay so you don't have to + one
uh but uh in fact you need to minus one
wait uh wait
so so this is the off by one
problem okay I need to think
so let's
see so the difference between these two
[Music]
e
so one 2 3 4 oh one two 3 4 oh so you
don't have two to add or
minus okay
so so you don't have to add or
minus uh let's make sure so what about
here 1 2 3 4 5 5 - 1 is four one 2 3 4
that's
correct so so yeah so looks like it's
correct okay so yeah so looks
like okay that's a
difference uh now the other problem you
need to
find
get all possible
pairs of the
galaxies order no matter
okay uh
then then just uh sum up all their
distances that's
it that is the outline of the algorithm
okay okay let's start to code
um let's start to code uh let's start
wam
language
um okay
input equals
to uh yeah that thing it's a
string so it's a string then so the
first problem
is
to the first problem is to make
them uh expand the universe so to find
all columns so let's think about how we
want to do this so God this is tedious
it's going to be 30 minutes or 40
minutes [ __ ]
uh this
so so can you use regular expression
yeah but the problem is how do you uh
find or out all the all the empty
columns
now that would be a problem if you use
regular expression it's very easy to use
regular expression to find all lines of
a s same
symbol but it it's a
problem if you have vertical unless you
do a transpose like you flip this text
but in general in most programming
languages you don't have a transpose
function on text in wfam language you
have a transpose function on
matrices but this is not a matrix this
is a text so is there a transpose kind
of function on a rectangular text no
because that is in general that's not
there's no such issue so what you can do
is you can convert this text into a
matrix so each element of The Matrix is
just a
character okay yeah you
can you can first of all expand all the
empty rows by using regular expression
then you turn this whole thing into a
matrix where each element is a character
then you do a transpose of the Matrix
then you turn the Matrix back into a
text you know into a string lot lots of
you know multi line multi line strings
then you again you do the regular
expression to find okay that's one
solution that's one solution you do this
conversion to Matrix back and forth okay
um the other solution is
you uh that you know that seems to be
the
easiest solution but not necessarily the
fastest the the more tedious solution
more direct is you just
[Music]
manually get the character each of each
column then you get the same
character the same column the next row
same column the next row next row next
row if they are all the same then you
insert a
row yeah you can do
that so the code will be a loop
well I mean
well yeah it's
tedious it will be extremely easier if
you just convert it to Matrix and do
this transpose okay now let's think
about if we convert to Matrix can we
walk directly in the Matrix without
converting it back and forth between
Matrix and
text if we convert these two Matrix how
do you find out if all rows are of the
same
character very easy okay also how do you
find out all Columns of the same
character very easy and how do you
insert a new row or new column very easy
okay so now it's decided let's convert
these two Matrix
okay okay so now the next problem is in
wam language how do you
convert a text you know like that to a
matrix
of course there are many
ways
um but let's see if there's a building
function
okay uh Matrix Q Matrix this matric
Matrix form okay this this is 100 um
functions for Matrix let's see
yeah why don't you do multi column yeah
okay
so Matrix form adjacency Matrix let's
look up what is that adjacency Matrix
give the vertex vertex adjacency Matrix
of a
graph okay
that's converts a graph to Matrix okay
so there's a
lot uh functions on Matrix but what we
want is some kind of function that
converts a string to
Matrix maybe there is maybe not I think
probably
not okay but but still it's good to look
at this thing because later on event you
know we'll need you know we'll kind of
need uh some Matrix functions scaling
Matrix rotation Matrix plus 3D Matrix
distance Matrix okay distance Matrix
gives the Matrix of distances between
each pair of
elements that that that solves the major
component of our problem here
exactly uh let's make
a screenshot of this
thing it's a
fantastic now what is incidence Matrix
incidence Matrix give the vertex Edge
incidence
Matrix uh of a graph okay that's related
to a graph now graph here means graph
Theory which means networks which means
dots and lines you know those are graph
graph and Matrix there's a kind of tight
relation uh although I don't understand
exactly so gives a Vertex Edge vertex
Edge so each vertex and Edge incidence
Matrix oh
okay so that's not
what we want um so we have incidence
Matrix now the other thing we want to
know is how do you identify all the so
given a matrix how do you
identify all the same elements you know
get their row row and column uh
coordinate yeah so is there some kind of
um yeah give a matrix you you want a
function to
find oh yeah I know cases so that also
useful case you know the function cases
will do that or positions
exactly uh why don't we just why don't
you show some code so that people
understand instead of uh
okay so let's say let's we have a matrix
here uh let's say you know now just two
dimensional Matrix okay now let's say
this is our Matrix and we want to know
all the position of the character I mean
the number one okay uh so let's say
equals to okay then uh positions
okay this is useful because we will need
to identify the coordinates right then
we'll need to do combinatorics to find
all possible pairs of each two Co
coordinates then we use the then we will
need this incidence Matrix okay uh wait
not instant what is that the other one
we
found uh what
was distance okay where is the distance
distance Matrix
okay there it is distance
Matrix between each pair of element okay
fantastic
so oh so in fact we don't actually need
to do the combinatorial pairing all we
have to do is just give give the
coordinates of all the galaxies this
will compute all the distance for
us
fantastic F
beautiful ah beautiful beautiful okay
but first of all let me show you this
position okay position Matrix and we
want to identify we need a pattern here
so the pattern is just one that will
return all the Matrix
positions that matches this C this
pattern which is just one so if you
evaluate that so let's see what is the
evaluate region so by the way I'm using
W mod I'm using
emx andan modan mod here is the source
code 3,000 lines of code and here's a
website you can go to it wam mod what
you know it's allow you to code wfam
language fantastic in emac with s flly
Keys the most efficient key binding in
the universe more efficient than Vim
then VI then neovim then Evo mod okay
flag Keys that's what I'm using uh and
I'm
using uh vak keyboard layout so WFAN
language mod the code is on GitHub there
you can get it for free okay so now back
here back here close that close that now
we want to run this yeah so now what is
the
region uh Eva region okay tab e okay so
you just select that and select select
that tab
e let's see is the syntax correct no the
syntax is incorrect so what is
the
uh what is the let's look at the
documentation of position
function to JavaScript so Google knows
where you live position pattern gives a
list of positions at which objects okay
so we got a extra comma here you see in
F language extra comma is not allowed so
let's try it
again tab e eval
region there it
is so the first result is the Matrix
there the second result is the is the
coordinate where this pattern one occurs
so the first one is 1 three row one item
three column three and the second item
is row two column two indeed so that's
what you're going to do okay
so that will identify all the galaxies
galaxies galaxies galaxies for our
problem this pound sign then you just do
distance Matrix um you know you just do
distance Matrix that will return all
possible
distances then you just sum it sum it up
okay uh which is total the function name
is just total a list you just return
return the sum why is it not called sum
like in python or other edotic languages
because sum in wam language you have a
function called sum
that that takes the sum of a
mathematical sum you know this is a
mathematical sum not not total okay so
for example 1 /x x goes from uh let's
say 1 to 10 okay evaluate
that the result is 78 7381 divided by
2520 that is sum summation okay
summation which is I use as my logo uh
my badge for my
website summation okay that's that is
why in wam language total is not called
sum as in other
uh languages because this is more proper
because total is actually what you
typically mean you know you want Total
things then sum is a summation okay so
but anyway that's not our problem so but
so okay so we demonstrated that so the
first thing is actually
to uh to turn this into a matrix okay
now let's go back to this problem so
solution uh
turn the text into a
matrix
add
extra uh add extra columns and rows for
any
empty column and row okay
then then
use
okay uh
then use position to give a list of all
coordinates how do you C uh well
coordinate in a geometry we say
coordinate but in a matrix how do you
call them the position
uh
index okay you call them index indexes
okay
then then use distance Matrix to get all
distances okay then just total okay that
is the algorithm fantastic
beautiful uh now so the first thing the
first thing is turn the text into Matrix
now that you that we still is there a
convenient way that's what I'm looking
for of course I can start coding and you
know do you know pass you know regular
expression you know read each line then
go through each character then push you
know into a matrix you know I can do
that but it's not the proper way
especially when you coding wolam
language because when you code wo from
language the the best way to get
solution is to think about the problem
you know exactly what you want to do
then then half of the time this one one
single function to do it okay this is
not C you know when you start to for
Loop for Loop oh this eror for Loop
debug
then see
idiots okay so yeah we want to turn the
text into Matrix so I don't think so
um okay so let's quickly look
for a list all functions that contains
the word text okay text grid text
justification text line uh enter text
packet find image text oh that's
artificial
intelligence return text packet that's
networking programming text text string
text sentences text structure what is a
text structure generates a nested
collection of text elements
what let's have a look text structure
generate the nested collection of text
elements object representing the
grammatical structure of the natural
language text okay that's not what we
want yeah it's it's representing the
grammatic structure okay uh I just want
to turn a text into some kind of
alignment and padding and
uh oh vertex texture coordinates okay no
that's the option text texture mapping
okay texture that's computer Graphics
stuff we don't care it's a text packet
text L uh string to Matrix okay I'm kind
of I'm wasting my time here this is not
you know I'm I'm like like just going
around okay let's start actually let's
actually code this okay so you want to
turn this into a matrix yeah but
still so you want to turn a text into
Matrix some something like string two
Matrix okay do we have string two
Matrix uh
there's no
stream partition
okay a c d e f
g g g
g okay that's getting close stream party
I and split string so you split string
and CH to string to
char so do we have a stram to
function string to by array string to
stream uh you have split
string yeah so split string we can can
use string rifle string
split okay string uh
split string
split yeah
patteron okay that's what we want to
split at any of the
position okay string St pattern
okay this is not good I'm wasting too
much
time great fantastic I don't know hello
I don't know hello oer Z
Ora okay
so oh God I'm wasting time how long I've
been talking 45 minutes we haven't even
actually begin to C let's just let's
start to uh write code okay string split
okay uh let's just manually whatever you
know stop like talking philosophy and
you know not let's just get the code
going
because uh okay so we got that that that
we don't distance we don't care yeah so
okay now evaluate the whole
thing do we have the right syntax we do
okay it worked okay so uh Sprint sprit
uh
print
evaluated okay so we got yeah that's
what we want and then for each we want
to
um you know uh we have a function that
turns a
string a character into each array
element we I'm pretty sure we have that
function okay so here is all functions
name whose name contains the word
character character counts
character uh I know the there's a
function two character code word
character wi space character uh
character
encoding characters okay character
string gives a list of characters in
string that's what we
want so let me show you okay so for
example character AB c d okay evaluate
this line
and uh wait characters not character
okay but is there a function with name
character there it is represent a single
character in read okay that's like you
see this read is like the lisp phonetics
read Mark you know read syntax read
syntax but that's not we want okay we
want characters
here okay so you see it turns a string
into each character by itself okay
that's what we want so so first split
then map okay so map map a function to
this list okay then the level we don't
care now what function this is the
function okay so map uh so we don't even
so there it is map so that will
return a matrix already I think yeah I'm
pretty sure that you
know how elegant let's try it tab
e eval region fantastic okay now let me
show you this in wam
language okay there it is there it is
how beautiful is it
beautiful so let's see so we each you
see so now we got the Matrix now we can
do this in Matrix
form which make it pretty you see we got
a matrix fantastic beautiful now let me
do a screenshot of
this fantastic okay so now we got a
matrix the next thing to do is add extra
column very easy
so you know let you know according to
this problem you are expanding the
universe basically what you want to do
is that any column that's empty you want
to add a extra column to it and same
thing for empty rows okay so let's do
the Row first so if a row is
omt then
um then you want to insert a column
okay
so again this is a matrix problem so we
need to look at
the
um why don't we I mean why don't we show
this graph what is this close
that okay that is fantastic
showing there but you cannot see
actually okay need to move on so next
problem is to identify all empty rows
now is there a buing function that lets
you do that that's why we are looking at
this all the all functions whose name
contains the word Matrix now this is is
one of the feature one of the property
of wolam
language when you C wolam language there
is only one thing of concern function
core function okay nothing else no
objects no memory no
reference you know no pointers no
methods no class you know this nothing
the only thing you needs to be concerned
is function which function to call
and function of course function names
and all function names contain are fully
spelled out there's no short you know FN
stand for
function or DF stand for defined
function nothing like that everything is
fully spell out that's one of the major
properties when you code wam language
okay so we are looking at you know all
functions that contains the word Matrix
which basically contains you know which
is all
functions having anything to do with
Matrix okay and now we need to find yes
we we kind of need to identify all
rows all rows whose entry are of the
same entity which is a DOT okay yeah or
we want to
identify now okay so now this
problem you know usually you want to
think of the problem in terms of
mathematics because once you
know if this is common thing in math
then you know there's a function uh in
this case to identify the same elements
is uh what how you
um so you do have identity Matrix SYM
you see you have symmetric Matrix
symmetric Matrix Square Matrix we don't
care shiming Matrix that's for
transformation unitary Matrix okay
unitary Matrix convert the uh the
unitary Matrix to a structured array I
don't know what that means unitary
Matrix
okay what is the unitary
Matrix oh that's you know that's like
basically your Matrix that means one in
complex Field Complex numbers
okay uh distance Matrix disk Matrix
Diamond diagonal matrix whether it's
diagonal matrix or not we don't care we
want to find the empty rows and empty
columns okay orthogonal
Matrix
uh I don't think we care about that
converts The orthogonal Matrix
to a structured
array now what does orthogonal converts
orthogonal orthogonal matrices when
represented a structured array allow for
a convenient specification and more
efficient operations including inverse
and linear
solve so what uh Matrix decompositions
that use orthogonal
matrices what
oh the co okay so orthogonal Matrix
is well it's like linear algebra the
property of these me elements they are
linearly
independent both vertically and
horizontally something like that
so so but what they mean by array I mean
oh this is new in 14
experimental okay we don't care about
that new in version 14 version 14 just
came out like a year
ago uh so distance so when whenever it's
new usually we don't care because new
it's not classic new is like you know um
let's see cross Matrix cross Matrix
gives a matrix whose elements are one in
Center cross shaped
okay uh give cross Matrix gives a matrix
whose elements are
one in a center crossed shaped region
that extends our positions along each
index Direction and zero otherwise I
don't understand oh
okay
uh literally
across
so this function cross Matrix generates
a cross
Matrix but
band okay let's look at band band i j
represent the sequence of positions on
the diagonal band okay no that's not
what we want we need
straight columns and uh so you got minus
you got
um okay again I'm talking too much now
let's why don't we just start to
actually code instead
of so we need to find empty columns and
empty rows
right so empty columns and empty
rows uh
oh [ __ ] I'm going to take more than one
hour today for this adjacency Matrix
okay uh view Matrix okay
so per
mutation
reflection negative Matrix
FL box Matrix
let's see distance
I I don't know I don't know so I mean I
can start to code
it or I
can look for
the proper
solution you know I can start to code it
just
by uh just by going through the Matrix
and get the first you know like do a
loop or a
map so
so let's focus on a row first so you
want to repeat empty rows I mean rows
that's just a
DOT so how do you do that well you
can you can
map okay well you can do a map okay
so okay
so you can do map
one of the map function map at map
thread moving map parallel map map
all oh God I really I hope I finish this
today okay let's just code let's not
[ __ ] around let's just
code uh code okay so
code
uh so you want to find all empty
matrices empty rows so for each empty
row you
okay let's just do it okay so so we can
do replace all okay that is
[Music]
the let's kind of find and replace okay
expression rules okay
expression rules okay that's what we
need to do so
uh let's say Matrix equals to that
okay that's our
Matrix then replace rules so we need to
replace this Matrix so the rule is
that uh empty row okay so we're going to
have a pattern here and we name the
pattern empty row so what is the pattern
the pattern is going to be like that and
uh each item is a DOT and uh
repeat it okay so that is how you find
an empty row okay so once you find it
you want to map you want to replace it
by this is pattern matching structural
symbolic pattern matching you can think
of it like a regular expression except
regular expression is for text only for
for string in wam language everything is
a symbol the whole language entire
source code
is you know like structural symbols so
you can directly replace the you know
the structure kind of like syntax
syntactic
manipulation and in lisp in a very low
level I mean in a very weak form it's
called lisp Mar okay so anyway that's
what we are doing we are doing symbolic
replacement so each empty row replaced
by uh two empty rows let me show you how
that's done okay so a list empty row and
empty row okay so let me show you so
there it is okay this replace
all uh let's say x Matrix equals two
okay so let's
see you know this is okay let's anyway
so replace all a matrix then uh we can
try it let's see if that works I think
it would
okay uh yeah let's try it here in wam
language let's just paste it
here fantastic okay now let's do Matrix
form uh
okay now this Matrix
form so it's easier to see fantastic now
we got a problem you see now this row we
repeat it however it become it become
kind of
um I mean it became kind of like uh
nested so we don't want that so in order
to you know we need uh in JavaScript
it's
called triple dot
operator um you
know let's go JavaScript
tutorial it's called what is it called
uh triple dot operator okay eer iterable
object
okay spread operator the most idiotic
name in JavaScript but anyway so in in
lisp you also have that you know usually
it's called called um anyway in wam it's
called sequence of SP splice okay uh so
let me just do it
splice sequence okay so let's look up
the documentation sequence represents a
sequence of arguments to be spliced
automatically into any function okay now
this one is new in 1996 that's what I
want now let's look up a related thing
is splice
okay splice into any list which is
appears a sequence okay splice Is 2020
so sequence is what we want represent
the sequence of arguments to be spliced
automatically into any function meaning
basically meaning remove the the
brackets or the braces you know so a
Leist becomes just a bunch of
arguments so so that is sequence okay
that's what we want to use so here you
say sequence
okay what wait
God
yeah uh
what uh why is it
not
anyway I believe like that okay so let's
try
no oh yeah wait what
wait the syntax is not
correct there it is I believe that's
it
so yeah this is original this is a new
we you see there's
two empty lines we added okay so that's
fantastic now we need to do the same
thing for row so uh we can do it but a
easier way is just to transpose the
thing okay so let's just let me just do
my things because we are getting too
long
transpose okay so we want to transpose
The Matrix then do the exactly the same
thing again okay let's forget about form
and elegance let's start to just quickly
get this going okay
so you transpose The Matrix then then
you do the same operation then uh then
you transpose it back when you are done
okay
so that should do it let's let's uh okay
let's The Matrix form here is annoying
okay so basically that is our code let's
do it again
uh no something is wrong transpose twice
Why Oh The Matrix form god well because
of
the wait that should
work transpose The Matrix you transpose
The Matrix then you do replace
or then you transpose back so why
so so
why so why is this
showing
that oh because you attach yeah so so
this is already stupid so we don't want
that you know you don't want this Matrix
form to be part of the assignment that
is why okay let's evaluate it again
there it is fantastic beautiful okay so
this is so you can see there's also a
double column here so that is we
completed our job now we
can you know we can kind
of clean
this
code yeah but but
uh let not okay let's move on so let's
Sol try to solve the problem so we we
pad it
then okay solution okay solution put it
to top uh so we pad you know we padded
them we expanded the universe then this
test code we don't need okay now you
need to get the position you need to
find all positions of of the that okay
let's try
that uh what not here here
paste
empty oh yeah the the variable name is X
Matrix oh
wait uh okay so let's do this all
again paste run fantastic okay so this
this exactly this is all the positions
of the Galax galaxies that's their
coordinate okay
fantastic
now uh so what's next then distance okay
uh let's try it okay so wait so
distance uh my Matrix then you want to
identify all
pound sign okay I
believe paste it
here okay zero so so what is the
documentation for distance
Matrix maybe we
misunderstood oh okay so you
need
what maybe this is not what we want so
distance
Matrix gives the Matrix of the Matrix of
distance between each
pair of
elements okay so what does it take I'm
not sure so let's
try okay there it is now
so what okay so it just take one Matrix
and it returns
this
[Music]
um this distance so what does this
mean distance Matrix
okay so distance Matrix gives the Matrix
of distances between each pair of
elements each pair of
elements uh
what what is that distance I
don't understand
so let me let me let me show this okay
so uh so
that so
that so that okay then
position let's try
that there it is much easier to read so
we begin with this then we expanded the
universe then we also expanded
vertic then here is the identification
of all all the Galaxy
is
then then here is the distance Matrix
this part I don't understand what is
it okay so you need to okay
so okay now we are trying to find a
pattern between this one and this one
what does it indicate
so here's 2 two one one it
doesn't I don't know what is the
distance
Matrix the uh distance function so so
what is the distance gives the Matrix of
distances matric of distances of each
pair
of each pair of
elements UI and
UJ
okay oh okay
so so but
does any
know anyone watching anyone like
continuing watching this
episode now my coffee is
gone uh yeah but I need to I need to
finish
this I I want to have a break but uh I
need to finish this so what right now we
are trying to figure out what exactly
this distance Matrix is
doing it seems to be related to our
issue you know our problem is that given
any two pound signs we want to know
their
distance uh so this distance Matrix
seems Seems related or can do what we
want but we are not
sure uh distance Matrix you see it takes
a bunch of arguments now I don't know if
those arguments are just
elements in The Matrix or it just the
whole
Matrix between each pair of
elements
so between each pair of elements so I
don't understand so let's
see let's say distance
Matrix 1 2 3 4
let's see what it
does
huh
what so it always return a matrix but
the input may be a onedimensional matrix
or it may be two-dimensional
Matrix uh okay this is confusing
what when is this function introduced
this is introduced in
2015 okay adjacency Matrix
nearest nor
cross okay find cruster distance
function
okay uh distance and similarity measures
okay so our problem is to ident
ify okay uh we
can ignore this function and just
manually code it it's not
difficult so let's see compute a
distance Matrix from a list of integers
zero one I mean 1 2 3 4 so you
got
uh yeah but I don't understand why what
what distance because a distance
implies two
things so is that a combination of all
these possible
numbers and what is mean by Distance by
them okay so this distance function
seems
seems AI is machine learning thing oh
okay yeah this is actually a machine
learning
thing okay now I don't understand what
exactly it is distance function so if
you look
up um distance function in machine
learning I think it'll tell you okay
okay so let's try to quickly see if that
makes
sense distance Matrix of machine
learning a distance Matrix is a
fundamental Concept in machine learning
particularly
including particularly particularly in
in
clustering dimensionality reduction okay
and other the
unsupervised oh learning techniques
here's a comprehensive overview what is
distance Matrix a distance Matrix also
known as a dis similarity
Matrix okay or similarity Matrix is a
square Matrix that represents the pair
wise
distances or
similarities okay so distance here means
similarity okay so it returns a pair
wise similarity between a set of objects
okay data points or samples
okay so for example you have a apple and
you have a orange there's a distance
between them here distance means
similarity how similar are there versus
you know say an apple and a cat a cat
and a dog a house and a car a car versus
a
Apple so this gives a number to indicate
similarity okay now
the but why is it a matrix
because you if you have a list of things
let's say if you have three things you
have one two three you have three
pairings
pairings so if you have four things how
many pair four out of two combinatorics
okay which is 12 I
think so when you have four things you
have 12 uh you know we are kind of
digressing but but distance Matrix
always return a square Matrix so that's
what the part I don't understand why
does it return a
matrix a distance Matrix okay so data
points sample each entry in The Matrix
represents the distance of similarity
between two
objects okay but which two
object oh so the Matrix is always
symmetric okay no negativity zero
diagonal okay that all works
out okay so that's not what we want
okay let's
not you know digress let's get back to
our problem our problem is to find the
actual distance so that's easy so what
we have to do is first of all identify
all the positions okay this function
will give you all positions
now each position each coordinate each
pair of numbers here represents
a nod I mean represent the Galaxy you
know this this pound sign symbol and now
you want to find all possible pairings
between them uh that's
easy
uh to uh there's a function to do that
so let's uh let's let's let's see what
that
is okay I I believe the function may be
named
temple temple list and generate the list
of all possible Andes of elements from
list okay let's
try uh
Tes
[Music]
AB okay uh Tes you need oh yeah you need
uh two okay so a a a b a BB okay that's
all possible turos okay but we don't
don't want we only want unique items we
don't and we don't want the order
doesn't matter so there's a permutation
there's a
subsets uh I believe it's subsets
subsets subset and give a subset
containing and most n elements okay give
a possible or all subsets no that's not
what we want uh
Boma there's a permutations and comput
combinations let's think
so possible or pairings so order doesn't
matter so it's like given N Things you
want
to take
two and order doesn't matter okay so
that would be called combination okay I
believe that's called
combination uh permutation so we have
permutation
sub
subsets uh least of all possible subsets
uh least of all subsets containing at
most n elements that's what we want
subsets okay let's
try yeah let's
try subsets let's say AB c d
e f g okay two
okay so yeah so that's what we want but
however it also include one elements but
we always want just two elements so
that's how you do so there it is a b a a
d AE okay that seems to be what we want
but too many let's reduce the items so
we can actually
see
verify so AB c d you got a a a d b c b d
c d that's that's what we want four
things the combination is then 4 * 3 is
uh then order doesn't matter divided by
two so you got six 1 2 3 4 5 six so
that's what we want
subsets okay so you you just want to
take the subsets of this positions okay
uh let's give a
name then say coordinate list okay
equals to that then then you just need
to say
subsets okay subsets only two possible
things okay
so that's what we
want uh
wait
positions uh position
what you got positions then
then you want subsets okay
so
subset
okay oh yeah so we got the syntax R so
there
there and there
no what what is
this subsets not subset you're missing s
so why is
it
uh oh okay so you yeah so s we are
missing s okay so let's try
again that's what we want so each item
here is a pairing is a possible pairing
between two galaxies okay now we just
need to find the distance
okay uh so the distance is Let's uh okay
so let's copy that uh so we getting
starting to get too long too tired so so
but
um
yeah so one pairing is like that okay so
let me just show you so one of the
pairing is like that so the distance is
you
um you apply a function so let's
say replace or
uh replace or we just want to replace at
the level one okay so replace add
replace replace rules level spec one
okay uh replace apply rule or list of
rules in attempt to transform the entire
expression okay
uh here by default apply rle was only to
complete Expressions
okay so for example let's say a
b a b
c a okay now replace a replace by three
okay evaluate it
uh that didn't
work why why why is that ABCA that
didn't
work uh because
is that because you need the list
here no
this is taking too
long
[ __ ] 1990 minutes already now why why is
this not working now I'm got impatient
now need to finish this talking too
much
a
what that El logical why why is that not
work replace AB C A A okay that should
work now there's something I'm
fundamental I'm kind of missing or
something the rule should be this form a
list of rules can be given the rules are
tried in order the result of the first
one that applies is
returned okay if none of the rule
applied original expression is returned
yeah but we do have apply oh okay so we
didn't specify a level that's
right okay so there you need the level
one there it is beautiful did you see it
yes okay so we miss so we are you know
I'm very I'm being very specific if you
know wam language because typically you
use replace all but I'm being very
specific but anyway so we we have this
you know this is how you
do kind of like this Mark okay syntactic
replacement okay so but now now we want
a form we want a pattern the pattern
will be like that so A okay so B is a
integer then then
C D okay A B C D we have a pattern like
that and we want to replace it by
distance okay uh let me show you so here
we are going to compute the
distance so AB is a coordinate so yeah
remember uh the way to compute distance
talk show is this diff row number and
diff colum number so a minus C
absolute okay
so so it's going to
be replaced
by absolute A minus
B plus is it
plus yeah
plus okay
plus B minus D okay ACB D okay a c b d
okay so let's Okay so this is a rule
okay so
now oh actually so wait let me show you
so actually it should be he that is the
pattern this pattern will get replaced
by that okay and here is a expression
okay so this is our
Matrix so actually not the Matrix we
want this subset you know this
coordinate uh thing then we just total
this and that's it okay so this now
let's just start to quickly code you
don't know what I'm doing but that's
okay so we got the coordinate list then
you get the
subset uh subsets okay uh subset is
uh Galaxy pairs
uh
uh God God got got got
got got got got okay that's that's the
list of pairs of all galaxies okay then
you just do uh
replace you don't care uh this this this
no then you just put that there okay you
for all pairs of the galaxies whenever
you see this pattern you replace by
their distance okay let's see if that
works okay so let's
try Galaxy
pairs Galaxy
pairs evaluate okay need to magnify one
more
time okay that's the list of Galaxy
pairs then all we have to do is just do
this
replacement this replace all the Galaxy
pairs by their distance then just total
okay
total okay percent sign means the last
output shift enter 37 4 374 is it
correct please Let It Be I'm done with
this problem I got tired are you working
on solution again yes Z Zelda or zela
whatever check check YouTube okay
where's my YouTube let's see what what's
the problem the Google
Chrome okay of code so 374 fantastic and
beautiful
now we're going to work on our problem
okay 374
fantastic
now we just compress all this thing into
one single line and and solve our
problem okay okay so yeah okay so wait
so you need to get the total so
uh so wait so okay not distance Matrix
we need total that's right total
add that so
result equals to that okay and that's it
that's
it okay that's a solution you know so we
going to we kind of so this is the
solution let's compact it let's let's uh
compact it now we need to read the
problem into a string okay let's put it
back so here here is today's talk show
the problem URL the description the
algorithm steps and our code for this to
input now we just need to the real input
now the real input is we saved it here
yeah copy the file path close that uh
and uh make a backup and let's start to
put out again so the input we'll need to
read the input
so how do you read the file I don't
remember so wam language so let's go to
you know if you just search for ex wam
tutorial uh Exel wam tutorial you'll
find it and what we need is to read okay
so just search for
read uh read uh no read file
what why is it why cannot you find read
function pattern matching Advanced data
structure symbol principles load file
okay uh load file is not what we want we
just read we just want to read the text
file so okay I need to add so this you
know you can find it by shell tasks you
go to Shell tasks then you have list
files list file path functions delete
the is file directory file exist check
file date read file there it is okay I
need to kind of make this page a link in
the panel so it's easy to find because
this is a general um so anyway read
string file path okay so read
string so X input equals to read string
and here is the file path there it is uh
let's copy it let's see if it
works okay that works then you know huge
file yeah okay let's delete
that H
yeah delete that so we we read the
stream actually we can we don't have to
go to uh the not let just run it here so
we got the input okay so input then we
set the Matrix then Matrix equals to
that then Matrix equals to that then
codon okay so but um
so if we just run this do we get the
result okay result equals to total and
uh
then
print result okay let's run this let's
just run it 376 or something
334 334 correct now let's use our own
input okay so the input now is this read
file
run
it okay
974 the solution is 974
[Music]
submit that's the right answer of course
one shot solution
fantastic now who is watching here say
hi okay give me some high
five finally we solved it
um and uh we can do more by you know I
can kind of go
explain and lots of simplification okay
lots of the you know this this this code
for example let's put it back wait uh
where's the solution so my solution is
uh
output output yeah so there is a
solution close that
solution uh let's
say my solution okay so that is a number
now let's put it back syntax color it
showing browser that's today's problem
and today's code now this whole thing is
just one single line okay you can just
make it one one single line no more than
80 characters uh yeah no more than let's
say 100 characters
so I can continue to do that or or
that'll be it that's it for the day I
mean so what should I do should I
continue to kind of summarize and
compact the whole code into one single
line of no more than 100 characters or
this is uh you know so uh those of you
watching congratulations thank you T
tjack we got it okay let's see uh okay
uh and I'm tired so I think that's it
let's um that's it for
today unless you know someone wants me
to continue on the technicalities on the
Wonders you know the Fantastic
wonderful the science of programming you
know the the the science and art and the
mathematics of programming fantastic
hearts hearts HS
okay where's my Google thing let's see
day 11 okay so let's see five people
watching oh
okay okay that's it for today I guess we
shut down unless otherwise we shut down
in 1 minute or two okay uh you know this
solution I really need to make it
simpler yeah but
let not you know it you know and there's
also lots of other ways to do
this anyway yeah let's uh that's it for
now thank you guys if you guys like my
stuff you know always go to my website
go to
it.info just search for it you'll find
it and you'll find this page Kar code
and you scroll down here is the chat GPT
in intro uction of myself you know what
chat GPT thinks of
me because I have a big website so chat
GPT grabbed all text on my website so so
when you ask chat GPT something remember
I'm part of the
answer chat G integrated so anyway to
the go to the bottom so you can patreon
me patreon me okay Amazon gift card me
PayPal me let's see patreon who's got
you know5 $1,005 a month okay
yeah okay thank you guys bye
guys where we expose products and
software Dev and their stupidity okay uh
you got to be more specific well anyway
let's talk next time