good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of xsa talk show
today we are going to talk randomise
about programming languages i'm going to
tell you
uh what i have been doing in the past
month you know it's been a long time my
last video is probably a month ago hello
robin hello solo blankets
so programming languages so um let's
begin
so i did a lot of work in the past month
so
um
and uh you know writing my programming
language tutorials
emacs lisp wolfram language
javascript golan
and also pearl python i forgot to add
here
and lots of updates huge amount of
update i've been working on past month
so let's so i'm gonna tell you the
um uh programming language uh
the general the general elements of
programming languages you know
programming languages is not that hard
to learn you know
in a sense okay but if you really want
to be an expert you have to
you know spend a hard time not following
some
these days anyway so programming
languages they shared uh you know
some general elements so let's go to
emac list so you know you can just type
study
practical emac this you'll find my
website
and so i did a lot reorganization of my
web page so let me explain what's going
on here first
so you have several you have six major
topics you have emacs tutorial
you know this is for you beginners or
you know uh or
you've been using emacs for a while you
can learn for beginners where to
download uh emacs some frequently asked
questions imax first day emacs key
basics you know these are emacs
tutorials then and then it gets through
some
advanced stuff such as uh keo ring
uh you know in emacs you have a infinite
well almost you you have a
uh copy history so you can paste
previous you know so anyway so this
section emacs tutorial practical e-max
tutorial okay so you can learn emacs
then you can have then this chapter is
about e-max init so once you click that
you click here it tells you what's the
init file where is the init file on
windows or mac or on linux
and then
uh it tells you how to start emacs
without you need file what that what
does it do and how to modify it how to
load it how to you know
how to refresh you know how to read init
file without restarting emacs and all
that so everything you need to know
about init file about
uh save command history you know
anything you you may want to do in your
ini file so this section emacs init
okay then this section is about emacs
keys now in emacs everything is about
command and keys
so keys are critically important so
emacs key overview what's a general
organization of emacs keys
and emacs key layout diagram
and then how do you
define your own keys you know emacs is
all about keys
so that is the emax key section
then we have one two three four four
sections about emac lisp
so this is the main topic of today
proper topic the programming languages
images okay am i am i am i going let me
check video video check audio check okay
so emac lists the language so there are
set four sections
lisp basics
practical lisp practical emac list
and the emac list examples
and emac this how to write a major mod
now the list basics
is all the basic language elements
you know so you have introduction
emac this how how do you start to run it
uh how do you evaluate
the emac list code
how do you um
you know the basic elements of a
programming language such as how do you
print
arithmetics
you know how do you add plus you know
minus multiplication
uh arithmetics then you have convert
integer to float flow to integer or
number to string string to number and so
on and then you have the boolean type
which is true and false now in emac list
you don't have boolean type you don't
have dedicated brain type but every
language has some form of boolean true
and false
so these are so these are the general
elements of a programming language every
language has it you know earth how do
you do arithmetics how do you convert
inflow string
usually you know if the programming
language has types then you have true
force in every programming language then
you have test equality this is also
critical and if this is quite different
in every language in
perl python
ruby javascript wufang language in lisp
so here is the how emac this does
equality what what they consider two
things to be equal
you know whether there's a type
conversion automatic or things like that
so in the emac this case in this case
it's more
complicated a bit more complicated so
you know these are elements of
programming languages then you have how
do you define variables
then you have
in this case special to lisp you have a
blog expression this is like c
programming languages curly braces okay
block of expression then you have if
then else
then you have loop okay i'm not going to
go each
to every one of them so you have loop
you have string functions you have how
to format string and then you have how
to define a function this is the
basically the
last lesson you have to learn when you
learn a programming language writing a
function because every programming
language that's what you do right the
function or subroutine
so these are the basic elements of lisp
then you have also data structures
list in the in the image case you have
list vector sequence type and uh
functions that operate on them
you have also association list which is
like a kind of like a hash table but
less
um
less hash table hash table okay
basically it's just a list of
key and value pairs that's what
association list is
that exists
in
lisp in e-magnesis and in commonly skim
this of course in enclosure and it also
exists is existing wufang language okay
association is a list
of key value pairs but it's this however
we also have hash table
so in emaclis we also have hash table
which is also
a key value pairs but it's not a list
usually it's unordered depending on the
language for example in javascript
their hash table is called map
a map object which is a collection of
key value pairs and in javascript
that map object is ordered it keeps an
order okay in the emac this case it
doesn't keep older now in python it's
called dictionary in ruby it's called
hash table in perl it's also called hash
table i have a tutorial for each and
every one of these okay so hash table
another fundamental data structure in
just about every programming language
today except c
okay so any comments pay me okay donate
donate and buy my emacs tutorial you
know
if you are buy my emacs tutorial or
javascript tutorial or my emac
uh packages okay
it's over for you mr lee what the what
what are you talking about okay so hash
table okay
uh emac this you have hash table then
you have um
then you have
okay so these are the basic elements of
a language then you have functions how
do you define your function
uh then you have more advanced things
like throw and catch and exit function
and how do you
document your function inline
documentation of a function very common
in almost all modern languages you can
add embed documentation
into your function
and then you have more advanced you know
specific to lisp things symbols now
symbol is one of the
characteristics of lisp languages you
have symbol you don't have that in any
other in most of the languages you don't
have that in c c plus plus java you
don't have that in perl you don't have
that in python javascript well in
javascript you do have but that's
different so anyway symbol is one of the
weird thing in this it's a good thing
okay symbolic language that means when
you do computation
uh
that you know when you do computation
you are computing with symbols symbolic
compute programming language and that
includes wolfram language which i'm
going to talk about today
so how long have i been going 10 minutes
okay so
these are you know elements of a general
elements a programming language
so now i have organized so they are more
okay so so this section list basics they
are all about
um
the emac list
things variables functions arithmetics
in float you know how boolean types
uh if then else how do you do that
in imacrisp however they don't cover
they don't cover things particular to
emac lisp because as you know emacs you
know you have buffer you know emacs
allows you to you know you have buffer
you have the mini buffer which you know
you have commands you know you can meta
x and
how do you how do you write them how do
you how do you prompt user for ask users
some question you know or the and how do
you
how do you increase the font size how do
you color syntax color how do you you
know increase font size
syntax color how do you for example i
can do this highlight this uh you know
html and i can delete how do you delete
text in your buffer now these are unique
these things are unique to emacs lists
okay
these things doesn't exist in every
other language pearl java python you
know because they are not edited they
are not interactive so
so this section
practical emac this
cover all these things this is the most
important thing when you want to learn
emac lists for so for example uh i give
you overview
you know what how does it work then
writing a command so you can for example
let me show you so
for example
so
so here is a so let's switch to emac
this mod okay so here is a function
different
you know say yeah and all it does is
just insert yeah so evaluate it
then
meta x
y a y
enter it inserts text into your buffer
you see so you can do this you know
um
so this kind of features doesn't exist
in other languages so they are emacs
specific
so that's what this section is about
cursor
uh text editing interactive forms get
user input you know you might ask user
for a file name as useful directory x
ask user for a regular expression as
user for number your age you know and so
on
or ask user to choose to pick a choice
from a list such as meta x you know i
made a x so i type xa and it shows all
functions you know all commands that
start with the word star so this is a
pick a choice
name so
not available in general purpose
languages but in emacs so that's what
this section is about practical emac
beast
okay then
because it's a you know it's not
it's kind of a little bit unusual so you
have this section that's emac this
examples
now in here you have you know maybe 20
or 30
actual emax examples
uh writing a command for example let's
see
let's say uh let's pick a useful one any
uh all of these are quite useful for
example this
code different subtitle case region or
line
okay i'm gonna i'm gonna show you so
change
change to title case so once you define
these functions so let me show you
something is the title here okay so you
can copy that paste it here so i want to
call this
function i wrote so i just press a key
you see
this is the proper way so okay let's do
it in a new buffer so we don't have the
coloring
okay so
press a key
you
you see the you know
some of the words are capitalized that's
a title case so
so this section
emac these examples shows you
many useful commands to
you know you can study you can for
example in this one this one is a
cycle hyphen log low line space so let
me show you so when if you are a
programmer
often it's a case you want to add a
hyphen or low line between the words so
what i do is for example
press a key you see
i don't have to add you know i don't
have to move the cushion you know i just
press the key press the key again it all
becomes low line
or underscore
press the key again it becomes space
again you know it cycles so very useful
so this is the power of
learning a little bit emac bisp okay
so uh psycho so so and all these remove
accents you know sometimes you get this
uh you know european language so anyway
so that's this section so let's shrink
back so that's this section emac these
examples
then
the
now this is the more advanced how to
write a major mod you know
you know in major mod you have
programming language mods you have gold
land you have pearl java python mods you
know how do you for example
i'm using some emac list mod so for
example i want to delete this
uh
this this insert statement so i just
move my cursor here press a key
it deletes the whole
parenthesized expression for me
you know i don't have to
like delete one ends you know each you
know
in you know and you can delete the whole
function you know so that's
this is xr emacly smart so you can see
so let's press ctrl h m
describe mod so you can see
here is the documentation for xr emac be
smart okay
and then it shows you the key bindings
the functions for example let me let me
demo okay so for example i want to call
a function insert so i just type i
space
it becomes insert space again
there you have it now if i want to
define a function b
space different space you know i did
emac this coding a lot of times in my in
my videos
okay so e might be smart so if i want to
have a function let's say i don't
remember so
uh press tab uh
so i want to
function start with i i forgot the name
press tab again you know twice um
i and s you know so all these are
functions in e max is so what
yeah all these are what are these
functions like you want
in
and
anyway so
if you like it
bikes are emacly smart okay it's on my
website you can just search for it and
you'll find it
okay so these are the sections of emac
these you know these basics
practical emac this
image examples and how to write a major
mod how to write the major mod covers
syntax coloring uh you know and the
mechanism how does it work font lock mod
you know how does it work how do you
program your own uh new programming
language for example
how do you define your face you know the
face for example let me show you
list face faces display okay so you can
see
in here
are the um
other different uh
you know emacs call them face which is
different styles for coloring you can
define your own
you know for example if you are into
e-max themes color themes
okay
so all this section how to write a a
major mod okay
so that that's about imagine so let's go
back let's go back and talk about some
other languages okay so close that don't
save close that don't save
show today's talk
so emac beast
you know and uh
we you know each language has these uh
these elements and they exist in all the
languages now let's let me show you
wufam language so i also worked a lot on
wolfram language wolfram language is a
lisp you can say that because it shares
all the characteristics of this purely
nested expression check
symbolic
every identifier in the language is a
symbol check
lisp reader that's more advanced which
is
a built-in
feature that allows the language to read
expressions to to to read and pass the
expression of the language itself this
reader check
language also has that
it's called just read i think
okay
symbolic
nested expressions everything is nested
reader
marco this marker is another fundamental
characteristics of lisp languages wufan
language has that in fact the whole
wolfram language is symbolic pattern
matching that's
kind of more advanced mockup
so then you have another characteristic
is kind of functional programming you
know in this you just have parentheses
the header parenthesis is a function
name the rest is argument same thing in
wolfen language i can show you
so wu from language expressions so
for example symbols this is
explanation about symbols in wolfen
language
and
principles wufang language principles
let me let me get to the interesting
part syntax
okay so you can see
here is a wolfram language
in a uh you know in a syntax that's
purely nested you see
just
but in in lisp you have parentheses then
you put the function name then arguments
in wufang language you
use the square brackets
and the function n name goes outside of
the square bracket then you have
elements inside so this is purely nested
syntax
language but you can but wufang language
provides what's called
metaexpression
which is a shortcut for example
this code here you see
are identical to just these two lines
identical
exactly because the way wufang language
works is that whenever you type a
syntactic shortcut for example something
equals to something
you know that's not nested but however
wufang language will
automatically convert that to the full
form for you for example you see this
set
set edge lines something something
you see here
h lines equals through something
something so the full form for that
equal is actually the set
something something function so wufang
language will convert your shortcut
notations into this into this purely
nested expression just like lisp before
it does you know then then it compile
compiles okay so wolfen language
provides this
this this in this jargon this is called
meta expression
okay
so symbolic and and purely nested uh
syntax check
and also functional programming okay so
here is my you know i've been working on
this wolfram language um tutorial
a lot more in the past month so now it's
much better
and again you can see many of the
elements of programming language that
that occurs in just about every
programming language you have strings so
i tell you how in language they quote
their script strings do they have do
they allow single quote do they have
special here dog for example or hear
string you know so-called tear string
things like that so woofam string
then you have
how do you list all functions in wolfram
language
this is specific to farm language
because in most languages you cannot
in most programming languages there's no
facility to let you list all building
functions in the language
but in the case of wolfram language you
can and it's very useful and in the case
of lisp in general you can do that too
in the emacs list case it's called up
array up array contains all symbols in
the language
but in most other languages usually you
can't uh for example python
you know you do have a symbol table but
some of the syntax is not it's not a
function it's it's just the syntax you
know like see if while loop you know
see those are crap
so anyway so wolfen language then you
have um
so some you know some ways to list
all functions
but in other language you also have some
help facility for example python for
example let's see let's go to um my
powershell
okay
okay let's go to my powershell okay so
let's see
python
it's magnified okay so i have python
installed
you know so python you have a help
facility um
i forgot what's the syntax oh there
there it is but but not these
but anyway it allows you to list all the
functions of a module things like that
so i have a python tutorial somewhere
so let's go to let's go to um
am i doing good am i doing slow talk
talk guys
so let's uh hold on a second let's video
check audio check audio check video
check okay
okay so let's open all these okay go
land so
let me talk about all these power shell
okay
uh powershell and javascript okay
then golan
tutorial
then we are going to demo this code
pretty format powershell okay you know
in some automatic way we are going to
demo that today
so but first of all let's show the
python let's go to so these are all my
programming language tutorials go to
python open perl
open ruby
okay
okay so python for example you can there
you know help building help
so what you do is pi doc well oh yeah uh
pie dog
pie dog wire
pie dog is not installed i guess i i
didn't install it
yeah
i pi dock three let's try that pie dock
three wow
god
okay it's not installed it's it's not
bundled so anyway so python python
then
actually so
so if you start python
python 2.7 exit
ctrl d yeah
ctrl z plus return stupid python
you know it's fun
okay that's another topic it's you know
different um command line interface
in general open source programming
languages or linux they
you press ctrl d
to exit but in a python case it's ctrl z
that's a bit
um
different
so anyway you go to into python let's
say python3
what
why am i microsoft store no i don't want
microsoft store
what wait i have python3 installed but
it's just not in my path okay anyway
let's skip it
so python again you have all these you
know coding stream
string methods format string
operators
and you also have complex numbers true
and false boolean if then else loop so
these are you know and then data
structures these are fundamental
elements of a programming language just
about every language you have these so
you have a list which is the data
structure then you have ways to
enumerate the list to go through the
list
okay
you have different methods you know you
can also map then
then you know then you have some
esoteric
uh
technical tips about how to copy a
nested list
nested list and also the concept of
shallow copy and deep copy this depends
on language because many of these
languages these industrial languages
pearl python ruby javascript
java
and
and c and c plus first probably you know
they they at least they have a reference
concept so when you have a nested list
it's like the elements are references to
a list so you then you get to uh extreme
complexity of how do you copy your list
because then you have you know the
concept of shallow copy and deep copy
you know it's
pretty confusing it's pretty confusing
this is one of the reason you don't see
much deep nested list in
these industrial programming languages
is that because
it's because of these okay because their
list is actually a reference you know in
in java for example you don't actually
have a data type of a of a list or or
any
kind of hash table rather you have the
reference type
so you know that's technical detail
so list then you have in python you have
dictionary which is a hash table or a
list of key value pairs
you know data structures turbo then
then how do you define a function
this is the ultimate thing you want to
learn when you reach this part that
means you are pretty you know you are
pretty ready pretty much ready to code
the programming language
okay i've been talking for 30 minutes
now am i doing good now let's see some
comments and let me refresh myself
refreshment
how do you narrow into non-contiguous
regions in
emacs you cannot okay that's a simple
question
that i mean i mean the simple answer you
cannot crazy
crazy frog
thank you
wow you won a hackathon fantastic
fantastic major martial fantastic
congratulations
okay so we were talking about the
general elements of a programming
language all these are you know
almost exist in every language you know
variables
how to uh you know how to create the or
if you need to declare and what are the
types uh you know true and false boolean
operators arithmetics you know
uh data structures list hash table
these two are the most common in every
language and how do you go how how do
you go through them
and
and also if then else
if
then else that's a conditional that's
called conditional or branching or then
you also have the
common element of loop
while loop do loop for loop you know
these are very common in every
c
derived language such as
most most industrial programming
language
programming language per python job java
javascript ruby crap you know this
imperative
or even object oriented you know these
loops
okay and pearl so
so i that's that's what i have been
working on same thing in pearl so you
have same thing same kind of thing i
teach you um so check out my tutorial
okay if you like them uh read them
brad brian nakamoto hey are you the
brian i know
you are i think oh my god no i
didn't i haven't
no i haven't seen you uh messages is it
on twitter i haven't been using twitter
for uh much
oh my god brian good
oh god
you know i um
i'm so happy to see you so let me um
when we are offline i'm gonna talk uh
talk to you okay so you know
we we should have we should do a a meet
up again you know let's uh yeah it's
been a long time and long story oh my
god my personal life you know
has it you know has been bad times
so anyway so
all the programming languages okay so
let's get back to yeah let's get back to
um
talk about programming languages
oh yeah youtube censored lots of
languages let's see top top chat let's
go to live chat let's see
[Music]
okay so programming languages so um
let's see what uh what else powershell
uh python to be so so let's go back to
what so you know we kind of covered that
you know the general element the generic
elements of every programming language
okay and um
wufam language powershell um
javascript and also javascript you know
i
uh javascript you know i have you know
let's not talk about javascript you know
because i already have it
uh javascript so i mean then there's
golan one of my favorite
language this is the proper c
and c plus plus replacement okay
screw
screw rust you know those those of you
into
memory memory you know digging memory
did ring
so golan is fantastic you know it's a
proper c replacement c plus and c plus
plus after 20 years finally you know
it's extremely simple
uh and easy to learn and uh
and and what's more you know you know
like you know you have beautiful
languages like scheme or maybe haskell
but the problem is nobody uses it nobody
use it
okay but gold line is different golan
you know some people will mention nim or
crystal any and others but but golan
is one major difference between golan
and the other cool languages okay golan
is industrial it's widely used okay it's
you know of course it's it came from uh
google
so it's one of the
uh powerhouse you know golan and very
simple and i like it
so again you have the basic elements uh
you know you have string you have string
functions you have how to convert to and
from string
and in the golang case you have special
issue of
byte
character
and uh
encoding you know these kind of issues
and integers you know
so um then you have types in gold land
you have variables you have zero value
which is the default
initialization values for variables that
you didn't assign a value so anyway go
then okay
so i uh i like gollan uh one of the most
simple and powerful in the widely used
programming language that will get you a
job
okay
if you learn haskell if you learn lisp
if you learn um
uh-huh
you know you learn elegant language if
you learn e-max list you'll not get a
job nowhere
you know for each one of those languages
you have ten thousand golden jobs
that's a power in java of course java
java and c and c plus plus in in c sharp
so okay so that's that's it about the
languages let's see i've been talking
for 40 minutes already so uh let's go to
let me let me maybe start to demo
powershell okay
so i want to demonstrate this great
thing pretty format powershell this
this i just discovered
um
last week so i wrote a script to do that
so you could you can automatically
format your code now for example
uh for example let's go to okay so let's
go to
yeah let me show you this thing so
auto format so let's so let me show you
um
you know so one of the two of the great
languages of modern day you know in the
past five years golan golan and
javascript deno okay they
they have the feature of automatically
formatting your code automatically built
in with the compiler so that means when
you download the demo javascript or when
you download golan it's already there
you don't you don't have to go out and
and download extra
lint or whatever
so you can
so let me show you okay so let's let's
go to uh javascript okay let's show you
a
demo or javascript
formatting javascript code using deno
okay
uh okay so let's
then after that
i'm gonna show you automatic formatting
of golem code with the building facility
then i'm gonna show you the powershell
the power the powershell
is not exactly built in you have to
download it but it's part of the
microsoft powershot then you actually
have to write a script to call that
because it the input is a string it's
not the file so you have to open the
file read the string
call the format it returns a string you
have to put it back into the file so
that's why in powershell you have to
write it
so let's demo um
javascript first okay so i have a i have
kind of a big javascript file so let's
put it here
and let's uh
use some javascript mod in
in um
in emacs okay
so you know here you have a huge
you know you have 34 thousands of
unicode characters data so let's just
remove them
uh yeah so that's just because we don't
need those
okay so anyway so here's the javascript
code
uh this is
this is act this is typescript or
javascript this is actually typescript
but they are similar okay so here's a
javascript code
of
250 lines okay now let's let's screw up
the format okay so you see right now
they are nicely formatted but let's
let's say we screw them up you know
let's
let's let's say
uh
can i do this yeah again okay so you see
so let's wait where do we do it uh
so for example this box results this
part this these are
oh this is this is a string this is
actually a
okay so let me let me do this quickly
okay so
so
yeah so let's
let's screw up the um
format okay let's just do it you see
let's just do it okay so let's see let's
look at the function uh fnomal search
that's a function okay now you see it
becomes one
long line unreadable
now save it xx
dot ts
okay
save okay now i want to suppose i'm
writing this code so now i'm i'm i want
to reformat the whole file so i just all
i have to do
you see these these two functions you
see all i have to do is
because i'm in emacs i've i've done
let me just show you okay
tab f
fantastic you see
you see this function
normal search now becomes nicely
formatted and also this this charts okay
undo
okay let's let's do it again
now watch my um
wait
what
my my command log mod is not working it
normally should show
let me fix that
wait my command log is broken so
normally it should show what i typed
okay let's
never mind okay so
so what are we doing so um yeah so we
want to reformat this so i can show you
control h m
so this is
javascript mod and you can see one of
the command is javascript format code
tab f so i press tab f so it reformat
the whole file for you and i've tested
you know the if you have a file that's
50 000 lines you'll do it quickly you'll
do it within one second fantastic so
you don't have to like typical
industrial programmers they are like
they are like oh you need you need to
align tab versus space tab versus space
that's no good okay
that's not good that's a
you want a tool that format the whole
thing one shot
so formatted and what else um so let me
show you the actual command so let's
for now let's uh
let's compact this again
okay
and okay so save it
now go to the file x6x.ts
that's typescript now go to shell let's
speed the window go to shell
now let's uh type deno
i forgot what's uh what's uh
what is the i think it's a demo fmt okay
then just the file name
i think that's it there it is there it
is now let's open the file again
there you go so okay that's a demo of
deno javascript deno is the greatest
thing okay they know
so i highly recommend demo deno do not
use the npm do not use not js okay
that's that sucks deno is created by the
same guy who created not js but once he
left not just
the not just up you know not just
has a bad leader you know you know i
don't think he's a good guy but it
up in all sorts of ways then you
got the mpm
mpm you know library thing every time
you install a package every package is
just five lines ten lines every time you
install one package one thousand comes
in
so deno
it's fantastic okay
use deno
okay so that's uh that's a demo of the
automatic formatting of demo um then
then let's do
golan let's not do gold line let's let's
stamp let's demo the powershell and that
that'll be it
so powershell okay so let's open the
powershell script
yes i'm using vorack keyboard let me
introduce my keyboard okay so this is
kinesis advantage keyboard you are
looking at
where is my
kinesis advantage and on top this is
ultimate hacking okay so you can see
you know there's there are two parts i'm
using it as a keyboard marker so like
everything is one single key press and
you can find them
you can find them just search for xrd
keyboard
okay i have
900 articles on keyboards
so here's my keyboard guide
then you go to other keyboards
then
here is the keyboard i'm using kinesis
advantage 2 and
ultimate hacking
keyboard okay you go buy them you know
buy them from my website
okay let's demo powershell powershell
auto format okay so i go to my document
so i have a powershell so here is my
powershell script let's delete the
backup
yes and make a backup
and open this file shrink the window so
you can see
i have lots of uh functions you know
for myself um
so let's
let's uh let's see let's show one of
them
okay so i have one function that's uh
backup drives so let's copy that
new buffer paste it save it xx dot
p s one now powershell extension name is
ps1 okay so let's work on this uh
override what
oh i already have a ps1 okay so let's
try again
what
xxx dot ps1
okay so we are going to work on the code
for so first of all let's uh remove the
indentation so
okay save it
now
control h m
so
this is again
my emacs powershell mod you know i wrote
it myself so one of the command is tab f
type f
will do
wait that doesn't work
you know because recently i you know i
just
i just wrote this script
and i have you know and i try to put it
into emacs so that
i can run in emacs but doesn't doesn't
work yet so i still need to work on but
let me show you this okay so
so for example so
here is a powershell function
and
you know we removed some of the
indentation let's remove more
indentation
okay save it now go to
go to diet
go to shell
close that go to shell
then all i have to do well actually
let's do it here okay so actually all
right i have to do open the powershell
window
what i have to do is
xsa
format
powershell script xxx.ps1
okay so that's that file
do it
fantastic and it says backup created it
created the backup
so refresh you can see here's the backup
here's the original open that expand the
window you see
now it's all indented
okay so that's a demo of that okay
anything else i think that's it for
today
so
do you think the narrowing would be
possible with zone.el i don't know what
that what that package is
uh
okay i think that's it for today
bye guys
i'm gonna shut down in one minute
okay
we don't need this anymore
refresh
close
this is a typescript
delete
uh okay close
and this is typescript close
unicode
excel talk show today's talk show
when using sparse tree how do you hide
unmatched headings what are you talking
about are you talking about emacs oak
mod or what what what's sparse tree
but that's it