welcome to another episode of sound talk
show we're going to C emac list today
okay so stop that uh emac this okay my
keyboard gl8 fantastic ultimate hacking
keyboard fantastic nulia track B
fantastic and the swab
board let me show
you so this thing okay
so this thing fantastic FC ultimate
input device
fantastic I have reviews for each one of
them okay so uh on my website and on
YouTube okay uh and we're going to start
coding emac this check audio check video
and uh if you are here say hi if you are
watching offline skip around and play at
1.5 speed because I Rambo all
over Okay so let's switch switch to the
my panel so let's we just going to focus
on emac dis coding okay so we're going
to write the command let's begin so we
ready so let's double check again so you
can see um and the pink window is all my
emac command Calles and uh keystrokes
okay so let's move this
here okay so new emx block and we're
going to code uh this command okay let
me
explain uh
so so right a uh replacing for Define
Define function emac this okay if I have
a lot uh iMac this video tutorials okay
we're going to write this command not
replace invisible characters okay
so similar to this okay uh so let's copy
that copy that paste it that
documentation or important date creation
date okay so there is this so this
function will be named that okay and uh
then it so there's already a function
replace invisible character so let me
show you describe function replace
invisible characters enter so here's a
documentation so you know these key
strokes will invoke the command and
here's the documentation query replace
some invisible Unicode characters the
characters are replaced the characters
replaced are from this list so let's
look at that list open so you can see
you know all these invisible unical
characters you have zero WID no break
space zero with space left to right Mark
right to left Mark line separator
paragraph
separator uh right to left override
narrow no break space What Joiner this
this these characters are invisible and
very
annoying and and also this variation
selector you know many of them are for
skin colors okay so so why do I have
this command because every time you copy
from
Twitter Twitter or YouTube transcript
you know you make a copy and you paste
in emac or
editor um you will see this you you know
they they will often contain invisible
characters very annoying you wouldn't
know because you cannot see
it why do they do that I'm not too sure
but but sometimes you'll see uh for
example zero width no break space you
know they they they put in Twitter and
uh YouTube transcript I don't know if
they still do that but they've been
doing that you know since like 10 years
ago so this command is very useful um so
let's uh let's show a example okay so
let's see uh go back here go back to the
code Co to the code and let's add a
invisible character between 2X okay
we're going to add invisible character
so let's see
[Music]
um let's see Zero width space
A2 03 is the ID for that character Zero
width space am I doing good are you guys
listening say hi hello good morning GCS
GCS where you from I
forgot
uh so let's add a zero with space so
what you can do is you call insert CH
character okay and just type zero with
space okay that's how you insert a
unical character by name okay do
it okay it's done so now check look
carefully let's magnify uh magnify
magnify magnify okay uh wait magnify
okay now let's move closer okay let's
remove that okay move closer to the left
move closer to the left you see it
becomes this Thin Line why because there
is a invisible space there move closer
to the left again then it becomes uh
full see so there's a invisible
character there but how do you know you
wouldn't know you know like you would
normally wouldn't know when you copy
from Twitter or YouTube so that's very
annoying especially if you are writing
code or blog you know you copy some code
that this invisible character McKing
around
invisibly so you call this command s
replace invisible character so let's let
me do it okay so for example meta
X replace invisible characters enter
it says found zero width space code
Point 8203 position three replace yes or
no yes okay so now you know whenever it
does a replace it highlight red you know
the next character so now now move
closer to the left you see that uh wait
not paste you see that invisible
character is gun so that is the
command replace invisible character now
let's shrink the fun back to smaller
okay okay so there is this function okay
now let's look up the
documentation again you can see it's in
this miscellaneous
commands and in fact here is the so here
is the source
code uh about 50 lines or something um
you know actually 30 lines okay and uh
and then then there is a website for it
so go to it show in browser there you
have it so you can copy the code and use
it for your benefits okay open source
fantastic thank you Sali so if you like
my stuff really donate okay I don't you
know so donate to me you go to s. info
emac tutorial you can you can buy the
whole thing as a donation you know it's
only $30 I need to increase the price
$30 okay I need to increase it to 40 or
50 um because things are getting so
expensive I don't get much you know like
few few a month so you can buy my emac
tutorial or just um s code go to kinfo
all the way to the bottom so there's
lots of programming language tutorials
and stuff and to the bottom so there's a
patreon Amazon gift card PayPal okay
give me $50 or something if you work at
Google give me 100 or
something uh you know if you are a
programmer you
know a professional programmer you know
doing a job so thank you and so let's go
back so so we got this command already
written but um um so this is used for
the current buffer it does replacement
of these characters for the current
buffer but what I want is sometimes you
know I write a lot of blogs you have
lots of
Articles you don't know you know for
example let's go to
um uh you know sound talk show right
there there's like uh by now
1,400 1400 talk show or something uh
well actually lots of these are um lots
of these uh uh video YouTube thumbnails
so you see this my past talk show this
is like five years ago when I was a poor
sub uh YouTube thumbnails okay so oh
Mathematica beautiful okay so also I
started to do a talk show S Talk on X so
on Twitter x.com so today this morning I
just did a episode six on lisp
programming language wolam language and
dat donation okay someone Cooper David
Cooper asked me about it so I just
started a a random talk about that topic
why wam language is a
magnitude more advanced more high level
than all other languages including all
lisps common lisp scheme lisp closure
racket uh or including all the
functional programming languages hascar
uh or camo FSH and including all
esoteric languages a Prue Mercury and so
on on on it's it's not just more
advanced more high level but by a
magnitude wolan language
okay uh you see few days ago we were
doing uh we have a episode on wam
language but I actually didn't get too
code so we were doing conic sections the
you know so one guy asked me what's your
favorite um uh what's his name you know
he asked me what's your favorite curve
that would be actually conic sections so
rich okay so let's get back to code okay
so this this is a beautiful we did this
live this is inversion of a grid a
three-dimensional grid you inverted so
this is geometry the most my my uh
favorite subject
geometry beautiful you see how you know
this is just
uh 10 lines of Code 10 lines of code try
that use C and C++
idiots okay so so that's why what I mean
why is it far more advanced by a
magnitude okay but let's go back to eag
this so emag this
is the most um powerful and suitable and
flexible programming language for text
editing so if text processing so if your
task is text processing you have to go
through thousands of files to make a
report or text manipulation emac is is
better okay in this case it's even
better than wam
language you know if you need to do a
lot text you know manipulation so any
anyway so iMac this okay so we so what
we want is to write a replace invisible
character in a d not just a file
so let's do this okay and that will be
it today uh we already talked 12 minutes
okay so what are the comments from
Brazil oh GCS from Brazil I think I kind
of remember you uh this one Brazil guy
are you like did you like posted a
screenshot of a game with Kar
flag Kar faction in a game I
think uh maybe or is your friend or I
don't know so Brazil Thiago uh Thiago
hey Thiago uh
Cypher x64 there are many Brazilian oh
bra oh yeah right I remember there's a
Brazilian G that invented invaded Kar
Discord they taking over
uh uh two years ago so on Twitter my
Twitter and score join okay so you can
find the links on my website
cinfo so uh was it difficult to study
Elis not really just like any language
okay
uh just found it
GCS just found it
here uh
what found what uh uh oh it's not you
okay
so yeah some uh Brazilian
uh I I still have it so let me just
quickly show that because it's kind of
fun so talk show homepage then you uh
got s talk show clips and index uh what
are these oh some notable
topics uh let's see talk show
miscellaneous okay talk show portray and
Discord stuff
so is it clipped uh sometimes this is
annoying so I want to
know and I don't know but anyway so some
drawings people have done on me this is
like three years ago four years ago and
uh some drawing ZW is a keyboard guy uh
and you know some four Chan this this
from four Chan four chan
people uh and uh uh then this Allen this
is by Allan Captain Allen and this one
fantastic and uh you know some beginning
so this is like three years ago the
beginning of AI taking over you know AI
started to draw things uh that's Allan
Allen's artwork this is car style car at
like California you
know and uh anyway so and another guy uh
thanks to this guy
HTS um and uh this is Allan sty
fantastic this is my hand pen you know
the
the repetitive strain injury and this
one is a fake photo from AI imagine that
you know you know this so AI is so
dangerous today so this photo is me but
the background and all that that's
that's computer AI
generated so anyway so there is one
um back to S talk show the the flag uh
what is
this oh yeah so that's a four chance
stuff
fantastic uh this is Dion Dion is a
better programmer than me
uh someone made it some of these uh
things oh yeah so this flag I was
talking about in a
game Dota okay DOTA to this sof action
made by uh emac Guild okay so made
by uh Tito yeah okay R Tito I think so
anyway that was uh what I was mentioning
so now let's go back to let's do this
okay so so this command let's look at
the source code this command does okay
let's why not copy it copy
delete and we want to
um okay let's
say rep
[Music]
invisible
characters in all files in other
okay okay similar
to okay so now let's start to code
so well first of all you need to
Traverse the directory okay
so uh
okay so that's a
directory
um okay you need to Traverse the
directory am I doing good questions ask
okay comments I'll see it and I'll
answer it later so go to emac this
Basics so Traverse directory you need to
go to emac disp so there is a section on
right file file and directory work
directory okay so this is what we want
we want to Traverse the directory so um
so this is list of directories not
nested and uh this this is what we want
list directory and all subdirectory okay
so we just want to copy just make a copy
that close that and uh let's begin to
code okay common Edan this okay
so you need the directory path and you
need the file name extension okay
so this is file name extension uh as
arguments parameters okay so let's do
it
so file list okay so set file list to
directory files recursively
and the argument will
[Music]
be
okay uh yeah so that's a directory then
file name extension is
a uh okay so you want to make
that
concact uh extension rejects okay so
should it be just the extension name or
regular
expression so this is
a this is a functions parameters design
issue interface you know function
interface design issue or uh so if you
allow regular expression it's more
powerful but it's harder to
use typically you just want a file name
extension right so this kind of a design
issue which one you want let's just say
uh rejects whatever is easier
okay because I'm doing code live so
let's just get it on and later on we can
change so you just take a regular
expression
string then um okay something like that
then then what you want to do we don't
want concact then uh Neil then
okay so something like that okay so this
put here clean the
code shrink a little bit
okay so now this file list is a list of
files okay so if you so this actually
let's delete that part delete it so
so now it should return a file list okay
so let's try it okay so now we can
actually try the command direct to file
path uh let's say okay this is my
tempter let's delete those backup gun
okay copy the file path close
so this will be the directory and uh
what about regular expression regular
expression will be um
txt okay because lots of these TX txt
okay so txt and dollar sign dollar sign
means it must happen at the end
okay so evaluate this command
now evaluate that fantastic now go to
messages buffer here's output is it
correct yes okay copy it new buffer
paste make it into line me you know
that's correct it truncates you know
when there's too many it truncates but
that's
correct so we got the so now we got the
so far this command it Traverse
directory get all the files you need
then next thing you just need to for
each file you want to do the
replacement okay let's just code it
quickly okay okay am I doing still
good have you ever heard
about
[Music]
the salaka 54 keyboard no it's an open
source keyboard they sell it very cheap
on AliExpress but ordered myself one
okay
fantastic uh hiar hi
oo Oro
mive F line is so
powerful uh
good evening good oh a lot of people
here I see you are fit for Tiding
Windows Manager
yeah don't forget my coffee
okay we need to get this code going so
let's focus on
code code is what makes America great
not the online talk show mouths or the
online
influencers or you know these
idiots or
lawyers code okay you want to be a
mathematician or Engineers or physicist
whatever
so we got the list of files now for each
file uh you can you want to do something
okay so let's look at the other so this
command so this command already does it
so we can can we kind of just borrow it
if we so let me show you what to do okay
so basically what you want to
do now
do replacement on each file okay so
normally you can do map C map c will map
a function to all these files so
function name Lambda so so function name
Lambda you can do something like that
just for example you know that and X so
the sequence will be f
okay so for each file apply this
function what this function do is call
that function on the file name X is the
file path okay except so basically that
will be it okay this is
the you know this is the whole command
but but however this function right now
is not
suitable because if you go to
it if you go to it you see it doesn't
take a file path so we need kind of to
modify this okay let's uh yeah let's
modify this so
that okay let's put it
here okay so this command originally
originally was written just for
interactive use you know for the current
buffer but now since since we are
writing one for doing the whole
directory so let's modify this so that
it can be interactive use but as well as
processing the current file so what you
need to do is you need to add a file
name okay add the file path to there and
uh so when it's interactive you need
um so when when the command is called
interactively meaning meta X you need to
feed the arguments so the first argument
will be
um current buffer file path for the
current buffer so that will be
uh okay
um
wait actually just that okay assume
assuming it's a buffer but sometimes if
you have a buffer that's not a file you
get a error but let's assume this
command is always called on the current
buffer which is a file okay so buffer
file name because if the current buffer
is not a file like this or such as the
message
buffer when that in that case the buffer
file name returns
NE so that's what you need to watch out
anyway okay so turn buffer buffer file
name that's a file path then confirm p
is uh true okay
so it confirm that means if it's true it
will ask you for each occurrence okay so
so now we do that we added file path so
then
next uh next we need to do is the file
path okay
if file
path if file path is NE then one uh
actually user error
okay current
buffer is not a file okay so if the file
path is
NE then
Arrow
out okay so we can just just do that
when
okay
that that okay we don't need the
if
so so
now uh now you need to W
God because right now it assumes the
turn
buffer
uh what to
do there's a lot design stuff going on
so okay let let's not do this
actually let's just make this simple
okay let's write the command uh simple
Standalone function to do the
replacement so all we have to do is open
file so let's not go
that so open the con
file uh
wait okay find file is a command to open
the file find file find open that file
then what to do then go
go to the beginning of the buffer okay
so go to character then you need the
integer Point minimum is the beginning
of the buffer it's an
integer so go to the beginning then do
find replace so
while while you find the invisible chart
then you do
replace okay something like that okay
so and uh
so uh we are almost done okay so now we
let's copy
some
uh let's
see okay that part let's grab that
part uh wait let's look at the code
oh you need this regular expression okay
so yeah let's grab the
code okay go back to the
top we need
to do a let okay and the lets these
variables okay and the rest
is the body of the
lead okay so the Lambda map a function
to each and every file in file list then
for each file we do this Lambda and uh
first of all declare some local
variables so case replace NE that means
don't
don't do smart case replacement case for
search means NE
means be case sensitive okay two case
sensitive then we Define a regular
expression which is a regular expression
for all the invisible characters okay
so so the character list is from here
okay so for
example you see so that's a this
characters I mean it's a Association
list so you want to so this is
customizable you know you can you know
you can add or remove things from this
list okay so this is a list of invisible
characters a pair each one is a pair so
then you want to turn it into a regular
expression that's how you do it okay uh
uh I'm not going to go into detail Okay
so you can look up map chart okay then
result uh what do we need result for
let's
see oh yeah you want to push okay so
every time we do a replacement we want
to push it to the result list so that we
can have a report what kind of
characters invisible characters are
replaced okay so we want the re result
there uh okay so result Okay so
so that's a list of local variables then
open the
file then go to the minimum
position then uh while search to find
and replace okay we also have the code
below somewhere
here uh okay so we need
to yeah
so delete that
okay so paste
it so
op open the file go to the top while
search by that regular
expression
okay
uh
then then more local variables okay
clean it
uh so character id is a code point for
the character then character name okay
so okay so for each one we
actually uh match string so every time
we found
it let's
see
we string to CH okay so we turn that
into a integer we want to know the
character id and this is how you get the
character name okay so if confirm we
don't need this confirm yeah we don't
need this because this is doing batch in
the whole directory so we don't want the
confirm okay so if confirm do that okay
so actually just remove that
okay delete that so if
confirm uh we don't want this question
neither what
uh CH ID and
name uh search you just simply say
replace match okay
so this delete delete delete
okay so CCT ID get a CCT ID get the name
do the
replace yeah
then push it to the
result okay and remove the push Mark
okay and
then then this overlay put is highlight
it will highlight the the character
where this replacement took place okay
should we do it yeah okay let
it okay then then that's it remove this
line clean it up that's it okay so so
this this part we don't need okay so the
whole code is this
okay so does that make
sense so here is the file list make it
into one
line so it's more compact okay then you
just map this
function I think that's it okay remove
that clean it
so that's the whole code okay shall we
try it yes let's let's try it okay
now evaluate the buffer so now this
function is
defined and
uh let's try it here
so yeah so in this directory and all
text files okay
now we need to add some invisible
characters okay so let's let's create
some file okay so create a new buer save
XX
state.
text okay go to the directory make a few
copies and now let's change this file
names okay change this file name
a
b c okay done so we got this this files
and uh let's add some invisible
characters there okay so
now we want some invisible there zero
width space
okay there is a zero width space space
there
okay that's one file save it now go to
a
uh now let's say let's also
add invisible i n v
i
invisible uh
actually we need
to you know we need to add
the Let's
see we need to add the characters that
are here okay I mean some of these so
let's add left to right Mark okay copy
that
magnify now
add left to right Mark do it okay you
see move to the left you see there it is
okay that's it let's not worry about
okay so we got uh this is
invisible describe
chart so so this one is there is that
okay go back here and this a describe CH
search for name this one is uh
wait okay this is uh left to right Mark
save it
close open it save it
close okay now make a
backup make a backup okay close close
now if we run this
it'll change okay
so please let it
work run
it did it
work yes you see there's no
longer invisible character there now
what's the other file this a file okay
open it
magnify there is no longer left to right
Mark so it worked fantastic that's it we
completed our mission mission complete
save it close close close uh
close
close what is this
close oh wait it it opened all these
files CD me
it open all these 100
files okay so you can close of them all
in one shot or you can use regular
expression to mark
it kill buffer yes kill them all oh God
so many buffer kill them
all kill them all those are my temp
files so what is this entitled CL uh so
here is the code now let's put it
back okay this is kind of like like the
skeleton then you can brush it up you
know you can oh yeah you need to close
the buffer
so you know you need to you know you can
just say kill buffer
um after you know after the
while I mean the question there's
another design question do you want to
if you close the buffer then you
wouldn't see the overlay highlight
anymore remember it becomes
red so it lets you see kind of easily
where this invisible characters
replacement
occurred and uh but if you close the
buffer then you won't see that so let's
you know leave it open so put back the
code
showing browser that's today's fruit now
syntax colorette showing
browser fantastic and
beautiful 20 lines of code 15 lines of
code is that good thank you for watching
let's see the comments and we close in
in few minutes
okay some someone mentioned some
keyboard let's look up what that
keyboard
copy showing browser back here new
buffer paste SAR
[Music]
search
okay oh okay so this is like the um
you know it's like one of
those Ogo dos or Ogo dos like you know
nothing too special about it you know
keyboard like this is like available
since 10 years
ago go to key my S keyboard block go to
do it yourself magnify so you know
keyboard like that form factor is
available
since long ago so you got this uh
qua keyboard and uh you know so like ly
ly 58 so anyway so there's a lot a lot
of
them oh yeah I was thinking
Redux uh am I correct yeah there's
nothing special about it
is
there this uh because today there are so
many so many of
them okay so
next so what's special about silaka
keyboard tell me so I mean doesn't look
special to
me have you heard of markers in emac LP
of
course so they are like point but you
get updated when buffer changes yes
that's true
hang what a question hang you think I
don't know
1,000 pages of emac list tutorial I've
written so you see the the the issue I
can show you my tutorial page about
markers the issue with markers is that
it slows down the buffer significantly
because every time the buffer changes
like you delete a
character uh you know every time you
insert or delete a
character the emac has to update that
marker okay so if you have 10 markers
it's going to do 10
updates so it it's like relatively slow
so usually you don't want to uh use
markers and if you do use them you know
you might want to delete it when when
you are done with
it for those of you don't know it just
like for example I want to know this
position right you know right here
I want this position remembered even if
I you know added more character here you
know I can still go back to this
particular
position
normally no because when you add
characters you know this integer you
know the position changes so your old
position becomes like
here so that's why you have markers will
save the actual kind of you a marker it
flows with the adjacent text so you can
delete before it or insert before it is
still you know you can still go back to
that for example in our case you know
here or anywhere so that's what marker
is but you know the price is that it's
slow every time you have a marker it
slows
down because emac needs to keep track
you know where all the markers
are uh
okay I think that's it for today thank
you guys for watching and remember to
donate okay and join Kar Twitter or Kar
Discord uh Mark says I've got a
problem uh yeah but what problem
oh this uh slacka is very cheap that is
the defining qualities about it okay not
bad cheap is uh price is
important oh Juan says I don't have a
marker
article actually juang is correct thank
you juang
yeah I don't think I have a I don't have
a article about
markers yeah I you know that let's um
let's get more ESO I mean more kind of
less used detail so if I need to add
that you know
because you know if you want to Mark us
you know
it's it's it's kind of esoteric like for
example where you want to add that okay
you probably want to add
it somewhere about position okay so CER
position so these are basic functions
about CER position points return the
current position which is the integer
you know region beginning Returns the
beginning of the text selection you know
then region end point mean point so this
command we have used and beginning of
line End of Line and you can save CER
position uh but marker you know
so you know so these are very
fundamental but marker is not
fundamental marker is more advanced you
know you add it here is kind of
confusing to you know most people don't
even know you know how iMac this
works yeah so anyway I don't have a
article that for that I don't know if
I'm going to add thank you guys
bye thank you hang