good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of
talk show today is 2020 august oh not
august anymore today's
september third nine o'clock in the
morning
san francisco time so today we are going
to talk about keywords
good morning alan good morning sergio
uh chrome kept crashing kong has been
crashing for the
past 10 minutes uh so
i'm not sure what
am i going to do chrome kept crashing
and i guess i'm still alive it's still
streaming
so today i'm going to talk about
keyboards the history of laptop
keyboards the evolution of laptop
keyboards
and by the way uh i like to mention
today at one o'clock
which is about four hours from now
there is a online meetup for
emacs okay
so there is online meetup for emacs am i
still live yes i am
good morning cortes so i'm okay i'm
doing okay guys
[ __ ] chrome kept crashing uh i
i'm not sure what's going on yeah i i
have to restart my machine i guess
[ __ ] modern technology [ __ ]
so anyway uh emacs meet up okay one
o'clock just search for
emacs san francisco search for
emacs meet up san francisco
it's a online meetup in about four hours
and i'm
probably going to be there so today i'm
going to talk about
the history the evolution of laptop
keywords
now let's try one more time just to get
the chrome
google chrome browser [ __ ] going
the google chrome browser
uh
okay because otherwise i cannot see the
comments
okay i'm gonna i'm just going to start
talking then then maybe
maybe i'll have to restart my machine
later on i don't know
so
laptop keyboards okay the evolution of
laptop keywords
fantastic topics okay let me tell you so
starting with thinkpad
now think thinkpad is the classic
uh the most respected laptop beginning
in 1992.
so think think pad
from ibm ibm thinkpad they
sold they got bought by a chinese
company laveno
the the uh what's how do you pronounce
it
lenovo in 2005 you know chinese is
taking over
so but anyway 1992 ibm thinkpad is the
most respected laptop the highest build
quality
and the the ibm thinkpad keyboard a lot
nerds love it because well because they
grew up with it
that's one thing but it's also the
highest quality now in the beginning you
can see here's a picture of the thinkpad
keyboard the keys you know what keys are
there what
what what is the layout uh in the
beginning in 1992
they are basically a copy basically
exactly almost exactly the same of a
full ibm pc model m
keyboard so you can see every key is
there you know you got the arrow keys
you got
control and alt there is no windows key
back then windows key didn't get
introduced until
until 2003 also i'll talk about it
so where does the windows key came from
well microsoft
invented it beginning with
uh beginning in 2002
uh beginning beginning in 1994 with this
microsoft
natural keyboard and this and this
you know i'm going to tell you microsoft
is actually the
innovator of keyboards so in the past 30
years
microsoft has introduced quite a few
innovations to keyboard and
some of them are subtle in the past 10
years you don't know
i'm pretty sure you don't know yet you
don't know them
uh but i'm going to tell you okay
okay finally the google chrome is
running uh
so good morning jacquard hacksaw good
morning from peru
yes peru night great to see you again
uh and from sergio from mexico
and bart from germany and
el derio from hello world alan
from the sunny california thinkpad
nation
so okay so let me talk about a thinkpad
keyboard so
post your questions in comments okay so
thinkpad keyboard is a great keyboard
for the laptop
keyboard so in the beginning everything
the layout
is basically just a copy you know you
grab the full
ibm model m keyboard and put it on a
small smaller space laptop so you also
have
you have all the keys you have you you
have keys like print screen
pause uh uh number lock
and uh score lock you know those are
kind of different defunct keys even back
in 1990s
so you have and you have full array of
function keys and one thing interesting
about ibm
uh thinkpad keyboards is that you have
this
uh track point you know this trackbone
actually checkpoint is a inferior device
okay it's inferior to mouse
and it is also inferior to trackpad
on a mouse or on a trackpad you can
operate
you can get two places much faster than
the track point and that is
uh scientifically verified because if
you go to wikipedia you go to the
article track point
there's actually a study uh where you
know you know they say
the track trackpad is actually superior
than trackpoint
trackpoint is basically just like a
joystick kind of
uh and so so it's
it has been experimentally verified
confirmed okay
checkpoint is a inferior device but
however there are quite a few nerds they
will tell you
oh checkpoint is the best thing you know
they are actually
wrong because you know
you know these things can be tested
easily you know you have a group of
people using trackpad or
another group using trackpoint you'll
find that the the people using trackpad
is just faster faster than you okay
but anyway checkpoint is uh it's
interesting
interesting device and experimentally
confirmed to be
slower however there's also a
theoretical reason
why checkpoint is inferior
that reason is with a with a mouse or
trackpad
you have you have
instantaneous variable speed that is the
acceleration the speed you know you can
you can move
slowly or fast in in any variation of
speed you want in a continuous
change of speed on the track point you
cannot do that
so on trackpad for example look at my
mouse i get
i can move slowly or i can move quickly
uh very fast
same thing with trackpad not so with
trackpoint because it's a
and the reason for that the theory
theoretical reason for that is that
well it's because the mechanism you know
a track point is just
four directions not much
more than that meanwhile on a trackpad
or a mouse
you can how do you how do i explain this
you can
how do i explain the continuous variable
speed
control from the
mechanics point of view how do i explain
that
in terms of mechanics
it's hard to explain i'm not sure what's
the logical way to explain
that but anyway track track point okay
many people love it
it's a code you know it's it's what you
call a subcode so anyway ibm so
so the thinkpad keyboard in two in 1998
they have they had a upgrade so this is
the thinkpad 998
they introduced uh the application
launcher
keys for example launching the email
or search the web or launching the your
home directory or launching your
you know home directory in your browser
you know back then in a browser you have
a
home directory basically it's a direct
it's a page you
you want to go to and the email
uh key you know and document key so you
press this button here open your
document folder
so this is in this is in 2000 uh
this is in 1998 to 2001.
you have these launcher keys by the way
during that time
around year 2000 these these keys are
popular you can see
uh on lots of keyboards
because back then now this is when the
onset
of the web you know the internet
becoming popular
beginning beginning to have internet
and and then they also added the windows
key
and the and the the menu key
and both both the window key and manual
key are introduced by the
microsoft natural keyboard in 1994
so microsoft keep microsoft head has
made
lots of in innovations one of them
okay one of them is this
ergonomic keyboard you know there were
ergonomic keyboards before but they all
failed
also apple made ergonomic keyboard and
apple also failed miserably
now this is this is this is the example
where apple
you know apple is known for innovation
they have apple has
introduced tremendous number of
innovations
in personal computers since 1990 okay
for example
the cd cd player dvd player
usb firewire uh they are all
they all first come on on the mac
windows usually takes three or five
years to catch up to copy apple whatever
apple is doing
so anyway apple but apple back in 1993
i believe 1993 introduced this ergonomic
keyboard and it turned out
is the worst worst crap so apple failed
miserably here
but microsoft you know their keyboard
caught on because it's actually
well designed you know it caught on so
so micro we have to thank microsoft for
introducing the ergonomic keyboard
concept into the wide
population so when they introduced this
they also introduced the windows key and
the menu key
uh and those i wouldn't call them
innovation those are not so good
those two keys are not so good
okay that's michael that's uh that's
about microsoft
uh you know there there are many
versions uh
over the past 20 years the microsoft
natural keyboard
okay back to ibm thinkpad so you know
you have long
launch keys and there are also a
few more changes uh then
in 2011 ibm you know there is more
uh another version they
introduced let me show you okay you see
the arrow keys
you see the arrow keys on the right
lower right corner
they added two more extra keys those are
browser backward and forward buttons
you know like on your mouse five button
mouse the thumb
buttons you know browser backward and
forward
and they also introduced uh
the volume sound volume up and down and
mute keys okay
i need to close the window because
outside they are building
[Music]
[ __ ]
okay so what you guys yeah knob is
excellent good to have options stab
on the mac boys and yes perfect for
computers with several
[ __ ] chrome just crashed again
oh god
uh i'm not sure what's going on chrome
chrome has been crashing
for the past few hours
what do i need to restart my machine i
don't know if i restart
that's going to disrupt my live stream
so anyway let's go back to the thinkpad
so i'll just talk about some interesting
points
points okay so so in 2011 this new
version
okay so far so good but in 2012
you know after almost like 20 years into
exactly
20 years they made a change to their
keyboard again
now by by 2012 this is owned by the
lenovo and they made a change and this
change
they basically simplified the layout and
design of the keyboard and they
you know simplified and modernized it
because
you know so we are looking at the
keyboard history actually so there are a
lot of changes you can see
for example back then you don't have the
windows key you don't have the menu key
but those are added
on every keyboard now but back then
you know around year 2000 you have these
application launcher launch keys it's
almost on every keyboard
but but now that's gone again around
late 2000
you know people stopped you know having
those keys anymore
but then 2011 you see i i mean not
2000 in 2012 they redesigned so it
becomes looks like
looks like this now the a lot
ibm uh thinkpad lovers you know they
they hate they they complain they [ __ ]
about it they complained vociferously
on the web saying that it's going down
the drain
but actually this is actually a
simplification
uh most of the change changes i would
say is good some of them is bad one one
of the very bad point is that they
they use the flat you know they use
so-called chiclet
keys i mean you know the terminology
cheeky
chicklet keys is actually very confusing
because two different people it means
different things
but but like but so how you call this
you know the proper way to call this is
actually island
keys like islands so before now look at
before
you know before 2010 laptop keyboards
are like that most of them
but now in 2012 they introduced this
kind of i
you know individual each keys individual
i mean not connected with uh the other
but
one of the bad point very bad is that
the key
the key caps are flat
on the other hand you see the old ones
the key
uh key cap tops are kind of uh dented
so flat is no good because on the flat
uh island keys you cannot feel your
position
your fingers position relative to the
key so
that means often you you you'll hit the
wrong key you're
you know you cannot uh feel
so that's very bad and uh so they
removed
you know the page up down key becomes
you know they become uh they when they
come to
here before he was on top anyways i'm
not going to go over all the changes
but uh you know you can read the details
okay
you know so so why would i say this is a
modernization
of keyboard why because for example you
know you have the pause key
you have the insert key you have the
score lock
key now those keys are has been kind of
defunct
defunct since 1990s you know even back
in 1990s
for most people you don't even know what
those keys do
you press them nothing happens
you know so so that's so you need to
change
so today actually today a lot of
keyboards
don't have those keys anymore we will
we'll come to
to see them okay but anyway so
ibm thinkpad love lenovo they started to
do that you know they removed they
simply just removed those keys and that
is actually a good change
um okay so so
okay so that's a basic history of ibm
thinkpad keyboards and if you know so
the thinkpad keyboard there are a lot
fans it's like a subculture
so if you want to buy it you can
actually buy it you know independent
external key keyboard you can actually
buy it on amazon
now let me tell you so the evolution of
laptop keyboards i'm going i'm going to
tell you
you know over the 20 past 30 years the
changes in ipad keyboards
now comes in the chromebook from google
the empire the google empire that
controls every
everything of every aspect of your life
google chromebook introduced beginning
in 2011.
google is saying it's time we introduce
our own laptops with our own operating
system
screw microsoft windows screw apple
you know apple mac os you know google is
having their own
chrome os you know and they sell their
own hardware
well they they you know yeah so their
own brand okay
so chromebook in beginning in 2011
now on the chromebook keyboard they
drastically uh simplified
the keyboard they removed huge number of
keys
drastically simplification and in fact
you know in my opinion this is actually
a very good
change you know they they read of the
30 years of baggage of keys on the
keyboard they just
throw them away so what what what are
the
um so let me let me go back to the my
live stream to see the comments okay so
so so
questions comments posted [ __ ]
google chrome crashed again uh
[ __ ]
okay let me talk about chromebook okay
chromebook you can see
uh what
okay chromebook chromebook they
so what are the salient changes
first of all you'll notice the alt and
control keys are now humongous
no more window key too complex windows
alt control shift alt you know
uh menu key too many of them read you
know
gun no more so but instead you have a
giant audience control and this is
fantastic because oden control
you use often for keyboard shortcuts now
they just make them big
okay so now it's easy to press and the
caps lock key the pesky caps lock key is
also good because that's not
a useful key of course they don't have
the pause
score lock and and things like that they
don't have that anymore
and page up and down gun two
because you know in modern computing
since about
late 2000s let's say 2010
you have you have a giant track trackpad
multipurpose trackpad and multi-touch
trackpad so you can if you want to
scroll you can just
swipe it you know swipe or swipe back or
right to go backward and forward so read
of the page up and down and you know rid
of lots of keys
lots of keys you don't actually need
and the function keys f1 f2 f3 is open
too
now some of these changes are
not good for power users what do you
mean by power users like us
you know we programmers or those
professionals
doing photo editing you know photoshop
or video editors you know they work
in the industry for movie companies for
commercials
you know commercials they need someone
to you know do video
uh edit videos so they are a lot that
you know that's a profession now that's
a new profession so
so when you work with photoshop or video
editing software you need lots of tons
of shortcuts
not just that you need special devices
uh designed for
design for doing photoshop you know you
can see several here
of course there's also the uh input pen
for example the jock wheel the shutter
wheel
the you know this for example the
tangent ripper
repo okay this is for grading panel it's
a specialization
of video edit editing
and then you have the sony video editing
console this
this complex console let's see if we can
magnify uh well the picture is too small
okay
this is like a star trek console you
have
trackpad you have these throttle you
know or
sliders and you have 10 000 buttons you
know this
this by the way by the way this this
keyboard showcases the idiocy
of those who uh those proponents
of the proponents of those
those 40 keyboards those idiots
you know they they want 40 keyboards so
everything is controlled something
so so so you imagine imagine this video
star trek video console
you're gonna reduce this 300 1000 keys
into 40 keys so you're going to control
meta control or
[ __ ] the [ __ ] idiots they you know
those people
they those people who are into 40
keyboards they often oftentimes they
tend to be fanatics
because when you say something you know
you say oh 40
is actually not good they they they'll
go uh bad [ __ ]
they'll say oh actually actually you got
four layers i got five year layers this
that that they'll argue you and to uh
argue with you endlessly
so anyway so video editing you can see
some of the devices actually
when you do a lot of video editing you
need these devices just like different
tools you you know
if you do math you need a protractor you
you need a compass and so on
so these devices for example this one
is uh designed for photoshop you have
you have you know the you have tons of
wheels and knobs okay you guys
go buy them now let's go back to
the laptop his history the history of
laptops
we digressed into the um
uh the the the you know why why are we
wait why did we start to mention that i
forgot but anyway
chrome keyboards okay chromebook
keyboards it's a great innovation
they reduced the keyboard complexity
oh oh so i was saying so i was saying
for
programmers or power users you those
professional computer users
some of the this change you know is not
that good
because for example they read up all the
function keys
you don't have you know instead by
default you have well you still have
function keys but they have a different
purpose
you can actually change it by software
anyway
chromebook okay chromebook it's a
chromebook so
so back to the overview of the history
of
computer keyboards on laptop chromebook
is a major
player you know it's a major milestone
in
the change of keyboards because once you
have chromebook chromebook is very
popular
because they they sell it very cheap you
know especially for
moms and pops you know they are not
programmers they are not professional
you know computer users they don't do
photoshop and so on but
but a lot of people mom and pop they
need a computer to search the web and so
on
so chromebook is designed for them you
know it's designed for them
running google's apps
uh and you know so
so so so that means there are actually a
lot of people using it
you know actually including programmers
because
this keyboard this this model chrome
book pixel
is designed for programmers you know
it's got a huge
screen you know over one thousand
dollars
so so chromebook introduced this you
know
drastically uh simplified keyboard to
the masses
and and what that means it has influence
it has influence to other people so
because
once you use chromebook for a while for
example if you happen to be
you know if you happen to buy a
chromebook or maybe your mom has it you
use it for a while
you get used to it so that for example
before this
you used to use the page of up and down
keys
but on chromebook you don't have that so
you use you know the
the the trackpad and so on but now if
you switch back to the
traditional laptop you'll notice that
you kind of by habit you don't use you
know you don't use those con
page up and down keys anymore so that
has
influence so that also influence your
choice what you're going to choose for
your next
laptop or your keyboard that you want to
buy
so chromebook is a major uh innovation
in the in the laptop history the
evolution of laptop
okay chromebook now another major player
is the mac okay mac is you know mac has
always been like
10 of all computer users you know
since 1990s is hoovering around 10
uh today maybe a bit more 15 or 20 but
but you know but most people are you
know window users
anyway mac is also a major player
uh in in hardware so back in 1993
you know you have this uh powerbook dual
you know very expensive back then
okay so 1993 but
i'm going to look at some of the mac
keyboards okay mac keyboards
uh so on mac you know
the macintosh keyboard is um
quite a bit different from the pc
keyboard
okay i have a page explaining that
anyway let's look at some of the mac
keyboard so this one is from 2003
i have this laptop i use this laptop
laptop for like four or five years and
it is this laptop
this laptop i've been using this laptop
laptop
exclusively for like four years typing
on this every day
since about 2002
this is when i got rsi
repetitive repetitive strain injury
because i was using a laptop
all the time like eight hours a day so
you know
i recommend as a side point you know do
not
do not use a laptop keyboard for long
for long you know you
you always want the external keyboard
but anyway
uh apple's laptop so you have this one
uh then so this so this one is
from 2015. now again you can see a
change you know
uh kind of history across the across
board you know back then you have these
kind of keys
each keys are adjacent to each other
then you have the island style
keys so that's 2015
then then the latest like today you have
these butterfly
um switches no good okay this crap
okay apple keyboard you know so what i
want to mention about apple keyboard is
that on
apple laptop keyboards you never had
you never had page up and down keys uh
never you you know you don't have you
don't have physical page up and down
keys let's check this one let's check
this
1993 do they have a physical page up and
down
i don't have a picture no they don't
yeah so on apple keyboards you never had
physical picture
okay that's about apple but now back to
let me finish
the topic of evolution of laptop
keyboards
uh we are not done yet there because
there is
quite a few innovations by microsoft
okay
i'm gonna talk about it uh let's go
to this article the evolution of laptop
keyboards
now my chrome crashed again let's
reopen chrome so i can see the comments
[ __ ] [ __ ] chrome the you know the
modern technology
you know it it seems funny because
this crashing stuff you know rather
crashing or bugs or this that
that this or that it's been with us
since you know since 1990 you know in
1990s today
today is the cpu the gpu the memory
whatever is like
100 times better than before
but however this crashing every day is
is still with us every day
like you know we have bugs and good
problems
would that be nice i mean why don't we
have a situation
i mean the programming you know
computers has been progressing
for 30 20 30 40 you know years how come
to this day we still have crash
this [ __ ] crashing [ __ ] problem
you know so so so you know
like back in 1990s you know things
crashed and on windows crash
on linux on unix they also crashed okay
so you have after 10 years after 20
years after 30 years you have
you still have the crashing problem so
you know so this seems to be a puzzle
okay how come
you know why how come we don't have a
situation you know after all all these
progresses
how come we can just uh a pool
a poor sub like me why can't i just use
a computer without all the [ __ ] crash
you know i don't want i don't want fancy
gpu or video
graphics card you know the nvidia
whatever
jargon [ __ ] i just want a computer that
just runs
basic stuff then don't crash it seems
it's not happening okay and i have
thought about this
for quite a while i can tell you why
this happens because kind of it's kind
of a
um side effect of capitalism
well it's it's a side effect of
competitive
competitiveness of the corporations
why well in other parts you could say
it's
um so why does it happen because
so suppose i build a computer suppose
i'm uh
i create a company i build a computer or
operating system
where my system is very solid and basic
i you know i don't want fancy
bleeding hard features no no bleeding
hard features like usb4
you know usb 10 whatever just came up so
my computer don't have those features
but however
it's solid it never crashes you know it
just it doesn't change much you know
so if i create that computer the problem
is
nobody will buy it why not because
not because people won't like it better
not because people do not prefer it
but rather because the marketing [ __ ]
because all these other companies
microsoft
apple and google they they have a
marketing department
on the marketing machine department they
will have lots of tons of clickbaits
you know they will tell you well
actually you should use usb
10 you know usb 10 because it gives you
this these that feature this
saves your life okay and and so they
have they put billions of dollars to
advertisements
so for most people they are not computer
professionals
they have no idea they just see oh oh
this one's
got usb 10 it will save my life
so they're gonna buy that instead of
buying my
superior solid you know no [ __ ]
computer
so you know corporations they compete so
that is why
to this day you don't have you you still
have crash problems
because the crash problems nobody knows
you know it's
it's not like when they buy you know
when it crashes
you know they these companies have
licensed you know uh
user agreement license fox that tells
you
they don't guarantee they don't even
guarantee the computer works
okay that's actually part of the user
agreement
okay uh [ __ ] google chrome is just
crashed again well i just wanted to look
at the
comments and it just crashed um okay let
me continue talking about the keyboard
evolution then
uh
[ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] the crash
and we'll be done today in in in 10
minutes how long have been talking
uh in probably 10
10 minutes or 20.
so i'm going to so so we have thinkpad
we have google chrome keyboards now
around year 2000 you have there's
more changes about laptop keyboards but
i don't have good pictures of it of it
but anyway let's
let me just skip to some of the
interesting things
okay so we are looking at 2012
uh laptop keyboards this one is from
asus okay taiwan you know type from
taiwan or china you know they
they are you know they are taking over
usa
so this one dell inspiron dell okay so
there
the made in usa actually is not made in
usa
but there are usa company you know so
back in around
year 2000 you begin to have
laptop keywords that includes a
number pad on it you don't have number
pad before because
in the 1990s the laptop is small you
know the lcd screen it's expensive
but now they you you have bigger lcd
screens so now you started to have the
number pad
on laptop back then
today i think there's a trend to to not
have
the number pad anymore for example look
at apple keyboards
apples laptops apples laptops or
google chrome's laptops they don't have
number pad
so that kind of influence the industrial
design
but anyway so let me talk about
microsoft keyboards
so microsoft introduced their own laptop
you know the microsoft
surface book in 2016
and there is also there is also
innovation there
now now now this is certain okay this is
certain innovation you don't see
now let me tell you one thing okay when
you so so you are looking at
the microsoft surface book laptop
so can you see what's the difference i
mean why why why is there why would i
say
there's a big innovation you have to
observe carefully
now you see the the slanted arrangement
you look at the columns right they are
slanted like usual okay but
uh okay i'm just gonna say it
they have less slant than the
traditional
configuration so you look at the for
example you look at the number one
key on the number row okay now you look
at the q
key now you can see the number one is
is about one fourth to the left of q
okay and q is about one-fifth to the
left of a
you know and a is one-half more than
one-half to the left of z
so that's that's there's a stagger you
know you call that
stagger layout but not
now you look at back you look back at
the traditional
for example this one this this style
inspiron keyboard traditional
uh layout you see the number one
is to the half half key space of q
on the other hand let's look at
microsoft again the number one is one
fourth
to the left of q so you see this this is
subtle
subtle change but this is a great change
because
because why do you have this kind of
layout in the first place because that
that
came from typewriters okay because
typewriters 200 years ago you have to
have that because
you know what why are the keys the
columns are aligned in such a weird
you know almost like half semi slant way
because they need they need the bars
beneath the keys to be
equally distributed look at this picture
you see
all the metal bars beneath them are
equal equal distance
in order to do that you have to you have
to
you have to slam the keys that's why
so so microsoft you know they
they subtly they almost like secretly
you know they
they they they are trying to remove this
slant which is a great thing because you
know this is a movement
this is a move towards towards ergonomic
layout for example as you know as you
know many ergonomic keyboards today you
you have a matrix layout you don't have
that slant anymore
you have a grid you know just a vertical
and horizontal lines
for example you can see many examples
here
and uh you know and here just just the
grid
uh for example there are many there are
many examples
just a grid you don't want that you know
200 years old baggage
that's a baggage from 200 years
so my so that's a giant innovation of
microsoft
okay that's one thing uh what about
other things
there are a few other things okay
for example they also removed there's no
more pause
key there's no more uh score lock
key and there's no more
number lock key you know they remove
that
so anyway so microsoft
great innovation of keyboards um okay so
i think that's
about it for today chrome keeps crashing
now let's let me read some comments [ __ ]
it crashed again
[ __ ] uh
okay i don't know why is it crashing
maybe i stopped
um
okay maybe my i stopped my other
applications maybe they'll
stop come from crashing
uh and that's that's about it for today
i don't want to save it this [ __ ]
idiotic
text edit
okay let's start chrome one more time
and that's about it for today and you go
to
my keyboard blog you go buy
keyboards um for my website
you buy amazon you patreon donate me
and stuff okay you buy my emacs tutorial
emacs list
tutorial and my javascript in-depth
tutorial that that is actually my best
tutorial
okay let me try one more time to read
the comments and answer them
and if chrome keeps crashing then
then that'll be it for today
so alan says if it did it would be
your fault what i'm afraid to scroll
because once i scroll
chrome is gonna crash so scott says hey
good morning scott
uh so i say it's agreeing with alan but
i'm waiting
for i'm watching from ark hark linux but
only because
i know that saudi thinks of linux
okay paul edwards hey paul edward paul
edward
are you the guy who is studying
homotropy type theory
uh you are correct alan no crashes for
me running ark
uh take a shot okay uh what
uh asus needs to take over more i like
their stuff
most of my macbook
and laptops mbmb from
mb most of my mb and laptops are from
asus
alan says i like on the i like on the
thinkpad how they
treated the arrows
they didn't smash them so small right
yeah
and they made up okay so
yeah apple you know apple apple
the idiocy of apple let's talk about
this apple thing okay
now if i crash again that'll probably be
it for today how long have i been
talking now for
you know it's about hour what the there
it is
it just crashed okay that's it for today
i'm gonna
tell you about apple apple you know
apple is going down
apple is going downhill
because why because steve jobs
died steve jobs died about 10 years ago
ago and apple is trying to
follow up steve jobs footsteps of
innovation
big bird
but what they came up is crap it's the
most idiotic crab
apple since you know these days
uh so let me tell you
about apple okay so i have a app i have
a page about
apple keyboards history all apple's
keyboards
uh and i'm going to tell you
okay it's not here i want to tell you
apple design okay the apple the most
idiotic apple
thing um
yeah touch the touch bar
okay let's hold on a second let's go
here let's go to design
now these articles are about design
and let's show you some of the apples
stuff apple design so apple
you know apple in 2016 they came out
with a new technology
the touch bar the most idiotic [ __ ]
yeah and and they they think it's
innovation and they made several
commercials you can watch
you know it's all pretty you know apple
apple is great at marketing
you know they made a lot you know with
video
with music video you know very
attractive
uh commercials they uh trying to wash
your brain
but the product you know when steve job
steve jobs is he is a great innovator
he's a great thinker you know
he's also the one of the greatest
salesman
you know he's part of his skill but
however he is indeed a great thinker and
entrepreneur to be to be sure too
because entrepreneur means you need to
have the
ability to you know start a business he
has
he has that ability but anyway he's also
a great thinker he know
you know he look at what people need and
he creates them and
you know basically start a revolution
evolution you know he's
he began for example so many things
online music business you know you can
buy
songs online you can stream you know he
began that
because before that people are just
stealing just you know
napster you know the people are just uh
rip
rips cds you know sitting then you have
the open source [ __ ] with their
pirate bay you know like
by day they are ethical we are open
source by night they are the pirate
pirating guys
saying that all info must be free things
like that
uh and anyway so so so so the
steve jobs you know he see the situation
you know people wants to buy
music but however then then the giant
music companies are just trying to sue
people trying to
chase chase those you know pirates
but in fact what you should have is a
you know is is a
you know online streaming service or you
know where people can buy songs
digitally that's because
time has changed steve jobs created that
market entirely and also he created ipad
you know
people needs to listen to music so you
have ipad and so on
ipod ipod not ipad so anyways
a huge number of innovations by steve
jobs but
he passed away so he died then apple the
idiotic [ __ ]
apple people the today you have this
this guy okay he uh
you know he they created the touch bot
you know the most idiotic thing
touchbar and you know the mac phonetics
even the mac phonetics phonetics hates
them
okay so that's one of the uh idiocy
of apple designs and there's quite a few
okay then
then you have the dongle hair uh
well known dongle hair hair because why
because apple
you know it's this is um
interesting because apple has always
been innovative right
they always use use the latest the
superior technology for
interconnected activity
interconnectivity
you know connecting your peripherals or
your internet
they have the latest wires you know
ports
but however when you do you don't
you have to do that in a reasonable way
you cannot go
extreme but apple you know has been
trying you know they've been
doing that to the extreme so that you
know the thing about that is that
it's not just about innovation anymore
why because when they push these
uh new ports they are actually you know
they sell these dongles
each one is like thirty dollars or more
uh which is like two or three times more
expensive
when than than the standard ones so they
make
huge amount of money on these dongles so
it's not
just about innovation but half of the
equation is about
how can we squeeze more money from you
know
apple stuff so that's what apple has
been doing dongle
dongles hell and they come up with this
thing you know
this you know mouse charger at the
at the bottom of the mouse and
enter this pen what
what the [ __ ] kind of idiot you know
you know created this
apple you know this is a huge
insult to steve jobs but apple is doing
that and also they come up with this
butterfly butterfly uh key switches
and they market it as you know the
thinnest
possible
[Laughter]
so what has apple become you know it's
these these are not
steve jobs you know steve jobs will
never do things like this
this touch bar or these you know this
thing keyboard
still because they are not actually not
practical because steve job will see
this is crap this is just like
you know let's use technology progress
for technology's
sake you know whatever new technology
let's put it in
and this let's sell it that's what these
things are this touch bar and these
these butterfly key switches breaks all
the time
and you cannot replace them why because
apple decided to do that so that you
when you when something is break you
broken you have to buy a new laptop
macbook you know that's why
and we have this we have this director
or actor
you know he's flaming apple keyboards uh
and you have these uh situation one
keyboard
okay that's it for today what uh i
cannot you know
google google chrome is crashing all the
time so thank you guys for watching
bye guys
i'm shutting down and let's look at the
comments one last time
yeah the technology in search of a
problem that's right that's the
that's the standard uh saying the
technology
silicon valley technology in search of a
problem
so uh uh dark
dark oak what are you guys with these
names
says will you switch to thinkpad or not
i don't know i'm not i'm not in a mac
market for a laptop
maybe but i don't think i'll buy a
thinkpad
why because i think thinkpad the quality
has degraded a lot you know it's
it's not like the ibm thinkpad anymore
but also today is the landscape
changed because there are so many
technology there are so many
different type of laptops now there's
also gaming laptop there's also you know
touchpad there's also flip-flop
laptops so there are so many different
uh
so i don't think uh you know if i want
to buy
i'm going to get a thinkpad
so why is the right side also and left
slanted
idiocy uh well
what do you mean well because
you know what so the well the question
is that why do you understand it okay
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching bye