more
good evening everyone welcome to another
episode of sadak show
and today is 2021
2021st uh June 8th
right now it's eight o'clock in the
afternoon San Francisco time
and we are going to talk about random
random today okay so if you have
questions in the stuff Post in the chat
box
and I I'll answer it I'll get to it okay
and best to mention my name sorry okay
so I can see
okay first of all what to do so I'm I
don't know what to do so first of all
let's look at you know there's only
three people two people so let's look at
some of the um
let me put on my iPad eye patch because
I have a bit cross eye
so let's look at some maybe some emacs
we can talk about emacs about keyboards
about uh quite a lot of things actually
let me just start to go over my
blocks okay the blocks I've been doing
so okay so there's a Code update for
HTML mod and you can grab the code here
and put in your unit if you want to this
is a great function or you can download
the song HTML mod let me show you what
that does okay so this command does this
command basically just delete tags okay
so for example here's the HTML file
showing browser back to emacs and you
see
delete the text you see
delete delete delete delete delete okay
and do and do and do and do okay that's
what did that function that the attack
does okay now okay so diode mod now this
is another mod on GitHub I added two
functions uh
so for example let's see let's go to uh
let's go to the directory okay
go go to the directory and go to for
example
okay show in browser I mean show in
desktop so this is a fantastic by the
way I'm coding uh show in desktop the
code is all on my website
all the emacs command I call it will
show up on the pink window and you just
search for it and you'll find the source
code and you can use it so I open this
directory and I press the button show in
desktop fantastic and now we are in
Windows so Windows you press alt V for
view extra weight
and then L wait
v l the idiotic Windows okay so now you
have the big icons now let's see let's
say this keyboard okay I I did a review
of this keyboard this is this is called
Signum keyboard just search for Signum
s-i-g-n-u-m uh it's a fantastic keyboard
I have it now in your drawer I haven't
set it up yet uh I did a review of that
just search for it
you'll find my review sorry and uh
there's a video okay so let's say let's
just say open let's just say open this
uh image okay let's open some big image
okay this is the laptop that where I got
my RSI repetitive repetitive string
injury the first time in 2005 because I
was using this laptop for one over one
years exclusively like six uh six hours
a day so that's when I got this you know
there's a story just search for emacs uh
RSI you'll find it okay so this keyboard
so I I want to open in Kira
uh
open key
krita okay krita is a
you know you wait for it to open krita
is a application is a drawing painting
of application it's got a fantastic
uh mascot okay let me show you okay so
let me show you the key round okay close
that
so so so that is the command close close
uh queue running kill no I wanna go back
that's JavaScript code okay
because that
so anyway I'm now I'm opening Kira so I
can start to draw stuff okay
I can start to draw so actually don't
save it no
okay so that's krita now krita's got a
fantastic logo let me show you okay so
you go to Sardi keyboard blog you scroll
down then you go to pane input so
there's lots of um
you know interesting pen devices we you
know so so so I got this cheap huge
human uh
join a tablet okay
now join topic tablet is fantastic if
you use this on Windows because it has
support for example I can I can I can
use it to scroll in in you know I can
use it to as a mouse replacement let me
put my microphone away so you can see
and I can you know press a key
to do a let's say let's let's see let's
do this uh screenshot
and I can
start to
write
Chinese
okay so you go buy it
so it works great on Windows but however
on the Mac it sucks because Mac sucks
you know Apple they don't support pin
Computing by default they want you to
buy the Apple pen they want you to buy
iPad and oh oh the Apple
um you know the touch you know the Apple
touch pad that's that's why it doesn't
support it on on the Mac so I have a
full review here and let me tell you
about creep uh krita okay fantastic
mascot fine artwork okay this is the
Judgment of artwork you know you
Millennial Generations you don't have
you have no idea how to judge artwork oh
you know is it memes
okay so krita is a fantastic artwork so
they got this mascot and Japanese the
Japanese are crazy about making these um
these figurines and they are really high
quality you know usually they cost like
fifty dollars to a hundred dollars to
200 dollars
and you see tons of boobs Okay so
hot okay let me show you what what
what's that figuring about so you go saw
Arts by the way I'm going to merge my
website into one sorry dot info and
xari.org get rid of the you know
different domains long story I talked
about
so here is the artwork artwork of human
animals throughout history well yeah
that that is true some of these are
ancient you know this this one is two
thousand years old letter in the swan
2000 years old uh and uh so what am I
going to show oh yeah I was going to
show you the
and full of girls you know because girls
is the most important element in human
animals okay girls young girls that is
new by our girls not old not women not
old women young girls that that is why
you see them everywhere
old you know Asian artwork to today's
artwork to every ad every you know every
website movie today's movies you know
theaters you know boobs tits and ass you
see them everywhere why are they
everywhere because to us Human animals
they are the actually the girls young
the young girls they are the most
important element and that is because
they they girls are the people who uh
make baby who who who bear uh children
who
you know that's the most important so
that is why you have you know uh ladies
first you know protect women women and
child children women and children these
women and children that you know because
they are the most important
uh so yeah I want to show you the
Japanese you know the Japanese you know
Japanese you know here here they are the
Japanese
Fanta beautiful extremely delicate you
know uh craft craftsmanship uh you know
with modern technology you know this
these are not just this requires high
technology uh because of the plastic
Material Science and and and so on
so you have you have quite a few action
figures you know they don't you know in
American you call these action figures
you go to toys Toy R Us which is no
longer around or you go to Walmart you
go to the children's section you see
action figures and they are crude and
idiotic
on the other hand the Japanese they have
a you know they have a thing for you
know they have dedication to to to Arts
so here is a Japanese version of the bad
man uh you know the then you know
superheroes one one the woman Iron Man
Okay that you know so they are also
making uh American you know uh comic uh
figures
uh so anyway so so Germany is our work
okay and then there is uh you know it's
kind of
anyway different makers they have
different styles so it's kind of they
have uh you know then you have tons of
boobs so these are American you know
these are why it means fables and and
and stories okay
Mythos mythology
so then but you uh I want to show you
the you know the some of the um
the Japanese ones so here's a Japanese
one
you see that you know this one is like
200 USD dollars so you can actually in
today starting about 10 years ago they
are on Amazon you know you go to Amazon
okay this one is not available but you
go to this uh if you turn on JavaScript
there's related you can buy tons of them
tits and ass essentially
uh okay so what uh what happened okay
did I close it okay I did okay let's
open it again let's turn on JavaScript
okay refresh
go down go down
you know classic uh beautiful sculptures
okay uh
you don't see those you don't see much
of this anymore uh you know
not because we cannot because but
today's people they lost uh you know
they don't have the they the sense of
beauty is gone since about 2010.
you know a bit earlier than that but I
would mark 2010.
uh okay so Japanese artwork so I wanted
to show you some of the Japanese ones
you know you know Japanese they
incredible and and most of them are
comic book Japanese uh what American
calls magna
or anime you know characters
uh so here is one of them you know every
time I some you know there are so many
they are literally thousands of them you
know Comics Book characters uh but
I used to every time I see them you know
I haven't been reading you know since I
was thinking I was I read a lot that of
that in Taiwan but I haven't been so and
I'm getting old so I you know uh but
every sometimes I see this I dig out you
know who is the character and I read
about the stories you know so she is
from Devil's Survivor Survivor two devil
Survivor two her name is fumi Kano you
can find it on Wikipedia
Okay so
uh and her address okay that's
remarkable of course that's a Chinese
cheaper and uh anyway the Western people
that you know you guys don't know what
that is
oh you know is cultural appropriation I
have no idea what's going on uh and you
know then in Japanese they have you know
look at these things okay so anyway
that's the Japanese
Japanese version of action figure but
what they call technically sometimes in
English they call it PVC figure PVC is a
a special type of plastic okay
uh and you know Japanese you know they
uh they are crazy about these things and
and and and also it's incredible
incredible okay incredible the word
incredible incredible they this one you
know this this is from a thing called
let me show you okay uh this this is
uh
battle Fleet girls okay I'm going to
show you what they are
it has to do with Nazi okay a word the
white people are obsessed with
World War II so there is this thing
called uh Fleet girls Fleet Girls
Collection which is a game one of the
most popular game in history okay uh
something like that top top top five
uh so what what is this game about so in
Japan you know created it you know World
War II they model the warships of Japan
and then other countries you know World
War II warships then for each ship they
have a girl to represent the ship so for
example this one you are looking at
Yamato the biggest
uh battleship
yeah the biggest gunship in human animal
history that is this one Yamato and she
is represented by this girl okay giant
huge boobs
so this game again so so this is Yamato
um you know they have a girl to
represent each you know of the
battleship or sometimes you know they
also have Cruisers or submarines and all
that so for example these girls one two
three four five six these six girls they
you know they have a arrow with a bow
they represent the um
carriers aircraft carriers of the
Japanese World War II battleships
but you know the interest in the
interesting cultural remark I'm going to
make is that what a wonder it is you
don't have you know why why how come
doesn't the German people you guys a lot
of you guys why don't you German people
create a game like that where you
glorify the German battleships you don't
see that What a Wonder and and look at
the girls this tits and ass
it oh am I am i m is taken am I not
seeing tits and ass and [ __ ] tits and
ass and [ __ ] they represent the
battleships of World War II of Japan
and what how come Germany doesn't make
that go God the German must be stupid
people right uh okay so there there you
have it and uh
and this is not Niche okay this is not
like oh it's underground oh you know
this is a Japanese train station with a
poster of this
of these three girls collection
plastered over it
then there's a airplane with the three
girls collection can't can call it
whatever however you call it in Japanese
pronunciation
an airplane of this thing amazing yeah
Japan okay
okay that's about that so I was talking
about the uh you know the the the PVC
figures okay let's write down today's uh
what we talked about so we have a log of
what happened okay
so that that copy the URL back to emacs
and make it linkify at least fantastic
and we also talked about krita okay
okay hold on a second so let me let me
let me just open that okay open that
open that
there's a lot Okay so
so there you see
close that go back okay so we were
talking about because of of this so
drawing software Quita okay
make a link now drawing software Quita
krita is a new one it's also is it open
source I think so so it's a [ __ ]
alternative you know why let me show you
okay so here is krita okay let's close
it
now I also have a command
wait let's go to krita okay so let's say
krita Okay so so jpeg so for example so
so you have the krita screenshot then
you have the krita let's say let's open
that one okay now let's open in [ __ ]
let's see so there's an emacs command
you can find on my website sound opening
game let's see how long it takes
the [ __ ] open source program loved by
the free software and open source
phonetics
you know so it opened now let's open
this in krita
now I can tell you uh you know it's just
better okay uh you know seems to me
although I haven't I don't use these
programs much mostly I just use you know
quap and stuff crop rescale and
something like that I don't use that
much but it appears to me krita is like
the new and better one
okay but anyway so anyway so there you
are so there you have it so close that
close that
uh okay shrink the window close that
okay krita and what else okay so then
I'm going to show you the
copy that put it here put it in my uh
okay
so
so what what what's up so let's see the
comments okay let's see the comments and
where we are going going so I was
talking about diet
um diet uh Emax package you can it's on
GitHub
and there are quite a lot
um commands you can convert JPEG to PNG
PNG to jpeg or you can reduce colors you
can remove meta you know meta
information like meta information for
example you take for example let me
let's see let's open krita again so for
example you take photos with your phone
and you upload on your blog and whoops
your photo like the photo you see
actually contains your address
you know the GPS coordinate so you can
see so for example if I want to know the
hidden data associated with this image I
just press a key okay so let me show you
the pink window so you can see what
command I call okay I press the key
so you can see the command is saw diet
show metadata and and you are looking at
the meta data of this image which does
not contain uh spurious things
so but if it does then you can just call
this command and you just you just
remove the metadata okay
so that's a bunch of comments uh in this
package.el okay you can try to use it
okay that's it for that let's so now let
me read the comments how long have I
been talking let's see uh
uh I've been talking for 30 minutes so
hi guys what's up fuzzing good morning
fuzzing good morning sit Ali
good morning
Jeremiah Johnson good morning
do I have a secret love for Unix
philosophy no I don't
but however am I do I have a let me ask
myself that question okay do I have a
secret love of Unix for us we know
I [ __ ] despise it
do I you know secret love so it's not
you know I don't do I have a love for
Unix philosophy at all maybe a little
bit no I don't I [ __ ] [ __ ] a Unix
philosophy truly
so why do I use Linux why do I keep
using you you know why why is my whole
life revolving around the Unix Linux
stuff well that's because I'm a nerd
okay I'm
well because first I don't like big
giant corporations so so for example
back then 90s in the 1990s you have like
okay you can choose Microsoft Microsoft
or you can use uh Mac
I was a Mac User for like almost 20
years and I also use Microsoft but wait
you know I'm a kind of a nerd guy so I
don't like giant corporations I like
free I also like freedom I you know I
talked about this before
so it happens
you could say you know it's my
personality I like the Unix kind of
stuff
not not the technology okay that's
important not the technical not not the
patch not the technology it's the worst
[ __ ] possible the Unix stock I like the
cultural you know the Cultural
Association of the Unix Linux kind of
stuff okay because I don't like giant
corporations because I don't like
under control by Authority I tends to be
more like Rebel like okay so I like the
you know I like the hacker types
somewhat somewhat okay
but I don't but anyway Unix technology
is the worst [ __ ]
you know so because so
you know I'm gonna start to rent for 10
hours if I don't keep talking about that
chloride okay something like that maybe
you are right I think we are still
waiting for his confession trying uh
talkable now dark table now what dog
table okay so you guys don't have a
question okay so let me go
so let's see what we're gonna talk about
next so let's talk about uh let's see
let's um let's put this in my talk show
so we have a record
so
so so we've been talking let's clean up
this page okay
showing browser right showing browser
what what do I want to save what what
modified
show in browser okay so talk show that's
today's weave a talk show and show the
video okay show the video and turn on
um JavaScript
okay so those are the topics we've
talked about let's see what else okay
beautiful girls I love them
love them
uh okay and uh then Japanese okay
Japanese
uh HTML delete tag okay copy that put it
here okay uh okay back to the topic Okay
so
so now let's go back to emacs let's see
what else I'm gonna talk about emacs
okay uh Emax okay I've been working on
my HTML
mod
I've been working on a tutorial for HTML
so here is the home page of my HTML mod
uh you can find you know lots of
commands but I started to do so all
these commands are commands in HTML map
so for you emacs users this might be
suitable you you may find this usable
not necessarily
because cosine HTM because ihtml mod is
focused on
focus on focus on writing HTML manually
like my 6000 HTML files are written
manually okay let me let me show you my
um
okay shall we shall I
okay press a button and open the
Powershell okay so you are seeing that
command opening terminal
so from emacs I control the universe
so now let's go to Let's CD okay now so
a Powershell
okay now I mean my web directory now
let's do uh let's do the
recursive
include
anything HTML file okay
uh let's count how many how many file
how many there is okay
I think that's it
so there are about maybe 30 000 files so
oh no so there are 10 000 HTML files
that I have written manually
tag by tag
every character I've written you know
ten thousand HTML of hours over the past
uh over the past now by now 20 kind of
23 years starting around 1997.
10 000 files so anyway excite HTML
amount so uh um
it's very useful if you write HTML
manually but it's useful in general so
what I'm saying is that it is not
so if you compare to another HTML mod
that people use today in emacs so those
HTML mod usually they you know like when
you if you work for Google Facebook
Twitter whatever you know corporations
usually you use a lot of JavaScript
react you know lots of CSS uh bundles
you know those kind of things
I don't do that so that that is what I'm
saying HTML mod may not possibly
suitable for you because if you work on
those things since I haven't I don't
work on those things so like the work
pattern the need the requirement is
slightly different
but however you might take a look okay
because I
you know ideas you know I worked I
walked down I you know SCI HTML mod has
been around for by now about seven years
so over the past you know of course I
use it every day so I refine it you know
it
uh you might find you you might find it
useful
let's see comments
okay keyboards so let's talk about
keyboard okay let's talk about keyboard
so uh do you have any specific questions
as ask it ask it right now okay
yeah do do ask do ask any particular
question you are interested in okay
don't
don't like suggest me your topic to talk
about but instead if you have some
question that you wanted to know about
keyboard and you think you know you
might want to know you want to know my
opinion and ask it you know the more
specific the better the better your you
know the talk the flow the information I
will be able to give
okay so uh so let's talk about keyboard
so I have okay I have only 20 minutes
because I have to stop let's see what
else I you know anyway so let's stop
emacs so let's go to keyboard so what is
this close Okay so size HTML copy it go
back here uh show this close that close
that
paste it close okay let's talk about
keyboard
so keyboard let me just show you what I
you know what happened to my blog in the
past month or so
okay this is not complete uh so
the edsc of hacking hacking keyboard I
got a new photo thanks to thanks to Rezi
okay anyway
he collects he collects happy hacking
keyboards he's got you know if you go to
Discord
he's got six six of them each one is 200
to 300 you know he collects
he collects the worst keyboards on Earth
you know happy hacking and uh and uh and
the you know the
uh what's what's those name the
you know Topo switch what's the name uh
a
um
wait I must remember the name
happy uh oh you guys say it okay tell me
what you know you guys say it
so what uh
it's a very popular brand in Japan okay
they make
they make keyboards using the topper
switch which is the same switch that
happy hacking uses topper is a company
in Japan that produces the topaz switch
um
[ __ ] I don't remember the names [ __ ]
uh you know it's on my website over but
um so anyway so
okay just to the fullest sake so what's
the name of that keyboard here
vehicle okay real Force yeah real Force
they have a red a real force and leopard
geopardy say so real force is also a
company in Japan that makes keywords
with topper switch and the open neopod
is also a Newport is a company in Korea
that also makes keyboards with the turbo
Switch so these keyboards are very
expensive now Leopold they cost like 200
uh 200 you know and rear force is
cheaper
some some of their brands are cheaper
okay some of their models are cheaper so
anyway so
so let's see what's news okay this one
is interesting so this one and I think
so if you are if you like happy hacking
keyboard This one is much better okay
this this is a better bio magnitude
so this one this one is from Kinesis
okay now let me show you let me show you
the
reinforce that's right you are late Sun
sensor will you switch to vs code not
likely not you know I might but not
you know not in the near future I see
because I because it takes a hard time
to learn it
I talked about that before uh about vs
code the situation is that vs code
considered as a technology vs code the
editor potentially has is much more
powerful than emacs can ever do okay
because vs code with JavaScript their
technology JavaScript compiler and
technology and Associated technology is
a magnitude beyond the emacs and emac
beasts and magnitude because for every
one single emacs user they are about 1
000 JavaScript coders and JavaScript for
every you know every com programming
language compiles to JavaScript today
Golan has got uh you know the lots of
your
you know
technology wise JavaScript and you know
vs code which is what vs code is written
on JavaScript is a magnitude Beyond
emacs emacs this is dead it's like you
know it's not moving so JavaScript and
and JavaScript using uh
vs code using JavaScript the technology
is a magnitude Beyond uh emacs okay this
so why have a nice switch I haven't
switched because it because I've been
using emacs for 20 years I if I switch
I'm gonna be very slow you know I'm I'm
gonna take time to learn and I'm going
to you know I need to write my own you
know stuff like this in vs code in
JavaScript uh but it's gonna take time
so for three for three months I'm gonna
be very slow so
and I kind of literally if I do that I'm
literally I'm abandoning my 20 years
expertise in emacs and emac beasts so
you know so there's a you know there's a
advantage and disadvantage but
so but right now I don't have the time
to spend on vs code I need to do a lot
of things you know at mathematics
Wolfram language you know I one of the
thing I've been wanting to tell you I
might want to talk about it but anyway I
don't we don't have time today let's
talk about keywords okay
so because because because
sit at least you know asking about
keyboards so let's talk about keyboards
so anyway this this keyboard Kinesis
okay
it's better than uh Happy hacking in so
many ways and those it's also cheaper
than happy hacking first of all it's got
some keys Okay small space bars so
it
so so from so many
considerations this keyboard is much
better than happy hacking okay from the
and this one is programmable happy happy
hacking the you know the the under 200
version is not programmable the classic
happy hacking Pro the new or happy
hacking codes idiotically called happy
hacking hybrid that is programmable but
that one is 350 50 dollars
so this this one is new interesting okay
uh this this from Kinesis you know not
my keyboard
so let me show you my keyboard Okay so
so let's go to so let me show you my
keyboard for a second
okay so Kinesis advantage and then
ultimate hacking keyboard I show it
almost in every one of my videos okay
okay so let's put it back
Okay so
so it's made by the you know the same
company in kinesis
you know so it's interesting I I think
you know I already have enough keyboards
and I want them to be ergonomic but if
you don't touch type this is uh I reckon
I do recommend okay
so that that is that let's see what else
uh let's see what else I talked about
this so I noticed uh there is a
foldable tablet you know affordable kind
of phone from Microsoft Microsoft
Surface dual so that's what it called I
don't know nothing about it uh some
update on sticky key now if you don't
know if you know sticky key is one of
the way to avoid the emacs pinky you
know when you need to press Ctrl alt
lots of times sticky keys is one of the
solution okay so I updated on this page
I show you how to do it on Windows how
to turn it on and how to turn it on on
the Mac and Linux
uh stinky Keys
um what so what's new programmable
keypad okay so here's a bunch of
programmable keypad uh what's new so the
new item is this one Hue on keypad okay
cheap
uh I think it's pretty good so far as I
know um you know
it's amazing in the past 10 years so
many you know Technologies you know so
these days you can buy it for fifty
dollars and it's pretty good I suppose
so my so this is gonna be for your uh
Marco macro pad okay so if you use you
know doesn't matter Photoshop video
editing image editing 3D CAD work or
even emacs for example even for browsing
for example I showed you my ultimate
hacking keyboard that keyboard has 60
something Keys almost all of the keys I
have used up as a macro so I don't you
know I don't control C or oh I don't I
don't do that everything is one single
press single key press key operation so
that that is why I recommend
if you have you know repetitive stranger
you know
so this one is new so let's see and also
this one from Cooler Master
this one's got two wheels at the top
okay so that's also interesting so these
two are new
um
so that's about keypad department so in
and here's a new photo of my you know
my keyboards and this is my software
automatic hacking keyboard okay uhk so I
can show you uh live
My ultimate hacking keyboard macros so
you go here so you can see
yeah so this is my ultimate hacking
keyboard markers
ultimate hacking keyboard you still got
the most easy to use software
okay so I'm gonna not going to
demonstrate it now okay so that's that
keyboard not go so
a bunch of other things these are kind
of the things I need to work on and here
is the mouse uh here's the track wall
very interesting it's got two spoke
wheels that that's a that's a very good
thing okay two square Wheels you know
most most good ideas you know they don't
come to the
average people or the hacker types they
don't you know they don't they don't
think but anyway these two two miles is
a fantastic thing because the mouse
wheel is the most optimal choice for any
command that involves two directions for
example page up and down
page up and down move the cruiser left
and right move the cursor up and down or
left and right by words like paragraphs
you know or
or volume sound volume up and down or
browsers browsers tab you know previous
tab next tab or Windows previous window
next window let me show you which one uh
wait do I have the key I forgot where is
the key
uh do I have the key
I don't have okay so oat I don't
remember so oats you know on Windows
oats Escape okay
you see so that's the previous window
next window
you know so any command that involves
left right up down or previous next
uh workspace previous workspace next
workspace the most the best the optimal
input for device for that is a mouse
wheel okay
uh yes
so so that's why that's why I say this
too much wheel is a great idea in fact
you know
anyway so
so that's uh you know so this this one
okay this mouse I think it's old mouse
but I'm not sure this Japanese guy he
reviewed it and he
you know this guy is a Japanese on
Twitter he is a trackball expert he's
got like almost every triple ever made a
hundred of maybe 100 of them like you
know this this guy got all the
trackballs ever made
and he you know he's talking so these
are his photos I got permission to use
it so he is a you know he opened this up
according you know I don't read Japanese
but it seems to okay so this one is made
in 2006. yeah I don't think you can buy
it anymore
so anyway that's this that's this you
know this this this is part of the
trackball history okay so I collect uh
essentially I collect virtual history
you know I collect photos of the old
track boss uh and uh
you know because some of them I grew up
with him for example The Marble Madness
this one's from this one from 1980s 1984
when I was in Taiwan I played this I
played this game fantastic I love it uh
Marble Madness so so I essentially
witnessed the birth of trackball well
actually the first trackball is uh 1960
something you know it's a giant bowling
ball
anyway so but these are the early
commercial trackboards you can buy for
example the earliest one is probably so
far as I remember is this one okay now I
don't know what date is this one
uh 1990s yeah so it shouldn't be here it
should be anyway so this one for example
in in 1989 I remember I remember this ad
okay that was very funny and some of
them so I very much remember it's in my
memory you know when I was uh young like
you guys you know every day you talk
about oh Apple's new chip M1 oh new
device new toy apples new phone so back
then you know you also have this so
trackball this one is the kind of I want
to buy it but you don't have money when
you are a student this this one cost
like hundred dollars in 1990 this is you
know this thing and also I remember
uh for example this this one I remember
this one
you know expensive
when you are a team but you want it
because you know it's uh and I also
remember this one
so anyway so this here are the trackball
history
uh okay so I think that's it I need to
shut down in eight minutes anything else
okay nobody
okay so trackball so okay so let's see
let's put this on my website
uh talk show against go to talk show and
uh pastry here
uh
okay is there anything interesting
actually yeah there are some interesting
um there are some things interesting
okay by the way I also have a complete
tutorial for auto hard key there is so
so right now if I want to toggle toggle
maximize window I can just press the key
okay press one key you cannot do that on
Windows you have to windows down arrow
and windows of Arrow two different Keys
If you press down arrow by mistake it
will minimize it will disappear the
window so that's not good it's idiotic
so you you use this other hard key code
I have a tutorial so you can go there
see how to download and so on then you
can press one single key to uh maximize
you know previous previous window
maximize uh toggle it back
previous window toggle it back okay
so this is fantastic so you want to you
want you might want to use that okay
let's see what else uh
how to set switch to how to set key to
switch browser yeah lots of technical
software tips about
keyboard shortcuts okay so I have for
example this is how to use set
this one is about how do you set a
single key press to
to either go to a application or launch
it if it's not already running okay one
single key for example if I want to you
know it doesn't matter which way I am if
I want to go to emacs I just press one
single key okay let me show you let's
let's show you okay
so if you if I want to go to emacs you
see it doesn't matter where I am okay if
I want to go to uh edge browser
okay uh wait there yeah emacs edge
browser this is Chrome okay and and and
and and this is uh Power Powershell okay
you see so why do I do that so why do
you want to you know okay I talked about
this before so what's wrong you know
normally you press Ctrl tab okay oh tab
is no good because you have to hold it
then you have to decide where where is
it you have to spend you have to think
about oh which one is it
then you you went over oh you have to go
back now you have to hold shift key you
know to go back that's idiotic so
instead you want a single key such as f
f five six seven eight F5 F6 F7 f8 map
then map them to the to the application
so you use the most frequently there
why because that way you establish
muscle memory because if you want to go
to emacs you you buy muscle memory you
just you know uh by reflex you press one
key and you are there
okay so that is why
that is what this page is about how to
set key to switch to browser uh wait
okay so
yeah so it may it needs not to be a
browser it can be anything else
no I don't use Virtual desktop okay I I
think it should be banned never use any
virtual desktop you know it works
sometimes it's called workspace or you
know don't use them you know they begin
in Unix then they started to have that
on the Mac on Windows that's idiotic
okay you don't need virtual desktop
because your desktop is already virtual
can you you know it's already all the
windows you know you by using a virtual
desktop or workspace you do not actually
kind of generate a virtual new space
actually it doesn't happen because your
space is just this big
your windows are already virtual okay
so so what the workspace actually do is
they kind of create a grouping that's
all they do they kind of create a
grouping for your workflow you know
maybe if you know one workspace for your
browsers one workspace for your image
editing work you know you have auto shop
or light Adobe something something or
something images you know then another
you know this is another workspace for
games or some something like that so all
they do is create grouping okay uh
which creates more management problem
than it's worth okay then it's what you
know so so speaking of that just search
for sorry window okay just search for
why
window
manager sucks why turning Window Manager
sucks okay
then you will find tiny window of
circulus so collects your ass this
[ __ ] website you know store my uh my
number one position because it
[ __ ] you know because yeah I I'm
pretty sure it's a
who is this
why targeting window managers suck less
success your ass
okay go to this page Why tiny manager
sucks you know the um
so this is a very popular for being 10
years so here I give all my reasons okay
and I suggest to you a alternative
workflow
if you try it for a month or for a week
you'll never use tiny window managers
again well actually use
you see you may still want to use it the
issue with telling Windows managers is
that it
it's it is not really the tiling that is
its primary feature although it's you
know it's in your name titling Windows
Manager Tiding Windows manager but
actually the
the good thing about the Linux tiling
Windows Manager is not about the window
tiling it's about
these applications provide a systematic
and elaborate way for you to have
shortcuts to control your windows
positions so
half of the title Window Manager
Fanatics the Linux idiots they are using
targeting windows and app manager not
because the titing but rather because
the the keyboard shortcuts anyway most
of them are idiotic okay these people
they have no no they have no brain they
have no idea what they're talking about
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
yeah that's it that's that's it
um random stuff so that's it for today
if you like my stuff donate okay buy my
stuff you go to
you know you can essentially go to any
of my website
then you go to okay go to study.info
okay
sally.info all the way to the bottom you
can patreon me you can Amazon gift card
me
you can PayPal me
I'll be calling me okay do it
and then you can buy
you can buy my emacs tutorial or my
JavaScript in-depth tutorial
thank you guys thank you guys for
watching
bye guys