mm good morning everyone welcome to
another episode of Zatoichi oh I look
very nice now I'm a thief okay
good morning Bartholomew
good morning Carrick where are you from
Carrick let me prepare today's topic
meanwhile you guys pick a topic okay
feel free you know type type something
in the chat box just type it and I am
going to you see this is RSI syndrome so
I have this metal boss so you see these
are made of stone solid stone and
meanwhile I have this made of krynki
metal okay let me show you so you see so
this is my workstation so dislocation
and you rotate them you can keep them
always in touch okay
Oh in in the other direction or you can
not have them touch each other when you
roll it's annoying they make this this
this clinky once they make they make
noises I rather prefer them not to make
noises like this so there is a lot of
them you can buy these are good for your
knowledge this is this not three of them
[Music]
three of them fantastic now you just
draw on your finger so and you know you
guys buy the keyboard this is the best
keyboard okay the best keyboard in the
universe actually I wouldn't say it's
the best in the universe but you buy
I know about you by okay you buy all my
for my website just such folks sorry
keyboard I give you the the master the
master advice about those things now
okay
heaven let's have a sip of drink and I'm
going to talk about today's thing so
first of all saw start command log mod
okay in case we are doing Emacs then you
can see all my commands right there
let's shrink the window and I'm going to
show you okay
show the hand exercise balls okay there
are few topics are prepared now let's
prepare today's notes SAR talk show
Emacs a brief okay fantastic now I need
today's date date okay now I need to
create a new page and create a link just
like this one so I go back here call X n
key X our new page all custom Emacs
Krantz
I have written fantastic now I press a
key you see on the left side you can see
tap now I type L i okay it becomes a
list item cut now go over here taste
shrink those okay now I go over here one
key press you see one key press one key
press cut that now I go to this you see
another one key press ok now I press one
key to save it open it show in browser
today's notes okay now another one key
another one key back to Emacs then paste
remember we just we copied we cut that
now go back here one key and make it a
list showing browser fantastic
there's things I want to talk about
that's the expert that's the mastery of
Emax operations the most efficient
possible
brought to you by sawfly keys soft like
keys okay magnify so today's topic what
is today's topic
good morning Carrick from Brazil oh
great I have a Brazil follow up from
Brazil Brazil you know in my brain Percy
when I think of Brazil Brazil is hot
women like Brazilian wax I've never been
to Brazil but I've lived in Paraguay
Paraguay in 1994 for one year that is
when I was 14 okay when I was young when
you were young when I was young that was
yeah so I was talking about my you know
this repetitive strain injury so right
now I actually have that like I can feel
some kind of hurt it's not exactly pain
you know this this been there for a year
so I do this this metal ball I hit it oh
just like that it feels comfort for some
reason you know you get old so I don't
know what is the cause of this time the
repetitive repetitive strain injury this
time I don't know you know the
repetitive strain injury when you when
your hand feels numb or tingling your
fingers you know it every person is
different some for some people it's you
know some tingling on the thumb or the
you know pinky or index finger you know
it's different for everyone
sometimes it's the you know the arm
sometime it's a wrist so it's different
for everyone so in the past 15 years I
had you know repetitive use and each
time it's different but usually when it
happens you know where I feel numb or
something I spent a month
to try to figure out exactly what's the
cause and usually I did find out you
know for example in in 2005 that's the
first time I have repetitive strain
injury you know as 2005 I've been typing
on a computer keyboard since 1991 so
I've been using keyboard for 15 years I
don't have a problem but until 2005 so
what is the cost of that the cause of
that is because for two years entire two
years I was using a Mac laptop that is
the cost
Mac Mac laptop laptop typing on a Mac
laptop that is a cause so let me show
you a little bit a bit of that so you
you know you so bothering me says why do
you have the injury if you are already
entirely ogo transformed yeah I can tell
you why you can tell talk about that
bathroom you says it's my favorite
language for my private stuff what name
oh you also do name well someone else
benefit besides me no name oh you okay
so cool what do you have the injury okay
so this is a mosquito in the u.s. you
know this is the best one minute later
actually I wouldn't say it's the best
yeah it's true you know so we so we can
talk about which exactly is the best you
know if I forgot if you like to you know
like if you want me to talk about that
we can you know just remind me just type
it so I was going to say you know you go
to my Emacs page just such focus on the
Emacs okay and you go to Emacs keys you
know this is some of topics like that I
talk often you then you go to there is a
section about Emacs pinky now all these
articles are related to how to avoid it
why Emacs keys are no good what can you
do things like that you
what's a method to press the keys ctrl
keys and so on so that's this section
Emacs pinky and what I want to show you
is how to avoid Emacs pinky okay I
talked about this in my video last week
or so anyway I talked about this often
so but today I want to show you this oh
by the way last time I forgot to show
you this picture you see some people
actually you put this wedge you know
wooden wedge on top of the control key
so that it's even easier for you to use
the palm techniques to hit the control
key so you know so you can do that this
is not the only way I've seen other
people with other creative solutions you
know you want to make the control key
bigger so you can just you know you can
just press it with your palm so this is
great you know you can do that and
actually I have another picture keyboard
block maybe I can show you that but
before I forgot I want to show you the
metal pores okay so anyways so let me
show you the metal boss so you go all
the way bottom to the bottom you can
find several hand exercise toys you know
you can buy this beauty you can buy this
plastic boss these are squeezed balls I
have it you know I have some of these
things and oh you can buy this squeezer
I also have it somewhere here yeah I
should have you know it's somewhere
there on the floor you know it's so
dusty and and juggling okay I can juggle
did you buy showed that in one of the
video I can juggle for example these
balls but but I think I'd rather not
because it's gonna if I drop it's gonna
be
it's gonna be a major problem okay now
this is this is I think my roommate
still sleeping so I should be not too
loud so anyways so you can buy these
they came from you know this this thing
this this boss metal boss they are from
China actually actually let me show it
to you one second okay open back to
Emacs close now on the left window you
can see all my Emacs commands and the
key I'm pressing by the way oh this this
you know s ha HW st s supposed to be
super so it means the command key on the
Mac but however they are actually single
key press for example when you see this
it's a it's actually single key press
let me show you I showed that before you
know but why does it say SW that's
because I'm using a keyboard Marco so I
press one key then that becomes command
W you know so that is why it shows like
that but actually it's one single key so
one of my advice is to always use one
you know to read of key codes you know
never never type key codes so what is it
I want to show ya these this one so
let's go back to kiss our talk show yes
put it here actually go to here and
paste okay so so you guys can go buy it
now suffer I keys okay so what is you
know so if you guys don't have topic and
I'm just going to start to talk randomly
so show exercise pose that is that that
is this thing
okay and then schedule for next week
yeah let me talk about so scheduled for
next next week let's say 10 o'clock
10:00 a.m. every day for next week we
had starting Monday 10:00 a.m. 10:00
a.m. every day okay
San Francisco time okay that's for next
week and I'm wondering if I should have
like fixed topic like Monday its Emacs
Tuesday Emacs Lisp tutorial Thursday
JavaScript Wednesday JavaScript Thursday
maybe YouTube you know random politics
you know things your current events
Friday is something else so I'm thinking
maybe I should do that right now it's
undecided so if you like that say it
okay okay I'm checking checking the
status okay I'm still alive so bothering
bottom you say it's very good idea
because some people want only specific
topic okay so yeah okay so it's okay so
let's say put on specific topic for each
day okay now where am I going to post
that you can go to youtube sorry okay
then go to my channel basically in the
chat box I mean not chat the community
community okay I guess you go to your
community I'm gonna announce the topics
there yeah that's where you go okay so
that's about that let's see you see us
something else I wanted to mention but
so Emax pinkie oh yeah so I was saying
so that's so so so bothering me says I
like all your topics except Emacs it's
not really interesting that one so you
don't use Emacs do you use Emacs so
let's have today's drink
today's drink is this this is a energy
drink sugar-free okay never drink any
drink that contains sugar such as Pepsi
coke and stuff those do things to your
body bad things and do things to your
teeth have you ever seen a video where
they put your teeth in a coke
you know they rot your teeth very very
quickly and I think I'm out of juice so
this is tasteless and I also have milk
with milk with powdered coffee
we both good morning weebo what is kill
highlighted region short cutting
Sophocles is there a comprehensive list
of leader key commands I can find of
course you should know it if you you
know read Microsoft like his page you
know so for example if you want to know
a comprehensive list of all commands
starting with a leader key all you have
to do is let me demonstrate okay so my
leader key is space okay so I'm in
command mod I press space okay
now you see the bottom is a space it's
waiting for my next keystrokes now you
press ctrl H ok let's do it ctrl H
that's it there you go that's a result
you see so this is a so this page can
200 lines so I have about 200 commands
that has a key each one has a key key
sequence beginning with the space key
space is the leader key so that's how
you find it in fact this technique
pressing ctrl H can be turned in that's
that's part of Emacs feature for example
if you want to know all keys starting
with control X okay you can do that
let's do it
so I press control X okay now you see
the bottom it says control X now I press
ctrl H now I get you know all possible
keys beginning with control X so that
this is a general Emacs technique
technique
this is building Emacs just press
control edge you know type the key you
want you know first then type control X
control H a it will list all keys you
know following that so I don't use Emacs
I use an editor you would probably laugh
about Oh bathroom you don't use the
Emacs okay so bottom you say
okay so you don't use in you max so what
is what is the name and the editor yes
name the editor veem so let me guess
okay I don't use Emacs I use an editor
you would probably laugh about I don't
know what me him you know you know you
in my thinking you know editors are not
really important you know you know like
I this is the topic I talk about
sometimes like I'm you know I'm this is
Startalk show so I tell you my thinking
how I think about things how I view
things you know my philosophy kind of
things so I can so you know I'm an Emacs
users and a lot you know
you know Emacs community Emacs users or
whim every day they say Oh which editor
is you know do you use man programmers
it sounds like it's so important in fact
editor is the most trivial it's it's
insignificant okay let me tell you this
okay how do you judge one piece of
software you know suppose suppose you
have any given software between two
software how do you judge how important
it is with respect to humanity okay to
the history also bathroom you says I
used micro made by Z Tyria okay I don't
know what micro I don't know what editor
is that okay let me talk about how do
you judge you know how important is a
piece of software with respect to human
humanity okay not with respect to tech
nerds
you know the with the UNIX philosophy
nerds idiots okay not respect to them
with respect to human humanity or even
with respect to human history how do you
judge a piece of software how is it how
important is it here's how are you
okay imagine there is a God okay there's
a disaster you know you know the status
disasters like earthquake or typhoon or
you know cyclone you know it happens you
know flood you know sue tsunami tsunami
in Japan in Philippines in India typhoon
in Asia in Taiwan in China okay
or in u.s. you have cyclones or storm
you know the whatever every time that
happens you know sometimes you have you
know hundreds people died sometimes
thousand people died it's a disaster
it's a natural disaster and when it
whenever happens you have you know the
stock market for example you go up or
down you know you go down things like
that the stock market and also the
government you know they will have
emergency you know some states they are
declared emergency you know things like
that
they will also access the damage like Oh
two billion things destroyed you know
one thousand people died or two thousand
people died or one hundred fewer dies
and things like that you access the
damage then you try to fix it you know
this is important because most you know
it's important you want to know you know
how much damage what is lost just like
you know just like yourself
if you fail down on the street if you
are riding a bicycle you fell down you
want to access the damage like do you
need to see a doctor or is it just a
scratch you know you need to know that
in the same way natural disaster for you
know region you government or access it
and also it you can see it reflected in
stock market you know all situations in
the same way you if you want to judge
whether language some programming
language how important it is or an
editor's Emacs you know how important
just imagine imagine there is a natural
disaster and from this second arm flip
of a finger Emacs is wiped out okay so
now on Emacs do not exist in a world but
by a magical
disaster let's say then you know the so
Emacs
today disappeared no there's like like
tomorrow like tomorrow somewhere I saw
to you you see max it's good it seemed
the the the entire history of source
code is so good okay nobody you know so
everyone will talk about it but you then
okay so think about just like not other
natural disasters what will happen the
government you know of course they will
exist the damage okay had you know what
will happen I'll tell you what will
happen when if Emax disappear
nothing will happen nothing you you just
switch to them nothing happens you
switch to Adam okay
that's how important Emacs it it is okay
so Emacs so from this perspective you
know my Pacific you know I'm telling you
from this way of expressing this you can
see that Emacs is not important to
humanity at all okay it's like it's like
it doesn't matter it doesn't matter at
all you know ignore the idiot you know
of UNIX philosophy people on the other
hand so editor in general is not
important if Adam died microsoft visual
code you know Visual Studio vehicle if
they anyone with them died doesn't
matter doesn't matter at all okay in a
same way
you can access how important these other
software or programming languages you
can imagine for example let's say scheme
list right many of you this my many of
my followers are list phonetics skin
Lisp you know the most elegant language
or name okay Nemo or that's okay call at
but let's pick one this lid and you know
let's say scheme B's so - so today
scheme this servant suddenly disappeared
what will happen okay I can tell you
what will happen almost nothing okay
nothing
you know scheme is so so in this sense
in this respect you can see
this has no importance with respect to
human animals okay with respect to human
history no importance
what if commonly disappeared nothing
will happen okay common lisp you know
the the my followers so many common list
phonetics nothing will happen let's pick
another language
what if Java suddenly disappeared like
right now disappeared a major disaster
what what will happen then that's
something big okay the the financial the
stock market will all crash okay that's
a major disaster maybe you'll have
people dead died thousands I don't know
people that it's going to be a major
disaster that is how important Java
language is okay in the same way if C
language disappeared C++ disappeared PHP
disappeared they all kind of have this
same effect okay
but if has now disappeared you know
nothing much nothing much happens you
know so anyway that's my that's one of
perspective I'm giving you in my opinion
this is how you Church how important is
a piece of software with respect to
human animals okay not not this with
respect to the wind UNIX philosophy the
Linux idiots the Linux tech kickers okay
or Linux open-source data or idiots they
are idiots okay so so that is about that
let's see what what what what's the
other topic we are talking about ok so
let's write down what we just talked
about over here how to judge the
importance of a of a piece how down ok
show the left window of a piece of
software with respect to humanity of
that is my opinion
you don't hear about this much
among the idiots among the programmers
every day they talk about the UNIX
philosophy people the UNIX phonetics the
Dinah's phonetics there everyday they
talk about over your V being versus VI I
mean win versus Emacs whether the
[ __ ] idiots okay they don't
understand like like I always said many
times they don't they don't understand
humanity they don't understand how the
work world works
you know the open-source phonetics most
most most of them they have no idea they
live in this small you know word the
hackers you know okay so let's schnitzel
so let's see what topic did I miss oh
did I let's I think that's about it
there is another thing I want to show
you which is kind of related to Emacs
and related to how work how do I work on
my website you know for example I you
know I have my website sorry dot info
and my Emacs website and and others
websites you know so what do I do every
day you know so I can show you that I'm
so busy I have to maintain 6,000 files
6000 of essays and tutorials I have to
maintain them 6000 I wrote them manually
tag by tag know intimately manually from
the past 20 years so every day I have to
work on that so I can show you one of
the things I'm doing you know the you
know okay but but that's that's that's
it huh what I have so let me just read
the comments and see what's what is
going on with you guys so we talked
about 30 minutes that's great and what
is this window close it okay so let me
read the comments magnify
magnify okay magnify
now you so if you have comments or
questions you know just type it now okay
type it now and get to it okay so why do
you have the injury hand injury if you
are already entire do go transform now
tell you I'll talk about that so okay so
I used to Michael okay no comments okay
yeah I don't see any comments never
heard of microphone before he looks very
minimalistic in a way is that Michael is
that the one used by Lena Lena store for
tobots
Justine good morning Justin okay so if
you give him convenience I'm Angie okay
okay I don't have juice okay I figured I
email exchanging there is Emacs command
sugar for that would laugh about it it
does not have capabilities of Emacs
yes minimalistic I don't church people
they can use what they like people laugh
that Emacs does too much what's the most
important piece of software then sqr or
PC or see I don't know where I don't
know both of them are important you know
when I'm just what I what I'm saying
about that happy is just that you know
I'm just giving you a method kind of a
way to judge what software is important
now important software does not
necessarily mean good for example you
know for example we have many countries
that are communists
you know the communism idea oh oh you
know when it comes to politics anyway
let's see some other subject let's see I
mean you know it's just wait the way
they are so see and sqr they are of
course very important because you know
they are used everywhere if if C and s
key or if if SQL dies today
then it's gonna be major disaster
nothing you know we're gonna or combo
down we think you know within one week
maybe we'll have zombies we have some
patients the same thing similar with see
if OC suddenly disappear you know yeah
you know we can make a distinction
between whether it's what if you know C
I mean there's two different you know
it's like you know we can think about
you know one thing is if C you can no
longer create any C code let's say C
let's say C compilers or C compilers
disappeared in their source code you
know or C compilers disappear that's one
scenario or the other scenario is that
you can think that all code that's
currently including binary code that's
written in C that oh that disappears
you know it's stop walking stops walking
and disappears that's more serious
that's kind of far more serious
so dingo says Emacs users can laugh they
are busy customizing Emacs I guess he is
pretty important because of all the
system code that would have to be right
and right yeah yeah I you know they are
Linux is written in C right so if you
know if all C programs and you know oh
also for that's written in C disappears
and then that would include Linux
so if Linux stopped working disappears
everywhere that means or Android will
disappear that's so that's going to be
major disaster
so that would mean you know by tomorrow
we'll have a zombie ward okay
I don't have any topics now so I guess
you guys don't have comments let's see
what is this stop play stop stop okay I
don't have any more comments I mean no I
don't have any more topics so let's see
how many people are watching 12 people
watching okay
so if no topic then okay let me just
show you how you know I'm working on
these okay
oh maybe actually I'm thinking maybe we
can stop because my video is getting
longer and longer so bathroom mirror
says bathroom uses how big would your
party be suddenly Linux disappeared I
don't really care I mean it's not like
you know you know he's not like you see
you know I'd you see you see I don't
hate I mean I don't pair it's like I
don't want you know you know I don't
want to damage Linux ok like maybe you
know maybe maybe many people so you know
they watch my flaming about UNIX and
Linux they think you know I would be so
happy if you if something bad happened
to Linux no I actually I don't want that
I I don't care about that ok what so but
what but what I care you know you see
that the thing that that gets me going
is that I want my opinion okay about
this thing to be known in other words I
want you know in a sense I want truth to
be known you know it's like in you know
I want to when I see something that's
untrue and that's why the V spread
that's the thing that that's the thing
that gets me so I want to kind of
correct it ok whether you know you
believe me or not it's up to you but I
want to you know I want to attack it
correct it so actually I talked about
this you know this this is kind of this
is just my life my personality okay this
just so happens some people are like
that
some people are more of a teacher type
some people are leader types some people
are philosophy type some people are
businessman type you know you have
different people so the thing with me is
that I just I want to you know maybe you
could say a critical critical
philosopher or query
you know I just yeah when something is
isn't true that gets on my nerves and
and a lot of people you know don't know
about it chanted that kind of gets on my
nerves so I've been fighting with you
know the UNIX people in Emacs P going in
these people about these kind of things
and I have actually an article I was I
was I wanted to talk about the other day
I mentioned but you can go there by the
hacker code you can click on hacker girl
code and go to there it is this one okay
netiquette anthropology take kickers and
trolls
Sansa's when a person sanity is at
balance when human passion is raging no
adequate must get in a way I wrote that
in 2001 ok this hate kept me alive that
is kind of my life story so anyway my
point you know you see so why am I like
this yeah I mean the thing you know is
that I want to so I don't actually I
have a formula that indicates you know
which issue in society or which tapping
inside society will gets will get me to
you know attack it actually I have a
formula that is ok so on this page is my
collection about about issues related to
internet trolling flame wars you know
internet argument basically quarrels
among people for my point of view my
observations you know and also you know
especially in the tech kickers or you
know UNIX
nerds among these hacker culture that is
the world hacker culture my criticisms
of them so you have you know a bunch of
articles in the past 20 years I've read
it about that topic
you know they many of these people that
you know it's they call me otro and they
attack me they gave me banned song and
and here is my retort you know I'm
telling you why you're you know actually
you know things like that for example
but there's okay so there's article I
want to talk about the the let's read
some of the titles okay and but okay
before we do that by the way there is
this this Shakespeare's quote okay hold
on a second let me read another passage
I also TRO is rather special because I
tend to put a final say on things in
contrast with one-liner trolls
I myself despise I actually despise
draws in a sense I'm an anti troll
untrue or an atrocious a troll
at first I poked at being branded a
troll now i rebel it i ah cytro is
rather recent beginning and getting
worse around 1998 1998 I have been using
online forums since 1990 perhaps one day
I'll write how I became a troll
it is bound to be a tragedy so I wrote
that in 2002 then there is this quote
I'll find a day to Massacre them all and
raise their family their fashion and
their family now this is Shakespeare
this is Shakespeare's play Titus
Andronicus this is fantastic play okay
Shakespeare I read the whole thing
several times and i annotate it it I
spent like a year annotate the entire
thing by reading Wikipedia you know
reading the whole thing word by word if
what I don't understand I look up
dictionaries and then I look up
Wikipedia so I actually did annotations
oh thing and this is my kind of my
favorite play okay this is this play is
this play is about revenge is about
trashes okay atrocious it's more trashes
then then you know the modern movies of
go you know and she you see this
character her name she is Lavinia her
hands got cut off her turn cut cut off
anyway
so so so about Rose okay so let's read
some of the titles program programs
infatuation with the concept of hacker
you know program has got the thing he's
got a you know obsession with the with a
concept of hacker and you know he's this
guy he's you know rich he sold you know
he wrote the you know the programming
common list and so lead to Yahoo and
became the Yahoo store he saw that for
you know several millions or hundreds of
millions you know in 2002 or something
like that so he become very rich and you
know once we come once you become famous
and rich and he's also the type of guy
he's a writer type of guy you know like
he talked a lot he web he liked to write
about his opinions on things you know
like me and like you know jamie zawinski
there are quite a few people like that
jamie zawinski richard stallman
eric raymond eric s Raymond yes ah yes
ah yeah Eric s Raymond you know some of
these guys they talk a lot you know the
programmers types and poor programmer
poor granham is kind of one of them so
he write a lot of pinions and and
typically with these people when you are
become more famous you have a lot of
followers right you have you know not as
a programmer for Grammy nerds following
you and you became kind of a god you
know you became the idolized by lots of
programmers and usually it's a case it's
like a movie star you know once you
become a star you have tons of followers
you know then it's almost like anything
you say all the people will talk about
it like watch what should are you
worrying today you know like what should
are you wearing today everyone wants to
know like if you are wearing or a blue
shirt everyone is talking about it
things like that
you know it's like that like that and
once you become a star soap or granham
you know he's reaching famous and he
started the Y Combinator company so he
had you know he wrote a lot opinions and
one of the one of his essay is about
philosophy you know he start to talk
about philosophy what we did you know
that article is rather idiot so I read
that I criticized you know it's kinda
kind of idiot you know me you know once
you become a star like V okay it's even
you know including Bill Gates you know
in any stars like you you you have
opinions but you don't really know much
about that things so generally this is
true so let me give you a device okay if
you know you know a star you know maybe
in programming or whatever you know oh
you know celebrity celebrity okay yeah
you can follow them but remember they
are whatever they say in general you
know don't believe it it's like almost
like [ __ ]
the only thing you can you can actually
trust whatever you know that has a valid
a good value is what they are known for
for example what things Paul Graham say
that I will kind of pay more attention
and believe it is valid he would be what
what whenever he's a pin he have opinion
on Common Lisp then I would you know
value it very much I would pay attention
to what what he say
you know now if I don't if I don't know
anything about Common Lisp then I will
just believe him okay now remember
Common Lisp not other languages not
Haskell not functional programming not
you know how how language should be
designed okay remember this is what must
be very specific
why common list because he is a we can
be sure he is a common list expert okay
because he he wrote you know Yahoo so in
common is
so whenever he says something about
communists it's likely to be very valid
okay and also whenever he talked about
you know startup companies how do how to
run a company
that's likely to be a VAT to to be valid
okay because you know he started Y
Combinator very successful about how
entrepreneurship you know but however
any other opinion like his opinion about
hackers
he's opinion about what's philosophy you
know what how you whether philosophy is
important that's that's basically almost
garbage okay
it's like you know almost garbage in the
same way let me give you this example
like if you read you know today people
like to cite instant
oh I instance said you know imagination
is more important than knowledge
okay you know people like to quote
Einstein this or that or everyday it's
all [ __ ] so what you know so you
know you should be able to tell now how
do you judge if our instance says
something about something how do you
church is good or not not okay it's
about physics now if I understand say
something about physics that's you know
maybe it's a good opinion you should pay
attention anything else on politics on
knowledge versus being smart or you
versus imagination on anything on peace
how to achieve peace peaceful world
you know what piece you know anything
it's tense it's likely it's just like
this is job blues opinion okay this same
thing applies with any Bo gates in any
you know hard shots you know celebrities
so okay that's about that okay let's so
this question so Zhang Zhang Zhang Zhang
Zika has ow what what name is that from
we're from I have I haven't seen you
before so what do you think about mark
Taba in his Shen language okay let's
talk about that
so close that go to go to the talk show
let me type that here okay so go here so
I actually go back to here copy go back
to Emacs paste okay
mob Javed so actually I know him a
little bit we we communicated privately
privately for a few times and also we've
communicated verbally you know income
income dot land dot Lisp a few times
okay
I have about three articles on him okay
this one there is another one there is
another one mop table is kind of a sad
person I mean he is he's extreme nerd
okay he is extreme not in you know I
like him okay I like him I wish him
success but he he's not getting he's not
kind of like me you know he live he
lives in poverty he becomes a monk okay
I mean be a monk you know I'm kind of a
monk in a sense I'm ascetic you know I'm
living in poverty below poverty you know
I I just eat bread just like that bread
milk and survive he's kind of like that
too but he's you know so I you know you
I can say I'm a digital monk you know I
still I do computers he's kind of like
that too but he's a real monk you know
he believes in a branch of Buddhism I
don't know I forgot what branch you know
typically any Westerners you know there
are quite a lot Westerners who are into
yoga who are into Zen who are into Dow
you know who are into Eastern philosophy
Oh dr. gene oh you know eaching oh you
know they pay you into that white people
okay Oh old you know
yeah they're you know they into Buddhism
typically when I see that I think they
are kind of idiots okay yeah just idiots
oh you don't know what it is you know
they the reason they are into Buddhism
because it's exotic because you know
they'd never seen it before it's new
it's novel it's a novelty you know who
Buddhism Oh booty something things you
know about the universe this way oh it's
so great you know doubt Taoism you know
they talk about you know sometimes you
see quotes or that you they name be a
software project Tao something old
cheese something you know when I see
that it's like idiots because to them
it's new it's novel you know they did
tired of the Western philosophy you know
they tired of the justice justice
freedom kind of thought you know yeah
you know so they they find Eastern
philosophy interesting so there a lot of
you know especially especially these
type of people are especially you see
that a lot a lot for example in Silicon
Valley in this California where I live
among Google among Googlers Facebook's
you know these people they are so rich
every day they drive you know expensive
cars you know the the Tesla you know
test our cars you know they are into
green and they you know they leave a
very comfortable [ __ ] these scumbags
and they chant open-source every day Wow
meanwhile they work for Facebook oh you
know Google Apple they make a lot of
money they chant then they say they
chant about open source and they read
open source software at night so they
eliminate any possibility of making
money for me you know who do not work
for open source this scum these are
these people many of them are in emacs
community everywhere everywhere of
course so anyway this typically
especially in California you know these
rich people
many of these programmers they are they
are into the yoga or you know your guys
mostly women okay they are like you know
why because their life is too
comfortable they did they are too
wealthy okay be a special by the way
remember that Jack Dorsey billionaire
who you know the head of trader he
he's into meditation you know he went to
the what country you know IIIi did a
video on that a few months ago such folk
sorry YouTube you know go to youtube
search for Saudi Twitter CEO or Saudi
Jack Torres Dorsey you know Twitter CEO
I think I talked about that so this is
these are people who are rotten you know
he has their life is like too
comfortable
so they search for you know meanwhile
they cannot stop doing evil you know
they keep you know the Twitter CEO for
example they keep doing they know you
know the the way treated you know the
whole society's become corrupt
you know diversion they know why but
they are not they are got not going the
the making more money is more important
for them so they are not changing
Twitter things you know anyway these
scum anyway that check you know Twitter
CEO is one example but he's the extreme
example because he's billionaire but but
but then among Google programmers you
have a lot of them okay so they have a
comfortable life you know they get bored
you know so they want to do you know
they find AC on things interesting you
know and and also also constantly they
have a key owed you typically white
people okay be yeah when it comes
through this you know I you know it's
true it's typically always white people
they have some sense of guilt they want
to help with so they you know you want
if you want to help you know stop making
you know there's so many ways you can
help okay but that's that's you know
that's not what they choose to do they
instead of they are you know they are
help you know other people is such the
way such way that they keep making money
they keep making more money then you
know they they will find a way to
convince others and convince themselves
that they are doing a lot help for the
world you know the poor or women or you
know but meanwhile actually they make
more even more money than before as
these white people so anyway
I wanted so that's my opinion about
white people in the end and into tau is
I'm okay but let me get back to talk
about marked our white people yuppies
programmers programmers had Google
Google Facebook Twitter act why they are
into Eastern religion okay that's my
opinion my commentary about that because
they don't know nothing about Buddhism
if they lived in China or Taiwan for
like ten years or half of their life
maybe they will not be interested in
Buddhism okay I can tell you for sure
now now about Mark Taba
okay let me copy the comments okay so
that meanwhile let's do some Emacs demo
okay
so speak okay hold on a second let's
switch back okay so you can see my other
command windows so open a new buffer
paste okay now copy the file path paste
paste here change the HTML to text okay
make it a paragraph and go back to put
kusa on here and open it it doesn't
exist do I want to create it yes okay go
back here cut back here paste okay close
save it okay now now make a link okay
now close that empty buffer now show
this in browser now I got the link of
today's chat actually it's not complete
so anyway so let's talk about mock tava
and now marked harbor so he's kind of a
very special person I mean so he's kind
of weird guy okay he he was a professor
he was a professor and he you know he
quit because he he do not believe these
you know this stack stash establishment
you know the institutional institution I
institutionalized education system well
because there's a lot corruption in
stuff so he just quit
he just one day he quit and he start
started to live a kind of a nomadic life
I suppose I don't know exactly
so anyway he and he believed in Eastern
Buddhism's some branch I forgot what and
he you know he saw he actually become
you know he's V okay not like typical
white people he's he actually believed
that deeply he went to live in India he
went to live in India and become you
know live with the monks and he becomes
a monk officially I think you know as
you know officially you know so let's
let's mark tava very interesting guy and
he created in a beginning he created the
chi language okay so I have several
articles about that okay the first one
is this one I created this logo for him
this is back in 2011 okay she okay why'd
she leave fails in closure succeeds
that's one article the another article
is why the Oracle is what's philosophy
of program ham Chile's creator marked
Harbor on is philosophy useful okay
remember Paul Graham wrote this essay
about whether philosophy is useful it
turns out mark Taba also responded to
that now mark Chavez got problems he's
you know he delete his website you know
his website his marketing skills is zero
okay it's it's easier to such a degree
that
you know that for many reasons his
language is nowhere you know not going
nowhere know this then so he created Qi
language C language is kind of a it's at
least okay it's a it's a modern Lisp
okay he created Qi then later on he
destroyed it then he created she - then
he renamed it you know it didn't become
Shen you know it's it's it's no good
okay I mean the Lang I think he's a I
don't really know the language I think
but I think it's good but however the
way he do things to it you know like
changing the name then changing website
you know he does that all the time
it's like he's easily that kind of a
kind of a idiot guy in destroying these
things okay any anyway he wrote a book
there's a book the book of Shen okay you
know by the way Qi so so he you know he
is very much into Eastern philosophy I
mean I mean he he becomes a monk he's an
actual monk
so Chi it's a Chinese word meaning kind
of it kind of mini it means energy or
energy and spirit I mean it means
multiple things Chinese words are like
that but generally means like energy or
spirit or your breath you know it's kind
you know this it means kind of like that
so Chi so oh oh it also means essence
the essence of something you know the
essence so that's that's the word Chi so
he created a language named Chi I think
it's great oh you might have heard
chicken which is kind of a kung fu
that's suppose you know anyway that's
Chi then he after a few years he he came
up with a new version he called Shen now
Shen that means God okay basically so he
created a language that means God you
know in Chinese God you know the West
Western people have this you know hacker
types have this
the attic kind of silliness like every
time they have they they have a
obsession to name something God for
example you know in Emacs you have won a
mod called God mod ok Oh in other
languages like you you know constantly
or god particle for example in physics
you have god particle
so in western you know in western
society among the white people it's a
kind of cultural you have this obsession
about Nimmi
oh you're like something something God
God God particle God mud guard language
you know it's kind of idiotic so again I
mean illustrating the difference you
know the Western societies you know
philosophy and concept is quite totally
different from the Eastern culture ok in
Eastern culture you don't you don't you
never name something god something you
know it's like you see the concept
doesn't exist ok you don't name
something God gods something yoga it's
like doesn't exist you don't do that you
know so anyway so he named you know he
named his language Shen ok so I don't
know I haven't tried these languages but
I tried to you know you know since I
know mark I've tried to since 2007 ok
yeah 2007 I created this logo for him
then he used it on his forum then after
a few years he did ditched it you know
then he changed his language to Shen DS
see idiot okay don't change your name
okay nobody knows I mean even through
this day nobody know what the [ __ ] is
Shen
he's a complete idiot I mean not at
marketing okay not even that we are not
talking about marketing I mean usually
nuts we don't like marketing right you
know we don't like you know the you know
so twisted commercial commercial
commercial a season you know the you
know monasticism becomes evil you use
also sort of evil tactics to grow your
product things like that we don't like
that anyway
the macht have a guy he's not even I
mean we are not even mentioning about
mocking he's such a person that his
behavior I mean whatever the way he
thinks his behavior is such that that
has a negative impact on whatever the
thing he creates like he makes it less
less and less popular he like like his
decision he's thinking just have that
effect okay just make it make it less
make it fail his peak is kind of like
that like every time you know thoughtful
example one example is like he kept
changing them rename his stuff like
nobody even know what is she yet you
know and she's being around you know
since 2007 but nobody knows but then he
decided oh we gonna be gonna have she
too then then he decided we're gonna
have shed fact you know idiot what a
complete idiot that's one example one
example of his his behavior such that
totally destroys any successful himself
there are quite a few other examples
that's you know that's that's where I
talked about it in this article why'd
she least fails and closure succeeds
you know Crozier is another another Lisp
family of languages but however the
closure guy which he ki you know I also
talked to him a few times you know the
week rich Hickey guy you know he's an
English guy he's successful you know
closure is such a success great success
I mean we are not talking about you know
oh maybe he he employs some nasty
tactics or some blackhat SEO so to grow
his language nothing like that you know
rich Hickey is just no more guy okay
he's not greedy at all I know you know I
study people like went wherever I touch
people I study them I look into you know
behavior what have they done their
history kind of these somewhat okay so I
know rich Hickey he's not a greedy guy
he's in my opinion okay he's good person
and also everything I like him except
you know the the crucial language
intermix with Java I don't like that
part that's why I don't you know it's
too much closure but anyway you cheeky
is a great guy you know so you know so
and he's not you know some kind of nasty
businessman not at all you know he just
do reasonable you know like I created
the language closure I put on my website
and you know I put create a website so
people know and it just squirrel like it
grew not because some Evo tactics
because people like it they just screw
you know and if people have questions
they can ask him you know maybe he if he
have time he answered it you know it
just grow and grow okay rich rich Hickey
closure very successful meanwhile you
know the Chi is kind of you know the Chi
or Shin is also very I think it's I
don't know you know I don't know the
language but I can I can kind of tau
it's also a great language okay a
complete new Lisp but is it's going
nowhere
why because why because mocked over
himself he is kind of like destroying he
you know it's it it kind of has to do
with a personality that's the thing you
see the reason it's like this now is
because personality maybe it's like me
okay I'm not you know I'm living in
poverty poverty you know things like
that you do to yourself you know it's
just the way you interact with society
your personality so anyway so that's why
I think you know Mark Hoffer is kind of
like that okay he just he just failed
okay this arco is kind of unrelated
that's anyway so anyway so I have these
three articles about Chi and also you
know I have you know also by the way
Mauck tava he has roads okay I actually
I have more articles than these let's
see if I can find it
he has another article okay he has
another outcome October you know mark
tava has road owner after toll where he
basically criticized open source and
free software foundation just like me
he's his opinion open source and free
software is almost exactly like my he
has written an article an essay about it
but then but he's his website is gone
like he'd this idiot okay mark tava he
one day the entire website you know it's
called lambda associated I think the
website is called yeah there it is it's
entirely one day it's just deleted so
it's this mock w he he you know he's got
problems with this issue
one day it's deleted you know oh wait
okay so anyway lambda associates dot org
he was his website he was the home of G
and home of shin one day it's just good
then I guess you know the then the the
web squatters the spammers took over you
know bad part the domain name that is
why you see these account suspended
that's that's why I'm pretty sure that's
okay so anyway so lambda associate so
you have to go to web archive okay you
go to web archive internet you know
Wayback Machine then you can search for
lambda associate that's the that's
marked Ava's website so you see back in
two thousand then you can start to read
you know you can go check your check it
out yourself so that's my opinion about
mark tava I don't know how he is doing
now you know and also he kind of pissed
me off
one one time you know because
at least in my mind you know I really am
his friend okay
I want to help him succeed even I don't
have money
I'm kind of liking the same same
ballpark as him okay on the on the edge
on the brink of existence but at least
you know I can you know I read my blogs
so I mentioned his stuff in you know I
create the logo for him I tried to
promote it but but then I also wrote
this article okay I wrote this article
you know criticize you know white white
she dispels and why croushore succeeds
this article is in 2011 but but then
later on like a year or two ago I
noticed on he's the same language or Chi
you know ocean they have a Google Talk
forum where people can talk about
language one day I saw you know in one
of his message I guess someone mentioned
someone mentioned my criticism of his
issues then as you know then mocked over
responded now I'm not going to dig into
you can you can search and find it okay
and basically he said you know oh yeah
casaya is such a troll you know
basically he said something like that
cuz i'll you know such is such as troll
you know that that hood you know that
hurts me you know because it at least to
me you know I was you know trying to you
know it you know trying to promote him
and Chi and then you know he's just like
oh he's a troll you know so that's about
that
so bottom USA's ok bottom you says a
closure already has a big advantage
being based on JVM yes maybe you need to
breath mochi into your inquiry about
what inquiry of what so closer ok so
these concepts are more volatile
especially than Western in my humble
opinion I forgot what's the context and
dingo says that ok then bottom you says
on Shane's website it never mentions God
he says that Shane means something like
spirit yeah that's what he said you know
Shane just means God I mean you again
Chinese has multiple meanings so Shane
so first of all the east and you know
the eastern word God do not have the
exact same meaning like the God in
Western society ok so God you know God
but but if you have to translate you
know it's a word God so instant society
or culture you know China or Japan oh
you know God you know you don't have
like single you know so-called
monotheistic religion it's not one God
okay so in Western society when you say
God typically the implication I mean we
understand typically one God
you know Christian God only or maybe is
them basically one God okay one God but
that's not the case seeing Eastern
philosophy you know doesn't matter Hindu
or or Buddhism or Germany you know you
don't have the concept of a single God
so when we say God Oh
son son okay let me show you Chinese
then okay how you can then you can try
to google translate okay so I'm gonna
type Chinese
okay that's the third word I think yeah
Chinese have many homeowners South third
okay that is the character now you can
you can google wikki wikki wikki
scenario google translate you know
whatever you can find what the meaning
so let's go to let's try to search okay
so wikipedia we can go to Wikipedia this
is a Japanese version and we can
actually let me show you my Emacs
techniques okay when you have it okay
type that magnify Emacs has this problem
and god reopen okay
magnify magnify okay
this Chinese character now let's say Co
Emacs command MX etymology actually
Chinese okay Sawa's Chinese link of I
okay now showing browser magnify so we
got three links okay so actually show
this in Google Chrome because I don't
have JavaScript on in Firefox okay so we
have this page we have three links okay
Google Translate Wiktionary and history
of the character let's look at them one
by one so I think that's it for today
I've been talking yeah that's about it
so you can see Google Translate is a
Scott you know god deity yeah deities
probably the better translation deity
but deity is less and you know less
common word most of you understand God
deity is like rest people understand
that divinity yes spirit yes
well look yeah look kind of yeah it's
expression not really you know if you
want that word to mean look or
expression you have to combine with
other words okay anyway by the word Sun
it's pronounced let me pronounce it okay
son
okay again son son now you can see how
Google pronounced it you cannot hear it
but anyway you can anyway so it means
cot tea or tea dimino tea okay then
let's go to wiki Wiktionary magnify you
can see similar okay let's see Chinese
you see Chinese characters are used in
Japanese in Chinese then also in Korean
so also in Vietnamese that's why it's
very confusing in Wiktionary so anyway
so let's go to so it shows you the the
etymology the you know the old way to
write the character so so this character
can be written like you know like went
2000 years ago it's like that and
there's Mandarin pronunciation you can
read definition okay so religion god
deity speriod speriod so mind okay then
expression continents appearance or
supernatural magic okay okay things like
that then on this page again this is the
history of the character so in bronze in
bronze characters Bronze Age you know
not Bronze Age bronze in any way like
2,000 years ago it's written like that
so eventually becomes like that that
this is what it looks like today
okay so anyway that's the how because
this website by the way it's made by
this guy this white guy he's you know he
study Chinese characters so anyway I
think that's about it so why are we
talking about this character yeah
because we were talking
the shame language okay that's that's it
for today anything else so two more
minutes actually this time for real two
more minutes I'm going to shut down any
questions last comments next video so
tomorrow and tomorrow next week okay
tomorrow is Sunday so tomorrow is gonna
be 9 o'clock
same same time as today but starting on
Monday - you know next week Monday we're
gonna have 10 o clock a.m. San Francisco
time
so any last last words guys last words
you know when you have something
something then you have what's your last
word shrink shrink
bye guys now I need to have a drag of
this let's see
can you see the smoke can you see the
smoke now this one this is THP it
doesn't have much smoke Carrick bank
Eric where are you from again Carrick
Tinga weeaboo weeaboo
Oh NIM I forgot to talk about name but
name is this language based on Oh your
name is like kind of like : in the same
class of goal and it's you know very
fast very yeah very fast it's kind of
compiled and the syntax is what is like
was it Python
I think it's syntax is python-based or
was it Ruby
I think it's Python but Ruby has similar
there's a language called crystal so
this is so we I'm gonna close close shut
down but let me type last you know one
thing crystal a name Christel :
let's see for liberation sorry
proliferation of languages let's look
ahead
it's all the way near the bottom so many
languages you know I can talk you know
so many things we need to talk this is
this is why that is why we have sought
out show you know we need to talk
Julia you know the the view you know the
look into humanity look at what human
animals are doing this is what they are
doing at least one aspect of it you know
this so so many languages Elm hacks hack
Swift elixir cuddling carving became a
very popular theme
I need a vim logo name not been named
name is a Python syntax with modernized
see like semantics in speed yeah I heard
a lot good things about name so so name
to me is just like Python you know
modern Python something let's see
something like that I mean if you want
once one sentence summary then it's like
fast Python like Python but in see speed
you know something like that then
crystal crystal is like Ruby in C speed
okay
and to me I you know I look at them I
think of them like go that you know I
don't I don't I don't fancy name and I
don't fancy crystal like I'm not going
to study them because I'm just going to
stick with : you know stick with
mainstream because like I said there's a
thing okay maybe you know maybe they are
technically superior you know it's
possible they are very truly technically
superior and better than call ad you
know but but the thing is you know you
it's kind of this niche you I mean these
are from you know I know there are
people you know computer nerds you know
they they kind of you know they are
gonna know where like scheme you know
after ten years
you know it's like scheme this you know
it's it's goin goin nowhere so you have
to consider the social aspect so I for
example you could say I wasted my life
for 20 years I wasted my life now I'm a
well-known and well-known Lemax
community and and and as they Emacs Lisp
expert kind of you can I kind of wasted
my life you know what would you gonna do
with Emacs him oh you Maglis nobody give
a [ __ ] okay that's it for today
thank you guys for watching I'll see you
Brazil all right
yes that forgot see you next time bye