moaning radians ladies and gentleman
welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh today is 2019 September 23rd Monday
Nile croc p.m. 9 o'clock a.m. in the
morning San Francisco time and I'm 5
minutes early today
I've got a lot topic for you guys I'm
going to talk about keyboard and but if
you have any topics you know type a
topic in a chat box just type it ok
let's check if I'm alive yes I'm alive
indeed let's stop this praying ok so
when the while there are no people here
yet let me show you what I'm gonna talk
about I'm going to talk about there are
some interesting things about index
finger you know if you are watching my
youtube channel not live if you are not
watching it live you can always play at
one point two five speed usually that's
better or one point five so good morning
Green deck good morning to Russia
good morning to ya cause ring bug City
is that right so green deck do you have
any topics you you like to see you know
type it okay
and good morning is splendid splendid
where you from again so today I have
several topics I prepared that's
interesting
that's about keyboard morning Amman
Amman morning to Egypt
Kerry oh so we have the world of people
here and good morning Pablo good morning
to Spain
fantastic Oh mistress mistress splendid
is also from Russia great
good morning arcane
moaning okay where you from so guys pick
a topic okay but I do have three topics
that's related to keyboard I'm going to
tell you about so one is this fingering
link okay and let's open them let me
show you okay
oh okay so also from Russia so splendid
and are can do you mind telling us what
city in Russia let's look it up
good morning mister ether flow I just
tried to set one point one point five
speed for leaves live stream can you can
do that I didn't know what happens if
you said one point five speed to live
stream I'm not sure what's happened that
oh okay is wrong in Moscow and mr.
splendid is also in Moscow Wow Moscow
okay that's interesting you know this
you we got week we've got a YouTube bug
here you see it says to watching that's
not correct I got at least five people
in a chat room so I can't say as he
lives elsewhere now okay so meet the
ether flow ether flow
oh nothing okay
okay if you guys don't have a topic I'm
gonna start talking about my stuff Mikey
related to keyboard okay hold on a
second hold on a second so fingering and
sake Ward and tenting okay some Pablo
says topic how do you construct your
website Emacs menu structure publishing
okay we can talk about that so okay let
me put it down here so I don't forget so
here is today's notes and let's type
that topic okay so now let's talk about
didn't let me show you something
interesting
about keyboard okay keyboard design that
is well it's of a general interest okay
everyone uses keyboard you know keyboard
is one of the popular topic because
because every you know every one who
watches my view Tube videos uses a
keyboard you guys are probably working
with computers all the time
you guys are hackers now you see look at
the fingering length okay so let me let
me see if I can show you my fingers now
observe okay now look at my let's focus
on my one hand yeah I want my head away
so you see you look at the the these two
fingers the index finger and the ring
finger you want to see which one of them
is longer so for me they are about the
same length okay for my right hand but
however on my left hand you can see you
can see my ring finger my ring finger is
longer than my index finger a little bit
you see that's interesting so for my
right hand they are of the same length
like this case see but my left hand my
left hand the ring finger it's a is a
case a here it's a about half a
centimeter longer so check your guys
check your hands so green deck says my
ring finger is longer on both hands okay
so you see this is interesting
so and I did a poll on Twitter so I
asked is is your ring finger longer than
index finger 60% says yes
so most people says yes 24 25 % says no
and 5% says the same and 2% says left
hand right hands are different
okay so it's interesting I got 44 volts
here now this is back in 2017 so green
deck green finger is longer
okay and splendid says ring finger
longer - okay
so most people are doing finger is
longer so Aman says type a yeah same
thing so all you guys ring finger is
longer Scott
good morning Scott good morning - Scott
Scott is on the east code USA after that
was City I think it's around MIT MIT is
in what state is Miss MIT the
Massachusetts are you in Massachusetts
right
so Scott say is significantly longer
ring finger the index finger okay so
oh you guys are case a new hamster okay
those you know I am not familiar with
camp Cambridge Massachusetts
oh good good morning max the Raider oh I
got a lot of people so watching so so
eight o clock 9 o clock in the morning
is a good time actually so it seems to
be so anyway so this is interesting and
why is it interesting because it relates
to the keyboard layout physical layout
design now look at this okay I'm gonna
show you some of the cases why how are
they relevant to keyboard layout design
you see here we have the oboe dogs
keyboard now oh go dogs is one of the I
mean not all go doc sorry keyboard IO
this is about $350 300 or 350 dollars
it's very good okay but it's a bit weird
you spend one month to get used to
anyway let me focus on the finger length
design so you see this is their keyboard
this is the right hand side so this is
the middle finger position
wait no ok so middle finger position is
here but so middle finger is here this
is a ring finger you see it's a slightly
lower than the middle finger because
middle finger is longer you know so so
the ring finger is slightly lower but
however look at the column for the
pinkies it's significantly lower than
the ring finger you see even for my hand
my hands you can see you see this my
pinky is much lower than the ring finger
now for my left hand you see pink pink
pink is much lower so you see they so
that's why they put the pinky column
it's like half of a key hate then the
ring finger key you see that's one
design now this is actually rare this is
actually one of the most extreme half
have a key hate lower for the ring
finger color this is this is one of the
most extreme you will not see another
keyboard like this but it seems to be a
good design but anyway when you
encounter a keyboard like that you're
spent like one week or two weeks to get
used to because you because you make
mistakes so anyway this is the keyboard
aisle and let me show you another one
let me type let me type it here so we
can we can get open last opened copy
link
switch to Emacs paste here link of I and
show in browser so we have keyboard IO
here okay
and let's go back to the page I wanted
to talk about this keyboard now let's
look at this keyboard now you can see
now this is called the verge 3 keyboard
I think it sells for 200 or 250 it's
actually I think it's pretty good I
think this is better than oh go ducks
okay because about
got some problems I mean if you don't
know what is over dogs or dogs is
actually I shouldn't waste my time going
about anyway this is all Pogo dogs
okay aqueducts is known for the some
problems because the thump are too far
out you have to move your thumb all the
time so anyway let's go back to the
diverge okay so yeah I think this is
better than oka docks but but let's look
at the column layout for the pinky okay
so this is the index finger this one so
same thing like almost the same like the
keyboard IO the ring finger is about
one-third key lower you can see let me
see if we can find okay so that this is
a go docks
okay now you can also look at a go docks
look at the right hand side you see this
is an index finger this is the ring
finger it's about one fifth lower than
the index finger then the ring finger is
about one fifth lower again so that's
over docks but now let's look at the
diverge okay so here's an index finger
the ring finger is about one third lower
now the pinky is a again half of a key
hate lower so in this case the for the
diverge three keyboard the pinky is you
know like the same as the keyboard IO so
these two keyboard they have very low
pinky layout I mean the column so that's
interesting so this is about the finger
length design you know so so what about
the Kinesis ago you see this this is
connect Kinesis advantage to this is a
completely different keyboard this is
the keyboard I use
let me show you let's see so this you
see this is Kinesis and look at the you
see they are they are curved
you know they form a poor shape like
rice ball and you can see this thick
this Tiki is much lower so instead of it
you know making them up and down I mean
it actually goes you know intent it's
like this camera is Logitech 9 2009 22
both
sucks they cannot focus but anyway what
I'm trying to show you is that how you
can see how they are a different hate
actual hate not just you see so for the
Kinesis that key you know so so you can
actually look at the picture you know
the picture is much more clear so the so
this key for the index finger T is much
lower than higher than higher so this
way it's a best actually it's a best so
instead of you know shifting shifting
them like in the direction of north and
south this is actually up and down so
that's about that
you know keyboard design keyboard
physical layout design and they are
designed that way because of the finger
length okay that's one topic now let me
read the comments and see where we gonna
go after that
so cabbage Massachusetts MIT is about an
hour south of me in Cambridge okay so
yeah you are in Cambridge Massachusetts
oh no you are in southern New Hampshire
you know those states on the north north
north and No
of eastern side of USA those states are
kind of small so you have a bunch of
them I have never been around they're
the closest state I've been to is
Philadelphia
so okay a bit weird
good morning Israel good morning to
Israel Israel is in Israel
stupid beam keybindings so max Reiter I
think that keyboard would be good for
Emacs because ctrl and alt keys aren't
are hit by thumbs yes indeed
greetings battle new battle new + Z
trunk crazy good morning - German
Germany Israel says then used you have
five three fingers this is all seems
over like over engineering to me mr.
splendid says canal system key cluster
looks similar to ogre docks but you said
over docks a problem with it let me
explain that okay
rice ball suppose regular ball okay okay
let me explain the Kinesis stunned the
problem with the oboe Duck Stamp keys
okay
although docks up go okay then we
magnifier go ducks send key problem
versus Kinesis or white Kinesis do not
have that problem okay this is actually
one of the common question okay I don't
want a paragraph I want the least okay
and you see we have multiple single list
now this is demonstrating my Emacs so I
want to remove the that copy it
move the cursor here query replace paste
it replaced by is nothing yes yes yes
yes yes
showing browser now it's better okay so
the next thing we are going to explain
is about a go Duck Stamp key problem
okay let's go there so ergo ducks
go - oh go ducks okay let me tell you
about a go ducks and one second
where's ago ducks so let's go to over
dogs then do it yourself then go down
there we have a go ducks now
oh go ducks is one of the first do it
yourself kind of ergonomic keyboard they
came out in two thousand two thousand
thirteen that's about time when Do It
Yourself keyboard starts to thrive and
the reason Do It Yourself keyboard
started to thrive is because the
progress of technology in particular 3d
printing 3d printers so anyway oh go
ducks
you know oh go ducks they copied from
Kinesis basically they just copied it
without you know the bow shaped thing
you know they just copied it and it's
created by this guy
Dominick Booker Dom Dominic Beauchamp
okay and Nestor ideas basically they
just copied Kinesis and Canisius copied
from mantra okay this is motrin this is
the earliest from 1977 okay so so
oviducts just copied Kinesis however
they did not copy
you know the bowl shaped curve you know
they just made it into a flat and then
but you got you know when you copy
things like that from curved to flat you
you cannot copy exactly because they are
not exactly the same thing you have a
flat surface here so there's a question
of you know how much to the left or to
the right are the thumb clusters you
have to make a choice I mean even a
little bit distance you know like half a
centimeter it matters you know because
it actually matters you know
slight difference in position matters so
they have to make a choice and the
choice they made is rather a lot people
complain that the thumb clusters are too
far out so you have to you know move
your thumb a lot to press for example
the middle thumb key that's why that is
why for many of the other subsequent do
do-it-yourself keyboards such as diverge
such as redox such as ago - such as iris
and so on they all fixed the thumb key
you see you can't live for example let's
look look at look at the Google Docs you
see the thumb key is below is to the is
below the N key in to the left lower
corner of n now let's look at the other
one so okay so hold on a second yeah so
look at the diverge redox ago - iris
okay now
so let's look so diverge you see they
are not to the they are not directly
below the lower left corner of n in fact
they are they are directly they are kind
of below the middle of in you see that's
the verge now let's look at the redox
Redux is even closer it's between N and
M you know kind of you have this key
between a nm all these keys can be
reprogrammed you know again you can have
them to be whatever you want so let's
look at but we are focusing on the
physical layout you know the physical so
let's look at ago - oh go - ok so again
it's Omo it's below the right lower
corner of n you see right lower corner
of in now let's look at
iris keyboard now this wins between and
and em I mean they even have a key to
the right of him okay and then and
that's to get okay that's it so you see
all these different designs so and but
how do you know how do you know that the
oviducts film cluster is got a problem
I mean who says okay that there are many
complaints if you go if you dive into
the keyboard do it yourself community
for example test Authority calm and you
know just such a search for a test they
spared desk Thoreau t-dot-com okay let's
see for example death Authority yeah
that's one of the keyboard nerds this is
the mecca of keyboard nerds extreme
nerds you know they they they build
keyboards and so on there's also there's
another website hack hack something
keyboard hack wait is it keyboard hab
does anyone remember yeah I'm pretty
sure you guys know that what's the
website
yeah it's hack something okay who knows
that the the keyboard website hack
something anyway there's another one is
reddit reddit are slash mechanical
keyboards okay those are the keyboard
places people gather so let me read the
comments israel says do-it-yourself
keyboards are so expensive though i've
got different cheap mechanical keyboards
for 30 USD and it's gray 30 USD 30 well
you are talking about a flat pc IBM pc
style keyboard yeah you can get for $30
that's made from china china
is very cheap as Femina so what are you
guys talking about okay if you have a
key question for me put my name to it
okay so it's it becomes orange so I can
focus on that so anyway this is what we
talking
yeah we're talking about the the ogre
docks thump problems so on these hackers
you know keyboard fanatics websites they
talk about that a lot there is not much
you know quite a few articles it's a
well-known kind of well known problem so
if your hand is big then it's good okay
but if your hand if you are Asian or if
you are female you know you know then
the Google Docs thumb keys may be too
far and this is actually critical
because there is someone let's see I
have a written somewhere here Missy oh
go ducks thump key pain okay this guy he
is a phonetics
he's a phonetic of old ago ducks
keyboard you know he advocate her go
ducks all the time you know telling
people to buy it and he owned several
but one day he sees got thump pain you
know he can he don't know why he got
thump pin you know there's some pain
then he thought because of the tenting
you know oviducts keyboard can have ten
teen a graze raise the middle part and
maybe he thought he said he removed the
tenting the same sped up but that the
campaign came back eventually he found
out it's a thumb key problem thumb key
you see it's a thumb key so this is the
oboe Docs original this one is modified
you see the thumb key now is right below
the middle of in so anyway he he wrote
this long
our code tells you his story about this
problem so he discovered pen then after
that he ditched he he sold oh his abode
ox he he went back to he oh the other
the other keyboard website is geek hack
okay this website dick hack and this is
the guy but I read now he's a very
popular guy among the keyboard
do-it-yourself communities so he wrote
he you know he wrote his tail so he you
know since he found out about this paint
problem he stopped using any organ ox
instead he bought this I can tell you
which one he went to the this very
expensive classic mechanical keyboard
which is called leopold d about this one
is made from korea he went to his
keyboard which is a very bad choice in
my opinion you know but you know anyway
so let me copy copy the things i want to
talk about and paste it here oh good oka
dogs keyboard problem so paste that here
go back go back
oh go dogs keyboard pen paste it here
remove that remove remove remove okay so
we talked about a godox keyboard pin so
there is that now let me explain the
next thing I want to explain if you have
comments or questions for me type it now
okay now the next topic topic is is
weight before
wait let me talk about this so this is
my desktop and Sasuke say sorry about
digression about new
England versus California it was all in
good fun
where is the digression I missed the
digression so England versus California
so which is so which is better
New England so Bartholomew says a
society has mentioned sometimes some
streams ago it depends a lot on how you
actually type if you type more than one
hour there you should invest into a
economic solution yeah so in the past
few days I had videos that talks about
keyboards so Israel you might check
check it out
you use emacs you use my go s yes that
new part looks very much like what I got
no it's very different from what you got
my friend Israel I I know because the
Leo part okay let me talk let me tell
you what is this video part of the
aboard about now in the keyboard nerds
community they love mechanical keyboards
right now mechanical keyboard has become
very popular in the past since about
2003 it becomes very popular especially
in the gaming community everyone is like
oh you need a mechanical keyboard you
know but before 2003 it's popular among
the keyboard fanatics keyboard nerds
community now among these keyboard nerds
people they are few you know the
so-called the best keyboard that stands
out just like just like among
programmers you have them and Emacs in
every every time you talk about
something then it becomes Emacs versus V
okay so in a keyboard community before
the mechanical keyboard became popular
they are a few there are a few keyboards
I considered you know the best and very
expensive
now Leo port is one of the
it's sales for like $250 it's like I
don't think history sells for 300 wait
why is this 120 away that that's a
different model okay
this model is completely different
that's why it's much cheaper what do you
want
what what's considered the best man you
know this extreme hackers is this one
Leopold FC 6 6 0 C okay
$300 in my opinion don't buy it okay
it's not good I mean you have to
consider the price I mean if you
consider everything everything but we've
divided by the price then this one is
not worth it you know $300 it's not
worth it today you can buy a mechanical
keyboard made from China like is Israel
you know that's $30 $40 and it's good
it's you know just very much the same
you know to me what I say it's the same
but not to these these these these
keyboard nerds you know they they are
very particular so anyway do part
Leopold FC 6 6 0 C is one of the you
know best keyboard considered the best
buy these notes not not to me okay $300
so that's one of them
and there are a few of them let me tell
you what are the the ones okay the
classic best keyboards they are let me
tell you now remember that we are
talking about before 2013 you know the
you know old times today is it's a bit
more different because today you have
you have tons of ergonomic ones and
other ones and also cheap ones so the
classic ones this is one of them
actually not this one the classic is the
IBM model M okay that is a classic I got
a lot of things to talk about so
actually
so let's see if I there's any questions
so Israel says California is an awful
place awful awful place hell on earth
well I'm supposing you mean the current
political situation then yes
anyway let's let me talk about keyboard
I sent you a picture once oh yeah I
think you did I want a mechanical
keyboard without arrow keys but with
number pad that's what a strange choice
a mechanical keyboard without arrow keys
but with number keypad what why why you
want one without arrow keys that's one
of the very strange okay people anyway
so IBM model M is one of the is this is
the the grandfather of all mechanical
keyboards this is among the keyboard
phonetics considered number one classic
okay it's got it's got this so-called
buckling spring key switch mechanism it
works like that there's a spring you
press it down then the spring cannot
hold it straight any longer than puh
you know it combos claps pocos that's
why you say it you call it buckling
spring so it's got this spoken in swing
key mechanism this is the classic the
granddaddy of them all now of course IBM
don't make this keyboard anymore but
they sold their patent to this guy
this guy used to work for IBM you know
the keyboard manufacturer the factory so
anyway he bought he bought the patent
and he created a company called Unicom
so that this is where you can buy today
for like $90 okay now if you guys like
my website buy for my website okay let
me let me just mention it so anyway you
can buy our Amazon
it's $99 okay so this is so let me let
me post my website so so you guys can
buy this is marketing this is
commercialization this this is monitors
monetization okay
this today's jargon you have
gamification in monetization in this
crap so IBM model M that's the classic
okay wait I don't want missed it okay
IBM auto-aim that's a classic and today
you can buy a Unicom but what are the
other classic so let me tell you okay I
be a model M then the other classic of
all times is this is this happy hacking
keyboard
this is $350 okay and in my opinion is
garbage I would not buy it for $100 in
my opinion it's garbage okay so make a
link okay so this this happy hacking
keyboard
it's made from Japan and the one of the
reason it's it's reason it's popular for
a few reasons one of the fundamental
reason is because it uses a this
keyboard switch mechanism it's called
taupe or taupe taupe free or topper key
switch mechanism what in Toby's table is
a transliteration from Japanese there's
a company it's it the this Japanese
company who makes these keyboards which
is called tofu okay but in English the
mechanism is called is basically is
called capacitor capacitance switch
anyway it works like that capacitance
switch okay
basically it's a combination of
capacitance capacitance is the
electronic switch but the the actual key
feel is let me show you this video
okay credit quite a few interesting
things to talk about this keyboard let
me show you a video where I don't know
hold on second so let me go to this is
the idiocy of having happy hacking
keyboard okay so let's go to Chrome open
a new window paste it now the video is
not showing in Firefox because if you
know some video format does not show in
Firefox but it shows in Chrome so next
page next page next page next page next
page next page next page next page where
is my video okay the video is in
keyboard mechanism okay let's search for
mechanism the video is in okay guide to
keyboard mechanism keyboard switch
mechanism page okay it's loading
shoes keyboard mechanism page okay so go
down go down go down go down this page
explains all the keyboard mechanisms out
there like an introduction so there we
have it
tofu toppers switch electrostatic
capacitive switch okay so that is he
happy hacking keyboard now here's a
video so this is what a happy hacking
kibo looks like without you know there
you go so you see the key feel is
actually rubber dome why is this not
continuous I need to modify it okay so
there it is that's the keyboard
mechanism so let me let me let me type
it here Pinkie Pie and go through the
page search for top free switch okay and
I need to modify so this is mp4 I need
to make it loop okay so do it again okay
so cut this out okay now refresh now
your loop typically they should I want
them to do so there is okay wait okay
it's on my website I need to okay go to
I Shou sync to my web server okay anyway
that's about happy hacking so now i
refresh now your loop so that's about
happy hack hacking keyboard it's it's
famous partly because because of the
tapas switch and it's famous because
it's associated with hackers you know
it's it's it's got the word hacking in
it and it does not have the windows key
so you know it tickles the brain of the
UNIX philosophy the you
type of people you know these hacker
type of community people so that's why
that's why the the this these two are
the main reason it's popular you know
it's a very popular among hackers so
back to our topic
so I was saying I was saying the classic
keyboards that hackers love includes
includes okay keywords which crows talk
show IBM auto-aim
okay and happy hacking and okay there's
another one let me talk about that let
me show you oh these are very expensive
they are like $250 $300 so and another
one is Rio force okay
Rio force is another one very expensive
actually not real force is one of them
and real force okay
and there is another one called
here it's made by this company called
vehicle this company co co now when we
are talking about the classic you know
best keyboard vehicle so for example
this one oh is hundred twelve hundred
twenty dollars they become much cheaper
now it used to be like two hundred
dollars so now finally their price comes
down because you cannot compete because
now you can buy almost the same one you
know made me in China for $60
so the here's another $170 these flat
keyboards okay so so you know Co Co is
one of them
Co Co is again a company in Japan and
the the key switch of vehicle keyboard
is usually topo same thing with the same
thing that's using heck happy hacking
and by the way I don't like the tope
tope a switch at all I don't like them
okay so okay let me read the comments so
how long we've been talking so we've
been talking for 44 minutes okay so
you know it's very strange that Google
is censoring these words it's like
impossible I mean it says you know
Israel says bathroom you and I will
happily accept one if you want to send
one the shipping will be very expensive
that's from Germany to Israel so and
here's another comment Israel says I see
it not regular mechanical keys my has
some Chinese blue switches I have
another one with brown switches
I like brown switches better but has
stupid short light shipped ok show so
I'm gonna read the comments answer
questions
California offer phase
picture ones as in mechanical keyboards
then you should definitely high quality
so Bartholomew Oh bother me Bartholomew
is making a do-it-yourself keyboard last
time he says so Israel says I have weak
sting yes weak sting is one of the
Chinese brand you know they changed the
brand name all the time it was used to
be called it's used to be called
something else you know they do change
them brand name basically what happens
is that they I think they have in China
they have many keyboard manufacturers
you know they just check out keyboards
then if you are company you can buy it
put your name on it you know then you
sell so so you know they change the
brand name all the time how they were
once
no need arrow keys no you need arrow
keys I mean well depending on your I
mean each person is different so in your
workflow maybe you don't find arrow keys
useful in my workflow I mean I consider
arrow keys physical arrow keys essential
essential well know where a long time
ago 20 years our computer no arrow keys
but number pad had school mod well yeah
I wonder if happy happy keyboard was
always 300 yes happy had happy hacking
kibo was always $300 actually more than
that
it was like 300 or 350 it's it's no good
okay it's totally not worth it I mean
the reason it's so expensive is because
it's kind of like demand you know demand
demand and supply and also because you
know it has it has a hacking status you
know here's the thing about psychology
pricing you know there is a story told
in one of the books you know there's a
one of a psychology book very classic
let me show you
I did not actually find the book it's
somewhere there but I found another one
this is also interesting so this book is
intimate behavior this is intimate
behavior it's by this guy Desmond Morris
it's very dusty you know my books so
that's interesting guy so let me let me
tell you something about that such Fork
sorry intimate behavior that book is
about human sexuality human sexuality
with respect to from a zoologist point
of view so you know we humans we observe
animals like we study Tigers we study
lions we study you know alligator or
deers or cows we study their behavior
their mating you know every you know
things like that so so that's what this
guy Desmond Morris his job you know
that's his profession he's a professor
he's a zoologist anthropologist you know
but now you take that point of view and
point it to human animals so you study
human just like you observe Lions you
know their life you know you know their
sexuality their mating behavior so
that's what this book is about intimate
behavior okay so I think it's a
fantastic book you know this kind of
thing usually people do not like to talk
about because you know it's touchy
you know it's talk about how male-female
how they get together you know but it's
a it's a it's something that happens
every day in real life mating behavior
how do you start to you know
how did you know people get married you
know but how do you how do you meet your
wife or your husband Oh your partner
okay you know if first of all you have
you must have eye contact you know you
met her you know let's say her you know
some way you know partying a meeting or
whatever it work face you must first of
all you must there must be some eye
contact the first time then you started
to you know they they in progress
progresses then you hold hands then you
know maybe you have sex or something or
maybe not then you get married you know
so you study that you know the the
behavior the you know so that's this
what this book is about okay that's that
book we digressed but there is another
book psychology book very famous it's
somewhere here I must have it somewhere
here influence
book
there this is a book I have a this is a
classic book by a psychologist
okay so influence the psychology of
persuasion now in this book where are we
talking about this book because in this
book I believe it's this book okay
they I learned that they there is this
psychological issue about pricing for
example I sell my Emacs tutorial right
how much should it be you know right now
I sell it for $30 as sometimes in the
past it's like $5 or $10 and for I think
you know I mean there is a story so if I
want to sell you let's just let's say a
pain you know so let's say the
reasonable price is $1 but I can make it
let's say $50 and people will buy it you
know some people will buy it because
with because no money when you look at
things we church things quality the
value you know by its price if something
is 1000 let's say keyboard we would we
are talking about keyboard you know if
some keyboard is $100 then you see
another keyboard that's $300 although
they look similar but you will naturally
believe that $300 is the better one you
will just simply believe that because
because because that's the feedback you
know that's the market you know that's
the because in general more expensive
are better you know that's just in
general so you will naturally believe
this is something that's the three
hundred dollar keyboard is higher
quality everything you know every aspect
should be better so that's the
psychology of it so there are some so so
let's let's go back to the keyboard you
know we were talking about why is this
happy hacking keyboard expensive now
where is it this one no not this one
happy hacking the idiocy of happy
hacking keyboard this one so why is it
expensive you know they need to keep it
they need to keep that 300 above $300
they need to keep these spies because
the moment mean you know be today you
have a lot mechanical keyboards that's
you know $50 this is not what $300 so
350 at all let's see how much they
charge yeah 250 okay 300 this one is 321
this is a silent version yeah this
supposed to be silent he actually is not
that much silent anyway so you see so
there's a question to them this company
happy hacking company should we lower
the price because today you a lot
keyboards out there you know even you
know even you know my keyboard
you know the Kinesis this one is only
$340 so should they lower the price you
see but the but they they did not okay
they did not lower it much you know they
they are CEO 250 or 300 that's the thing
because they need to keep you know the
the price becomes their asset you know
because they they are sending out a
signal saying that look yeah it is true
you can buy a lot cheaper ones but we
are the best you know we have to always
being the best you know so they do not
lower the price that's the thing you
know that's that that is the thing
actually they are you know these not
worth you know it's not worth 300 at all
you know because if you because for
example if you go down my page if you
want the tapas which they are there are
I have a list of keyboards that's tapas
which and they are just 150 so like
hundred dollars cheaper for example if
you
here search for Tova okay I'm getting
tired and I'm getting tired and kind of
anyways so here you have a list of
keywords that's all using the toggle
switch so if you if if Tobi's switch is
what we really like then you can buy
this one for $110 something like that or
you can buy this one this one is not no
longer made I don't think so or you can
buy y'all do port you know that's
another one or table you know this one
$150 something like that
so you know so it is there's no reason
to buy to buy the happy hacking at all
but they need they want to keep the
price up because once they lower the
price then it's like they are gone you
know no you know happy hacking the the
famous the fame heavy hacking will be
good because nobody will consider they
are special in any way anymore like
right now they are not special at all
they are not special at all the the only
reason they are special now is because
they are you know for the past twenty
years they are you know the company that
makes the keyboard so I need to get a
drink so let me read the comment
comments so green deck says you had a
topic save at the start of the stream
yes I do and it's all about keyboard oh
basically I want to talk about tenting
so let's talk about that for a bit
tenting tenting is important okay and
the other thing I want to talk about is
it's just just yeah about my keyboard
Kinesis and also key log this killer key
log like how many keys you type a day is
critically important now we've been
talking for how long I'm kind of get
hungry and tired so
so let me talk about that topic and talk
about an answer the comments and that
should be it for today so okay
today's juice is tomato juice tomato one
dollar a bottle from Dollar Tree good
morning Louise so we were talking about
Cibo today and we are about done and
[Music]
here is to health this is cheap nameless
energy drink sugar-free okay
tomato energy indeed moaning dingo so we
talked about we're gonna talk about
another another 10 minutes of 5 or 10
minutes and that'll be it for today so
what is is closed oh we are we only
talked for one hour so we have you know
in the past week I've been doing 90
minutes per video it's getting longer
and longer it should be that's not good
you know one hour is good enough brands
which are nice that's not a bad idea I
mean the so
[Music]
so Israel says why are they always
holding my comments for review I'm
guessing that Google decided you are
controversial
so did Scott say something I want to
answer Scott's questions it is any
anything Scott says I want to answer so
Scott says Scott Scott is a I forgot C
program a'right C or C++
Scott Scott is designing Scott is a
expert in in optimizing GPU optimizing
chip design GPU design and image maps
how they call that image Maps textures
yeah something about that so Scott says
it's well into lunchtime here in the
East Coast color go Oh Scotty gun
Scotty is think back okay yeah texture
texture maps right yeah lunch time we
are about we are about done as well five
minutes or yeah five minutes or so so
comments okay gonna go by Israel don't
say any of those things is my okay so
one more topic then we are done five
minutes okay so yeah so one more few
more you know one more thing about
keyboards is that
so this is my keyboard and key logs
okay you want you what you want to lock
your keys so you know how much you
actually type you know if you don't I
mean for most of you I guess most of you
all these fancy keyboard doesn't really
matter because you don't really type
that much I mean even if you work in our
company I mean yeah for most programmers
working a company you know the actual
amount of time you type is you know like
you have to go to the meetings you have
go to you know lunch you have to go to
you know in company you you talk to
people and you know you don't actually
spend time you know just typing all the
time I mean and and when you are
programming most of the time you have to
read the code you know understand the
code so so the first thing you really
want to know is how much you actually
type like use a keylock okay I have so
many articles about that
how many key strokes program last type
of day so this article talks about that
in detail and I give you a detailed
account of how much I actually type I
have a log of that so here is my Emacs
log this is two years worth of vlog in
Emacs now mostly are typing Emacs so so
the Emacs vlog is good enough for me
because ninety 98% of time I'm typing in
Emacs so so I have this keylogging Emacs
and that that mod is called
you know just go to my website you'll
find all the links because I have too
many things to give up you'll find the
package ok this Emacs package called let
me show you ok I showed this many times
so he frequents show okay right now I'm
knocking my keys so you can see I call
self insert this many times and I kept
called previous line this many times and
next line this many times that's my key
rock now how how long was this
Kirra a tequila back for how many months
I don't know I forgot but anyway in this
one it's two years worth
so self-insert I called self-insert 3.8
million times so compared to here okay
so this is only 700,000 so anyway I have
two years worth of Kedar q and you know
assuming if we if if we assume I type
only 50 words per minute I mean normally
if I like you don't want to assume - I
mean you don't want to assume too much
suppose you assumed 50 words per minute
which is kind of normal then assume I
type every day including weekends then
my typing load is equivalent equivalent
to continuously typing for one hour a
day you see this is how you get a sense
of how much you actually type you know
first of all you lock your keys then you
can't how many keystrokes you know you
can't total how many keystrokes
a day you average it out then then what
you assume you know 50 words per minute
then you can find out how you know like
go free if you type continuously then
then how many minutes of that of you
actually type a day I'm getting tired
and hungry so I'm starting to not so -
focused it's getting bad SEO got 15
people watching so anyway so that's
that's about logging your keyboard
that's important okay so like people
like because every every people every
time you go to Amazon every every time
programmers talk about keyboard they say
oh I type all day
therefore you should
so that that's all okay first
of all yeah how much you type how much
you actually type is your all day you
know everyone types all day every
programmer types all day but actually if
you are a programmer chances are you
know it's it's if you are programmer
chances are you you type no longer than
20 minutes a day I'd you know for vast
majority of programmers if you
continuously type 50 words per minute
it's less than 20 minutes so for me it's
about an hour I know for you know for me
some hour that doesn't look much but but
I know I type a lot more than most
programmers you know like so so you want
go you know when it comes to key binding
and keyboard stuff you want to go
scientifically so lock your keys not
your keys so I have a list of keylogging
software here you can see not your keys
then you can you know what you're
talking about
you know you how much you actually type
so so once you know how much you
actually type then you can decide
whether you know you need keyboard
something like this you know like for
vast majority of people you don't need
you know this is overkill you have to
take you know a month to learn it right
so the fat PC keyboard may be good for
you
but for some people I mean it doesn't
matter if you whether you lock your key
or not you you know you have hand
problems like you type too much in that
case you also you know want to consider
keyboard like like this okay that is
about the what this that's about that
page I want to talk about that key
logging and close that and the last
thing I want to talk about is tenting
now now tenting basically means the
keyboard with the middle of you know
that is actually a more natural hand
position the natural hand position is
something like that you know
not like that this for typical keyboard
flat it's like you put your hand like
that it's no good you you want this
isn't more this is natural you want
something a bit you know
slanted that's called tented yeah I'm
not sure why they call it tent but I
suppose it's because right it's like a
tent you know it's like camping tent so
you do want these again again it
comebacks - depends on how much you
actually type you know for a lot of
people especially programmers if you are
maybe some other many a manager position
then you know you don't really type that
date that much so you may not need it
but anyway this is important why because
I know I know for firsthand because I
was using this keyboard I was using this
truly economic keyboard beginning in
2013 to 2017 oh no - I stopped I used
this keyboard for like two - two or
three years that's when you know during
that time I was typing a lot and I know
so this keyboard is very ergonomic
but however there's one aspect it's
missing its flat it's not tainted but
back then you know I thought oh 10 is
not too important you know it's not
really too important as long as you have
you know mechanical keys and you know
they are you have separate groups for
right hand and left hand that's good
enough I was wrong again it depends on
how much you type but back then I was
typing a lot why how do I know I was
wrong because I realized you know I
started to feel
I forgot was a tingling somewhere here
or I forgot what's a symptom I have read
written down somewhere on my on my
keyboard pages so I was using this
keyboard for three years and I noticed
that this this problem tingling I think
it's a tingling of the arms here and
eventually I realized it's because of
the 10th
because well how do I know because
because when when I trace my hand like
that I feel comfort like if i trace it
all the way I feel like release relief
I feel comfort that's when I know you
know I know that you are you know
putting your hand like that too much so
that basically that's about the time I
switch to the my current keyboard the
Kinesis okay guys no comments anything
else that's about it then so you I give
it the sold it's in in one minute we're
gonna close down if you have any
questions comments posted okay then
we're gonna shut down any anything about
keyboards type it okay
type it typing guys tab it type and say
goodbye so if you like my stuff you know
go through my website just such sorry
keyboard and and you find all these they
are about like 250 Holocaust or about
keyboards if you like it by its Watney
Oh support me from patreon Amazon gift
card PayPal
or the links are there dingo says what
do you think of the 40% keyboard okay
that's the last topic 40% keyboard I
think they are okay
that's my true the most honest opinion I
think they are don't use it it I
mean well again it depends on the person
okay if you like it if you like it that
probably means you don't really actually
you don't type that much 40% let me tell
you about 40% keyboards so they are a
lot of them especially like for example
this one they don't have the arrow keys
this is actually 60% it's got this one's
got 61 keys okay 40% is even less keys
40% is like about 40 keys 45 something
like that it's not good 60% is not good
either you you want if you want compact
if you like compact keyboard keyboard at
least get one that has arrow keys okay
for example this one yeah this one got
arrow keys and this get arrow keys okay
arrow keys and page up page down that's
good and you know and and today there is
a fashion of you know getting smaller
even even with the ergonomic ones let me
show you for example many of these they
don't have many keys this one 50 40s
that's not enough a standard IBM PC
keyboard has about 105 keys okay
you know so so the IRS got 54 keys no
good fortitude 60 keys not enough when
you have keys if you like a keyboard you
know such as these this one Scott 768
keys it's not enough when you so if you
like a keyboard like that you want to
get you want to buy a programmable
keypad ok I mentioned this a few times
you want to buy a programmable keypad so
anyway there is a fashion of going with
less and less keys for example this the
verge TM 246 keys is idiotic okay it's
it's extremely idiotic and this mitosis
48 keys okay the granddaddy of the of
them is this one Atreus 42 keys please
this one is actually more extreme 42
piece means that you cannot they don't
have even keys for numbers whenever you
need to press a number key number like 1
2 3 you have to hold down a modifier you
know it's extreme idiotic and it's the
fastest way to get repetitive repetitive
strain injury also with this 40 percent
keys
you cannot type Chinese you cannot type
Russian you cannot type you know some
other languages Oh chopper Japanese no
Chinese no Japanese no Russian idiot I
don't know what what the people you know
design is keyboard like that 40 percent
you know is it it has a kind of it's
like a hack it becomes it's somewhat
fashionable you know like a lot of
people love it on these nerd keyboard
nerd
forums this is like again is smaller and
smaller you know these people
so typically typically ok I can tell
right away typically they are English
speakers they don't they don't type
another language okay they just English
and also yeah and so they never you know
they never thought of of typing Russian
or Chinese or even math like in math
anyway so so even so you see even number
keys you have to hold down a modifier
and then with these 42 keys when you
want a punctuation such as question mark
you cannot type that you have to hold
down a modifier you know so it's
extremely it's a pain yes basically it's
you know the this this one is original
142 keys but some people have made
alternative versions
this version is 58 keys this version is
62 keys this version this one is a kind
of a completely different keyboard but
similar in design succeed two keys so
anyway so that's Atreus you can you can
buy the kit from this guy
techno Mansi so yeah I don't recommend
40% keyboard at all we do okay so what
what about the advantage of reducing the
distance to the mouse no that's that you
see that's not about 60% keyboard at all
for example this one I use you see my
mouse there's no distance you see
there's no no no distance between I mean
this close as possible this is you know
this traditionally this is the Enter key
so it's like it's also close as possible
there's no distance you don't need so
you know what I'm saying is that you
don't need 40% keyboard for that for
example this one or or this one or even
this one you know you don't you see this
one you don't need 40% keyboard for that
and this one is very good okay I
recommend this one for Everage people
you guys are there and you see all these
basically all these you don't you don't
need 40% of keyboard for that except
except those who's got number pad but
even I mean some keyboard compact you
know they I mean you get the idea right
you get what I'm saying I'm getting
tired so for example this one compact
you got arrow keys
this one also works you know this you
know it's not too much distance the only
problem is when you have a big number
pad then that's a problem okay thank you
guys for watching for today so thank you
bye my stuff patreon me and stuff I'll
see you guys next time