good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh
today's 2020 January first in the year
of our Lord 2020 Wednesday 4 o'clock
p.m. San Francisco time hello oh and we
got quite a few things to talk about and
let's start saw start command log mod so
you can see all my Emacs commands on the
left window and let's go to talk show so
this is today's top sheet optics and
let's set background color
emily's color feasel ok and let's make
this correct size things needs to be
correct
and Papa so the correct size is
something like that and so we are we
have a lot to talk about
I'm going to talk I'm going to tell you
about good morning
Kathy great to see you again Thank You
Kathy for the money thank you Thank You
Kathy
and good morning Emily and Nabi and
Justine's classified Justine's
classified a great mathematician ok and
I'm going to introduce you guys to
Justine's
scarf I so today's topics I'm going to
tell you the how how did the massive
evil rise the rise of the evil empire
okay how how did massive evil rise and
I'm gonna talk about and I'm gonna do a
lot a max workflow that is I'm gonna use
my Emacs to walk on my website I'm going
to show you the commands in live coding
and stuff so that's one thing the rise
of Evo and the Emacs workflow and I'm
gonna tell you about some movies ok
movies and musicals and ok and today
it's going to be more than one
our so good morning Justine scarfie good
morning Dan Morris ok so let me tell you
guys about Justine Justine who is a
disabled person mathematician disabled
and Chinese heat from China hey Justine
so if you have any new info just type in
a chat okay so in case our discord if
you have not already joining ok we have
all the weird people and the fringe ok
fringe of a society kind of weird ok
most of most of you guys all the weird
and those of you failed and or disabled
in one way or another
okay so Justine so let me show you let
me tell you guys let me introduce Justin
okay Justin if I if I if I didn't do any
justice correct me OK Justin's cos Phi
so he so he's from China and he's a
mathematician and he has disabilities
okay and so let me show you some of the
let me tell you the story and he won a
canadian math competition canadian
mathematical society or something you
know those competition are very hard
extremely hard so he he he got a perfect
score when he was young he was born with
a some sort of a heart disease okay so
anyway so for a year also he cannot
speak you know he can just bring his
eyes like Stephan Hawking you know the
guy the famous physicist what's his
name's Stephen Hawking let me find that
hold on a second let me find the post
okay
so I'm gonna find a post just give me a
second okay so just team is one great
mathematician you know he is in the okay
so let's go here jump - good morning
Vokoun okay so introducing just just in
scarf I and Adam Bundy okay so there's a
lot to talk about okay so let me get the
mid rid of these this side panel here
okay first of all let me show you this
so how have you guys been going yo-yo
Vulcan Vulcan Vulcan is a FreeBSD
phonetic a free vspeed FreeBSD expert
and he's you know coding B FreeBSD and
contributing code every day like he's
telling us he contributed you know he's
contributed to the FreeBSD offering
assistance he's posting the stuff which
I don't understand so wait let me get
this one thing at a time okay let me
talk about justing where is just change
stuff
okay hold on second discord
you have so much stuff it's hard to find
so if you have not already joined this
code okay
sorry this code you can find the link on
my website on my YouTube and bunch of
other place
okay here so first of all let me show
you so this photo so this is Justin with
his adviser so justin is recurrently
a research mathematician so here here is
the photo you know Stefan what's this
guy's name is Stephan Hawking right so
he's on wheelchair and so is Justin on
wheelchair and right now justin is a
mathematician research mathematician at
British Columbia University and seems
also Oxford University okay so I'm
honored to know adjusting you know I'm
no mathematician so and Justin's is
researching his specialty is number
theory okay an analytic number theory
and so you can see his his room he spoke
so these aha
you know I know what those books are oh
these are math books like graduate level
math books you see those yellow covers
those are published by by
springer-verlag okay so so do we have a
high-resolution photo in the early days
okay so it's not high resolution and so
anyway that's just in home or office
something like that and okay so Justine
are you still here like say something
say hi to you know people say hi so
anyway so so what what else anything
else just seeing anything else
interesting Oh Alan Bundy so Alan Bundy
apparently is one of Justine's advice
something Adam Bundy's mathematician in
United Kingdom UK
so Alan Bondi is a professor at the
School of Informatics at University of
Aunt edinburgh known for it known for
his contribution to automated reasoning
especially to prove planning the use of
meta-level reasoning to guide proves
research proved such so he is you know
so so there is you know homotopy type
theory which is a buzz buzz word among
you know among like among programmers
you might have heard of that and it's
basically doing proofs by computer so
Alan birdie Bundy is one of the leader
and let's say or something
Oh pioneer want one of them okay so
that's that's about that I guess so you
can you know if you go to discord in
such for Justin you can find he's
karikalan vital something like that you
know his resume so for example here's a
photo he showed and this photo is
justing at clay mathematics Institute
now this is an Institute Institute that
has the Millennial math problems that is
seven problems and if you solve one of
them you get 1 million dollars so this
is Cray math Institute and just in
skaffa is either visiting lecturer or
something a member or something ok so
that's about I guess that's about Justin
and Justin has some questions like he
always you Nemeth ok you Nemeth is the
new foundation of mathematics you know
Justin he's a research mathematician so
he have talked to all the
you know many many of the top
mathematicians you know around the world
and the one of the thing I learned from
Justin told me is that he is starting to
do proof systems you know starting to
get into this unit valent mathematics
univille and mathematics is kind of is
it's basically homotopy type theory they
are related but anyway the proper name
is you know valid mathematics that's a
new foundation of math and this
foundation is amenable to doing math by
computer so the traditional foundation
of math based on set theory and
first-order logic you know they are
solid but they are not amenable to doing
math proofs by using computer it's hard
because the approach is incompatible so
there is this guy who created this
universe and mathematics so actually we
have a lot to talk about that math block
okay let me show you so we have this sky
vadoma watsky he died like two years ago
he created the universe and mathematics
the found a new approach a foundation of
math by the way if if you are a
programmer you know if you are Haskell
programming that you might have heard of
homotopy type theory category theory
they are all kind of related okay but
not the same okay so you know as I my
rent typical rent goes you know if you
are a Haskell program stop it stop your
Haskell [ __ ] okay you don't know nothing
about math you don't you know stop stop
learning categories theory okay it's a
[ __ ] so anyway so this is you know valid
mathematics and that's you know where
and you and it's also related to its
heavily heavily tied to [ __ ] the
language [ __ ]
see oh gee
it's called assistant proved system so
this is a programming language but it's
not exactly like a programming language
it's anyway so that you can learn this
I'm going I'm going to learn this I've
been wanting to learn is this for a long
time
okay Justine Justine Justine scarf where
are you say some things it's just in
scarf I okay so that's about just ending
that that's that's it yeah so vadoma
modo ski he created his theory you know
which I plan to learn in the next five
years so that is about that okay and
Justin Justin always asked a bunch of
kind of strange questions like very
general questions I don't know what what
is what is the issue like okay so
Justine says Donald Knuth does next
interview okay um yeah I don't know I
don't like that guy okay so I have a
YouTube watcher whose name is I forgot a
moment but anyway he he was you know he
introduced me to this guy next Friedman
okay animation let me show you this guy
next Friedman you you might know because
he do a lot of YouTube videos he is
somewhat popular if you are interested
in artificial intelligence so I've
applied this is the guy
hold on a second YouTube is slowly
so this guy Lex Friedman
he's a YouTube he's a AI researcher he's
well known you can find a Wikipedia
article about him next Friedman this guy
so he's doing YouTube now almost every
two days or so he's got a new video and
the video content is usually
interviewing other artificial
intelligence related celebrities for
example you you go to his channel you
can see he interviewed Ella mask he
interviewed this Michi Kaku is famous
for the physicist you know you know I
don't like this celebrity type of guy I
like Ellen mask but this michio kaku I
you know he is popular physicist
okay so Lex Friedman interview
many of these people Eric Winston Jim
Gates I don't know who's Jim Gates he
and he interviewed donald knuth so he
interviewed many the celebrities
mathematicians or programmers or you
know famous programmers physicists or
those involved in artificial
intelligence and so I have watched by
now maybe five five or so of his videos
Lex Friedman I don't like that guy okay
I don't like this Lex treatment guy
what's the reason yeah I just don't like
him he I don't like his interviews what
is the reason
the reason it's hard to pinpoint the
reason the reason seems to be he's kind
of he's doing these YouTube videos as a
show you know the kind you know like say
say my education or say my entertainment
and the target audience are you know
programmers or scientists in artificial
intelligence research but I just I don't
like he I just don't like
show so I'm going to stop watching him
you know I I subscribe to him but I
don't like his stuff but anyway so you
could watch you know so Elemis and many
celebrities has been interviewed on by
him so you can watch them but still I
just don't like the way he interviews
that's just personal personal opinion I
don't have nothing against him
yeah I just don't like I just don't
don't like his show that is all so
anyway that's Lex Friedman okay
and also he also interviewed Stefan
Wolfram so you know you go to his
channel you'll find actually that's not
an interview he introduced Stefan gufa
then Stefan Wolfe and talked to anyway
so that's about X treatment so it looks
like just in Scots of just in skaffa is
very found of this guy because Justine
scoff I has posted you know the the next
Friedman's video a few times okay so
that's about that so let's go to the
next topic so we actually we have so
many topics now we already talked for
how long 20 minutes ok never finish so
yeah so the the language is called [ __ ]
because [ __ ] is French it's from France
you know by France scientists in France
and you know the [ __ ] means I think it
means [ __ ] you know the the the the male
chicken the male foul that's what it
means in France in French so Kathy says
is first time I saw people owning and
probably finishing all the GMT books
graduate math something books what's GMT
so what time how long have I been
talking so see
14 people watching okay so I've been
talking about 20 minutes so let's see
Douglas Packard just came from your old
video on math foundation and homotopy
type theory great thank you
Logan says Logan says oh no I have a
feeling some may see the long
conversation between me and Susan yes
this morning something like that
maybe one us cookies is the secret
hidden there no I will see it I have I
have eyes over so you guys fringe fringe
of society that that's what we are
that's what I gather I collect I lead I
attract the fringes of society you know
I've been trying to tell you guys you
know I that's not what I want to be you
know you wanna you wanna do something
you want you want to do something that
you know get out of your [ __ ] hole
change society you know don't hide in
the underground things like that
interesting things are they in the
research papers okay so you are talking
about just in scoff I research papers
right so just suggesting scarf I has
posted his resume okay you know in for
other for programmers when you apply for
a job you send in your resume
that's a stupid word okay resume
basically it's a list of what you've
done you did represent yourself but in
academia for those you know in academia
professors or PhD students in academia
you don't you call that curriculum how
they call that VC okay V tau B tau
that's that's a Latin something like
that you know this pumper so these
[ __ ] pompous words academia n--'s
like including this the word resume
itself it's the [ __ ] idiotic word
okay so anyway I saw
so just so anyway just means calcify has
his resume and you can see his stuff
okay some somewhere in this link some
somewhere here here take some some time
to find it anyway so let's get on to the
next topic
let's investigate
boo Buckeye group okay I don't like the
public eye group neither [ __ ] boob
okay the good you know let me tell you
ladies okay I'm going I'm starting to
get on to a rant and today's rant is it
will not be the typical UNIX rent rent
again it's the UNIX [ __ ] but
mathematicians some of the stea stuff I
don't like and one of the things the
public eye group introduced is limitary
injection the [ __ ] injection a jargon
okay let me tell you let me tell you
about that injection you know you guys
you need you guys need to study math
okay because from what I know you guys
you know most of you guys are
programmers well that's what I do too
I'm not you know much of a mathematician
so so you guys don't know math but it's
the way when I talk to my my in my video
when I start to talk about math
basically it becomes like entertainment
purposes you listen then you forget you
know that's not what I want I want is
people you know we actually learned
something anyway Injection you okay so
injection
is it coding injection let me let me I
forgot okay so anyway math so you have
by ejection so in math you have one to
one function in on to function one to
one function okay and you have function
that's on to okay so that's two to kind
of characteristics of function not
characteristics but the classification
kind of so and then okay let me just
show you this ok
the Boubacar group introduced this
idiotic jargon Despicable jargon
non-intuitive and there it is injective
subjective subjective they are ass it is
introduced by the gubec I goof okay but
you guys probably don't know what I'm
talking about what what what is Pooh
Buckeye group you know Boubacar group is
a group of mathematicians space you you
know a group of anonymous mathematicians
in from 1920s to to today but most most
active they are famous basically around
let's say 1940s or something for 20
years 30 years so they introduced so
they they are a group of anonymous
mathematicians like six or ten of them
the membership comes ago comes and go so
okay so let me just be let me just tell
you okay P oh you are p-a-k-i okay I'm
actually not in the position to
criticize them because I'm not really
qualified you know because at best
I'm just graduate you know I have a
degree I don't have a degree in math but
what I know is basically undergraduate
so anyway this is Abubakar group okay
Nicholas Park I that's a that's a pain
name so this group of mathematicians
they are the best best mathematicians
okay they are you know the top
mathematicians and they so they they
they got they get together and use the
pen name and they wrote several volumes
of math and this mark this is the the
the force of their this is why they
become famous you know the public eye
nobody at for a period of time nobody
know who they are you know but however
they you just know that there are
several volumes of mathematics published
by written by Nicolas public eye okay
you don't know who what that is and this
and so this group of mathematicians were
these several volumes of these math
books and this these books they they are
go is that they want to capture the
entirety of modern mathematics in one
coherent set of books so you know so the
entire all we know about mathematics
they want to capture in these set of
books that is this is the reason why
boubakr become famous you know if you
are studying math you you know this okay
it's like Donald Knuth you know Donald
Ruth is known by every hackers every
programmer every day is like Oh Don oh
goodness don't agree with that you
cannot on underneath this that that [ __ ]
okay Donal goose I don't like a single
thing created by Donald Knuth the tech
crap garbage Tech and lock Tech a
pestilence in mathematicians and in
programming community every hacker types
the UNIX people you know the drivel
they'd Revo about tech and low tech
every day they don't even know what's
going on it they have no idea they just
oh the oh the you know why it's popular
because it's free open source is free
it's it's like drugs free cigarette guys
free cigarette that's why UNIX and the
tech and low tech becomes
very popular you know I have an article
on that and I talked about taking or
taking my previous videos so you can
check about that so anyway back to boo
Buckeye so he so this group you know
these mathematicians created this whole
set of math books that captures the
entirety modern of modern math they add
assess their core so it's huge it's a
huge walk you know it's a it's a you
know it's epic it's a you know it's a
opus you know so anyway so so in but
when they created these set of books
they have certain styles that they have
to follow certain approach you know to
so that the entire body of work is
coherent anyway that's an Internet that
that is my introduction to what is this
Nikolas public eye thing now if you if
you you know study Matthew you know this
okay it's know among or mathematicians
so that's public eye so but you see the
thing is you know just like programming
languages you have many different styles
approaches so the approach you know so
they pace their book on say theory you
know with Regas you know extremely good
say theory and and first-order logic so
it's it's great but also they introduced
some jargons okay they introduced some
dragons which you know is reasonable and
you know it's it it's almost even it's
necessary to but I you know one of the
jargon they introduced I happens to do
not like that is subjective subjective
function and injective function those
are idiotic names is created by this
group injective function so they call a
function one-to-one function like you
know one-to-one function they call it
injection
or injective function and and I'm to
function they call it subjective
function
idiotic makes it to the extreme now if
you are not you know method mathematics
you you should know you should know what
is one-to-one function okay and what is
the onto function if you don't know I'm
not going to explain it it's very easy
to understand okay but I know most of
you guys are programmers so you've
probably heard of it but not sure
exactly what it is but anyway this is if
you are you know studying math which I
do recommend you know stop stop your
programming stuff
stop stop stop your Haskell [ __ ] okay
stop you
let's go category theory fact stop it
right away this this study this thing
such a subjective function injective
function by each action this this are
you know more fundamental then then then
your category mu not fat [ __ ] so anyway
I'm not going to explained one-to-one
function because if I start to expand it
it's like basic basic math and and and
if you guys are not interested you know
it's like entertainment okay injection
by section pooh-bah high group okay so
that's about that
so I actually we I talked about a lot
you know I have lots of topics to go
through but I don't think we can finish
today we barely begin we'd even I didn't
even begin oh I did it was introduction
of Justine scarf I scarf scarf I okay we
didn't even begin
[Laughter]
okay so you like the other programming
in volume 1 I don't like the auto
programming
I don't like a single thing done by
Donald Knuth injection okay so a a is
explaining injection so let me show it
I'm not going to read it though because
they'll take too much time for me and
also I am Not sure it's correct I hope
you wrote it correctly okay so you know
I don't know what's your guy's
background so you know I'm just doing my
talkshow so if I'm incorrect about you
you know I'm not talking you know so
anyway so I like the art of computer
programming volume okay poor to Rao says
there is a lot ik pay based Emacs Kathy
says probability and say theory seems to
be an easier entry point than bubucaca
in reasoning well the it's not an you
see the boo ba Chi books they are not
entry points they have nothing about
entry points they are for professional
mathematicians you know like like you
have you are you know you you have a PhD
that's not enough you know typically
once you have a PhD then you do postdoc
like you spend 3 2 3 4 years wandering
around postdoc to research work then
possibly you become assistant professor
typically that's the way you know that's
a step then then a system professor or
lecturer then you become professor like
vo professor you know there's a rank
just like in military so anyway so the
public eye books they are not
introduction engines are not intro they
are there they are like they are for the
humanity there for the you know they are
permanent walk they
they capture the entirety of modern
mathematics in one coherent set so
that's the goal so it's not about
introduction to math or something like
that at all so so it's fall it's like
it's almost like in cyclo encyclopedia
but it's in a sequential way so anyway
it's a monumental walk in math so it's
not about a specific topic
you know per se for example it's not
about oh you know they approached you
about probability I don't even I don't
think they cover probability I don't I
don't know I I haven't read I haven't
even seen the book okay so I'm just
giving you a layman's layman's
impression
so okay so Hess cow and out there even a
Scullion cats the what so okay so let's
go to the next topic let's do some Emacs
okay so I'm going to show you yeah let's
just talk random then I'm going to show
you some Emacs Emacs okay let me show
you a song okay so I want to go to this
song opening in brave open linking brave
and turn on JavaScript okay I don't want
[ __ ] Google Translation extension I
don't want I don't want Spyro
spyware install okay and don't ask me
[ __ ] so here is a total song from China
this is about 20 years ago
[Music]
now the lyrics is in Chinese so you know
this is fan fan created song so and that
is it's fantastic I love it I never
played dota so I don't even know what
I've watched you know videos of it on
YouTube but I don't know anything about
it in detail but however I find the zone
to be fantastic but because also this
song you know this this song is so this
this is a Chinese song it's kind of a me
you know in western you know in
english-speaking world you have lots of
means sometimes it's a song and so this
is kind of a mean in China and the
lyrics it's amazing you know so it's
quite funny you know successful means
they are successful for a reason you
know successful means not did you know
you can just create something that
becomes a mean success or means they
capture you know the mentality of
thought and sometimes for a song or some
lyrics or poem you know they are actual
poems yes they are you know they are
actually pom-poms but you know for
example in a internet slang style you
know you can if you don't have talent
you write it you doesn't walk
many of the memes or even pictures they
are created by very talented people so
anyway this is one of them but it's in
but it's in the Chinese you know gamer
community and I read it it's fantastic
okay so but what I meant what I'm going
to show you is that I'm going to steal
this YouTube video into my home's own
website so back to my Emacs so you see
this is a link to my local link so I
open it so this is the HTML source code
for that page show in browser you can
see and let's go through the YouTube
section so here this line that's the
YouTube
so I'm going to steal it okay so I'm
going to steal this youtube link so let
me show you what I do so this is kind of
a for those of you Emacs users kind of a
demo or workflow so I copy that
split-window go to a directory III okay
go to the diet go to the directory and
start easy ow so I mean yeah so let's
look so I'm going to type u cube
download UT D okay and that expand to
the YouTube download command line okay
that's a great software that that
software is for you to steal YouTube
videos so now I paste the you URL for
the YouTube I press ENTER it's going to
download that song you know usually not
usually but almost always I have
concerned about copyright you know you
can you I don't I personally do not just
grab copyrighted stuff but in this case
it's okay because this is first of all
this is from China
this music is this musics by someone
else and you know like means you know
means where everyone participate you
know you you know so it's it's hard to
trace exactly who you know who is who
created it and who since it I know who
since it this girl okay but it is
usually it's hard to find the real name
and stuff anyway so so you see the okay
let me show you okay so so the command
finish download okay actually let me
show you that command
so here is my tutorial about that
command Linux command to download
youtube video so you guys can go and
grab it and let's go back to my excel
talk show okay so hold on a second there
it is
okay and now let's go back to Emacs now
the the download has been completed now
I go to the directory refresh so you K
you see my command option downloaded the
multiple formats the one I want is this
one
MKV that contains both the video and
audio so I call command to copy the file
path okay and now I go back to the go
back to the to the page okay and go to
the top paste the path and pressure key
and becomes a huge video link show in
browser there it is this one on top now
because I'm in Firefox Firefox does not
support this MKV format so Firefox kind
of you know sucks so you have to show
this page in in Chrome so let's open
open in brave so there it is why is this
keep asking [ __ ] so now I can pay it
[Music]
so we we got that YouTube and there are
more things I want to do you see this
link the file name I need to change ok
you see so I'm going to call command
that will change the file name on the
fly so I call it and I type a new name
so it's type total so okay and insert a
random stream enter you see that's a new
name fantastic I don't even have to go
to the tired
rename it then go back to HTML and
change the link you know I'll do it in
one shot because all these personal
commands on the Left window you can see
on the pink panel so but so now I go to
tired here and refresh you can see there
it is the new name and the others I
don't need anymore so delete them press
ok good ok
there's one more thing I want to do
because this is this I I director is the
temp directory I don't want this file in
this directory I want to be in the I
directory so again I close tired I close
I shall close that so again let me do
another change so let me type call the
rename command again dot dot slash I /
okay so you see it it's renamed the in
fact it's changed to a different
directory so and here I'll just say ok
over here that's a youtube link I don't
need it anymore so remove all the text
copy the line copy the line back here
pace it showing browser fantastic and I
need to change the date you see today's
state is this is last change is 2018 two
years ago so I'm gonna press three keys
to change the day
now watch one two three then you see
it's 2020 now
so showing browser again 2020 January
first it's updated now go to Isha again
let's coax our interactive a brief now I
got that expansion enter type password
and it's uploaded to my website synced
to my web hosting server there it is
it's still uploading Oh tota
typos oh I got data
okay so let's I need to change it okay
let's hold on let's wait for this to
finish so what do you think of the Emacs
application framework what what Emacs
application framework what do you what
do you mean what are you talking about
translate because you are Chinese you
know so I thought about translating this
song into English but it's not easy
because it's very difficult because we
are talking about kind of a verse here
you know like poetry literature verse
and this verse is not that funny you
know it's an online mean you know it's a
verse of Chinese online means you know
filled with the gamers in China they are
jargons and puns you know things like
that so it would be very hard for me to
translate
I love translation but this will be too
hard you can duck duck go search it I
don't want to search it yeah I mean tell
me what it is because we have lots of
turns of all the topics so anyway so now
I've done so you see right now you are
looking at the local version so we go
back to the
this is my website sorry music domain
name now refresh you see the YouTube is
gone now we just have this my version my
own I mean the version on my website so
this is great and of course you can also
download it you know modern technology
embedded video okay so let's go back fix
the name so you see I got data this
should be dota
so we name it call the command again
dota ok done ok close this okay before
we close it I want to copy the file path
of this URL it's done close it save it
now use some bookmarks type music then
this is my music blog ok so then then
create a new section paste the file path
link if I put a paragraph showing
browser so this is my music blog and now
there's a new entry dota ok so and now I
need to make a RSS link so let's do that
ok so it's done actually let me show you
the command window okay so it's done you
can see this is the new entry there
close it showing browser
close it okay that's that finished one
thing I could actually I have a lot
other things I want to tell you today's
main topic we have not begun yet by the
way if you go to my music blog you can
see you can see this song okay this is
Chinese social media Tik Tok they have
all this mean means memes and stuff you
know and this video is like 15 minutes
or something you watch it you see all
the young Chinese beautiful young girls
like a collection of them doing their
things you know it's very similar to
memes in in english-speaking world you
know you you have girls they did they do
their things so what is the okay so what
do you think of okay so the Google
Translate pop-up does it appear because
you have set language preferences no I
don't have set language preferences it's
it began to pop up you know last week or
something
so AAA says it's an effort to extend
Emacs with PQ pyqt it integrates a web
browser a PDF viewer a video player
that's no good
right away net don't use it never use it
that's just that's my personal style
okay pyqt what is pyqt now i don't like
those things okay you know many of the
Emacs fans they love it you know like
you have this XV something Emacs
actually something that which which
embeds on Linux it embeds the x11
windowing system inside Emacs so you
know instead of
being a browser you know window Emacs
window and other application terminal
instead now you have like just Emacs and
browsers is inside it as a window or
multiple windows you know everything is
inside Emacs people like that I don't
like that okay I I do not recommend it
and I think it's crap
it's a worst hack it's a [ __ ] okay it's
a [ __ ] up way to do things I don't so
I do not recommend it at all
Emacs let it just be Emacs okay powerful
in text mint text manipulation no hack
you know you see my basically I don't
like hack of any kind so don't do that
windowing we know in system is windowing
system Emacs is he just a Mac so very
text primarily text text things okay so
that's a that's about that and by the
way also the x11 is one of the worst
hack possible yeah I'm not going to
start into it start to begin a UNIX
trend because I talked about that
intense of my past videos it's gonna be
one hour on X 11 X 11 is one of the most
[ __ ] up [ __ ] in the entire history of
computing ok X 11 that is why now after
30 years you know that way that is why
today you got people the Linux Linux
people they say have you tried the you
know the new windowing system what is
that new we know in system that you know
the computers are not a hack what's the
new windowing system I don't remember
names ok so you know it's old its old
story because I've been ranting on it
since you know 1991 since 1991 you know
today young people you don't know you
don't know the history since 1991 I mean
yeah well I big you know since
since 1990s there is xxe Devon is known
to be the worst [ __ ] possible since
since 1990s okay but but because you
have code people don't know did you know
you fight you know you don't change so
now it's after 30 years and after 3040
years then people start to realize oh
x11 can no longer walk anymore we really
need to change it we really really need
to change it so Weyland yes thank you
thank you
Emily yes as this day the young young
people they say Oh have you have you
tried yet wait and yet oh you need to
install you Weyland [ __ ] you know so so
in in my eyes you can you know you guys
are just like the flow the app you know
the the flow of history is just you know
it's your turn goodbye you know it's
like like you don't know what is really
good or what is bad it's just fashion
fat okay wait on today's you know wait
line is a fad now but you don't know the
history of it you don't know why why the
you you don't know why you don't you
don't know like every hacker knows back
in 1990s
x11 is one of the worst [ __ ] possible
okay everyone knows well but however it
however you have the UNIX phonetics UNIX
coat every day is like that like that
like you don't you know they wipe this
information out that you know they they
argue again is they say oh x11 is the
best thing it's a server it's a first
server based GUI protocol [ __ ] good it's
a first networked you know the windowing
system it's the far ahead of Windows
[ __ ] my ass okay x11 it's well known
I'm what I'm saying is I see this is
well known packing 1990 okay because
there's this articles every every hacker
knows you know have heard about you know
read it
you know x11 the worst III did a video
about that before but anyway so this is
well known okay but the UNIX philosophy
the unit's code
people you know they don't you know
they'd keep chanting the UNIX code then
UNIX become obsolete becomes Linux and
hence the freeze FreeBSD is still
hanging around okay you guys
FreeBSD these are that still hanging
around
but anyway Linux took over okay Linux
took over so and and now after you know
so then then 2000s past they not raise
2010 and today is 2020 another new
generation the Linux people they are
like oh Weyland have you tried wait on
yet oh god you must you must be placed
you know you must it's a fashion you
know it's like you know this being
having it 30 years ago this is no it's
like like like what can I say what can I
say I mean they are also people ordered
I mean you I did you know it's just
generally I'm not sure what to say about
that you know because it's you know what
I'm saying is that it's not right
because you know so so today you have
people phonetics about Weyland's you
know they are saying oh oh by the way so
you know they think they knows things
you know these young people they think
oh you don't know you don't know you
haven't heard of way line oh my god you
are you are you know you are not
studying hard enough you know there's no
way that no I'm using wait and on this
system I'm using we land on this you
know how clinics or whatever oh I'm
using my land on FreeBSD or decided that
they think it's hot you know they think
it's they are they are getting they are
on edge leading edge of technology or
something but they they you know so my
my pony is sad they don't know you know
it's it's it's it's the the reality is
so let me tell you what so what's wrong
what's wrong with this mentality what
what is not the reality is the Linux the
UNIX the fact that
the worst possible operating system in
every design of complete entire garbage
but you don't know it you think it's
actually you think it's the pioneer of
Technology in some way that's true okay
but let me let me be dramatic so in my
opinion the UNIX is the entire factor of
system it it it becomes the most popular
some somebody
it still doesn't kill Microsoft even
though it's free it's it's quite a
[ __ ] insult okay
white what doesn't we're having Linux
replaced cured Microsoft because Leonid
sucks donkey ass even when it's free the
most powerful way to spread [ __ ]
it still doesn't replace Microsoft
because the leaners in Kumasi inst was
[ __ ] possible it's it's it's espoused by
you guys you know the Nerds
you know the underground hacking you
know people got problems in a niche you
know forever in your niche in a niche
like you don't go out anyway you don't
you know you don't see the light and
meanwhile Google is chanting or masazi
controlling the world and Microsoft now
it's even bigger than 20 years ago 20
years ago when open-source rose we think
all Microsoft might might I know it's
it's 10 times more powerful okay so so
so so what is my point about that x11
the Weiland it's it's the thing you see
that the thing is that you you have the
worst system possible you don't realize
it in fact you have a code that that
chance that that says one plus one
equals two three that x11 is the best
you know the the the the the first GUI
you know networked system GUI base
things like that you know you have that
complete fake news you know for 30 years
and now it's like and now finally
because you cannot sustain it because
that's not truth you know truth you know
fake force things cannot sustain forever
so now after 30 years now you have a
panic because x11 cannot no longer last
forever
you need really really really need to
change it so now they start to do
Weiland
but wait and is not going to just take
over because you have 30 years of
package deeply entwined are on UNIX you
know so that's a situation that is my
you know my grant my hatred about the
UNIX thing you know so this is you know
you might say this is an example of the
UNIX damage a hum you know a deep harm
to computing society to to to the world
that is my personal opinion that is that
is the nature of our talk show Weiland
Wayne Wayne is gonna happen you know
like I can show you articles god okay I
know now we digress into this so I have
to show you articles I guess sorry
UNIX pestilence [ __ ] [ __ ] UNIX this
this Argo is written in 2002
okay UNIX haters handbook in the in
there there is a chapter the you know
the the worst [ __ ] of the x11 system but
that's let me show you where okay
I mean I'm gonna show you this yeah I
have actually
an article on that X 11 you know then
Mac the oh yeah Mac is a Mac is BST look
at how this is history
this is history this page is written in
2002 okay 2003 and back then is like Mac
is Mac UNIX or not UNIX this [ __ ] this
code [ __ ]
and BSD this is a classic I like I like
PST logo Allah
I like this logo the best okay not the
new fact this this is fantastic logo PSD
and we have you know we have the so this
is the UNIX hist
this one is stupid I don't like this one
but it's kind of popular among the Nerds
Berkeley okay so this this is a
fantastic comics okay this this is this
is gray beard gray beard comics the
ancient of eunuchs back then in 1980s or
1970s okay these eunuchs use Nick's
pipes you know you got these UNIX pipes
and buckets and no okay clothes that I
can actually copy the link and go
through my Emacs so we are not going to
talk about my main topics today so we
just chose that so that article I want
to show you about x11 thing and this
chick is beautiful and this is 20 years
ago so she is now 40s I guess this is
Linux word 2000
history you know things come and go and
you have next you have BOS which failed
because apple you know apple you know
because evo apple
software engineering parroting and
practice computer languages UNIX - and
in software okay so oh these are old
okay these these are written in year mm
these are the things that's that's hot
you know every programmer is dreaming
about it have you used the patchy have
you you must you must move to Apache
every [ __ ] nuts is driveling about
this and pro FTP and X in X in a net T I
don't know if you guys still know this
the you you guys the UNIX tech heads you
know in UNIX you have Annette T which is
a demon that takes that processes the
the the networking jobs okay so if
basically every anyway it's being a long
time when I was you know doing this
seriously samba you know I dived into
Samba for months to the technique called
details of Samba which which actually is
a Microsoft protocol so anyway X okay so
X so here is the X Windows okay and and
CVS that's the old version control
system that's their logo then you have
subversion then you have a sink unison
GCC group eg MySQL Postgres
so the thing I want to show you is
actually I don't have the logo okay I
have the logo okay anyway let me show
you this okay this article this X 11 X
the X Windows disaster if you have not
read it yet go read it okay don't have
Hopkins he's still around he's often on
Hacker News he is also on Twitter and he
he followed me this year I see
well I emailed him a few times since I
think even since 1990s Don Hopkins he's
a mathematical program he is the he is
x11 expert okay he ported Sim City to
x11
but anyway he wrote this alko this is
1994 okay this is this is one chapter in
the UNIX haters handbook
you know x11 is the worst [ __ ] possible
and then III have maybe another arc or
somewhere it's not linked here you know
he's I don't know where maybe I deleted
it but back in back in year 2000 there's
another project you know as early as
1999 okay this is a project that that is
intended to replace the [ __ ] x11 that
didn't go anywhere because I think that
guy you know just it just became
vaporware so what is the name let me try
to find a name since I'm doing the show
I might as well go into detail does
anyone know the name anyone you guys odd
beasts the real story behind Weyland and
ex-love exhale wait line okay so love
exhale hunt and today you have systemd
okay I'm kind of outdated so I haven't
really know the technical details of
UNIX and Linux and things change you
know today most of you are most vast
majority of people actually are using
phones they don't even have a laptop
okay so they are using phones hi phone
Android you know and if you look at
phones they are operating system is
rather entirely different from Linux
UNIX okay like on UNIX or Linux
you know I know every directory
structure okay so let me show you let's
go to Asia okay so CD action
okay CD CD to the root directory okay
and now let's go to the root directory
okay so if you are you know if you are
assisting me you know you know very well
the UNIX directory structure you know
almost every file what's their purpose
now on a Mac it's a bit different okay
but it still have the similar things I'm
on a Mac you can see it's a bit so you
have been which which holds all your the
most fundamental core command line
utilities but usually you have espying
which is the core the more fundamental
command line utilities okay that's in sp
then you have been then you have okay on
the Mac the directory structure is a bit
different they don't have all the UNIX
one so you have act so on a Mac the axis
becomes private act anyway so I haven't
been you know doing with these kind of
things for a long time for ten years now
over ten years but what is but what I'm
saying here is that you see so I know
this I know every file every single file
in UNIX system by heart okay and that's
what you should do to you know if you
see something or programmer if you want
to be a good one you know every heart
every file every single file you know
why is there why what's the purpose in
the UNIX entire Linux okay you don't
have Unix now Linux entire Linux root
directory okay that's what you should do
but but what I'm trying to say here is
that things change yours so today vast
majority programmers I mean even if you
are on Linux you don't even know what
the [ __ ] is in this directories but
anyway that's not even yet you see most
people are using iPhone or Android you
know most people and you ask them I mean
even you guys ok like I want to
no easier so you see a tutorial
something so I can know every you know
file structure on Android or iPhone
right yeah you know the iOS or Android I
want to know but it seems very very few
people know and there are people who
knows that for sure
that's my goal if I'm going to you know
I don't use the phone I have a phone I
got this phone about two or three years
ago and this is my first smartphone okay
but I don't use it much
there's nothing I don't install nothing
I you know I use it only for let's see
anyway so what's the brave braver what
so there it is my phone so this is this
is a cheap one the cheapest I can get
Motorola 6g g6 or something I got it
because I have to travel when you travel
these days you need a phone
otherwise it's it's kind of necessary
because back in the days you have public
phone booths you know remember that you
don't have that you need a phone so but
I don't have a number because I don't I
don't have a phone number now so anyways
so I asked peoples also so so if you are
using Android or iPhone you should know
I mean at least you know from my
generation you should know every file
you know the structure and I hope you
know someone can just tell me simply
like in 10 minutes I can learn the whole
lot you know what's the structure how
they walk you know what's the iOS
exactly but it seems you know you don't
find those kind of mentality or people
anymore you know like if I asked on
Twitter I asked you Emily you know Emily
no so are things but as family one day
she doesn't know I think crash hacker
you know the BST hacker and some you
know I asked some of you guys you guys
don't know you know and and someone said
I don't remember you know who was
somebody said oh oh it's just Linux
that's that's not a good answer it
that's that's not a good answer
what I'm talking about is you I want
someone and it should be you should be
have a lot of people you know it's like
you someone can just tell me exactly
what's the eat every fire what's the
directory structure how the operating
system works but it's hard to get those
kind of people anymore
and also these days you search it's not
even it's you don't you cannot find the
information anymore it's hard like for
example I want
you know what's every directory
structure every file on Android OS it's
hard to find those information it's hard
to relatedly hard okay it's not like
before so what well so what I might so
we were talking about X here okay I
think that's it for today I was going to
talk about today's topic this is there
is this fantastic topic about the rise
of evil but but I think that's gonna be
you next day and they also there's quite
a few Emacs stuff I want to talk about
so this kappa raid okay you guys you go
you guys go watch it
okay cabaret watch this movie this movie
is about the rise of evil how it rises
and invited in my opinion today we have
similar and that the name of that is
social justice
that's the rise of the massive evil I'm
talking about massive scale you see Evo
Evo doesn't came to be for example in
this case in this case you know you
recognize this thing let me show you a
few screenshots okay you go watch
cabaret tokay it's a great film okay so
let me copy okay I have a link here so
you can go to my let's do a sync to my
website
I need to close my window actually
become stuck so how long have I been
talking 14 people watching steal one
hour in 20 minutes okay we're gonna shut
down you see I need to close my window
because because you see it's dark here
and you can see people outside can't see
can see clearly me and there it is my
system let's see so there it is
so you go watch let me show you this
okay so you go watch you go watch them
so it's uploaded to my website so open
new buffer paste
so today's sauce today talk show
you go there you can find the links to
this cabaret movie okay and so evil in
my opinion Evo did not rise because
there's some Darth Vader okay it's not
like one guy who created all the evil no
evil usually I'm talking about massive
scale Evo like killing millions of
people they usually okay rise from
within that is the people all the people
opinion you know the millions of people
they all together agree and created that
and today in us you know us a we really
have that evousa you know the for
example let me give you a few examples
first first first example is this thing
now this thing you guys are familiar you
know every you know every day in America
or in Europe every day this thing okay
you are familiar this is a foot this is
as if you are a white person this is the
first thing that comes in your mind
because you in your mind you have
nothing else this is the only thing you
know you are obsessed with this thing
this evil okay now let me give you some
other examples you know the American
wiped out American Indians entirely you
know I you know so that's that's several
millions entirely how did that happen
how did that happen easy
evil guy no but rather it's the older
people you see all the people did that
together they did it together
we are in it together guys they say they
did it
and let's say so that that that is like
200 years ago or 300 years ago and today
we have well the Iraq war Iraq war
600,000 dead
you don't even so what does it mean to
you what does it mean to you guys my
fellow Americans what does it mean to
you
600,000 Iraq people civilians died in
2004 to 2006 what does it mean to you it
means we go to Starbucks and drink
coffee and talk about the philosophy
talk about how great power must have
great responsibility that's what it
means
you know 600,000 I says you know so that
is evil so so white white why did that
happen because each of us wanted that
okay for one reason or not we may be
ignorant just like these people okay why
did this happen maybe because they are
ignorant not because they are evil okay
they did that because not because you
know all these people look at how many
people are there not because everyone is
like oh [ __ ] we need to cure puppies
it happens because all of them thought
they are doing the right thing okay they
these people are doing the right thing
each one of them they are mom they are
sisters the girls they agreed it's the
right thing to do that's what Eva
happens you see in a same way we have
you know the wiping out of American
Indians oh the Iraq war 600,000 died
okay who what do we what you gonna do
what what what what is it you are doing
what are you doing in 2004 what did you
do to stop it
okay then then then today we have
another great example of evil rising
that the name of that is social justice
they are they they are very powerful
okay you know that they are the most
powerful almost the most powerful group
in USA right now what the name they have
you know social justice that's the
mantra and they are doing in my opinion
something their deeds they are you know
they're they are doing something similar
to this that's the the rice okay that's
the rise of them okay that's it for
today I was going to talk about the
other musicals the fantastic things but
I think we okay that's it for today
thank you guys for watching
what what are you saying
leo cada what are you saying so
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching if you like my stuff buy my
stuff okay buy my stuff on my excel
website you know go to PayPal me PayPal
and patreon okay give me some money and
bye guys