foreign
say hi okay say hi in the comments I'm
gonna get my coffee and it's cold
okay so today we are going to write a
emac list command that transposes HTML
table so let me show you the HTML table
so you are looking at for example this
part that's HTML table as you can see
the first line is let's stop this
the first line is you know switch this
is about keyboard switches so the first
line is switch Roman G tactile sweet
drum and G linear GX blue GX Brown GX
red so they go by raw you know six rows
by six columns or something so but in
HTML it looks like that so but what I
want to do is to transpose them that
means make the rows becomes column and
columns becomes row okay and uh you know
in Wolfram language Mathematica there is
a building function that lets you
transpose a matrix or in fact
arbitrarily dimensional Matrix three by
five by seven you can transpose in in
very different combinatorial ways but
typically transposition is done on a on
a m by m Matrix two-dimensional Matrix
you just want to make the Rose becomes
column so basically for each entry you
you you
swap with the other entry so that's what
you do
transposition okay transposition of a
matrix now now HTML table or table is
you can think of it it as a matrix so we
are going to write a command to do that
okay a e-mac this command Okay so the
first thing to do is to um okay write
your transposition function so the first
thing to do is to let's see for eight
okay so the first thing to do is to turn
this HTML format into a
into a lisp
nested Vector okay or or nested list
okay so let's see so a few days ago
about a month ago we wrote a emac this
transpose Matrix function
you know actually I think I wrote this
offline but when doing one of the talk
show we encountered the problem where we
need to transpose
a nested
you know a nested list or nested Vector
so I wrote this command
so all you so you know it already exists
so you just say you know you can make
Matrix and transpose it let's show it
okay let's show uh if it works
um okay so who is watching so guys say
hi okay say hi
so let's see let's search for Star make
Matrix okay so it's not there it's in my
init file load it somewhere I mean it's
not loaded
okay so it's there so you can see here's
the command by the way I'm using the
keyboard oh I forgot to show you my uh
screen the keyboard you are looking at
is
um
glove 80 okay I did a review last month
just search for Sally review gravity hi
Sanders Okay so
you know I wasted five minutes
talking without showing my screen so
here is the trans so here is a transpose
Matrix function so we we were doing this
um you know here's the HTML table we
want to so you know that's how it looks
like in each
um
okay then it's show let's go back to
so HTML table it looks like that and in
browser it displays like that we want to
transpose column become rows rules
becomes column column okay so the first
thing to do is to turn this text into
another text format using the lisp
nested Vector syntax so again let me
show you so here we wrote the command
already
so make Matrix create a matrix of nested
Vector like that and then you have the
transposition because now transpose
function that takes the Matrix and
transpose it okay so let's start to look
at the code and let's demo the code okay
so here's the code so let's make a
matrix okay
so let's say for example uh let's just
say make Matrix okay so what row let's
say uh not it's three by two okay three
by two and what what value do you want
to give in okay zero okay so now
evaluate that
Arrow void function okay oh yeah we
forgot to
um evaluate this buffer so we need to
eval the buffer
okay uh on the pink window you can see
all my command codes and the keystrokes
I'm using overall keyboard okay so we
eval the buffer now we paste this code
uh now let's make it larger
hmm
okay so now we evaluate this slide let's
do it so you can see in the mini buffer
in the message area you can see here's
output
zero zero zero zero zero zero that's a
that's a three by two Matrix okay and
now
now remember that let's copy it put it
here okay now let's transpose it okay so
let's say transpose
okay where is the key for yeah the
cassava transpose okay and what do you
want to transpose you want to transpose
this Matrix
okay let's actually put it here okay
yeah so there now let's do that control
U eval last six so you can see
zero zero zero zero zero zero becomes
zero zero zero zero zero okay
transposition fantastic
okay we demonstrate demonstrated
transposition of the emac basis code now
let's go back now let's write the
function you know we need to turn this
okay so turn turn this HTML table that's
actually what we need to do okay
so
so let's start a e-maglis code block
okay
and uh
so what do you do how do you want to
name this Define function okay Define a
function
okay then we want to say
um
let's say x i HTML table 2
nested Vector okay
turn on HTML table so given a table
text okay so this table text is a string
that is a HTML table okay so doc string
turn a HTML table
into convert
into nested Vector okay that Vector in
lisp Vector means array okay
uh in contrast to list
so in lisp the language
a list
is a array-like thing but you can add
items in the front you can append or
remove one item in the front a vector is
a fixed array okay that's the difference
okay so now version let's give it
today's date okay so this converts a
HTML table to the next state Vector okay
now
the code how do you do okay so the code
first of all the table text is a string
okay so let's look at the table here
and let's let's okay
so
okay so it takes a table text okay
so if you know we want the region you
know this region we want to take that
region and uh
you know let me show you okay so this
you see
so we want to we don't want the text as
argument we want to take the region
so the region will grab the text okay so
let's go back
so instead of text let's let's not put
it there
in region okay into a nested Vector okay
so so first of all we want to grab the
region so region beginning let's just
say selection okay region beginning
let's put two marker here
P1 P2
P2
do you keep track of your progress in
HTML files that's creative what what do
you mean keep track of your progress
you mean like to do explain okay you
mean like ogma to do
basically I I do I write every note
everything in HTML because I grew up
with it you know I've been coding HTML
manually beginning manually since 1996.
1995 is where I learned HTML for the
first time that's the beginning of
Internet
cyberspace HTML you know you have you
have CGI Gateway you you have the you
know web servers so
hello there I have a nice string uh
stream Ivan where are you from where are
you guys from
okay so in 1995 I learned HTML a Wolfram
research and learned about the web and
some a little bit about networking so
back then you know it's known as cyber
internet is not a cyberspace because
it's a brand new thing brand new vision
and people don't we don't know actually
you'll survive you know it's just like
science fiction you know it's called
cyberspace and HTML is called hypertext
you know hypertext and links are called
hyperlink you know it's all amazing
hyperlink
so in HTML it's kind of like the
beginning you know it's kind of half
science fiction and you cannot there's
no such thing as sharper sharp online or
like today whatever video you know they
they you know anyway so I learn HTML in
1995 and started you know in the
beginning I manually code every single
tag and in Microsoft word in the
beginning actually
yes
then 1998 is when I began to use emacs
okay so anyway so
we want to first of all grab the region
beginning and end position okay let's
say user makes a selection we want to
grab this text okay so we declare two
variables let's just say P1 P2 okay so
that people don't get confused with my
naming convention okay P1 P2 is two
variable Now set variable P1 to
region beginning okay region beginning
Returns the position of the beginning of
the selection okay now do the same thing
set P2
region end okay I'm using sa fly keys
and I'm using vorac keyboard and I'm
using sa emac be smart if you like them
if you think I'm doing fantastic
efficient pay me then buy it okay it's
open source uh you know you search for
XR emac B smart you'll find it okay so
now
uh now we got you know purify the code
so we have the position beginning and
end okay now to grab the text okay
uh
okay here's html text now actually let's
go by my convention because I
let's add some Quark to to it my naming
convention
start every variable Name by X
okay now you set
this html text to
uh
buffer okay
but for substring no properties okay
let's just grab the string in a buffer
from two positions P1 and P2 okay so
that will get the HTML text okay now
once we got the text now we are in
business to do the transposition I mean
okay this is the HTML text okay
and html text is that okay fantastic so
what's so good
Ivan from Russia now how do they
pronounce it is it Ivan
or Ivan well in America I think most
mostly Ivan but in Russia maybe Ivan
that's some Kings names something
or leave out or leave a win sphere hello
okay comments questions posted okay
so continue continue the deed so html
text so we got the string which is this
string now uh now what let's copy that
okay so actually uh let's just show it
in this window
okay so now what's what's to do next now
um
now that's hold on a second let's grab
the Matrix code okay copy it and
comment that up comment on copy it close
and switch buffer paste the code there
so we got the code for transposition
level
necessary vector and now we do this now
we want to so we got the string now we
want to convert any of these you know
table TR th into some sort of
um
bracket because you see basically we
want to convert them into this you know
the lisp syntax okay
so the first thing you have to assume is
that you assume in this text there is no
occurrence of the bracket
character
okay let's see
does it occur now
okay
it doesn't occur here but
um but okay let's proceed okay since it
doesn't occur so let's proceed
so but you have to write the code to
make sure it doesn't occur because
otherwise you're gonna get EX you're
gonna get extraneous square bracket
so um so you have to add code here okay
so make sure so okay so let's let's
think let's focus let's get this done in
within one hour okay
so you got the TR thing
so TI indicates the beginning of a row
okay then th is just
um
okay let's go brainless let's just
quickly bend the code out so that we
have some progress during the live
stream instead of thinking and planning
okay so so you got the text then you
want to
let's say
um
uh temple with temp buffer okay so you
create a new buffer temporarily and now
you insert
insert this text into it okay
then you
go to the move the cursor to the
beginning
uh
okay point mean is a function that
Returns the beginning position of the
buffer okay it's not necessarily zero
because sometimes when you narrow to
region so anyway Point me is the
beginning
Returns the beginning position Returns
the integer okay so go to charges move
closer there okay then you
now you want to do search and replace
okay uh
so search for word okay
while so this is a idiom for find and
replace okay so why I'll search for word
search for word we want to search for a
string search for word let's say TR okay
okay search for what let's say search
for TR optional bound no error no error
true okay pound Neo no error true can't
can't we don't care and what do you want
to replace it with use replace patch
replace it by
so TR means a okay so Tia means a
bracket like that
actually we need a lot to do here okay
let's not worry let's just do this now
okay
um
Okay so
so replace match replace it with left
bracket
fixed case
Fisk fixed case Neo because we do want
Capital tr2 literal true and those we
don't care okay so
so that will do it that's one part okay
uh okay so that's one part then let's
copy it let's do it again now this time
is slash TR you know that's uh ending
bracket
full html text you know
TR means row table row okay so now here
you need
uh
you need a
okay so you need a
right
square bracket okay
okay so you replace TR by that now you
copy this again
now you want to replace th okay so every
time you see T well not t h t d okay so
you can see well th2 but you see each
column is bracketed by is marked up by
TD okay so you so TD indicates a column
uh okay so TG indicates out what
so the first of all you got the th part
so you want to
th means you know th is the reason that
the
the title card the First Column or the
first row is bold you know h means
header so table header so that's why you
know so it's kind of special so first of
all we want to replace th and T slash th
by TD okay so first of all th
replace all th by
TD okay and copy that
paste it
and paste it again and the end tag
backslash I mean slash th by td2 okay so
now
now let's let's convert the
the th tag okay
so now let's convert the th tag
I mean the TD tag okay so what TD should
become
[Music]
so
each TD should become
htd should become some kind of a
let's let's do this okay so let's make
the TD to become
uh
let's say a Unicode bracket this bracket
this is called Corner bracket okay so
you can see the name
let's magnify okay so here is the
character you know and the name is
Corner bracket here okay that's a
Unicode Corner bracket that's from China
okay this character
okay so TD becomes that copy that and
replace it
and now
slash TD
slash TD is the
closing Corner bracket okay
hello
Okay so
transposition HTML table so we so far so
TD becomes the corner bracket
uh let's let's stop and let's just post
the text okay so now
but for substring let's get all the
purple substring point mean to point Max
okay
Let's uh shrink them a little bit
okay so actually
let's make them
make them one line so it's kind of
so you can kind of see the whole thing
okay so anyway here's our code so far
not too bad so create a temp buffer
insert the string then do all this
replacement then grab the text here's
the text so
so yeah so the the result text will be
create a new variable
okay so here is the result text
okay
predify okay
and the result text is a variable of
course so we add here and let's just say
insert result text okay insert to the
buffer okay
okay so what does this code do right now
it just convert
HTML
text like that
into by removing those texts but make
them into use brackets okay so let's try
that
oh God this is gonna be another half an
hour at least okay so HTML nested Vector
copy
not
copy the code
now let's try
okay okay let's try to work on this okay
so call the command
okay let's do it let's see
please make it work no it didn't work
oh yeah of course you
require a region because right now
there's no region so you have to select
it okay wait cancel and do
uh select okay now we got now we call
the command do it fantastic
okay kind of worked because but we
didn't delete the original We inserted
the new so you can see here it's much
more
clean so you can see each row are
bracketed by
by the square brackets then each column
is bracketed by the corner brackets
fantastic
now next so we made progress that's one
step
we now we need to turn this into a lisp
vector format okay and the things inside
that needs to be streamed so they need
to have the double quote okay and then
we also need to remove the table thing
okay so
okay so uh yeah let's
so
yeah okay so we let's do that any
comments and questions
I got a few people watching nobody
watching okay
a lot to do so
I want to focus on writing this emac
this today
I'm doing live because it's less boring
because I've been doing this coding
every day you know for the past 15 years
on images
so usually I just call this
um
okay so now you got this table string
you need you want them you want it to be
removed okay so you need to add another
line here
so another line
okay so wait copy
you need to replace okay well search
forward this time you want to use a
regular expression okay so search
forward uh re-search forward that means
use regular expression and the regular
expression you want is
something like that okay so
table
space
one or more
followed by a
and followed by
anything
that is not a
not a
greater than PSI
okay
and one or more
okay where is my first sign
Okay so
okay there is my first sign
is it one normal or zero or two or more
uh
search table
space
zero zero or more actually
uh
space
so zero more let's do that yeah
okay asterisk means zero or more then
then that which is zero or more okay
it's let's just do that okay well you
found this stream optional bound Neo no
Arrow true account you don't care then
you want to replace it by
um
yeah okay replace it by that
okay let's see that does that make sense
let's make it one line so when you you
know when I make it one line it doesn't
looks so good so why don't we change it
then
okay find and replace okay uh it's
do it
maybe that's better okay
yeah that's better okay so
do that but don't forget actually you
also need to do the
slash table okay
this part is simpler because you don't
have the attributes
so replace that by VST
by a closing
square bracket that's right so okay
is that clear does that make sense
not about this specifically but I need a
work on a second stream of income
that has a more flexible schedule than
my job as you know I'm not but I'm not
purple unicorn
okay okay
I don't know what is the personal issue
okay so
um so that that so so so we've now we
change the table okay we should have
fixed this line and that line
and what is what else do we need to fix
okay
so
see we need to turn this into a
huh we we turn this into a lisp nested
Vector syntax then that means it's a
string it's a steel a string
is it yeah I think so then we need to
actually call Eva in this to evaluate oh
God this is complicated
to
transpose that just means column to row
row to column so that's what transpose
means you know it's part of the kind of
linear algebra so you just
kind of want you want to flip it by a in
a diagonal line lines rows becomes
columns columns we come through
hello from UK so okay so transpositional
Vector so let's continue
so we did that so far what's the what's
the next thing to do
so we
um
so we actually we should have started
with a simple toy example because that
way
it's much easier to understand anyway so
so so far we
converted that into that
then what to do next
then okay so then each of the corner
bracket needs to be
double coil
okay so does that make sense I think so
okay let's just keep doing it okay so
make a backup
okay so now
let's add more things change here okay
now
for each
Corner bracket left corner bracket you
found replace it by
uh
you need a backslash quote okay
okay so you need a backslash quote
replaced by a quote okay
same thing now for the right corner
bracket
you replace it by a
by a double quote okay now
let's just do this let's run this for
now and see what we get
okay
pretify the code
predify the code eval buffer done
now let's put here delete that so let's
do this okay
so now you need to make a selection
first then call the command
HTML table nested Vector okay actually
this we need to rename this because this
should be
HTML table two nested Vector okay
leave out the buffer copy the command
name go to this buffer
select or call it paste that's it okay
fantastic you see
okay there's something else we're
missing so we need a space in between
oh God
we need a space in between here you know
it's just um
okay let's just be seated and let's just
you know replace the turbo according
that's probably not the right thing to
do but
now let's just say
uh
I mean so what do you need now you need
the backslash
insert mod
you need a
slash
who is backslash
okay backslash is there
backslash
quote okay so you need two of these
two of them
replaced by
you need to add a space so just add
space in between
okay that's CD but
let's just do it okay
Eva the buffer go back here cut this out
now select or call the command do it
fantastic we're getting better and
better
yeah that's uh that's a lease vector
format okay now remember each time we
have to do a selection first because our
Command
requires a selection
now let's
make it automatically select by
uh
that's on that's not let's just keep
doing this let's focus on finishing this
then maybe we make it convenient okay so
now we got the
stream now let's try to eval the result
okay Eva there's this command
called eval
okay now let's describe function on Eva
let's look at documentation eval form
optional so it says evaluate form and
return its value
if lexical is true
evaluate using x equals scoping okay
yeah we want lexical scoping actually it
doesn't matter here
so what does it mean I mean does it say
what
type is the form I suppose it's a string
okay we can test it here so let's test
it so for example let's eval
let's eval
the expression
Plus
and
wait
okay yeah okay press
two
three okay
now string okay now let's eval Eva last
six
do it
oh
the answer is not what we want
you know it actually it Returns the
string itself we want it to return five
we want to turn a string into a this
code but it doesn't work here so I think
maybe it's read
okay so let's describe function
on read maybe that is the right function
read stream
read one display expression as text from
string no
yeah this might work but we have to oh
wait a string so it can the argument the
stream argument can be your string
okay let's try that
okay read
this expression okay
invite
oh
it worked
it seems to work
now once you got so now it turns that
into a list of expression now all you
have to do is eval it okay so actually
put that here
okay so purify it let's try the result
should be five okay
fantastic you see at the bottom
fantastic that's what we want this is
how you turn a stream into a this
expression and evaluate it okay
so now we just want to do the same thing
you see this we want to do it
to these you know the thing we just did
okay so wait
so
this is the result here okay there
okay now this is two too many lines
let's shrink it okay
now this shrink it
comment this out now back to our code
now
don't be too big okay now you can see
the whole code here
okay it's a complete code
okay now
so now we do it again
buffer
okay now go back here select it
call
do it okay first of all it inserted the
transforms thing but now let's go to the
messages buffer
it should
um
it should return a lisp object
that is the nested syntax
but it's not printed out I suppose
that's normal
foreign
okay so what you're gonna do so okay so
now let's go back here
instead of printing this out let's
delete it
okay let's
say
let's say let's print the results okay
okay so let's
let's insert
instead of that let's insert what we
want to insert we want to insert
format format a string
of this expression so that s means
s e x p symbolic expression it just
means list of expression so let's put
the expression here so that will turn
this nested nested Vector this object
into a string then we insert into the
buffer okay so let's copy that purify
the code
Shiva the buffer go to this buffer now
select the HTML table call the command
meta X do it
is working
you know that's how it looks like when
the nested Vector is printed okay you
know so you can see
so for example we can format it so
that's easy to see so there it is you
see
fantastic
you know there it is so now the next
thing to do is transpose it transpose
okay so we already have a function we
have written the other day
there it is star transpose okay so we
just call it here
because our transpose and what do you
want to transpose you want to transpose
this thing okay
fantastic okay predify the code remove
that we don't need any more remove that
fantastic fantastic
okay Eva buffer now go back here DD dad
select all
meta X call it
did it transpose let's see the first row
is switch feedback type actuation
yes it did fantastic
fantastic guys so you see it did the
transpose now all we have to do is
change all these bracket you know the
square bracket back to the trth
you know that should be easy because
that is you know that's we we already
did it before the other way okay I think
that's it for today
yeah you know
um I can do it this offline but the
basic idea you know we did it I think
yeah
are you doing this for any arbitrary
HTML table yes so that's the ultimate
goal
I mean right now it just work on this
table but it can work on any table it
already basically already works now but
it's not done yet of course because you
need to make sure that your table
does not contain
you know does not contain characters
such as the double quote
or it does not contain any of these you
know the special bracket we use or
square bracket
so what you have to do is that first of
all
decide what kind of character you want
to use
they make sure the table doesn't contain
those characters if it does you want to
trans you want to replace them to
something else first temporarily
then you convert your you know the you
do the stream replace to convert them
into the nested vector
as a string then you convert back those
temporary characters to whatever they
want
okay so that's uh you know so you have
to worry about you know quote inside a
quote in that case you have to do Escape
you know backslash you have to worry
about those kind of things
but you know that's it
this code so there's another question hi
everyone from UK okay
uh does coding with the live audience
make it easier to get results
uh usually it's the you know when you
call when I code live usually it's
at least two times as slow three times
you know because I also have to explain
you know like without audience
I don't have to explain to myself you
know I just do it it's it's it's at
least four times faster
uh but the advantage with
doing YouTube live is that you know it's
less boring because I have you guys to
talk to I can like explain I love to you
know I love to teach anyway so I can
explain this and maybe you know uh
programming language issues we came into
and the idea the concept of
transposition is from linear algebra
what uh matrices you know I like to talk
about things
so it's less boring but it's much slower
also you know so
so basically the idea you know we
already know how to do it but it's this
is not the final result because also you
see when you do it lasts it's it's not
efficient right now you know we are
doing lots of repetition because we you
know
so be anyway the basic idea is here okay
so I think that's it thank you guys for
watching anything else
uh anything else any emacs questions
okay I think that's it yeah so if you
guys like my stuff you know
buy my emacs tutorial you know support
me just search for
search for practical emacs tutorial
search for my name and you'll find it
and you'll see the buy button
and you know support me if you like it
okay that's it uh what else
yeah we got the transpose so so so let's
let's pop the code back
okay let's fix my pump here okay
Ctrl B pop them back and press this key
to syntax color them in HTML and press
this key to show in browser
fantastic so we want to transfer this we
did it we did it almost you know
here's a code okay thank you guys for
watching
bye guys
I've been typing a lot you know lately
so my my hand you know I've been typing
this the 80 is a fantastic keyboard
but I'm waiting you know because I have
repetitive strain injury especially
especially over over many times over the
past 15 years so I need a lighter switch
so I'm waiting for them to send me a
lighter switch meanwhile I've been
typing a lot on
you know on these on my Expos
light fantastic okay this is and these
two keyboard I recommend the most okay
so I've been typing a lot you know a lot
a lot
in the past week again so now I'm
surfing right now actually I'm suffering
from pronation pronation problem like
pronation is naturally your hand is like
that this if you put your hand on a desk
that's called pronation and if you do
this for
eight hours a day you have you'll have
isi so right now I'm kind of suffering
from that why how do I know this
happened in the past but for example if
I right now
uh you know
my hand is usually like that right but
if I put my hand this way oh comfort you
know there's a lot of comfort here it's
right away I can feel right away well
that's because the
there's no tainting and so I've been
using expose that's why so
but glove 80 has tinting okay so there
are advantages and disadvantages of
different keyboards
how emacs work for you Windows fantastic
okay okay I get that question a lot
people asking uh you know I don't know
how you guys get the idea you know
there's some idea that emacs on Windows
have problems not really
emacs on Windows is a bit slower than
emacs on Linux that's true okay however
on Windows you don't have a problem
whatsoever
you know it's inferior on Windows then
on Linux that's why because that's what
Richard storman wanted he intentionally
don't want the emacs and window version
running any better if if it happens to
be better he intentionally
tell his
underlings basically to destroy it you
know he want to make sure emacs and
windows smack Linux emacs runs better on
Linux in
tentionally do that but anyway the IMAX
on Windows works fine okay