good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Star Talk Show today we are
going to do Advent of code problem
number two
or as the Christians would say day two
Advent of code so yesterday we did a
live stream of the event of code day one
solving problem one
exploratively so in wufam language and
here's a solution fantastic and today we
are going to continue
to problem number two
okay so we're gonna coding wolfam
language and it's gonna be fun chatty so
if you have questions comments ask me
okay I'm gonna code this live
so today uh problem number two I already
read the problem which is this one
uh wait uh at the end of a cold so you
go there that's a website so number two
okay now this problem you know the
Advent of code
half of the problem is actually it's not
about coding it's actually understand
what is the problem
you know like I don't like this because
I like I like you know like
um mathematical quiz you know you
specify the problem in a precise manner
technically you know what's your
function you know your your job is to
write a function this is the input and
this is output and what your function
should do
you know that's the precise that's a
typical programming problem
but in advance of a code they don't they
don't describe the problem that way
instead of instead they tell you the
story that describe the problem
so but this is actually quite important
it has a merit of its own because most
problem programming problems in real
world is of this nature you don't have
respect you know you roughly have some
idea of what is the problem you know
because maybe your client or even you
know even in your own coding exercise
you don't have a nice fully specified
mathematical description of the problem
you know but instead you have some some
idea oh I need to do this turn this into
that but you you you are usually
um you don't have the full description
now from the step of giving a problem in
English in human you know need
to a full mathematical description of
the problem it's not trivial okay so
this is actually a quite important skill
you need to develop
in fact this is I would say this is what
mathematicians do
mathematicians when you see a problem
you start to analyze almost
instinctively what exactly
is the input what exactly
is going to happen you know you you
transform the problem description into a
exact mathematical specification and
that is extremely important in fact I
would say that constitute the essence of
mathematics okay very important
important skill
of course in real life usually the
problem changes also like you have a
fussy idea for example be on the website
you know maybe you have a client to
build a website you you know the client
don't exactly know what they want they
just have some idea then you have to
turn that into more specific and anyway
in real life it's more fuzzy but anyway
so what I'm saying is that this
this skill of turning a kind of a
description a general you know fuzzy
concept of the problem into a
mathematical essence
that is that is if you take it
um deeply that is actually
a
that's a that's that's almost the uh
half of the field of mathematics and
logic you know mathematical Foundation
the foundation of math
because that's the nature of mathematics
you need to condense you need to
eliminate it all the fluffs so for
example this event of code problem
number two day two rock paper scissors
you know it's a bit long you know I
already read it you know trying to save
time uh live stream
so how many people three people grand
total of three okay
zero zero concurrent viewers what the
[ __ ]
okay so so this
so this example Paper Rock Scissors you
know it takes sometimes to uh read I
already did and you have to
uh it's it's it's actually uh not
trivial hey hey hey Jay ah okay first
guy
like some of you uh talk to your
Watchers okay let's go to it
so let me describe the problem you know
it's uh it's you know they wrote up the
problem but it's
um takes some time to read so I'm not
going to read them I'm just going to
tell you what the problem is okay so you
are given you are given a string of that
nature you know let's write it out so
you are given a string
uh a string like that you know
and the string has several lines
each line has two letters okay so column
one column two
and the letters the First Column is
gonna be ABC okay the second column is
gonna be any of the x y z so the first
column
can be the possible types the possible
characters is either a or b or c the
second column is either X or Y or Z
you know so
so given a stream of several lines each
line contains two characters
the first character is a or b or Z the
second character is why
X or Y or Z okay that's that is the
problem input
from a program of its point of view
now
um
sorry this is a good question to ask but
is a worthwhile and save task to become
an efficient hacker that depends on your
personality you know if you are an
engineer type if you are a programmer
you write a lot code you know if you are
engineer architect mathematician then
hacker is not for you
well it depends on what you mean by
hacker hacker has many meanings hacker
do you mean cracker like do you mean you
know you want to break into password uh
you know find you know break into
website crack passwords or find security
problems or if you are a white hat
hacker you know security problems or you
want to develop your company's firewall
or whatever to prevent uh malware or
viruses
so that's a security or hacking you know
security field
of of programming okay of and there's no
anyway so that's a security field and
part of it also includes crypto analysis
you know like cryptocurrency and crypto
you know stuff like that encryption so
depends on what you mean by hacker there
are two primary two different primary
meanings one is kind of someone works in
the security field
okay that's a hacker the other
kind of more classic meaning of a hacker
just means a great programmer who a
programmer who is able to quickly solve
the problem such as advantable code I'm
I'm actually not that type of person so
this type of person typically they are
good in Unix they love Unix they are
good in C or C plus plus they are good
in very practical languages or
JavaScript or python
you know but usually C C plus plus Java
this type of guy had
and they are usually not interested in
in let's say scheme list in Haskell they
are not interested in elegant or elegant
language or great design that they are
not interested in that you know this
type of this hacker you know the classic
meaning which is Richard Solomon uh
which installment that generation of
hackers MIT hackers okay they are they
are quick to code they they love clever
code they love you know clever code you
know they to make things work so for
example let's say you know the famous
game programmer
karmac
hammock or however you pronounce name
he's that type he's a hacker you know he
can code esoteric you know graphics
uh you know computer Graphics graphics
card diving into assembly how CPU Works
they don't actually care about design
they they are very good at you know tons
of code millions of lines they just get
things to work and and and one of their
like most prestigious thing for them is
speed like you you your code is very
tight very fast but incomprehensible
they love that clever involves lots of
cleverness walk around okay that's a
type that's the MIT classic
type
meaning of hacker
okay that's that type
okay so so so so so this type of people
I despise that's not my type that not my
personality it depends on your
personality I despise these type of
people typically C C plus plus Unix love
us enjoy us of C or C plus or Unix this
type idiots okay but I mean different
people different type of people
different personality have different
stronghold you know you're good you're
good at something good bad at something
so that type you know that's one type I
don't like
I like
great design or these a great engineer a
great programmer great computer
scientist you know I understand you know
a great mathematician great logician
that's that's what I'm inclined to you
know
I don't want clever I don't want
cleverness in my code if there's a
language or CPU design that requires you
to like work around this that's such a
[ __ ] [ __ ] okay that's a [ __ ] idiot
this hacker created those things
that which incumber incumbents burdens
or the other programmers okay this see
particularly C and all the Unix in that
entirety of the Unix facts the these
hacker types created that okay so the
extreme complexity
you know I don't want
I'm more like you know I prefer
you know mathematician logician you you
and you create programming languages
that's great design and also efficient
you know okay anyway hacker so that's
one type the other
more more mother meaning of hacker
especially propagated by mainstream
media is is basically people breaking
law hacking you know government websites
or whatever Corporation websites release
password you know league league you know
passwords credit cards you know those
and then you have people who try to
prevent that so that's another meaning
of hack to different things two
different things Okay so
so your question you know uh how do you
is it worthwhile
and you know to become efficient so what
do you mean
maintaining a stronghold on a
Eon system with constant Wi-Fi outages
be a good case for more way of
prevention okay and I am a asparian
software engineer but I'm not on that
level of programmer okay so I guess your
sense of hacker is people working in a
security field
okay which is becoming a very important
more and more important which is so is
it worthwhile yeah sure you know if you
are incline you love that kind of work
about security about crypto analysis
about
passwords how they are created where are
they stored how to prevent people you
know and how does virus work
um if you like that yeah sure you can go
into that field
what do I think of oding programming
language I don't know what about or what
you know there are so many so I don't
know usually I get questions about what
do you think about this language or that
language
um
I don't know what he's holding let's get
back to at the end of code okay
yeah cyber security yeah you know I mean
it's a CD question is it worthwhile that
you know so first of all
if you are a programmer or you know the
security the hacker types you know the
the field you are talking about they are
typically they are not programmers
you know like because when you get into
detail you there's a big difference for
example there's programmers there's
certain mean or uh you know system mean
or these days what they call Dev app you
know so you have programmers
you have devops or seasoning then you
have the security cyber security kind of
Staff people okay
yeah they all deal with code but when
you get into the details they they it's
very different requires slightly quite
different skills okay and so and but all
these are viable they you know there's a
lot of jobs and money as especially when
times goes on it requires more and more
so it's good for you to get into so yeah
so Odin programming language I don't
know what they said I don't know what
happened have I heard of it let's see
uh
you know programming language is like
lame you know don't don't you know don't
don't you know like you typically this
is a question young people ask you know
what do you think of Huska when Haskell
is hot what do you think of just oh rust
is gonna be something something when
Russ was hot now there's a lot there's
name there's Odin there's a lot okay
uh let's go back to uh
so for example if you go to kasabi's dot
info
so I have a article about that okay
programming languages proliferation of
programming languages you have a lot
Mathematica wolf and language you have a
new list this is old actually 1991.
Oculus program
Chiles which became Shen you know 2011
then you closure so to me these are kind
of new young kids in town but to you
guys you got new one you got other new
ones so generation so you know
then scheme the granddaddy of lisp
and then you have lots of you know you
have Dylan at one time it's very you
know it's a like do you like Dylan
everyone is talking about didn't around
1992. okay Dylan is kind of a this deal
is a lisp
supposed to be the replacement of common
disp it's supposed to be a revolution
Dylan is created by Apple okay Apple
Dylan you know it's supposed to be a
revolution you know originally it has
the same syntax of nested parents at
least but eventually they dropped that
they adopted the C language circuit
syntax but the language the nature of
the language is still uh lisp so Dylan
but then it died you know Steve Jobs
took over and basically skipped uh
Steve Job took over Apple when he came
back around 1997 you know I CEO you know
iMac iBook
iPad
and he's a Ico
and he killed lots of projects because
apple is dying apple is you know but
Steve Job is a great
business innovator you know he's a he's
got a vision he's a great and he's got a
spectacular impeccable uh articulation
skills you know convince you
yeah and he he has a vision he is he's
able to see what is good what is bad he
creates things that people need as
opposed to as opposed to what do you
think of Odin what do you think of rust
what do you think of Haskell those those
are typically
nerds they create things trying to find
a solution
typically okay roughly you know but
Steve Jobs is almost the opposite he
creates things that people need okay
but once he you know since he passed
away about 10 years ago then Apple
become corrupt and they create uh mostly
idiotic facts
Steve Jobs great guy okay so Dylan he's
a fam you know so then you have F sharp
you know it's amazing you know when I
talk about programming languages I
cannot stop so it's gonna be a one-hour
digression
so you know then you start you then you
have F sharp which is the first time a
giant Corporation
embraced functional programming
you know it's this is year 2005 F sharp
F sharp is a derivative of O camo which
is a derivative of ml meta language okay
so when you when when people you know
new people they
um the [ __ ] you look at the [ __ ]
spammers
you know this is a rumored Malaysian
generation the [ __ ] [ __ ]
so F sharp 2005 Microsoft created it you
know in their dot net
framework Enterprise in.net today's open
source 100
amazing how things have changed you know
turned in so then you have you know lots
of languages you know the new generation
don't know uh then of course there you
you have erlang you have Haskell Mercury
you have q you have ours you have Pearl
PHP uh Ruby and Scala groovy and and and
a lot okay TCR Lua
and why the list and creating a
programming language is relative easy
okay I'm not going to talk about
languages uh let's go back to uh event
of code okay
basically if you you know let me put it
dramatically
if you ask me if someone typically young
people and student you know they ask
what do you think of the programming
language it's idiotic okay
learn a programming language you know
depends on your goal Okay so
okay
so actually let me just uh point
uh you
to a you know go to sally.info scroll
down
you'll see this video okay
characteristics of Haskell Pearl Ruby
python Java closure JavaScript lisp and
Wolfram language so watch that video and
actually several videos before this one
so I tell you you know why
you know it's a very common question
what language should I learn oh what do
you think this language you know that's
those are
typically in Practical and idiotic
questions
okay
so if you want to if you need to learn a
language to get a job find those
languages
heavily used in industry such as
C C plus plus python Golan
okay JavaScript
and Java okay these are basically top
five and Ruby you know you might count
Ruby as well if you want a job okay
start stop asking oh should I you learn
rust should I learn this or that [ __ ]
okay
no that's practical advice
most people need a job especially young
people especially the type of people
asking these kind of questions so
practical need-based do you need a job
yes probably you do you know instead of
leaving your mom's basement so you want
a job Focus learn Master one language
that's used in industry and I would
recommend go land I recommend Golan
python Ruby well you know is in Java you
know many of these
very popular industrial languages are
not good languages okay so anyway
practical
you know if you have a need
then you the language is chooses you not
the other way okay on the other hand
on the other hand if you already have
money you are silver spooned you are
born in America
you don't need to find a job you know
you can you know you can say you are
poop and smoking a crack or whatever and
use iPad and complain all the time and
sipping Starbucks coffee and saying
complain oh I'm poor shut the [ __ ] up
okay but anyway if you don't if money is
not your concern you are interested in
languages just for the pure you know
whatever interesting
you know then you have lots of other
choice different choices you can is to
skim this you can do Haskell you can do
wufam language buffum language if
especially if you are a mathematician or
physics not a programmer okay
uh and then you can look at oh oh ding
or name and they're quite quite a lot
okay
so what is so ding Odin is the general
you know and and and we have people in
our Discord Saudi Discord you know
mentioning cop you know there's also a
lot of lots of crystal
pop cop is a lisp
with static typing okay crystal is like
a python
uh
python in
a fast python something like that it is
a lot okay
so what is the
language with distinct typing build for
high performance modern systems and data
oriented programming or this is a c
alternative
see alternative there is a c alternative
I approve Golan okay
wipe C and C plus plus out of this Earth
the [ __ ] these are C and C plus plus
they are created by this hacker idiots
extremely complex
okay I don't I don't know about Odin I
don't care
uh
so I mean if you ask me what's my
question or then it's [ __ ] it's a pure
[ __ ] [ __ ] unless unless you know some
other reason come up that's that's my
opinion and that's that's also I would
say
this is probably you know that I would
say that about rust too
okay so uh God we digressed so much uh
30 minutes already we haven't started to
do the Advent of coding
you need the knowledge you know continue
discussing the language I need the
knowledge pay me okay Jr who are you
pay me did you donate
okay let's go back to Advent of uh event
of
code
uh
okay so yeah let's try to finish this
you know we meant to do this today so
let's try so so the problem is you know
given a string of lines each line has
two letters the first letter is a or b
or c the second letter is x or y or Z
and uh and uh
and then
you want to compute you you you need to
write a function that takes this string
as input and output a number okay but
how does the how does it work so you so
here is how it works okay so again this
problem
you know more than 60 percent like I
would say 70 percent
of
of on the of solving this problem is
about analytic skills not about coding
skill okay so you need to be able to
read this and and be able to think about
to analyze to distill the essence of the
problem because the problem you know
they they use lots of words in stories
you know Caesars rock paper scissors
game rock is represented by a you know
Caesar is represented you know by a
paper is represented by b b and Cesar is
driven you know blah blah blah blah so
anyway so let's let me let me get down
to the problem so you need to write a
function that takes a string as input
and and the function must return a
number integer okay
and but how does it work so let me let
me try to uh do that that that's the
essence of solving this problem
uh less about coding
so okay close that close that close that
okay
so
so let's
um let's do that's ready and mount okay
I want to focus on this problem and
solve it in today
let you know I don't want to get
distracted and become something else not
today
thank you Jr so I don't mean to be rude
but sometimes I it turns out that way I
don't mean to be rude
uh
so let's go back to the problem so
so this problem you know actually to
write a
spec
of this problem is actually not easy so
that's what we are doing that's what I'm
doing here so given a string of two
letters each line
so how do you what does your function do
so
write a function
uh F okay
F returns a integer okay
and
and how do you describe it okay so a
means one so basically you know rock
paper rock paper scissors they are
playing this game so a represents Rock B
represents
uh paper C represents Caesar so Caesar
Beats
you know so basically the latter one
speeds the previous one B beats a c b
and a b c so it's a cyclic
uh ABC so and uh
but they so it's about rock scissor and
paper but there's a Twist rock paper
scissors there's a twist
you see a has a score of one B has a
score of two
C which is a Caesar has a score of 3. so
when you play this game
you know
when you put out Caesar you have a
higher score
if you know if you win and but you know
so depending on what you put out you
actually have a higher score so you know
that you you you you want
you know if you are creating an
algorithm to play this particular
variation of rock paper scissor you want
to
increase your chances of using Caesar
you know but of course if you do that
then the opponent strategy will you know
another way they will increase using
Rock so because they know you are going
to put a lot of each one you know they
are trying to put a lot of scissors so
but so this is very interesting
intricate variation okay but anyway back
to this problem
so a is you know a b c means one two
three you know you know each one has a
score but also x y z you know so it's
confusing they also use x y z to
represent
ABC so x y z x is
Rock Y is paper Z is Caesar so that's
the second player so also that means one
two three that's a score okay but
but
so first of all your function when you
see a you have a score of one when you
see B you have a score of two when you
see C
you have a score of three you need to
add you know so so for example this line
a y immediately you have a a is what
there so you have one and y y is two
so a and Y
you have a score of two already then you
have to determine which one wins so in
this case
Y is
uh Y is why is paper and a is Rock so
the the second player wins
so that means so here's so that's why
it's um
not trivial to describe this problem
mathematically
so basically
um when it's a draw you get a score of
zero you are the second player Okay so
if you
um lose
wait if you lose you get zero so if you
draw
you get a score of
um
you know these these story like problem
okay so here zero if you lost three if
if it's a draw six if you win okay so
you are the second player you know the
XYZ so lose zero draw three and the win
you get six
so your function needs to basically
compute you know given this list of rock
paper scissors you need to compute the
the score for you the second player okay
so what does this function needs to do
is so draw loose so for example when you
have a y
what happens is that
becomes uh okay so
so a is one
Y is 2 so a uh one plus two
then
because Y is
paper beats a rock so you win so you get
six plus six okay now it's becoming
clear what what to do so
for example
let's write them out like that okay
okay so let's let's see
okay
which is equals to what
9. so if you get a y the outcome is nine
so your function needs to do this for
every one of them and sum them up I
think yeah sum them together okay
so we need to write this in Wolfram so
yeah we're gonna write this in Wolfram
language so let's start
okay we got 20 more minutes I hope you
know we can finish yes we can in 20
minutes but we probably don't have time
to write this in JavaScript or
emac this okay
so start computed come start the kernel
Okay so
you know this is a preparation to
understand the problem so the function
basically the function
function
compute three numbers
basically
for each line
the function compute three numbers
and sum them okay
okay and
so the first two numbers are easy to
compute because they just correspond to
one two three the
the third number
depends on this Windows draw so
that's that's kind of the a little hard
problem so
so for example so you need to convert
these numbers you need to determine who
which one wins Okay so
you know there are many ways to do it
but one way is you you represent ABC or
XYZ by numbers by this one two three
themselves then you can easily compare
using modular arithmetics to see which
one is greater than
to see if the second one is greater
by one then the first one if it is that
means you want you are the second player
that means you won't
if it's the same then it's a draw
which you get three if you win you get
six
nobody however is
you know if their difference is by two
then then you get
um
then you lose you get zero okay so
that's already that's how we start
that's so basically that's the algorithm
we already solved it so let me tell you
let's write out the algorithm okay
convert the letters to
numbers
a to uh
a21 B2 2 c 2 3 and same for x y z
add them
then
compare
the modular
arithmetic
uh
modular 2 3
actually modular 2 2 because 0 counts so
so the input is one two three but you
want a cycle of three so so you have 0 1
2 instead
so modular 2 2 and if the diff is 1 then
add
three if at six
if if the
something like that okay we'll work out
the detail if the
div is two
if the
then add three if zero has zero okay
that's an algorithm basically
okay so okay so let's let's let's put
this into a list
so we can view it in browser
so that's a problem description and
that's the algorithm description we have
it okay let's write start to write the
code okay so input
uh
okay so let's trade in Wolfram language
in
emacsawwal fan mod
so X input equals to
okay so let's see what's the Stream
okay so we have a string
so first of all the problem is uh Define
function okay so we want to define a
function
function equals to
okay so function is X is a string I'll
put a number okay
I'll put a number that's the function we
need to write okay and first of all
okay let's start to do okay okay let's
start to explore X
first of all split you know turn the
string turn one giant one blob above
string into a list of items and convert
these ABC to numbers okay
so turn the split okay
Spirit string X input
uh
so
okay so we got a list
uh lines okay
so each element is a string of lines but
before we do
before we change it turn the string into
a list we first of all we do a
conversion to change all those into
numbers okay because numbers is much
easier to
we need to use numbers to compare them
so
so we got a string replace
okay I need to look up documentation
what's the Syntax for string replace
turn JavaScript
okay string replace uh pattern yeah so
yeah that's what we want to do
let's see what about alternative string
DDD string so what is the String replace
list
gives a list of the strings obtained by
replacing each individual occurrence of
substitution
okay so let's see example
okay so when there's multiple occurrence
the string replace this just
returns order possible
Replacements you know for each possible
occurrence
so that's not that's that's that's not
what we want uh
yeah we want to string replace all so if
there's for example if this
you know what because when you click the
you know get your personal input you'll
see a you know here's here's the input
you know you have a huge number of them
you know that's the input
so we want to replace all a by B okay I
mean all a by
um
easy so
uh should we use one based or zero base
let's just stick with one okay so
um so
stream replace
X input
and here is a list of replacement
okay let me show you how that's done
okay so 8 replaced by one
um
yeah string replace
um yep
okay so actually let's do this
okay so it now it's easier to see
okay so one
two three
ah
one two three now let's you know as I
write this you know it occurs to you
sometimes there's different algorithms
that might be better but let's not worry
about that let's just stick with this
this way and go through
okay so
um
ABC is one two three x y z is one two
three that's rock paper scissors okay uh
and uh in Wolfram language you cannot
have
you know
extraneous coma at the end okay so
string
input that
so then here you turn that into a list
first of all you do the stream
replacement okay
uh
okay let's assign it then
X2
becomes lines okay and then
um
you need to split again
so you split
and you need to split again
so because you want to turn this into a
a list of
least
so this first line
would be a list of two items yes a list
of least and the elements would be
numbers okay so just like yesterday
similar to yesterday
so you split it first
and let's say X3 okay
so you split it first then X4 equals to
okay function
okay
X so this function
you want to map it
and this time when you split it needs to
be a space
space is a separator okay
so actually let's just run it so instead
of just let's run it okay
looks like we got it
close not quite
okay
uh so X4
um
foreign
am I still doing good what's up guys
let's see okay so
okay so we I want to finish this oh [ __ ]
five more minutes
um
he placed him by numbers okay then you
split
right when you split it's still
[Music]
oh okay actually
yeah when you split
when you split by your end of line
character so each one each each line
becomes
so this Y is true this is one two okay
so that's the one two
okay like that
but okay so there's something wrong here
when you split the first time
you need to say we want to split by
new line I think they assume both new
line and
space because you can test length at
output number four
so let's
so by default when you split stream it
assumes you want to split by any y space
I suppose
that's what happens there so let's look
up the function I mean let's look at the
documentation and we are C
yeah you see
speed string into a list of substrings
separated by white space we don't want
that we just want to
we want to split by end of line then
split by space but another way we can do
this
by the because of the power of wufan
language is but before we do that let me
just show you this way it works okay so
run it there it is that's what we want a
better way
we can do it is like this okay let me
show you
so split by yeah so just split
that and then
partition
this thing into two parts Okay so
okay so these two lines
is equivalent to this one single line
let's try it
yeah yeah so let's for example let's try
it copy all
Lego paste run see fantastic we reduce
them into one
and is it more efficient yes more
efficient than these two
okay now we got a pairs now for each one
of the item we need to turn it into a
number right now they are still streams
Okay so
X5 equals to 2
expression okay
copy all select paste then
okay now they are actually numbers for
example because you can see output 17
the first part
first part
equals to
you can say
number Q okay I'll return true
that means percent 17 means the output
17 okay that's a shortcut or you can
write that way okay
so output 17 which is this thing and
this double square bracket means
the function part okay so that means the
first part
open language is one based index so the
first element is that one then first
element so that would be that one
and is it number number Q means is a
number and this is a post-fixed notation
so if you have X slash slash F
that is equivalent to F bracket X you
know very you know it's exactly the same
as the Unix pipe
okay slash slash okay so we got that
uh that's the explanation so now next so
we got into a numbers now
you need to compute a score
so for each pair
so you want to do a map okay
for each pair map takes two arguments
okay the first argument is a function
okay so we're gonna write a function
the second argument is the is a list
okay so we want to process this this
basically summoning sum them up
so we map we want to turn each of the
pair into a single number okay
so this function will take
um
your take
here take a variable X let's say
and what does it do so okay
first of all add them up
okay so the function
yeah the function takes that
takes one argument this argument is a
pair
and
a Google user why the end right why the
Red theme
well not because it's Christmas because
Red theme it gives me this red border so
that when you have lots of windows in
the in the Microsoft Windows idioc or
flat design it's easier to see the edges
you know which actually is a window is
that's why
and no significant reason anyway I just
changed my thing
so
you know you guys ask questions you know
focus on the topic
you guys just here for the drama you
want to come here to see because our
talk show oh rent and whatever right
learn something learn to you know learn
learn coding and stuff
uh so so okay I need to finish this
so let's let me just code it
don't worry about it okay I'm just
commenting you know for fun so don't
worry about it
you know I I have no idea who guys you
guys are you know uh so don't worry
about it this is this is sad talk show
okay so we need to finish this so
function um
function takes this input it's so
let me let me see what we can do
function takes that input so you want to
say A and B okay
uh
so let's not worry about let's let's
write a separate um
let's say compute line score
uh let's compute
um
you know so what what's the What's the
phrase they use to describe this
each round
your total score is some of your scores
in school for a single round okay so you
can say
let's just say line instead of round
okay so here's a function
you you want to write a function okay
compute this computer single line okay
uh actually
let's write it in a different way okay
so
F okay F takes
yeah actually idiotic okay X Y so it
takes a kind of a vector okay and uh
and what do you want to do so
God I need to go to the bathroom so you
you give it a module so module is kind
of like lips let okay module is for
local variables Okay so
and here's a body okay so module let's
see empty no variables so the body will
be X Plus y that's that's the Caesar
Rock score you know this is a rock paper
you know that's that's those A's one two
you know so first of all you add them
together
then
then you add
okay the last part is a bit complex
modular rhythmics okay
mod
okay mod
two okay
so
if
if mod
X smart
so hold on a second
minus so if y mod minus
X Mod
is
equals to
zero
then
no no difference they are the same okay
so
so that means zero so it's a draw so
when wait when it's a draw you have a
point of three so instead of if you need
a condition okay so first of all
so this is getting uh
Queen
so score
wait
ing Do's or Draw status okay
let's say so we Define a variable
outcome
okay so outcome is a variable
wait
t2e G3 company
right oh yeah we did [ __ ] it okay so
I'll come is a variable yeah
so first of all we need to
so here's a body so we need to Define
outcome
so so we we need to Define several local
variables okay
mod x mod Y okay
mod x equals to
that
okay
and the mod Y equals to okay mod x
equals to that mod Y equals to that and
so let's remove that
okay
so mod mod x
mod x
let's make sure it's right so one two
three
mod two
mod 2 means the possible outcome is
so oh wait so we better use now we
cannot use
we have to say mod three
mod 3. okay so actually so the whole
thing
yeah so it's it's actually better if we
use zero based index
yeah so we have to change the whole we
need to use zero based indexes okay
which is better because it works with
Mod
okay
so now you have zero based index you can
say mod three
wait Mark two or three uh
wait you don't even need to mod
is that right
yeah you don't even need modular
arithmetics
because to compare win or lose
he's just
because there are only two conditions
two or three one two three you know
three possible conditions it's not like
there's ten so when there's only three
possible conditions you can just use a
uh
you know
two or three if statements or
conditional statements
oh God epic run time
okay so
um God this is taking too long we need
to finish it okay so okay
finish it
let's see should we use zero based or
one based
yeah I want to use one based okay
so I don't you know zero base these
cryptic
so when based so the outcome
one two three one two three so wrong
season let's see
one two three
so if
so we don't we don't
we don't even need that so if y minus X
equals to one
uh so there's a decision problem should
you use modular arithmics or not
so you rule thank you so much shade I
need to go to the bathroom
um
so X Y if x is
one more then
if Y is one more than x then you win
so your score is six okay let's let's
see let's
you know compare let's see let's let's
try the possible possible so
one
two
and three that's one possible
input of a line so the second possible
input of the line is
okay and the third possible so this is
all possible input of the line
one one one one versus one one two one
three uh so let's write
sure
wing
loose okay
Okay so
[Music]
and on this column let's put the modular
let's put the difference
of the second number minus the first
number
I don't think we need modular rhythmics
arithmetics
so the difference is one here the
difference is one
here the difference is
2 okay lose here the difference is 1
minus 2 is -1 okay
here the difference is zero
so when the difference is zero it's
always true okay so Wing is one so the
difference is one is always win okay now
it becomes clear you see when we when we
enumerate them out we get
we obtain the uh Clarity in the whole
logic
and then we can decide whether we're
gonna use modular arithmetic or not
so here the difference is negative two
wait
uh
oh wait so
one
is Rock
three is Caesar so here is you win
but one minus three is negative two oh
so we got actually
Okay so
okay so wait so Wing here is One Wing
here is one
uh maybe you do need modular arithmetics
[ __ ]
loose means
lose means so 2 minus 3 is negative one
draw is zero so draw is always zero but
let's see the pattern for wing and lose
so here is a win here is win
so can we
so here's a pattern so you can we find a
way
either
differences between these two numbers or
differences between
you know both numbers smart three
and come out the number that
that clearly indicates it's always a
draw or win or lose in this case you
know in in our current way
you have one is a win but negative two
is also a win
so to be to make this work we can just
be inelegant and just use all statement
so if the difference is 1 or negative
two it's both win
um yeah we can do that so lose you see
those is also a bit you know you know
there's two different uh
numbers for lose
okay that's not elegant I don't want I
don't want I don't want in elegant
solution I want so we we do want to use
modular arithmetics
foreign
is the result of Y minus X okay
okay now let's try a different scenario
let's try a different scenario here
okay
uh
so this is already for uh
70 90 minutes we still haven't solved
this problem yet
third column is a result of so here
let's do
so actually the best
the fastest solution is if you think
about it
so
yeah so if you use modular arithmetics
then you can simply
take the second number minus the first
number
and
if it's zero it's true if it's one it's
win
otherwise
it's
lose okay
so so first of all let's see what uh
well but if you use mod then you
actually need to be zero based
yeah so this is one of the those
problems off by one very annoying
what oh what
what
oh yeah mod right right the the mod
cannot be zero that's right
so let's do a table yeah
[ __ ] around
foreign
so many ways to
to go
but taking too long
so
so yeah I was trying to avoid thinking
about this but actually you need to
think about this
zero one two three
ah zero one two three
[Music]
Okay so
I don't think we have to change base
okay
so
so let's go to the
let's go to the talk show
okay so let's let's write them here
okay so something like that
and
um
yeah so we so
we can actually do all possible outcomes
so
okay let's just see what we get
this is
um
trying to be lazy instead of thinking
hard we just
doing the code and see what are the
whole possible outcomes
okay yeah so what we can do is uh
so do you see what I'm doing
I hope you do
um
okay
okay so now it's easier to see so if the
input is 1 1
the amount is also one one and it's a
draw so if the input is one two
their mod is also one two
so now we we need to see
so wait so I actually just focus on this
one
one is a draw
one two is a wing
so Wing is negative one
one three is a lose lose is one
okay
now so we have three states
win draw lose we want three distinct
numbers
to represent them so here is apparently
not correct because the you can see
sometimes you got one sometimes you got
negative ones sometimes you got two
so that means your modular arithmetics
is incorrect
so you either need to reduce your ABC
instead of one two three you want zero
one two
or
yeah so you need to yeah so
God this this Sealy problem
so you want to change your index to 0 1
2 based okay yeah let's do that let's
seems more logical now it's clear
uh your index needs to be zero one two
okay zero one
two okay that's the index to represent a
b c x y z or rock paper scissor
okay rock paper scissor okay then here
the sum you just need to add extra two
because
you know
okay
so and now back to the mod so now we
started you know it's pretty messy so
it's pretty messy so now we know
so we can try this so so instead of uh
one two three so we have 0 to 2 okay X
and Y possible values for X 0 to 2
possible values so for y 0 to 2 and here
the mod is just O2 okay so let's work
here
okay and replace three by two
okay so here's our code and go down here
run it with
table form okay
yeah okay let's do it again you need
the you need them to be
[Music]
on the same line okay there
fantastic you see all the outcomes is is
zero is either zero or negative one
or one one
you know so negative one is win because
you
you know we are
Computing the difference x minus y
instead of Y minus X so this is perfect
that's what we want this code okay this
line of code
this line of code let's reverse the
order so anyway we got the
okay let's let's make them into a
so now all these are useful again now so
X Y X smart equals to
okay
mod Y equals to that
okay those are our variables okay
we are writing this function okay
and uh
outcome equals to
uh you know the
later variables do not have the value of
the previous variable so you need to
Define outcome here
the outcome is just equals to that this
basically
and
fantastic it took a while to work out
the logic but I believe that's correct
so now all you have to do instead of
this if the if if then else if
we just get you know just add the
outcome
oh wait you still need outcome you still
need so if outcome is
um you see because the problem if the
outcome
then let's write it okay let's
if outcome is zero you get zero so if
outcome is one which means you win
wait if if outcome is zero that means
you lose wait what
wait so wait
let's write down so negative one so
what's the score for the
the outcome so
zero if you lose three if it's a draw
okay six win okay
zero is loose
zero so draw is three so one is six six
you know one means you win so
so now the problem a sub problem is how
do you turn these numbers to to these
numbers so negative one becomes zero
zero becomes three and one becomes six
okay that's uh
you know again you can just manually
code the if statement or conditional
statement to get to turn these numbers
but um
but is there a more elegant way
yeah of course there is
you add one to each you add one to each
of the input so this will become one
I mean this will become zero this
becomes one this becomes two then you
multiply by three fantastic
so here
um
so you see here's the outcome you add
one to it
uh wait so actually you need to put the
pattern okay
add one then multiply by
by three
fantastic okay that captures that
so all you have to do is yeah so that's
the result fantastic okay so let's move
that
let's move these lines to our
talk show
page don't close that don't um
okay that's our notes okay
so actually so let's
okay so here's our code let's let's
let's see if we can
that's our code okay
fantastic
so again here's the input and here is a
string replacement
okay replace the ABC by numbers then
then we do this
to let's leave those
then we just do this to turn them into a
list of lists okay then
change all of them to
numbers
okay like turn a string into numbers
okay then here's a function to compute
one single pair
okay and then we just map
this function
to
F5 then we got the list of numbers okay
copy all back to from language
paste it here
run it
fantastic
so our score is 939
so we just because there are three
rounds you see there are three rounds
there
so now all we have to do is just sum
those numbers total
oh God this is I hope this is the
solution you know just total you know so
21.
9 plus 9 is 18 plus 3 is 21 okay so now
you know to begin get your personal
input which is this huge input let's try
it
God I want I want to go finish this damn
thing
so first of all copy that
copy that
paste so that's a huge input copy all
select all
and this is uh interim Mathematica
computation so
let me do a screenshot of it
so that we have um
a record later on I need to
put on my website okay
to a screenshot
okay now
copy the entire code here
select or paste so here is a problem you
can see
here's a problem okay input
okay so now let's run it
you're in it
oh God then we have to repeat that and
it's
okay let's why not just show it
the bottom
okay here's the result
eighteen thousand two hundred ninety six
I hope that's correct we don't know but
um let's put some semicolon when you put
a semicolon into the expression it
suppresses the output okay so let's put
the same I call it okay
okay and here let's clean up the code
so that um
let's clear up the code X1 X2 X 3 x 4 X5
just just for the sake of Okay so
there there there X3 X4 X5
um yeah and then
hex result uh X answer okay
equals to that
basically
and also put that here okay
okay that's the answer but
okay copy all
copy your selego paste
eval okay that's clean now I will be now
we basically done go back to advantage
of code and paste the answer here that
should be it but I want to make sure
make sure you are doing
I don't want to get the wrong answer
okay so first of all
cut that
paste it here so I want to make sure
this is correct
you know double check your code so
so that's our code right okay
so in this example they didn't oh total
score oh they say okay so in this
example the score should be 15 okay so
let's try
so is it 15
incorrect
okay so that's so incorrect something we
need to fix
rock paper scissor
each one has
um one for rock two for paper three for
these season
okay so here we add two is correct
then um
this can be shortened
okay
ma oh mod okay so why no wonder
no wonder we got it wrong wait
mod Y
mod Y minus mod x that should be correct
mod Y minus mod x what mod Y minus mod x
first one
uh
understandable what what what you guys
so have cheaper for review mod x minus
oh fantastic Hefty buffer that's
that's great suggestion yeah
oh okay so actually yeah you are right
so
oh [ __ ]
we did we wasted a lot of time so here's
a solution we don't have to change the
base
um
I'm glad somebody's you know actually
focusing on the problem
okay so so right now we got the arrow so
mod why mod x
mod Y mod x
plus one
hey why is it not right oh God [ __ ]
let's do this first
so here it says the solution should be
15 why
a 1 6 8 1 6.
so the first round your opponent is rock
and you should you have paper
so win for you
score of 8 okay 2 because you choose
paper
oh you do not add your enemies Ah that's
right you you don't add your enemies
number so you just y plus one okay you
don't add
your enemies whatever the city okay
let's do it again
a16 it was uh since this is 15 that's
correct
fantastic okay a16
so that's the answer that's it
copy the whole
paste this giant input here
go back here
and you need you need to say total again
copy all
slego paste it run it that's it anyway
I'm just gonna paste the answer
paste submit
that's not the right answer [ __ ]
what
yeah this is shitty
your answer is I don't want you know
this is I don't want it to this is what
happens when you
don't I'm not careful
accuracy is the right answer for someone
else you might be logged into the wrong
account what the [ __ ]
Jesus
need to be using your personal input so
that's my personal input
your personal input
tonight
and see what is the my previous personal
input
CX
b y c z c z b x
c z b x wait P X
huh it's different
c y b y c z c z b x c c c z v x p y
VZ VZ VZ c x c y b y that's correct
that's the same
CZ okay so all the way to the bottom
BX c y a x okay that's is
that is my input
yeah that's the same input
go back
and
got go
x y z
and
addition to expression
compute School
mod x smart y
uh come
so what is the
negative zero
so so you do the any any suggestions
I don't understand why is it
so on that one it's correct
on the on the example input
a16 is correct
okay
under example input is correct
a16 a16 result is 15.
now what what possibly can go wrong
did I forgot some kind of local
variables
leak of local variables
uh
how did I
so miserable here
no no uh F6 f
6 this is closing this is running into
two hours
so compute x y
yeah so
I'll choose six four five he's incorrect
Okay so
don't know what's the problem so
let's clean up the code
two expression
okay so you don't even need
Okay so
so where's the input
try
okay
oh the input is not what
oh yeah so there is still stream speed
oh yeah I forgot about here
so you still need extra here so
two
so this part let's let's
put it here okay now so now the code is
completely
incomprehensible
hmm
yeah so he can do that do that do that
yeah that's correct now
copy the whole input paste it here run
it and now
compute these two
lines
so that's the
that's the outcome for each
round
in 12
but it says it's incorrect
I don't get it
what what is what what would your total
score be if everything goes exactly
according to your strategy guide right
so you
you sum them up
and uh
that's what it's supposed to be
and I gotta go
so let's
um let's do this let's take a break
let's not stop I want to so I want to
actually finish this code [ __ ] I got
pissed
you know it's like playing a video game
you know when you get cannot pass the
boss level you play until you drop dead
you know you play non-stop no eating no
sleep
so I'm going to finish this problem I
need to go to the bathroom badly so I'm
going to the bathroom and it's
intermission
okay guys
I'll be right back
the meanwhile on his show um
indeed see you in five minutes okay
see my video settings
be right back five minutes
foreign
okay I'm back
gonna find out what the [ __ ]
is going on with the problem
miss my toots or masterton masterton is
no good
masterton is one of the open source
fantasy you know there's quite a few
before it
canoe social you know for example
there's quite a few before in the past
in the past 15 years and each one of
them just fails you know you got
a handful of nerds
high-powered you know very smart you
know coding like Linux Fanatics emacs
phonetics theme phonetics those people
Unix phonetics c c plus you know they
were gathered there
fraught with problems mastered in you
know each instance they ban each other
you know in theory the idea of the
vision is that oh masterton Federated no
central control very good idea great and
so you have Federation each instance
communicate with each other but in
reality lots of problems one your
password is open to admins you know you
don't know who the [ __ ] is running it
your or your password or your private
messages communicate on Master them
everyone you know you you don't know who
is reading it okay that's one thing and
this centralized systems they have
people who are responsible of course
there's a lot of problems but
what I'm saying is that mastered and the
ideals Federated you know it doesn't
work in reality so first problem you
don't know who is running it and they
can you know it's open source but the
the person who is running the instance
maybe maybe [ __ ] around with the code
you don't know
you know you can say you know show me
the instance the source code you are
running you don't know what they did to
it okay so all your private messages is
public or your password
is is you can consider it public or your
secret or whatever
okay no security first of all then the
Federation you know whoever you want to
follow you can see them you cannot see
their messages because
Master than in real life each instance
span you each other as in particular in
America for example you have the social
justice group of Gan then you have the
anti-social Justice group of gang or
Democratic party supporters versus the
Republicans voters they ban each other
well typically the social justice can
ban the Republican
you know or Nazi you know instances so
ideally you know you you follow someone
you know you like they are in different
instances but you can see their messages
like you don't know who you know you you
can't see them
that's the second major problem you
cannot actually communicate each other
except on your local instance
then so so your audience or who you can
follow is very small because you know
then then there's a complexity problem
the extreme complexity of the interface
like you know you might see people the
posting of the people on your instance
then there's a concept of the post from
Federated instances you don't know who
they are you don't know where they came
from yeah like it matters sometimes you
know
and then so lots of problems you you
know you want to follow someone in a
different instance very complex okay
very complex
so Macedon
it's a failure you know it's being a
failure for you know
so Hefty buffer thank you so much you
know you are like the only one who is
actually paying attention to the to the
coding problem today so here's our code
so
so uh Hefty buffer is helping me solve
the let's go back to the coding okay
so I think your motto is incorrect oh he
says my model is incorrect consider
winning payer
3 1
3 1 so 1 wins yeah well if you use one
two three then yeah so you win the
second player win
um
YouTube doesn't let you format your
messages don't worry about it
so let's see what you are saying I mean
maybe you you you have a point okay
uh
what
what am I doing yeah
all right
okay that's not good
okay
I think your motto is incorrect consider
winning pair
V1 enjoying pair one one so
so what uh
okay see so if we got three one uh you
know we we change it to two to zero
based so it's two zero
and then
modular arithmetics
no wait uh okay so
basically you are seeing both of them
become zero
oh so my model is incorrect okay
so so basically you are saying both
situations
one is Wing one is draw they should
return two different numbers but in my
model they return the same number
uh but why is that
so you are saying so when they are the
same obviously this works out so let's
let's
let's format our code so okay
so let's copy that
you know you can format your code
I cannot do it in subwoofer mod but here
you can okay so here's easier to read
so um
so my model is incorrect so that will go
back to this code this code is the
essence
so let's review the model okay
you know I if I just think about it now
I'll probably find out
so you mod
you mod them
actually you don't need to mod each each
element
yeah you do the
you you do the difference then you mod
them you can add three to each I mean I
add two to each so you do the difference
and you mount them
so uh
but let's look at your your example
so you are saying three one we change it
to two zero
uh and then
mod 2.
uh
too much to is zero
what
oh yeah so you are right so I I kind of
figured out so what you have to do
is add three we we didn't add three so I
mean in this case add two
I think okay that's just my guess I'm
pretty I'm pretty sure because when you
do mod arithmetics
maybe maybe that's right so I don't know
let's just try it okay
Bennett
correct
okay now let's run it with a big input
who has a big input
so evaluate the big input
and now let's run this
same number
two
um
one two six four five same number no
oh yeah we didn't we didn't modify the
code did we
we are here
add to add to
so
okay split
then run that code
then
split
then run that code
yeah [ __ ]
it's just yeah let's just select all
right okay that works now let's get the
input
copy new buffer paste the input here
okay huge input minute
and now
now let's just copy this part
yeah
[ __ ] big numbers
one two six four five that doesn't
change nothing so
but uh so let's go back to your example
what's going on
to think
so
mod 2 2 mod 2 is 0.
0 mod 2. is also zero that's right
so two Z so zero minus zero is zero so
this is incorrect so my model is
incorrect
so
so yeah two two directions to go one is
figure out exactly why is it incorrect
where is the logic
that's incorrect that's One Direction
figure out exactly
where the logic is wrong
the other direction is simply just guess
walk trial and arrow I kind of you know
I kind of know
because all you have to do is
um you know instead of that
you just do
y minus X
mod okay mod Y minus X smart two
okay
um
that will probably be walk
let's just run it and see what happens
uh
21 that's not correct oh [ __ ]
oh God this little problem [ __ ] [ __ ]
that's supposed to be 15 a one six eight
one six so we got a seven here
seven means this one is wrong yeah [ __ ]
okay we have to rework we have to
think about this
okay we have to think about this okay so
I'm going to think about this
X and Y
which is in our case Zero
one two
zero one two
so what you can do is
so you who you all you have to do is
first two
first two for the Y
plus two for the Y
and
so
when you lose you get zero okay when you
lose you get zero so if we do this
X and Y
you know here that's the part where
that's the part where we need to fix you
know either that that or that
of that
so
x minus
okay so let's add let's not add two
because that's gonna be the same anyway
you know you know you mod 2 plus 2
doesn't matter so this here is you is
where you need to add two okay evaluate
it
I don't know exactly the logic yet but
um
no so the
so maybe you know you don't need to
press one now okay
yeah this is your own fat [ __ ] it
forget the problem
so we need to go back to where is our
other code for the model here
okay
here is the model
so let's try it again
so
so in your example three one which is 2
so that's two zero so this is wrong
so this this is wrong
yeah you are right
so 2 0
zero is Rock
2 is Caesar so rock beats Caesar so we
should have
wait we got the god
here is X x minus y
c y minus X
got
zero the same
if you look at this part
x minus my
okay so you really need to think about
this
so y minus X Y minus X
0 is when you lose
Okay so
zero one two
oh yeah so we need two first one don't
we
let's just try it again
now
so the answer should be 15.
a16
this tricky [ __ ] you know they gave an
example where
you know
where a different input
uh even if your algorithm is wrong you
you still arrived at the correct answer
okay so actually so you know
you really need to think about the
problem so
what do you think about the problem so
x y z x y z
mod
so here is our table
okay
so here is a table here is a key to find
out what's going on let's let's make a
copy
and the
so you don't really need to mod it here
because you see the first two row is
always the same zero zero zero zero zero
one oh wait here's the difference
what what
zero one two so when it's zero two
okay so you yeah so you don't want you
definitely don't want to mod each
you want to
take their difference
name plus two they mod okay let's try
that
so first of all here's the old result
the new result is going to be
okay so you don't want
you want to x minus
y minus X
Plus 2.
okay
then U mod 2. so that you don't get
negative numbers
so the output will be zero
one or two okay
so let's try it
zero
wait
there should be three outputs
oh God this is so tricky
there should be three outputs so in this
case we only have two possible outputs
zero and one therefore it's not correct
so when is the secret you you need to
add three I think
God modular arithmetics
the result should be three possible
results so this is only
this is also wrong
so from 0 to 2 so X is zero one or two
why why is also zero one or two
and uh
okay and uh
[Music]
oh God
why why do we just have
[Music]
no comments probably zero watching now
anyone still watching what do you say
probably
you are coding it
[Music]
so
um
so again I think it would be better if
we
do this again you know
actually tabulate
[Music]
oh two won't be up but
oh so we actually we should mod three
right God the you know
that's right
let's see let's see our old result
no our old result has three possible
outcomes zero one and negative one
so actually
oh God
that's
that's let's go back to the mod
what's your first comment
oh Mark three okay
that's right so you are saying we need
to mod three
okay that's okay you got the correct
answer already
[Laughter]
let's just see there it is okay
you are probably right
tired of this problem
so here yeah Mark three you don't need
to add one
so let's copy it
and let's run
uh language and it's open new one paste
it there run it
five seven three fifteen
okay
it's kind of right but the solution is
correct but
the numbers are different
what a headache
you know
all this guessing
is no good I really need to think about
modular arithmetics
so let's use this notation so
possible number is zero
mod 2 let's see
zero mod 2 equals to
zero okay
one mod two is one
two mod two is zero so that's no good
let's try mod three
um actually so it's easier it's so much
easier if we
okay let's do that
very embarrassing problem so Mark 3 is
the correct Behavior
that's right I forgot of course
obviously zero one two
three possible numbers you want to mark
three okay now once you mod three mod
three is the correct
answer okay so all these confusing [ __ ]
Mark 2 is not correct answer so you want
to mod three okay so now you know you
want to mod three
so
do you need to mod individual item or
not you know I think you are probably
right you already give you already gave
the answer
multiply by 3 assumes that loss is zero
draw is
One Wing is two
that's right that's what we did here
right
so anyway so the first question you know
I want to know is do we need to mod each
number individually
uh no because first of all it should be
three not two okay
second secondly
you don't need to do it
zero one two Mark three is still the
same so you don't need this smart X
smart y okay so let's just
take them out
okay so the outcome
the outcome so
so why
minus X
so you here let's add three so Y at
three then minus X then
mod 3.
then
you should have
so we have to try that
okay so like again you are probably
right and you got you know I got the
win last thing wrong loss is two
okay okay you are probably right
so
yeah okay I get I see what you are
saying you know you are probably right
but for me to
come out you know to do the correct code
I have to think
I have to think myself so anyway
Bros so yeah so this is uh God tedious
so here let's try let's try the code
here
so
um
so you don't need to mod individual
number
instead you just um
let's see give an extra number here
okay
so here
let's see what happens okay
foreign
so here
what is this three what
oh okay uh table form
so zero zero zero okay zero one
one
this is the wing okay
this is a win zero one one this is a win
zero two two so two is loose
you are correct okay
and then
two is loose one zero two that's loose
one one zero let's draw
one two one one means win so one is wing
lose is 2.
so basically you need to in order to
make them the right order you have to
cycle it
so you have to cycle it so what you can
do is just add one something like that
and see
add one in mod again so lose add one two
add Y is three three more three is zero
that's correct so so thank you
so we all we have to do is
um
add one in mod okay so basically what we
have to do is here so let's Okay and
write a new one
add one mod three again okay
I think
zero zero one
let's draw
0 1 0 1 is win two
zero two Let's Lose 0.
when you lose you got zero so no score
that's right
one zero means you lose so zero again
one one is a draw so one
one is one so one is draw so that is the
correct
solution
mod twice [ __ ] [ __ ]
so here
that is the correct solution comment
that out
it's an outcome okay
so I'll come so so now you don't even
need a variable outcome anymore
because it's just one
you know so actually so this becomes
much simpler
that's just that
that function
with a pen
okay so now let's let's try it
copy or copy your
new buffer paste it computed
there it is eight six eight one six
eight one six and result is 15 correct
what the [ __ ]
now let's get the
the big input okay
so
copy that new buffer paste and uh
xava mod and remove this [ __ ]
and remove the input
get the new input here
paste it here that's our code okay
select all
back to Wolfram language let's open a
new one paste it compute it
back pain I need to now walk back and
forth
okay so now let's go to the bottom here
is a result I'm just going to copy it
and just challenge the [ __ ]
paste
submit to use
no that's a great answer you you are one
code star cursor to collection enough
star fruit [ __ ]
that's two hours of coding two hours and
what
one two three two hours almost three
hours okay let's continue to part two
the [ __ ] Advent of Coach [ __ ]
uh the L finishes helping with the tent
and sneaks back over to you
anyway the second column says how the
round needs to end
X means you need to lose y means you
need to end the round in a draw and Z
means you need to win good luck
right so it changes changes the meaning
the total score is still calculated in
the same way but now you need to figure
out what shape
to choose so the round ends as indicated
now now God
okay I think it's an interesting problem
events of code quality programming
problem and
yeah
okay thank you guys for watching
I don't know if this is good video
probably very shitty
ah and uh that's it for today
close to three hours I think
bye guys and thank you Hefty buffer
Hefty buffer who are you
okay who else is saying things he said
you know much time referred me to the
new website yeah that's you know
laughs
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
shutting down I'm gonna clean up and
shut down okay
so here's the input go to the talk show
page
here's the input I'm just going to talk
show page and create a page that says
input okay
you just just save this
okay don't not in temp
here paste it save
the event of code
to
input okay something like that save it
drop to diet
add
underscore instead of space low line to
it then modify the buffer
change the file name add the text okay
commit open it that's correct copy the
file path close it close it paste the
file path linkify linkify and now let's
try to open it again on oh
open and again that's correct that's so
that's the input now go back to our code
here
now this input is too long let's
let's get back to the original input
Okay so
so today's fruit it finally is just one
this simple
uh computation this simple function does
it okay
and uh yeah this simple this is a
solution okay it takes a while and
that's only part one we haven't done
part two yet
uh sad and this part you know lots of
nesting because Wolfram language is like
lisp and but you don't have to write all
this nesting so we can do a lot clean up
but uh
okay good close
yeah so uh oh yeah so we need to clean
up this okay here is the
Hefty buffers comment
uh fantastic Hefty buffer
um
so I have tip of a great suggestion
solve the problem and here is like
exploration about the mod you know
finally you know you have to so
I'm just mumbling okay so when you do
lots of programming
oftentimes trial and error doesn't get
too far
so when you do several trials and errors
you find you still you know that happens
to me a lot
like you find you you you think the
answer is right there so all you have to
do is just change something hello George
it's been you know I've been coding this
for the past three hours I'm about to
shut down so when you we you know when
you think the answer is right there but
you haven't thoroughly thought out about
the logic
some programming problems are like like
that in real life so but you think the
answer is right there so maybe you just
add one or change the loop you know
limit you know add y minus one something
and
sometimes you still get wrong answers
and you struggle for hours
and eventually finally you are forced to
really really think about your logic
you know
then you realize exactly what needs to
be you know I think mod is a good
example because I do have uh
from past experience that happened
so you know
yeah okay so that's that's so here's a
test code
let's copy that and to talk show let's
add a wolf
so we are shutting down
and here is by the way so George here is
the Wolfram language solution so let's
pop it back
let's syntax color it
and show in browser
on a second syntax color the whole thing
showing browser so here is today's talk
show we are trying to do
Advent of code problem number two after
three hours with Hefty buffers help we
solved it uh and uh
here is a result in Wolfram language
and during these three hours we
you know the first 40 minutes I was
talking about something else about
programming languages but then
here's uh
you know uh notes when we think about
the problem
so we have several notes uh eventually
we got it right
and that's only first part of the
problem there's also there's the second
part
second part
well that's a lot that's gonna be more
thinking to do so
but anyway so now we have this code
that's a solution what I want to do is I
want to you know why not I want to just
I want to
uh elegantify this code so to you know
this is wolfam language
so I can
make it more elegant okay let's see
actually in that case there's not much
we can do that's that's it
yeah
there's no
elegant vacation you know you can make
it one line
but
um
yeah uh you can replace the map by a
shortcut syntax but that's
that doesn't do much okay and uh
okay so let's not do that then
then about the modular arithmetics we
can also
go back to
one based
thing yeah so instead of 0 1 2 we can go
back to one two three
and that means we'll change something
here
you know more thinking but let's not do
that
so okay so here is a result bye guys
yeah so let's remove the this remove
why why is it more
what
yeah tired three hours bye