good morning welcome to another episode
of talk-show We Need to Talk and there
are a lot to talk about so let me show
you what I'm gonna talk about today's
topics so let's go to I'm just going to
give you show you what we gonna talk
about we are going to talk about
JavaScript string problem and so and I'm
going to explain you know what is the
problem and what is you know JavaScript
what does it mean to have a code unit
you know what does code point mean it's
related to unicode then we are going to
talk about category theory for you has
girlfriends but actually I'm going to
talk about something related to
mathematical logic the branch the math
logic branch which is about related to
proof theory model theory
category theory magic you know symbolic
magic predicate logic first-order logic
and you know for example let me show you
some Wikipedia articles so modal logic
so this is modal logic it's magnify
magnify so we have modal logic good
morning Isaak hoorah
so we have model logic we have links
from theorem we have yeah load load load
we have first-order logic we have
interpretation of logic which which is
which means a model when we say
something well you know I'll do some
explanation a little bit because I'm not
really qualified to teach this subject
and then we have standard model of
arithmetic now that's too advanced I
don't understand so I'm gonna talk about
these few things okay
and if you are new here the format is we
got three people watching all right yay
so the format is you ask I talk okay and
right now I'm going to drink this coffee
you know I'm so I'm gonna drink this
this is cheap coffee you know it looks
like Starbucks see this is $1.00 in
Dollar Tree store so we're gonna talk
about JavaScript and some math and some
stuff stuff and stuff that's what I'm
gonna talk about break the loop
good evening great to see you so break
loose break the loop sighs what do you
think of the price you got on Twitter
about Unicode in JavaScript yeah that's
the topic I'm going to talk about so
let's begin but as usual I am going to
digress I'm going to show you this for
two minutes okay now this is a castle
home you know this this is this is real
this is not toys you know you got this
like Disney style castles you got
hundreds of them where are they they are
at this modern modern new mutiny in
Turkey so apparently some real estate or
some you know some rich people they
build this bunch of castles castle homes
you know homes in a style of a castle
and they want people to buy but for some
reason the market is down or the economy
turned down and so they became a ghost
town so you have all these castles
hundreds of them and nobody's living
there so I mean if you search the web
you know Moodle root turkey castle you
know gotta read that you'll find more
information in fact today they are there
are so many there are so many photos you
know like all the website they want you
they want
want your money they want ad money you
know they want you to visit so they are
turns of website you know have having
beautiful photos of these architectural
stuff and by the way as you know this is
part of my architectural beauties
website which is part of the art
Startalk okay this is my local copy so I
started to collect these for example the
first one is written around 2006 so
that's like 15 years ago and you know
because they are beautiful by the way
you know back in 2006 you don't have
that much websites you know Wikipedia
just began like three years ago and you
know and it's in its infancy you know as
we say this is not much anything so I
began this to collect this architecture
of photos beautiful architectures you
know and look at this one it's
spectacular you know it looks like a
dream from science fiction you know but
this is this one is actually India
conscious River against River I don't
know how do you pronounce it but in
India you know it's so so it's beautiful
you know the world is huge you know you
know since today in our digital age we
begin to see so many things I mean yeah
wow that's a no topic so like like we
can see everywhere in the world like you
know you go to Google Earth you can see
almost just about every city streets
photos you know billions upon billions
of photos good evening so that's a
digression and let us get back to
JavaScript shall we is it good
anyone everyone good three people
watching okay three people three is
lucky number so let's close these Sal
talk show that's right let's open that
now let's so let's talk about the
JavaScript problem
sheis
so how is it going to break the loop so
you did study Java of our language I
don't like so you you you you did so
let's talk about JavaScript okay Isaac s
activist programming JavaScript I don't
think you do right okay let's talk about
JavaScript so what is the JavaScript
issue now look at this now just look I'm
going to demo okay let's go to Emacs so
let's open a new buffer and save this
file as X X dot J s so it's a temp file
and let me show you what's the issue
with JavaScript okay it's it's it's kind
of surprising issue okay since I'm using
Emacs let me start sauce start command
log mod okay so you can see all my
software keys commands in this window so
I'm going to so go to JavaScript so
javascript mod console log print and
make a string and let's see what smile
you know okay let's go to a brief I
forgot what's my op read further and
that character okay there it is
horror cat face no well let's for a
change let's use this one no no I want
to use the clown okay cow okay you see a
cow hold on second magnify you see which
so we got the clown character and let's
say what is the length okay wait I'm
sorry but the clown character is really
just too big I mean too complicated to
see well so let's switch back to the
crying with tears of joy so Isaac Isaac
sighs what do you think about freedom
proprietary software I think it's good
yeah you know yeah because mostly
because I think open source has become a
ideology and bad one so you know I mean
you I mean you've been here I mean you
guys know I talked about this quite a
lot so I mean today we got lots of other
topics so anyway so let me read some
comments
I see crying with crying crying with the
tears of joy it's the best
hey King herring I haven't seen you
before good morning good evening oh are
you are you from Germany your name
reminds me of from German because I
think German names got this her
something so anyway let me show you let
me let us go back to JavaScript so you
have this character you know you know
okay
tears of joy okay and you sure you want
to see how many characters are there so
let's run the program doin it now you
see the result is - how idiotic so let's
see you know equals to two it returns
true you can see that true so this is
what I mean by JavaScript problem okay
this is like very you know very stupid
you know like as a programmer every day
we you know we we work as a programmer
right and you encounter all these hacks
and problems and so on and you know
every day you you spend time to debug
and then you have a bunch of crazy
things patterns and [ __ ] like that
agile you know hoodoos of programming in
UNIX philosophy ok I hate the [ __ ]
UNIX philosophy you know those are
Buddhist this is this is you see this is
one example you see if you got this
voodoo but why does it happen
okay well it's complicated but we're
gonna explain so this is a problem okay
let me show you some other examples then
we so here are some other examples okay
so let's go hold on a second let me
shrink this this is too big we don't
want it to be okay that's good so let's
do that paste paste so we have that
let's put it here and let's put it here
okay now let's run this all this returns
true so basically now I have a string
and I want to use the method pad start
meaning like I want to pad X in front of
it and I want the total length of the
string to be two so I'm expecting X
smiley but instead it returns just
smiley why because the this smiley
character is already has a length of two
now here's another example we take a
slice you know basically we want a
substring of this string and so
substring from 0 to 1 which should give
us you know that character however it's
not equals to that character because you
know because for example it's let's do
this let's see what it returns you see
you got this you got this this none
character this you know half-assed
patched character so this is what I mean
by JavaScript string problem so in fact
all stream methods in JavaScript have
this problem you know this is really a
serious problem I mean it's incredible
that it's like you know if you are a
programmer you know you think why have
we searched have this extreme complexity
is it idiot idiotic totally stupid it's
it this kind of situation permeates
throughout the country
programming industry technology you know
UNIX the unities was the [ __ ] ok UNIX
and Linux permeates throughout the
industry what do almost every technology
you know UNIX web tab especially web web
tab
you know JavaScript dome technologies
you know there it's like all these kind
of stupidities and we have to endure it
that's that's our job you know that that
is our job
so ok let me let me just talk about this
let me not digress too much finish this
one discussion ok let me read a comment
a little bit do you know about Terry
Davis yes someone asked what about that
and actually I talked about that two
weeks ago something like that so he's
kind of he's got he's got schizophrenia
meaning that he see illusions you know
he see things that's not there he hear
things so he's got anyway I talked about
that the other day I'm a Zek American oh
okay cool so break the loop says he said
we a burg of Unicode in JavaScript no
it's not a bug okay let me explain
oh you interviewed David Terry Davis Oh
to tell us the story but okay let me let
me put focus let me focus on finishing
talking about the JavaScript then you
know if you have a comment about
JavaScript then I'll talk about that
other comments I'll look at you know
after I finish talking about JavaScript
so anyway so JavaScript you got these
problems so why does it have this
problem it's it's not really a bug but
actually it's fairly complicated it has
to do with the history of unicode the
history of adoption of unicode in
programming languages and technical
details of unicode encoding okay so let
me explain a little bit
so first of all let me the problem you
can understand you can see the problem
this problem you know when you have a
string of single character but it
actually has a link through lengths of
two that is a problem and this happens
for all stream functions in JavaScript
yes
so it means whenever you want and and
this this is a problem only when your
string contains a character that that
that is emoji or or whose code o or your
string contains a character whose
Unicode code point is beyond 2 to the
16th power I'm going to explain them but
anyway so the the simply put you have
problems with all string functions in
JavaScript only unexpected results
wherever you have an emoji okay that is
a problem now let me explain why this
happens okay let me let me just answer
that quickly the reason it happens is
because JavaScript string you know when
we see a string for example ABCD you
know we think you know it's just a
sequence of characters right but
technically you know it was technically
the definite actual definition what it
means is a bit complex because what do
you mean by character you know what do
you mean what is the character if you
use a pen to write ABC obviously you
know you know what is a character but
once you use a computer it's hard to say
what exactly is a character so so so so
they meet so so anyway the the the
reason this job this problem happens in
JavaScript is Java is because JavaScript
string is actually technically defined
as a sequence of 16-bit code units okay
so it's called code unit
so each character you see here is
considered it's called a cold unit it is
actually so what it actually is is
actually just sixteen bits you know
binary number six sixteen of them so so
so what so why is this smiley has length
of two that is because this character
unicode character when it is encoded it
actually has 32 bits so so you know 216
code units so so that is actually
considered considered to unique units
you know so that is why you know this
smiley length is two and and in for the
same reason all the stream method does
not work as you expected okay so so that
is a reason now let me explain about
unicode so
okay so so so you're a code code unit so
okay let me go in detail them about this
JavaScript problem okay
so to understand it in detail you have
to understand JavaScript string is a
sequence of 16-bit values that is a
technical definition of a element in a
JavaScript stream okay so each element
is actually 16 bits
values and so when you use the index for
example when you use an index of a
string for example when you do slice
index of a string the index actually
means you know each of the 16 bit values
it does not mean a character so what so
what that so you know on this page I
give the detailed explanation but so
basically let me just kind of go over it
so Java string string and character
based on Unicode standards version 5.1
or later okay today the current version
is a Unicode 12 I think 11
yeah Unicode 12 I think now each Unicode
now each Unicode character from the
Unicode standard you know each unicode
character has an ID integer ID code code
point okay so this is an important
concept so each character has a ID
that's called code point now Unicode
specifies specify several encoding
standards
the two most popular ones are utf-8 and
utf-16 so what does the encoding mean
encoding means you want to turn a
character into a sequence of binary bits
that's what encoding means of course
there are many ways to do that for
example you can say you know the
character a you can say you know it it
should be encoded as one
one zero zero one one for example you
know it's kind of arbitrary but so but
there are some sent standardized way you
know encoding to turn a character into a
sequence of one and zeros that's what
encoding means so they are the most two
and two most popular ones defined by
Unicode is utf-8 and utf-16 okay now
let's talk about utf-16 because that is
what javascript uses to encode
characters into bits in JavaScript
string okay now what now so when you
have a string in JavaScript it takes
each character and converted to 16 you
know sequence of bits by utf-16 encoding
now the utf-16 encoding the result of
one character in utf-16 encoding is
either 16 bits or or 32 32 bits okay one
of these two when when is a character
encoded into 16 bits and when is it
gonna be 32 bits this is how okay when
your character whose code point is is
less than 2 raised to 16 okay when your
characters code point code point is less
than 2 raised to 16 then it's encoding
in utf-16 is 16 bits okay when a
character whose code point you know the
integer ID is greater or equal to 2
raised to the 16th power then that
characters encoding in utf-16 will be 32
bits
okay selling up in other words you know
Wow yeah so so that so that is what
happens so you so so now let's talk
about JavaScript strings code unit so
what does a code unit mean
so first of all you take you know you
you you are given a stream you take each
character you convert it to UTF you know
you take all the characters converted to
utf-16 encoding now some characters will
have 16 bits some will have 32 bits if
that character is you know the code
point is beyond 16 bits you know so so
so you end up with a secret sequence of
bits you know you know once and zeros
then for every 16 bit you consider them
as one unit called code unit okay so the
first index of string will be the first
16 bits the second you know index index
2 will mean the the second 16 bits you
know and so on so that means for some
characters such as this smiley which
actually has a takes two code units to
encode so that means you know this
character will not correspond to the
index javascript stream so that that is
why when you say you know the this
smiley you know length will be equal to
2 because this character actually has
the encoding is is 32 bits so it has two
code units so that is why okay that is
why now on this page I explain in detail
you can read okay let me read a comment
a little bit
well okay yeah let me be the common in
answer the questions so generously
called Unicode encoding is the worst of
both words English in okay what wish
okay let me answer the question about
surrogate code points Wow big they don't
say surrogate code point they say the
surrogate pay us okay no no man asked
about surrogate pay us now in Unicode
there's a concept of surrogate pairs so
what does that mean
so remember we talked about in utf-16
encoding some characters is will have 32
bits you know become 32 you know once
and zeros so so these 32 ones and zeroes
so we have two code units you know 16
bits each now these particular 16 bits
is called a surrogate pair you know it's
one pair because these two 16 bits these
two code units makes up actually one
character so so why is it why is it
called surrogate pair I mean first of
all it's a pair because it takes two
code units to make up one character to
encode one character and surrogate just
means it kind of means they are together
but but why does this happen okay
why does some characters needs to 16
bits well because you because remember
the characters that become 32 32 bits
require 32 bits in a utf-16 encoding
those characters whose code point the
point is beyond 16 bits you know to 2
raised to 16 so obviously you know you
are you know if you only have 16 bits
that's enough that's not enough to
encode you know more than 16 bits of
characters
so therefore they they created this
method you know to encode characters you
know to encode more characters that is
why some character will be 32 bits you
know and those characters are the
characters whose code point is larger or
equal to 2 raised to 16 so that that is
what surrogate pair is you know
surrogate pair basically refers to this
any of these 32 bits 32 bits you know
basically basically two code unit big
sequence that corresponds through those
characters that whose code point is
beyond beyond 16 bits and also let me
emphasize this this so the surrogate
payer notion only happens in utf-16 in
encoding it does not happen elsewhere
okay now remember encoding is a process
to turn a character into binary sequence
and Unicode defines three of them you
have utf-8 you have utf-16 you have
utf-32 now utf-32 is the simplest of
them all every character it will become
32 bits you know and that's it so every
character we have the same number of
bits when it is encoded it's the most
simple one but however the problem I
mean that disadvantage is that it takes
you know lots of space it takes more
disk space it takes more memory to you
know process it so I mean each of this
encoding utf-8 utf-16 utf-32 has
advantages and disadvantages so it so
happens that utf-16 is used for
JavaScript and as well for Java and
c-sharp and microsoft windows file
system and also in max HFS+ file system
I think so anyway so so so that's about
encoding that's about you know utf-16
encoding that's about surrogate pair now
surrogate pair the notion only happens
in utf-16 that's a good thing to
remember okay that's good thing to know
it just refers to the the code sequence
that's from a character whose code point
is beyond 16 bits so so so that's what
surrogate pairs means so um okay so what
we're gonna talk about so let me talk
about so why unicode 16 I mean why
utf-16 you see this so so yeah first of
all let's talk about utf-16 a little bit
so which encoding to choose you know
today it's it's basically utf-8 is the
most popular it's the most widely used
and you know it's used by like 94% of
the web worldwide and basically all web
technologies they you know the the
community today the industry you know
the web programming community the
standard so you know HTTP they they they
converged into using utf-8 as the you
know recommend they all recommend utf-8
so you TAS speaking becoming the most
popular but as we know technology does
not happen I mean it's not you know back
then in 1995 when JavaScript was created
utf-8 was not there yet I mean it it may
have already been invented but it's not
ready you know it's like when you have a
new technology for example I created it
new language okay people are not sure
you know they they will back you up
unless everyone you know all the big
companies realizes ok this is not really
reliable you know we we want to use it
you know otherwise when something is new
people are not sure you know we don't
know maybe that that take we all die
you know Unicode is actually one of the
case you know back in 1990 for example
we don't know you know nobody knows this
if Unicode is going to survive you know
over the past you know technology over
the history of technology lots of
technology come and go you know Pro like
Pro is dead to make almost so so at the
time
you really don't know if you know you TF
you know Unicode we should you know it's
like still a question oh and also it's a
question you know where the JavaScript
will survive you know who knows like
this scape just one day said oh we
created JavaScript you know this is
gonna help you for the designers for
interactive dynamic you know HTML and so
on but everyone is not sure you know
Mike Rizzo is not sure they have to make
a decision you know that you know every
big companies they are fighting all the
time right like Apple Facebook today you
know Microsoft you know Google you know
all the big corporations they are
fighting about technology they want
everyone to use their own so it's a
situation when there's a new technology
nobody is you know you have to see
whether it survives or not you know so
so anyway when JavaScript began around
1995 and also Java they began about the
same time Java is a bit earlier and at
that time the common thought is that UTF
unicode will be popular you know único
is already widely accepted but but
however you utf-8 is is almost not on a
sing yet okay you know utf-8 doesn't
come
it came later in a beginning there's
utf-16 and utf-32 okay they are just
these two so back then at a time you
know utf-32 will take lots you know like
two times so four times
disk space so people are not sure about
that you know you know so with so
obviously people are thinking utf-16 is
a right choice you know
because remember back then internet just
began this is 1995 Internet you know
there's only few hundred websites
something like that and you know so and
and most people are using ASCII like
most people have no idea what the heck
is Unicode you know and and it's not
common to see you know other languages
because there's no internet yet I mean
it just began you know so USA lives in
USA Germany is you know lives in
Germany's you know home buh buh Japanese
in Japan Superboy like there's not much
communication yet he's except in
printing like newspapers you have to
ship it you know fax you know so back
then we are most people you know people
are still using there people are just
beginning to start to use new Unicode
and most people are just no ASCII you
know which is 8 bits so to most people
you know you know we think you know 16
is oh my god now we have 16 bits
that's plenty that's like enough enough
until Kingdom Come so everyone just
adopted utf-16 that is the original
history okay that's that that that is
how utf-16 became in so many standard
systems but not until later on until
like you know 2005 or later people begin
to realize you know 16 bits is not
enough to encode you know other words
languages and so on so so
and utf-8 is easy
interesting story by itself utf-8 is a
despise utf-8 okay I know because you
know you guys probably know you guys are
probably chanting for utf-8 because it
is from the UNIX you know if you love
UNIX or Linux you love utf-8 because
there's huge amount of propaganda you
know there was a you know utf-8 they
come up mostly because they became so
popular today mostly because backward
compatibility with ASCII okay
what does I mean meaning that if you
have a file and if you you know if you
do not have any Unicode you know non
ASCII character if you encoded in utf-8
and if you also encode the same file in
ut in ASCII the two files will be
identical so meaning that as long as you
don't have any Unicode characters you
know the strange Smiley's or whatever
you know it's compatible with ASCII you
know it's just it's the same encoding
us-ascii you know so utf-8 is ASCII
compatible and that was a big advantage
especially for for the UNIX fax in Linux
because you know other corporations Java
you know some Microsystems which is dead
today Samara systems Microsoft Apple
they you know there are corporations
they have money they make they sell
products they make money you know if
they products don't sell they die you
know there's no ideology you know they
have to sell it if people don't buy they
they disappear like some micro system
micro systems with their java so so
Apple and Microsoft and some ecosystems
and you know so they they want utf-8 you
know so they created but Linux you know
the ideology open source you don't have
resources you don't have people so so if
you want you know it's to support
Unicode
that means you have to almost rewrite oh
you're UNIX kernels you know you're
Linux Linux or UNIX kernels your patch
tours you know the bag of tours you have
to rewrite them all because because in
coding you know you cannot use ASCII
anymore so that is a serious problem
you know if utf-8 did not begin ok did
not gain alive then basically that Linux
may not be alive today you know did you
know that's kind of one possibility you
know so anyway so the Rob Pike and
Friends you know the UNIX people they
they they invented utf-8 and that's half
the problem and Linux and UNIX people
loved it because with utf-8 now to
create your you know Linux to bash or
the whole you know Linux package to
support Unicode it's not a huge task
anymore because it's compatible with
ASCII you know you you just patch a
little bit to support you know
characters that's you know so anyway
that's a story of utf-8 but anyway so
back to JavaScript but about utf-16 so
javascript strings are technically the
definition of a string is a sequence of
UTF is a sequence of sixteen bits called
core point
I mean code code unit code code unit
okay so each 16-bit is a code unit and
when when a character who's encoding in
utf-16 has more then has 32 bits then
you start to have this problem because
the index does not correspond to the
characters so that's you know okay so
that's a problem that is why Oh Chavez
so whenever you have a string and if
your string contains a character who's
you know code point is being
16-bits you have problems meaning that
all stream functions all stream methods
may break we break Europe will break you
know it's a serious problem can you
imagine you know programmers a good good
evening
am I so so that's a serious problem so
so I'm I'm very annoyed about this
problem okay so I asked you know
JavaScript started to have a standard
you know a new version every year since
2015 so there's this question in my mind
you know this is a serious heavy problem
you know because by the way it's not
just emoji that creates a problem be it
any character whose core point is beyond
16 bits have this problem now what kind
of character what characters that whose
code point more than 16 bits for okay so
almost all emoji has more than 16 bits
and also lots of Chinese characters like
where less frequently use cherry Chinese
characters and and any basically you
know there are thousands of them you
know so so this is a practical issue in
JavaScript because now when you have a
string first of all as a programmer you
know you do you write web applications
or whatever when you have a string you
you must have first of all be aware that
this is my string contains any
characters that's beyond 16 bits if no
if if if no then okay I don't have
nothing to worry about
you know I use string functions you know
but if it does contain a code you know a
character whose code point is beyond 16
bits then I got a problem I cannot use
all the building methods and functions I
have to kind of walk around you know you
you know imagine you have a language
where all string processes was
same functions which we you know which
is a call of the language is spoken so
every time you have a string you have to
know oh just my string
you know contains any particular
character that's a serious problem but
the programming [ __ ] idiots I cannot
imagine they don't you know know I like
I talked to my my years of programming
experience 20 years I talk to all these
programmers especially the UNIX and
Linux [ __ ] they almost always never
see the point the problems I see like
for example this is a sickness this
example about geometry to me it's like a
huge what you know a huge problem but
whenever you talk to industrial coders
especially the elite you know they talk
about UNIX philosophy and whatever
jargon so a pattern so you know the like
my interaction with them I always find
that they don't see whatever I find
either use a big problem and they don't
find it a problem for some reason ok ok
so anyway so in my mind this is a big
problem in JavaScript starting in 2015
they have a new version new standard
every year each year they add you know
little things you know they fix lots of
problems so in my mind what so what are
they going to do with this problem are
they going to fix it that is a big
question in my mind for a few years so I
yesterday I find finally I asked I asked
the guy Brendan Eich who created
JavaScript ok by the way javascript is
now the is there's a design committee
called tc39 ok so something like that
let's go back to ok so I asked the
Brendan Brendan Eich ok you can see the
Twitter tweeted [ __ ] so let's show you
the thread ok now on Twitter the threads
are disconnected but so anyway yesterday
I asked him the question and you know
people
finally I got answers and people start
to discuss it so you can see this is the
URL you can you can go there read it and
you can link to I mean you can let me
paste it here okay by the way Twitter
thread is not well connected because
they are much more posting than what you
see here this more than 10 so you have
to like you have to put focus on a
thread then for example this thread has
two answers but you can you can only see
what you have to click on that post then
you can see the other posts related to
that thread okay so anyway so so this is
not all you see but anyway so yesterday
I asked Brendan okay Brendan Eich who
created javascript in 1995 but however
by the way javascript is not today is
not like in his under his control you
know he basically I don't think he
actually has any control he can only
recommend and discuss basically you know
they have like nonprofit standard
committee called t t c13 i you see it if
you you know follow this thread you know
try to see all the posts because they
are like yeah twitter is got a problem
because it's hard to find all the posts
related to this thread any anyway so so
so anyway so I asked Brendan and Brent
although he is not controlling
JavaScript design but however he is
heavily participates in the process you
know because he's you know he's his
opinion people still respect so finally
and and and and he also linked to a
bunch of people in the comma in the
JavaScript design committee you know who
works at Google and so on and another
guy called fake unico
he's on Twitter he's actually one great
guy okay he knows you know I learned a
lot unicode from him you know this this
well let me show you the you know just
for fun
fake unicode okay this guy there's a
account called fake new unicode so I
know him on Twitter for like three years
by now and I have learned Unicode from
him you know many esoteric technical
details now he doesn't say you know his
hand oh is fake unicode but he doesn't
say what's his name oh you know who he
is or who he works for
but I'm guessing I get a sense that he
is actually working for the Unicode
consortium you know that's just my guess
you know maybe he doesn't want to tell
but anyway but but yeah he's a great guy
but anyway let's go back to so yeah he
you know he knows you know with many
esoteric details about Unicode and let
me show you the other guy who is on the
who is in the JavaScript Technical
Committee
his name is Matthew this this guy okay
matheus finance I came across this guy
before like five years ago but anyway
he's so so there's these threads and you
know they answered my questions so
finally so that what what is the answer
so my question is why is there any plan
for JavaScript to fix this string
problem it turns out no because they
want backward compatibility okay so you
know they just decided you know they're
gonna do nothing about it well they they
are aware of course it's a problem but -
for some reason okay - these industrial
people they they just you know they just
live live with it you know to me it's
like this is a [ __ ] for
we need to you know to do all things
possible to get it fixed but not to most
of these people's so so they know it of
course it's a problem but so their
solution is actually you know they have
some solutions in the works kind of that
that possibly will fix it okay not
certain yet we don't know but I mean if
you read the thread you'll see it's
called international segment segment
okay or international segmentation do
something like that you are see if you
read the thread which which is actually
not fixing the problem but it's a but we
might evolve into resolving this
eventually okay but anyway to me this is
I mean this is a serious problem
so I mean if they are ran out like right
now they don't have a plan to fix this
so what does that mean that means for
forever you know you know whenever you
know they are how many people code
JavaScript millions right because
javascript is like almost the number one
most popular language today so for these
millions and billions of software
applications websites every time you use
a string you have this problem now how
you know how idiotic is that you know I
cannot possibly imagine that people will
be will say oh that that's okay that's
no problem you know I don't care what
you you know I don't care what is the
issue you have to like you have to fix
it even even if there is no solution
other than you know break backward
compatibility
anyway that's so I saw that I think that
concludes my explanation of the
JavaScript string problem and by the way
this problem happens also as I learned
learned from one of this guy it also
happens in Java and it also happens in
c-sharp now if you look at this
code this code is Java okay so have the
same problem you know you have a smiley
and the length is two and also this
example also shows that a method you
know a string method is also broken just
like JavaScript and here is an example
from c-sharp language the same problem
so you know so to me so I have lots of
problems with the programmers you know
many of them call me a troll now this is
one example where you can see a
difference okay I cannot you know it's
just a difference of the way I see
things you know I cannot I mean these
things are not except acceptable to me
doesn't matter
I don't well I mean of course I
understand there's a historical context
you know I just explained the history of
JavaScript and Unicode so so that is how
we have the situation today and you know
backward compatibility is also very
important in fact almost critical so I
do understand you know I do understand
why JavaScript you know stream methods
are broken like that but however however
this is like not acceptable not
acceptable to me like these people I
mean today's JavaScript standard they
are thinking we're gonna just live with
this forever I mean that's impossible
but anyway brandade you know they they
do have logics you know they give their
reasons you know what either you know we
for example brendan has said no either
like he said him he mentioned that we
have two choices one break or backward
combat compatibility okay meaning that
if you change the JavaScript then all
the website in history will be broken
including all those printed out on DVDs
or CDs you know in 1990s and 2000's now
that's obviously not you know that's
actually very
because when you break things like that
it it's it's also it has critical
consequences because that's similar to
erasing a big chunk of history too
because lots of things rely on it so
yeah I understand so so one way is break
backward compatibility the other way is
just to create new features so as time
move forward we use the new features now
so they obviously they decided decided
to use you know just stick with new
features however to fix this or this
tree method problem meaning that either
we have to create a copy you know of all
the stream functions like there are 30
of them ok let's go to my JavaScript
tutorial ok let's go to JavaScript
object reference and this go to string
prototype so here's a tutorial I mean
this is a reference or stream prototype
so this shows all the string methods you
know they are like they are like 30
string methods so so if we want to add
new features that means we make a copy a
new version of each of the string method
you know and that is also you know
fairly ugly right
so another option you know I have
thought about is that we create a new
language directive for example if you
call JavaScript you know that we have
this use strict that's a string just use
strict and if you have that in your
JavaScript code that means the compiler
will treat treat your JavaScript in a
different way considering it as kind of
a new language not backward-compatible
they created you strict around 2000 2000
I think they created that I forgot when
2008 or something but anyway they didn't
is it they did not do a very good job
so even have you even if you have used
strict it doesn't change much except
some of the very bad things about
JavaScript so anyway my vision okay my
idea of solution is we create a new
directory for example you strict mm you
know to 0 to 0 that means you know in
2020 or 2019 we create a new language
kind of like backward incompatible that
fix all these issues so for all new
JavaScript code we can just say you know
use you know let's just say used to use
to 0 to 0 meaning but you know so if we
do this you can be backward compatible
but meanwhile it can also you know have
a more elegant code but for some reason
again these people you know these
industrial programmers including Brendan
Eich ok he they they they think this is
they think this creates more problems
and more complexity so therefore they
decided the JavaScript team you know the
future future team decided not you know
not to introduce any discord pragma or
code directive I think it's called
its technical technically called pragma
in JavaScript you know each anguish
cause this kind of thing differently
whimper oh it's called directive I think
in JavaScript is called pragma or
something so anyway they decided they
don't want to do that so okay so that is
the situation with a JavaScript that
that concludes my my my-my-my discussion
my talk about the JavaScript string
problem
okay in the comments please don't swear
okay I don't I mean I don't care if we
swear but however Google today you know
YouTube they are starting a heavy
censorship so if if you have if I if my
channel has you know swearing words
they're gonna ban you you know they are
going to bear my channel you know I
tried not to so so let me read the
comments and then let's see maybe we can
talk about the next topic now we've been
talking about for an hour maybe ten more
minutes
I think the technique now Auto all those
says Kyoto other says code unit can be
full Unicode no well no well the the the
turn code unit the jargon code unit it's
just a term that means sixteen bits in
the utf-16 encoding so so first of all
you have Unicode Unicode consortium okay
now his history is a little bit
complicated but but anyway we can think
of the Unicode consortium which is a
nonprofit they start the concept concept
of Unicode so that you know we can have
all the words languages Chinese Japanese
English
you know French owing one one kind of
standardized encoding so that's idea
Unicode they began in 1987 or something
like that so that's idea of Unicode so
Unicode began then then you have they
they also define encodings right there
so they defined utf-16 utf-32 in the
beginning so in the utf-16
encoding standard you know publication
they they define the jargon code unit
which means you know sixteen bits of you
know of a encoding so that's that's my
understanding of where the jargon code
unit came from now it had it may have
history before this but I'm not sure
about that but mostly today when you say
code unit you pretty much means the
utf-16 sixteen bits
okay you know I'm gonna you know I'm not
gonna answer every comments okay because
they're so me I think you're cemented
like daily Prague what is steady Prague
website normal says
okay I forgot what's a context okay even
with utf-8 things went down here so if
you if I did not answer a question oh I
have questions about your questions just
type it again I'll see it then I'll get
our answer okay so let me see the next
question
so Todd says good morning Todd Todd says
even with utf-8 things went downhill
after Unicode yeah Unicode has become in
my opinion the organization itself has
became somewhat corrupted you know
unicode today since around since about
let's say five years ago it has become
political itical issue why you know it's
strange it's just the technical standard
about characters encoding why is it
political because emoji emoji has become
a huge political issue because you know
some people they want skin colors you
know for you know they want skin colors
for everything then they want girls you
know they you know so you have like a
castle then people say oh but then you
have church you know emoji right then
people say oh no then you need a mosque
emoji to represent Islam okay then you
need then your of course then you need a
Buddha temple
emoji okay so it becomes a big political
issue of skin colors then they then they
becomes also part of it is gender you
know sex issue like if you have an emoji
of a face is it female or we say the
male okay that's a that's the question
so you cannot have you know if you have
a tenser you know a girl dancing you
know there's a emoji character called
dancing okay let me show you let me show
you the emoji characters okay
so for example if you have this emoji
character okay let me go to Chrome here
so you can see actually you can actually
see the pop up for example this is this
emoji okay it's called coded the name is
dancer now emoji or originated from
Japanese phone you know Jack mostly
Japanese girls back in 2002 or so you
know emoji came from emoticon you know
so well I'm not going to go into the
whole history history but anyway emoji
came from Japanese phone you know
Japanese you know girl teeny teenagers
they a used phone so you they want to
send pictures you know people smiling
dancing or eating Japanese food like
sushi you know let me show you food so
these are some of the original emojis
Japanese food let me magnify so in the
beginning you don't have all these
hamburgers you know bread you don't have
no of that it's mostly just these
Japanese here so you have these Japanese
rice cracker Japanese rice for sushi
you have Japanese fish cake you have
this Japanese bento which is kind of a
lunchbox you know so emoji or engineers
Japanese pictures you know food you know
icons used by teens on their phone
around through 2002 something like that
and different phone companies they use
different images so it became you know
it came to the Unicode consortium head
that we can unify it you know wouldn't
be nice if Unicode created a standard
you know code point for these images so
that each phone company don't have to
you know
convert the image into some bits and
transmitted and that bits come us
convert back to image and
and phone companies may not use the same
image for example sushi sushi on my
phone looks different than the sushi on
your phone you know so the Unicode card
idea you know they they can create a
code point for the emoji so they did
that so remember this is from Japan
okay this emoji or engine is from Japan
not in Japan they don't have whatever
[ __ ] your notion of American notions
they are different culture they don't
have your notion of your justice or what
it want whatever okay so in Japan they
have for example let me show you an
example of a derogatory thing emoji
originally from Japan that is about
Chinese this one okay this the emoji
name is men with gua prima okay so what
does I mean so you see this Chinese
character face okay
this face got this hat you may see the
head from Chinese TV drama or kung fu
movies sometimes you see it it's called
this hat is called Cuauhtemoc okay mommy
is a hat so what does crap he means what
he means is like watermelon okay
watermelon or cantaloupe you know it's
like a melon okay melon you cut it and
have you got this semi-spherical thing
and you put it on your head so that head
looks like that so in Chinese we recall
that go up Hema or you know melon hat
but you know it's it's not something we
we like to you know we like to associate
with you know it's it's you know it's
more like that's history of China okay
you know and especially its history in
an era where it's not we Chinese are not
proud of that because you know farming
innovations and Japanese invasions you
know the Qin Dynasty okay you have this
hat
but in Japan you know Japan had Japanese
war with China you know so anyway Japan
you know they created this emoji you
know they okay so you know yeah yeah we
don't we don't care much about you know
I mean anyway anyway Japanese you know
they created this emoji on their phone
so they did that so anyway the or engine
that's the engine so this this is one of
the first this for example this
character men with quite Pema is also
one of the first emoji it came from the
Japan all these others you see here are
new you know these fairies and wizards
and anyway so what I'm saying is that
okay so emoji so why is it became
political okay let me mention let me
explain so so let me show another okay
this tensor is also one of the original
emoji from Japan okay so you have a
dancer it's a girl dancing you know
invest red skirt you know it's like very
you know flame flaming it's like sexy
and also this character women with funny
years showing two girls you know with 20
years it's like Playboy Bunnies okay
it's nothing like what you see today
it's it's originally originally in Japan
it looks like to playboy girls you know
meaning sexy you know like doing crab
dancing stuff to women with too many
years that this one is also one of the
original Unicode characters from Japan
an emoji so but anyway so so look at
this tensor emoji now to the Western
political you know today like okay you
have a dancer but why should it be
female you know and so the white people
want to ask you know so we should have
you know you should be male 2 you know
because because this or that so they
created man dancing and and so for
example any character for example this
baby so so since 2005 also you
every year unicode added more emoji you
know for example now today we have
hamburger we have pizza
we have Western croissant you know
French croissant we have cheese eggs you
know all kind of western food then we
also added Chinese food Chinese
chopsticks and so on but before it's all
these are not there you just have the
Japanese basically these these these
ones you know you know about maybe you
know five or ten of them because that's
our internal you know Japanese teenagers
they use their phone you know they are
not thinking oh we must be fair we must
represent all the food in the world you
know they just want you know they show
sushi because sushi is I don't know you
know food that they eat often or
something like that right so anyway so
but to the Westerners you know so when
you have a baby emoji some of the people
are thinking oh but should the baby be
male or female
oh wait we need a baby with black color
skin mean the big baby with red color
skin and so on you know so so today it
becomes a very heavy emoji political
issue and for example you have this
picture you know men with women men and
women holding hands I am I don't know if
this in our internal Japanese emoji of I
don't remember but anyway let but to the
Westerners then it's you know their
thought is become oh oh but but but but
then we need men with men holding hands
then we we need women and women holding
hands and things like that so everyone
it becomes very political issue so so
that is why ok that is a situation and
in fact today we have come to the point
that the Unicode consortium they decided
they decided that all emoji they should
not by default associated with a
sex you know you cannot you know if you
have an emoji you cannot have you know
it's not supposed it cannot be either
male female it has to be like new
neutral for example for example look at
today's emoji okay um our Apple Mac OS
you know look at this emoji BAE it's
like almost all of them becomes so this
they don't look like men they don't like
they don't like they don't look like
women they don't look like a girl and
they don't look like old man they don't
like they all become this generic
extremely generic and and creepy thing
that's that's this social justice have
created you know they they they all
become this extremely creepy face and
look at this so so in the past to 2018 I
think 2017 or 2018 we added a bunch more
emoji so you have this more person you
know what wait what do you think of a
mermaid you know my person came from
mermaid mermaid is has long history you
know like two or three thousand years
ago from Greek mythology you know you
have mermaid and you know it's always
mermaid this you know you have you know
statues of mermaid you know that's
thousand or 2,000 years old but today
you know in a social justice era you
cannot you cannot have a mermaid because
then because that would be oh that would
be mythology or what whatever you know a
stereotype or whatever so so you have to
have a character that's you cannot have
mermen either you you have you have to
have a more person and look at this this
thing ugly extremely ugly thing what is
this you know mermen you know this not
like a man not like a boys you you have
this so and and then you have this elf
then this look at this genie
I mean does that reminds you of a genie
I mean genie
Jeanne's has Asian history from the
Middle East okay
now of course when you think of when we
think of Jeannie today we think of
Disney Disney's genie okay that's just
Americanized genie genie is a fictional
creature
you know mythology in Middle East
okay I'm not sure exactly what's a
ranger but it it it's not like you know
Disney's version but then you look at
you know this emoji version of genie on
Apple platform it's look it looks very
creepy it looks like nothing it looks
like a semis zombie it looks like a semi
boy and it looks like you know all this
becomes creepy things and this this
match okay anyway I think you get what
I'm saying that's that's a political
situation of Unicode and you know the
social justice people they are you know
they are doing these things all day
every day now okay no youyou do have a
different skin color you know like like
I mentioned Unicode has become so
corrupted and complex you have skin
color but to do that you basically you
add another character called variant now
you have like 16 of them 16 variant code
point or characters so if you place that
character Jason you know right after the
more person then you'll get the male or
female and also the I think there's the
social skin color so it's like anyway it
becomes very complex Unicode has to
become you know this political situation
and very complex so let me so I've been
talking too long I think
being okay I think that's it for I mean
that's about it so if you have more
questions as yet and we are done and we
are going to skip
the math the talk about logic model
theory and stuff so let me finish
answering the comments and that would be
a good talk today
so Norman ask ask
number ask thus direct indexing ever
makes sense for Unicode
I think you must process the entire
string to find all graphine clusters no
I think yes and no depending on what you
mean but okay so so I think what you are
asking is about more complicated problem
because well I'm not going to talk about
that but but I think but anyway let's so
if you let me point out for those of you
JavaScript so such for JavaScript int l
SE g m-e and t okay that is the new
proposal in javascript to find to find
the boundaries of graphemes
in unicode okay i think that that
relates to what you are asking normally
so you might check out this page you
know that that discuss that in detail
and also for for you know different
languages deal with the unicode problem
in different ways for example python 3
they created a way so that every stream
python 3 is just unicode characters you
know unicode code points that's it it's
not bits is not bytes if every element
in a string of python 3 is a unicode
code point or character ok that's how
Python 3 deal with the problem and which
I don't think is a good solution because
a lot you know they created lots of
problems I don't really know the details
but anyway they a lot of people don't
like it and by the way also let me
: which is my favorite favorite language
they solve the problem in another way
let me find the goal and my column page
so if you go to sorry : tutorial you can
see I discuss how : solves the problem
in this page
Oh dangerous you're asleep but soon ah
butcher
so color itself to this dream like my
roommate asked me to eat so grass off
this page solves the problem so in : :
soft steel with the stream problem and
Unicode in a different way different
from JavaScript different from Unicode
different from JavaScript
well don't want don't want don't want
lights that was different from
JavaScript and different from Python 3
okay so in : a string is a sequence of
bytes you know a thick string is a
sequence of 8 bits you know that's it
it's not about Unicode it's not about
characters it's simply your string in :
is sequence of bytes you know 8 bits so
so you know but how do you you know but
what if I have a smiley you know what
what if I have what if I have a emoji in
in your stream well you can still solve
the problem anyway I'm not going to
explain about that you can read my
website if you like to I kind of have to
go because my roommate is calling for me
so folks are stories and wolfram well I
I kind of heard up name I think it's a
great language but I don't have time to
learn it yeah I heard many people
totally in telling me so name is kind of
a language kind of like in the same
class s :
it's very fast very
for you can use it as a system
programming language but McGuire is also
elegant
I think the syntax is Python right it's
a python-based syntax but however it's
also typed just like Cola and very
efficient oh you know coding Emacs
that's another very interesting it's
Emacs is the most wonderful language
when it comes to Unicode but anyway I
gotta go so thank you guys for coming by
if you like to support me you know just
go to Holly blog okay any of my blog I
got patron you know PayPal you can
Amazon Cape Cod I appreciate that
okay thank you thank you guys for coming
it was a great talk today I'll see you
guys next time
if if you got a comment I didn't I
didn't answer
you know posting YouTube comments then I
see it and we talk about it next time
Thanks good night guys