hi I want to document what I eat as a
documentation of my life so um for the
past one year or two I've been you know
i' I've been for the past few years I've
been living on$ three a day and what do
I eat it's daily routine I prepared here
for you milk I always have milk in the
fridge so I buy this uh cotton and wow
that's milk usually um you know in my
whole life I drink on average every day
in my whole life about one cup a day at
least um and I always drink skin milk
when when I was a team I drink uh fat
milk you know but but since my 20s to to
few years ago to 40s I drink skin milk
uh but
um if I didn't see it enough you all
around 300 60
degrees so I've been drinking skin milk
but in the past few years two two years
or three I've been drinking uh fat milk
uh yeah fat milk full fat or or reduced
fat or skined you know I mean half skin
because that gave me more calorie per
dollar so yeah it's economic um and I've
be so in the past year I've been eating
um
muled
bread so this this is this bag and four
four piece of bread here see see is um
$1 it's not clear
but basically you know they they have
it's a local store they make bread every
day I guess and then but they have to
throw away after the day you know so
they put in a bag
um to sell it cheap
um yeah and so that's a piece of bread
and some sometimes there's more down it
so you just have to um be careful like
oh there there it is you see
right
here in oh no that's food coloring yeah
but anyway so I take this bag and
actually I think it's it's still good
it's still good oh my God you know when
when you were young uh your mom your
parents tell you
that
um you know they tell you to eat veggies
so you know you complain you are hungry
and they tell you to there's banana
there's veggies there's lots of food in
the fridge and you I don't want to eat
those yeah but then that means you are
not hungry which is true
uh how long I be okay which is true
because um because there's a degrees of
it you know like when you eat every you
know when you eat pizza let's say when
you eat pizza every day or you know you
have pizza or different things then
certain certain food you don't want to
eat because I don't want to eat it you
are hungry but you don't want to eat it
okay but then when you become poor um
Pizza is oh my God Pizza is Rich men's
food I haven't I haven't had pizza for
many years you know so it's like pizza
oh my God then for me you know I eat you
know I eat these kind of things
sometimes I get luxurious but today I
have a bag of potato this is this luxury
$4 a bag something like that um and uh
you know I eat oatmeal every day so I
have
here cricker oats oh this is amazing
this is the most the most healthy and
the calorie per dollar is the
most you Oats
oats oats you see delicious
oats yummy
yummy oh my God food
f o o d food edible and healthy oh my
God that's uh what could one ask for
more and
milk okay I think that'll be it for now
you know usually I talk nonstop because
I have so many things and I have to talk
fast because the information you know I
need to
but I need to be
short oh thank you for watching and uh
be sure to subscribe and uh subscribe
you know down there and uh and donate
don't forget