hello guys welcome to another episode
ofar talk show we are going to do Wam
language coding continue from yesterday
Advent of code 2023 day 14 part two take
four um if you are watching this
offline skip skip around and play at 1.5
speed minimum because I ramble a lot if
you are here say hi love to see your
comment comments
Okay so yesterday let's start coding so
yesterday we um ad Advent of code
2023 part two is fairly complicated
problem okay now there are people who
solve it in just like 10 minutes or so
you know they are this incredible people
uh they are code competitors they are
programming speed coding you know
competitors they focus on speed coding
so and it's quite
amazing um but usually they are
not you know in general they are not
great General uh programmers anyway so
we so this is yesterday and uh let me
let's um let me talk about let let me
show you what we're going to do today
okay so okay so today's talk show so go
back here so remove this um okay so
today's talk show and we're going to go
to
yesterday link here uh and we're going
to do let's see back to emac showing
browser so this is
yesterday we so we want yesterday's goal
is to write a command a function such
that the function
takes uh two things function takes a
function and takes a initial value and
the function will return the
periodic of the given
function when it is nested Okay so
yesterday it's about almost three hours
we
explained so we have
um you know we
discussed Mod Five you know mod a number
by five modular arithmetics this is a
function that has a
periodic of of
five
okay so you know give a value one it
returns a value give a value two it
returns another value and you know after
five five inputs it repeats so the
repetition the cycle is 0 one2 4 012 4 0
one2 4 okay if you give it a consecutive
SE sequence of integers as
input now that's a periodic of a
function by definition but what we want
is the periodicity of a function of
nesting a function so given a function f
you passing a value and you get the
output then you take the output and uh
pass that output to the function again
you Nest the function so you get a new
output you repeat this process and if
the output repeats you know 1 2 3 1 2 3
or 3 4 2 3 42 you know whatever it
repeats it's a cyclic so there's a so
the the nesting of the function is
cyclic so there's a periodic periodic is
a number of uh uh you know diff you know
the cycle the length of the
cycle in the tail of the list of the
output okay so that's a periodic of a
nesting function which is a different
concept from the periodic of a function
okay so we you know we kind of
discovered or refined into that concept
so that's a periodic of a of a a nested
sequence of a function
okay now is it possible for discret
function to have a different nesting
period for different initial value the
answer is yes
and yesterday we talked about how it
happens often in dynamical
systems and which relates to Chaos
Theory uh often known as Butterfly
Effect Butterfly Effect
means you know a
function such that given a initial value
it may become periodic you know when you
when you Nest it okay it become periodic
in into some kind of loop but however
you give
this initial value that's very very
close to the to the previous one you
know differ by
0.0000001 you know it's like a butterfly
flapping the winds somewhere in South
America or something then after 10 years
the result is very different so the
function you know when you n the
function the behavior is completely
different so that's called Butterfly
Effect uh it's kind of part of of Chaos
Theory which is part of the dynamical
systems that's a branch of
mathematics okay and yesterday we went
to we also talk about hell Stone
function which is the collapse
conjecture okay so here we Define the
collapse function if a you know a
function that's defined of integers if
the integer is even then divided by two
otherwise
multiply by 3 and + one so you got a
value then you feed the value back to
this function and re and repeat the
process see what happens so this
hellstone function or also known as
collat conjecture is unsolved the
conjecture is that the function will
always uh arrive at one you know for
whatever input so that's a conjecture
that's
uh unsolved right now so the hellstone
function is very interesting that is a
example of a nesting a function
where supposedly the periodic is uh uh I
think it's three because it always come
down to I believe 432 one something you
know we looked at yesterday so hellstone
numbers so that's the things we talked
about so but ultimately what we want is
to write a
function that's named um that's Nam
named get period okay actually it should
be named get nested period okay so let
me let's start to code okay so this
function uh let's copy it undo
wait let's start to code so yeah so we
copy the function delete it show today's
talk show paste it
here and uh let's pop it out let's start
to code so this is from yesterday so
ultimately what we want is we
want to find a function to define a
function uh here okay get period okay
that actually you should be named get
nesting period okay so let's rename it
replace get period by
get Nest period okay replace replace
replace replace replace so this is the
function we want to write so the
function takes a takes a function f then
takes a initial value F evaluated at the
initial
value then feed the output back to the
function and repeat so you Nest this
function and you want to see if the
function is cyclic you know periodic so
and you want to try a Max Nest number of
times because if it's not periodic
because you may not know because the
function may be periodic but the
periodic is 1 billion so you have to run
the function what nesting it one billion
times and even a billion times you can
still not be be sure that the function
is not periodic because the it could be
a huge number gab billion you know then
it repeats but you don't know so
computationally we have to say you know
uh a Max Nest so that you know we just
try this max number of times uh what's
going
on uh what so control we have I have
sticky keys on window okay so now yeah
so you give a Max period okay cancel
this um so far so good say hi if you are
here so we are trying to Define this
function and we yesterday we are very
close today we're going to finish it
okay now once we got this function
working then we go back to the original
problem of Advent of code 2023 day 14
part two
that's kind of a tricky uh problem you
know we'll see if it works out so we
want we need uh get nested Nest period
of a function okay so so but in order to
do right to write this function
yesterday we
explored that we found out we need a
function to such that given a list of
items let me show you here okay uh where
is it we want to write this function
find cyclic tail so this function take a
list given a list you want to find out
if the tail of the list is
repeated so so for example if 9 32 32
then it will return 32 because the 32 is
repeating uh if it's 9 32 321 one it'll
return one because that one is repeating
so
so this is the function we want to write
and we have the answer
yesterday um and the answer is that okay
so this is wam language so let's start
to uh kind of code and show
um you know wam language so this is what
we have yesterday so control shrink
shrink shrink shrink a little
bit okay so we got this function from
yesterday find cyclic tail and this is
how you define this is a Syntax for the
documentation of a function inline
function typical you know typically in
Python in emac lisp you can all do that
you can have a like documentation for
function and this feature by the way is
first the first time this feature came
to a programming language is from lisp
okay that is that is why they say lisp
language is kind of like the father of
many modern programming languages
features including automatic memory
management so-call garbage
collection which the the the term the
Jon garbage collection gets the C and
C++ and rust idiots very excited you
know they love the term garbage
collection but however they don't like
the automatic garbage uh memory uh
management okay the proper term is
automatic memory memory management not
garbage collection my ass you know so we
digressing into the jargons the
terminology of computer
science the terminology is critically
important because when you have the
termin when you have a phrase a jargon
used in scient in Sciences you know the
the ter it's a it's a science about the
terminology it's in computer science in
in mathematics it's in engineering it's
in you know astrophysics is in cosmology
you know it's in chemistry in biology
it's all in Sciences okay so and there
are consortiums or associations that um
Define the jargon that determines what
is a proper you know better jargon so it
the the Judgment of a scientific jargon
is very actually very critical it's a
big thing okay so I was saying that in
computer science we have the term
garbage collection which is a very bad
jargon because when you have a jargon
you know garbage you have tons of it in
O in functional programming you know we
we know the like hash table stack uh for
example hash table should it beit better
named hash table should it be better
named Association list which is also a
common name for hash table kind of thing
should it be better named as a
dictionary which is what python calls it
but they are essentially the same idea
you know it's a list of key value payers
NE uh e possibly ordered or unordered
but essentially it's a efficient idea is
a efficient implementation of a key
value pair okay so you you know it goes
by many names Association
list hash table or just hash or
dictionary and in the case of wolfan
language they call it
Association even just dropping the list
just they they call it
Association so the Jon you know the Jon
hashtable so which is the better name uh
that you know so that's a question
that's a question about the judging of
the Jon which is uh fairly
important okay so let me do a digression
and uh let's just go to cali. info and
search for jargon so you can see I have
actually quite a lot uh articles about
that because this is one of my uh
Obsession because I'm interested you
know because you you want a jargon so
what is a good jargon what are the
criterias to judge what is a good Jon
and what is a bad Jon for example oop
object oriented programming is it a good
Jon now remember we are not judging what
the thing you know we are not judging
for example o object oriented
programming we are not judging whether
that is a good thing or not but right
but the thing about Jon is that we are
judging whether that Jon is a good Jon
or not you know so so I have a lot
articles about that for example
synchronous and asynchronous functions
you know very very common if you are
JavaScript programmer uh J and repo you
know J and repo used to be very popular
like 10 years ago like rippo python repo
repo repo repo my ass it's bad Jon um so
what so so I mean so there are here are
some examples of a Jon okay uh Jons of
software industry Jons and what
determines a programming language's
popularity okay math jargons explain
let's open them of them uh you know
let's open them and we are digressing
okay say hi if you are watching online
if you want to get my attention if you
like to make yourself known to me and my
audiences you know you want my feedback
or
interaction so in for example in O
there's a lot of Jons classes methods
objects you know so the question to ask
in our context is are these good Jons
are there other names would would be
would convey the idea better okay
so classes methods objects and then you
have you have a lot more in O Okay so
the static class instant you know static
variables instance variables very common
in
Java uh then you have Constructors and
accessors okay then you have access
specifier in
Java then you have um uh inheritance
that's another Jon uh also in JavaScript
also in Python you know um then you have
class hierarchy okay uh then you have
then then you have the you know the the
the Jon
interface then you have the J Jon
abstract class abstract methods which
are derived from the Jon class and
methods okay then you have the jargon
iterators and
enumerators very popular in O croud not
just in Java you'll see that in
CSH as well and I believe C++ I don't
know C++ I don't know C really so then
you have um code re reuse well code ruse
is not a jargon per se but it's a
popular phrase in in the
op communities okay then the worst of
them all is this polymorphism [ __ ] okay
this is a this is a jargon from idiots
that misled confuses the you know like
few generations of programmers
polymorphism came from some idiots in
Academia the history of that ter came
from some
idiots so so that's a example of some of
the jargons then you have poly poly is a
new Jon which started life about 10
years ago from the
JavaScript Zuma idiots okay you got you
got the Jon poly okay I'm not going to
explain it but if you code JavaScript or
if you are web dev then you know what
that means okay you can look up poly by
a scumbag in this case the poly is spe
specifically we can trace trace the
history the origin of that Jon
specifically from a guy okay that guy is
um do I have it his name mentioned
somewhere uh no it seems like that not
but I know you know I know who who
created that jgun you can look up it's
on Wikipedia poly okay poly that's a
jargon new from the JavaScript
imunity uh but it's also interesting
this polyi
jargon as far as I know so far I mean
it's it's kind of just remained in a
JavaScript Community it it it didn't go
out it just stayed in the JavaScript
Community okay then you have the jargon
Lambda you know Lambda if you are a lisp
coder you know if you are a fan of emac
scheme lisp common lisp you'll be very
well Ed with the Jon Lambda extremely
popular among the lispers and also among
the functional programmers Lambda is one
of the most idiotic jargon okay now I'm
just showing some uh some examples of
jargons then let me briefly talk about
how do you judge a jargon what criterias
make a jargon a good jargon what makes
it bad now again remember we are not
judging what the that thing we we are
not judging whether the thing is good or
bad we are judging the label for the
thing you know what are the good labels
what are the bad labels you know so then
you have the Jon invariant in
programming languages I actually I
discovered this only five years ago like
in
2017 uh which is like seven uh seven
years ago invariant you know the
invariant invariant Jon actually is uh
came from mathematics but I discovered
in programming they also have this
invariant okay uh I don't remember
exactly what it is now but um okay let's
read it okay I don't know when when did
it happen but the term invariant is
beginning to to pop up in programming
language community so I wrote this in
2017 invariant in programming language
means something assumed to be true for
example say power n raised to n it is
assumed that n and M are number
type okay uh three programming language
in variant for example hash table access
is assumed to be fast constant time for
any key okay so inv Vari in okay so four
I first saw this use of invariant is in
JavaScript
specification ecmascript
2015 for example excript 2015 so I was
reading lots of the JavaScript
specifications so let's open that let's
see you know just for so here's my own
copy local copy of JavaScript
specification on sari.
info uh
so let's see where is the invariant uh
static semantics is valid simple
assignment Target okay uh
12.10.3 runtime semantics
evaluation uh where is the invariant
mentioned let's search I don't know
uh okay so here okay so we found an
instance so what is
this
12.10.3 run time semantics
evaluation so this section is
about is a specification of how
JavaScript evaluation should behave okay
so equality expression colon equality
expression equal equal relational
expression JavaScript spec is very
complicated very
complicated and a bad one I would say
okay so anyway here's a mention of
invariance note two the equality
operators maintain the following
invariance a not equals to B is
equivalent to okay a equal B and not
okay and a equal equal B is equivalent
to b equal equal a okay okay they call
it invariant yeah so invariant just
means like I what I described here it's
something assumed to be
true
uh still a FY definition but anyway so
this is the first time where I see the
invariant Jon
mentioned so five practically invariant
means something that is implicitly
assumed but now
explicit just so it's clear for example
in language specification
context uh and number six today I saw
invariant mentioned in Eric Raymond's
skoland versus rust essay okay so Eric
Raymond you know I was reading his blog
He also mentioned the word invariant you
know he he's got a block this is written
you know go versus rust versus Go
written about 10 years ago where is the
date let's see if I can find the date
you know I truly despise those
programmers who write their blocks but
do not clearly indicate when it is
written so this you know you know so
they don't have there it is are January
2017 rust versus skull okay good he has
got a date there so this 2017 which is
seven years ago Russ versus scope so
this let me let me mention this article
so in this article he he basically
he he likes go he do not like rust and I
share similar opinion go language is a
great language rust is
[ __ ] okay now ESR Eric Raymond he's very
famous programmer of course as you know
he he wrote the Bazar you know he he's
one of the big he he's one of the
founder of Open Source movement which is
a split off of Richard storman free
software foundation so the open source
Foundation began live around
1997 okay 1997 or 1996 which is
essentially started by Eric
Raymond now Eric Raymond wrote a lot
books he coded a lot Unix you know you
can you know add of Unix programming the
Bazar versus the
cathedral uh which is very popular book
you know he wrote several other books
and he's a pompus guy he's a assuming
you know he's a very pompous guy and
he's a he's a white man of course first
of all very pompous guy and very um you
know he's a conservative also
politically speaking he's a conservative
and he is um also you know the nasty
part about this guy he's somewhat of a
neocon so he
promote you know in his belief about
opinion he believed that USA
our country should be the cop of the
world you know we should in his opinion
we should attack Iraq you know back then
the weapon of you know mass destruction
the the war of Terror ter
Terror which we
killed
600,000 Iraq people nonmilitary people
we killed them you know because we
thought supposedly they have weapons
so-called weapon of mass
destruction but we found none and this
Eric s Raymond is fully promoting for
the Iraq War okay so that's uh so in my
opinion he is a
scumbag he is also uh one of the you
know he he you know he's very popular
guy he has done many things so promoting
Iraq war promoting gun which I agree
today 20 years ago I'm not sure but
today I fully support idea that
Americans in
USA we should have you know the right to
own a gun as the you know as the
Constitution you know so he's got many
opinions he's also kind of you know he's
also the one of the founder one of the
two also big founder of the open source
movement which is a branch off of the
Richard storman free software Foundation
they are enemies you know these two
camps are enemies at each other of and
today after Now by now 30 years we can
see that the open source movement kind
of won the free software Foundation you
know the richest stolman Branch they are
at War you know but they can you know
rich stman kind of became obscure except
in emac he's still you know saying
things but the open source W but open
source has
mutated mutated out of his out of Eric
Raymond's control completely open source
the idea the movement became you know
took over by the Google Microsoft
Facebook Amazon Empires you know they
don't care nothing about your uh Eric
Raymond and in fact Eric Raymond became
an enemy of the open source why because
the corporations the USA deep State they
began the social justice
movement
again so they promote things like men
can get pregnant men and women are the
same thing you know the trans men you
know like and women can can be uh
lesbian women lesbian trans are also
lesbian things like that promoted by
United Nation you know united nation has
a giant poster about you know this this
extremely
corrupt you know Corruption of you know
extremely corrupt things so Eric ESR he
founded open source but his movement got
took over by the you know D State and so
he became so this huge amount of
smearing against this
Eric uh s Raymond okay so there's a lot
you know stories and history so
ESR uh so you know let's see you know
he's got you know he's one of the most
popular blogger okay so this is not even
his side you the name people don't know
the his abbreviations anymore you know
this scum ESR official home this is like
a fraud trying to you know to to took
over his name but today the Zoomers you
know the Zoomers don't know nothing the
Zoomers got you know their brain got
washed since they were born so
here uh okay so you cannot even found
his homepage by searching ESR so if you
search ESR
Blog then there it is is okay you know
he's he's got this um [ __ ] on his
um he's got this uh how shall we say it
Maxim this this this chant phrase this
um
slogan for his blog armed and dangerous
you know this is Eric s Raymond you know
so so looks like uh he's getting old you
know he's like 7 something so the last
blog is only
wow what yeah this is this is his
website yeah so the last one is
2021 you know he's getting
old um so is Richard strowman and
Richard strowman got cancer you know it
came out about two years ago um so yeah
so anyway ESR the story of ESR which is
is a chapter of computing history espe
especially a chapter of
Unix okay so we digressed a lot we were
talking about poly field we about Lambda
Jon Lambda we talk about
ESR uh why are we talking about ESR
because yeah we were talking about
invariance and ESR one of ESR blog Russ
versus scope have used that jargon let's
search I am v a r i there it is you see
Russ gets a uh Russ gets A+ one here
because exposed
invariant that you can reason about are
better than relying on runtime on
runtime that you cannot re readily
ordered in practice
anyway so the Jon invariant which I
think is very stupid Jon I mean the the
very concept of invariant I don't think
it's good anyway so a Jon invariant then
we have um so here is my index of my
articles for for the jargons I came up I
came across and read about wrote about
so you got o
Jons we got list comprehension which is
made Popular by Python and uh hascar
these lisp comprehension idiots extreme
idiots okay the hascal idiots the hascal
people you know the hascal people are
extreme idiots you know you think you
think they are oh they are functional
they are pure functional programming
they and they must be mathematicians
because
they but you know but
actually 90% I would say 90% of all the
people who promote hascal are just
idiots like programmer idiots they know
nothing about mathematics and they they
kind of champion the you know like
whenever I say I I wrote an article
about why the J and this comprehension
is bad and this hascal idiot will
counter by saying that oh but but it
came from
mathematics [ __ ]
idiots why is it that because yes it is
true the jargon list comprehension came
from mathematics
came from set theory came from the set
theory set notation okay and that itself
is one of the most idiotic thing the set
notation to create a set okay it's the
most idiotic thing one one of the most
idiotic [ __ ] in mathematics the set
notation for generating a for describing
for kind of kind of a math notation
although not purely you know kind of dis
describing what the set is for example
let's say the set of even numbers so in
mathematics usually you can
write okay I digressed a lot so let me
just do so uh you know go go where my uh
where my brain is okay so for example
let's do a screenshot and let's start to
draw I want to draw so you want to snip
and sketch okay so for for example set
of
even numbers okay so usually you write
it like
that X then vertical bar uh uh then x
divided by
two is zero okay then you say x / 2
equal to zero
okay that is a
um set notation well there there's a
specific name for this
[Music]
um set I forgot what exactly is a Jon
anyway this is also called list
comprehension uh how exactly anyway so
this is kind of called list
comprehension okay you can you can go re
check up Wikipedia list comprehension
okay so the the the Jon list my what I'm
trying to get it is that the dragon this
comprehension came from this mathematics
notation okay the generating a
describing a set so the hascal idiots
and the python idiots they you know they
they they are brainless they don't know
the history of mathematics they don't
even know his mathematics but some of
them the elite hackers like the Unix
idiots you know or python priests will
say you know when they when you see
article you know when they see my
article criticizing the Jon this
comprehension they will jump out and
claim you are so stupid it came from
mathematics but you love
math you know that that's a this
comprehension
okay but why why is this uh why why is
this s notation bad because that is
[Music]
the that that's another topic okay that
is about constructive mathematic it has
to do with the foundation of mathematics
or the philosophy of mathematics okay
that's a huge Topic in
mathematics in particular regarding the
foundation of mathematics what is
mathematics what should it be what are
the approaches we should take regarding
mathematics
especially very uh you know abstract
concept such as infinity or infinitely
small like calculus you deal with like
something infinitely small that do they
actually exist have you ever seen
Infinity then how can you assume that
there is just like infinite like what
what does exactly does it mean isn't
mathematics supposed to be very precise
you have never seen Infinity how can you
say 1 two 3 4 five it just goes to
infinity or oh it's just
Infinity so you know but all all those
are valid questions so there's a you
know philosophy of mathematics so you
have to deal with these questions you
know and among mathematicians there are
different schools some mathematician I
mean first of all all of them you have
great greatest mathematicians in
different schools of philosophy so some
people some do not even believe Infinity
actually exist well they believe it
might exist but it's not something you
should use to Pro to when you do proofs
or things like that
so back to my point so there are there
are different philosophy of mathematics
okay so the most the three top most
popular ones are
logicism which is idea that mathematics
is just a branch of logic okay you just
you know like logic logic is a thing
then you know all mathematics can be
Rewritten in terms of just logic
statement logical statements okay so
math is a branch of logic you know
that's one major branch of philosophy of
mathematics the foundation of
mathematics that's called logicism and
the most well-known proponent of that is
bertron Russell which is my favorite one
of my favorite mathematician in fact
beron Russell influenced
me a lot influen my life my view of the
world uh you know philosophy of the
world logical positivism for example you
can look up logical positivism okay look
up Wikipedia that's another topic about
philosophy so anyway Buton Russo
influenc me a lot and I usually like but
transversal philosophy or his view his
point of view about math mathematics or
about the world of things for about for
example about not just math for example
about
Christianity you know about religion
about other things so so one philosophy
one huge School of philosophy of
mathematics is
logicism uh
and and by the way speaking of logical
positive top logical
positivism uh one of the rep
reprentative literature is Alice in
Wonderland okay let me just digress in
random uh so you can
find I have a collection of the
literatures that I liked and I have
annotated so including Arabian nightes
the original translated by Sir Richard
Burton not a Disney thing okay Disney's
you know Disney's Arabian nights 1,00
and one night is not is completely a
different thing it's very you know so if
you want to know what is the nature of
Arabian kns you know these These are the
nature of Arabian kns
okay so that's about that's the Arabian
Knights the nature the character of
Arabian knightes you got this you know
thoughts thoughts and cheating wives and
and so on and be with beautiful tits and
ass literally you know it's like
literally
described how they how the
girls in some case slave girls you know
have like huge tits and ass okay then
you also got this monsters you know
monsters and you know this uh Genie you
know this is is called a
genie you know so that that's what
Disney focus on you know this
Genie so and you know the genie of the
Islamic world you know it kind it kind
of came from that region Middle East not
just Islam but Persian Persian you know
or today's uh
Iran Iran was known as Persia so Persia
you know basically Middle East um you
have this that's their Fork CLW Fork CLW
so Genie okay so that's about Arabian
kns you know
so why are we talking about that because
I was talking about yeah my collection
of
Articles um literature okay let's go
back so Arabian Night flat land so let's
go back to Alice in Wonderland so I was
saying that Alice in Wonderland
um I have a copy on my website cali.org
you can I this is this is one of my
favorite literature I read it like three
times from cover to cover in
1990s um so in my
opinion this Alice in Wonderland is a
representation of the philosophy logical
positivism okay if you don't know that
philosophy you need to look up Wikipedia
it's kind of complicated because a lot
of philosophy they are like little
details like exactly why you know ex
existentialism or and you know quite a
few or idealism or materialism hello
Alexandra so Alice of Wonderland in my
opinion is a great
representation of the philosophy logical
positivism
which is this philosophy logical POS
positivism is the foundation of Western
Society in the past 100 years okay all
the Sciences all the
massive
progress and uh and uh you know uh
critical thinking that's all from
logical positive vism okay the
foundation of Western Society it in the
past 100
years okay but I have not seen any other
person express the idea that this Lis in
Wonderland actually relates to logical
positive pos positive positive
vism um so anyway that's maybe it's just
me or but maybe it's been said before
but I didn't I'm not aware of it so back
to so we were talking about ESR so I was
talking about logical positiv positive
positivism and we were talking about
berron Russo that's because we are back
to uh because berron Russo is a promot
prop proponent of logicism one of the
major branch of philosophy in
mathematics now what are the others the
other one is formalism
formalism which is most most repres
presented by Hilbert you know the one of
the greatest let's say top 20
mathematicians in the history of the
humanity okay one of the greatest
mathematician
Hilbert he's a prop proponent of the
formalism school of philosophy of
mathematics what is formalism formalism
means that I mean the idea is that math
doesn't mean anything
what does mathematics mean is simply a
sequence of symbols governed by
particular rules you know like wam
language or like when you study regular
expression or when you study um you know
the grammar you know the the the the
context dependent grammar or something
when you study passess formal
language you know so so in this school
of thought formalism mathematics is just
a sequence of meaningless symbols but
you have certain rules that tells you
how to replace this sequence of symbols
by another which is what exactly what
wfam language is you know just which is
this technique is called term rewriting
so you just match terms like we are
doing here match you know it it matched
then we do replace okay this is one rule
there are other Roots you know or in
other words it's string string
replacement system so computation become
just replacing stream strings we using
regular expression or others okay so
this is called in a programming language
is called term rewriting system which is
the the heart of the wolam language okay
that's
formalism another big philosophy of
mathematics now the third
biggest
[Music]
um I'm not sure about the you know um
okay so you got logicism you got
formalism there's
another uh yeah the the the other one is
called um intu intu uh intuitiv ISM
something like that okay I forgot I
forgot uh let's say let's go to
Wikipedia
philosophy of math okay you'll see the
three main branches
okay now the Stanford philosophy of
mathematics from the
Stanford website is not very good you
know they they are too much philosophic
philosophy you know I thought it's good
but after 10 years reading them I don't
think it's good I mean I mean it's it's
good for you know but it's uh I wouldn't
say it's the best okay the Stanford
encyclopedia
philosophy why I have that opinion why
do I not highly value this website
because this sfold encyclopedia
philosophy
they they are oriented towards for
philosophers uh so what does that mean
so they they they they they focus they
are oriented towards
like like the philosophers of a
philosopher like they they go into
esoteric things okay like like like you
know does does does the things exist or
maybe it not exists exists because you
know anyway you'll find Lambda calculus
you'll find uh you know Lambda calculus
philosophy of math mathematics formalism
you know like we talked about logicism
in
intuitionism okay that's that's the word
then formalism okay that's the three
biggest branch of philosophy of
mathematics classic okay you you'll find
a lot a lot of actually uh programming
language topics in this in this Stanford
encyclopedia or philosophy but but they
the way they write it is like is for
philosophers so if you are a
mathematician or if you are a computer
scientist you know when you read their
account it's it's no good it's because
they they have to fit the philosophers
mind that like the crazy stuff like
heigo hego is the worst scum grifter
heigo you know you might have heard of
name heigo especially h e g e l okay
heigo this this this scumbag okay heigo
this heigo
guy is
the classic grifter okay this heo guy
German a German philosopher he sells
Voodoo
okay to those of people to people the
you know who don't know so much they
will think this is very Advanced hego
you have to spend a lot time to
understand hego but but actually he's
just a grifter okay this grifter so in
my opinion
this Stanford encyclopedia philosophy
they are kind of like like like like
heego like like you know like they they
they talk like meta of the meta of the
meta like out of like
useless uh so we digress so so much so
all over so we were talking about
philosophy of mathematics so uh let's go
back
to uh why are we talking about
philosophy of mathematics because we
were talking
about uh let's go back Lambda okay Jon
Lambda uh okay let's go back to okay Jon
invariant Jon list
comprehension uh we were talking
about what how did we start to talk
about philosophy of
mathematics I forgot can
anyone is anyone
listening can anyone remind me give me a
clue help me
out
uh how do we how did we start to talk
about the philosop philosophy of of
mathematics okay I forgot and we also
haven't covered what is int
intuitionism which is very interesting
because I have a personal story to tell
because I
believed I used to believe
logicism and I kind of believed
formalism but it turns out this intu
intuitionism is actually the most
practical and concrete and mo have the
most to do with Computing using
computers to prove mathematics okay
that's how it turns out in
intuitionism very interesting
constructive or in in kind of a sub
branch of that intu intuitionism is
called constructive vism okay so in this
philosophy anything mathematics that you
cannot actually construct it you cannot
actually write it out or build it is in
a in in a sense nonsense okay so
Infinity well that's nonsense okay so
that's that's intu is M or
constructivism okay which is today the
foundation of the all the theory
improvers you know the co the H C Coq
the you know Assistant math provs CQ h
o or Ling Microsoft l e a an Ling
programming you know like like proof
systems you know and address you know
these are kind of
um you know these are you know
programming languages to
to uh to
to uh the you know prove theories
theorems so anyway they are all kind of
based on this constructivism okay this
in this in intu in intuitionism you know
I object you know like 10 years ago 20
years ago I
object the intuition ISM philosophy of
mathematics because they are silly
because they say they say you know you
in like they say kind of like Infinity
doesn't exist the only thing that exists
is actually things that you can actually
build and and I was like what the
[ __ ] you know you know I mean you cannot
build in Infinity but it's natural um
concept you know anyway so it turns out
so so it's very interesting you know in
the history of mathematics and history
of proof Theory and history of you know
Foundation of mathematics or history of
computation you know this philosophies
goes through different tsts and and
almost kind of
eats its own tail you know like before I
was thinking logicism I'm you know I'm a
proponent of logicism everything is just
logic you know I support butron veral
because how how else possibly could it
be it's just logic you know there this
this therefore that you know therefore 1
+ 1al 3 it must be logic because
ultimately there's nothing there's
nothing more fundamental than logic so I
believe all mathematics is just you know
logic you know then then you look at
formalism of the Hilbert then then that
makes sense because well yeah logic but
you cannot like verbally argue about
things otherwise you got 10 million 10
billion pages and you cannot like Define
a single thing you know so you need
symbols like especially with computers
you know like all the computer
programming language is kind of like
Lambda calculus that's
formalism which means formal language
you know look up Wikipedia okay that's
very
interesting formal language okay that's
a that's a foundation of theoretical
computer science for example regular
expression that is a formal language
okay now a lot of people don't know this
especially the cc++ and rust idiots and
Java idiots these type of people like
they have no idea they have no idea they
just know about memory bit daing and
stack and and hashtable you know these
idiots so if you want to know about
theoretical computer science formal
language is like the foundation of it
okay and regular expression is a formal
language Lambda calculus is a formal
language okay you can you know you can
try to study
it so formalism formal language is kind
of
the the theory of formalism okay formal
formalism is the school of mathematics
Hilbert's philosophy of mathematics
which says that or math is just
meaningless symbols and you have rules
to say you know which one transforms
into what and you just you know do this
form formula replacement you know that's
what this formal formalism is about
formal languages you know so that make
made sense to me because when you do
computers that's what it
is so so it's funny so what but what
about logic well you know it it's hard
to say which one is exactly so that's
that's an interesting thing about
philosophy you know like because when
you hear
materialism then you you think oh that
for sure because everything is just
things you know then you hear about
idealism which says well they are not
actually things they are just your
imagination because you know you are
just thinking about things so you know
you don't know which one exactly is true
that's a interesting thing about
philosophy so anyway so you hear about
logicism then formalism but then I hear
about the in intuition uh ISM okay so
let's go
to let's get the Jon right okay so by
the way the Wikipedia article on the
philosophy of mathematics is very
corrupt okay so don't read this one
because they the social justice Warrior
scumbags starting about about five years
ago about about
2018 okay they started to like they they
started to get onto mathematics you know
the math Departments of University you
know they begin in the social studies
you know the race issue gender issue
gender study social study black African
American study you know they they have
those courses starting around 1990s in
United States of America and you have
women studies now be you know in the 90s
begin with women studies and black
people africanamerican studies but now
the women's studies is banned because
you cannot allow you know how can you
allow women because because there's no
women men and women are the same thing
so so you have the trans and queer
studies the [ __ ] scum by the white
man okay this is the phenomenon of white
man power struggle with other white men
they created this mess because the white
men they are fighting them among
themselves doing a power struggle then
they they they created this
situation okay so so the Wikipedia
article on the philosophy of mathematics
starting I would say around 2018 they
started to mutate because they started
to add you know like the social justice
Warriors they will say you know one of
the philosophy of mathematics is that
it's all just in your head it's a social
construct just like
gender uh it's the fault of the white
man because of the patriarchy you know
that's let's see if we can find that
part uh con contemporary philosophy okay
wait this is a philosophy of mathematics
okay let's
go let's see history blah blah blah
contemporary platonism okay artistic
what the [ __ ] is this you know this this
this doesn't belong here okay this
someone [ __ ] added this artistic
[ __ ] it doesn't you know it's not you
know that's that's the the the the fake
news uh put in by the Deep
State uh then then this is what is this
maatic ISM crap okay that shouldn't
belong there logicism is classic yes but
transversal there formalism yes okay by
Hilbert this guy yes okay then the other
big one
intuitionism okay started by yeah this
guy leop chronica okay kind of
uh then you have
structuralism embodied mind theories
like what what never never heard of
it
uh okay so you started to have Fringe uh
Fringe okay you then you got
psychologism uh you got okay so
fictionalism is a bunch of crap oh there
there it is there comes the social
constructivism it's all white man's
fault that's what this social construct
you know constructive it's it's it's
men's men's
fault Beyond traditional schools okay uh
okay so
anyway so we digressed into the
philosophy of mathematics but uh can
anyone tell me how do how did we started
to talk about that so we were talking
about the Jon Lambda in Decline rust
versus skull and the Jon in variant the
Jon then the Jon list comprehension oh
yeah we were talking about oh yeah so we
started to talk about the philosophy the
different philosophy of mathematics
because we were talking about list
comprehension because the jargon list
comprehension came
from came from this set theory set
notation in classic you know classic
math notation list comprehension that's
where it came from and I started to talk
about philosophy of mathematics because
this this set notation is one of the
most idiotic [ __ ] in
mathematics according to the if you go
by the school of
intuitionism and
formalism okay
yeah okay but the python people the
hascal people don't know okay they like
they they have no idea they don't know
anything about math or history of
math so we were talking about yeah this
comprehension okay then yeah so I was
talking about this Jons I was showing
you my collection of essays on joggin
then there's closure okay very big topic
closure uh which the programming
language closure is inspired upon you
know you have the you have the thing you
have the concept called closure then the
lisp you know the lisp programming
language in on JavaScript I mean on Java
jvm machine they you know they call it
closure with the difference c o j r e
so so you have you got the Jaron curing
Which is popular in functional
programming curing it came from the um
mathematician Curry
logician you got the JG and tail
recursion which is Sun by the scheme
lisus all the time you got the Jon
asynchronous in you know synchronous in
JavaScript very much you got the Jon
instance which is um which is in O
Community instance like this is this
this object is a instance of that class
which is idiotic you know some some of
some of these JG let let me talk about
another aspect of interesting aspect
about JG about this computer Computing
jargons you see instance it's very hard
to Define mathematics
mathematically now intuitively we kind
of understand because instance is just
um uh let's show the
article uh where did it
go yeah instance you see so this jargon
happens in O programming object oriented
program me and intuitively like most of
the Jons we kind of understand it you
know you can create a class then you can
say you know a variable name equals to
you know a class declar Declaration of
the you know class is the type of the
variable then then equals to
new a Constructor you know so that
creates an instance of this class
assigned to a variable you
see intuitively we kind of understand
you know it just create a object from a
given class
okay but if you want to Define this in a
mathematical way without any talking
about process or procedure like Define
what it is not how it became okay like
that's a major difference between
computer science and mathematics
computer science is about processes
algorithm you know you have to there's a
time going you know like I do this this
this and therefore that that you know
this like a process going on that's a
heart of computer science mathematics is
what it is nothing moves okay you just
say given this thing this is the result
this is the consequences properties and
so
on so when you want to try to Define
instance you know in in a mathematical
way I found I you know I found it's
fairly difficult it's like like you
don't so like you don't know exactly
what it is what the [ __ ] is the instance
it's hard to Define it in a mathematical
way okay so you have instance you have
the code point from unic code you have
you know then you have the Jon finite
automata in finite state automata which
regular expression came
from uh go back okay so you got
um go back go back okay anyway you got
all these Jons so let's go back and uh
so we already talked for 70 minutes we
didn't uh we digressed so much where are
we we were talking we were trying to
we were trying to
um start to talk about at the end of a
code writing a function to
um to find the
periodic when a function is nested
okay okay we digressed all over I think
maybe we'll start this topic another day
then let today just be this philosophy
of mathematics
and computer jargons digression as the
topic so Alexandra says you were talking
about Infinity when you diverged about
mathematical thinking yes
yes uh yes that Infinity is a
example example of a thing in math of a
concept in mathematics where the
different schools of philosophy of
mathematics they have like very quite
different takes and there are big
consequences with that so anyway Rudolph
says I once almost took a philosophy
course this week we had tons of readings
packed with extraordinary claims and
complex terminology not a single
definition I dropped right
away okay uh in in my opinion philosophy
was a precursor to science today it is
useless and most of it is just laziness
written by people too lazy to earn real
science yeah well that's uh interesting
because I you know because the that
touches upon what is philosophy
itself so and uh I do have have opinions
on that because philosophy is one of the
thing I'm very interested I have kind of
Interest
similar to my interest in math in
programming and the other interest are
psychology and philosophy okay or about
brainwashing such as how does marketing
Works how does fat and fashion arise in
society how does brainwashing works
there these are all kind of related this
is about social
psychology or how do you persuade people
for example there's a book about
persuasion like right under here this is
a very popular
book the psychology of influence the art
of persuasion something like that by
this uh
Robert uh
sh CH
Chini Robert
Chini okay this was very popular book in
1990s so
persuasion
or um you know brainwashing by the CIA
for example how do you for example
during war during Iraq all propaganda
how does propaganda work you know very
serious very important thing in in World
War II there's a lot of propaganda on
all sides
there is uh you
know how to how to persuade people how
to brainwash people propaganda or
fashion and facts how does a fashion
arve arise for example for for a few de
for a decade we have patterns you know
programming patterns which is ubiquitous
in programming Community every
programmer will mention oh this is
patterns you need to do patterns you
know like product patterns was you know
was for for about 10 years one of one of
the most
popular uh fashion or fat or there's
there is agile you know
programming um you know
so how does it arrive you know like like
like like often after 10 years they are
they are gone they are never heard of
again but but during your time every
programmer is is like this is the most
important thing
so be you see when some if something is
really truly the most important or
critically important you would assume
it's going to you know last for good you
know it's last for Generations Because
unless there's more more fundamental
concept or theory that you know pre uh
you know that override it so but but but
that's not usually not the case when
when there's a fashion or thought you
know it dies you know in programming as
well especi but also of course in
women's fashion or or for example then
in the thought patterns of
Americans every 10 years let's say you
have certain thought that people for
example today you know for example we
you probably heard of uh
uh let's see let's see
some you know patriarchy for
example today that that idea is kind of
wind a little bit you know because the
social justice thing is kind of going
away uh but let's say five years ago
it's over you know uh safe space safe
space main spread spreading main
spreading in safe space uh
patriarchy uh you know you hear that you
know like by
everyone okay so so let's go let's go so
where are we so we um yeah that's it for
today so we were talking oh yeah we so I
was saying that
psychology was is you know one of my
interest especially about
the uh you know thought and fashion and
fed and marketing you know marketing is
a billion dollar business you know like
you know and especially applicable in
America because America is
a uh is a you know you might
say capitalism you know kind of very
practical American capitalism so you you
everything is about sales you know go to
Starbucks McDonald's you know McDonald's
Starbucks
they represent
America in you know in a significant way
actually so everything you do is about
you know like Twitter you know you got
ads on Twitter Twitter you got ads
marketing Google Google makes money by
by ads by marketing and if you have a
brand you know you have to know about
brand names yeah Google Microsoft
Facebook Apple you know the all the
Apple Fans every day is like you know
tarting their their latest Apple iPhone
or this got this feature you know every
year apple has a conference Apple you
know developers conference or whatever
showcasing their things then there's Las
Vegas you know tech tech show and
whatever
so marketing you know a billion dollar
business so that's you know that's
critically important in
America structure
uh and for example social
networking you know so-called social
networking which are basically websites
Instagram
Twitter today known as
x uh where is my here uh wait let's go
to it today know is X you know Twitter
Instagram uh
Reddit you know Hacker News this you
know social networking website you know
it
became as the white people say toxic
toxic you
know you know how did it begin because
the Mark Zuckerberg scumbag starting
around
2004 he started Facebook and he
discovered oh if you have a thumb up
that that that's called um gamification
you know a nice word gamification so you
just create this thumb up on your
website and people will be conditioned
you know when I write something I post
something then other people saw it give
me a thumb up I feel happy oh oh this
guy read my stuff he you know I got got
thumb thumb
up it that is the beginning of
psychological
control psychological brainwashing your
brain by this giant Corporation f begin
with Facebook the thumb up then other
people saw it other this socalled
Silicon Valley entrepreneurs you know oh
oh that works you know then then then
you got Twitter all the websites got the
you know got some kind of thumb up or
heart or Star so you have to like you
know plus or YouTube everywhere you know
that is the
beginning of the
rotting of the brand of the popular
ation because you stopped you stopped
you know you stopped actually saying
what you want to say instead you started
to think about what kind of thing what
kind of style what you know what post I
post so that I get the maximum number of
the thumb
up Begin by
zuker Mark zuk zuker scumbag okay and
today's zumas you know that like they
they have no idea what's going
on you they they they they they were
born into this social network work
networking world with all the thumb up
and downs and you know they they don't
know what is what is a genuine opinion
and in fact they don't know how to write
they don't they don't know how to
express and opinion anymore they just
know memes because meme is the is the
best way to get you thumbs up you know
lots of spread and you became so-called
influencer and you can make money by
putting ads King ads to your
post uh okay that's it for
today bye
guys so we not you know we going to not
doing this
problem uh because we digress so much we
digressed for 80
minutes uh and uh this problem still
very
interesting uh we'll continue it you
know you'll be uh take
five okay bye guys