Good morning, everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Xah Talk Show.
It's been a long time. Long time no see,
guys. How are you guys?
So, today we are going to do Emacs
Xah HTML mode tutorial. Okay, I'm going
to demonstrate this Xah HTML mode
tutorial.
Now, let's check
check video check. Am I alive? Yes, I'm
alive and audio check. Fantastic.
Now, let the show begin. So, today is
2000 um
Let's see, switch the keyboard uh 2021
September
14th. Okay, time flies.
Especially when you get old. But, you
know, in a blink of an eye, you'll be 50
years old.
So, Xah HTML mode tutorial. So, in the
past month, okay, more than a month, I
spent like 10 hours a day coding Emacs,
you know,
among other things, you know.
So, coding So, I rewrote Let me show
you.
Okay, so here is a source code of Xah
HTML mode. So, you can see
this is uh this code began in 2012. So,
now it's been
uh 9 years old.
So, but in the past month, I rewrote the
entire thing. So, this code is let's say
let's you know, let's have a look. It's
Right now, it's 4,100
lines of code.
A month ago, it was close to 5,000 lines
of code. So, I basically rewrote the
entire uh
you know, 90% of it. Rewrite and, you
know, every day. So, I spent like 100
hours on it.
So, now I would say it's
fantastic. Okay, I would claim this is
the best HTML mode on earth.
The best HTML mod on earth.
Trust me. You can try it, okay?
Especially coupled with staff like keys
and oh my god, it's going to be
fantastic. It's the most the minimal
keystroke required. I mean even more
efficient than org mod, okay? So today's
talk show, so you are seeing you see
I work with HTML since um
1996.
1996 is the year I learned writing HTML.
And in beginning it's manually by hand
and I code them in Microsoft Word.
Your favorite editor, Microsoft Word.
So so you see today so you know this is
today's talk show and I'm using of
course I'm right now using C HTML mod.
In fact in the past year or two or you
know since I started to do YouTube I've
been using my C HTML mod. Hello Huang
Wen and hello Christian Samp. Hello C.
Learning list yeah list is great and
hello um
Clat
uh
talent comma, okay?
So I've been you know coding HTML mod
from the you know manually tag by tag
since 1996.
That's the year I learned uh
HTML at Wuhan research actually 1995.
Uh and uh you know and this mod C HTML
mod began in 2000 um
let's see where's the code where's the
code in 2012.
So
so it's been nine years. So let me
demonstrate. So today I'm going to
demonstrate um
you know some of the features like what
what does the mod do? So
Okay, so let's go to talk show. Let's
open it. Let me just show you so you
know so for example, here's a video. You
comment out and show in browser so it's
going to switch back to
Emacs and do
showing browser. Okay, now it says error
because I have JavaScript off. So you
need to turn on JavaScript for Google's
to get your information.
So you see this this block of code is
the YouTube embedded YouTube and and you
got a figure. So you can see you can
jump to the tag. You see I'm jumping to
the tag. Oh,
I forgot. Let me turn on the highlight
lines, okay.
Now highlight lines so you can see where
my cursor is.
Now what's the Emacs highlight lines
mod?
Highlight
current um
highlight that.
You know, there's so many commands in
Emacs you don't remember what key is it.
Okay, hi.
You know that mod, okay, let's go to
let's go to you know, let's go to Emacs.
Let's go to Xah Lee Practical Emacs
tutorial. Then let's go to Emacs in it.
Then you can see then just search for
h i g h highlight current line, okay. So
you see with this mod on you can
highlight the current line. So you see
Emacs naming is not consistent. Now it's
like hi line h i not h i
g h that's why I remember. So
hi line
mod.
God, why is it highlight mod?
Wait, why is it global highlight mod?
Okay.
Wait, this this is strange. Okay, okay.
We are digressing, so but um So, what's
going on with this command? Let's
magnify.
So, HL this is L, right?
Small letter L, so HL line mod, okay.
Ah, this is
This is This is a major pain in the ass,
the most idiotic thing in in Emacs. You
see, this mod, highlight mod Let me turn
it on first, okay.
So, you can actually
see. You see? So, basically when I move
the cursor, you'll you'll highlight the
current line, okay? And by the way, on
the pink window is all the key press or
all the command call, you'll see on the
pink window and also the key.
You know, the key press on the side.
You'll show you what key I'm pressing.
So, anyway, the highlight
mod, okay.
A little bit digression. This is idiocy
of the naming, you see?
Normally, you think of highlight is HI,
you know, or HIGH, you know,
highlight. But this mod is called HL.
It's
It's a brief for highlight. So, it you
cannot find it. Anyway, so
we found it, okay? So, close that. So,
what we are going to do? So, show, where
are we? So, Emacs tutorial, yeah. Close
that, close that, close that, close
that, close. Okay, start talk show,
we're back to here. So, you can see this
is a figure. Now, I can jump to the
closing tag
by pressing a key
and uh
and I can move to any tag, okay? So, for
for example, I want to delete the figure
line. Press a key. You see, it removes
the figure tag, okay? so hold on a
second. Let me put some annotation.
Figure caption, you can see.
So, this is start talk show. Okay, now
show in browser, you can see we added
that that.
Am I good? So many people, okay, I'm
going to get get to your questions,
okay?
So anyway, let let's let's So yeah, let
me show you the feature. So if I want to
remove the figure tag, I press the key,
you see? And if I want to remove again
the previous tag, I press under key just
space, okay?
Show the pink window, okay? Undo, let's
do it again. Do it, you see?
Do it. Oh my god, this is fantastic. Now
press the key again.
The YouTube frame is gone.
Now this is this feature is great. Let
me I show you, you see? This tag it's a
frame, you know, the whole the whole tag
is a frame tag and with a URL embedded
in it. Now normally if you delete a tag,
you know, you delete the closing tag and
you delete the opening tag, the whole
line will be gone. But however,
that's usually not what what you want.
You want the embedded information
to be remain intact. So when you do
that, you see, it leaves the
important info important information.
And for example, let's go to this one.
So if for example, here one here we have
a let's let's make it a paragraph, okay?
Press the key, you got a paragraph. Show
in browser, so you see it looks like
that. Now here you have a list, okay?
You have a list of one item and this
item is a link.
Now let's say I don't want the links
list, okay? So I press a key,
remove all the lists, okay? Show in
browser, okay? I
I can do it one shot or I can do it this
way, okay? So anyway, so now I got a
link, you see? Now I got a link.
This line. Now
the whole thing is just one tag. Now I
can call the delete tag pair again.
Do it. You can see now what you get is
not Now, let's add a paragraph, okay?
Now, what you get is this markdown
uh formatting of the link text
and the the URL. So, you don't actually
remove the whole,
you know, tag. So, this is fantastic
because, for example, let's make a
backup
and let's undo.
Let's revert to the previous, okay?
Actually,
undo back. Let's Let me show you Let's
do it from the scratch. Now, let's say I
want the extract the URL of a link,
okay? So, I press a key, it's done. Now,
I go somewhere else, paste it. You can
You can see it's a link. Now, I want to
linkify it, I just press another key,
you see?
So, remove that. So, let's
return to their state, okay? So,
cop- copy the link, paste it here,
delete that. Delete the paragraph tag
and this is a YouTube
URL. Let's embed it, okay? Now, the talk
show, this the annotation figure
caption, put it here. And here is a URL.
Let's make it a link plus
make a list, okay? Show in browser. Now,
it's fantastic.
So, that's You see, that's some of the
actual use of the site HTML mode, okay?
Now, let's go to the URL, okay? So, you
see this is a URL.
Now, this if it's a some other website,
let's say um
let's say digital pen, okay? Let's Let's
go to some Wikipedia, okay? Let's go to
Let's go to uh
microsoft.com, okay? So, Microsoft, they
are selling you digital pens. By the
way, I have opinions on it. You just go
to site keyboard.
I can tell you oh, oh, you you see
Microsoft.
digital pen. So, anyway,
uh first of all, okay, digression. Let
me show you Xah keyboard, okay? So, you
go to Xah keyboard blog
and use uh you comment, okay? Keep the
comment going.
You go to Xah keyboard blog and you go
to um
miscellaneous pen input, okay? Click
here. Then here is all you wanted to
know about pen input.
So, I give you opinions on which one to
buy.
I have this one, for example.
Then there is the Microsoft Surface Pro
and there is the
you know, the drawing tablet.
Then there is the, you know, the Apple
Magic Pad
which you can draw with your hand. Or
there's a, you know, display, um
you know, digital pen with a display.
So, actually, in the past year, I
started to have some of these and I
started to dig, you know, to realize
what what are the differences and which
are good or bad, okay?
So, you read my reviews and and let me
show you, okay? Let me tell you, this
one, if you have a Surface tablet,
Microsoft Surface, this is the best,
okay? Cheap and best.
Otherwise, you know,
anyway, the digital pen, they come in
two different classes. One is active,
one is not active, which is basically
active means there's a battery in it.
So, basically, they support pressure and
all that. Inactive is just like your
finger, okay? So,
anyway, so anyway, so that's a
digression about the pen input. Very
interesting technology.
Okay, so what I want to show you, go
back to to to um
keyboard blog, okay? So, go to keyboard
blog, go back to here and we uh I want
to show you
Remember, today's topic is CIDER HTML
mode, okay? So, let's not digress too
much. Yeah, I want to So, I want to copy
a link. So, I have a keyboard macro set
up. Let me show you.
Am I still alive?
Comment, guys, okay? So, I have a
keyboard macro set up. Let's see.
Again, I Let me I want I need to show
you my keyboard, okay? Fantastic
keyboard system. So, this is Kinesis
Advantage 2. You go to my website,
Kinesis Keyboard Blog, buy it. Kinesis
Advantage 2. And this is ultimate
hacking
ultimate hacking keyboard, okay? This is
a left side, right side. I use it as a
macro pad. So, for example, switch to
the last application, just that key.
Okay?
Okay, good. Now, let's get back. So, I
want to show you
So, I want to copy a URL. You know, I
have a macro set up. So, I copy the URL
back to Emacs, and let's show the pink
window and put it here. So, you see, we
got a URL here. Now, you can
you can
link it. Okay, now it becomes a link.
You can You see, and let's put a
paragraph, okay? Show in browser. So,
you can see we got a link there. And
now, if you put the cursor somewhere
inside the link, you see, I put the
cursor here and press enter,
we just go to that website, okay?
So, this is, you know, one of the
feature of CIDER HTML mode. So, for
example, if I press enter now, you can
see in the pink window, it's actually
it's actually um
How do I move that?
Okay, I cannot
I used to be able to move around this
pink window, but anyway, so
you can see the command I'm calling is
actually here, you know, cuz I HTML open
local link. So, for example, let me try
again, okay?
Press enter and you look at the pink
window.
You see? It's calling C HTML open local
link.
So, that's a feature, you know. But, if
you your if your cursor is somewhere
else, you press enter, it just
enters enter, okay?
So, that's some of the features, okay?
So, let's now what to do, okay? So,
So, okay, let's go to this page.
So, I give you I gave you some of the
demonstrations of the
C HTML mod. So, I wrote a tutorial here.
You can see
how to use it, okay? So, I mean, I give
you some introduction.
I was planning to go through this item
by item item, but I already pretty much
demonstrate us
a few of the fe-
uh features, okay? There's a lot a lot
more. Let me let me demonstrate, okay?
Let me show you. But, let me first of
all first of all, if you want to get the
map mod,
you go to Okay, this is the old uh C
talk show.
Uh
half a year ago, my god, half a year ago
I was doing uh HTML stuff. So, anyway,
this is the C HTML mod and uh you can
download it, you know, on GitHub.
It's not on MELPA. I haven't, you know,
I'm
not sure I'm you know, just download
from GitHub, okay? And you
it also requires several packages, okay?
It's all on my website, or it's it's all
on GitHub.
So, that's how you download it, and I
tell you some of the features. But,
today I'm going to show you, you know,
demo. So, let me let's do some more
demo, okay?
So, image, okay? So, let's say So, you
have an image here. So, let's see.
So, you can see the image is this one.
Okay? So, let's say I want to remove the
image. Again, I call the command, you
know, delete tag pairs, so that image is
gone. So, show in browser, you see it's
gone.
Uh instead, you got these lines that and
now, let's say I want to
Let's say you have a file path. So,
let's say you want to add an image. So,
you all you have to do is you paste the
file path. It can be relative path, or
it can be
absolute path, okay? So, either way. So,
once you have a path, you just call a
command. Boom! There it is. You see?
Now, show in browser, you can see now
there it is.
It adds the image tag. It also adds the
the figure tag, which allows you to uh
name and the figure caption, which which
is actually uh good, okay?
That's about HTML. So, it's you know,
more it's some details about HTML. So,
for example, let's say
So, if you don't know HTML, yeah, let me
tell you about this. You go to site HTML
tutorial. So, this is the most simplest
tutorial from the ground up. If you
don't know nothing about HTML, you can
learn from my website.
Okay, site HTML, then HTML tags, you
know, HTML is not too difficult.
So,
Okay, so,
so, let me uh close that. So, uh
So, for example, we talked about figure.
So, figure tag, so, here's the
illustration of how what how that tag
works, okay?
Figure tag is actually new about 10
years ago. Okay, let's get back here.
So, um insert tag, so, what what did we
do? Okay, so,
so, we you see, we added that. So okay,
so we don't need that anymore. So
delete this block.
Copy that. Copy that.
Paste it here. So before we turned a h
image path into the complete image and
figure tag. Now
let's say I already you see I already
have the figure and figure caption. I
just want to turn it into a image tag.
So what do you do?
Just press three keys. There you have
it.
So showing browser you see that's how
you do it.
So okay, so
what do we do now? So there are a lot
features. Um
do we go through each and every one of
them or do I just make maybe demonstrate
as a few other interesting
ones then
that'll be it for today. Then I'm going
to read your comments, okay?
So one of the questions what other
packages do I use? Actually this
not many just
packages.
So for example I can show you. So let's
go to
for example my Emacs directory alpha,
okay? So
So this you know so so I don't use
company mod deleted. I don't use stash
despite stash early map mod I don't use
then helm I don't use I don't I don't
use. I installed them to
do some experiments, okay?
Okay, so first of all delete them all,
okay? Delete those
I don't use. Then I do use go
basically two, okay? Well
what you know let me explain, okay? So I
use go mod that's for go land and I also
use magic, okay? Magic is I don't you
know I started to really very annoying.
Magic installed installs a bunch of all
the others. Magic installs a sync git
pop-up transient which and I don't use
which key, okay, deleted.
So
I use go mod and magic. The rest is
installed by magic that I you know
I really don't like it.
You know I have a urge just to delete
the magic right now, okay. So
let's
delete the magic.
I'm rage quitting.
install a bunch It's you know
it's like JavaScript. JavaScript npm
where a library is just five lines of
code. When you install npm you know when
you install one package
it installs 10 other and each one
installs 10 other. So once you install
one package whoo,
100 1,000 libraries comes comes in.
Deleted. Okay, so go mod is what I use.
There are two more, okay, so
let me show you, okay. So what is the
okay, so let's go to site html homepage.
Okay, you press a key you type you
meta x which key then you press a key
then you'll show you the
documentation for the
site html mod. So you can you are seeing
you are looking at the documentation of
site html mod. And you see so you have
about 100 commands now.
Now so let's jump to it. So here here's
a source code.
Okay, so here's a source code.
Okay, yeah, so I want to show you what
mod am I using? So
So here is all the mods. I think You
know, most of them are some mods, okay?
Or or basically all my stuff.
And uh
but two of two of them, so I use
htmlize,
okay? This is actually required by
xs-html mod. What this mod does is that
it turns syntax coloring
from Emacs to HTML, okay? Let me demo
demonstrate that, okay? So, HTML mod
htmlize
mod I use. And this this is written by
this guy, okay? This guy is from uh
northern Europe, you know?
Sweden or something like Norway, some
somewhere there.
He's a old
it is coder, okay?
Uh
So, so so htmlize mod I use.
And smex, smex is fantas- fantastic,
okay? It's a
enhancement of
meta-x, okay? So, when you call meta-x,
it allows you fuzzy matching on that.
You know, I don't like, you know, today
many mods they they became elaborate,
you know, like helm.
I don't like helm, okay? Helm and a
bunch of those.
They you know, elaborate, they are slow.
They you know, they make you they make
your Emacs slow and they have a bunch of
colors.
I want simple, the most simple, ugly,
efficient, okay?
Now, if you want a enhancement for
meta-x, I recommend smex, okay? Now,
it's written by this guy. I believe
he's also a he's a I think he's a
professor, okay? Um
I forgot. Anyway, so
um
Anyway, smex is great, okay? This By by
the way, there's also upgrade like this
happens a lot, you know, some people
upgraded Smex into something better, but
I tried it. It's actually not better,
okay?
So
So I use HTML as I use Smex and
And that's it, okay? That is it. Then
the the rest are my things.
Okay, let me just demonstrate another
feature of HTML, it's a HTML mod, okay?
Close that. Close that.
Yeah, close that.
So let's do source code, you know, we
are all into source code, okay? So let's
go to start talk show.
Open that. Show today's talk show. Let's
say I'm writing a Python tutorial, you
are writing a Python blog or JavaScript
blog, okay? So let me just demonstrate.
So this is if you are using a org mod
fan, org mod babel, you'll be you know,
interested in this. So I want to add a
Python code. Let's see this
Here's what I do, okay? Press the key,
code Python. So Python 2 or 3, let's say
just let's say Python 3, okay? Enter.
Then
Now watch the pink window if you want to
know what command I'm actually coding,
okay? Then
you
press the key
then you got a new buffer that lets you
type whatever, okay? So let's say so we
are in Python.
Print
three, okay? Now run the code.
Oh, Python 3 you need parentheses, okay?
Run the code. There you have it, three,
okay? Then say let's say 3 + 1, okay?
Run it. So you got four, fantastic,
okay? So here's your Python code code,
okay? So you are done. You press the key
So you see, it
pops the buffer back to your HTML
editor. Showing browser, you can see
you can see
is you can see that you know you have
your code there and let's make it syntax
colored okay you see right now it's not
syntax colored but let's make it so.
Um
do it okay back to the browser refresh
you can see
Python code and similarly let's do it
again let's do JavaScript now. Okay
uh press the key what you want
JavaScript yes and
let's do it let's say let's write a
function.
Constant arrow so this is start
JavaScript mod constant arrow function
okay.
Now if okay so what is going to do this
this is going to add two numbers x plus
y okay so you have a function and we
let's console log call f
call f three and four. So run the code
run it so it result is seven.
It requires standard by the way okay. So
so let's add a comment okay here is a
demo of arrow function okay.
Okay here's a demo of arrow function
okay. So you are done with it press the
key you see your code is back here. Now
show in browser
there you have it now you need syntax
coloring
do it
go to the browse browser there you have
it okay.
And of course you can do Emacs.
Let's let's do some Emacs Lisp.
Okay
defun let me what we going to do okay
let's just say okay three okay x
x y magnify
add
plus three
uh x y okay.
Okay, prettify the code. We don't need
the let, okay? So, remove the let.
Prettify the code, okay? That's it. Eval
the buffer. Now, call meta X.
Oh, okay. So, let's let's do this Yeah,
let's prompt, okay? So,
uh okay.
Let's uh make it interactive, so
What is X? Okay, you have to type X.
That's get complex.
Let's forget it. So, anyway, so here is
the
um
And then then
you know, here is the here is a function
in
in Emacs, okay? So, now suppose you are
done, press a key, so you can see your
code is here. Now, sync syntax color it,
show in browser.
Okay, there you That's the That's a
demonstration of these features, okay?
Now, let me read um
the comments and
and perhaps that's it for today. So, how
long have I been talking?
For half half an hour?
Hello Kasausa, "Starting to learn E
Lisp, that's a great, you know, with E
Lisp
it makes your coding trivial."
Enough with the gum.
Now, coffee.
Per programmara,
hello, good morning. Nuts video, hello.
Nuts video LLC limited corporation.
Now, okay. Now, it's time to say now if
you like my stuff cuz HTML mod, you have
to pay, okay?
Pay me, you know, send me $20.
Yeah, send me, you know, ching ching
ching ching send me $20, okay? And
you'll you'll benefit from these
fantastic features.
So, how long did I work on, you know,
I've been writing it for 8 years, but in
the past month, I
basically full-time, I worked on it,
rewrote everything. So, you'll notice,
you know, there are you know
there's quite a lot improvements. For
example,
for example, you can see for example,
this this tag, okay? This is a list,
okay?
So, you can see the beginning tag and
the end tag are colored differently,
okay? You can see
can you see that?
It wasn't like that before. It, you
know, before this month, before
you know, 2 months ago, the beginning
tag and the ending tag have the same
color.
But, you know, but but then I started to
think that actually
if you make the ending tag
you know, not so apparent, you know,
like gray,
it actually is much better. Uh it's much
better. So,
you know, this is a refinement of
experience, you know, you don't see this
kind of thing in uh most other, you
know, syntax highlighting in HTML. For
example, in I have compared them. I you
know, I I
I dig into these things. I spend days on
how editors do syntax highlighting. I
mean, that's another giant topic, okay?
I can talk about for a few hours.
You know, the science and art of syntax
coloring in a of a programming language,
which should you color? There are so
many ways, okay? In fact, I have an
article on that. Just search for style
syntax color, you'll find it. I have
more than one articles.
So, I looked at, you know, VS Code. But
anyway, the point is that you don't see
this
uh you know,
you know, you can try it in Vim, you can
try it in VS Code, you can try it in
Xcode, the Mac, you know, Mac OS Apple's
Xcode, or you try uh any editor or
whatever in
uh you know, in in any other editors,
you'll see that they don't do this.
They don't color the closing tag to be a
different from the beginning tag. But
actually,
so this is kind of my
you know, if you know, you might call it
innovation. I believe so, it's a good
thing, okay?
Why don't they do that? Because, you
know, most of these syntax coloring,
they don't
they don't, you know, they want to
especially commercial ones, they want to
make money, right? If you want to make
money, usually you want to stay
uh
pretty common to the know gnome.
You know, you know, yeah, that's why,
you know, like if you are a big
corporation, you you stay to the gnome.
Unless you are a startup, you are new,
you are then you try maybe you try to
innovate.
So anyway, so so the it's interesting.
So the ending tag is colored
differently.
Um
and uh so what else?
Okay, I'm just going to read comments,
and I think that's it for today. Uh what
about other features? Uh you know,
there's quite a lot. There's quite a
lot, okay? So, let me demonstrate uh how
to how do you make a list, okay? So, A,
B, something, and uh C, something else.
So, you know, you write, you know, then
you want to make a list. So, you what do
you do? You press a key, it becomes a
list showing browser.
There you see.
What if you want it to be ordered list,
okay? You press a key
showing browser refresh, you got a
ordered list. Okay, that's how you make
a list. Okay, delete. Okay.
So, let's say
this is how you make a list. What What
if you want definition list, okay?
So, let's say uh Emacs
is a great
editor, okay? Let's say
Emacs Lisp
is a great programming language, okay?
For example, if you are writing Python
tutorial or if if you are blogging about
Python, there are some functions you
want to explain what they do. So, you
can explain so range, for example, range
uh
uh let's say range
generates a list from zero to n, okay?
Now, so you want to make this into a not
just a list, okay? So, let's try let's
show a
By the way, this is Sacha Discord Sacha
Discord. Join if you haven't already.
Uh
Okay, so you see right now you have a
list, but we want a definition list. Let
me show you, okay? So, you can see I
press a key.
Done. Now, go to the browser, refresh.
Now, that looks fantastic, you know? You
have a definition You have a word, then
you have a meaning. So, Emacs Lisp is a
great programming language. Range n
generates a list from zero to n. So,
that's
how you uh create a definition list.
What What if you want a table? So, let's
say
uh table, okay?
Let's say multiplication table, okay?
So, we have
one, two, three, okay? Uh let's say one,
two, three.
Then 1 2
3. Then, 1 2 1 * 1 is 1, okay?
1 1 * 2 is uh 2, okay? So, this is 1 2
3. 1 * 2 is 2.
1 * 2 * 2 is 4.
2 * 3 is 6. So, here we have a
multiplication table. We going to make
it.
So, 3
uh
Okay, so 3 2 is 6. 3 3 is 9.
Okay, so
if you show in browser,
you know, it becomes that. No good. You
want the table. So,
let's see. We want to make a table,
right? Yeah, so how do you So, when
let's see.
I got a 1 2 3. So, space is a separator.
Okay, so we need empty. So, let's ready.
Let's do it. Okay, so
Okay, you got it. Now, go to the
browser. Show in So, you see, you got a
table. Fantastic.
And by the way, you can also So, you can
also remove the table. So, So, what you
do is uh You see? You press a key, it it
becomes back to that, okay? So, now you
can make that a table again. Let's copy
at Let's uh make a table again. You see,
now it's a table again.
So, that's a table and uh
So, that's how you make a table. So,
what what else? What other features?
Create a list, create a table, create a
link. I already showed create a link.
Create any link. So, there are different
type of links. For example, let me show
you another one. So,
for example, if you got a URL, okay? So,
let's see.
Uh Amazon, so
uh
So, let's say you got a URL, okay?
Digital pen.
So, you paste the URL and you can make a
URL. So, let's put it here, okay? So, do
it, it becomes URL. But, sometimes you
don't want you don't want the that
format. You want, for example, let me
show you, okay?
So, here is a CSS file. I did a I did a
video about a month ago on CSS. If you
haven't already, watch it, okay? So,
this is and I I also have a tutorial on
CSS. Just search for it. Ksadi CSS
tutorial.
Or search for Ksadi visual CSS. Okay,
anyways, here's a CSS file. You copy the
file path, close it, shrink the window.
Now, you go down.
Okay, you go to the top. You You You go
here, paste the link. So, you see,
here's a CSS file. You want to link it
to become that. You see, in general, you
don't want the, you know, you don't want
the
you don't want the A, you know, link.
So, anyway, you press the key, it
automatically becomes that. And And
similarly,
uh What What if you have a JavaScript
file? For example, JavaScript. So, you
press a key, automatically become a
script link, okay? So, this is, uh
you know, the features.
Okay, so delete that. So, uh do we have
Okay, delete that, delete that. So, back
to So, create a link uh
So, create a link, create a table. So,
what else?
Close that, close that.
Embed image, we showed that. Tag
navigation, okay, this is another
fantastic thing. Fantastic, I say.
Tag navigation, you know, HTML tags,
they are a tree. So, you want to
navigate them, you press the key.
You see? Now, I want to go to the
previous beginning tag. Or I want to go
to the previous end tag.
You see?
I mean the
next beginning tag, previous beginning
tag, or next next tag and previous tag,
okay? Next tag, previous tag, you see?
Previous tag, you can press the key. Oh,
you So, if Now, let's say you want to go
to the
matching end tag, okay? Now, you press
this key. You see?
You press again, go to the matching
beginning tag. So, let's let's try
again. So, next, let's go to the next
tag here. Now, you want to go to the end
matching tag of that TD. So, you press
down arrow. So, there you go.
So, that's a tag navigation. So, this
allows you to move to anywhere you want.
What about tag selection? Let's say you
want to select the whole table tag. So,
you just press put your cursor here,
press a key, you see? You got that whole
thing selected.
What if your cursor is here? You see?
Press a key, you see you got the whole
TD tag selected. What What if What if
your cursor is here? Press a key, you
got the whole DD definition uh
uh
You know, that's a definition um
tag, you know?
And you can repeat it.
Uh okay, so anyway anyway.
So, that's some of the That's you know
uh
tag navigation.
And remove tag, there are also several
commands to remove tags. And preview in
browser, you can preview in um
in many browsers. For example, let's say
let's view this in Brave browser, okay?
This link. So, all you have to do is put
your cursor on a URL
and call I don't I don't remember what's
the key, so
HTML open Let's say Firefox.
Okay?
Uh HTML HTML open in Firefox. Press
enter.
Uh Firefox asked me to update. Okay.
Okay.
I stopped using Firefox.
So, you can use, you know, you can open
several different browsers. And by the
way, there's a great feature
that is
if your URL
is
on a link, for example, on a URL, for
example, on on a URL. Then, you call
HTML open in Let's say open in Chrome,
okay?
HTML open in Chrome.
Okay, so it opens that URL in Chrome
browser. Now, go back. Now, if your
uh if your cursor is not on a link,
let's say somewhere here, then you call
that command again,
and it will just open your current
buffer. So, it's, you know, it's a great
feature.
Okay, that's it. That's That's about it
for today. Let's see what else. What
other questions?
Uh
Thought about LaTeX. I talked about that
many times. Just search for my YouTube
video.
Search for Xahlee LaTeX.
Xah Q Q question. I touch type. What's
your new one keyboard recommendation?
Kinesis Advantage. Okay. Uh yeah.
So, Kinesis Advantage
and uh
And let let's let's show you this, okay?
So, you want to
So, the keyboard I recommend is Kinesis
Advantage, yes.
And uh Expose X
bows. Okay, this is also fantastic. I
got the keyboard right there. Okay.
Uh this is fantastic. Okay.
So, which one which one should you
choose? I mean, I cannot give you, you
know, one choice. You know, I can just
say
some of these are
the best. Okay, so I have article. Okay.
Best ergonomic keyboards. So, I give you
some choices. They are great because
depends on your Each person is
different. Okay, I talked about this
many times.
Okay, that's it for today. I I think.
Thomas picking. Okay. Just pick random
things you find interesting. Okay, how
does your package handle other web
stuff? Inline JavaScript and CSS. It
handles them fine. Haha.
Let's Let's find Okay, let's go to a
website. Okay, let's try this one. Let's
try Wikipedia. Okay.
Uh let's say philosophy.
Uh let's say Emacs. Okay, Emacs
Wikipedia. Okay.
So, we are going to Emacs Wikipedia
page. Why is it so small? Never never
ever donate to Wikipedia. Okay, because
they
they your money goes to the Jimmy
uh pocket.
Wikipedia has become like semi scam.
Okay.
Anyway, so here's a Emacs Wikipedia. On
Emacs, you press
control U to show the URL to show the
HTML. Select all, copy it, back to
Emacs, magnify,
new buffer, paste the whole thing in.
So, we are looking at the source code
of um
of the Wikipedia HTML. Now, it's take
it's slow. It's kind of Okay, it's not
too slow. Okay, so you see Emacs got a
problem
when you have a line that's, you know,
thousands of characters. Emacs becomes
slow with that.
So, anyway.
So, this is the Wikipedia
um
HTML source code
displayed using xs HTML mode. It works
just fine.
Okay, so that's you know, okay, that's
answer. I hope that answers question.
Uh next question.
My theme is horrible to look at, really?
I think it's actually great.
Okay, that's Leo. It looks great, yeah.
It's not bad how now watch volume. Okay,
so let's see what else.
Uh
really strange uh really changes your
life. Syntax coloring is really uh
interesting. How much did that take to
write?
Okay.
10 years, okay.
xs HTML I talked, you know, as you know,
in earlier I said xs HTML is now 10
years old.
But, I rewrote it
in the past 2 months.
Uh Leocardio, good morning Leocardio.
It's not really you know, many of the
features are new, but you know,
basically I rewrote the thing. So,
there's a lot improvements.
Would HTML with Mathematica or Lisp
syntax looks looks better in your
opinion? Okay, that's another topic
that I can go on for hours.
But that's it for today. No, I don't
have two monitors. I only have one.
Uh
Okay, that's it for it. That's it
for today. Thank you guys for watching.
Um
So, I think tomorrow I think tomorrow
10:00 San Francisco time, 10:00 in the
morning San Francisco time.
Uh I think I'm going to do a a live
stream again. It's been a while. It's
been a month I haven't do a done a live
stream. So, again, if you like my stuff,
okay, try go download HTML Xi HTML mod
and uh pay me, okay? PayPal and Patreon,
you know where to find it. I got links
over on my website.
Anything else, okay? We we shut down in
2 minutes. Anything else?
Paul Edward
Uh where are you from, Paul Edward? I
forgot.
And uh Leo Cardo, I always forgot where
you from, Leo Cardo.
Okay, that's it for today, okay?
So, let's see what we talked about. So,
we demonstrated Xi HTML mod. Now, look
at this huge
uh
Okay, shutting down.
So, Xi HTML mod and what is So, this So,
this is a source code of Wikipedia. You
know, sometime you know
because I've been coding HTML since 1996
and uh I do frequently look at how, you
know,
others website do things.
Uh you know, because over the past 25
years HTML, of course, they have
changed.
Oh, there are big big and small changes,
you know, the fashion and fads.
You know, some tags become obsolete. You
know, beginning in the beginning you
have HTML 2, 1995.
Then you have HTML 3. Then you have HTML
4. You know, 1995 HTML 2. Then HTML 3,
okay.
Around there, 1998 or something. Then
CSS got invented. You know, there is no
CSS before. CSS, 1999 or so. And
it didn't be
People don't like it. People don't use
it until much later, like 2002 or so. It
becomes more and more popular. CSS,
cascading style sheet. Then XML, you
know, HTML, then you have XML and HT-
XHTML, you know.
That become That becomes the a trend,
you know, that
you know, everybody is saying you you
need to switch to XML XML or XHTML. Then
the HTML 5, the What the
group came up. That's made of Opera,
made of Opera, Apple, and eventually
Google. You know, they were going to
overthrow the HTML W3C standard. They
created HTML 5. Why? Because they You
know, they say they say screw XML. We
don't like XML. We want We want a new We
are going to We are We are going to be
the standard, you know.
you, W3C.
You know, the power struggle among the
open source heads.
So, HTML HTML 5 is a abomination.
Long story, you know, I I think I talked
about this in my past videos, too, you
know, the history of HTML. So, um
um
you know, HTML 5, why is it invented?
Because Apple wanted you know, they they
they they they created iPhone. They want
canvas, you know, so they can, you know,
they don't want to use they don't want
to use Adobe, they don't want to use
SVG. They they invented they want to use
canvas, you know, so they
So, for reasons like that, basically
canvas canvas is one of the big reason
HTML5,
you know, the what the group HTML5
got created. And for for about 5 years,
there are two HTML standards.
One is from the what the group, you
know,
from Apple, Opera, and Google, you know.
And the other one is W3C.
So, there's two HTML standards.
Then eventually they merged, you know,
they finally agreed to
merge their standard, you know,
uh about 2 years ago.
Uh lots of uh struggles, you know, power
struggles.
Uh
why does that happen? Well, mostly it's
all because money, okay?
Because money. Because, you know,
So, anyway, so here's Wikipedia, you
know, one thing they, you know, one
thing is that every tag, you know, they
have this long giant line.
Uh let's So, let's do a find
replacement.
Let's add a line to
uh between all the tags.
So, now we added the line. Let's use uh
Tsar HTML feature of navigation.
Uh navigating the
So,
let's
Okay, so wait, let me show the pink
window. So, let's start navigate the to
the beginning and next tag, okay? So,
beginning tag, beginning tag, so you can
see
go to the beginning tag.
Go to the end of that. Okay, so there's
no end. Let's see. Let's go to the
previous tag, previous tag. Go to the
end. It works. Okay, go to the previous
tag, go to the end, jump back, go to the
previous tag. Next tag, next previous
previous pre previous.
Matching tag previous, okay. So, we are
navigating the Wikipedia's
HTML source code.
Uh what what else? Okay, so it's a long
document, okay. So, anyway, a lot of
lists.
Okay, so let's go to the top. So, you
can see they come Okay, so so here is
the JavaScript. Here is the part where
they want to know which part of the
document have you been looking.
And they're going to send it to Google.
You know, this is amazing. Let me let me
ramble about this thing about Wikipedia,
okay. Remember, never donate to
Wikipedia because they become, you know,
your money goes mostly half of your
money. Like a million dollars,
something.
You know, goes through the Jimbo Wales'
pocket.
Every time he give a talk, you know,
he's got he gets like
$100,000
or you know, something like that.
You know, but they
anyway, so don't donate Wikipedia. I
have an article on that. In fact, if you
go check my videos about two or three
ago, I have a
a video a talk show talking about
encyclopedias,
basically for 40 minutes about all about
encyclopedias.
So, now we are looking at JavaScript
code, okay. So, you can see this
JavaScript code. Let's see how big is
it. Let's jump to the end. So, if we
copy that
Okay, so
copy that, new buffer, paste it. So, how
many lines of code is that?
Okay, uh
4K characters. Okay, here's the
JavaScript, 4K characters.
So, what uh
what uh was I going to say? You know,
you need to So, you need to actually
make them into a
Now, they actually don't
Okay, so actually so you see, you cannot
even line break them because
Why can't I line break this part? Well,
because they are so
tightly uh
closed together, something like that.
Oh, you cannot You see,
you see, you call fill region. Okay, so
let's see. You call fill paragraph.
It doesn't It doesn't even cut it.
You see, fill paragraph is a command
that makes you,
you know, inserts empty lines into it.
But, if you call it, it doesn't even do
it because
because these characters
So, that shouldn't
happen, you know, because the
Because basically because there's no
white space.
You know, so this is kind of the
This is a generated code. That's why
they look like that, ugly crap. So, what
is it, JavaScript do anyway?
Document class name client job
JavaScript. Okay, then then Okay,
whatever.
Oh, yeah, let me I want to mention uh so
So, go to uh
go to Xavi JavaScript Web Dev, okay? Let
me tell you a story about JavaScript
about Wikipedia. I discovered recently,
you see?
So, here is a taskbar.
I mean the browser task manager. You can
see so here is the Wikipedia
uh tab road skating. So, you know,
Wikipedia article. And it's load it has
a subframe.
And it's loading
googleaccounts.google.com.
What the Wikipedia
Yeah, Wikipedia. Why is it so when you
visit Wikipedia Wikipedia
it's loading
uh JavaScript in a hidden frame, okay?
Let's Let me show you. Let's try again,
okay? So, you can see So, we are doing
some you know,
uh magic of uh HTML, you know, Web Dev.
So, we are using the you know, browser.
Let's see what I want to do. Oh, yeah.
So, first of all, turn off that. So,
Wikipedia
Let's see the network.
Okay? So, refresh.
So, Wikipedia uh
loading
Oh, so and also I have the you know, I
have the um
the uBlock Origin on.
So,
that maybe blocks it out. But if you I
you know,
Let's see where
Let's see.
Let's say if I Let's turn it off, okay?
Refresh.
So, let's uh Google. Let's show the
um
more tools.
Task manager, okay?
Subframe YouTube. So,
So, right now it's not showing it.
So, I don't any anyway, so you know,
that's uh something interesting I found
about Wikipedia.
It's um
you know, if you go to the road skating
page, it has a subframe to Google.
Wait, am I mistaken?
Maybe I'm mistaken. The subframe must be
maybe it's YouTube. Okay. Yeah. Okay.
I'm mistaken there.
Okay. Bye, guys.
Bye, guys.
Fuzzing, no, I haven't played with
Arduino.
I'm happy XML died. XML is good, okay?
HTML5 is not good.
Close the video.