good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of xsa talk show
uh today is 2020. what day it is today
august 26th when wednesday august 26
and 4 o'clock p.m in the afternoon san
francisco time
and today we are going to talk about
emacs basically uh i'm going to
uh work on uh my website with using
emacs so you're gonna
see my workflow and stuff and let's talk
random about emacs or keyboards
so first of all let me show you the
cell keyboard one of the the very first
one
the very first lisp keyboard it is
this keyboard that started the list
evolution uh revolution
well it begins it all so this cell
keyboard
is from 1970 okay 1970.
now let me check my status so good
morning guys good morning
allen and alan and
clawfoot and good morning danielle uh
so shall we continue am i alive
okay so that's good my video is going my
audio is
going so cell keyboard let me tell you
about the cell keyboard the grand daddy
of these keyboards and these
keyboards are in some way are the
granddaddy of all the keyboards let me
tell you so this keyboard
cell keyboard from stanford ai lab
cell is cell s-a-i-l it stands for
stanford a.i lab artificial intelligence
from 1970
and the stanford ai lab is started by
this guy
okay it's started by the guy who
invented
lisp the programming language john
mccarthy
okay john mccarthy started started the
stanford ai lab
in 1963. now you see in 1963 those are
the very old days
they are still using punch cards but
then we have this keyboard
cell keyboard you can see it's got a
control key now ctrl key is already
there by that time i think i'm pretty
sure
but it's got meta okay so it's got meta
key
uh you know today you have an old key
you can see there's old key
so you know on on the mac you have the
command key you know the mac command key
began
in 1980s in 1987 also
where does the command key idea came
from it came from this keyboard okay
it came from the cell keyboard
so this cell keyboard now now notice so
you
also have you also have these
math symbols and greek on them
and so 1970 and this is this is even
before the space cadet keyboard
and also you see you see the arrow
uh labels on the keys that precedes
so this is probably i think i'm not too
sure but i think this is the first
keyboard
that started to have arrow keys now this
is not uh not stand on
a long arrow keys but it's the beginning
you know then
later on then adam the adm
3 keyboard that the vi started on you
know
have error symbols on them so that's a
sales
sales keyboard so sales keyboard give
gave way to the knight keyboard
you started to have list machines the
knight keyboard
the end then the knight keyboard is the
daddy
of the most famous space cadet keyboard
we talked about a little bit uh
yesterday
and uh you know i talked about this
keyboard
uh a bunch of times in in my past video
so let's see what's what's up good
afternoon cortes good morning
bot okay i think so so
that keyboard sales key cell keyboard is
the
um the background of today's image so
you see these are the
list machines the lambda machine one of
the very
uh first one list machines
it's you know it's very large it's it's
like the
size of a refrigerator
okay that's about sales keyboard um
and i want to tell you the history of
arrow keys the arrow keys arrangement
and then we're gonna get on to emacs
okay the so
so it's a sales cell keyboard that has
the
arrow symbols on the keys i think that's
the first one
i'm not too sure uh by the way so all
the
photos you've seen of the cell keyboard
they are from this guy uh this guy
uh martin
why curry okay he is also a somewhat
famous popular programmer now he
is this guy is at least this this guy is
a keyboard expert okay
so he is writing a book i don't know if
it's published
yet he is writing a book on keyboard
history
so of all the people i know of keyboards
of all the
you know people that are keyboard
experts
some of them collects antique keyboards
you know 1970s 1960s
uh you know they have hundreds of them i
know a couple of people they have
hundreds
collects hundreds of uh antique
keyboards computer keyboards
of course there are also people who
collect antique typewriters that's even
earlier 100 years ago
and there are also keyboard you know key
switch
experts you know uh some people focus on
the mechanisms of key switch and of
course we have a lot of do-it-yourself
keyboard experts
of all the people who knows about
keyboards i
as far as i know in my experience so
this guy
this guy must sing white curry i'm not
sure how do you pronounce his name i
think he's originally from northern
europe
he he is the i would say he's the uh
keyboard history
expert the top real
historian of keyboards so he would know
you know all everything about computer
keyboards the history of it and he's he
he is writing a book i don't know if
what's the status of the book
i don't know if it's published or not so
anyway
and he you know he traveled he go to all
the museums or visit
people to take photos to do research on
keyboard history so all the photos
you've seen
of the cell keyboard for example this
one is from him
you know the cell keyboard
uh of course you know it's interesting
like in online
the most famous this keyboard is a space
cadet
you know partly because of the name
probably because it's got all these
fantastic symbols you know weird keys
thumb keys
and the roman numeral keys okay hold on
a second let me close my window i have
guests
okay so
so yeah i was saying you know the space
cadet keyboard if you are
if you are into these keyboards i'm sure
this is the first one you hear
you know the meta control meta super
hyper keys and
and greek keys and also apr keys
however you know so this is a most
popular but
actually if we if we want to trace the
most important historical
this keyboard it should be the cell
keyboard because
the cell keyboard is the father of these
keyboards
okay cell keyboard then of course then
then
this one is famous i talked about a few
times the
adm3a terminal this
is the computer the terminal you know
back then it's just a terminal that
began
the vi the vis began on this
on this computer was born from this
computer
and you can see the famous vi
arrow keys hjkl by the way of you
let me put on a thing of you
vi users this arrangement you know this
interesting question about the arrow key
arrangement
which how do you arrange errors so that
it's most efficient
this vi way hjkl is pretty efficient but
actually it's not optimal okay i because
i've done
in fact i've talked i've made a video a
live stream about this issue
uh i have a page on it i'll show you in
a moment
maybe but anyway on this page i'm
talking about
this is still work on pr work in
progress arrow keys the history
the his uh kind of history of arrow keys
and
and the the possible arrangement of
arrows
so first of all you have inverted t now
this one
most of us this is the most popular of
course
the first keyboard that began the
inverted inverted t is this one
deck vt 220 terminal
now this one is uh this one began in
what year
uh i have the year here
i didn't write it here but if you go to
history
deck 220 terminal okay
uh here 1983
so so 1983 dec vt 220 terminal
and it comes with the keyboard with this
inverted t arrow arrangement that's the
first one
and this keyboard uh it this keyboard is
is uh the model name is deck lk
201 so this is the first
keyword with the inverted t layout
and there is actually a story about why
why they created a
you know why they that why did they do
it that way
because it turns out this guy who
created who designed the keyboard it
turns out this
arrangement of arrow keys is actually
the most efficient okay
now he's got a website i link to
uh i'm still working on my page but you
can at the bottom you can
go to see his website this guy is jim
jim burrows so in 1998
he wrote an article history of the
inverted t
arrow key arrangement on keyboard he
wrote article 1998
jim burrows here is his article okay
now his article is uh you know this is
the
you are looking at 1998's web 1998
web design uh it looks like this okay
so you see all the figures are very
pretty small
you know and the phone is pretty small i
have to enlarge
several times so right now it's enlarged
200 percent
so so you see there are several
ways to arrange the arrow keys and then
he also covered the vt100 arrow key
arrangement
wait this is up down left right
you know that you know many uh different
arrangement it
it you know you read his article it
turns out the inverted t
is actually the most sufficient meaning
that
if you are going to let's say if you are
going to play pac-man
you know the pac-man the inverted t
will require the least amount of finger
movement
okay so this is gonna be
uh
disruption for you veeam uh
phonetics the yeah so okay so that's his
article
and of course here is my article
with computational study calculation
about which which arrangement is uh more
efficient
is it the vims hjkl or is it
inverted t i j k l
so there is actually a javascript code
you can type numbers you know type the
frequency and so on and
come out a number okay so by the way
there is a game
called google pacman i don't know if you
guys seen it
it was very famous about 10 years ago
google pacman
it's one of the google studio so you can
play
let's see if i can play magnify magnify
magnify
magnify insert coin
okay it's uh it probably require cookies
okay yeah so i i cannot play okay copy
the link
go back to the youtube good morning
reaper
any comments comments and questions post
it okay
so there is google pac-man let's see if
we can play
insert coin there it is
now i'm on this kinesis keyboard where
the arrows are separated
to left and right so i don't i don't
know if
i don't play well so by the way this
google pacman
is written by closet
google pac-man is written by this guy
okay close it let me show you
google pac-man close it
written by this guy this keyboard
history expert
martin why curry he he was
working at google i'm not sure he maybe
he's still working at google so
it is actually he who wrote that google
pacman
you know so this guy is very interesting
he studied things
uh many things he studied
in depth you know he he's a guy who
tends to study something in depth
that like he will go very deep research
the history spending
months to research the history and he
he happens to also be a javascript
expert
so javascript expert keyboard expert
both of which i'm
also also very interested but the other
thing another thing he study is
um for example he study fonts okay
in-depth fonts in depth i i
am by the way i'm also uh very
interested in fonts and symbology
you know you guys have seen my unicode
page right
i talk about that often let's say
unicode arrows
okay let me show you my unicode page
this is my marketing
department talking
uh unicode [ __ ] i'm on the third place
now
i should be the third the first place
where people steal
my ideas like you know somewhat
[ __ ] what [ __ ] my page is not even
it becomes fifth page [ __ ]
anyway so the unicode arrows so here's
my unicode pages you know you
study of symbology you know but anyway
back to the guy okay
this guy uh martin why curry he also
studied he has a great interest in font
and he studied font fonts in depth
and in fact he has done some google you
know presentation at google google
google
google i o you know one of those google
um
conferences he has talked about uh
funds ligatures and things like that
that that i think is crap so anyway
so that that's this guy okay uh martin
why curry and he also has he has written
another
you know quite a few javascript apps
that's
uh very interesting you know i i'm very
interested
okay so that's about that guys so let's
go back to
the list keyboard let's yeah let's go
back to the arrow key arrangement so let
me let me show you the arrow key which
arrangement so inverted t that's more
sufficient okay
then you have uh left down up right
which is which is the vi uh keys okay
left down upright the first one
to use this arrangement i believe is
the vise you know adm3a terminal
then you have up down left right
you know another interesting very
variation and this one is used on
deck vt100 terminal
okay up down left right and
actually it's positioned on upper right
you see it's
interesting position on upper right
you know row uh of the keyboard
then you have apples you know apples
left
right down up let's let's look at one of
them
okay apple uh so this
this is what 1983
so let's show here it is you see
left right down up
apple and apple has you know all
basically all apple keyboards
they have that left right down up
including this apple standard keyboard
1987. so apple key arrangement you know
apple's
uh left right up down left right down up
then you have the cross arrangement
like a cross you can see
in this lisp keyboard xerox
1109 this keyboard across
uh the cross is no good okay it's the
most inefficient
however it should win a word for the
most
uh intuitive because you know up down
left right that's the most intuitive
actually but it's the least efficient
uh there are quite a few so you have
these keyboards
ergonomics my key keyboard okay i
uh they have a here you can see on the
left
you have this circle for the function
keys then you have this
you know in the middle of the circle you
have the arrow keys
and then there is also these home
computer
panasonic from japan you can see the
arrows
it's a in a cross arrangement but
however it's it's
kind of the got the diagonal uh
cuts
and in fact if you have a cross like
that with the diagonal cuts this is
actually more efficient
than than this you know this actual
cross greek cross by the way that cross
is called greek cross
then you have something like this okay
so so you see this one
another japanese keyboard from nec
in 1992
so you have this
uh this diamond shape
arrow arrangement and you can see also
see this on this japanese keyboard
and then microsoft also
their their microsoft natural elite
1998 also use that configuration
then you have the truly ergonomic okay
truly ergonomic you can see
on the right they have also a diamond
shaped arrangement for the arrow keys
but however
they have like a horizontal diamond so
so
instead of left and right adjacent to
each other
now they have up down adjacent to each
other
and the the left and right is separated
uh i talked to this guy and you know
i i tell i told him the best arrangement
for arrow the most sufficient way
is actually inverted t and he doesn't
agree
he says oh no this is the best okay
so he's uh he doesn't agree he think
he think he's kind of proud of the fact
that he designed this
diamond t-shaped arrow keys
for truly ergonomic so in their new
version
you can see their new version is already
out
the cleve the truly ergonomic cleave
keyboard 2018
you can also see the arrow keys is like
that
uh in my opinion it's no good okay
because
i have this keyboard thanks to him he
sent me for
review and i used i used it daily for
like
uh four years the arrow key arrangement
there is very annoying it's no good
and and it's annoying to such a degree
that
doesn't matter how you remap the keys
you just you just can't make it work i
mean it doesn't matter
you know you so i was using the truly
ergonomic you know the early
early version so i thought
you know the arrow key is very annoying
so i thought maybe make this
one of the key control or one of the key
oats and put the arrow somewhere
somewhere else but doesn't it just
doesn't work out
so the arrow key is very annoying that
way
and then let me show you so so all these
arrow keys arrangement
then there is this kinesis this is
actually a
you have the separated hand for arrow
keys
so so i like on this keyboard uh let me
show
is there a clear picture let me show you
so the left hand you can see the here
here's a picture the left hand you have
left right for the left right arrows
the up down arrows are on the right hand
up down
arrows uh
i don't i don't really like it okay i've
been using this keyboard for by now
four or five years it's still my current
keyboard let me show you
comments questions posted okay rank wars
so let me show you as a routine hold on
a second
okay that my configuration doesn't work
so let me just show you
so you can see again i'm showing you my
keyboard
this is the kinesis advantage too
you go to my website watch read my
reviews and watch the video
review and buy it then there is this
this uh ultimate hacking keyboard which
i'm using as a keypad
fantastic so you can see
it can you know i owe single key press
operations
so anyway so the truly i mean the the
the um kinesis advantage you see
this is the arrows up and down
and on the left side you have left and
right
so let me let me talk about let me tell
you about that
how do i think about that arrangement
so in in this range so you know you
separate two left and right let's see
if i can find the better picture okay
let's go here
let's go up let's go uh do it yourself
let's go ergo docs ergodox is the most
um
okay anyway so google docs there is a
standard arrangement anyway this guy
puts
left up down right
that's the same as vi i think
so i'm trying to find okay so you look
at this one
this one is using a custom keycaps
using elfish alphabet elfish language
tengwa artificial language construct
constructed
constructed language from lord of the
rings
uh very beautiful all these you know
symbology so anyway look at the arrow
key arrangement of this guy has chosen
so
up down for the right hand and left
right for the left hand
so this arrangement in theory
in theory it's pretty it's very good
because you use both hands instead of
using one hand
you if you use one hand then you have to
move a lot
now if you use both hands because if
if you use one hand you have three
fingers but you have four keys
that means you have to switch fingers to
different keys
when you play pacman but with this
uh both hands all your fingers are on
keys so
in theory this should be the most
efficient
when you want to use the arrow keys
heavily such as when you play pacman
but but it's kind of annoying um
i didn't really like it by now i'm used
to it but i
but i still play pac-man much better if
if i use one single finger on it
i mean single hand on a inverted t
layout so i don't i don't really like
these separate uh hands
arrow key arrangement so uh
anton zappaco says hexa just got the
ultimate hacking keyboard
do you think i should swap to a tactile
instead
oh yeah if you want to uh doctor is
certainly better
obviously i mean ultimate ultimate
hacking keyboard is fantastic okay
no mistake about that but
um you know if you don't know let me
show you okay so
here is ultimate hacking keyboard for
those of you
haven't seen wait so you go to ergonomic
keyboards
then you go to uh ultimate hacking
so that's the ultimate hacking keyboard
you know it's fantastic 230 dollars
something like that
plus if you want to buy the wrist pad
it's more like 250 260.
so this is very good um
but if you want if you are more
concerned about ergonomics
so you have you know tactile tactile is
a do-it-yourself keyboard
so why is it better because it's more
ergonomic you got
curved surface you know
yeah it's up to you because if you go
with the tactile then
it's not portable anymore it's this is
problematic if you want to bring to
uh if you travel or go to work with a
keyboard you know doesn't
you cannot carry it
so if you are on the go often the
the ultimate hacking is much more
suitable
so i think that's about it about the
keyboards
for today let's maybe let's do some
emacs
what do you guys say
uh so about arrow keys about
cell cells keyboard
okay comments okay comments and then and
uh let me
uh any things you comment i'll talk
about that
so how long have i been talking i've
been talking for 30 minutes
okay so we have like 30 minutes more so
pick a topic
pick something something you would be
interested to hear like you if you have
a question you want to ask me
don't you know i'm i'm not asking for
suggestion of a topic you know don't
don't think about oh
you know let's suggest something no
something if you want
me to talk about then you post it i'll
talk about it
so i have some corrections uh yesterday
we talked about
emax uh
let's see it's not the same as vi okay
it's not the same okay
so yesterday we talked about i was
giving a reaction on the speed bar and
tree max basically i don't have good
words
for them not much the speed bar i could
adapt i could use but not remax actually
so
so someone told me so let's let's try it
okay
so again back to my emacs magnify
magnify
now go go to the directory uh go to up
go up the directory
then start speed speed bar start speed
bar magnify
and let's make it bigger so
you can see all my directories okay
you can see all my directories so i was
trying to find a command to expand all
the directories so the key
is left square bracket okay
so let's type it
oh wait oh it takes a while okay i guess
yeah this is uh they are like
there are about 20 000
files in this directory so it's actually
taking a while
20 000 files i'm you know
okay it's still showing
wow 20 000 files it's gonna take a while
i guess
it could be actually there there might
be 30
000 files because most you know
more than half of them are image files
okay so i guess e-max is stuck
all my cpus are maxed out almost
well the you know when it's slow
most of the time when your computer is
slow most of the time is disk
us access like right now
it's trying to access tens of
direct tens of directories and listing
you know
20 000 files i i guess that's why
so emacs i guess it's stuck
speed bar 30 000 files
it's not responding
so anton got a new chalkboard
so which one did you get
okay maybe maybe i should stop
this speed bar
just too much for it to handle
you can see at the bottom of the e-max
mini buffer
you can see it's trying to update it's
trying to go to
it looks like it's trying to go to
why is it um
it's trying to go through each directory
yeah it's still doing that
x keys trackable lights blue okay so you
got x keys trackball so let's talk about
that
uh speedbar is still going so let's go
to okay so let's show
go to trackball
the x keys trackball is one of the best
trackball it was known as l
track but they they sold
the company after 30 years they sold the
company
uh last year in 2019
and they sold it to the x-key there's a
company called
key so so this is this one
by the way so this trackball is known
for as the
best quality uh as far as quality goes
this is the best quality trackball
but not necessarily the best trackball
because it's the best build okay best
build but not necessarily the best
because for
trackball there are lots of different
issues and concerns mostly for example
the design
the shape of the trackball so different
people actually prefer a different shape
but ltrack is one of the best uh the
best
build and um you know
and okay so you know if you guys anyone
like it but go
go to my website buy it and i think you
bought it
for my website right anton thank you for
that
so let's see next comments or question
uh
is this key bind to expand directories
uh default or is it a custom it's
default
so you start on e-max in e-max you start
up speed bar
then you press then you put the cursor
on the speed bar window
then you press left square bracket
now it's too slow we're gonna stop it
ctrl q uh ctrl
g okay let's see if it will respond to
my control g
this directory is too big for it to
handle
control g stop it
stop it okay
e max you know this is one number the
problem of emacs
now this rainbow the rainbow of death
on the mac the rainbow of death
so emax one of the the
the almost the number one problem of
emacs is that
it's said to be single threaded what it
means
is that when emacs is doing something
it cannot do any other thing it has to
wait until that thing is done
so right now it's trying to open okay
cancel successful
okay it worked so here's the speed bar
you can see
my whole entire directory is a tree now
this is actually
yeah i'm telling you so this is 30
000 pages that's why it takes so long
and it's not done yet let's see if i can
page down
30 000 pages yeah so page down
speed bar so speed bar is great i might
use it sometimes
speed bar is building okay
so what does that uh so these are what
does that
connect it mean okay so you see it
haven't it hasn't opened all these yet
because of 3000 pages
yeah anyway so that's speed bar
yeah so someone corrected me thank you
for that yesterday
and uh there is another correction
so yesterday i was also reviewing the
tree max
package which
which allows you allows you to view a
directory
as a tree as a tree structure
and navigate among the files and i do
not recommend tree
max at all one of the reason is because
it uses the dash package
okay so let's go to my emacs let's close
that
go to my emacs uh blog
okay go to my emacs blog and
close okay wait
uh what are we doing
oh god now i'm trying to switch to speed
bar
and it's stuck again okay
ctrl g cancel cancel cancel okay
now i'm gonna quit speed bar okay
close it can we
close it uh do you want to save
speed bar modified do you want to save
no
okay close split so go to my
emacs blog
and then go to emacs
why not use dash okay open the file
so you can see yesterday i talked about
why not use dash
near the end of the video so i created a
page for it
uh let me repeat the reasons okay why
why why
why i actually i despise dash okay i
despise the dash library
dash library is one of the the most
actually it is the most
the top five most popular
package on melpa you know it's got tens
of thousands or hundred thousand
downloads
why because it's a library that is
meant to be a modern lisp
modern list processing api so it
basically
contains a bunch of functions that
processes
list you know lisp lisp
emacs lisp the the word lisp stand for
list processor so when you use you know
lisp languages because everything in
lisp
is a list that's what you know because
it's you know it's said in a name it's a
list processor
so it's kind of ridiculous i mean it's
kind of preposterous it's an
insult to the lisp language
when when you have a list language a
list processor at least language
list you know then you have another
language
another you need another package to help
you process
lists you know you need to call another
package
to help you to help your list functions
what the [ __ ] that's an insult to the
language
and that is what dash does okay dash
it becomes the most popular why why so
why why why is it most popular because
the
incompetence of the gnu emacs people
you know they sit here they sit there
they don't change nothing because you
know
they are gods you know they don't listen
to anything
but the society moves on the pearl you
know the python
it has several compilers you know new
completely new compilers they
listen to what people need programmers
you you know take suggestions
improve uh after three five years a
complete new
pro compiler after five years another
complete totally
re compile the written from the ground
up
same thing with javascript one two three
four five seven
compilers same thing with php new
compilers every five ten years
okay or even a complete new language
from facebook
hack lan okay php a new version of
php hackline python python 2 python
three
complete you know new fixes and all that
when it comes to emax list no change no
change
so emac list functions they don't even
have basic stream
manipulation functions you know such as
stream stream stream
dream stream in emac list
the language that's the most that's
designed for least
for for you know text processing
you don't have a function that trims
stream
uh string that like remove the the
the white space in front of the string
or and end of string you don't have that
function
doesn't exist until five years ago
imagine that
why does it exist now because someone
else
you know they saw they saw the
popularity of dash
they inspired them to write another
package called
s you know this these people they this
new millennium generation people called
us they
they created the package named s
which is supposed to be the modern api
for uh string functions you know they
are trying to
replace you know you know they write a
wrapper kind of thing
on top of emac this
you know so so i don't i don't so i
despise these
libraries but there are good reasons for
why these libraries becomes popular
because the new emacs people
the new emacs dev they have lots of
problems
political problems organization problems
they don't change they don't listen and
you
have to sign everything you try to
contribute you have to sign a paper
lots of problems and people there many
are obese they argue they don't they
refuse to change
lots of problems i talked about this
many times
for example you go to my emacs blog
you go to my emacs blog you go to the
home page
you click the yellow navigation
button you go to the home page you go to
the
emax modernization then you have a
collection of emax problems but that's
not it okay you go to the
emacs miscellaneous index
you know i did a video talking about
some of these problems
then you then you have this collection
of articles titled emacs controversy
now these are instant incidents i have
collected
about emacs problems controversies like
every
every three or four years there's a huge
controversy
the rich richard stowman did something
you know
so you can see the problems you know so
emac these
for 20 you know they don't make
improvements you know they
there's some improvements but not
nowhere comparable to
the real world you know the like php
python
ruby or javascript what's going on they
like the emacs people they live
in a hall they live in a cave they have
their own word
free software free software foundation
their word you know they are like a
commune
and the emacs people of the emacs
phonetics every day they are saying oh
emacs this is the best best language oh
emacs can do
everything crap you know it's all crap
i i am a emacs lisp fan
i like emacs this and e-max to improve i
i live in e-max for 20 years by now i
like it i
want to improve but i don't want crap i
don't want i don't i don't want code
all right i don't want something that's
untrue that's
you know kept spreading around untrue
things like that so i talked about you
know that's why people they buy me they
don't like me you know i
you know they just you know so anyway
the dash package
the dash becomes hugely popular because
on one hand the emacs the gnu emac list
they refuse to improve
so there comes dash a
modern api this male engine they say
this modern api
so it becomes hugely popular almost
every package on mailbox uses it
and then then five years ago about five
years finally the emac
the gnu emax people finally
improved emac these they wrote a new
package
now it's part of emacs it's part of
now it's part of uh bundled you know
it's part of the e-magles
core that has those functions let me
show you okay
uh so so emacs so let's go to
uh where do we go to we you you know you
go to my emacs blog home page
you go to emac this
tutorial and you go down
and you see this is my tutorial on emac
this
you can learn emaclis from the ground up
then i explain this
vector sequence type sequence functions
okay so here this page
teaches you about all functions that
manipulate
list or vector or array you know these
in e-magnets
all these are called sequences sequence
data type
so so then you can see here sequence
functions
there are there there are like 20 of
them all these are new
20 30 of them all these all these
uh for example for example sequence p
uh copy sequence uh
reverse and reverse sort
some of them are old okay but uh 20 of
them are new sequence drop sequence take
so these are new this began in 2016
starting in uh emax 25 2016.
so it's four years ago gnu e max
people finally added this why because
of dash they see that dash is
all hugely popular then they finally
realized
oh my god we actually need these
functions in d magnets
so that's why you know they added this
so that's about dash you know i don't
like it because it's not
it you know personally i don't like it
because
it's kind of a rapper it's trying to
modernize
things on the other hand they have a
point because emac these
people they refuse to change you know if
you try to be nice you know you go to
emacs dev and try you know
hey guys you know i wrote this could you
possibly uh
maybe we could uh put it in emacs they
will not listen you know you are
you are nobody nobody give a [ __ ] about
you that's what happens in the emacs
this
step you know every you know it doesn't
matter who you are even if you are a
well-known
celebrity you if you even if you are a
head
you know tech leader of google they
don't give a [ __ ] about you
the god the only god there is a god in
imax list
dev that's richard stowman who have not
coded a single line of code for 20 years
something like that for at least 10
years he doesn't you know he doesn't
know what he's
coding anymore he was a great he was one
of the greatest
coder 30 years ago for you know 14 years
also
but he haven't quoted at least 10 years
10 or 20.
but anyways you know he's the only god
nobody you don't
most people don't even know who who made
all these emacs
improvements you know there's a code
problem there's a serious problem
every time every time when i do a video
i
i i talk about these things i started to
flame these people
then you start to see thumb down okay
you will start to see
thumb down on my youtube that's the
condition of the society okay nothing
you know that's just what happens
okay so we have been talking for how
long for like
uh 15 minutes maybe that's it for today
50 minutes
so let's read some comments um
actually there's something i want to
tell you uh
dash and what else there's some
corrections
oh yeah so another correction i want to
make uh so yesterday we talked about
tree max
one of the thing i i said is that tree
max uses a
idiosyncratic buffer but
this guy rick ricknam says
3max buffers aren't magic
they use an emax feature called slide
windows
you can toggle them with window toggle
side windows
which is pretty handy or clear it with
key of this buffer okay
okay so i stand corrected i will look
into maybe he's right
uh you know he's i haven't looked into
so i would say 99 percent probability
he's correct
but sometimes they are wrong you know
sometimes when i look into exactly
another case
anyway so so this uh apparently there's
a new feature
or maybe it's an old feature it's called
the emacs
list called site windows i'm not aware
of you know i i'm not
i'm not a that great uh lisp coder
there's
a lot of people who know uh emac is
much better than me
okay so let's see what are the comments
uh
and post your comments uh and we shut
down maybe we'll probably shut down
soon down of okay so yeah emacs
also i got my first trackball okay so
not much comments
uh is this keybind to expand directory
default yeah it's default what
sign sign in your paper yeah you don't
know
you know you young people new generation
don't know this anymore so
guru emacs free software foundation
if you want to contribute code to emacs
well the easiest way is you know you
just write code and put it on mailpad
everyone can use it okay and also you
have to use
gnu gpl3 it must be
version three version two is no longer
allowed
because three years ago i have an
article on that
i you know i mentioned before you go to
this page you'll find the article
three about three years ago i can show
you here okay
2017 three years ago richard snowman
told
tells other people to kick out
any packages on melpa
that is not using gpl3
so gpr2 is not enough you know you know
free software foundation gpr2 that's not
not good enough
he tells people to tell other people
to to to use gpr3 so and the male power
people
i know the melpa people so they collab
they conceded
they you know they they started to kick
about
five or ten you they started to contact
those people tell them to upgrade to
gpr3 and eventually kick out
packages that's using gpr2 or some
others you know
so my so back then my all my packages i
have like five
about five packages on mailpad i'm all
using gpl too not gpr3 it's a big
controversy okay
gpr2 versus three for example linus
traverts
the guy who create who wrote linus
linux he he flame you know gpr3
according to him is not ethical you know
because gpr3 tries to enforce
anyway that's a big controversy i'm not
going to get into okay
gpr2 is good okay so
anyway so richard snowman they tell
other people to kick out
gpr2 and and it happened
you know so then the male part people
are quietly you know
they don't they don't make an
announcement in in my opinion
that's evil okay that's the one of the
evil deed but
i don't blame the them you know like
these people today you know
they just follow the flow because oh
let's quietly you know
do it
anyway so that happened so i had you you
know at that point three years ago i was
thinking i'm
i have to make a decision i'm kind of
tired of
open source phonetics phoneticism and
the the open source
it becomes you know huge evil
empire in society and they essentially
made google facebook twitter you know
these
global empires that controls every
aspect
and even controlling programmers because
you have code of conduct all that google
control
and as a programmer you can no longer be
independent
because open source you know they they
work at google
these [ __ ] people working at google
facebook
make tons of money they you know if you
work
for google or any company in the bay
area here
you make ten you know ten thousand
dollars a month that's
like almost minimum ten thousand dollars
per month i'm making 1 000 not
not not even 1 000 a month if you mop
toilets at mcdonald's you make about 3
a month okay so these
people are working at google they are
open source fanatics oh good you know
that's right you know open source we
need open source they make a lot of
money
a day they work for google and uh you
know they propaganda
for open source phonetics phoneticism at
night
they write open source software open
source so
if you are independent like me you know
you you are
you know a poor sub
you write code there's no competition
for you because
whatever you write there are 10 [ __ ]
thousand
rich elite [ __ ] they are working
for google they write the same thing as
you do
they have support they are competing
with you or whatever you are doing
that's what that's that's the open
source so if you are a
supporter of open source or free
software foundation go [ __ ] yourself
right now
i'm telling you i'm i haven't been that
extreme before but right now i'm saying
this okay
go [ __ ] yourself it's time
to stop support anything open source of
free software foundation
well i still support it you know i i
still
you know i still use emacs as all my own
oh
basically all my packages software is
all open source
it's been like that for 20 years even
before
before the foundation before open source
becomes a thing
my packages in mathematica 1995 1993
it's all uh use it free
okay you know if you like to you know
there's a quote you know
if you like it you please go ahead and
use it okay this
is a good this is good spirit no open
source [ __ ]
string attached not not like like you
have to use this this this this
licenses otherwise you are evil go [ __ ]
yourself
you i write a code okay so you know feel
feel free to use it don't abuse it okay
don't abuse it
go ahead and use it and i'm not
responsible for
uh for disasters out of you know
certain minimal legal requirements
open source [ __ ] phoneticism
okay i got angry then it becomes a flame
of open
source again i guess that's it for today
uh so yeah so back to the question i i
digress you know so
so if you want to contribute code to
emax
the easiest way is just to write and put
it on mailpad okay
put it in gpr3 and put it on the mailbox
that's a go
but if you actually want to contribute
to the glue emacs
you know on their lpar repository
or on gnu emacs call you have to sign a
paper okay that that's been a case for
like
30 years ago and it's a big controversy
you know but
it's still you know is still required of
course i have to sign
paper for urgo emacs package and the
experience is not so good
it's not nice you know back and forth
delays they don't they don't give a [ __ ]
they you know that's
i can talk for another hour about that
issue you know and then i show you
articles i show you other people's
experiences and i tell you who is you
know who is doing what
that's another one hour
so who is watching eight concurrent
viewers not many okay that's it for
today
did you hear about the best ergonomic
keyboard on earth no
velocity no that's not likely
let's search for it velocifier what the
heck is that
search
demand dk6 ergo v2 make
typing better okay so
first of all let's look at images i'm
not sure i want to go to their
website oh looks like it's not bad
oh that no this one is crap
but i'm telling you this is crap
no good okay so this is one of those
keyboard
they designed so that you can adjust
your keys to different positions
whatever positions you want it's crap
why because it's too elaborate you don't
need to
you know you you rather you want
something
you know designed fixed position then
then that's it you don't want something
that's movable and you know
so what is this keyboard good for it's
good for if you are a designer
if you are a designing stage of keyboard
you are still trying to find out which
one is the best
ergonomic shape then this is maybe good
for keyboard designers
once you find out one specific
configuration
that's good then you want go manufacture
it you don't want a keyboard
where you use every day that has this
complexity okay this is
crap and also even if you are a designer
this i don't i don't think it's that
good because by now
by now after about seven years of
ergonomic keyboard evolution you know we
have lots of studies people have studied
ergonomic arrangement key arrangement
for like seven years already
we already know you know we already know
what is the best position you know
what's the thumb you don't need
you don't need to experiment anymore
okay uh
you know if you haven't seen
they are already like hundreds of
different varieties
of some key positions you know you you
can see all of them here
you don't need to you don't need that
anymore so
i don't recommend that keyboard
the attachment is super strong and it
does not move it's still no good
it's still no good but why
i don't want to see i don't i don't want
to have a keyboard where i
see this inlet in elegant complexity
crap i don't want to see those lines you
know
and of course it also adds to the cost
you know nothing comes free
you know this will add to the cost where
you have movable movable keys and things
like that okay
that's it for today uh
thank you guys for watching well
bob says every hand is unique that's
right that's why when you buy a keyboard
you pick one of these you know there are
so many choices you pick one
you use that okay
uh you don't need you know that's my
opinion okay so i might check out the
website okay so
yeah okay that's it for today thank you
guys for watching
uh if you like my stuff subscribe and
thumb
up or things like that you know support
support
the
support the consumerism uh society
and let's make everyone a dumb
i have no choice or actually the
you know the best thing to do is
actually you know let's talk about the
video the the
let's talk about the youtube phenomena
the society you know
you these days every time you watch
video people you know the
everyone is trying to make money right
except maybe except me
i'm not you know you watch your video
everyone is like
please support if please please thumb up
please subscribe
you know the girls you know girls has
their style they
smile please subscribe thumbs up
for the great peaceful words go [ __ ]
themselves
then there are the different types for
example the linux
the leaners tech review this leaner sky
he's become a multi-millionaire
his youtube videos become so rich you
know so popular he's doing
several videos per day with a full
full staff behind him this linux
linux tech review guy this number
he he style is speaking very very fast
if you like it thumbs up
if you don't like it thumbs down you
know what to do and
he you know he lena's text review he's
trying to you know he's that his style
he's kind of like trying to be cool this
cool guy he's
he's seeing it all the [ __ ] idiot the
linus
linus tech review guy yeah but
you know they in my opinion they are idi
you're kind of
like you know they are not that great
uh content but however that's how you
you become
rich you wanna you want become rich
you want to become success successful
that's that's the things you do but
you know that's uh that's what you have
to do you know somebody please thumb up
and don't talk about controversial
things you know don't say [ __ ] you [ __ ]
them
don't don't be like me okay be a dummy
in society be a [ __ ] wheel
bye