good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of star talk show
so today is
uh i'm going to do some demonstration of
emacs some emacs tutorial
and let's write some emac this code
and today it's mostly gonna be emacs
okay
so let's begin so if you have comments
and questions post it okay
so emacs
uh so today is 2022
march 12th
so first of all you know someone asked
me on twitter what is the most efficient
way to open files so let me show you
okay so if you are not if you are um
using a glue emacs you know doesn't uh
if you are using emacs so let me see
open file fast okay so open last
okay so
yeah so the most efficient way to open
file is e-max bookmark okay so uh
so i'm using e-max i'm using soft like
keys i'm using vora keyboard this is
very
physical for a keyboard this is kinesis
advantage too
and this is ultimate hacking okay so let
me show you quickly sally
keyboard
so you go to exotic keyboard
guide
then
ergonomic keyboard
let's turn on javascript so you can see
any youtube
videos okay go to ergonomic keywords and
you can see there it is this is my
keyword this is my favorite okay
and then the other one on top this one
ultimate hacking keyboard
that is the best marker the key the best
uh keyboard for macro so i have reviews
there you can see
you know i'm only showing half of the
other half is over here let's see if you
can see it
uh
yeah there so
[Music]
this is the best keyboard for program
programmable markers key markers i i
talked about them uh several times so
let's move on to today's topic so uh
yeah so emacs bookmark so let me show
you okay so xrd emacs book
mark search for that
and you'll find my tutorial so
the most efficient way is you uh to open
a file is used bookmark you know what
you should not do is never
ever
have this
you know fine file you know this open
file
uh prompt pop-up
so when this pump pop up you usually
have to navigate the directory it's it's
okay so when you find that when you find
yourself
doing this open file you know
and typing the path name and file
location
when you find yourself do this
too much you know several times a hour
stop set a bookmark to that to set that
path to a bookmark okay so let me show
you how to do that so for example you
are looking at this current file you
know let's go to diet
so let's turn on highlight uh
highlight the current line so you can
see this is the file okay this is file
show in browser this is today's you know
my today's talk show file so
and if i close it
close it you know i
how do i open that file okay so you know
usually normally you say find file then
you type the file path okay oh god i
don't know what is today's date
so two zero so that's not good okay so
whenever you need to do this often so
uh so for example
the file right now is
this talk show index page
and
if i close it if i want to open that
again
i can you know it's already in bookmark
so i just press two keys
you know this this command is called uh
let me show you okay so
uh okay
and let me move this up so you can see
the mini buffer okay let me show you so
there bookmark bookmark jump that's the
command
you want to call okay so i'm using stuff
like keys so i have a
alternative but they are
similar
okay
let me try to get to the point so i mean
the point is that
use bookmarks okay so for example i want
to go to the talk show page let's close
this
so i call bookmark jump okay then talk
show there it is okay now this is my
talk show index page showing browser you
can see
and
you know normally you know every every
week i do a talk show so if i want to go
to the current talk show that's this one
you see 2022
uh may 12th
or not march may 12th right
so i open it
open it so you can see uh today's talk
show
but if i need to open this today's talk
show often
so i just open the file
and press the key set bookmark okay not
that one
press the a key
then you can see in in a mini buffer it
says uh
you see set bookmark unconditionally you
know
then you just type a name you know
whatever
whatever name you want no you know
normally by default it suggests your
name so you can just press enter
or you can press some special character
let's say ttt okay
tdt okay
now
now this file
this file is now in a bookmark so now i
just call bookmark bookmark jump then
just type tdt it's already there by
default it you know
because
it
the first choice is the last bookmark
you set so anyway
so
the tip is never
you know never use fine file oh you know
like when you find yourself typing the
path you know a few times of the same
file
just press a button
and uh
and set bookmark okay what's the command
so the pink window shows all the command
cores i made okay so where is the
bookmark
uh
yeah bookmark set you see so we can we
can magnify this see the full glory of
this
command log
okay so
so anyway so
so i hope i'm making clear you know you
just you can read this tutorial let's
copy the file path read the tutorial i
have it you know bookmark set to set up
set the current file into the bookmark
and you can give it any name you can
give it a
some
particular letters so that it's easy to
type such as tdt
you know so bookmark set set the file to
book bookmark then
if you want to see all your bookmarks
just call this command so for me
i have the key space tt
you know because i'm using soft light
keys but otherwise in uh glue emacs is
ctrl x rl okay
so you see so here's all my bookmarks
okay close it
then whenever you want to open a file
just uh call this command bookmark jump
okay so
that
is the most important this this is how
you want to open the file okay
this is the first thing the first way
okay so
never ever
try to type a file path or navigate
directory don't do that okay
always just bookmark
okay so because this way you can
you know every day certain you usually
you know typically for most people
uh your week every week or every month
you have certain certain set of files
that you work with
you know
so
bookmark you know book so bookmark so
let's open my bookmark you know you see
how efficient it is just like you know
once you uh
become familiar with the keys you can
just you know uh is a second nature you
know
to get to uh
get to a file you know second file oh i
i just overwrote this this one but
anyway so bookmark okay
so um
so bookmark
then
okay now let me let me let me explain
what is this
open file fast you know
right now i'm using emacs 28 okay so let
me show you okay so for example
uh control u
then
meta x
version
then you can you can see
i'm using e max 28
emacs 28 has a great feature called fido
vertical mod i talked about it
about
last month okay watch my video
the entire video is on that so this
great feature
means that now when you call bookmark
jump for example
when you want to open a bookmark
it
pops up this vertical choices
and
and you don't have to you know whatever
you type doesn't have to start with the
first letter you can type whatever
characters appear in the middle of your
bookmark names so this is a great
feature in emacs 28
but before emacs 28 you don't have that
rather you you need to call i do so
that's why i have written a command
open book open file fast
so what this command do is basically
it's just like a bookmark jump okay so
let's try to call bookmark jump
uh there
it's just like bookmark jump
except that it uses uh it um
you know it uses the idoof interface
basically you know pops up choices
vertically and allows you to use flex
match to to make a selection
okay that's why i have open file fast if
you know that's part of soft light keys
in fact let me show you okay describe
key then press the key to
uh press the key for open file fast you
can see it it's the documentation it's
here
then
let's jump to the source code oh or just
read the documentation you see
so this key delete key by the way is
over here so it's right under my thumb
so
delete cr
okay it runs the command custom open
file fast found in overwriting terminal
local map which is ink soft like keys
okay
okay now and but it says it's an alias
for bookmark jump you see
why let's look at the source code okay
let's so you hit tab and enter to jump
to the source code so
you can see here is the full code
now let's
narrow to region
so that you don't see the rest of uh you
know so you can we can focus on this
file i mean this function so here's the
entire code okay so you can see i made a
change in april 7th
emacs 28 came out in april so i
installed it and it's fantastic and i
realized emacs 28 has the feeder mod so
you no longer need i do so i made a i
made some changes essentially you don't
need this command anymore if you are
using emax 28 so
so i made a command here
that uh
wait and it's
yeah it's over here so you see
if version is less than e max 28
then do nothing
but if but otherwise you know make an
alias so sound open file fast is just
now bookmark jump
provided that you also turn on fido
vertical mod okay so
so bookmark okay use bookmark
okay now there are several other tips
and tricks to open file fast for example
in right now in this file for example
i'm on the
top show index page
so
okay so that's this file now if i close
it it's closed
okay now i want to reopen it how do i do
how do you do that you cannot do that in
gnu emacs
because gnu emacs does not record
the file you closed it only record the
files you open
so if you have a file open let's say a
month ago
and a month you know and
after 30 days you have opened so many
other files
and and now
let's see um
you see
so but now
now you close the file
you you know
you cannot basically be open the last
closed so because emacs does not record
whatever file you close
but if you are using stuff like keys you
can so what i do is i just press
um
ctrl shift t okay ctrl shift t
that reopens the last close you can see
this command is open last closed
now this command is part of flight keys
um
and let's try again okay close the file
now i need to press ctrl shift t now i
have a macro with this ultimate hacking
keyboard so i just press one key there
it is so i can
open this file
and close it and close these two
reopen last closed
reopen last closed you see
fantastic convenient now let's go to
this buffer so you can see i have two
files open now let's try again close
close close
reopen last reopen last there it is show
in browser so you can see
so that command is um
open last closed
okay now let's that's part of sapphire
keys okay so let's jump to it let's look
at have a look at the source code
so describe key
press ctrl shift key t
to jump to the documentation there it is
then let's uh press tab to jump to the
source code there it is the source code
you know
just three lines of code
but in order to have this code
you need to whenever you call a command
that close a buffer it needs to record
basically
uh you know
put that
files path
into a list
so that you have a record of last closed
file so for example
uh open last closed
um let's see where is it so actually i
have a code here
you can see my website open last closed
file yeah so if you want this command
you can just copy
this code
this this code into your emacs init file
and you'll have it
okay i'm not sure emacs 28 did anything
to it i don't yeah yeah i don't think so
i don't think this feature is available
in
emacs okay that's the second way that's
one of another way to open file fast
this is very convenient this is uh
open last close very convenient
especially when you have a key
that close a file easily such as you
know for example i do so i just press
one key press one key press one key
press one key press one key you know i
just closed four files
normally in gnu emacs
you have to
control xk
let me demonstrate okay reopen reopen
reopen reopen so normally when you want
to close the file in gnu emacs you have
to
ctrl x
k
then it asks you are you sure are you
sure you want to close this file that's
not good that's idiotic okay for example
let's do it again close close close
close okay we open
real uh that the wrong key reopen reopen
reopen reopen okay
so let's look at my buffer list you see
you got four files open
close close close so close we open we
open we open reopen reopen
fantastic
let's try again the glue emax way
control x k are you sure you want to
close this one yes
close this one are you really sure
yes
control xk are you sure you know that's
no good
okay let's
let's open last
closed file open last close you can get
a code okay so this is similar to
browser you know in browser for example
ctrl w to close the tab close close
close close close close
oops i made a mistake reopen so control
shift shift t
reopen reopen reopen reopen see close
close close so close
and you can close more reopen reopen
reopen reopen reopen very convenient
and the key you see
so i made sure the key is similar to the
browser you know it's the same key for
the browser so that
so that you can have a keyboard macro it
doesn't matter i'm in a browser or i'm
in emacs i can just press this key
keyboard marker this is ctrl w close it
reopen
close close so close
the okay you know oh in imax just go
oh okay so i close too many
there's no more uh record for the close
file so
okay so that is the um that is one of
the other way to um
let's see where is my talk show so let's
show today's talk show
that is the
uh
very convenient command okay uh close
last
open last closed okay now the other
very useful command is recent dev
recent file open open
recently open file
so in emacs you have a feature that
because you know every time you open
file
it will record it
so that you can open that file again so
let me show you okay so recent dev um
[Music]
there you see here is the seven files i
recently opened you know usually the
list is like 30 50 100 files there's a
limit i i forgot you can set the limit
so basically this feature allows you to
open any file you
any
past 100 files or whatever you have
opened but it doesn't record closed file
you it
only records the last you know the
recently
uh
open file so what you do is you if you
want to open some file you recently
opened
and closed you know so you can just um
press a key in software keys it's uh
you know it's i'm using a varia keyboard
so it's space ch
on core t it will be space i k
uh yeah
so it's all on the right your right hand
home key you know the two strong fingers
this is because this is a
very useful command frequently needed so
you want to open a file you recently
opened
bam
and you can just now type a digit to
jump to it the first 10 will have a
digit
but otherwise you can just uh search
let's say search let's do search talk
show you know uh wait i typed it wrong
search
talk yeah so you know
okay so that's open recent file so uh
let me show you my um
tutorial okay sorry
open recent
okay let's just say that there it is
emacs
open recently open file
so you can read um the tutorial and
and you can put this in your init file
then you have that feature okay it's
great
okay so
anything else let's see
okay so this is my tip you know someone
asked me on twitter uh i'm sorry i don't
remember your your you guys names
because it's not real name it's always
changing so anyways someone asked me on
twitter so
this is my tip for opening files so the
first one is bookmark
okay so let me modify
most efficient way to uh open a file
okay so let me demonstrate another
another command let's just do it uh
never mind okay so open
most efficient way to open file okay we
don't need that date
we don't need that so
open file fast this is actually just
bookmark jump okay so let me
uh let me write it
describe key and get there no describe
key
uh
there it is yeah so actually you want to
use bookmark jump or
if you are in supply keys do that okay
then or this one so actually let's
let's make them
then so then
recent open files okay then then you do
find file
uh okay let's
mark them up so you can see they become
red red means
actual commands emacs commands
so then find file find file is the
command of emacs to open a file so
that is this so you have to now navigate
directory let's go to my emacs blog okay
so my emacs blog so let's close this
reopen it to get rid of the highlight
you know
so let's say now i want to open my emacs
blog
you know so you are looking at my let's
dial jump
direct jump
to go to the file the directory i'm in
so you can see my directory structure
this is
you know web saudi
talk show okay now let's say you know so
this is my website study.info now let's
say i want to open my emacs blog
which is saudi info slash emacs
you know something something
so
i have a bookmark so let's do it
okay
bookmark jump
e
e max block e and b there it is the
first choice
press enter
showing browser xr emacs blog fantastic
let's do it again
you know because it's all muscle memory
for me
uh oh uh
there okay open close back to emax close
let's do it again
there it is you know you you know
usually i don't blink on eye it's just
all muscle memory
so
yeah speaking of muscle memory another
thing you want to uh it's a efficiency
tip is that whenever you set a bookmark
whenever you set a bookmark you
you can make it so that you make the ch
you
the way you choose the file name you
want to save the bookmark us as you know
choose a name for the bookmark is that
you can make them so that
it's key stroke based instead of a name
rather based on your keystrokes so
those files that you open
open often the most often have the most
easy keystrokes so once you use it for a
while it becomes muscle memory
so because i i need to uh open emacs
blog often because i blog about emacs
often so i just uh e e e and b okay
there
um
yeah so you know
if you if i don't have the bookmark
you know so that then i call find file
then i navigate to i have to remember
you know sometimes you have hundreds of
file paths you don't remember where it
is so
bookmark saves you from that
so otherwise i type emacs okay
tab to complete then okay
okay complete that directory
and uh
you know i don't remember you know there
are there are a thousand or there are
800 files there so i have to
which one you know what is the name but
for my emacs blog probably a blog okay a
blog no match oh right so i need another
directory emacs
then
choose this directory then blog there it
is that their second choice
emacs block so now open it showing
browser there it is so
the efficiency of bookmarks remember
that okay
uh
so then there is another command i'm not
gonna i'm not going to demonstrate it uh
it shouldn't be here but anyway it's a
start open in external app for example i
go to
my emacs blog let's go to a
the directory i
open it
and i can open this in windows file
browser
you know press the key
you can see all these image file files
let's magnify so there are you know
several hundred image files
uh
you know it's my emacs blog about
or you can open an image directory like
let's say this image so press a key
okay that's a picture of the
my
laptop
ibook g4 used in 2015
to
2002 to 2005 and this
this is the laptop
that got me
repetitive strain injury this is the
reason this this is the cause because i
was you know laptops became popular and
i was using this
laptop exclusively
you know typing just on this laptop
nothing else you know for two years
every day several hours then i feel oh
my arm is not feeling right you know
something you know that that this this
is the reason okay
so
so you can switch to the next image this
also interesting because this this is a
you know you see this
huge
key at the corner
why is this corner key huge because that
allows you to use the palm you know your
palm
uh to press the control key the control
key on typical
uh pc keyboard is at the corners so now
you can a giant key so you know i have
an article on this and this image is
interesting because it's a grand
of
vim
actually not this one
no not
no no
but this one is a very popular terminal
in
1980s 1985 so something
remember back then yeah so during these
times 1985
you see this screen
this screen
is 80 characters by 40 characters okay
you can i don't know if you can see
so here is a terminal this is microsoft
terminal
and
uh anyway so anyway 880 characters by 40
characters you know
so back so basically it's pretty small
it's it's like um
you know that back then this and it
it's like this size and the screen can
only display text
uh and emax pumpkin that's interesting
interesting
um
okay anyway so
so
what i was demonstrating was some of the
my external command okay let me let me
show you the
um
let me show you where they are okay
okay there is there it is the command
okay
so open in external app okay again this
is uh part of part of stuff like keys
uh
okay so here's the source code so if you
don't know what it is what if you don't
know what clock stuff like key is
you can see just search for it you can
see um have a page okay i think that's
it for today let's you know
i was gonna do something else i was
going to do some e-max coding and some
other things but
i think that's let that just be it so
today this video is just uh
efficient ways to open file in emacs
okay any comments
oh i got a few people awesome
celtic orthodox i forgot what's your
name on discord
you guys using nicknames
jacob l from discord okay oh yeah i
remember you
uh jacob
and ludwig no way uh none quality layout
yes that's what i'm using
anything else i think that's it
uh yeah so how long have i been talking
30 30 minutes yeah so let's
zencico hello so yeah so
let me think about what anything else
so open file fast introduction yeah
let's
okay that's it thank you guys if you
like my stuff buy it okay
buy my emacs tutorial
or paypal me or patreon me or bitcoinme
uh you can see
the links on my website you know lots of
good stuff
okay bye guys