hello guys welcome to another episode of
sound talk show today we are going to uh
Implement and we are going to test a
customized stack uh data type in Python
we are going to test the efficiency so
we have the code already which I
struggled yesterday uh uh for one hour
and failed but Dion our great guy Dion
he he made it you know I was missing
I was missing this particular function
uh clear that clear method anyway so
Dion coded a stack you know a customized
stacked data structure in Python which
is what I wanted and today we are going
to time it we are going to push a
thousand items and uh see if it's more
efficient than the default python okay
so let's and we are I'm going to try
something new this is this video is
gonna be this live stream is going to be
20 minutes no more than that let's see
if we can do that okay so video check
audio check I don't have my headshot so
you are just looking at my keyboard okay
so let's begin uh testing efficient
stack so I was doing some testing about
timing code okay time of function this
is how you do it
color it and show in browser so okay so
we got a code
we got a code now we are going to uh
push
yeah so let's let's try the code okay so
Dion's code okay so first of all so okay
so
so Dion's code make a backup go to the
directory DD the existing backup make a
new backup close it that make a backup
and pop out so here's a Dion's code
so a stack using linked list this is uh
so let me show you if you run it you see
push code so this this stack or list is
made of nested uh two items so that's
that's how they linked list okay like
these cons so okay so so you can run it
so
okay so what I want to do so let's make
a copy let's make a copy here in case we
screw up we can quickly go get back okay
so uh we got now we want to time it okay
so let's remove the testing code
and let's time it okay so two time
python functions there's a building
Library uh
there's a building Library there's a
guest there's a guest uh uh in my house
so anyway so yeah so
so we finish at 9 50 okay so we got we
got um 20 minutes ago so here's you
so okay let's put the timing here okay
so
uh
so here's the timing code and we want to
time the start stack okay so we want to
first of all create
um what's this what's the name create
AIO so we're gonna do this fast okay X1
equals to create LL create a stack and
let's say range
uh zero two
uh let's say let's say just a list okay
let's start with a list okay and push
okay we're gonna push
let's just push one okay and we're gonna
repeat that a thousand times
so
push push push push push push let's see
and now print X1 okay uh forget about
that brunette
missing one okay yeah push uh push you
need a
stack there so X1 there it is run it
fantastic that's the result okay so
you're gonna do the same so that's about
stack so okay let's measure the speed of
the stack okay uh
measures the speed so
the here is the speed of the stack here
it can be a string or it can be a
function so what we want to do we want
to
um
let's see create a
we want to
let's see uh we want to time it time it
so this can be a function uh
let's let's just say push okay let's
just say push one times okay push it
that many times okay let's see what
happens
uh let's move here okay so
okay done it
okay stack uh stack push push okay
remove that okay so here it needs to be
uh yeah so you need to be Lambda
oh
this oh 50 000 times this is too much
oh okay so stop that
okay can we start uh Emax okay
this is gonna crash emacs
fantastic
cancel come on cancel uh okay cancel
recursion Arrow maximum recursion depth
exceeded okay we got 15 more minutes
okay so close that now which uh we need
to um
so there's a print statement that that's
that's bad because I was doing testing
okay so remove the print statement and
the the number of tests let's say 50
okay so Lambda push it
um
let's do it okay so you see you are
doing it
50 times okay so and we are printing the
stack and the result is
correct we can assume it's correct okay
so that's how we test we push it 50
times okay and we don't want to print it
because it's gonna be huge
let's say 5 500 okay so let's say 5 000
times
wow it's it's huge
uh let's try 50 000 times wow it doesn't
take much time okay that's stack now
let's try a list okay
uh let's let's
um
rename the variable X1 X stack okay
okay so X is a stack now let's try a
list okay
paste python list
okay so python list you begin with just
that okay and then you want to time it
uh you want to time it so you want to
append yeah so python list is a pen now
what is exactly the method name or
function this method okay
python the pen there's append and extend
okay uh append a pen just a pen one
element while extend
removes one level so we want to use a
pen okay so so here it would be let's
let's test it first x equals to
x equals two let's remove that x equals
to
X list dot append
and one argument so let's say one and
now print X2 okay run it
uh wait this at least and now you append
and Y is print X to none
that's going on
let's move that he uh wait it's
the node again
train X2 is none oh it doesn't wait what
okay the pen doesn't actually return
stuff yeah okay it is a imperative
programming
it doesn't return things okay now let's
print this thing fantastic now
okay a pen is working okay so this is
what you want to test okay now we uh
time it
okay you want to basically time that
okay
and for now that's not that many let's
just make sure it works okay
and uh
print it here okay done it fantastic
okay
oh it takes what oh zero zero uh that's
so exponential negative exponential so
zero zero zero point is something one
second I got 10 more minutes okay
oh any comments questions I don't have
time to read your comment hello Diego
let's pop this up
I got 10 more minutes to finish because
previously my live stream is like two
hours one hour so now now I try to do 20
minutes focused on one topic and that's
it okay so today it's a comparison of
the efficiency of customized stack
structure data structure in Python and
next week tomorrow and so on we're gonna
do it in JavaScript in Wolfram language
do the same thing okay so now
um
now that works okay now we can time both
uh let's let's try to print it okay uh
yeah so
print that what uh
what
uh you can't beat it twice I guess uh
uh yeah print
uh what
oh they're too big okay maximum
recursion so because we the number is
too big let's
run it okay so one is stack
one is list basically 50 items okay so
now let's let's don't print and now
let's time it five thousand
Dragon Ball 9000 okay
let's see who is faster stack is
losing
right is the first one is stack
stuck is losing
please
same speed list is losing
now if we uh um okay if we increase
increase when let's say
double yeah double
or nothing do it it's gonna be take two
seconds now
yego what do you think
he's losing
Jesus
why is that
stack is to taking two seconds
point out the um
well the uh let's let's let's
clarify our code
yeah
what
stack is losing
I don't understand let's shrink the
number
donate again
stack is almost three times as slow
I don't understand okay so
we have seven minutes to go so
these efficient implementation of Stack
failed what what I why is that
because according to my
understanding you know if you use
Python's default list you know it's a
smart array basically so when so when
you create a smart array I mean when you
create at least of 10 items let's say
and if you want to add item append
python sees that it's more than that
more than the existing size deal we
create the array and make it like 20
elements with empty spots and we'll it
will pretend there's only one 11 I mean
11 size
so uh so python
so every time you append something to
the array and when it's
uh
let's try this okay
basically every 10 python when you
append items through array and it's
beyond the existing size python have to
recreate the array so and that is very
expensive so I assumed the python array
I mean the this python list is going to
be slow if you keep adding uh but turns
out that's not the case very strange
you see stacks
is almost three times uh slower let's
run again
stack is three times slower okay now
let's now let's uh try to have a range
let's say one thousand
okay let's
uh
let's say x equals to my God
you bought the my mouse recommendation
fantastic
okay now let's see if this works
okay so wait uh X1 is range
X list is what
why is there error
object has no no attribute append
okay yeah because the python the
iterable
e-trail will hideously and stir it again
what
what the wait wait
what we had before
okay I see I see okay so you yeah python
iterable because and let's do it
this again okay
uh range
1000 I have
five minutes okay
you have to actually say uh at least to
convert it to a list okay and let's do
it
okay so stack is still three times as
slow so
let's say ten thousand okay stack let's
say one hundred thousand now can we use
underscore
fantastic that's a new feature by the
way you can use underscore to uh as a
number separator okay
now stack is super slow now let's see
uh let's say increase that
increase that
now it's the same speed
you see oh okay so there's some tricks
in some situations
yeah because you know every time python
adds its exponential I have three more
minutes okay
so here now stack is faster no no no no
no let's let's increase this
oh now stack is slow again
okay I I think I get um
there's one way to make a snack faster
okay I think so I think so so so let's
let's do this one more time okay I think
there is a way to make stack faster uh
now but let's just comment out
okay let's do it here so
so you're going to create a huge
Beast okay first of all and all you have
to do is push it one time
because python is gonna hey because with
the stack it's instant but with the
least python is going to you know oh
it's beyond it's gonna recreate a range
of like
two median uh slots let's see
let's hope it's true
that
is that true close okay hold on a second
ten
uh those scientific
numbers how to see okay I think that's
it for today I I got one more minutes
yeah so this evening with negative five
means uh means you you move it
um okay so this E negative five
that means you move this point to one
to here
then two three four five
okay so it looks like stack is faster
okay let's let's see if we can just uh
okay now you can see stack is faster
see let's see the trick
oh stack is now slow again
is DNA again stack is slow again
one last
wait
Bennett
a stack is slow again yeah as long as
you started to
push push push then stack is slow again
okay so the conclusion is actually
just use Python's default list
okay
uh yeah building because
you know what is the reason maybe maybe
because it's written in C and maybe
because
um
maybe because we can trick
uh implementation of Python's stack okay
so you go to Mexico talk show that's it
for today thank you guys for watching uh
if you like my stuff buy my stuff okay I
have Python tutorial I have lots of uh
computer language tutorials all these
wufam language uh this you know this
emac this and emacs tutorial is
available JavaScript in depth is
available
uh as a book I mean you buy you get the
whole thing they are like uh close to a
thousand pages each
so I have Python tutorial a woofer
language okay support me support me
spread my videos comments okay thank you
guys and this mouse is fantastic
yeah because in particular because
because of the spin wheel okay thank you
guys bye