hello guys everyone good morning oh good
afternoon
oh good night oh good evening so today
I'm going to talk about Emacs the main
topic is going to be I'm going to
demonstrate a HTML mod and I'm going to
talk about writing HTML raw raw meaning
you you you type
you almost type every tag manually with
the help of Emacs commands so you
actually don't type any tags and I'm
going to talk about using XHTML mod
versus using oak mod or any other
content management system so hi guys so
if you have any questions you know so
today's topic is going to be focused on
Emacs so please to keep the comment
coming you know type any anything you
rate it to Emacs you can just type it
type in the chat box here okay let me
let me say it so type your comments ask
any questions anything related to Emacs
any questions you have or when I said if
I said something you have a question
just ask for it
I'll check the comment every few minutes
and so so let's stop let's begin so we
have one person watching her good
morning and but first of all let me
start to show the command log mod so you
can see every command I call you max
I've done this a few times but I'm gonna
show you something okay hold on a second
I mean let me tell you what I'm gonna do
so this is my email okay so let me show
you what what it is
come on rock mod so go to my app at the
rectory local directory and go to
command knock mod so now let's go to
okay go to top eval eval eval so
here every every commands I call you max
your show on the left window
on this window so but there are a few
things I want to do first now you can
see this package I downloaded from my
Appa you can tell because it's in the
Alpha directory but since I started to
do video I use that I use this package
so often so I'm going to move it to my
local local file system you know not not
using my Appa you know well they are
already in my local file system but I
mean just I'm going to move it out of
the Alpha directory so let's do that
let's do settings so this is my Emacs
directory gets a Emacs in it it sunk it
so I'm going to okay split the pen
switch to command lock my wait okay okay
switch the pen switch to command log mod
file go to the directory diet jump and
I'm going to copy this file copy it over
so you see this is here now I'm going to
copy the copy the file path and go to my
Emacs in it this is the my starting file
for my Emacs in it so I'm going to put
that file somewhere here so let's see so
let's expand window let's see what do I
want to put it
okay let's put it here so copy that
paste it and here is a path and let's
see wait delete delete again keep the
comment going so I'll check check it and
you know if you have a questions ask it
and also let me know you know if I'm
going too fast or too slow
um so let's go okay so I want to find
okay okay here is what I want so copy
that paste delete that and require okay
so let's see so here is a provide
command log mod so I want that copy it
close and so I just say require command
lock mod and I don't need the other
things that's right because you see this
file command lock Mario is now in my in
this directory and this directory
directory is already in the load already
in the load path so that should be it
now meanwhile I go back to the airport
directory and actually I'm just going to
delete the whole thing to read the whole
directory you can do that by the way you
know if you you can do that but instead
of just deleted let's just rename it so
let's just rename it oops
let's give it today's date
you know it's a backup well actually
let's move it out of the directory so
move it out so go to the parent
directory and mark mark
move so they are moved to the parent
directory which is not in local file
path load path anyway it's moved there
so let's just close it close it close it
close it and quit Emacs let's restart
Emacs
so if you have a question keep it type
it just type it so I'll see it
so now I just restarted we started Emacs
now let's go to settings my local Emacs
settings directory jump to the directory
and oops command log mod open it go to
the top then let's see if it works
execute execute execute okay there it is
it's working and now because I use this
this this smart so often I want to write
command I want to write a Emacs command
so that I just go it without having to
you know open the file and each time and
run the list code so you know without
doing that so let's go back to go to the
directory log open the file so basically
I want to write a comment that learn
these three lines command log mod global
command log mod then CRM open command
log buffer so let's let's do it so I'm
going to go with I'm gonna go over here
it's open
sorry max miss so this this is a
miscellaneous Emacs Lisp code so let's
just go to the bottom make a backup copy
and let's start code defend or not
delete file
Tiffin okay the the name of the command
will be a start command log okay
that should be fine and star the CIM
analog mod okay and put that there so
that so that when you do describe
function this name will be linked so
user can click it so start the command
log mod globally g GL obal y version
today's date okay and oh it's going to
do is just call these three commands so
copy it switch it back put it here
remove remove the comment remove the
comment remove the comment okay intended
intended well actually we don't need the
lead so actually so let's do let's clean
it up we don't need the left indent so
that's good
so evaluated that looks good let's
restart Emacs quit oh he asked me do I
want to save no I don't want to save so
quit Emacs we start in UX go
so I'm doing okay am i doing okay
oh so back to you max it's put the
window in the right place okay so you
see now I'm ready to call my new command
i just wrote cuz i'll start command log
mod so I'm gonna MX hold on justice so
okay copy MX paste cuz I'll start
command log mod actually I want to start
it on from this window so MX start
command log mod yay it works it worked
so you see that's very convenient okay
close that window we don't need it
anymore hey green deck I want to use
Emacs for note-taking like Todd okay so
I so there's a question I want to use
Emacs for note-taking like top like
taking notes when reading books or
something not for programming right now
it seems like oak mod is best for me but
do you have any advice for me oak mark I
would suggest yeah just use oak mod you
know that that's that's very suitable
suitable for that purpose but however
what I'm going to talk about is I'm
going to use HTML mod because I have
been writing HTML by hand since 1995
almost basically when HTML because I was
there you know so I'm used to doing that
and today for example this is my blog I
mean if every notes even for example
this is a new buffer hold on a second
so okay so new buffer now you remember
every command ICO is gonna show up on
the left so if you wonder what key I
just pressed you can just look up on the
left and the command name
so anyway new buffer switch to HTML mod
and HTML edge and I got a template and
something okay I just discovered this
book math is great okay for example you
know put a paragraph and remove the
something new book let's say 'wait a new
book too and I also want to set the
title okay let's do that
say the title new book ok view in
browser Oh save it I need to save it was
so xxx dot HTML xxx is kind kind of my
temp name wrong type of argument why is
that anyway
view in browser so there it is you know
so you know this is like taking notes so
if you look at the keystrokes I mean you
can you can write this whole thing in
oak mod for example let's try it new
buffer MX oak mod okay hinto okay and
let's save it actually X X X dot hog
temp file name okay and I can say I
forgot what's the oak title something
title new book
okay then new book then you just type
these okay type that so there it is I
think this is the same thing but okay so
because I'm so used to HTML so I'm just
you know I don't find this way okay this
is of mud let me magnify so I don't find
using oak mud this way saves me time no
does it saves me keystrokes you know I
I'm I'm I'm as fast as writing the HTML
mod by itself I mean just creating HTML
tags well because I mean the reason is
because I'm used to it because I've been
coding HTML for you know you know since
1995 so what I'm saying is that for you
if you are not a programmer and if you
just want to take notes go with oak mod
oak mod is you know it's designed for
that it's got lots of features you can
export to HTML for example let's try it
okay I don't remember what's the key for
export and see so whenever you don't
know any command in a new major mod like
right now I want to find out what is the
command okie to Co to export the oak mod
so whenever you have that problem in any
mod you can just go describe mod okay so
let's try Amex describe mod okay then
Emacs will pop up this window let's
expand it the first section we it will
tell you what minor mod are turned on
usually just ignore it like you know
usually you know
so so then from here on it's about oak
mud because right now I'm in augment so
it tells you you know all the keystrokes
and other commands this particular major
mode provides so I'm looking for the
HTML export command so I just search for
HTML oh wait it's not there so search
for export instead such oh there it is
see see see II so that means ctrl c ctrl
e close it so let's try ctrl c ctrl e ok
it asked me what kind of file do I want
to export I want to export to HTML I
type H and type H again because I want
to export it to a file so type H so it's
done now go to the directory tired jump
you can see here is our HTML file it is
just generated so open that we read from
disk Lea ok apparently it's already
opened so you can see here is a
generated file it's pretty agree
you know whenever you've got a generated
HTML it's usually ugly so anyway so you
know so if you are writing ok so if you
just want to take notes
you know oak mark oak mod is perfect
however if you are a programmer you know
you've been programming for 10 years I
mean eventually you will be programming
for 10 years so you you know you are a
programmer you have some experience at
least programming and then I would
recommend possibly that you want to
write H
raw instead instead because when you
write HTML raw you have several
advantages well let's get to that for
example well one example is that you
know look at look at this output
generated by old Mart
huge amount of like garbage I mean they
they are you know look I mean I got this
title and you know paragraph I don't
need this you know whole bunch of CA CSS
you know because it's you know template
template based for example let's just
delete the whole thing did a whole style
you don't need it you know it looks
exactly the same you know so so yeah so
limit okay so I don't need this anymore
let's delete it it's close this buffer
let's leave that on let's go back to
where is my file okay so did I delete oh
I what happened is that when we both the
oak mod name is X X X and my previous
temp file name is also X X X so that the
generated oak mod HTML just over
overrode my HTM I created before so high
lira so again if you have questions any
questions about Emacs just ask you know
just feel free to interrupt me or you
know feel free to ask a different
question anything related to Emacs so
I'm going to talk about so what I'm
gonna yeah so I'm gonna talk about HTM
so what I'm saying is that is if you are
a programmer and you don't mind spending
time to learn HTML or CSS actually you
should because if you have a programmer
and you if you are working with HTML you
should actually take some time to learn
HTML course and CSS because that's
fundamental I mean most people today you
know you don't actually learn HTML or
CSS because there are lots of templates
you know there's you know you just use
templates but it's actually a very good
thing to learn HTML you know at least
you know spend a few days to learn them
because it's because that's because HTML
and CSS that's what you work with you
know especially if you are a web
programmer or if you work on iPhone or
you know Android phone program you know
so those are fond of HTML and CSS are
fundamental technologies you want to you
know be familiar with them by the way I
have a tutorial you can just search for
sorry HTML tutorial
so there it is my tutorial and there's
also a CSS tutorial
you know just spend a few hours you know
learn about them so what I'm saying is
that it's good for you if you are a
programmer it's good for you to to know
to be familiar with HTML and CSS now
once you know HTML and CSS and if you
are Emacs user of course you are you
know and you are interested in you know
Emacs stuff so you might want to learn a
little bit emily's eventually you will
problem you know this high pass high
probability if you keep using Emacs you
know you are probably a fan of Emacs so
learning a little bit eMac this goes a
long way I mean even if you don't Kody
Maggie's so what I'm saying is that if
you are programmer you know you're gonna
learn some HTML and CSS and you cannot
learn some Emacs Emacs Lisp then when
you are when you are in this situation
then it's absolutely absolutely better
to to take your notes or yeah write your
notes or create your blog in raw HTML
like instead of using Oakmont that's my
opinion okay that you know that's not
like that's simply just just a opinion
they are a lot MX experts you know
Americus experts who are a fan of oak
mod you know even though they know a lot
about HTML CSS but they still use oak
mod you know there are quite a few
people who does that so so my opinion
about you know coding HTML row is just
opinion which you know I I do I use you
know I think it's a good alternative
because so what is the advantage of of
you know writing something raw HTML
with with the Emax help versus as
opposed to oak mud or any other content
management system so if you compare them
first of all if you know HTML and CSS
and Emacs Lisp then I mean just look at
first of all the keystrokes is no more
than oak mud or any other mark any other
such as markdown okay you might think oh
ok ah will save will save you a lot
keystroke not really for example okay
you know for example I typed that and
there is my paragraph if I want the list
this item one to you know I just press
two keys you see look at the left that's
only two keys now I'm using a special
keyboard so the delete key is actually
my how my thump-thump key so you see if
I could want to create a new blog entry
that's just three keys new entry you
know and make it make it into a
paragraph two keys now I want to view
this in browser one key you see so
here's a new entry and here's a list
which created so once you are familiar
with this you know coding HTML in Emacs
row you will create you will eventually
create your own system kind of like
customized just for you whenever you
need something you can just create it so
so compare to augment you know first of
all you you don't type more keystrokes
and possibly less keystrokes that's for
one thing the other thing is that okay
the other advantage of oak mod is that
for example oak mud
let's go back to Oakmont you know people
say look at oak mud it's easy to read
you know you don't have to your eyes
your eyes don't have to go through all
these tags you know that that's like
confusing or distracting that's true but
first of all once you get used to it it
doesn't it doesn't matter it's like you
know let's see it's like for example
Emacs Lisp code for example all these
nested parentheses it doesn't bother it
doesn't bother Emacs these programmers
because you get used to so in the same
way these tags doesn't bother me you
know I I read them you know well but
however do the other significance is
that when you are in oak mod when you
have lots of things actually you know
sometimes you can have tech like you
know math Tech or lab tech and that's
unreadable
you know that's unreadable to when you
have complicated tech expressions so you
actually when you actually want to read
oh oh if you have images you know you
are not going to read you know the pen
up my text anyway you're gonna need to
export it you know to HTML or PDF so the
end result is that you cannot read it in
a browser so but if you work with HTML
directly you know I can view my things
in browser like right here you see
everything is clear you see because
there's nothing compared to the
readability of a browser you know I can
have images let's see Emacs fun you know
all these render this this will beat you
know oak Mart you know if you have
images you know like okay HTML is
ten times more flexible in akhmad and
ten times more feature-rich plus you can
use JavaScript to a script HTML
especially especially if you are a
front-end web developer you know you are
familiar with JavaScript so you can just
sew this this far more potential if your
file source code is HTML then some kind
of template system you know like some
kind of markdown system but okay so so
there are some advantage that we talked
we talked about the number of keystrokes
Oakmont versus writing HTML raw so they
are I would say about the same we we
talked about readability okay and Mike
on my my tip is that you you just read
it in browser so it's no worse you know
and so it's it's comparable to Oakmont
then we talked about extensibility or or
number of users
now obviously the number of users of
HTML is some 1,000 times more than oak
mod so there you have lots of utilities
for formatting HTML for you know you
have like thousand one thousand times
more libraries or utilities helping you
do HTML and or tutorials like you have
ten thousand tutorials about HTML then
Oakmont okay then what else to compare
okay there are a few things and there
are many advantage advantages of Oakmont
- you know oak mod has it has very huge
number of users although not as much not
as many as HTML users but you know you
have let's say 10,000 you know that's
enough and oak mod you can
you can embed you can embed programming
languages let's let's let's show you
some practical Emacs so this is my image
Emacs tutorial and if you go down Oak
mod so this section is all about Oak mod
and you have source code markup so what
this means is that you can actually
embed programming language source code
in Oakmont and you can actually evaluate
you know those source code and these are
lists of supported languages you know
supports like 30 languages many
languages but ok I'm gonna but but this
can be done in HTML as well so anyway
that's about that that's you know so so
that that kind of I I finished my
discussion about oak mod versus writing
HTML raw you know it's so let's go back
so any questions type it keep keep the
comments
oops I made a mistake
damn
okay okay so so that's about writing raw
HTML versus Oakmont now I'm going to
show you such tml mod so that is this
one okay so actually wait so let's go to
the browser
so there are a lot HTML mods in Emacs
and I'm using my own though this one I
created myself it's let's see
so because since I started to do Emacs
video there are more people beginning to
use it I've been using this mod for a
long time for like 10 years maybe so
let's let's go through let's go to it
let's have a look describe key f10 space
edge so here is HTML mod you see these
all these are commands in their keys so
let's let's go through the source code
so here's the source code for 4,000
lines of emag disp let's go to the top
so I started this Emacs around 19 around
2012 so I've been using it for like 6
years and mostly I'm the only one use it
but now it seems there are more people
are starting to use it so I think I'm
going to do a demo of this a little demo
of HTML mod
so is that good am i doing good
did I get the green deck did I did I
answer the question do you Diana sell
you a question
so anyway I've been using XHTML Mart for
you know many years so you know all the
HTML on my website I have like five
thousand six thousand HTML files written
raw and they are all created in Emacs
using using size tml mod so so I'm I'm
going to do a demo then okay how am I
going to do a demo am I going to do it
okay cool I mean if I didn't explain
something where I'll just keep keep
asking you know just you know just talk
just keep the comments going so I so you
know give me some direction so I'm going
to show search team Ahmad it's on alpha
I think it's a male power let's try
let's let's see these packages okay
I noticed male parts of to wait for a
while for the for them to show up oh
it's not a oppa wait let's see
no it's not a mail path so you have to
go to github so here's a URL you can
just download it yeah it's so I'm think
I'm thinking I'm gonna do a demo of
excit ml mod but you can create the
example page with many different HTML
tags image okay yeah let's do that
that's excellent thank you great
suggestion so I'm going to do an example
with HTML yeah okay let's do that I'm
going to create a new HTML page with all
the simple tags and examples you know
example a sample HTM page so a new
buffer again look at the left window
okay so every command I go it's gonna
show up there so you can you can learn
from it you know you know and most of
these command almost all of them is on
my website so if you see a command you
think it might be useful to you you can
just search for you know for example
sign you empty buffer you can just
search for it you'll find my page with
the source code then you can just put it
in your new max in it okay so let's
start to write a new HTML file so let's
save this file is X X dot HTML so I'm
gonna type each team okay first of all
enlarge the font HTML H so that gave me
your template now HTML H is a HTML H is
abbreviation and the last H is just it's
simply there's so so that if I type oops
if I have HTML it won't accept it won't
expand because sometimes you want to for
example I want to say
writing HTML okay I don't want that HTML
expense so therefore I created on a
brief that ends with edge basically any
HTML template or HTML tags I ended with
edge so that way when I want the
template at a page
I got a template when I don't want it
you know it's it's fine so it's showing
browser so there it is it's magnify
okay so title sample okay for title you
can you can call this command such fight
figure what Oh actually you have to have
something okay that's a bug
so anyway well let's for now let's just
type the title manually HTML page sample
copy that and now I want the h1 header
so I press the by default the keys tab
key tab key will will prompt and you can
type attack name for example h1 so how
do you know when you know what tag name
it is so this this is the part where you
need to know HTML because you know for
example if you are using oak mod you
don't need to know because you know mod
you just you know it's very simple you
use the historic risk you know title and
you know two asterisks a force
subsection you know you don't need to
learn the tax but however if you want to
write HTML then you kind of happen to
know what tag you want
so press tab key h1 enter then there's a
tab name
it's let me just do this fast you can
you know so okay let's add an image so
go to tire jumped tire jump to go to the
directory hold on cuz split tire jump go
to the directory okay
hi is the directory now look at the
directory in in desktop so let's say I
want this this image do GE so search for
do G there it is copy the file path wait
this one this one copy the file path
paste it here make it into an image
expand the window showing browser okay
this is a fun fun screenshot it's from
someone made a splash logo for the space
max so that's an image what else so I
have a custom command that insert
section that so a new section I have a
command what okay what else image both
okay so something this is important you
know I want an important to be both so I
just move it I just press tab B enter
okay now I want a paragraph I can press
tab P enter okay oh well there's another
command I can okay do another command is
called this search team I'll wrap P tag
the difference is that if I have many
paragraphs like this and that okay if I
have many of them I can just press a key
and view in browser so
so there there is okay links
what about links so let's do a link
[Music]
but by Jack so so let's do a link so I
want the link let's see I want to link
to this this page so copy the link back
to Emacs add new line
paste the link press the key it's linked
now make it a paragraph view in browser
let's go down see there it is a link
visual CSS now let's say I want to add
some styles let's let's go to the
default side let's say I want to change
the font size so go to top here at lines
and press cat key style so that gave me
CSS styles so I won't say it body okay
and switch to CSS mod now font size okay
- am - I am okay good
switch back to an HTML one showing
browser everything is - am twice as much
no I want let's say I want to color them
let's just type color red
okay showing browser it's all red so so
what
so you see you do have to know some CSS
and HTML you have to spend some time to
learn it because otherwise you know so
that that is the advantage of oak mod or
the template system you don't have to
know CSS or HTML but if you plan to
write HTML raw but manually you do have
to know these kind of things
so what else dink
red okay I think that's that's it
because you know it's so I we've been
talking for 46 minutes that's you know
this is just a short introduction to
HTML mod which is my own mod for writing
HTML now there are several other HTML
mods let me give you some introduction
let me intro
so actually let's just remove that
remove all these let me just type this
out some intro to HTML mods in Emacs
okay so they are our HTML mod this is
wait this is the default you know Emacs
okay okay and copy that then there is
HTML mhtml mod this is new King kuno
Emacs version 26 okay show in browser
now in Emacs 26 there is a new HTML mod
it's called M HTML mod so the HTML mod
this one is ancient this is written in
1999 or something like that
the mhtml mod is new it's just like two
years old something like that now you
make in Emacs 26 you can download right
now it's it simply pre-release beta but
it's pretty good like I'm using for
example I am using Emacs 26 point one
point
- so yeah so what what is the difference
the major the major difference is that
mhtml mod that M stand for is stand for
something like Multi multi mod so
basically what it does is that when you
have JavaScript code when you have CSS
code and when you have HTML code all in
one file it will reasonably color syntax
them or correctly so for example let's
let's try it let's switch to HTML mod MX
HTML part okay so this is HTML mod this
is the you know Emacs 25 now let's
switch to M X HTML mod MX m HT m ma
enter you see you see how this part gets
colored let's enlarge you see this this
part
okay so there's M HTML mod I recommended
you'd having its new it's its new and
new usually new is better and okay then
there is such TM l mod now size chairman
mod this is mine so excit mama is just
the one I use I have added a huge amount
of my own commands I mean commenced is
you know fairly fairly many new commands
compared to HTML mod I haven't I haven't
used mhtml mod much much but anyway
inside came about you have I have you
know a huge amount of commands by the
way when you when you use em HTML mod
the mod
look at over here it will say HTML plus
okay so so anyway so there's exciting
amar there's another one which is very
popular it's code let's see what it's
called so let's call these packages it's
search for HTML HTML
okay so let's list matching lines HTML
I don't see it here let's try again this
match means least match Reno is HTML
okay I don't see it here but let's go
back to my Emacs tutorial and practical
Emacs and scroll down scroll down scroll
down HTML topic so Emacs HTML tips
so actually this page you know tells you
what HTML mods are there you can you can
read it wave mod that's it okay the name
there so there's another HTML modest
which is fairly popular that's called
web mod you can try that okay so I think
that's it for today so any any more
questions
not much I don't get much comments today
any questions
so what else I want to show it's it's
not dude right I'm going to 9.2
Oh detailed tutorial about oak mud oak
mud there are so many tutorials about
Oakmont
you know out there you know on YouTube
and elsewhere
you know I the thing is I don't really
use Oakmont that much by the way hi hi
hi Diane hey see you Greg Greene thanks
for coming by
tutorial I have well no I have a
tutorial about Oakmont you know let's
see
Emacs blog you see if you if you just go
to practical Emacs then scroll down then
this oak mock topic so yeah actually
they are you know fairly basic but but
the thing is about Oak modest I mean if
you have not read this you know you can
you know read them they are very basic
and paper but they they cover the
fundamentals the most you know the
concept the most basic you know you can
just start to use oak mark by reading by
spinning you know say 20 minutes about
you know reading these pages and when
you want to learn more you have no
choice but dig into the oak Mart manual
I mean I can recommend that so you do
you do that by ctrl H I then you get the
Emacs info page index so search for org
you see there it is right there and now
you just see tab and just open it so
here's the Oakmont tutorial and also you
can you can just search for Oakmont
and go to the oak mod homepage Oak MoDOT
hog and they have a lot documentation so
let me show you which one is good
so manuals and tutorials go there and so
there is the manual you know browser
menu you can read the menu but however
the official menu is like it's huge
I mean it's hundreds of pages so it's
kind of it can be too much especially
for beginner so I don't you know but you
can but you can also read this one
there's another one beat the compact
guide so this one it's much shorter it's
somewhat yes it's still a lot a lot it's
shorter so I don't know so I mean so if
you want to read you know you can just
start with my tutorial you know and then
you can read the menus or the guide on a
future website but if you want youtube
tutorials they are quite a lot of people
who have created you know very good
Emacs video tutorials maybe I can tell
you which one for example there is a guy
called Howard oak mod let's say oak mud
getting started with Oakmont Harry
Schwartz oh I think I've met Harry
shruts in emacs meetup in near San
Francisco I think I'm not sure so you
know he's got the getting started with
Oakmont yeah I think you know anyway so
yeah I you know so they are quite a few
tutorials I think they are good you know
you can just read them
yeah controller is useful now control I
control it right let me try it again
control H I it can it it gives you the
index page of all the manuals that are
bundled with Emacs so all these links
are local and they contain for example
magic magic tutorial basically
everything about Emacs but also
something else like Adam Adam and okay
Adam Adam mod is part of Emacs you know
it's for the other language CC mod for
is for C language octave mod is for well
octave language well basically so it's a
full documentation you can so there's
like thousands of thousands of pages you
can read them but usually usually they
are not easy to read and they are very
extremely verbose like you have to spend
many hours reading them of course so
that gets you to mastery but so I just
I'll just say that you can always just
you know start with my tutorial you know
this because I try to give you the most
basic I try to write it in such a way
that you know it's the most efficient
tutorial I mean in in terms of how much
hour you spend and how much you learn
and once you read me you know you reread
my tutorial you know where you want to
go you know you can start to read the
official menu okay so thank you guys for
coming that's it for today thanks bye