okay well guys so today this is a new
device you can see my screen I'm using
OBS now so OBS is this software someone
introduced me thank you for recording
and streaming and and video editing well
I haven't I haven't learned how to edit
video with it but it looks like you know
the you know I read a few website it
seems you know so far it's mostly for
streaming and recording for gamers you
know the gamers Evo you know for the
past 10 years they are occupying the
recording the video streaming space
basically they is because the gamers
that created the wave of you know video
streaming mostly oh and and of course
PPP n you know I don't want to say the
word you know because Google these days
you know this heavy ship you know it's
pretty bad so anyway so let's start so
what I'm gonna do is today I'm going to
record a video about Emacs so Emacs
Emacs is my screen okay Emacs you see
okay let me show you what I'm gonna do
so you this is a traitor okay so this is
the traitor link let's go to Safari so
open a new tab paste so now it's 4:15 so
let's do this for 15 minutes for 30 max
okay so you see this is my thread so
basically that URL just give me this
thread this this way okay so with this
software I cannot see myself you know in
order to see myself up to like point
actually I can do it here
this is this is my advanced technique
you see I have Auto click on I have Auto
click on when I move my mouse there to
the right lower corner it toggles it so
you see now I don't have no it's off I
move my mouse there no it's on you see I
don't I don't have to move I don't have
to click
he's you see with this technique you
never have to click ok let's go back so
i'm today i'm going to do a rather you
Mac this tutorial well I mean recording
of my coding emag list basically so so
let's set windows so I can see myself
actually so anyway so that link okay so
this list it's this focus focus okay so
so this is link now if I view this link
in Safari it's not going to work because
I have JavaScript off so it needs to be
and and you know I have my use several
browsers Safari Chrome Google Chrome
brave and Firefox Firefox is Firefox is
with JavaScript off and cookie off and
everything off so this guy is the Korean
artist Kim junkie he's incredible
incredible Korean artist so he can draw
from memory like this one he's doing
like he's traveling around around the
world doing live demos so for example
this thing he just sit there and start
drawing you know like without copy or
something he just and without looking at
some models he just start drawing all
these basically all these so some people
you know they are dedicated to some some
something and they are incredible in
this also the ease of course he's gifted
so anyway so what I want to do is you
know so this is a this is link I want to
go to that link using Safari or using
krump yeah brave so I'm going to write a
command so if I just press a key now you
just sent me to Safari or Chrome you
know a browser of my choice so I already
have a program link let's not use this
page it's called Emacs blog so you see I
already have okay
let's oh my god my stuff is like I have
to think about privacy stuff privacy
privacy privacy let's go to Emacs l-pod
that command LACMA turned on yes go to
the file and go to here okay eval eval
eval
so you can see my keys okay is this you
see all my keys are there so now sit the
windows of to put it in perspective now
turn the auto click off you know with
with the auto click it's sometimes it's
problem you know there are occasions
where you want to turn off like
especially yeah the occasion is that
when you want when you whenever you need
to drag stuff you want to turn it off
but now I'm done dragging turned my back
on that's why I put it on corner so it's
easy to toggle so so actually yeah I
don't need to look at myself so with
this software you know before I was I
was using ok let let's get on this I
have 10 more minutes so ok so I did
already have the command now my job is
to find out what's a command basically
make a copy of it so go there make a
backup copy that paste it so I'm just
going to work on this this one casabas
you under kusa mmm
visit site ok wait there's another
command let's see
so let's also go there this command lets
you open file under Cruiser ed kusa what
that do is you see so you see I got this
command you might be smart so I got this
command open file in the kusa so like I
can call it now like for example coy you
see it goes into Firefox which is not
what I want okay so basically I have to
do is just modify this yes all right
yes okay let's do that then yeah let's
forget about this one say temp temp file
name xx GG whatever what okay open file
and the Cruces so this this one is going
to open open the file in the cursor now
is he's always going to be a browser
link not a file name so this command is
actually quite long so let's see so if
stream matches that HTTP then then do
that else if not starting with HTTP that
we don't need okay so I'm thinking there
are two solutions I mean either so
either I I used I write a new command
like open file on the open link in
browser in Safari so this would be the
name so I'm gonna write that and write
another one
open [ __ ] him brave okay so for example
so either I write a new function like
that Oh
I modified the original you see there
are two options there's always options
like when you start right programs you
have to like when you start to write a
program you have so many ideas comes
into you like you have to make a
decision it may be implementation issues
choosing algorithms or how do you
implement the interface right now we are
facing an inch issue of how to implement
the interface for example I can just
write this function it's a totally new
so whenever whenever I want to go to
Safari of a link I call that specific
command or I stick with one command I
stick with the same command as I had
which is called Open File and the
cruiser but if where where when I want
to go to Safari then I I can call
Universal command which is control you
what control you does is let me show you
control you it does call this universal
argument okay I have seven more seven
more minutes this is gonna work so let's
just do it then you got a I'm gonna just
gonna do it [ __ ] talking too much
whatever you can skip that yeah just get
this done okay just just finish the
video and open browser URL oh I have to
do is change that to us URL now okay
there's another option options okay so
actually there is a browser URL you see
there are several commands for us you
are browsing I'll come and they are
problematic actually I've tried them
like ten years ago
that you have to set a path and all that
it's easier actually if you just read it
yourself
like okay so if if that is found then do
that
if match string that way did I school
that's right so so if this is found
actually okay it becomes so simple now
it see actually it's just that first you
know so but I don't want was you know so
I have another commander browse you are
open in Safari there it is you see I
have so many commands I've already
written so let's go here I make a copy
so hopefully in Safari open the current
file or data that's right okay let's
actually open the file that's not open
the link what I want is open a link so
okay this is a command we need shell
command as you are
so so let's put it here shell command
format open Safari and now that part
should be the rink okay so where is the
link the link is path okay so it's so
wait file path crossing our path that's
right so yeah oops
so let's do that
it's not even bouncing your eye out so
so suppose that's it
it's avow it already so open thinking
Safari let's try it oh my god this is so
good it worked it worked okay
so that's it for today I hoped you liked
it I hope you liked it if you liked it
please make like like please like it
please face face and let me know what
you think let me know what you want to
see next because I'm making a video
everyday I'm going to be like a
professional I'm going to be now I'm
going to be a YouTube star okay okay bye