good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of Santa Joe
what a rush
today's 2019 November 24th Sunday 5 o
clock 20 minutes after p.m. San
Francisco time in California and in
California what a rush I thought I
thought I thought it's going to start
one hour later but when I look at the my
video stream here he says you know
beginning at 5 o clock so so I had to
rush concurrent views 5 5 or 6 ok hello
people hello beautiful people so let's
see what we have so today we are going
to talk about in my own in my life
yay Matt Matt from Germany yay Emily
so today so today we are going to focus
on Emacs and Emacs Lisp we are going to
do stuff like he's special we are going
to live code a normal layout for support
folks of artists a feature request from
one of the guy and I must mention he
paid me $20 but he paid me $20 you know
he just donated so so that immediately
pump up the priority of course that's
reality so I have to do this and it's a
good topic and so this guy woof
apparently you know okay well so he is
saying he want a no no man layout good
morning Kathy so good morning everyone
Cathy part and Emily and then
hi Dan from to Brazil and so we're gonna
do this and what okay so what is the so
what are we going to do we gonna do this
your life support up normally
and I'm heavy milk I'm doing a rush to
get my milk I haven't been fed yet okay
let's get on with the topic so yeah so
let's begin shall we
yeah so anything else right let's begin
stuff like he's apparently there are
more activities and stuff like he's like
in the in the past few days so I haven't
I haven't logged in okay sign sign in
and you are not going to see my
passwords good morning Alan
so hold on second an issue my shows show
my beautiful village
so let me login to github
okay I'm locked in milk Cheers
and for many of you Europeans it's good
night it's good night milk
yes Emily is how you say in America
a trucker actually I use that phrase
incorrectly but there's the Americans
land code the trucker means it means
yeah some some meanings okay so anyway
so so sorry Keith so we cannot do an
omen layout okay so what is normally out
not if you don't know okay so saw start
command lock much since we are doing
Emacs we need to show the command log or
the Emacs commands I call you will see
in the upper left window and Safra keys
okay so you guys know what is sapphire
keys right so well yeah because stuff
like he's github okay it's a you know
it's this is Mike Suffolk his github and
it's a Emacs key binding it's a key
binding for Emacs so you don't use I'm
Superman hot and oh I need to close my
window because my roommate is
I need coffee in Bosnia so so soft like
ease sucks a ficus yeah it's getting
it's let's get going okay so let's get
going and so soft like he's like it's a
key binding for Emacs and what is normal
layout so let's show you normally out so
you go to sorry keyboard block and
wonderful interesting things thank you
zoom way out so we're going to go to
layout
okay so layout layout is over here let's
see if I can you can see my windows okay
move that there and move that here super
okay they are so alternative layout so
normal layout so you have Kody you have
Iraq you have programmers work you have
Cormac you have many others and so
Commack colemak and warwick are somewhat
popular and so these are alternative
layouts so and one of them is this nomin
layout so he wants this support for
normal layout in Safari keys okay so we
are going to code this live this is not
scripted so I don't know what to do we
have to you know you're just gonna watch
my how I you know you just gonna watch I
walk on on this so no man layout okay so
you know normal layout is kind of funny
because I read you know Norman Norman
layout is kind of new relatively new
compared to audio las maracas like 30
years old Commack is 20 years old 15
Commack is 15 years old then workmen
came out like 10 years ago
then all the others are self video so
all the others are pretty old I mean
but anyway no man layout came out after
walkman so you have low rack here let's
see so you have you have or AK here then
you have you know after 20 years or so
you have Commack then then then you
start to have a lot then you have aukmen
then Norman came out so Norman this guy
his name is Norman okay that's it's
named after him he you know he studied
all the other layout you know nerds
you know notes that you must have one
perfect layout you have to keep going at
this so every year maybe every year you
have new layout so normal layout you he
so he studied you know varrock Commack
and and walkman so he decided though
those are not good enough you know we
need a new one so he created normal
layout but that you know the in a
beginning I he this came out in 2013
okay so it's like four years old nine
minus three six years old so and when I
look at that when I looked at it in 2003
also I didn't get what is his point
typically when you have a new layout you
have a website you explain why you
created it you know what's wrong with
the others why you don't like the others
why you create one so he has a website
very pretty good design website and I
went there but I don't get what is his
point you know like for example the
workmen layout the workmen layout is
created because the guy he tried Borak
he didn't like barack you know many
people didn't like Barak especially
because of the L key L key is the P key
on the court he is right yeah L key is
the P key on Kody so it's pinky and
especially in UNIX stupid eunuch
you know I have reasons I have defense
against that but let's not go into that
today so anyway so the workmen layout
the guy his name he's a Brazilian or
Portuguese
I think does anyone can anyone correct
me if I'm wrong the ten you guys in
Brazil so he anyway he creates a layout
he criticized you know he didn't like
work and he tried Commack he did not
like it because the lateral movement the
the Commack has this issue anyway and so
he created walkman and he explained you
know he has an essay on the website he
explained and he he explained what he
then he explained why he didn't like the
others the problems he see and he
created his own and he has reasons and
you know but then when I read the normal
layout he also of course he tried to
explain but I don't get it like what
what just what is the point you are
trying to fix what what is the problem
what is the issue I don't get it
why oh I get is that some general saying
so normally is kind of better but I
don't see what is the point
but lassie lassie oh I think oh maybe
this year I read his website again I I
think he tried to explain a bit more he
probably have seen my you know my my my
description like I don't get what he's
trying to do so he I think the I noticed
some change but still it didn't stick
with my mind so so normally I is
designed by David Noma let's go to his
website okay we should go to people's
website when we are talking about
people's stuff so here is his website
you know I have JavaScript off here so
maybe we should go over here
normally out there it is
so 64 less effort than quoting you okay
whatever
they all say that of course but look
anyway that let me make criticism about
Commack and Norman okay I know many of
you use Commack you know they are fans
you know you have fan clubs work Commack
you know layout was I know Emily uses
Commack and I know some of the others
people have used Commack anyway one
criticism I want to make about Commack
Norman and quite a few others asset they
what they want to do they they what they
tried to do is that they want to fix the
z-x see the way z XC week is same as
kotti why because you know those are and
do cut copy paste keys and they you know
they are used to those shortcuts so they
think that if you rearrange them to
somewhere else like Barack then it's no
good because it's all over the place
so therefore many of these layouts mini
Mac corporate qwp our asset norman
Commack they all keep they all try to
they all keep the z XC p keys in the
lower left corner okay so that the
shortcut doesn't move okay in my opinion
that's crap that's that that's actually
a very bad quite very bad decision very
seriously yeah there to a degree it's
actually a serious flaw in my opinion
because let's just keep let me give you
the short version okay because i
actually got is i from that you know why
because let me try to explain okay I
need to think okay so why why why is it
no good to have Z
xev keys in the same place as quarry now
okay let me explain that
now when you when you design a layout
usually you want the most frequent
letters to be used on your strong
fingers typically these two you know
sometimes card that you know typically
these two others strongest fingers okay
so but look at that the key Z I mean the
keyed X that's for cut
okay that's used that's by your ring
finger and in a bottom row that's
typically considered no good so so when
you have X key there and cut is you know
cut and do is actually frequently used
that's then you got a problem you know
you got a problem you you are you are
like you are like destroying your
principle of putting the most frequently
used keys on your your strong fingers
you see now you put the X there you got
a problem with that so these people I
don't want to be too harsh but nah but
this figure you know they don't you know
they don't they haven't thought of that
they you know they is like it you read
their sites or discussion forums like
nay you don't hear that mentioned once
oh they the work you know so I think
that's a serious flaw I mean what why is
it serious because you know before you
know I just thought no you shouldn't do
that because you shouldn't you know have
some keys remain a Scottie you rather
you should just optimize the whole thing
you know just like new layout is that's
why it's new you know you just optimize
whatever is the best arrangement and and
let people learn the new layout but some
of these I mean these people these
creators they they part of their you
know their focus is that all learning is
difficult for those who already know
quality therefore
they don't want to change many keys they
tried to minimize the key position
change and so in my opinion that's nice
not really good okay you just you know
if you wanna if you are creating you
just create a new like optimize every
position don't you know so I didn't like
that
okay that's before but but however in
back in 2013 or so let me show you my
heart ago okay so here is the Oracle why
undo shortcut why undo cut short cut
keys are bad so anyway I you know I just
thought you should design a new you
shouldn't you know have QWERTY keys you
know like try to minimize key change so
that's what I thought but anyway I you
know is that so that's one of the reason
I thought the colemak and and friends
are not not the best okay but then in
2000 let's see I have documented
everything here in 2000 my repetitive
strain injury log history of my
repetitive strain injury every time that
happens I try to write it down so in
2012 okay it's a long history actually
we are digressing in 2012 I was trying
to you know I yoga Emacs keybinding ago
Emacs is a packaged Emacs key binding
package which are designed I worked for
like 10 years
before South I keys so we created a
command for cut such that let me show
you okay so we created a command for cut
such that you don't have to make a
selection like typically you make a
selection then you cut right but you
don't have to like save if you just
press the shortcut for cut it will just
cut the current line without having you
to have you know mark you know go to the
beginning of the line then start the
mark go to the end of line
then cut you know save keystrokes so if
you don't have selection you just cut
the current line if and if you cut again
you just cut subsequent lines you see
cut cut cut cut cut
and now if I do pace your paste the
whole thing you see because it
accumulate all these consecutive cuts
together so I find this so convenient so
convenient so I started to you know I
stopped for example if I want to delete
this section this whole bunch of lines
I don't select any more like I don't
like Smok beginning of selection then I
move closer I don't do that anymore
I just I just you know cut cut cut cut
cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut cut
cut
you know that's what I that became my
new habit ok because I found this so
convenient then the problem comes one
day you know when you have eyes i when
you have hand pin that's very scary you
don't know why because I don't know why
then you know one day you wake up your
your your my arm is tingling I don't
know exactly what's the case here you
know because I have several issues with
is I about every three or four years st.
since 2006 6 2006
anyway so you wake up you know one of
the this incidents you feel your arm is
jacked like numb players you there's a
ting go like that's that's very scary
because you are programmer now your your
hands are done for you it's a major
problem so so I don't I can't figure out
what's wrong you know I thought I was
using vorak I was using you know organic
economic keyboards and and I know about
these things so why is happening I don't
know eventually after a month after you
know one month of you know in in this
distress I finally noticed the problem
the problem is using the this ring
finger to press the
X key cut that's a problem
I know it so so in open Emacs that's
control X okay contracts so that is a
problem you see so so when this happened
oh my god you know finally I realized
because once you realize you know when
you okay let me talk about when you have
eyesight you you want to try at least to
pinpoint what exactly is causing it
usually it's difficult you know you
don't know you got used your hand hurts
you know it differs from person to
person sometimes the finger have pain
okay sometimes they're not know cause
have pens
yeah and it's different for you know
different fingers for each person
sometimes it's the ER thump okay and for
me actually right now it's like over
here you know it's hard to explain but
it's in this area like I have to do this
you feel comfortable I think I know why
but anyway that's another topic this is
the current situation but anyway so back
then so I note I realized it's the X key
so once you so you want to try okay
every time you have eyesight whatever
doesn't matter what which finger
sometimes it's a wrist for some people
sometimes they'd see here like it's a so
when you have a situation like that you
want to try to figure out what is
causing it okay sometimes it's caused by
too much this movement I call that VI
escape syndrome you try to press escape
keep I always like doing this like
either escape hit escape command Malcolm
Emma don't do that okay and sometimes
some people use trackball to much the
Thunder Bay strap oh they got problems
with a thump then they develop paint
here I have read a lot of that and some
people for using oh go ducks they got
problem with the Sun because they do
they they started to do these too much
you don't realize it until if you feel
different ting ting goes or some kind of
hurt you will feel it but you don't
realize it because it's just habit
so when you have that pops those kind of
problems you want to try to find out
what is wrong try to trace it down it's
it's difficult okay but you can try
another tip I can give you is like you
put a camera recorder just record your
hands for like wait for one hour or
something when you are doing a lot
typing then you watch it afterwards fast
forward then you can see what you are
doing a lot you know because anyway so
that's a technique okay I used to be on
the swimming team in the nineteen in
1991 also in college for Hill Community
College and the coach sometimes they
record our swimming so you can see where
you know your strokes you know is
incorrect not efficient by anyway so so
you want to try to find out what is
causing your pain okay and and for this
case I found out it's a it's it's me
using the ring finger to press the X too
much because when you are if you have a
touch typist the the way you press X is
you just you just move your hands now if
you are not a touch typist okay then you
don't have that much problem but also
you type much less okay those of you who
don't touch type don't be don't be like
yeah you should alert learn touch IV
because then touched iPod you know you
have better handheld that's that's
incorrect that's wrong okay anyway
that's another topic anyway so for touch
typist when you type X's you just I just
move this down and that is causing my
problem that's causing the problem so I
I realized that and I started to change
your whole bunch of you know the keys
for ago he may expect in so I don't I
don't press cut anymore like that I
press you know the function keys or
something I have a complete you know log
documentation on that on that incident
so once I realize this then then when
you look back at these these layer
designs then you
this is serious problem this keybinding
I mean this layout designers they they
didn't realize this is a serious problem
ok those they are so that's my opinion
of course this is a contentious issue if
you are using a comb a go others you
know you you don't like to hear that but
of course there are another many
different aspects to it so anyway so
that is about this design so you know
the Z X CV and also let me just mention
I mentioned these few times in the past
if you have a programmer actually if if
you are programmer if go ahead and get
the key logger lock your keystrokes ok
so you can actually see statistics not
by your what do you think oh you think
oh this should be that though that you
know to statistics get a key logger when
your so once you get a key logger you'll
find that for a programmer the
keystrokes you type more than half of
them is actually about keyboard
shortcuts ok like a holding down control
like what I mean such as moving cursor
moving cursor delete some paragraph
delete also and do things like that it's
not it's not typing ok it's not typing
so what I'm saying is that if you
measure your key logs keystrokes
then you'll find find depending on
programa ok depending on what you do but
in general I would say on average most
programmers their keystrokes are not
typing it's about opening file and do
move cursor and you know delete you know
edit you know edit
that's what programmers do it's not
about just typing so so that makes the
this issue about the cut key more
important because you actually do that
more often you know like this layout
designers they
pace their KeyBank keyboard layout based
on english writings you know novels news
articles journals that's their data set
so in english language of course you
don't type X much X the letter X does
not occur much but if you are a
programmer that's it's not typing that
that you are doing you are doing
shortcuts and follow especially
Photoshop users CAD users AutoCAD you
know blender users many of the digital
media people today that's all about
shortcut you you know their keystrokes
will be mostly about shortcuts so this
is a to me now it becomes rather serious
flaw in key layout design okay okay that
is that is about that
this is what I want to say okay let me
check the comments so Emily says you
know I've been like keep going so I
didn't have room to look at the comment
before so let me look at a comment now
so let's see yeah so close this window
to save memory okay
30 20 30 minutes night people watching
so Emily says my like my layout is space
of Commack th with some extra personal
modifications yes so comat Commack has a
kind of a new version th that's called
Commack mod th which fixed the lateral
finger movement problem and of course
Emily you know Emily Emily is a super
nerd she has her own modifications in
lots of places not just not just
keyboard layout total change so angry
that's best to go for total change and
not hand on to courtier like stuff it's
like how you see or not up not stuff
going to extreme for efficiency yes
so Nobby says what I did miss about
Commack saw started early I just joined
yeah sorry hi I got my time mixer I got
you know I thought he's one hour later
but according to YouTube
it's one hour you know in so I decided I
have to go with a youtube one because
that's been there for the whole day
anyway so that's about a little some you
know my story about you know the why and
do cut short cuts are bad now for those
for the C and V keys I think that's okay
you know the C and V keys stay there is
okay you you know because those are
strong fingers for the undo and the cuts
no don't you know I don't think those
good positions so in summary when you
design a layout you it you know might
you might think about also about the
shortcuts of course there are different
approaches then you can design a letter
layout that do not consider shortcut
then but but then you have a layer layer
or you know if you are using Emacs or if
you are using editors you can have you
know another pro game that that solves
the shortcut problem which such as VIMS
evil mud or veins
you know model modo system or Kassab
sawfly keys okay so now let's let's do
any any questions on that let's do let's
get let's do then the colemak let's try
to implement Accomack I mean not come
back the normal layout into Excel fly
keys okay any questions comments post
okay see okay so yeah so let's do that
so that's now okay so soft like he's so
first of all describe key press my home
key and that shows the sock Frankie come
on mom odd
okay first well before we do that let's
go to settings I want to increase my
font so for all my buffers so you can
see go to the
sorry Magli smart
magnify so actually don't magnify but
actually so on the mag I want middle 15
now i eva buffer now it's magnified okay
so okay so let's begin so I go to I
describe key go to cassava key is code
and go to the directory so I have bunch
of garbage
now let's delete those backups okay
because I did a backup yesterday which
is here you can see so anyway Safa keys
so this is the file we want to open it
make a bag back up no just in case now
knocks off my keys is you know you I
have four thousand lines of code but
vast majority of that is functions so if
you actually look at the code for those
of you Emacs these coders you don't have
to know a lot actually you can actually
you can create a layout yourself it's
not that hot so I mean so if you look at
Sophocles it's very easy to understand
because I try to avoid I you know in the
coding style
I vote Markos least Markos I avoid
devices you know functional advice I
will avoid that's kind of my coding
style I avoid all the fancy you know
programming language features used
because usually I don't I don't think
they are helpful so the code is very
simple very simple to understand and I'd
rather have more code then just like you
know very short code that very short
code that like a marker that represent
hundreds 100 lines if you have a
boundary lines I rather have hot 100
lines because when you have that you can
actually in your glass you can
understand what the code is doing such
as like look at this
you know such as you know for example
these examples anyway that's that's
about coding style that's another issue
because to properly talk about that I
have to go more into detail because then
I know a lot of people will say oh no
you just you think you're
stupid that's you know the Nerds they do
that all the time especially the Lisp
coders they love Marcos like Marco is
like has cows Mona Mona Mona every day
whispers it's Marcos Marcos you need
Marco's you need you know two to one
plus one you need to create a Marco
anyway so so look at suffer okay let's
just do this okay so no man layout so
let's go to the top then let me start to
create normal layout so let's go through
search for Commack okay search for
Commack ma th so we see this Commack
okay so Tsavo ACTU Commack ma th map so
this is what you need so we are going to
create a copy of these for the normal
layout okay so okay let's just do that
so let's do that for act 2 programmable
acts so let's add at the bottom maybe
so we're act to quote he AP&T Chima key
map okay that's that's useful Brazil I
think so let's go back to court Zhi
Liang so go back to walkman they are ok
let's copy go back to walkman paste okay
and modify this will act to normal key
map okay so this is essentially what we
have to do we just create modify this
okay so now this problem now because I
have to
now I have to do these okay so wait so
wait so close that maybe actually kinda
showing from okay I kind of want okay
hang on a second
so
am I still going yeah okay so we're
gonna need a EO UI okay a yo UI that's a
s e TG okay a s e TG now it's similar to
walkman somehow
so a EO UI that's Warrick left hand home
row
so our nomen it's a SE t he might make
sure yeah this is rhomin so ASET ASET G
okay now now on the right hand you have
th T and s so on the right hand you have
th T and s so our nomen it's Y n io h YN
i o h o it's very similar to walkman
interesting so that's an omen layer so
on the top row and on the lorac you have
okay so let me show you maybe let's show
of Iraq
on the top row you have ' coma period P
Y okay so that would be here
' comma period py okay that's the left
hand so our normal you have qw d f k q w
DF k okay on the right hand on vorak you
have F G C RL okay f GC our right here
so on an omen you have J you are L
semicolon J you tell semicolon okay so
here's a top-floor left hand top row
right hand me the home row left hand
home row right hand and let's see the
bottom row so on Borak you have
semicolon q JK x semicolon q JK x that's
right and on an omen you want z XC v b z
XC v be okay for the right hand bottom
you have on the on the vorak you have
p MW v z PM wvz correct on an omen you
have PM PM coma
period okay so p m coma
period / okay that is done that is the
heart of it I think that is heart of it
so modify the doc so at least each
element is the form first chai first
choice for a second corresponding Norman
layout okay
not all chars are in the list such as
digits when not in this list they are
assumed to be the same okay let's just
that's the bulk of it so once you okay
now we have created this for act to
normal map there are some other places
you need to change your course we can
find out by just searching for this
Walkman let's see where it is
oh you don't find it anywhere okay I
know I know what's going on so hold on a
second it's such for act to quote Z okay
you don't find in any way so we now we
need to find a place where this key map
is used I know where because it's the
eMac this generates a stream then
convert that to a symbol that is why you
don't find this symbol anywhere so
anyway so let's go to the top let's go
to the documentation part and add a
nomen here
so now let's search for workmen wherever
workman is mentioned we just modify that
to add an omen that should walk so
search for nomen I mean such for workmen
then workman
okay then search for workmen here okay
soft like he said layout here is where
you said I said we also had Norman okay
so here is how you said they are stuff
like you can lay out so anyway so search
for Walkman again okay you don't find it
anymore okay
now to trace where that key map is used
is this this function so sit stuff like
he couldn't they are to to this argument
they are so such this function let's see
where it is there it is so define
variable the current layout so the
current layout is is depending yeah
that's if that's Neil then sedative Iraq
now here is the function that's what we
need you see here is a function supply
current layout key map
yes Emily yes but I just haven't got to
it let me get to that Sox are currently
out key map so this is the place where
the key maps matters so you see this
this is a variable defined var okay you
see this is confusing so sapphire key
color layout is a string it's a variable
whose value is a string the string
specifies what is the layout and this
very box off like current layout key map
is also a variable whose value is a key
map and which key map it gets the value
depends on the variable depends on the
very box of like he current layout so
that's how it works
so you see it sets the key map set Q key
map then it look at you know it look at
this this is a key line so contracts are
Borak to then the current layout then -
key map so that that does it so you
don't need to add nomen anywhere I think
now it supports nomen yep I'm pretty
sure we are done so we always change
these two places we create the map from
black to Norman then we then then we
change another function that is all we
did let's go to let's go back okay we
cannot go back so search for walkman
yeah so another so we created a out the
conversion team at first then we just
change this function stuff like his cell
layout actually all we did is add a
documentation so that's all that's all
it takes
so save this file let's switch out of
Emacs EOB automatically
saved so let's see Emily says could you
write some abstraction that allows for a
user to just input a string of their
keyboard layout yeah that's very
convenient I being you know wanting to
that to do that on on the Ocoee max
project which is a key binding for Emacs
I did that you know like seven years ago
for for like seven years that's a
feature I want so so basically you want
people to just create a string let's say
for example that you know I'm trying to
explain what's going on so X play out
okay let's say so all you have to do is
choose just to wait just make a string
then on Borak is for example HDTV so
this is the this is a home row and let's
magnify and the top row is just that
okay the bottom row is okay something
like that
so you just tell people to create a
string like this then then you know for
whatever new layout people just create
that then that's done that this is great
well I haven't coded that you know you
know you just walk now it's lazy and you
know lazy yeah you need more code you
know also they are of course there are
some other improvements I need to do and
also I need to mentioned in the past few
days you know they many people started
to suggest and for example let's look at
issue anyway so that topic is done so
let's talk about something else so if
you have comments questions post it now
okay so yeah that would be a cool
feature to add you know I'd like to so
Emily are you volunteering so emily is
using a
I mean evil mod which is good you know
the advantage with Evo mod is that
because it's kind of popular it's like
ten hundred probably hundred times more
popular than Java keys why because then
you know him is hundred times more
popular than Emacs why because wim is
spilled in every Unix
by default I mean come with any Linux
you know by default so Daddy that is
very powerful just like Microsoft you
know people use Microsoft so they are
you know they just use Microsoft Word or
whatever Microsoft come with it you know
because most people are not programmers
I mean even if you are a programmer you
don't like if you just download that
Linux you just owe him you know you just
use it and also they teach in school
because it's part of Unix you don't have
to down you know if you want to use
Emacs that's extra step you have to
first of all no no like someone told
some of your friends told you there's
Emacs then you know it you become aware
then you maybe after a year you try to
download it you know
so things that spawned oh that's
tremendously powerful you know just
spend it with it so so vim is like
hundred times more popular than Emacs
not because other things okay nerds
ideas it's force it's factually
incorrect vim is more popular in Emacs
because it's bundled with UNIX for the
past thirty forty years that is why and
what's the next thing so what's Salim ya
Salim is very popular and the advantage
with Evo mod which is vim based on VM
key binding is that so you can use vim
to you know so you can you build muscle
habits you can use vim or Emacs you
become quite versatile versatile
especially if you have a hacker type I
give you our Mission Impossible movie
you know you have to go to some place
and
five minutes you need to you know hack
on some system on a keyboard you never
touched before on a new UNIX system
where you don't have your own setups and
key bindings and also you have five
minutes to you know to be there hack
into a system and if you are not safe
successful the CIA FBI whatever you'll
be shot okay that's that's in a movies
hacker it means you're impossible now if
you are that type of people you don't
want Emacs okay you want vim and you
don't want war act you don't want
Commack you don't want you don't want no
personal setup you want to keep your
fingers be you know we be you know
familiar with you know everyday systems
that's of course on the other hand if
you are that type of people then you are
not you won't be a good programmer
because you you know the anyway that's
another thing if you are you know
developer that's not what you want you
want a setup like you want the power
station you want Kinesis you know you
want a you want a station you want a
mastered battle station you know where
you can do you press winger one finger
the nuclear missile is launched you know
the leg not or start the application
then you know then is something you know
you just you have a complete setup
motrin kinases so Emily's has that such
a system and you know so I also have
something similar so you want a battle
station let's mention that okay in the
petrol station so let's go to its let's
show some the interesting pictures of
battle station and I'm gonna read the
comments so actually so after that maybe
we do three more minutes and that that's
about it so if you have comments posted
okay yeah so we finished the major thing
we want to do which is no man layout
okay battle stations battle stations get
on your battle stations
let's look at okay this this is a
example of battle station this is what
you want this is you know you know guess
what this is this is fantastic this is
actually you know this is a lousy photo
that is not big but anyway hide it it's
not height resolution but anyway this is
a parallel station okay here wait yeah
so you see I press everything just by
one finger I don't have to control shift
+ sign to magnify then control - to
something you know I just one thing go
operation now you can I can hold it down
and magnify and shrink and so on so you
know you have this panel station you
have this how do you call this what's
the proper name for this this thing this
throttle you call that throttle right no
well throttle usually refers to the
airplane kind of thing so these those
are not those are kind of like sliders
were not really how do you what's the
proper term code to call these guys you
know you know so you have knobs you know
you have I believe that's a trackball
you have buttons over the face you know
so this this is actually a video editing
console so mohchung so let's see the
comments but wait wait I want to show
you panel stations so let me remember
that okay my roommate is cooking like
he's chopping chopping beef so battle
stations
now you you want to look at battle
stations you can go to look at Emily's
setup and she's got a spectrum analyzer
spectrum and analyzer
she needs to analyze spectrums when
she's coding yes okay we you know we did
a video of her set up a few days ago
last week also in fact more than one
video so anyway there are other parallel
stations let me show you so you know I
corrected some of these okay this you
know these are the battle stations
different people different styles you
can you can see then this guy's screen
setup everything and you have Emacs mug
that's all important Emacs mug do you
have that Emily are you going to get one
Emacs mug and then you have this okay
clean setup then you have this is most
fascinating this guy this guy's oboe but
he's a mathematician you
he's got homotopy type theory book there
that that book came out like four years
ago and to be able to understand that
book requires basically a graduate level
math okay so this guy you know he
doesn't you know you can see he doesn't
have money like all the other fancy
setups he's using you know twenty years
old keyboard thirty twenty years old
trackball a cheap headphone headset you
know this and also I was thinking maybe
this is 20 years old photo no because
he's got homotopy type theory book there
that book came out only five years ago
so this is not a old you know photo so
this guy is a poor sob but but he's got
you know he's really homotopy type
theory few people literally I would say
ten thousand people maybe twenty
thousand people in a world understand
homotopy type theory understand you know
yeah yeah so this we have a rare beast
well sometimes you know you have the
book does not necessarily mean you know
that stuff I try to read that that's
that's hard you take you take you a few
years to really understand it so we have
you know different people different
styles their you know their desktop top
that's always very interesting to look
at then you know some of them are
professors some of them this guy is from
Keck Caxton okay a patriot of kicks Dan
and you know any fun fun stuff looks are
what slow for what what is your battle
station nabi okay so let me read a
comment saying that there'll be it so
Wow Emily you not sleep yet so nappy
nappy nappy young young Nabi young young
oh I never noticed young that's a
Chinese name so you are a Chinese spy by
blood are you
were you born in America or were you
like you've been here like you know it's
different anyway so what I did miss
about Commack saw started early okay so
yeah you might check out you know watch
the YouTube Winston
so Emily says could you write some disco
yeah we did talked about that it should
be really easy to implement based on how
your code looks now but I haven't have a
proper look at it oh now if you if you
contribute you know I would look at it
right away as priority you know so soft
I kiss you know it's open source but
I've been doing open source ago Emacs
for ten years in South Africa keys for
five years it works
it just works you know you can download
it and use but of course people has
requests for features you know but I
don't have money you know I don't work
for company you know so I you know
basically I don't have money so when I
look at that you know it just means I
just have to spend you know one hour two
hours to do them and you know I cannot
you know so usually it's like when I see
features you know like the issues
typically they they want some features
right it takes time you know it takes
more than you would think like it's not
just oh five minutes you know it's take
Wow becomes two hours becomes three
hours I do this every day you know
replying comments and stuff answering
questions for Emacs
oh I installed Emacs but the found was
one shocks ah do you know what to do
yeah I get that emails you know it's you
know that's the situation but you know
so and and also and also some people
Daniel Anglo is he contributed you know
big chunk of code and he and then you
also follow suffice a lot you know but
you know it's like we are hackers right
we are in some sense nerds hackers so we
I enjoy them but but not if I don't have
funny things to eat you know so I cannot
spend my time just you know then you
like to like he gently what I know he
contribute code but he also he talked
about generalize things house design
should be then you know I'd it's it's
it's you know it's it's gonna take me
time to you know the gist and think what
to do about that you know so so open
source you know it's not often is that's
that's my point unless you get paid I
don't I don't I don't get paid so anyway
anyway so
you know many people have contributed so
thank you guys and of course they are
always we I need improvements for the
code there's a few things to do but well
anyway anyway if Emily if you if you you
know do some code there I'll look at it
first
okay I think that's it for today so Nabi
says guess I better keep practicing
corty and vim I only use Evo models I
haven't finished my Emacs in interaction
there so Emacs so Emily is creating her
own model mod I think okay so now we say
small Tron definitely looks like a
battle station indeed and Emily is is
going to buy that need to call them up
tomorrow yeah
so George good morning George hello
Danny Daniel hey Daniel now buo trashing
his desktop no money
no and I'm sleep here so no means miss
in Korea what no it means miss in Korean
what does that refer to
the car alarm in my neighborhood is it
means miss in Korean Oh Jung means
missing Korean I'm half Korean oh okay
half white American Oh here so you are a
Eurasian you well you know the Eurasian
you know they are beautiful you know I
want I want to have a baby with a blonde
well actually biologically when you mix
races they're your children becomes more
healthy I am not sure exactly what's the
theory but it's called Viggo it's called
something G does anyone know remember
George you might know what's the name
for
giorgia did not block you that's by
accident because because I have Auto
Creek you know that anyway so what's the
name for when you have mixed race you
know let's say white guy and black guy
your children or even animals like cats
one race of cats you know with another
race so you have you know children cats
kitties kittens and and there's a
biological term in general they become
more healthy like more
it's called hybrid vigor yes I knew you
knew it George
hybrid vigor so sorry so I heard of that
I'm not sure what is a biological basis
you know I I don't know much about
chemistry or biology but I've tried to
read Wikipedia sometimes hit head
so apparently okay hybrid vegan hey okay
so Wikipedia has this article about what
okay here so anyway that's something to
read hybrid vigor yeah okay heterosis oh
our breathing enhancement is the
improved or increased function of any
biological quality in a hybrid offspring
an off stream is heterotic if it's
traits are enhanced as a result of
mixing the genetic contributions of its
parents these effects can be due to okay
here's a tea these effects can be due to
mender lien ornamentally and inheritance
okay I don't know what that is you have
to read it so apparently that's the
thing because if you look at cats you
know in general when I look at cats
purebred they usually ugly I don't like
them you know what I like the cat I love
cats
I like tabby cats the most tabby cats
which is
the most common Street cats tabby cats I
find them to be most beautiful actually
accept some purebred okay some purebred
you know there's Bango Bango cats which
is kind of like a tiger mainly anyway so
you have this you know this concept of
hybrid vigor and also for people you
know human animals I think it's also
true that you know I think when you have
like Asian and white people mix usually
it's beautiful they're your children I
think that's it for today anything else
eleven people watching in one hour and
six minutes that's it for today I think
so George
so so let me read so George says all the
Chinese guys I know who married a white
woman always a very small petite blonde
woman must be an Asian thing now really
yeah I guess maybe I don't know but
always a very small petite brown women
woman well okay I don't know if that's
generally true but actually that's not
generally true so what I'm saying is
that if you asked Chinese small Chinese
okay I know because I'm Chinese if you
ask most Chinese in China which I never
been to but in Taiwan which I'm you know
I I was born in Taiwan you if you ask
most Chinese today like for example due
to the today like America you know white
blonde woman women to be their sexual
partner or marry you usually know
usually the Asian girls are more
attractive to them and I think this is
in general okay on average true for any
way so if you are black you tends to
like blacks better if you are AC on you
like I see if you are white people you
tend to like white people
you know I think that that is actually
more true of course but but you know for
example if you are a white person and if
you like Chinese girls or Chinese guys
for example then that fact tends to be
more popular because that's unusual that
becomes more dramatic that's what people
talk about so that's that is why I think
people get that idea
hey girls gasp OH woo from Taiwan hey my
countrymen
Nihao Taiwan Cathy so okay so anyway so
I just mean the ones who married far in
the most didn't right okay you know I'm
I'm always just commenting you know my
you know I'm doing my show not
necessarily you know Anthony you know
your you guys all the people's any
specific thing anyway so let's see I
think that's it for today so let's see
Danielle
half British half Georgian oh I see
where's Georgia what is Georgian
Georgian is at a country so no it's miss
okay young is mixed-race missed but miss
was purify Danielle is half British half
Georgian yeah so what
what is Georgian how is it pronounced
something like not be young young Hanja
what is I character well now I need to
read that so let's see copy that go to
Emacs a new buffer paste and magnify the
hell out of it Mia song that's not a
common Chinese character okay so I'm not
sure how to pronounce that it's not a
common Chinese character
so that's Korean honja I don't know
Korean but Korean that's actually
alphabet Korean has this interest
interesting writing system
they created a writing system such that
it's not like you know the European ones
where you just put adjacent to each
other forming a line but the Korean
alphabet you have a bunch of symbols but
you combine them to form one character
you know so that's Korean system very
interesting so anyway this this
character I don't know
I would pronounce it Mia or not so I
don't know Korean
so Beth hit it something kupah veludo so
what are you saying okay no swearing
words okay
Beth so I don't know what that is I'm
thinking some of some Japanese words hey
Tony okay we got new people
Tony where you from so actually I think
we are sitting down so we shut down in
one minute okay no more comments I think
I mean you know we've been talking for
an hour so Navi says don't know how
people read Chinese on computer it's so
small you know you don't actually you
don't actually read each character
stroke like you don't
for example this this this character you
know it's so it's fairly complicated
right you don't you don't read each
strokes rather you just look at the
overall shape that's how it works just
like English you know English you do the
same
you don't actually read you know the
each letters there's shape why a you
know you just look at overall shape of
the world same thing with the Chinese
characters bye guys thank you for coming
by guys like my video subscribe and
stuff and I have PayPal account on my
you know on my website you know where to
find so Tony from Canada all right I
think I yeah I think I've talked to you
so join this code okay I got a discord
you can find the links sorry disco bye
guys