good morning everyone welcome to another
episode ofan talk show today we are
going to uh code emac lisp live coding
uh about an hour several problems three
tasks uh so let me introduce my keyboard
This is glove 0 fantastic I have a
review on my YouTube website this is
Ultimate hacking keyboard I use as a
keyboard markco fantastic and this is uh
this is data hand SW board SV a l b o a
r d magnetic switch so I'm going to use
it down the road I have review on on
YouTube and on my
website so but today we are going to
code emac be so let's begin coding emac
L okay I'm using sof FL Keys uh
uh as as you know sof flag Keys is a
efficient key binding system for emac if
you use emac I recommend it there's a
video there's a tutorial there's lots of
information
customization uh essentially you don't
have to press control keys I mean you
don't have to press control X or meta
key so makes your typing much more
efficient even more efficient than Vim
or VI or NE VM or uh Evo
mod okay so but today we're going to uh
code emac this if you have questions
related to emac or about Programming
type it okay the pink window shows all
my command CES uh command code names and
uh keystrokes I'm using a v keyboard
layout okay let's
begin so let's begin coding yeah so
there are few tasks so first of all okay
let me show you what I need to do so
usually in my keyboard I mean in my uh
when I work on my website there are
about 9,000 original Pages written since
1997 so you see there is a for example
on this page uh United Kingdom layout
actually let's show emac um since we are
subject this emac so go to emac
blog uh and uh let's go to
uh let's go to one of the page uh let's
say Okay read file content or or strings
or lines so you see over here there's a
list of
related uh uh article for example buffer
how do you manipulate bu buffer
functions and you go to the bottom and
then you have read file or all are
related how to read a file and here is
read file as a string or
lines and then you have how to write the
file so all these are related so let's
copy the link and uh close it and uh
close it and let's say paste the link
here so and you go to that page you you
go down and you'll see this
um topic box okay so this is uh this
this is the topic box uh but there is
another one called related box so let's
show that so search for
rltd so for example uh let's go to emac
Dev inefficiency this is a Asian article
2010 I discuss how emac Dev development
is fairly inefficient okay it's old
article so anyway you go down so these
are related Bo related
articles you know it's a bit different
from the topic box so anyway that's you
know that's some detail about but anyway
so the the bottom line is that I have
this related you know um navigation box
for a bunch of links so normally the way
I do it so I I you know lots of page has
these marks so I need to create it how
do I create it it right now I use a for
example let's extract all the link here
press a key you can see the command is
right there K HTML extract URL I'm using
Kar HTML mod if you want it you pay me I
get uh donate and I sent it to you
search for HTML you'll find
it so we just extracted the link and we
can make them all a link and make them a
list now so we got this list
and I need to add this
dive uh dive HTML element with the rltd
class name so normally what I do I have
a brief
rltd so you get that then I copy that
cut that paste it
here then show in browser then you go
down so you can see you know we just
created new related uh uh articles
box but this is inefficient because I
mean so what I want to do is I want to
write the new command so I just call the
command I related you know I TD and
press enter and it will just wrap this
RTD around that very easy okay so let's
do
that so uh close that close that so what
I want to do now is write vile I'll
close that okay let's start to code
it emac disp so I'm using HTML mod
Define uh let's
say
HTML uh this this prefix means that's my
personal HTML command not part of the ex
HTML mod
so add related box something like that
okay let's just name it uh uh for that
for now
version today's version okay and uh
documentation add a dive of iltd
class to current text block
Okay okay something like that so let's
begin to write it so first the first of
all first of all if you have questions
comment okay
so first of all you uh you want to find
the beginning of beginning and end
position of the text block
okay okay I already have that command so
that command would
be uh okay so let's go find
it so here is all my packages Elis uhar
thing Kar thing is is online free search
for defund so you got all these
functions it's on GitHub you search it
you'll find it so uh get position a
block okay or okay all the current text
selection okay let's call that function
so okay let's go back to our code so
let's create a variable xp1
XP two that means position one position
two beginning and end okay and uh
let's okay so then we call this function
and we want to set um set this to the
variable it returns two integers that's
a beginning and end position so we want
to set them to xp1 xp2 so there's a new
um let's let me show you sequence okay
that's a new function uh new about 5
years
ago so you call sequence function
and put a sequence here and the ARs is
going to
be oh actually I don't want sequence Le
okay I want sequence set okay sequence
set yeah so argument is the X1 that's a
variable name and the sequence quence is
that okay so this will set whatever this
return this returns a vector which is a
sequence data type in emx disp and that
set the variable so this is very
convenient instead of instead of setting
each one you
know um in separate lines so you set
them so you got the beginning and end
position of the block and then all you
have to do is just wrap the HTML dive so
let's
[Music]
see uh RTD yeah so let's go back R LTD
yeah all we have to do is wrap that so
you need to make this
um so Escape quote okay so you need to
es escape the
quote that there okay so you need to
insert so why don't
we so first of all we got beginning end
position and um then X text okay so
that's a variable set X text equals to
buffer
um buffer substring no properties okay
then give a positions xp1 xp2 that will
grab this block of text into to a string
X text okay then we grab that and
actually delete region delete region is
then delete them then just
insert insert that and then insert X
text then we just
insert that okay pry the code
uh let's remove the extra new lines
let's remove that okay that's it that's
our function let's double
check add related box Okay add HTML dive
tag to uh dive
tag uh with
class name rltd toon text block okay so
that's it actually so let's if evaluate
the code run curent buffer you can see
the command name there eval and uh put
this
back syntax CLE showing browser that's
our code will it work I'm sure it will
uh let's we can try it on over here so
call it s add related box okay do it you
see fantastic it works so now showing
browser there it is is fantastic so this
is convenient like before I have to do
rltd a bre then you know copy whatever
then go here paste it then you know uh
you know but now we got it perfect uh
except we want to pedify you know we
want the extra line here so we just fix
the
code we want a new line here
and and a new line here
okay
fantastic eval the
buffer pop it back syntax C it and uh
delete that put it here delete that now
let's try it again call it yes fantastic
beautiful okay that's one job done
fantastic so now I can when I work on my
lots of my 9,000 Pages blog I can easily
create the
I mean slightly easier saves you five
keystrokes also okay that's one thing
done how many people are watching
uh you you know this YouTube uh you need
to change the video resolution the
current resolution which is not
supported for this
[Music]
configuration the expected resolution is
am I doing fine am I doing uh
uh test if you are watching test okay 10
people watching so am I like live stream
okay uh this a YouTube you need to
change the video resolution because I
changed one thing I reduced the latency
so so if you are here oh there it is
hello hello
okay fantastic fantastic so we did the
first job now let's move on to the next
job so this one we did so next job is
okay so let me show you so you see since
I write you know the 9,000 Pages HTML
manually beginning in beginning in
1997 so we you know in emac of course
over the past 25 years I've you know
started to write lots of emac this
functions to help me so but essentially
still like manual I don't use any
content managers or or mod convert to
HTML or markdown you know I don't I
don't use any of that um and I consider
my system more efficient meaning that
less keystrokes to do exactly the same
thing so if you are using o mod you know
OG mod like
um uh you know some title then you press
a key to convert to HT HTML or if you
are using you know that Jacker or
whatever Hector or whatever content
management system for static
website I I I'm pretty sure that you
know the way I do it is less keystrokes
for exactly the same thing okay for
example if I want to make this a title I
press the key to that okay so in or mod
you you press you know shift start and
something you know similar okay
so anyway so there's a command for
example uh right now I want to copy the
current files file path copy it okay
paste it it's there okay let's do it
again let's go to some page some other
page okay Sly Keys uh let's go to some
other page okay press a key three keys
copy file path that's a command name
close it close it go back here okay
close that go back here uh okay that's
today's talk show go back paste so you
see we got this file path now I want to
link it press a key uh not that key
press a key so that's a tab edge with v
keyboard layout HTMI any link so you got
a link and I can make it a paragraph
undo or make a list undo you know just
like two key strokes okay no control
something
so now the next job we need to do is
that so you have a file so this file um
example let me show you what this is
okay so let's uh viewing browse let's
Okay open in Firefox okay let's view
this link
in Firefox okay so this is you can see
this
is.info so This see you see this is a
unical search so I can
you know this is a JavaScript
application so you can type fire so it
will show instantaneously all unic code
names containing the word fire uh water
okay uh very interesting smile or unic
code names containing smile
Latin okay so so but I got a problem so
you see you go to the
link copy the link and go back to uh
emac you paste it you see you got this
query string okay now if I make it a
link do
it uh okay wrong key do it it works okay
so you can see you know so now you can
press enter just press enter to go to it
and you can you know you have the result
there uh I don't like this one so let's
change it to uh fire okay fire link it
again make a make a HT uh list go to it
there it is all unic code characters
containing the word fire you know quite
diverse emoji and all that and Chinese
characters and Japanese
so so okay that works however if this
link if I'm doing you know right now
this link is htd P you know s. info
however if I'm
on
uh for example I'm on this let's open
that uh okay so actually let's copy
this uh new page paste that you see now
I'm viewing exactly the same page but
locally so it you know it's a local file
it still works this JavaScript
application but however now if I want to
link this into that you know into uh
that it won't work because for example
copy you know
so uh link it doesn't work so it
says
HTML arrrow so you know
um calling HTML local file to link look
any link eror something file not exist
so it's trying to open this
with the query string as a file so we
need to uh fix that okay so is that
clear I guess that's clear description
of the
problem so let's do
it how come you you are writing this
blog for that long because I'm beautiful
yes that's true and because you guys are
beautiful okay so we need to fix this
function so the so what you need to do
is
that fix this
function okay so what you need to do
that when a local file link contains a
query
string uh you need to you need to First
remove the query stream
then link
the file then add back the query string
something like that okay let's begin to
write that okay so uh emac list okay
create a e
um emac list block okay go to it open it
Define
function uh actually we don't okay uh
actually we need to fix it we need to
there's a existing function here so we
just open that okay so uh describe
function there it is go to the source
code there is a documentation go to the
source code open there is a source code
so we need to modify this
code okay this is a bit hairy uh about
50 lines okay
so okay so well I mean let's let's do it
so I mean this
is you know this is
a slightly larger function function so
it's
not suitable for a live stream because
then you you know because it's not a
simple thing uh then you guys don't
understand you know what I'm doing but
anyway let's do
it okay small break I've been talking
for 22 minutes how are you guys
uh subit says subit MRA hea just
wondering if one can modify the
transpose command let's
see wondering if one can modify the
transport transpose command such that if
a plus b and put my crua on the plus
Mark plus it becomes B plus a are you
talking about the transpose command on
my
website no you are not you are talking
about oh you are talking about the emac
transpose command I don't like those
command I don't use
it
uh yeah so you know so emac has a
transpose command which basically swaps
the swaps the word before before the CER
and after CER it just swap it you know I
I don't like a lot of people like that
command I don't I don't use it but your
problem is that when there's a plus sign
you simply want to swap you know before
the plus sign and after plus sign uh uh
you can write it you can write it in 10
minutes okay I can I can show you how to
write it in 10 minutes uh but uh not
going to do it now I because I got other
things to do if you chick Ching give me
$10 I'll do it right right now 10 10
minutes you'll have the
command okay and uh the donation you
know if you guys donate via the YouTube
YouTube takes half of it so anyway so if
you want to donate donate okay uh PayPal
is the
best Okay so let's go back um let's go
back you know you can easily write it
okay us you can easily write the command
because I've talked you know so let me
show you guys the I've talked about you
know coding emac for there are like 50
videos dedicated to uh learning emac
thisp from the ground up so you just go
to ex talk show homepage and uhan talk
show clips there's a section on emac so
here is a section on
emac and there's a section on emac disp
I believe so it's pure yeah so all these
are from the groundup you know my best
videos each one is about an hour and so
to write that command it's been covered
like I've been you know coding it live
for like over 10
times uh and you can also find them in
my you know if you just go to my emac
website you know there's emac tutorial
emac customization init file tutorial
emac key binding tutorial everything you
need to know about it and uh then you
after you are familiar with emac you can
start to learn emac lisp so lisp Basics
you know the number how do you do a
number string buing variable and
function Loop and data structure list
Vector sequence type hash table how to
write a function and then you are famili
once you are familiar with the basic you
know the syntax of lisp you know very
able function then you go to
um uh then you go to practical emac dis
that's when you get to know buffer how
do you you know buffer buffer position
like what we just did you know uh 10
minutes ago you know buffer buffer
position how do you manipulate curser
how do you move how do you search text
you know text processing so that's this
section then you know so this is most
important this is like what you use emx
for then once you know that you can move
on to learning how to write a major mod
that's when you need to know you know
how to how to write a you know directory
editor like you know like like directory
or or a shell you know so we are in a
shell uh the okay LS you know you can
you know you can write a shell so this
is not about text processing so any
anyway then you can write a model major
mod syntax cing and all all that so I
talked about this a million times okay
so if you really are
interested in learning stuff like that's
usually you know what what I do so you
know you can easily find all the
information you
need and so back to your uh question
about that I can recommend you just
write the new command don't modify the
default I mean and also it's not
suitable just you can write that in 10
minutes I well I can write it in 10
minutes because I've been coding emist
for 20 years uh you but you from scratch
you can um you know you can do it in two
three hours okay so I recommend you do
that you know so that's my advice for
that question so okay go back um so
let's see S Talk Show close close um
what is this emx block close Okay so we
need so right now we need to fix
this CU HTML uh local file link okay
okay uh so in this case I won't be
talking
much
because because otherwise the code
there's a lot to go through basically
what this command do is that it takes a
link like that
then it converts it to a for example you
know takes a
link convert it I mean takes a file path
local file path converted to a link so
it's pretty simple uh but why do I need
you know like for example let's open a
new file 50 lines of
code so why is that 50 lines of code
well because it actually does lots of
things because it
um yeah you have to deal with for
example sometimes your file path
is is like that but sometimes you your
file path is let me show you like that
okay you see this is like a this is a
URL
format and so and this is a Windows File
path they have a you know beginning
letter for the drive drive drive so on
Unix so on Unix you
have just that and if you get if you get
the path from
Shell then your path is uh let's Okay so
let's run a command let's go to Shell
for example du let's
magnify so if you are from Shell then
what you get
now the
uh what is what is this got
the okay the
um uh God Windows you know I hate these
windows they don't show the full path so
if you want to full path you you need to
do okay we are digressing a lot
um okay so this is how you get the full
path in
Windows and but then but you can see
they are using
backslash you
see so your command needs to deal with
all these case you know that that's the
issue with the coding like when you
learn a tutorial or some ad Advent of
code usually it's totally problems very
you know you just very simple
but in real life you know you got to
deal with this it's easy to do but it's
tedious you have this you know it's
just you know different cases you have
to deal
with also this Capital C you see in emac
there's a issue it Returns the lower
case C but typically in Windows it
should be Capital Case
C so that's why this command is kind of
and this command also does lots of other
things for example if you don't have any
selection you'll just do that line but
sometimes if your file name contains a
paren which is a valid file
name then it won't work because you know
so the issue is there is no standard
that
specifies which character is allowed it
it's different on Unix on Mac and on
Windows
and and so and basically you cannot you
know there's no program programmable way
to to have it work 100% of the time so
when you have a situation like that you
need the user to make a selection so
when user have a selection then call the
command then it use a selection so that
part is you know it's kind of
here that that gets a beginning position
and end position and then there's other
complexities so what if the file begin
with HTTP for example so uh so let's for
example let's say uh copy
okay so that's one example of file path
but what if the file path
is that you see these two are exactly
the same file except the first one is
local this one is the you know the the
the the
website so when you have this situation
you have issues like so when when user
call your command do you want to for
example let's copy this here actually
let's create a new file paste it okay so
you can link that uh wrong key so let's
copy it here okay link it so you see it
becomes the link now Now link it you see
it also becomes link however this link
even though they are the same file but
but this link use the HTTP you know so
you have to make a decision you
sometimes you don't want that you know
you always want local file should be
always relative link that depends on the
the website design you know so it gets
that that's why so this is why this
function is you know 50 lines
also uh
so so let's get back to our current
problem we need to I want to should we
do it or should we not yeah I want to do
it so let me just quickly fix
it okay so the problem is when you have
[Music]
the you know the query string you want
to remove it okay so let's go back let
me just quickly fix it
uh first of all we need to know the
structure okay so local F path right
so okay so file path is the file path
okay yeah so we just need to fix this
part and uh and here we are using set
Q okay so we are getting the text
input both substring no properties okay
uh and uh
then convert HTP to file
path okay
so so but anyway so this is the input
input Parts there it is so the issue is
here so you
see when you have a hash link you know
sometimes you have a if you know if you
know web dev this file path
can have you know for example this file
path can have a pound
sign that will jump to a specific
location on the page okay
so so this line deal with that but
however we didn't deal with query string
so we need to fix that okay easy to fix
because I already have a function
written somewhere that extract the the
query string so let's um let's describe
function jump to that so this file is
HTML
engine and uh so this function split it
URI hash mask so actually I want to
rename URI to
URL because URI is like complicated
esoteric
thing and the HTML 5 stand
they decided you know we you know they
don't use the URI anymore they just use
URL you know this is a big thing among
the Nerds like 20 years ago you know
they they would argue about how URI is
different from URL
anyway so there it is okay so right now
let's just um so here's a function sped
urri query Mark okay sped the
URL um hrf value by question character
return a vector okay let's let's quickly
fix this okay I don't want to you know
let's just hack it
up and I'll deal with it later for the
live stream let's just hack it so input
parts
then then okay and
um so yeah once you you split the query
Mark then okay then
[Music]
you yeah so actually this is not good
because
yeah because once you split it you have
to you know take the first
part a ref
means take a first part of the vector
the Zero's index
that's what a ref
is and uh then frag part uh that doesn't
that's not right well I mean that's
right but you see the the issue is that
you don't
know whether there is a
hashm okay let me just think about
this uh actually so
so let's so all these are set okay
so okay so something let's
see so there's a question if there's a
hash Mark and if there's a query Mark
which one comes first okay so let's look
home do we have um do we have another
function that
just deconstruct
URL defend list matching lines defend
pass URL okay so we need to redo all
this let's say pass
URL uh so so let's answer the question
where the the hash mark comes first or
the query string so you go
to you go to visual CSS you go to
JavaScript Dome that's my JavaScript
tutorial then you go to you need uh pass
URL so don't methods so you go to D
methods basic
examples
uh element attribute add remove class
attribute get parent child sibling
create not insert no change element
content add remove Handler no HTML input
radio box buttons no web scripting
examples okay that's user
interface uh and misl there it is uh
pass URL
okay get URL okay so get
URL so you have search stram query stram
and hash
so syntax okay okay so the query string
comes before the
hash uh
ID that answer that that question but
anyway so we going to use
this pass URL okay pass U return a hash
table uh oh return a hash table
result has the following Keys okay let's
use
this okay let's do this properly okay so
instead of hack let's go back to yeah
here
so so so call that function pass
URL let's say URL hash okay it's just
random name for
now so you you got a URL Parts okay so
let's say
actually okay URL
Parts Ching thank
you thank you
Mishra I thought you have to go that
swap around operator to make a
uh
what okay so we passed the URL so we got
URL parts and uh and
uh and uh then the result is a hash
table okay
so
Jesus so the result is a hash
table then you have to
oh God this is T tedious to do
God because once you separate it you
have to put it
back
yeah okay let's put the code back okay
let's Let's Escape shrink back
to okay so here here's a kind of like
the original code now let's not touch it
let's um hold on a
second I have a function written before
so let's cheat and look up that
function uh that would be similar for
example the function will for
example copy that paste for example if
if you have a local file you call this
function that will turn the local file
into a HTML I mean into a HTTP URL plus
the title of that
page okay and that function isas site so
let's look SAR
site I think that works
on you know so when you have a hash mark
coite you see it
works and but if you have a query string
so let's try where is a query string
uh okay okay we need to get the query
string
there okay now let's try the query
string if you have that
cite it
works so yes because it you know it
works so let's look up Sasa side and uh
let's just copy the code copy and paste
the most fantastic methodology for
programming if you are doing functional
programming okay if you are doing oop
you
you know o copy paste does not
you know supposedly op the Mantra of op
is that you can just like everything is
modularized you can just copy and paste
because the class object but actually no
the real magic you know the real
Advantage for copy paste is functional
programming because every function is
inde
independent even part of a code because
every function is you know all you do is
co- function and every function returns
exactly the same thing given the same
input so anyway so we have it here there
it is you see how beautiful input
fragments the that's a hash table and
then okay so this is actually manual
coding fantastic I'm going to I'm going
to use
this okay so input
fragment and
uh fragment one fragment two
okay actually this code is
incorrect because the query string comes
first yeah because I I forgot you know
so the query string
technically comes before
fragment but over
here I assume the fragment come first
yeah but usually you know practically
speaking this almost never happens that
is you almost never have the fragment ID
with the query string
together so that's why this never run
into a
problem uh so what you're going to do
now God this is you know this this issue
is getting all the time in talk
show Hello Apple
Abdul okay we we've been coding 48
minutes okay
um should we continue yeah let's why not
let's solve
this
so so this is actually a bug
um that's it's kind of common
bug query
string comes
before hash
fragment
okay so we need to take care of that but
anyway how does this code work so you
get the you get the fragment parts then
you get the query string
part
um then you normalize and
whatever H okay so let's not do that
okay and
let's Okay close that let's fix it let's
just fix this code manually okay so what
you do is
so again what you need to do is you
have you know you have
a you have a path with a query
string
okay so let's we can do we can
just solve this in the most simple
way by first checking if there is a
query
string okay
let's then then we can worry about
okay okay let's do this the Primitive
way let's just get this fixed
first check if there's a query string
then check if there is a
hash mark
okay okay so let's let's okay let's do
okay
H query okay let's kind of just hack it
up has hash okay so now we hit so
um if so X input okay if uh stream match
match stram stream match okay if string
match uh not string stream stram match
not
sometimes yeah string match so if string
match this
string okay if it match a question mark
now question mark is a special a regular
expression so you need to escape it so
if it contains a question
mark
then then you just say that
okay okay let's do that that that that
that that that that that that that that
that that
okay has query string okay that's one
shot to do it and uh now similar
here okay wait not pound sign okay clean
up the code okay now we got we know it
has or has not so
now h s has hash okay we need this value
because afterwards we need to put it
back to you know combine them so so so
the input parts so
now so now we can do
this if has query
then then set
[Music]
Q input Parts
okay else do nothing okay so actually
let's do this
when
okay fantastic okay so that and the
wind has hash
oh we got this
wrong there
okay hello Big
R hello Big
R amazing thank you chick Ching chick
Ching me oh oh chick Ching thank
you so if has chck Ching thank you
so uh so we got that uh we got you know
if has query then change the input Parts
okay now if it has hash
then oh wait that's not all so hold on
second
so yeah so this is a bit complex so if
it has
query then we split
into two things okay let's check the
documentation okay it returns a vector
of two elements
okay oh God this is getting
complicated okay so God this is getting
complicated
and needs needs a better way to do this
by the way I looked into the URL pass in
in emac LP that's not good that's
worse okay so this is actually getting
complicated because once you if there's
a query is split into a vector you know
so you got two things then you need to
set the first part to a variable then
second part to a variable then then you
check the check the second part if it
has hash and if it does then again you
need to split in you know it's just too
many code too much
code so now let's look back uh the other
function this seems
now sweet pass
URL uh yeah but it returns a hash table
all these comp complicated
vertical or engine host host
name yeah but this returns too much
complicated
that's right too much rating too
much so if we I mean the real the real
proper way is actually just use this
pass URL
because that's actually the most robust
because the URL may contain www and port
number and all that all that you know in
practice doesn't happen
much so if we use this function
then then after it's done you need to
like reconstruct combine all
these yeah but then then that means uh
you know that means lots of code to
extract the hash key you need to extract
the hash key for each one of these key
then string join them
together oh
God uh you know I can just abandon this
YouTube
[Music]
video and
then yeah because this this practical
coding
is is um where is our code yeah
here okay what you what do you going to
do
so so if we okay let's keep coding okay
let's just keep
coding
um so that people got something to
see okay let's just keep coding so that
people get something to
see uh okay so this this is one way to
do it so but if you do that
[Music]
then then then it is like this okay so
let me show
you then then it is like these
so okay so what
um what wait
okay actually I need to really just
think and
uh okay so I actually need to just think
about how to solve this
properly okay let's do it then okay
so you got a query string you got a
query string and you got the you know
possibly a query string and
uh and uh a
hashtag
so usually they do not happen both of
them
together
but yeah in my case they it never
happens to to have both them them
together but in my case in my website it
does happen sometimes you have the query
stram and sometimes other times you have
the hash
tag but in either case they it rarely
happens like I only have one or two page
has them so
anyway so the task is to write this you
know make a
link take a take a file path or
URL to turn them into a link but
preserve the query string and hashtag
and also a local file you see all these
are local file you see if it's HTML it's
much
easier but the thing is with local file
you need to make a local file a relative
link so you need to you know you need to
turn a full path into a relate for
example like that relative link full
path and uh so you need the reason you
need to pass them is because you you
need the actual file
path and and then sometimes you need to
verify the file exist you see right here
file exist
so that that is why you need to take
them apart first but once you have the
link you need to add them
back
right
so the situation I have now is
that okay if I want to solve this
completely I need to make sure to cover
the case that both of these happens qu
string and
hashtag but in my case they all they
never happen together so
so which way should I do I can just
um in practice they never happen
together
okay yeah in reality they almost never
happen
together okay so that's one way to do it
so we I just
assume one or the other okay they never
happen
together but
a okay that I can do so the alternative
is just more proper way is to not make
that assumption both of them can happen
together so that is uh more proper way
but that more proper way still doesn't
cover port number and also sometimes you
have the loging string you know URL the
protocol is extremely shitty created by
the Nerds you know from 90s ' 80s and
'90s like they go by RFC it's a
crap extremely complicated
so
so so which one should I do
so so uh so if we do the parts
then okay so if we do this
um you know if we do this then you got
this hatch
table or engine
protocol yeah uh this doesn't
work okay this does not work because
because the input path is not always a h
you know uh
[Music]
HTTP you know it's not always a HTTP
thing
so the input is more likely just a file
path like that or
that
so so if you use HTML plus URL it's
actually a
problem you know because file path don't
have port numbers and and all that um
God okay close
that so maybe maybe not
that uh let's look at theas site okay
let's try the Cass site again
so in this function we already kind of
solved it however this is
incorrect okay let's do this let's just
assume this way okay
oh I got it okay so I got it so I yeah
let's do this I got
it okay so
now we okay so we got we check query we
check hash then
[Music]
then we check the query string okay then
then
the then we check the hash okay so the
hash the X input equals
[Music]
to okay we need a new variable okay
so okay
something like that okay
so so actually
if has okay if has query
okay so if so if has qu string then
input input new equals
to uh wait what's this input
Parts oh God did we make a backup
backup input parts
so so we don't need input new okay so
if so if it has
query yeah this is not
good uh What what is is the input part
used input Parts oh yeah that's okay
that's the parts okay so input
Parts got input
parts so input
Parts it's it's two parts okay
so so input part is a vector of two two
elements okay it's a vector of two
elements and
then
input part is a vector of two things so
God what is this so what are we doing so
input parts Part One frag part okay so
file path is the the real thing we need
file
path
so yeah ultimately the file path is what
we
need so we have f
part and we have query string part so
okay let's just declare a bunch of local
variables let's do the easy
way query part
okay you know just like that so
okay this you know temp variable is
always like you know you can like abuse
you know temp variable always make
things much easier so let's just use a
bunch of temp
variables uh so file P part would
[Music]
be okay let's get the vector
get
the input parts and
uh zero okay that's the file part
then okay
then
set query part equals to the
vector input one okay so so
then okay now I got a better idea you
don't even need to check as query let's
look at
uh split URI query Mark okay so let's
look at the describe
function SP the URL
by question character return the vector
so the second part always contain the
question right okay so you
[Music]
simply got it so here is what we do so
sequence set okay sequence set is
fantastic
okay
fantastic file part query part okay so
we do that then we
like remove the hole make it simple then
what about
hash we don't even need to check has
hash okay we don't even need to check
has hash
so so here you split into the file part
so actually
oh God do you need to check they exist
or
not the hash part happens first okay so
actually no wait yeah the hash
happens last so what we can do is do the
hash
first so
so we get the hash if there's no hashtag
then it's empty okay so split URL
Mark hash mark okay split the input and
return
that file part and hash tag part right
then that's right then the then you do
split again so once you remove the hash
tag part you can do the query string
part
so so here you need to not input you
need to take do the on the file part do
the query Mark split then you got the
you reset the variable file part and
query
part okay that's kind of so in here we
have this this is a local
block
okay so now we need to make them into so
where is this xp1
used okay so now let's copy this hole
because this is getting comp complicated
copy
this paste it
here save make a new file this is our
temp
working we just going to work on this so
we don't screw up the oral even though
we kind of already did things so here is
our code and uh
let's so
this input parts
this part
one color them frag
part and X path
okay so we so th those are the variables
so X pt1 frag part this is all going to
be good because we are doing this
fresh so actually X frag part we can
[Music]
reuse so frag is the hash part okay
so right so let's just remove that and
uh rame
okay there there it is we got the
fragment part and
uh then X pt1 is like
[Music]
temporary yeah so this rename this to
okay and that's not a good
name something like that okay
so and let's rename the frag part to
Hash
po okay so let's
see so we got the
just make them one
line hash part file part hash part so
you need the query part okay so
let's remove that to
here okay so we got the query
part color them
so what is this file part so it's
already happened there so you don't need
this okay
then do we need this has query not
really
because because when you split them if
there's none it simply returns
empty okay so we don't need
uh has query okay so delet it has hash
deleted okay this becomes empty Le okay
since it's empty we can take it
out
okay
fantastic so we get the hash part so now
it's
becoming clean now is we started to
uh you know this
is okay so we can
see so we got the hash part we got the
query
part and uh and what is this file part
okay file Parts uh and what is input
Parts uh
confusing the input Parts oh that's all
okay so actually we can actually kind of
remove it so the input
parts thank
you so we stuck with this yeah this this
live stream but anyway that's what live
stream coding is
for uh you know we get into this complex
technical but that's real life coding so
so now
we so we split hash file part hash part
and then we split hash part query part
then okay then we don't need this what
is this file part we already set file
part there and uh yeah this is the
previous original code we don't need
it okay so that's right remove and this
line also
remove okay double check okay search for
file part okay file part there there
there
there there
there file part is kind of temporary
actually so file part you don't need
anymore and uh hash part such suchar
such hash pod you need okay hash
part such such such such such such such
okay so hash part also remove because
it's
here okay and what is
this so this is the file
path so once you do that then
you right then expand file name to to
get the full path of the file okay okay
then after that you
just you just uh attach back
the attach back the hash part and and
the query string part fantastic we
almost done
so here is where you attach them back
con CCT
string so what is this so if file exist
there can do this otherwise eror that's
right okay so if file exist you need to
get the file
title you know so you call this function
to open the file get the file
title and
uh what what is it
doing so if file exist you do
this okay so file exist that's
right oh you have to do is here right
here you con concact the hash part and
the query string part there it is
fantastic and let's let's clean this up
so you so it's easier to see you
see I think that's that's
it I think that's
it all these trouble so now let's make a
backup go to the directory compile it
yes no error you know one so we buy
compile we just we we just did uh bite
compile the emac this file there is a
advantage of buite compile first of all
it's faster but also whenever you do
bite compile there's unused variables or
syntax eror or things like that emac
will tell you so bite compile is a very
good um thing to do to check if your
code is correct you know one of the
preliminary step so we buy compile that
everything is good there's no unused
variables there's no you know unknown
variables like typo so it's good and uh
let's color this so you see let's close
it reopen it let's recolor you know
let's recolor
this color color color
color okay so now you can see all the
variables where are they
used
so actually we can try to run it okay
now just run a code Eva buffer uh let's
go back to our previous problem this
line we want to make it into a link so
copy paste is let's see do
it fantastic can you see you see it
changed this line which is a you know
the URL form of a file path not just
file path but
form so this complexities then it's got
a query string then it becomes a link to
this local file you see this is a local
file link you know I can press enter to
open it showing browser you know this is
your Unicode search page
right so it makes it into a link and add
the title for the
link oh there's error so this this
string
shouldn't be part of the title okay
there's a mistake this query string
should be part of the should be
here yeah let's see if I can still open
it fantastic you see yeah okay let's fix
it fix the
code where is
it here okay so we
concact we add it to the wrong place
so this is the title part okay so
actually the query string should be
added
to
uh okay the quer string should be added
to where the relative
path file path to related path or URL
okay
so oh God this so you need to add a
concact
here you see okay let's
try concact that of that wait that
that okay something like that
you see we con we turn the file full
path into a either relative path or
URL okay then okay let's make this
easier to read then we add the query
string back if there's any because if
there's none it's empty
string okay let's just r at let's not
think too much because live stream okay
let's copy that paste do it again do it
fantastic Powers shell plus telephone
something like that so go to the page
return to enter okay now it doesn't wait
it does oh there's another bug to fix
anyway showing
browser uh wait so okay so this is a
link so actually
what you have to do is you what is this
page talk
show you make you make a link okay now
remove
that and uh remove that right we don't
need that so let's put a
paragraph cut that paragraph paste it
here showing
browser so if we click on that if it
works that means we did our job so
click it worked fantastic close it try
it again in case it's you
know
fantastic thank you guys for
watching the successful completion of
emac this
coding okay how many people are
watching two oh
God okay that's it um so we did this
after 90
minutes okay uh yeah
it's yeah we did this um and uh there
is oh there's other things to do but
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching if you like my stuff go to
a.info
s. info and uh then you can go all the
way down to patreon Amazon gift card or
PayPal thank you guys bye