test audio
finally lots of problems sorry about
that
so chrome chrome kept crashing now it's
too loud outside hold on a second
so we wasted like five minutes or 10
minutes chrome kept crashing so we are
using safari
and then there's no sound and now
finally it's working
uh so good morning guys good morning
george coney
skyro uh
so so we can begin so today we are going
to talk about
uh emacs live emac live coding it's
gonna be condensed
tutorial uh live coding of emacs this
and the background image i said it
before it's a typing of the dead okay
it's a video game
uh you can find this page if you just
search for xally
keyboard sorry typing of the dead you'll
find this page
okay so today's topic we are going to
start to code emac these okay so
uh what do i want to do so write a
command
so that two lines of file path one html
file path
and one image file path will become
linked with a
with an icon so let me show you what i
want to do okay
so you can see uh okay so wait let me
start
command log mod uh start
command log mod so you can see all my
emacs
commands and keys on the pink window
okay
so uh so we have two lines of code here
what i want is let me show you what i
want to do okay
so these two lines of code i want
linkify so it becomes a link here and
this
image also linkify this is the image tag
and uh move that here
and add a break and add the dive okay
so i want to write a command that
transform these two lines
uh file path into these so what is
what does it looks like in browser let
me show you okay show in browser
so you can see so before it was just two
lines
uh a file path but now it becomes
you know a iconized link so you can
click on that
then you go to the page uh of this link
you see i'm i'm i'm writing a lot of
blogs so that's why i want this kind of
um for example you you you go here you
see all these icons
they are done that way so back to here
so i want to turn two lines of file path
into a uh we don't hold on a second
um
copy that two lines of file path like
that
into into this okay so what
what what this looks like is is
basically so you have a link
html link starting here and ends here
and in between you have a image file
link so that's what we're gonna do
so let's define uh let's do this quickly
emaclis
okay let's open a new empty buffer and
define a function that's right
define a function so
uh let's let's call the command icon
linkify
okay given two
lines of file path under
cursor make them into a
link with image
okay so for example
let's see so version
today's date let's put today's date as a
version name so for example to file path
for example
this
becomes becomes like that
okay now in this is the emac these uh
docs docs string so you can see so these
double quotes you need to escape them so
i have a command
called xsa escape quotes
okay you call that it will add a
backslash
in front of these uh
quotes okay so that's a command
documentation so let's begin to write
it uh so first of all let's go back
to let's open a new buffer go to the
talk show
uh open today's talk show so so what
we're gonna do
is we are given a lines like that
we want to okay so
i have to think so first of all we want
to make this a link
so the first line should be the file
path
of a html file the second line should be
a
image file path okay
so let's uh
okay let's do this quickly because
there's a lot to code
now questions and comments per se okay
you're good now mike
microphone working okay good so
so let's go back to the code so let's
begin code okay so first of all i want
let's let's copy the code here
the file path so uh assume the cursor is
on the first line file path
so first of all uh
file let's say html
path okay image path that's two
variables
we declare local variables so
the let's set html path
is going to be
thing at point okay thing at point
uh i think a point um
wait let's see bounce up thing at point
bounds of
thing at point so
that's gonna be oh wait
let's think a point again so this is
gonna be file name okay
so this line this line will return a
of two elements that's a beginning
position and end position okay
so let's say p1 p2 p3
p4 those are variables for positions
they they store an integer of the
cruiser position
so so and say let's say
boundary
let's say bounce one
boundary one boundary two okay
so set
um
set boundary one equals to that
file name so that will return the
beginning position and end position of
the
file name then
set position 1
to be the car of boundary one
so that's the beginning of the uh
the final path position p2 will be
uh qatar boundary one okay
so that parts gets you the beginning and
end positions
of the file path html file path we set
it to p1 and p2
now now now
now we have to now the now we can set
the
html path that will be just uh
substring no properties okay substring
no properties
and gives two positions p1 p2
so this part will grab the string
between those two positions
and set it to html path
so that we have done now um
now we can delete region
delete region position one position two
you know delete that file path
because now we already set it here
now the second thing to do is um the
sake
okay now we want to deal with the image
path
so
so we we got the first path uh first
the file path then we move cursor to the
right one character
so uh forward char forward chart one
basically move to the next line
uh let's say forward word okay forward
word one okay
then we do the same thing we basically
do the same thing for the image
file path so boundary
two bounds of thing at point file name
that's right
then position three uh
boundary two then position four
set it to boundary two cutter boundary
two then
the here will be the image
path okay then here will be
p3 p4 okay then delete the region
p3 p4 delete that image file path
okay so far so good shrink
predefined the code we don't need this
part
evaluate the code so we have icon
linkify we have that
you know let's run it so copy that paste
it here
uh then we put the cursor on the
first line so we we put the cursor
uh wait so we put cursor on the first
line here
anywhere in the line so call the command
icon icon linkify okay
call it it just deletes them
that is expected undo okay so so far so
good
we you know this is interactive coding
we have checked so far our code is
correct
so we don't have to you know so later on
when we have uh do more complex things
we know at least
so far this part is good
so far so good anyone uh everything is
good
let's let's double check my voice
[Laughter]
the idiocy of me my voice check my video
check
okay so
so we got the image path we got the file
path what do you want to do you want to
uh you want to linkify them
so we want to make the first line into a
link okay so
so basically we want to recreate this
part okay
we want to recreate this
part okay so back to the code
split the buffer open a new buffer paste
it here
so we have kind of a reference now
this this file path is too long so let's
shrink it
because just for sample code
we don't need all these complex looking
[Music]
things
okay so now it's much more clear uh
you see the structure is much more clear
this is what we want to insert
into the buffer okay so now we just
now it's pretty easy so we just insert
it okay so
insert why don't we copy the whole thing
here
so uh we just uh we
insert first of all insert the dive
then insert
[Music]
okay so
so to code this properly uh
actually is a bit more complex but
let's do the same simplified version
first okay so let's just do the
simplified version then we'll
improve it so so insert
then we now insert the uh
h r e f um
oops and
so so far so good so then the file path
then insert html
html path then
insert
the closing tag then is
okay so there's quite a lot to do
you see we are first of all we are
trying to insert
the link let me show you okay first of
all we are trying to
insert a link like that it looks simple
but actually there's quite a lot because
for example
where do you get that that
you know that that text description
where do you get that
well the way i get it is that this text
description actually came from the title
tag of
of the linked file so what you actually
have to do is you
open the file find the title tag
grab the title text you know then then
put that here so it's a bit complex
but for now let's just say dummy okay
let's say
title text actually let's just say the
file path
okay so so insert the file path as a
as the text description for the link
okay then then we insert
we insert the closing tag of course
now and and and and now we insert the
end dive tag now in between
in between here you need to insert the
image file path
so okay let's do that again okay
so insert
okay so insert that and also insert
you don't need to worry about that we
don't need to worry about that we do
that
with you see another issue is how do you
get the width and height
now that's also a bit involved but let's
do the simplified version
first okay uh let's insert
here the that
and actually
that okay
then one thing at a time okay so
then in between so here this part is the
image
link in between you need the image
file path so insert
uh image path
okay so that's essentially what uh the
code looks like
let's pretty fire it
um
okay and remember these image images
needs to be in between
let's cut it it needs to be in between
these um
[Music]
you know it needs to be inside the file
link
so actually somewhere here
[Music]
so you need to add a bracket
i mean not bracket add a new line
there
eval buffer okay let's try our code
let's uh let's do as we go
okay so back to the html page so put up
so these are the two lines file path and
image pass put the cursor on the first
line
call the command i icon linkify
do it fantastic it seems to work but
however
uh we are missing something we are
missing a quote here
because the color is not right so
undo back to our code we missing a
double quote here
indeed so backslash
quote that's right eval buffer
back to html call it again do it
fantastic you see fantastic
okay uh let's do it show in browser
you see here is our code okay let me let
me
let me redo this again so we let's re
remove
all the existing ones
okay show in browser
okay that's how it looks like now you
see the two lines are here
now we are going to call our command
icon link if i do it back to browser
refresh fantastic now it's
it's working now so there are
uh quite a few things to fix for example
the link text
that's too long we want we really just
want need the you know we need um we
need to open the file we need the title
we need the shorts
uh you know we don't want the full path
there
um so far so good
so
okay so i i we we need to do this
actually so there's another task
that will be more interesting um
okay so let me finish this so what do i
what do we want to do now first of all
this uh
break i want a line return there so
let's add a
line return okay line return eval buffer
okay and now the link text
this link text we need to fix we need
the title of the page
so let's go back to the code
how do you get the title of the page so
we need to get the grab the title of the
page
so let's say link text
declare a new variable link text okay
and we are going to set the link text
here
set link text okay
uh so what how do we do what what's what
should be the value of link text
so first of all we find file
find file will open the file actually um
firefighter will do it okay let's just
press on let's do this
so find file html
path html path
so that will open the file then
go to buffer minimum go to char
buffer point minimum
so that will go to the beginning of the
buffer then
search for word okay search for what
what do you want to search you
you want to search the title tag okay
uh okay bound no bound
no arrow uh let's remove that we don't
need search for
title
okay then then we need to set position
we want
we want that position to be marked so
let's add
more variables title plus one
title plus two okay
so here set title position 1
to be point the current location of the
cursor
okay then we need to search forward
this time we need the end brackets
you know we go to the end of the title
uh
tag okay and ignore
all the arguments then we search
backwards to
the less than
sign why because we want it
in between the title tags we want the
position to be in between the
title tags so we can grab them grab the
text in between
so said so okay so set
title position two okay now we are ready
to grab the text
what you do is you set set cue
link text
to be both a substring no properties
and given two positions so the position
positions will be title position
one and the two
okay prettify the code
uh and actually um
actually wait so we need a
you see we we are already trying to set
it so
so the rest of code here should be
return a value
so we actually we don't want we don't
want that part
we want this we want buffer substring no
properties
and this whole this whole block of code
needs to be inside
a program uh
grouping like that okay so
so set set link text
to whatever this code returns
okay buffer substrings no properties um
then you gonna close file okay cure
buffer
uh
okay like that you see because we
we open file here with that find file
then we did something something
something then we are done with that
file we just close it
and now now for the
link text
we will just say
title text uh
wait we will just say link text
right okay eval buffer
go back to our html
and undo so let's start a fetch
okay so these are two lines of file path
showing browser
so they don't look you know they don't
look nothing special
back to emacs put the cursor on the
first line
call our command go do it arrow
wrong number of arguments set q1 okay
uh real number argument set q1 okay so
let's look at the problem
uh back to uh so somewhere here we have
real number of arguments
uh what is the
wrong number of arguments sec q1
so somewhere set queue is incorrect here
you see secure set queue
title position two you need a
value you know that so that's a problem
eval buffer back to our code
uh so showing browser
nothing special back to emacs put the
cursor on the first file path code
command
do it fantastic showing browser
fantastic now you can see we got the
title there
okay but that's not all there are a few
more things to fix
because you see um let me show you
uh there are uh a couple of things we
need to fix
you see the file path here that's a full
path
uh that's that's a full path that's no
good because once you upload your
website to the you know to the web
server
you know the you don't have the full
path you know all you have is the root
of your directory you cannot access
you know outside of the root directory
so you want a
relative path instead
okay so actually we uh we end up doing a
lot of things
so let's declare more variables
relative html path okay
uh let's let's kind of prettify
all these so we need a relative html
path
and we need a relative
image path okay now by the way if you
are wondering why do i declare so many
variables
because i don't want to reuse them
because that's part of functional
programming
uh you know if you do functional
programming there are certain
advantages and one of the things you
want to avoid is to have a mutable
variable
so so to do functional programming one
of the things you do is that you
never change the value of a variable
you know once you have a variable it has
a value
it just always that value so when you
need a new
you know you just use new variables
instead of changing
values of the same variable okay so we
we need a relative html path and
relative image path
okay so how do we get that let's copy
that
let's set them okay so
first of all let's do relative html path
set relative html path there will be so
there's a function in emaclis
that takes a full path and returns a
relative path
okay so what is that function i don't
remember so
uh the easiest way is just to look at my
tutorial
so you search for xr emax tutorial
so you go to a practical emacs lisp
then you go to uh there's a section file
file and directory functions so
make directory make directory directory
files delete directory copy directory
file name sends extension file name
extension
file relative name there it is that's a
function you want
back to emacs back to our code
so file relative name there it is
that's our function so here you give the
full path
okay that's how you do it but actually
the file relative path takes two
arguments
one full path and one directory
so the relative path will be generated
with respect to the directory
for example we call describe function
and
magnify you can see
uh you know it says so it says so the
the okay so the second argument
directory is optional
so if you don't give the second second
argument it will be just relative to the
current
uh current directory i think yeah which
is the current file
so so in this case the current directory
so the
you know that will be let me show you
okay so we are backing our
um
uh wait where are we
okay so undo so show in browser so
you know this is you know the the talk
show page
so you see that's that's the two file
path
so when you call this command
the the current directory the value of
the current
directory is going to be uh this file
that is whatever directory this file is
in
when user calls the command so that
means you know
in our email this code here the
you know the directory path is already
correct we don't need to give it because
it you know it's related to that web
page
okay so here is the setting of the file
relative path and we need to do the same
thing for
image path okay
do exactly the same thing
okay now purify the code so so so that's
the relative path
so now
is instead of inserting the full path we
want to
insert the relative path that's right
and same thing for the image
part so instead of inserting the image
path
insert the relative image path okay eval
buffer
back to our html code put the cursor on
the first line
call the command do it fantastic
look that's a relative path and look at
this one that's also related path
and they are correct showing browser
you can see it works
okay so so we are almost done this but
there's
one more thing there are actually two
more things
now you can see in this image
um let's mag let's magnify okay let me
show you the
glory of the full buffer so you can see
here is the image
link now do you notice something odd now
if you're coding html then you know
uh the record
it's recommended that you have the old
tag
so okay hold on a second it's uh it's
so it's recommend you know here's the
file path
it's recommended you have these um
old
uh wait
here you know uh that gives a textual
description of what image that is
supposedly for the blind so we'll say
a surface book keyboard
you see you need to add that the old tag
and also typically you also want a width
and hate
why do you need that because when
browser reads the image tag
when it sees width and hate
it kind of speed up the rendering
because it has some idea of what what's
the size of your image
by the way you can you can show the
image in emacs you know just click on
that
i mean just press return uh well because
i'm using
html mod so anyway what we
need to do is add the oats and the width
and height height okay
height i don't know it's correct me
should be pronounced height
not hate oh thank you guys
alan is here scott and alan
and george oh fantastic
thank you guys for the money that makes
me happy
so now our problem you know we are we
basically done with the code but
now you know we want to do some touch up
we want the old
tag it's kind of annoying the old tag
and also we want the width and height
now the old tag
is a bit problematic because it involves
the decision of what what exactly you
want to put the old tag because
typically
for image you know it it requires
certain imagination
for this one you know a microsoft
keyboard it's easy
you can just say a keyboard but often
when you have a photo of your food
of your you know let's say a photo of
your cat
you could say that you know the
description could say my cat
or you could say cat or is it could say
george's cat
or you could say my home because maybe
the the the cat is
you know uh you know in your home you
know
showing your home so the description is
kind of
arbitrary and and you know it involves
some
uh thinking to to describe it and this
uh it's there may not necessarily be
necessarily have a there is no
mechanical way to do it
unless unless your image file name
is very descriptive
so that's that's about how to how do you
do the old tag
um you know we have to let's go back to
our code so
so we in order if we want to add a o tag
we have to
say somewhere here i mean the the main
problem will be
what you're gonna decide uh
you know what do you want to say so
typically what i do
let me show you what i do okay typically
then i'm going to read the questions
alan says hi and buddy toyo and moyo yes
toyo and moyo in e-max list
for the past 15 years and scott says
have a good
labor day weekend oh that oh labor day
is coming up i didn't know
and george says please enjoy some rich
man's food
thank you guys anything
are there any questions any other
questions
uh here there will be a
stream uh hi guys good morning good
morning scott
okay so let's back to the code so we
need to so
normally what i do is that you see once
you have an
image image file so let's copy the image
file you know
so here's the image file um
it's not mac that's not full screen okay
so
here's the image file so typically what
i do is you
you remove the directory name okay
remove the directory name so you just
have the image file name
then you remove you know all the
underscore and dash
okay so there's no underscore and dash
then you remove the
the extension the jpeg so what you get
is basically
you know kind of a transformed file name
can we do that shall we do that that
that's
that's a lot more coding ten minutes
five minutes to do that
okay so that part is the old part then
then there is also then there's the more
complex part of
image width and height how do you do
that
uh
blue color web dev levels unite did
chrome crash yes
chrome crashed again so that's we are
using safari
apple safari uh
why do you still use uh closing html
tags
so have you have you had any thoughts on
the experiments where emac lisp
gets compiled into native binary
uh instead of the elc byte compile code
yeah so
you know that's a new feature in in
in the coming version of emacs emacs 28
where
you can where the emac list code is
compiled
natively so that means it should be much
faster there's a branch
you know those of you the adventurers
can try that you know
especially on linux you can do that
uh you know but i so you you can do that
today
and i but i asked people i you know i
was in so there was a emacs
meetup online uh run by
uh you know if you search for
emacs meetup sf you know that
you know that's a that's hosted by emacs
meet of san francisco but it's an online
meetup
it's hosted by jeff it's because i was
so i was in that
conference for the past uh two times
so i asked people there you know there
are some emacs
uh heavy emacs users whether the native
emax version is much faster or not well
their response is
well yeah it's faster but it's fairly
noticeable
so you know that's that's the case
you know if you are going to sort 10 000
things in e-max yeah then you will
notice
a speed increase but for average
e-max you know using
the impression i get from him is that
you know it's pretty much the same so
so anyway so so back to the code um so
we're gonna do
back to the code i guess
how long have i been talking so let's
see let's check how long have i been
talking
uh 46 minutes oh god so
so i guess we finish this uh then you
know 15 minutes then that'll be it for
today but actually there's another
interesting thing i wanted to do
that is uh the interesting thing is that
i want to display uh hu
as a line i know how to do it now
because uh yesterday i
i learned a tip from jeff from the
emacs sf meetup online
so we can code that next step next time
okay
so right now let's go back to code the
alt alt tag
so let's add the old tag okay
so image tag then relative image file
path
then we want to add alt here okay
so alt equals to
let's insert a new thing
insert
alt equals to equal
double quote okay
then we're gonna insert again
uh
closing quote and space so
and in between is gonna be the old text
okay
alt text
image alt text
okay but where is our image or text we
don't have it yet let's
let's generate it okay so back to the
variables let's add a
image or text here
okay then we're gonna set it uh
somewhere here so link text
relative path so let's set it here
image or text so how you gonna do so
let's
let's do it set
image or text program
so what you're gonna do you're gonna get
the file name from
the image file name from the file full
path
okay so
so there's a function now back to our
emac this
tutorial there is a file let's say easy
so there are these file name directory
file name none directory
yeah that's the one we want file name
none directory
remove the directory name so um
file name none directory okay
file name none directory
uh file name in none directory so this
will be image path
okay so get get rid of the directory
part
and also get rid of the extension so
so we need a file name
file name sense extension okay
then so so what that returns is the
file name of the image file without the
extension
one more thing we need to do we need to
remove we need to
tran we need to change the underscore
and dash
to space but let's not worry about that
for now
okay prettify the code uh predefine the
code
uh prefix okay so that's
image all text so
okay so if our code eval the buffer back
to our file here
now you can see here are the two lines
shown in browser okay back to emacs
now delete delete that back to browser
refresh so we have the two lines here
now back to emacs the two lines here
so now we're gonna call the command put
the cursor there call the command
icon linkify please let it work
okay it works there's some problems okay
you i misplaced
i misplaced the insertion
you see because yeah so undo
let's fix it
so it's adding the old um
yeah so the oath doesn't belong here
wait
okay so actually i know what to do so
actually
so this part will be so
so after we insert the image relative
file path we need to
close
we need to close the quote for the file
path
then we need to add
the alt tag here then
then we add the end tag for the image
tag right yeah eval buffer let's just
do it call the command do it
looks like fantastic now we need a space
here okay
we need a space in before the old so
back to the code
we need a space before the oath if i
refer
back to here and do call it do it
fantastic now this looks like
what we want so here is the image
part and here is the alt
tag fantastic now back to browser
show it okay good
now one last thing now the width and
height
of the thing of the image tag
so far so good questions
so let's look at the questions um
you know it actually took an hour today
so
safari is more efficient uh no safari is
not more efficient
are you sure i'm not sure about that uh
well it may be more efficient but but
safari kind of sucks
less electricity excellent have a
thousand can help as well have us
have a house plant can help i'm now a
urban pe farmer okay
okay so
so back to our code so
so the last part is to add the width
and height the the core
uh issue is how do you find the width
and height of a image file
okay that is the main question but
before we do that
let i'm thinking
maybe we should push on with that or
simplify our code first because now our
code is kind of ugly
you know because you see all these
inserts they can be
you know you you can use a format that
makes them more elegant and easier to
read and easier to understand
okay so either we clean up the code or
we start to explain
explain how do you insert the width and
height
let's explain okay so so the problem now
is given a
image file path for example let's say
undo
so here is the image file path given
a image file path how do you
in e-max list find out the
width and height of the image dimension
okay i don't know of hand but i have
written a code to do that
you know like almost 10 years ago so
let's look at
let's look at our code okay so you just
go to
describe key space space
space edge then that is my shortcut
key to html mod you can see here
so we move cursor here enter then you go
to the source code
so here is the source code of html mod
and there is a code to to link a file
you know
most of the things we did today is
already written i've written them like
you know tens of times
um and so most of the code is already
here
i'm doing it again in live because
so that you know i can demonstrate you
know how it's done
uh so there's a code here that's image
linkify so if we search for
for example um these matching lines okay
let's say this matching line is less
than sign
img space then you can see
here is a here is all the code
i mean the lines containing that you
know so we have
we have quite a few lines that deal with
image image files
okay uh but let's say defund okay let's
list matching lines
let's list all different functions in
our file
so then search for image img
wait let's search for img
oh let's search for ima
g okay there it is html get image
dimensions
that returns the width and height okay
so go to there
go to there so here is our code is
is our code
so i guess i'm not going to actually
code um
you know uh this here because i
it's already written but instead i'm
just going to explain how do you do this
get how do you get the width and height
so what you do is um let's see
okay here here is a part okay so so the
you know there's a condition here
now in the condition the first one is
to check if it's a svg file
you know svg file is different from jpeg
or
or uh or png files svg is a text file
it's an x
xml file so if it's svg
image you can find out the width and
height
by actually opening the file and just
search for the word
width typically that will have results
i mean if it you know you like yeah you
just do that
but if if it's a binary file
if it's a you know a png file or
a jpeg file what you do here's what you
do
okay so you do so you set uh
yeah so here's the code i don't remember
exactly but
but basically there are some emacs
functions
uh functions in emaclis that lets you do
that
so let's see set q so x and y
is a width and height height
width and height pair so we
we we declare x y to be a local variable
then we're going to set them
here so so what what does the code do so
you first of all
you uh
[Music]
you call the image size okay so image
size is a function that returns
uh the cons pair that contains the width
and
height okay then the argument to image
size
is a create image
[Music]
yeah so you can use create image and
give it a file name
basically your file path and emax will
create
kind of recreate the image internally
then
once you have an image you feed that to
image size
then it will return a cons cell
containing the
width and height
okay so that's that's how you get the
width and height so actually we can
actually try it so let's you know let's
just gonna try it
so for example
okay so that's how simple it is so let's
go to let's go back to the talk show
okay
let's get a image file path for example
this one okay copy the file path
back to here paste the file path here so
you can see
uh let's maybe prettify
uh yeah it's kind of you know because my
file path is super long
okay so that that you know so
now we what we do is we call
control u eval last
sixth so you see that's a return value
28289 217 pixels that's how you get it
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching i think that's it for today
um
how long how long have i been talking
one hour and one minute just just the
right time to close
okay thanks thank you guys thank you
alan
uh uh george scott
[Music]
and if you like my emacs lisp tutorial
uh you know go go buy it okay emacs this
tutorial fantastic you know where is it
here
okay just search for emacs this tutorial
and uh keyboard fantastic stuff
and uh
bye guys