Hello guys. Good morning. Good evening.
Welcome to another episode episode of
C++ show.
We are going to code. We are going to
code programming languages design, okay?
Design of programming language functions
and we got I'm going to show code in
JavaScript in Python, in Emacs Lisp and
maybe also in Wolfram language, the most
advanced symbolic computer language.
Okay, my keyboard this is ultimate
hacking keyboard UHK80.
This is Nulia trackball n u l i a.
I have a review on my YouTube. You can
search for it. You'll find it and on my
website stop that. Okay, switch to my
screen. So can you see my Emacs screen?
Can can you see my
browser? Uh and
so you see let me show you a prelude
what we going to do today. So you see
this screenshots.
This is what I need to work on. So one
two
three
four
five six seven. Can you see? Eight
nine
13 or 12 of them. Okay, so I'm going to
talk about this interesting topic about
programming language
functions parameter design.
Okay.
When you call a function and you you
pass argument those are called arguments
in the call syntax, okay? But when you
define a function those are called
parameters, okay?
And in fact we have some kind of
argument today in with Steve and hot
dog.
Steve and hot dog about this design.
They they got some they got some points,
okay? Now this is our friend hot dog.
Okay, that's
that's he's a zoomer.
Something like that or late millennial.
And we have a
uh
computer scientist. Well, he's a
programmer Steve, okay? Actually both of
them are programmers. Hot dog is
professional programmer. Steve I I don't
know what he does.
But we have some debate about these uh
about programming language function um
parameter design. And the conversation
began because I was talking about
Let me show you because I was doing uh
my programming language research.
And I wanted to know
I asked Quack.
You know, AI is your friend. Ask AI
questions every day. You must. You
should. Okay, so I asked Quack about
about this question, okay? And this
question hold on a second, my wife is
back. So let me uh
tell my wife I'm doing a live stream. So
don't disturb.
Okay, so
but let me tell you about this, okay?
Record of combo with Quack any girl,
okay? That's another thing very
interesting. Any, okay? We you know, but
we I wanted to tell you about beautiful
Annie, okay? I wanted to tell you about
this question I asked Quack about which
is um okay, let's go.
Let's go see um
uh
Okay, so let's go up. So let's see
magnify discover vehicle motion cues.
That's very interesting on iPad. So uh
computer science programming language
design.
S- I started to think that named
parameters is a problem in functional
programming.
So in functional programming languages
your function should not support named
parameters, okay? Instead
you want to pass a key and value
collection a single optional last
parameter instead. So you should design
your function in your functional
programming language to accept a
optional parameter like the last one.
And the value of that parameter should
be a key value pairs or collection or
also known as map or
associative array or dictionary, you
know, basically key value pairs.
Basically like the the way Java does. I
mean JavaScript, okay? That's my notion
because I started to have this notion.
So I asked Quack several questions,
okay? Hold on a second. I think my wife
is back. Let me just tell her I'm doing
live stream.
I am back and if you are here say hi.
Let me tell you. Let me let's resume to
talk about this fascinating subject,
okay? So I started to ask Quack AI
about these very interesting things.
And so first question, does Haskell have
named parameters? And Quack says no,
okay? So there's a link to it. There's a
detail you can read about it.
Uh does Haskell have named parameters?
So this is a big page, you know.
And so that's one question. Then next
question, okay? So let me shrink this a
little bit.
Okay. Then next question, what are
alternative names for named parameters
in programming languages? Because
different languages they may call it
different things. So we got um
So it tells you like some of them call
it named arguments. Some of them say
keyword arguments. Uh
Yeah, basically that's about it, okay?
But the but basically named parameters
is kind of standard, okay? Now list the
languages and their named parameters
syntax, okay? So we got Python, Ruby,
PHP
version 8 or greater, C# version 4
greater, Swift, you know, like over the
time many languages changes evolved. So
there's a lot changes. I know in PHP I
know for sure. And of course in C#.
Anyway, so Python, Ruby, PHP, C#, Swift,
Kotlin, Scala, Ada, Common Lisp are
Fortran, PowerShell, Smalltalk,
Objective-C Objective-C and this more.
So this table shows their uh
how they call the named parameters, you
know, like some of them some some of
them call it um
keyword arguments, okay? And here and
also the syntax example of defining a
function of named parameters and the
syntax to call a function
having named parameters, okay? So Quack
is telling you how you know
AI supremely useful.
Then next question, list functional
programming languages. This is my
interest, okay? I want to know about
functional programming languages or math
programming languages of their named
parameters. So show me
functional programming languages their
named parameters how they design it.
And here we we we we was we we will see
some variations because um
Yeah, well, kind of.
Um anyway, so
functional programming languages or
math programming languages. I want I
included the math programming languages
in case that Quack may not list
you know
may not list like scientific programming
languages because they are kind of
different area. Because in what I call
industrial programming languages like C,
C++, Python idiots, JavaScript idiots
uh this type of people. And and also
include Scala and
um Go land
Rust, C#, you know, and Java, these
common industrial programming languages.
So, among them,
you know, among them, they they they
they might know about functional
programming like starting to become
popular in past 10 years such as
Haskell, F#, but
uh but few of them know about math
mathematics programming languages such
as Wolfram language and R uh and others,
okay? So, so I include oh almost every
time I when I post about um
about programming language when I ask
Wolfram, I also include a full link to
Wolfram, okay? Hold on a second.
Jesus, my wife is
She's talking with her friends.
Uh okay, do I do do
Do Do I have customers? How many people
are enjoying
my show?
Let's see. Uh where where is my uh
Google Chrome? Let's go there see.
Incredible, zero. Wait, am I alive?
No, let me make sure, okay?
Mhm,
what the [ __ ]
Uh okay, so let me just continue talking
about this very exciting uh topic people
will
uh see it.
That uh you know, I noticed. So, um so
hold on a second. So, let me uh
but make sure I'm like broadcasting and
everything. Video check, audio check,
yeah.
Okay.
Okay, so so you um so you ask Wolfram AI
or you can ask other AI about
programming languages, okay? So, design
of programming language design. So, you
got all these languages, very
interesting. And then
functional programming language is very
interesting. So, I
you know, wanted to know about this and
I wanted to know how
is it true that in functional
programming languages you you you you do
not want to have like the typical named
parameters?
And and and one of the great thing that
Wolfram summarized it is this, okay? It
un- con- cur- I agree with my opinion.
So, in mathematical scientific context,
such as the programming language R or
Mathematica Wolfram language or Julia,
named parameters are extremely common
because functions often have many
optional arguments, plot options, solver
tolerances
for example.
So, that is true. I know for sure in
Mathematica.
Lots of functions have lots of options,
especially plot options, you know, uh
you you want to whether show axis or not
or the scale scaling of the graph or
uh color of the background or do you
want to draw grids or do you want the
label of the axis, how you want to get
them labeled? Do you want the frame
around it or not? Do you want the title
of the graph? You know, lots of options
for plots and and also other functions
have a lot options even for list
processing functions, Wolfram language,
okay? Uh I showed you guys many times in
my videos. If you don't know, search for
it. So,
so in mathematical scientific context
programming languages uh
so apparently they do have a lot options
and they use named options. But
but in pure functional
theory programming languages such as
Haskell, Idris, and I also uh know
notice it's also true for OCaml and F#,
okay? Named parameters are rare
because they interfere with currying and
higher order function composition. Okay,
this is
fairly interesting fairly interesting
because
you see in functional programming
languages they so in this particular,
you know, like
pure functional programming languages,
you don't want named parameters because
because let me tell you guys why.
Because in a math because they are kind
of modeled after mathematical functions.
Like in a mathematical sense, math
mathematics, okay? So, you don't in
mathematical in in in a function in
mathematics, you don't have like named
options. Like what the [ __ ] is that? You
don't have that.
You You just have a functions with
one parameter so fixed number of
parameters. You never have like named
parameters, okay?
So,
and the function in mathematics, you can
have composition. Like for example,
lambda calculus, okay? You can compose
functions, you can nest functions, you
can function recur- uh you you function
composition and currying which means
like um
which
uh kind of like me- it means like
decompose functions, okay? You You might
say um
decompose a function of multiple
parameters into
a sequence of functions each one only
have one parameter.
Okay, so so basically you are given a
function with with let's say two
parameters. Let's say you want to plot a
surface. So, two parameters, X
coordinate and Y coordinate and the
function come out output a number that's
a
Z coordinate, the height of the
function. So, so this function is a
surface, you know. So, but it has two
parameters, XY. But you can rewrite the
function as a as a sequence of two
functions each one only have one
argument. That's So, this process is
called currying, okay? This process is
called
currying. Very idiotic name, extreme.
Because the name does not convey
anything. The currying means like it
came from uh
basically a mathematician's name, okay?
Usually those kind of names are the
worst because they don't show they don't
teach you anything.
It's like what the [ __ ] is currying,
okay? And confu- Of course, it is a peg
uh uh
a peg adds to confusion, okay?
So, uh what I want to So, anyway, so
this this line is important. In in pure
functional programming languages, you
usually don't have named parameters.
And if you want them, so
the best way is to have like
one of the parameter optional.
It can, you know, by default it can
become null or empty. So, that
that argument should be uh the value
should be a
a map or collection of key-value pairs
or also known as map or dictionary
or hash table. So, that effectively
function
as a named parameter, okay? This is the
best design.
Okay, that's that's that's that's the uh
at heart that's what I want to say. So,
I'm looking into, you know, I'm doing
kind of like research into So, what what
does other programming functional
programming language do?
And uh it's interesting because, you
know, nobody actually know what is the
best way, you know, but we learned it
gradually over the past uh let's say 50
years of programming language design and
evolution.
Okay.
So, that's my that's kind of my the the
the the the point I wanted to uh talk
about, okay? So,
I learned about this I'm still learning
a lot, you know, because that's not this
is the beginning of the research, okay?
So, I posted it to
uh
to Discord.
Then Then Steve saw it. Uh Steve saw it
and he started to say something about
Python and we started to have arguments
about
Steve showed me something about Python's
way.
Python is like incredible extremely
idiotic. I'm not I've not seen anyone
the
Guido van Rossum like
extremely idiotic almost like in every
way in any almost every aspect I looked
at Python, Python is the worst, okay?
A- amazing.
I'm I'm getting myself ahead of time
because you don't know what I'm talking
about. I'm talking about, you know, so
Steve and hot dog showed me
eventually he they showed me the Python
um
the Python like the Python's parameters
is
convoluted [ __ ] okay? Python's
parameters.
Python function when you when you define
function in Python, you could have like
the there is a positional arguments,
then you can have optional argument,
then you can have an asterisks by itself
without letter after it, okay? As one
parameter in in the parameter
definition. Then you can have a asterisk
with a letter after that. That's kind of
like the rest parameter so-called
understood by the industry as the rest
parameter. But then you can also have
like two asterisks and a letter after
that. That stand for like um
like unlimited uh
named argument, okay?
But so so the Python way
Let Let me Let me start to show you
Python, okay?
Python, okay? Python, the [ __ ]
extreme idiotic Python. [ __ ] Can I
cannot believe, you know, like every
time so
if you guys don't know, this is this is
my Python tutorial.
xahlee.info, okay?
xahlee.info.
You go there. http, no s.
Not secure. It's actually very secure.
But they they tell you they want to
scare you because they they think, you
know, every website going to ask you for
credit card.
So, they
My website does not ask you for credit
card. It doesn't ask you to you type
your credit card or type tell me your
secret. Where did you live? I don't, you
know, I don't do that. So, I don't need
to have https, but but this, you know,
the these the the deep state, the
Google, the Firefox, they they they
started to
make it so that so immediately all the
website become censored because they got
this warning security. This website is
not secure. So, the the first 20 years
of internet history, all these website
that does not have https, they got
censored.
They don't want people to see them. They
don't want to see the internet history,
you see? Because when you go to one of
these website, they people feel like,
"Oh, this is insecure. Oh, dangerous.
Maybe I shouldn't, you know, go there."
That's what they do, the Google, okay?
That's about this, you know, this https
issue. A lot of people ask me, huh?
So, anyway, xahlee.info is so you go to
my website so you can find uh you can
find my lots of tutorials on Emacs Emacs
Wolfram Language Unicode for programmers
Visual CSS JavaScript in depth.
Golang
PowerShell, SVG, Scalable Vector
Graphics, Python, Perl, Java, okay?
So, Python my Python tutorials is okay
or is it for beginners? Okay, some of my
tutorials is good for beginners, some of
them are more like in depth.
Good for beginners, but also very much
in depth. That's That's my JavaScript
and Emacs Lisp is pretty much
extremely good, okay? My Emacs Lisp
tutorial JavaScript tutorial very good.
My Wolfram Language is
tutorial is also very good.
And my Golang
tutorial for beginner very good. My
PowerShell for beginner very good, okay?
I would say this these, okay? The others
Python, Perl, my JavaScript tutorial and
my Linux tutorial tutorial are like
so-so. Okay, you can like I mean, today
there's like thousands of tutorials. You
can actually you can ask AI. Anyway, go
to Python tutorial, okay?
So, Python. So, I have I wrote a poem
about it like
like 20 years ago.
Okay, so Python, you go to the function
section. Function function keyword
arguments.
So,
so you see you you got the named you got
keyword parameters very complex, okay?
Then you got the double asterisk, okay?
Then you got, you know, double ask
double double asterisk
keyword rest parameters, okay? Then you
got um
then you got single parameter single
asterisk tuple parameters.
Uh then you got but but one thing I
missed here. So, so you you you you can
have single asterisk. One thing I missed
is that you could have a single
asterisks, but without any letter after
it. It signifies
that all the parameters after it must be
named. Anyway,
my point what I wanted to say
is that Python
the functional parameters design in the
Python language is like the what the
what the one of the worst.
Incredible. I have not seen worse than
it. Not not in Perl. Perl
is
Perl is
the most well-known as the as the most
sloppy. Like slob. Like today they say
AI slob.
Was it slob or slob?
What?
I forgot what's the you know, I always
like get confused.
AI slob
versus slob. Okay, slob is like drivel.
Slob is like [ __ ] okay? Slob versus
slob.
Very interesting. Let's see what AI
says, okay?
You see? Let me Let's go back to AI,
okay? So, Perl language is known as like
sloppy, okay?
Slob and slob both sloppy, you know,
Perl Perl the language design. But but
but as far as I In my opinion, okay,
where is the function section? Can Can
you go to the function section? Loop
iteration function, okay?
In my opinion, even Perl is is most like
sloppy design like
Do Do what I mean, you know, like the
ugly camel. Have you guys seen the ugly
camel? That's be by design their logo,
okay?
Uh you know, Perl Perl language, have
you guys seen the logo, okay? So, let me
show you, okay?
Uh
you know, Perl is a ugly
Wait, why don't I have the logo here?
So, let me
um
let me go to it, okay? Let me Let me
show Let me show you
the Perl language logo, okay?
Logo. Uh lambda logo tool logo logo
design. So, it's all about logos, okay?
Purpose of logo and principles of logo
design. Let's just go there and go to
logos of software industry, okay? We I
talked about this before um
like few few two weeks ago or so. Watch
my video. Search for it. Logo design,
okay? About all programming languages.
Why
what what is a you know, what's the
criteria for good logo design? Their
history their their logo history
logo logo history very interesting,
okay? Anyway, let's go back to Perl
logo. Perl logo is a ugly camel.
Ugly, but very fitting because they
wanted that way. They are like proud of
it. Like the Perl people like, "That's
what we are. What you going to do?" You
know, like that that's what the Perl
people are.
So, Perl programming language is known
to be like this sloppy like no design.
You know, to to most people, but they
are proud of it, you know, that like
that's our intention, okay?
Like
like they spoke they they go by Tim
Toady, you know, like
Tim Toady do what I mean. Do what I
mean, you know, there are more There is
more than one way to do it. There is
more than one way to do it. Tim Toady,
Perl.
You know, and dream. Do what I mean, you
know, that's the Perl slogan part of the
Perl slogan. They They They sling around
the it every day, you know, Perl people.
But Perl Perl programming language kind
of died, okay? So, do I have a section
on function say data structure
function? Let's go there. Yeah,
actually it's pretty simple. The The
Perl syntax, the way they are concept of
function
parameters is very simple. In fact, Perl
function you don't have to declare any
parameters. Everything is become the
building. Every When you call a
function, every argument you give it
automatically became
uh array. You can access by the dollar
sign underscore.
Dollar sign low line, okay? It So, every
argument
um
in the function call became became that
building variable. You can access array.
So, in a sense, Perl doesn't, you know,
Perl doesn't deal with this
named parameters or or or rest
parameters or, you know, how many
parameters or uh
you know, like totally skip it. It's
just by this way.
Python
JavaScript is actually kind of similar,
okay? JavaScript by happen by chance,
okay? But JavaScript is the worst, okay?
Okay, so JavaScript in depth my tutorial
xahlee.info. Let's So, let's go to it.
You got comments and questions, post it,
okay? So, JavaScript function, you can
go to function ways to create a
function. You got arrow function or you
can define it by the function keyword
with a keyword function, okay? So, and
but then you got the function argument
object, okay? So,
so when you define a function with a
keyword function,
okay? Remember, not in arrow function,
okay? If you do if you create a function
in with the arrow function key
syntax, okay? That's
that's good. But if you create a
function with the function keyword, then
your function will automatically have
this building object named arguments.
That's a object. That object contains
basically all the
arguments people pass to your function
when the function is called, okay?
Just like Perl. So, this in this
example, in this case is both they they
are very similar, okay?
So, but but as we know, the the this
design is very bad because this design
if you you can do that, you know, just
like Perl.
Like you don't deal you don't have to
declare like how many variables or what
it is does it mean? You like you just
skip the whole thing.
And in your function definition, you can
access, you know, whatever uh is is
actually passed the argument, right? But
but if you do this way, you lost the
ability to like um like compile time
time check.
You know, like this is becoming
important uh in functional programming
languages.
You lost the ability to type check. You
also lost lost the ability to specify
for humans to know exactly what does
your function accept, you know, what
kind of parameters,
you know.
By the way, Pearl, you you can define
function with parameters, but it's not
required. That's the thing. You see? So,
but if you So, if if you don't require
it, you do it this way, then
like all your functions, people, you
know, become can become sloppy. They
don't know what the function do uh
require the argument, what they are.
What what is the type of the argument or
how many argument is required? It's not
specified.
It still works, but it's, you know, so
so but you but so you lost the ability
to type check to, you know, do those
kind of thing.
So, in general, it's bad, okay?
It In general, after 20 years, we know
this is bad. We don't want that. Nobody
No programming language, you know, try
to do this in, you know,
like like like the Pearl. So,
JavaScript, however, inherited because
JavaScript was created in 1995. That's
when Pearl was at the, you know, big
star under the sun, okay? Pearl is the
biggest star, like the last, you know,
the scripting language, okay?
So, JavaScript borrowed from Pearl, like
it's got the argument object. Well, so,
what is this for? This is particularly
this is for when you had when you need
to create write a function that takes
multiple arguments, such as the plus
function,
like 1 + 1 or + 3 or + 4. You can, you
know, a function can have multiple like
endless arguments, like unspecified
number of arguments.
That's when this is very useful.
Okay, but
So, this is like like the the primitive
way, the most brainless way to implement
that
feature to allow a function to have like
unspecified number of parameters. This
is like the naive way to do it. Okay,
but if you are more refined, you know,
that's this is not a good way because
then, you know, you can you can't you
can't specify how many you know, you
can't
specify you you can't even specify, you
know, this function takes arbitrary
number of argument. You don't know.
It doesn't say.
So, the best the better way is to
actually define your function to
actually have a rest a rest so-called
rest parameter syntax. So,
when you when when your programming
language language have this rest
parameter, so-called rest parameter
syntax, then
it
it is a formal way to specify that your
function can take arbitrary number of
arguments, okay? So, at the compile
time,
the compiler can check for it, you know,
to see correctness, right? And So, So,
why do they call it rest parameter?
Because usually this parameter must be
at the end, like the rest of it.
That's why it's called rest parameter,
but you but actually what it really
means is that it allows it declares the
function to take unspecified unspecified
number of parameters, okay?
So, anyone watching,
uh So, let's let's check one more time,
okay?
Okay, so I got so busy talking. Uh Let
Let me Let me Let me hold hold on a
second. Let me take a break, okay? I got
so busy talking. So, very dense today.
Today is like very dense session. I
talked for how long?
Um
20 minutes.
Almost 30 minutes.
So, you see, the rest parameter, okay?
So, JavaScript started to have the rest
parameter syntax in 2015.
Basically, that's after um
after 20 years, JavaScript.
After 20 years, JavaScript fixed the
problem.
So, these days, so today,
it's recommended you don't use you you
don't use this argument object at all,
okay?
So, anyway, that's the story about the
rest parameter Java in JavaScript. And
we talked about Pearl, how JavaScript
borrowed this idea from Pearl.
Now, I don't know where what's the
origin of this like the whole thing uh
came from.
Uh it might
I think it came from shell, Bourne
shell, you know, like the Unix [ __ ]
Anyway, that's So, that's a programming
history. We can we can we can act
actually ask Google, you know, like the
history, like which programming language
first began the idea of
of a built-in variable that holds all
the arguments passed to the function,
okay? Actually, we can ask Google.
So, we need to ask another Google.
Okay, so let me let me just do do that,
okay?
Um
Which programming language began
the idea of
of a built-in variable holding all
arguments passed to a function, okay?
So, Google will do research for you.
Okay, the idea of a built-in variable or
object array-like structure
automatically holding all arguments
passed to a function, something you can
index like arguments zero, arguments
one,
or check the count with
arguments.length,
is mostly famous associated with
JavaScript. Oh, shut the [ __ ] up. I'm
asking you about the origin. I'm not
asking about the most popular, okay?
Earlier related concept, but not the
same. C
introduced variadic functions with a dot
dot dot ellipsis.
Okay, [ __ ] [ __ ] stupid C.
Uh but you access the arguments manually
using macros. Oh, God.
Okay, Lisp Lisp got the rest parameter,
okay? But that's not the same thing. I'm
talking about this like one blob
variable, okay?
Those are, you know, Lisp got the proper
proper design for Scheme Lisp especially
got the proper design for um
Wait.
Right. For the They They They got proper
design for the rest parameters, but
but um
but I'm talking about this built-in
variable arguments. So,
it didn't say. You see, silly.
Uh failed, okay? I consider this Google
answer kind of like failed.
I'm asking the origin, okay? I think it
came from shell, okay? But anyway,
that's
We can rephrase it and maybe you'll, you
know, ask it again, you'll you'll
answer. But anyway, the other question
we ask Google is about um
By the way, this is amazing. This is
Google Annie, okay? But it's not
because I got busy lots of other things
we need to talk about. So, let's not
talk about that.
Uh but so we wanted to Okay, so I wanted
to Yeah, slap slap versus slab.
Slap was
slap with P and slab with B
are two distinct English words that
sound so much similar, especially in
casual speech, but have very different
meanings, origins, and modern usage.
Slab, the person, primary meaning a
lazy, untidy, sloppy,
or slovenly person. Someone who doesn't
care about personal hygiene, neatness,
or manners. That's That's Pearl.
>> [laughter]
>> That's Pearl and the Unix [ __ ] heads.
Slab, okay? Then slop, the stuff
content, traditional meaning,
semi-liquid, messy waste food, okay? The
dominant modern internet online slang
meaning, especially 2024,
low effort, low quality, mass-produced
digital content. That's right. That's
also Pearl. The Pearl and Unix [ __ ]
heads.
The Pearl and Unix [ __ ] heads and the C.
They are slab and they are slab.
All right. Okay.
Oh, God.
Okay, don't hate too much. Um
Okay, so let's go back. So, so so so so
so so, we got six people. So, you guys
need to watch from the beginning, okay?
When I'm done, you guys going to, you
know, rewind, start from the beginning
because there's lots of good stuff in
the beginning. Okay.
I think now I'm in a break. Now, I need
to Should I like go through this Let's
see. One
two Let's see. Hold on a second, okay?
So, I got this
I got these 12 screenshots I need to
work on.
I'm wondering should I work
on them while I do the live stream and
chat
or should I, you know, stop, just do
this offline? So,
Okay, so basically, I need to like
reword my tutorial in some parts.
This is like editorial, you know, I
working on my tutorial.
Um So, next try So, you got to, you
know, so for example, in this this page,
I'm trying to I'm thinking about some
stylistic change, okay? So, let me show
you. Let me work on this page. Let me
show you, okay?
So, you go to JavaScript. so you go to
um
JavaScript in depth. So, let's go to
JavaScript in depth, okay? JavaScript
depth in depth in then you go to the
function section, define a function,
okay? So, you see this red kind of title
heading, they are H3. So, search for H3.
So, you see return statement, you see?
So, that's that's why it's red. So, this
you see this is H1.
This is H2 heading, smaller. But, for H3
heading, I make it red, so it's kind of
more distinct. So, so you can easily
tell, they stand out. Because if you
only go by their size, then it's hard to
tell when you have, you know, quite
quite a few. So, I made So, I made the
H3 headings red, so you can see.
So, but I'm thinking, you know, maybe
it's confusing. Maybe I should make it
change the style. So, let's do so, okay?
So, we go here, go here, search for H3,
there, color dark
dark red, okay? Now, instead of that,
let's put border top, okay? Border top
solid one gray, okay? Let's see
uh that, okay? So, for example, this
page is about arrow function.
Uh so, go down, go down, go down, go
down, go down. So, let's see, can we
scroll, scroll, okay? arrow function,
okay? Left-hand side, now refresh
refresh.
Okay, so we got
um
So, can we Now, if we don't dark red,
let's see, how does it look?
Uh kind of um
You see? So, right-hand side, you can
see
we added, you see? We added a like
a border, a line on top of it. So, let's
see, function parameters.
Uh Okay, then arguments object, there's
no H3 here, function rest parameters.
So, all these are about JavaScript
function parameters, which is the
subject we're talking about.
So, function parameter default values,
there's no H3 here, then functional
argument destructure, okay? This is
kind of uh complicated.
Okay, there's no H3 here, um
Yeah, so let's say function declaration
versus expression, this is very complex,
okay?
Uh okay, so but anyway, I think that's
it, okay? For today. Closure. Uh very
dramatic topic.
Function call, apply, bind.
Okay, I'm not finding any H3.
Let's uh let's do this, okay?
So, let's close that and and call
Xah count, Xah find count. What do you
want to count? You want to find H3.
And uh greater than, let's say greater
than three, okay? Do it. In JavaScript
directory, yes, okay.
.html
suffix, yes, okay? So, you got the all
these files, so
So, let's just select all, select all
and sort them, okay? Then, so this file
go open it, show in browser.
So, this file, CSS decoration,
underline, overline, line through, and
wavy, okay? That's about CSS, cascading
style sheet. Okay? So, in this page, you
got several H3, you see?
Okay, so
So, now I see, if you do it that way,
you got too many lines, it's also
confusing, so
I think we should have the that H
We should have that color, you see? Go
back, refresh. You see, now
can you kind of see? Uh you see, that's
why I made it kind of red, so it
distinguishes H3 from H2. Can you guys
see?
So, there's a decision I need to make.
Do I Should I make it like
you know, should I
make it color red, or should I
have this
over overline above, or should I not
have the over over the top? What do you
guys think?
Okay, I think maybe that's about it,
that's that's it today, okay? We we
talked a lot really about this topic
today.
Off topic, but have you talked about
dynamic versus static typing anywhere on
your website?
I would be curious on your thoughts. I'm
working on a statically typed Lisp.
Uh
I do not have much articles about that.
Okay, so but uh so, for example, let's
look um go to Xah programming
you know, Xah daily homepage and search
for uh
dynamic.
Yeah, I don't I don't have um oh, okay,
I I do have articles, some notes. Okay,
Steve Yegge, Stevie Steve Yegge, he's a
well-known programmer
during the 2000s, especially late 2000s,
because he worked for Amazon and Google.
And he talked and blogged a lot.
But, he basically stopped any activity
since I don't know, since um
He he kind of stopped any activity since
um
since since like 2015 or after 2010,
okay? So, Stevie Steve Yegge, okay? So,
in 2012, he
he talked about this issue at Stanford
University.
Uh he's uh
he's kind of a fan on dynamic language,
okay? So, in programming languages, you
have the deep deep big debate
uh of dynamic type dynamic
um
type versus uh static typing, okay?
Uh ac- ac- actually, technically, it's a
bit a bit more complex because um but
anyways, that I'm not going to go into
details, but basically, statically typed
language would be
would include C C++,
Java Go lang, C#.
Okay, that's that the most common
statically typed language. That means
every time you
you you create a variable, you need to
say like int, long, double, you know,
you you need to say what type it is, or
string.
Okay? So, that's statically typed
language. Most common are C, C++, Java
uh
C# and Go language.
Okay? Hold on a second, let me Well,
this There's more to that, okay? A
statically typed language. Now, on the
other hand
you got the dynamically typed language.
Popular examples are shells, basically
all shells, PowerShell, Bash, Bourne
shell, Z shell, TC shell, you know,
shell. Shell,
um Pearl
Python, Ruby Lisp. Lisp is also
dynamically typed. So, Lisp is one of
the very old, it's 1960s, okay?
Okay? So
all shells, Pearl, Python, Ruby,
JavaScript
Lisp, Emacs Lisp, Common Lisp, Scheme
Lisp.
Clojure Lisp, they are all dynamic
typed programming language, meaning that
when you declare a variable, you don't
have to say, "Oh, by the way, this this
this variable X is meant to be string
only, or it only holds a number. It must
hold an integer, but not like float, not
decimal, or it must be decimal only. And
how many like bits you're going to
have?" Okay, you don't have to say that.
So, [snorts] in a sense, dynamic typed
language is like more natural.
But, the the static type, you know, let
me tell you, so this is get getting
interesting, because the statically
typed language, why do they do that? Why
do they, you know, have like
like why do I have to like I just want a
variable, X equals to three.
Like a mathematician you know, I want
for convenience, let X be three
from now on, okay? Then, I'm going to do
X plus Y or whatever. Right?
Why do I have to the [ __ ] do I have to
say, "Oh, by the way, the X I'm going to
use is going to be for numbers, okay?"
You have to tell the computer first,
okay? I'm not going to use it for string
to to store other things. I'm going to
just use it for numbers, so
you know, you you know, I'll let you
know. The computer can [ __ ] find it
out.
But
but the static typing language, you have
to do that first. Why? Because that's
the primitive, that's a that's a that's
the idiotic primitive way, because
that's the most easy way to implement
it, okay? Because computers, they deal
with bits and bytes and memory. They
don't know what the [ __ ] is integer or
string or number or letter, okay? They
don't they don't have they don't know
that. So, when you implement, you have
to say, "Okay, this memory address is
like you know, these bits." They they
are all bits, you know, they are all
just one and zero. Then you have a
special
um
part of the one and zero saying that,
"Okay, this one and zero is meant to be
a integer."
And another part of one and zero
sequence is meant to be, you know,
a letter like ABC something. So So
every, you know, it's all this one and
zero. Some part, you know, like you have
to
the computer must know, you know, is it
what what exactly it's meant, right? So
the easiest way to implement a
programming language is to
to to force to force this this
declaration of what type it is to to the
human, okay? So you don't have to worry
about figuring figuring it out.
So as a compiler writer or programming
language designer, you you you you can
go brainless.
Let the coder worry about it, okay? When
you say X equals to three, when you need
to use a variable you have to say,
you know, X. By the way, I'm going to
use X for for for for as a integer only.
You know, you have to tell the computer,
okay? So this is the easy way out, you
know, this C [ __ ] heads.
Okay, that's a statically typed
language. Now there's a twist. There's a
major twist, okay?
So after this went down for like 30, 40
years, then you started to have
functional programming languages.
Now like for example, Haskell.
Haskell, okay? Haskell is the most
popular, but but there is um
but it's not but the but the the the the
OCaml, Caml, ML, MetaLanguage came way
before Haskell, okay? 10 years prior.
Haskell is like since 1980 something,
but the
F#
Caml before that.
Okay, F# OCaml before that, then Caml,
then ML
ML ML MetaLanguage stand for. It It It
began in 1970s, okay? Something like
that.
But what what is this ML MetaLanguage
for? It's for mathematics proof systems,
okay? Proof.
So So when you So they they started to
have these functional languages.
By the way, functional language is is
also
statically typed just like the brainless
C idiots, C and C++ [ __ ] heads.
Why is that? But there's a big
difference, major, okay? There's a
tremendous fascinating difference.
On the surface, both of them, like when
you use a variable, you have to tell the
computer, "Oh, by the way, I'm going to
use this variable as a integer or
whatever first." Otherwise, you can't,
you know, you can't you have to tell it.
But in the C in the case of C, C++,
Java,
they that they they do it because they
came from brainlessness, okay? They they
don't want to worry about it. So you
have to as a programmer, you have to
tell the computer. You have to like do
these things manually.
Okay? But the in the case of the
the F#, the OCaml, the Haskell origin,
you know, origin is the MetaLanguage ML,
okay?
That's not the reason they have these
types, okay? The ML language The reason
they have the types, you know, you have
to declare type, that's because came
from mathematical type theory.
Okay? Because via these types, we can
we can uh prove lots of things, okay? We
We can do mathematical proofs.
From set theory, then you have type
theory, okay?
So
although on the surface, both, you know,
both Haskell
and C, they both require they they are
so-called, you know, type you know,
strongly typed languages, but they but
the the the the fundamental they are,
you know, they are origin is entirely
different, okay?
But also plus with the functional
languages, they have like automated type
inference, okay? That's another thing.
Okay, I think I think I
talked enough. Is it enough?
So So
So back to the um question about
So So So I I I kind of give my view
about
about the
uh dynamically typed language versus
strongly typed languages and how in in
strongly typed languages there's a major
difference between the C, C++, Java camp
versus the functional programming camp,
okay? They are entirely different
origin, okay?
So
but
I don't have much
actual opinion about this because but I
can tell you my experience. Like when I
was younger, I thought
I thought um Any anyway,
you know, I thought you don't you don't
you you you you know, I can tell you,
you know,
the the static typing of the C, C++,
Java, that's the worst, okay? You should
never do that. These stupid
utterly idiotic
harmful languages, okay?
But
today you you you want the you know, the
the the types the statically typed
languages in functional programming,
that's
critically important. That's
critically important, okay?
So but if you ask me between that, for
example, Haskell and F# versus let's say
Lisp
or a version of, you know, let's say a
version of, you know, F# or whatever
that that's dynamically typed. The
Julia. Julia is a good example. Julia is
a modern
super efficient and faster, even faster
than F#, faster than Haskell, okay?
Julia.
Okay, you you you guys know Julia?
Julia, okay?
Okay, I think I rambled a lot. I got to
I got to go. Julia programming language,
okay? It's a pure
Well, not pure, but it's a very advanced
functional programming language and new
starting in 2012, okay? Julia, it's
faster than F#, OCaml, faster than
Haskell, okay? And it's heavily today
it's heavily used in machine learning
and scientific programming, okay? Julia.
Now Julia is Surprise, it's not typed,
okay? It's dynamically typed like Lisp,
okay? Like Lisp.
But But But Haskell and OCaml
and F#, they are like statically typed,
strong strong typed. So So it's very
interesting even though all all you
know, all these are
very advanced functional programming
languages.
They differ in their philosophy about
type. So I do not know which one is
better. So that's what I'm trying to
say. I do not know which one is better,
okay? But I do know
the static typing of the C, C++, Java,
those are [ __ ] idiots, okay? The [ __ ]
the C and C++ idiots.
That's what I know, okay? So back to the
my article. So anyways, C C V egg, you
know, he he he he did a talk. He's a fan
of dynamic languages, okay? And uh so
So you go there. And then then there is
a paper. This is a computer science
paper publication by Stefan Hanenberg in
um
What year is this? Um
So it's talking about dynamic versus
static type system in programming
languages from a um
I think
um
I forgot what this article is mostly
about. It's written in 2010 11, okay?
2011.
Um Oh, static versus dynamic type
system, an empirical study about the
relationship between type casts and
development time, okay?
So yeah, I I don't think um anyway,
there's you got this article. I don't
think I
I think it's like on my to read or like
to read a second time or something. I
forgot what it's really about.
So anyway, so
the bottom line is that I don't have,
you know, I don't have much articles
written about it, but
other than what I
uh said about the
you know, the typed in functional
programming.
Uh let's see. Lexical versus dynamic
scope makes no difference in functional
programming, okay? That's another
article.
Okay, I think that's it. Thank you guys
for watching. If you like my stuff, pay
me, okay? Go to csadi.info, okay? Let's
see
see some comments. I do have it as
optional static typing right now. So you
are doing a
um
You are doing a statically typed Lisp,
okay?
Uh I do have it as optional static
typing.
Optional static typing. Now full static
typing does seem annoying.
I think best of both worlds in that I
enjoyed so far, but it's interesting
debate. So do you solve Advent of Code?
What are you talking about? I've got,
you know, I got several videos about
Advent of Code. Did you ever checked or
was it Is it Are you trolling?
Uh
Like you go to YouTube, I have Advent of
Code, you know, last month uh several of
them.
My syntax like this and completely
optional only provide benefits
performance in the repo server hence
when you use it
like this define add two um
Okay, so um
I don't know. I Well, I don't know.
I I
I mean they
um yeah, thank you.
So, I I think on on there quite a few
people who tried to do a list static
type typed list. I know there's a typed
closure. I know you know
I don't know what's the status like 10
years ago it's like is someone you know,
people are doing it.
Uh
but I don't know. Did they
like did they shut down or what what's
going on?
You see so
So, you know, you got this typed closure
project. I know it's somewhat going at
least 10 years ago.
Um
But I think
anyway, I think I I think there's other
project that does this with types.
Anyway, good luck. So, I think that's
it.
Hi guys, we shut down in 1 minute. Okay,
shut down in 1 minute.
That's a big talk that's um
Yeah, so today I talked fast about this
function parameters, okay?
Um
And I recommend if you are interested if
today's talk show is interesting, you
should check out check out
um
check out this one.
Episode 760.
Intro to classical piano music and
lambda calculus math foundation set
theory category theory homotopy type
theory. That one
will interest you, okay? So, that's one
of the best one. And um let me recommend
another one, okay? Another one it would
is about um
programming language design for
programming language strings, okay? So,
you will uh you can find that one by
going to C++ talk show best best of
C++ talk show best of
uh then just search for string.
There.
Episode 702.
The C printf and new prime and you and
new syntax for string rock string, okay?
Episode 702. So, that's the best one.
That's about
the design of strings in programming
languages, okay? I believe that's like
my 10 years 20 years experience, okay?
So, if you like today's talk show, watch
that one and and the other one.
Good night. Good night. Bye.
Shut down.
Okay, shut down.
And also by the way, my website I told
you guys yesterday my website
have haven't been updated since for a
week because I'm having I run into
issues of using RSync.
So, right now my website is like 1 week
old. I cannot update it. So, you won't
see like today yesterday, you know, talk
show.
So, I need to fix that. It'll be fixed
soon, but
Anyway, bye.