good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sun talk show
and today we are going to talk about
keyboards keyboard layouts in javascript
and uh and svg scalable
vector graphics hi guys so we're gonna
talk about keyboard layouts and
javascript
and svg so today is 2020 september 20th
uh sunday eight o'clock in the afternoon
san francisco time good morning guys
george uh emmanuel torre
clawfoot james knee hi
hi uh processor bot
so keyboards layout okay so i'm gonna
show you so let's show you the talk
show page now let's check my status
audio check video check
do i look good i look beautiful okay
so uh there are some updates about
keyboards on my website so
you just search for exotic keyboards and
let me show you stuff like keys okay
starfly keys is one of the thing
uh okay so let me show you actually
let's just do search
software keys so you just type that in
browser
and there you have it
stuff like keys fantastic magnify
magnify
so this is a key binding system in emacs
is the
uh very efficient keybinding system and
i have some update let's
i'll just go directly to tell you about
the update okay so magnify
so you can see i updated i updated the
interactive javascript uh
keyboard diagram keyboard layout diagram
so you are looking at the volatile
keyboard layout
the command key you know the commands
layout so you can switch to quality by
clicking the button
or you can switch to comac or comac dh
which uh you know so comac this is comac
dh
comac comac d dh it changes about six
six keys uh then you have walkman so
comed comac dh and wokeman are new
additions
so now notice now the in soft like keys
when you are in quote
for example if you are in quality the
ijkl
keys are the arrow keys so you can see
it says here
but if you click on vorack it will also
update
you know the keys for the commands so in
work it's
chtn so
so so i updated the javascript i'm going
to show you javascript okay
in this video uh how do i do that in
fact i'm going to live code javascript
uh but the other thing i want to show
you
is hold on a second before we
uh go away from stuff like keys so so
here is my kinesis keyboard layout
as i have shown many times again
you can change the keyboard layout
quality work
comac comac dh and workman
okay so this is my layout i use for my
kinesis
advantage to keyboard you are seeing it
right there
and let me show you actually uh as a
ritual
i need to show this every time
uh good morning crawford good looking
okay so
yeah uh so let me show you the video
okay hold on a second
see if this works
no the video does not work that's okay
but
i'm just going to show you
let's pull this out
so you are looking at my keyboard
so almost every video i show you my
keyboard so this is the
kinesis advantage to keyboard you can
see
kinesic kinesis advantage too then this
is the
uh this is the ultimate hacking keyboard
two parts
i'm using it as my um
as my
thing it was my uh keyboard macro
keypad so put the video back
okay so let's see
okay that's good so so that's my
keyboard okay and uh
then then what are we talking about so
yeah so
so that's my physical keyboard kinesis
advantage too
and this is the layout i use for soft
like keys and
it's fantastic okay so close that
close that and today i'm going to show
you
uh so i have another page which is saudi
keyboard page let's go to it
this is the main thing we're gonna talk
about
so let's close that comments and
questions type it okay
i love kinesis advantage too uh yeah me
too that
that turns out the you know i've i have
uh
i have a few uh ergonomic keyboards
so you go to my keyboard website just
search for my name
sorry keyboards and you can see here are
some of the great
greatest ergonomic keyboards i recommend
so among them i have i have
ultimate hacking keyboard i have exposed
which is right there i've done a video
uh
i think before yes and kinesis and also
truly ergonomic so i had a few
and it turns out that so the kinesis
advantage too
is the most comfortable of them all
uh okay so so what i'm going to show you
so
today let me let's talk about keyboard
layouts okay
so keyboard layouts you know the it's
one of the things
nerds are obsessed by you know because
over the past
let's say 20 years there are so many uh
keyboard layouts
so there is the quality layout again you
can switch the layout so
corti comac
comac dh workman uh
asset okay then norman layout
then capwell layout then this this
this uh this beast qfmlwy layout
each one has a history why they are
designed that way
and who designed it and year you know so
on this page i explained them
all but what's new is that i
created this uh you see this heat map
so this is you are looking at the
quality layout and the bigger the circle
means that key
when you type english okay english in
english
e is the is the most used key by far
you know well after space if you just
count the letters so e
then t you you know you can judge the
frequency of the letter by the
by by the size of the circle so this is
you know you call it heat
heat map so this is fantastic this is
written in javascript
and javascript and svg you see you see
it's not
a static image because you know i can
select
you know i can select it and copy paste
so it's
svg technology if you don't know svg
well if you don't know what is svgx
svg just search for that
and i have a tutorial okay so uh
well so this is part of it interactive
tutorial
so this is circle arc for example this
is all written in javascript you
here you adjust the center the x-axis
the y-axis
then you adjust the major and minor axis
so you now you got the ellipse you see
now you can now this part is you yes
major and minor axis
then you adjust the angles uh the angle
and sweep
okay then you can adjust this you know
how much of a sweep
then you can rotate the whole thing
you know svg it's interesting because
svg
is actually very quite difficult to draw
this
elliptical arc i mean not just
it's it's difficult to simply draw an
arc let's say you want quarter of an
arc of a circle that's very difficult
you see the code okay let's refresh this
page let me show you okay the code to do
it is actually
um well it doesn't let you refresh
hold on so here you have a
arc of a circle right so let's change
the sweep
let's say let's say you want half a
let's say you want a quarter of a circle
that's very that
so here is a code you see you have to
use this code
so anyway so i wrote a javascript to
make it easier
uh and some you know here's a javascript
code and here's some explanation and
this
turns out a lot of people need this
because if you need to draw a pie chart
which is very common uh you it's
it it's almost impossible to do you have
to create this
you know this uh mystery you know the
bunch of
mystical uh puzzling points
so anyway so so anyway i was telling you
about
java svg which is scalable uh
vector graphics so here is a tutorial
you can learn from scratch
and you can learn how to uh create a
clock you know analog clock in svg so
here's the code
like 150 50 lines of code you can
shorten it of course
then there is canvas versus versus
svg comparison you can see canvas is no
good okay george
you can see canvas can you cannot scale
that's why svg technology is called
scalable
vector graphics i despise the bitmap
canvas
[ __ ] that's the opengl that
you know opengl um yeah those kind of
[ __ ]
loved by nuts you know you know the
nerds always love that you know
ray tracing uh you know bitmap
image you know gaming you know they
always love that kind of thing
uh it's craft bad technology
so that's digression to svg well at
least you know what svg is
and that's my marketing for my svg
tutorial let me stop this
okay good morning reaper so ripper
says the more keyboard layouts i see the
more i became
an adherent of quality theory
[Laughter]
okay so so if you want to learn
svg check out my tutorial okay so of
course there's also javascript
tutorial so i have html css javascript
in depth okay
and okay so so that's a digression to
svg and javascript so let me show you
back to the keyboard layout so you have
quality you can see it's
quite lousy you know the e t you know
it's pretty lousy so then in comparison
to vorack you can see
let me uh let me shrink the image okay
so you can see them kind of side by side
you see so here is quality on top
right at the bottom you see all the most
frequently used keys are the home row on
the
home row so you have quality you have
hold on second
it's uh so you have quality you have uh
vorack
then you have programmer programmers for
rack which is
same as vorack except that they changed
the number row keys and uh
and for the keys and then you have
uh the very popular call mac
so if you want to know the details read
my page
okay um and you know so i i
i did this uh you know this svg image
and there's something interesting
because
before that i was using somebody else's
code
this heat map heat map you see
this is a this is an image file i
screenshot from
someone else's website and that website
is let me put a plug
to his website so this website is by
is done by this guy patrick something
okay
patrick weed or something so
you know this is his web
site and it shows a heat
map and
it is using the canvas
technology okay as you type it shows the
heat map
so i was using you know screenshot of
his website and it turns out you know
once i
show the you know once i did my own i
always wanted to do
it uh i find that
actually with circles it's actually
better because it's more precise because
because now i have we have so many
layouts we can you can compare them
and see how they differ when you have
heat maps
you kind of by the way these heat maps
are
using french language so here you have
corti
then you have the vorac there at the
bottom is the
comac and they are showing french you
know if you type french
so but once i used you know the circles
i find that
you can actually um compare the details
for example for example you look at this
uh
let me magnify okay you look at this
heat map koti
you know so so you can see r the letter
the letter r and the letter
o uh u okay you cannot
you cannot quite tell which one is more
frequent
you know but if you have it with circles
you can tell let's see where it's quotie
okay so let's go to quality
so u u is here
and i is here you can tell right away r
is
uh quite a quite a bit more frequently
used
than you yeah so circles you know
precision
circles gives you that advantage
by the way i'm using the circle radius
as the frequency
so you have kodi layout vorax then you
have comac
you know you compare them in detail so i
kind of so looking at these graphics i
kind of see
some differences for example let me give
you an example
for the first time i see that i see the
point about the norman layout okay so
the normal layout let me show you
here so around 2013
which is you know not long ago they
came up with this norman layout you know
he has a website you can go to
let me show you okay so a plug for his
website just
you know he's got the website he
explained uh
normal layout you know why it's better
why it's better than
asset better than comac better than
welcome and better than borag
in his opinion uh you know but i read it
i don't get it you know like usually if
you read other
uh designs of uh keyboard layout there
you'll see a few points okay this is why
they think
their layout is better but when i read
the normal layout
to this day like you you go read his
page i don't quite get what's your point
like
i mean i've seen you know we have seen
many other layout and he also mentions
it but
what what is it about norman that stands
out you know what's your
it's like fuzzy you know you can't you
cannot you cannot tell but now
you know once i you know by happenstance
i look at you know i was redoing this
page
and read them in detail then i realized
no money is actually
why is it good i well in my opinion okay
it's
the you know the the the design goal or
the point about normal inside you also
focus
so you focus on the home row but not the
one in the middle okay
you know your four fingers not the you
know you don't have to
move your in the index fingers to the
middle that's why you see
very small circles gy in the middle on
the other hand you see
this is acid you can you can see there's
a big edge
not on the home key you see here is the
home key
home key circle you know you have the
black squares
that's a home key so you have things in
the middle and also
on the core mac on the coil mac
it's highly criticized you know this
edge
you know you have to move your index
finger a lot because h
is one of them t h e v or he
or she you know that's involves h
that this that he she uh
what where here
actually one of the letter that's
in most of the most frequently used
words
in english i have a page somewhere that
that tells you what
what are the top 10 let's say top 10 the
most frequently used
words in english and they all almost all
of them
involves edge so when you have edge not
in the home key that's a problem you you
have this
lateral movement problem so
that's why comet dh comet dh layout is
invented to fix
this lateral movement problem
and workman is also for that reason
augment is invented
to fix that lateral move out movement uh
problem so anyway so i look at norman
and you see they don't have that problem
and also they focus on the
you know the two strong fingers index
finger and pointing
middle finger and pointing finger on the
top row
you can see by this circle uh graphics
so that that's you know
so anyway so that's what i did and okay
so how long have i been talking and
questions and comments
put it there okay and uh
and put it there and i'm going to
explain i'm going let's i'm going to do
a live javascript coding
okay so anyway so i did i'm i'm so happy
i did this javascript i'm going to show
you the code okay so
so let's go to actually let's let's have
a look at the code okay
let's go to so this is a page the page
you
are looking at is this web page okay
let's go to the top so you can
so show in browser of course and then
then the javascript code let me magnify
okay
magnify magnify and let me oh
so here's the javascript so you can see
layout heat map
so go there enter to open it
magnify magnify so you can so this is my
javascript code
and we are going to do a live one today
i'm going to explain why
so let me before we do that open a new
buffer
and call the commands cassah start
command log mod
so that in this pink window you can see
all my keystrokes and commands i call in
emacs
this is for you emacs users okay back to
the keyboard page
now what are we going to do we are going
to um
we are going to do one live okay so
what was i saying so let me read the
comments and answer some questions
so george george says george says
uh i have disavowed canvas fantastic did
you see my
svg version yes i did so george
george is also a hold on a second let me
hide my
height hide it
okay so i'm going to show the canvas
hold on a second okay i'm going to show
my screen
i mean i'm showing the um my discord
okay let me turn the screen back uh
it's first with technology first first
first okay screen is back
oh actually you [ __ ] see all my
screens anyway that's a screen
capture the problem with the you see the
problem is that
every time i start discord it will show
all my friends
you know that should be private but
anyway that's
that's okay so let's
so this is sadly discord if you haven't
already join in so because we have so
many different people from
over the world we have you know people
in china
in hong kong in uk in um
in of course canada in usa
and uh in germany and uh
quite a lot and and people in uh yeah
so anyway so george also georgie is a
javascript coder and ruby code primarily
i think
ruby anyway joe george so george did
george inspired me to use the circles
actually
so george showed his uh code
he's got a canvas version and also a svg
version
and he just wrote it from scratch you
know so
let's let's let's let's demo his code
okay so so here is his uh
code
let's wait for the js video to show
it's bouncing bouncing what the [ __ ]
okay is it gonna come up so meanwhile
hide that let's go back to
uh youtube studio commons
reaper thank you thank you for the super
chat
so reaper says why did you say
previously that you liked php more than
javascript
php versus javascript okay that's a
topic we can talk about
let me answer that then okay since since
reaper paid
the ticket for the question okay
php okay between php and javascript both
of them
okay the js video is not showing up the
[ __ ] stupid
[ __ ] george did you delete your script
anyway uh
so so you know php the language
programming language php and
javascript are both cons the most
hated language in the history of
computer languages
yeah they they are
mostly in the year 2000s okay for 10
years they are the most
hated language by the edit hackers
by for example by by those kind of
people who loves
who loves uh you know who talks about
unix philosophy
who loves eunuchs who loves you know
uh scheme these people uh haskell people
you know everyone is badmouthing php and
javascript
why let me let me tell you why okay
because php
the original name for php is personal
pretty home page okay pretty home page
that's a history of php but if you go to
wikipedia they don't talk about that
they hide it
it becomes hypertext [ __ ] processing
[ __ ]
okay it's pretty home page created by a
teenager originally
it was a script written in perl so you
know because back then post perl is the
most popular okay
okay george well it's not showing so uh
well i'm we're gonna stop demonstrating
your code
let's close it yeah okay so php homepage
you know it
has humble background it's just uh some
kid
uh 19 years old 18 you know created his
pretty home page using pearl
then it becomes uh very popular it
becomes the most
popular language around let's say 2005
yeah i mean
for for like 10 years the most popular
language on earth
php one of the most you know top three
let's say depending on how you count
what so why does it become the most
popular i can tell you why because
php the language is the most humble
without the [ __ ] unix philosophy [ __ ]
[ __ ] these
computer language notes the haskar
monads you know
you talk to haskell people the munas
munets math you know
you talk to list people at least markers
so you tell recursion or [ __ ] [ __ ] them
they they think they you know they think
they are elite that's what they are
the php is the most hung you know you or
for example you talk to python your java
people their class
jump object oriented programming
yo you have to use class you know
factory class
patterns for the [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] it's
academic mumbo jumbo
php had has none of that it this is was
it was created by a teenager
just for his pretty home page personal
page then he
you know uh and so so it has no
jargons you know it has no jargons it
doesn't tries to tell you what you
should do
like the python people pearl people that
you know pearl is kind of the
slacker you know sloppy people from the
unix philosophy
uh community they are like jargons you
know
uh you know uh you know uh
more than one way to do it uh you know
the lazy laziness is the greatest
virtual programmers of the the [ __ ]
crap
the unix that's pro
but anyway php has none of that no no
pretension
no jargons some teenager just wanted to
create his web
website and then um
exactly php now has class exactly let me
go let me explain the cover to
the history okay before for reaper's
worth of the money's
worth my opinion anyway that's just my
personal opinion
of my and my view of the history so
p has no pretensions but it why is it
popular because it because
first of all it has no pretension okay
and
it it's most the most practical language
on earth
which programming language is the most
practical
period that is php okay most practical
whenever you don't have you have a
question you go to their website they
some
somebody will explain how to do it
unlike
for example the list [ __ ] the unix
[ __ ] the python [ __ ]
they are trying to tell you what to do
oh did you try to use
monac no you should you you you should
use
mona you should use tell recursion you
should you should use marco as a [ __ ]
[ __ ] lisp you know this kind of thing
people
you have a question in php people tell
you oh you just use
you know do this way solve the problem
no pretension no
not trying to sell you anything and
the php documentation is the best
documentation ever well actually one of
okay
there are a few others you know i have 1
000 articles about that
i'm not going to show them but you just
search
you for i'm not going to show them i
don't i i have a tutorial basic tutorial
on php okay anyway let's go back
so php why is it
you know because why is the why does it
become popular because it's the most
practical it's the most down to earth
it has no pretensions not from academia
no pretensions just
you know just a bunch of functions and
it doesn't have you know
it doesn't have you know complicated
uh programming language which construct
for example like what like like like um
like tell recursion the [ __ ] tell
recursion tell their ass
the skin people they skim these people
like these markers
like symbols from these people you know
the the fight
like monat from haskell or currying you
know from you know currying from
uh haskell people pattern matching you
know none of that crap
well and not even oop [ __ ]
you know class class uh you know static
static class
the [ __ ] child what's what's the
jargon
and let me show you an article okay
jargons now this is about opo he's got
also tons of jargons oops jargons and
complexities
now this is one of my best articles go
read that okay
this is the essay so in op you have
classes methods
objects you know [ __ ] [ __ ]
then you have uh let me tell you let me
let me just go over the jargon
static class versus static variable
versus instance variables the [ __ ] op
go [ __ ] yourself then you have the
constructors
and accessors go [ __ ] yourself that's
java the mostly
you know it goes to a better way php has
them
too now then the you have access
specifiers
you know then you know then then you
have the
inheritance then you you know you have
the black box and all that inheritance
then you have um
inheritance then you have the class
hierarchy
[ __ ] their ass then you have the
the interface concept
especially java it's [ __ ] mutated
it's not interface at all
it's like one [ __ ] up [ __ ] that's the
old piece
the the the height of op um
uh era is around let's say 2000 to let's
say around
2000 basically java okay from 1995 to
2005 that's the that's when op is over
the place
then you know people were talking about
object oriented data databases
everything
will be anyway so you have then then you
have abstract class and abstract methods
then you have iterators the [ __ ] the
iteration
and you have emulated in enumerators
anyway
so then they of course you who cannot
forget
the jargon of polymorphism
[Music]
the [ __ ] them the [ __ ] the ob
[ __ ] the idiots
they they they are idiots okay they are
crackpots uh
you know they are uh i can because i you
know some people might say oh
oh maybe because oh these dragons oh my
god i need to
learn them i need to understand them
because they are so advanced computer
science no
they are not they are crap they are [ __ ]
they are crackpots okay that's what they
are
because i know i know the stuff okay i
know mathematics these people they don't
know
so they are the snake oils so anyway oh
he doesn't even have that
you know they all this class and
abstract class
php has none of that when you code in
php you just call functions okay
you know i mean not like the you know
like haskell's functions pure functions
no
side effect you know you just call a
function okay give parameters that's the
most
basic fundamental concept of programming
language
okay functions parameters and you
come out it does something or you you
may call it subroutine
so php is all all just that you do you
you have 500 or something
just functions you need to do something
just call these functions
and variables of course that's the
nature of
php the most basic no-nonsense
practical down-to-earth uh no
pretensions
programming language okay and it's for
the web and also because web is going
and growing you know
starting in year 2k that's when php was
wrong
that's why php become became the most
popular programming language in history
in
you know uh depending on how you count
let's say the top three or top five
the most used programming language even
though
you know the even though all these elite
[ __ ] the these people
you know the the the skin these people
the scream these
the haskell people the functional people
the java
c plus plus people the oop people in
python
they all despise php they will say it's
a [ __ ] [ __ ]
possible they'll say it every day every
day but
that doesn't stop the growth you know
the real popularity of php
php become the most popular language
okay that's a history of php
okay so reaper i'm going to cover
javascript in a minute okay and you know
and also
uh php becomes once you become so
popular you have uh
evolutions you cut you have newer
compilers every
every few years so eventually they try
to fix things and they have newer
compilers and newer compilers it's
faster and faster
then facebook created hack language
which is php
then you have you have real class and
it's done well okay
the class system it's basically php has
a class system around around 2009 or
something
uh and it's the best class system there
is
okay it seems it's like a java it's
modeled after java's class system it's
pretty clean
if you are into uh you know oop
so anyway that's php okay that's the
story of php
very good now let's talk about java uh i
mean javascript
and and let me tell you so why is php
better than java okay
yeah php in my opinion is a better
language than java
i mean not java javascript okay now
javascript is also one of the most
hated language javascript was created in
php is created in year 2000. i kind of
finished this i gotta go back to the
keyboards okay the
but anyway javascript it's it's it's
it's it's a language created and
you know designed and implemented in one
week in 10 days okay by by this brenda
guy
so it's pretty lousy and it's bad you
know because
so so why is javascript bad because
it's designed and implemented in 10 days
10 days only you have to think of a
language and yeah and
and create a compiler in 10 days and it
becomes a product part of the netscape
browser
they need to you know ship it
that's part of the reason it's it's a
pretty bad
uh very bad language okay pretty bad
of all languages is one of the worst
language even today
even counting javascript 2015 okay it's
one of the worst language
because what you so what what are the
reasons it's a designed and
implemented intended that's one thing
uh let me let me cover okay there are
quite a few reasons okay
and also javascript
was designed based on scheme lisp okay
scheme list
is a great language okay the brenda guy
is this
uh phonetic i mean he's at least fat he
wanted to create a language just like
skim
this okay but however in the industry
he worked for netscape you know netscape
they have to be
you know some microsystems meanwhile
invented java in 1995 and he
they put billions of dollars in
marketing so java is well known is you
know everyone is talking about java
so so netscape wants to uh hop
onto the bandwagon you know you know get
a ride you know from the name of java
so they changed the name from originally
it's called
oak you know javascript is called oak
script
or something like that you can look up
you know wikipedia
but because of java because of the
marketing because you know
so they changed the name to java also
they changed the javascript syntax to
java
you know because it's what it was lisp
this
itself based based on two languages list
you know skim this
itself anyway they change the syntax to
java
they change the name to javascript even
though it has nothing
no similarity to java whatsoever it's
like javascript
and java is like that in entirely
different language you know it doesn't
share the same model doesn't share not
no [ __ ] a thing but but they ho they
have to for
for marketing reasons they they call it
javascript
and and also they have to they have to
because oop member op was
you know all over the place because of
java
microsoft systems is selling java you
know selling the
selling the concept orp by by a huge
amount of
money dumped to market marketing
so javascript als you know trying to
write you know
write the java bandwag wagon you know
the fash
fad so they also try you know they
change the syntax
um i mean the semantics you know they
try to emulate java
in some way you know so so the language
becomes pretty uh lousy it becomes kind
of a monster
at heart it's kind of self you know
based on the language called self
there's a language called self i don't
know much about it
where the prototype object
system came from self okay the language
itself
and it's based on the scheme this
functional programming language
that's the heart of javascript that's
what
brenda when brenda ike you know the guy
who created javascript
that's what he really want he want you
know skim this
and the self you know uh op features
but because of marketing pressure he it
has to look like java
okay javascript has to look feel like
java so
they add you know so it becomes one
[ __ ] up one [ __ ] [ __ ] up
[ __ ] monster it becomes a monstrosity it
doesn't look like anything
that's the origin of java that is why
every
every programmer who love languages
despite
javascript okay so but
you know okay there's a long history of
javascript okay but after
you know 15 years it also became it also
became the most used language
okay so so so why do i think so php
compared to javascript
why do what which one do i think is
better
i think php is better okay because
javascript um
no uh mike malek kennedy says
uh javascript is based on dialect of
small talk
not skin you know i don't think so uh
well we can argue about the details
anyway you go to wikipedia there's uh
history okay
and also brenda ike he has a he he's a
he was a blogger he has
his own account of history of javascript
you just go to his
website brenda ike i've read you know
some of them
[Music]
okay so so between php and javascript
know both okay i coded a giant uh
project
in php in year 2005
for a harvard hoover institution
you know part of stanford hoover
institution is kind of a
think tank uh associated with stanford
university i happen to
do a contract work for them so i wrote a
website for them
entirely on my by myself in php and my
sql so i know php but i haven't coded
php since since about 2006.
on javascript i started to learn in 2013
okay then i dived very deep
uh javascript is extremely complex okay
it's a [ __ ]
it's a [ __ ] complex monster
so both languages become the most used
language
and both languages has progress and
progress
but php in my opinion is better is is
it's kind of it's better because
javascript has lots of
watts and the syntax that you cannot
change
i can go into details okay but i should
do it another day
[Music]
javascript yeah so why does javascript
sucks
that's a big topic i can talk about one
hour i should do another
i should do it another day okay is my
answer satisfactory reaper
so how long have i been talking i i i
want i
you know i mean we've been talking for
long and i was
thinking uh uh what to do now should we
go back to
the um that where am i should we go back
to the keyboard layouts
so i've been talking for 43 minutes uh
let's go back to keyboard layouts i
guess
so ripper are you still here
so is my answer satisfactory you have to
you have to answer okay because
because you paid me to answer a question
okay let's go back to okay check out
this article okay this is
um well if you like my stuff that's one
of my
uh good articles go to talk show
go back to talk show today's talk show
and paste it so this
is the topic we talked about showing
browser
and you can see it's there so i want to
yeah let's
wrap up let's do 10 more minutes i want
to
give you a demo of javascript
so okay so let's do that and and if you
guys have any questions comments
post it okay well let's do ten more
minutes we should be done
uh so so let me tell you what i'm going
to do
so on this page keyboard layouts we have
diversity
of layouts and uh
so you go down so you have voice you go
down go down go
all the way down down down and you can
see
there is this mini mac layout now
i don't have uh svg for that for that
layout so i'm going to do it right now
okay so i'm going to create you know
just just like they
like these of you know svg javascript
for the mini mac layout so let's magnify
let's see what what is this
so mini mac is a layout it actually has
several versions
let me let me explain mini mac okay so
it has like three or four versions the
first version is the easiest it
only changes four keys from quality
layout so it changes four of the worst
keys
in quality you know these four keys d
t k e it only change four keys so it's
supposedly
it's the easiest to learn and
you know and it it fixed the worst key
so it's you know it will be
drastically better once you learn this
then once you once you are used to this
layout
you can advance to the next version of
mini mac
which changes four more keys so a total
of eight keys change
okay so it's progressive
so once you adapt that one you can
switch to the next version which which
changes 12 keys okay that's the that's
the idea of mini mac
in my opinion yeah nah you know so you
can see
here's a four keys change version a keys
change version
then 12 keys change version it's cd in
my opinion
silly because these nerds they are all
obsessed about
keyboard layouts they and they you know
typically these notes the
pro programmer computer programmer nerds
they
they are not thinkers they don't think
okay they they are just
following the trend like whoever
whatever people are saying or slack
you know on slack on hacker news on
slashdot on reddit
they just read consume you know they are
consumers
they read what they say oh there's a new
layout
i need to be uh deleting a edge oh i
need to create my own layout
they don't they don't think why is that
because
because when you look at keyboard layout
there's much more than they are for
example i said this many times
keyboard shortcut layout almost nobody
you'll see
except no one except me okay
nobody have ever you you will not it's
very hard to find it
you will not find someone dive in depth
into the shortcut layout and how
important you know i talked about this
many times on my website you can see
uh so many page pages about key binding
layout many articles okay 20 articles
about key binding layout
what what does that mean keep any you
know like copy cust control
copy cut paste you know control c
control
uh p is for paste control v is for paste
p is for print you know open shortcuts
if you use
emacs if you use vim if you use
photoshop if you are a video editor you
know
whatever adobe premiere whatever you
know a lot of people use that
today the most your
keystrokes is mostly used on keyboard
shortcuts
you know especially for those people
photoshop you know
or emacs even programmers because i've
done stuff
i've done statistics
you you check out my website you'll find
it or just search for xr
saudi emacs command statistics you'll
find that
even for programmers most of your
keystroke is spent on
keyboard shortcuts not typing okay
so you realize the keyboard shortcuts is
actually more important the [ __ ]
keyboard layout
okay the keyboard shortcut layout
is more important than the
the you know the
you know quality overact you know the
key letter layouts
but you don't see anyone you know you
don't see programmers study the keyboard
layout at all just me
then but but but however when it comes
to uh keyboard
you know later they are they you you
have one million people
telling you which one is better quality
a comac
come at the edge no man oh we need to
create another new one because i don't
like
the [ __ ] idiots these are none
you know typical typical programmers
they are not thinkers
but they but the problem is they think
they know
like they're gonna tell you you should
use imax default keys because this is
what
they they they think they know they
think they know this much
you know they think they know this much
but actually
they know this much no more people know
this much
they don't need no people know this much
but they they didn't think they know
that much they they just
you know they are the programmers okay
these uh idiots uh what do i think of
media wiki so media wiki is one of the
most popular website of course written
in php
wikipedia what do i think of it i guess
it's good i don't know
i haven't used it uh
so actually uh we rented a lot okay so
let's can we actually still do mini mac
and let's let's start coding okay let's
do this quickly
so i want to create a svg version of the
mini mac
so first of all let me just do it okay
so
first of all i do it quickly
uh so let's see first of all let's see
what keys are changed okay
so create a new buffer let's show okay
uh
well i need to show this create a new
buffer
magnify so quality
quality e uh quality e is changed to d
magnify qrt d
is changed to t okay
then quantity um
quantity wait according what
quantity is changed to t then quality
uh what is that key quantity t is
changed
to k uh oops
then quality
l is changed to e
is that right
uh let's see
okay so uh i need to do this quickly
well anyway let's let's just just go
with this okay so
copy that close it let's go to the um
let's go to the heat map page and close
that so
here is my javascript uh so we are going
to create a new layout here
so paste that here first so
so paste that and delete that
so this is gonna be qwpr
wait what's the name of the mini mac
okay
so mini mac layout
mini mac okay and create a new map
so here will be
[Music]
we need a array of pairs okay so
so what i'm going to do is uh
okay space replaced by
double quote comma double quote okay
okay then we're gonna do this command
okay
let's show you can see the command on
the pink window let's do this
okay wait that's not we want ah let's
just do it manually
okay so
that's what we want we added a new key
map
mini mac then go down
all we have to do is to
uh
we need to okay so we go back to the
browser
go to the top you can see the bottom you
you can see all those
um buttons here we're gonna add
a mini mac okay
close that uh button
so here is the part here is where you
see the buttons
here okay so we are going to add a mini
mac
button mini mac okay
and there it is mini mac
so back to browser refresh
you can see there's a mini mac click on
that doesn't do anything because we
haven't
done the code yet so back to the
javascript
code open it
so open it magnify go down
go down a bit and
all we have to do is mod is add mini mac
here so let's do it
mini mac okay that should do
so let's let's see okay
refresh now click on mini mac
wait let's click on kodi first
oops doesn't work that must be syntax
error somewhere here
did we add
oh yeah so i forgot
you need you see i'm missing
i'm missing the double quote
yeah okay so back to browser
refresh click on quality now you see
quality now i'm going to click on mini
mac you should see
uh you should see four letter changes
do it yay i think that's it so
d t e so anyway let's
here's what we're gonna do we're gonna
do a screenshot
actually let's not
so is that is that uh we need to look at
the picture of mini mac okay
so
so wait wait okay so here here's what we
do refresh
click on mini mac and uh
click right click inspect elements
and you can see the
svg element here okay
then you can right click
copy copy outer html
okay shrink this window back to emacs
close this page search for mini
mac now we are back to the uh
mini mac layout section and all we have
to do
is just paste here so you see
this whole thing this whole thing is the
svg
so you can i don't know if you can see
so you can see we pasted a whole bunch
of
svg code here okay
now we go back to browser magnify
we go back to where minimax was
there it is mini mac layout okay we're
gonna refresh
then you'll see the svg refresh it there
it is
now we just check if it's correct q
w d r k q w d r k correct
y u i o p y o iop s
t f g s t f g correct
h j e l h
j
k e l wait
h j k e
what what okay there's arrow
uh
oh okay so wait
yeah i made a mistake so this key
quality k should become e so i made a
mistake so let's do this again
delete the svg
go back to the heat map page
so quality k should be e that's right
i was wondering that's right so this is
the correct
um so back to the browser
go to uh magnify go to all the way to
the top
refresh click on quality
click on the mini mac and now
copy the outer html
back to emax
paste the svg here
back to browser magnify
go down to mini mag okay now we're gonna
refresh you'll see
it there refresh there it is
h j e l h j e l correct
so we so it's done so i think that's it
for today uh any comments
comments comments
julian says uh what do you think of
media wiki good man today i agree with
them all
good night good night
oh yeah i forgot to go so i think that's
it for today so
thank you guys for watching if you like
my stuff
buy my stuff okay you can go to my
keyboard website
and look at the fantastic number of
keyboards and you can buy them
for my amazon links or you can go to my
javascript
in-depth tutorial or svg tutorial
or e-max this tutorial oh you can just
pay me
paypal or patreon
okay thank you guys for watching that's
it for today i'm gonna close
in one minute
okay now yeah we we shut down in one
minute now it's cl uh it's clean up time
like usually when i do this live i have
to do things
quickly because people don't want to
stare at me at you know just looking at
the screen thinking
so now we kind of uh clean up the code
save it okay that's the javascript code
let me show you the whole okay you can
see so
here is the whole code basically yeah
that's too small so only
so you know it's 120
lines of code okay close the javascript
and here here is back to my uh
keyboard page so did we actually do mini
mac
yes we did so let's switch to let's try
different combination of change mini mac
qfm cap well
so you know mini mac and okay now let's
go down
let's go down oh so we've we haven't
done the heat map we need to add the
heat map
to mini mac layout so let's do that okay
back to the javascript code
heat map okay so
so we need to go to mini mac section
okay so uh i forgot to change these this
is so
so here is the you see here is the
minimax section
and uh you see here's a minimax section
and i've i need to give a id to the svg
so this will be mini mac layout
and give a random id so here is the
id string for the svg
tag element so now go to the top
go to the javascript heat map page again
and the heat map code is here
you can see actually it's it's the
bottom
okay so all you have to do is
copy that let me magnify okay so you can
see better
so copy that paste it here
copy that paste it here so that's i
think that's it
we add a new element there and
yep that's it so go back to the browser
now if i refresh you should see the heat
map for minimax
do it yay so you can see
by by only changing four keys
it fixed the quality um
layout pretty good you know it actually
did
a great job only four key change
mini mac okay yeah so i guess now i
guess i see the point
actually it does very well very i mean i
mean yeah
pretty very well just for key change
thank you for watching bye guys
you