good morning my friends good morning my
friends welcome to another episode of
saw talk show and today I'm going to
talk about Unicode so I'm waiting for
people to come in and basically I have
these topics in mind so I'm going to do
I'm going to show you how to input
Unicode Windows Mac and Emacs but first
of all let's look at some beautiful in
Unicode seriously emoji very interesting
emoji the history of emoji and so on hi
guys so the history of emoji and stuff
and hands you have food you have love
stuff you have clothing you have animals
you have lots of things then you have
symbol kind of thing such as stars stars
and you see they have many asterisks
asterisks all these are asterisks and
they also have snowflakes actually let
me switch to Safari so that I have the
JavaScript down so first of all let's
look at some Unicode beautiful Unicode
you have faces this is my website by the
way you just search for sorry Tod info
Unicode okay wait sorry Unicode okay
just search for that and there it is so
you have astrology very interesting
and you know you know Unicode is amazing
because every symbol for example the
earth symbol you there's a history to it
you know like some of them are truly
ancient for example these signs I'm not
sure how old are these signs female and
male symbols in earth anyway you know
some of them are Asian and some of them
has rich history for example this thing
is called Imperial orb globulus
globulars Kreuziger
something like that so anyway so these
are unicode and there is so on the top
you have emojis and then you have stars
stars and asterism asterisks you see
these are stars then you have asterisks
asterisk by the way it just means star
the etymology of asterisk is just star
and then you have snowflakes such as
this in in that then you have flow rate
it's quite interesting you see I'm not
sure when is flow rate used you know
usually in general Unicode when there's
a Unicode character especially in the
other days early days like you know
1990s or 2000s usually if there's a
character in Unicode that means in some
book somewhere you know they they used
that character unlike today you know
today since the emoji about starting
about you know five years ago the emoji
became crazy and it's senseless it's you
know a bunch of garbage doesn't make
sense at all but anyway there is a
history of emoji I might talk about if
you want to ask questions by the way if
you have a questions just type it okay
because when you type it our answer it
oh and and also you'll come
will direct me to where I'm going if I'm
you know if I'm getting bought you know
you know if my talk is getting boring
just say it you know that type of topic
something like that
so anyway I'm gonna cover I'm gonna talk
about Unicode today and so first of all
I'm showing you some of the very
interesting unicode's for example there
is math Oh math the how I love you so
but you've been quite difficult math
symbols you know each of these has
history and you know depends on how far
you want to go because because for
example if you look at this page
these are math symbols and you can spend
years literally years just studying
these things because first of all
there's okay what the symbols are used
now many of some of these symbols or
many many of the symbols involves
advanced math so you can't really know
you know you can't really understand
what what the symbol is useful unless
you actually understand that particular
particular subject the particular branch
or field of math that symbol is useful
so imagine give you you know going to do
that and if you are not a mathematician
that basically means like four years of
study and and and that's just knowing
what the symbol means and but besides
that there's a history of math notations
history of the symbol used now that's
almost entirely a different topic
because then you have to research the
history of math notations and math
symbols you know that is another several
years because there's a specialized
field for math history and that can go
quite deep
well so anyway math symbols so that's
that's unicode then there's APL stuff
now APL if you don't know apo is a
programming language it's a math
oriented programming language and they
are a lot fans you know people are fans
of the API API language they differ from
other languages by two primary
characteristics one the most dramatic
and spectacular is that the APL
programming language they use all these
symbols they don't they don't use like
normal English words for function names
every function basically they use
operators and every operator is you know
just these symbols so you actually need
special keyboard at and special fonts to
input that API our language is pretty
old
I think it's 1970s I think they are
still people using it today but not in
the mainstream industry though oh hi
Michael my code is Simoni just something
did - Alice it right I can never
pronounce people's people's names may be
asked about any topic or related well
related to Unicode for today let's say
anything I talked about or anything
related to Unicode so I'm gonna talk
about some you know so today I'm going
to talk about basically these are the
topics I'm gonna show you so I'm gonna
talk about how to input Unicode Windows
Mac or Emacs and how to about font you
know you you can display some of the
characters unless you have a fount now
I'm going to give you a introduction to
Unicode for programmers now this part is
slightly technical so you know let's
cover that after we show the other
things then some Python script module or
JavaScript or other languages I'm going
to show you some tutorials about how do
you deal with Unicode okay then
something
loading conversion tools in Linux or the
premiere programming languages and Emacs
to okay it's getting technical okay so
this part is not technicals show some
Chinese Japanese Arabic Devanagari
scripts I'm not sure I pronounce that
right that's that's a script used in
India by use used for Hindi Hindi and
other languages and maybe talk about
writing systems you know one thing
interesting about writing systems and in
languages human languages is that the
writing system of a human language you
usually have nothing to do with the
language in fact they are about you know
mostly they are about maybe five or six
writing systems used for a for for the
thousands of languages for example the
Arabic script for example the Latin
Latin half a bit you know as you know
it's using English French Spanish
Portuguese and tons of others German
language language and so on
although they differ a little bit you
know adding an accent here and there but
essentially it's Latin alphabet on the
other hand Chinese for example Chinese
is used in Japanese as well and used to
be used in Korean and Vietnamese as well
so I'm gonna show that that's non
technical so maybe maybe we'll talk
about that first then show Egyptian yeah
some interesting languages and how they
look it's it's quite amazing so I'm
gonna look at comments every few minutes
so global single alphabet so how crazy
would it be to have a global single half
a bit well that's what Unicode is well
if you mean you know alphabet yeah well
actually almost I think Oh actually
right now almost other words languages
can be written in Latin I mean usually
they have a romanization system or you
know so-called romanization system or
some kind of phonetic system that
transcribed whatever language into Latin
and in fact you know Chinese the one for
Chinese is called pinging well there are
several others but ping is the most
popular basically it just transcribed
the Chinese by sound into English and in
fact daddy that is a that's how Chinese
in China learns learns how Chinese is
pronounced you know when we when they
are in school kindergarten in middle
school and you know and at one time like
during 1950s and 1960s there there is in
fact a movement to abolish the Chinese
characters let me show you some Chinese
characters there it is Chinese
characters it's incomprehensible if you
haven't studied you know I grew up in
Taiwan so I I understand them I can read
them and you know most most Chinese you
know you you can understand it
of course I mean you see newspapers in
everywhere but it takes you know it
takes a lot of money you know you learn
so basically you need 3,000 well on
average you know you need 3,000 you need
children 3,000 of these characters one
by one to to basically read newspapers
actually 3,000 is not enough but if you
know 3,000 characters you can you can
you know you can basically read
newspapers although you might not
understand some details so in general a
Chinese college college educated person
you need five five thousand characters
so Chinese so this is this is Chinese
and actually it's part of Japanese
because Japanese power Chinese
characters for their written language
even
even though Japanese and Chinese they
are completely different they don't
share a root I mean Japanese language
and Chinese language they don't they
don't share nothing basically as far as
the language you know the grandma and
everything goes of course they share a
bit many vocabulary because the
countries are close together you know
they borrowed each other but yeah so
that's about writing systems yeah you
know so it's interesting that even
though there are so many like 1000 oh
yeah 1000 let's let's just say 1000 okay
languages in the world and even though
many of them don't share nothing with
common in come with each other they
don't have the same route however many
completely different languages uses the
same writing system meaning the
characters the set of characters to to
write it so Chinese is example using in
Japanese and and used to be used in
Korea and Vietnam but another example is
array B array big so let's see here
way big I don't you know this is how
Arabic looks like I don't know nothing
about Arabic and Arabic so so this you
know they you know linguist linguist
East's they call this written systems
they called script so so that
yeah they in general the writing system
kind of the the set of writing system
they call script so this is a rate
Arabic script you call this Arabic
script
however from Arabic script you have
Arabic alphabet so a ribbit-ribbit
alphabet is the set of Arabic characters
from the Arabic script that is just for
the Arabic language but however the
Arabic script is also used for many
languages for Persian
Kurdish as something something something
something something you know and
apparently was once used for Spanish as
well and it's right to left
it's not left to right it's right to
left so let's see modern Korean Mandarin
you know is made my three assistants
yeah Esperanto is very interesting that
that's artificial language constructed
constructed language actually I we I
what I was talking about it yesterday in
yesterday's a livestream so anyway so
yeah so some of these are very
interesting for example this Cairo guys
I'm not sure how you pronounce that but
Egyptian higher grass Cairo guys you
know there is something interesting
about the each each each Cairo guys they
there are these characters look let me
show you page to tell these characters
and by the way Microsoft censored these
characters that is on Windows 10 they
are using Seiko UI historic font to show
the Egyptian characters but these three
characters these ticks ticks and Peters
in Cox they are censored that means it
just show a square it doesn't display
them but on a Mac it works so Egyptian
so you have Egyptians and you have
linear b which is also ancient now there
is a linear a and Linear B linear a is
never deciphered but linear b has been
deciphered then there's this one Kunie
form
that's a very interesting so let's go
back to let's go back to our Unicode
topic so let's talk about how to let's
talk about font because you need font I
mean yeah you need fun to display
Unicode
so let's reorder this a little bit so
Chinese show Egyptian so by the way this
is my Emacs show in browser okay so show
chinese japanese yeah this interesting
characters let's talk about that
Devanagari script so let's go here
actually it's nice just go to Safari
so this script is used for Hindi which
is language used in India but it is also
used many other languages like you know
like like tens of them but a bunch of
them looks interesting you know there's
a one characteristic of that is that it
has this horizontal line that just
connect them all and this is bangari
which is kind of similar but rounded
more rounded and then there is this
tamio which is different language from
the hindi completely different does not
share any root with it okay so this fun
yeah what is the best one - for Emacs
I'm gonna show you that I'm gonna cover
there thank you for the question so guys
keep the common question going good
because sometimes I get stubs stuck so
what do they mean what does the Egyptian
mean well I well I don't know if I don't
know but from what I read I'd read from
Wikipedia but basically Egyptians they
are they are a mixed bag of phonetics
ideograms and and some character
semantic meaning I think I just read it
from Wikipedia it's hard to understand
so yeah so you know I don't I don't know
what they mean with it
so but basically some characters has a
phonetic component that means for
example let's say this one this one
looks like a tie you know a tie under an
arc so
and so if it's a phonetic character it
it has a particular specific
pronounciation let's look at some other
let's say you know this person so if
it's phonetic that means its it has a
specific pronunciation if it's ideogram
that means you just look at the picture
it has a meaning by the picture but
there's another part usually in
languages that that is I'm not sure the
details actually so so it's a mixture so
when does a picture mean you know the
picture when does it is used just for
the purpose of pronunciation it's mixed
as far as I know as far as I read you
know so when you have you know Egyptian
text some some pictures you will take it
as a meaning but I think most of them
depending on the context as well so so
it's so it's complicated okay let me go
through the question okay so well so
many questions let me go through them
quickly see catch you
hey Scott nice to see you here Scott is
a old ancient Emacs users since 1970s I
think from the time Emacs began I guess
you would need a global single language
do you use new max champ mod I don't use
mod yes I'm using it for my Emacs
yeah but well I I could I could show you
but let's go on with Unicode today you
know because I might take a while
man on Korean okay the external okay
Egyptian do they mean
pull it in a story in the computer
actually numeric yeah okay let me go on
with the
yeah so so let me go on about the let's
go to the next topic so let's talk about
font
yeah unicode font so you know you can
just go to my website you know over here
the URL on top it's just such folks re
unicode and then if you scroll down
you're see there it is download found so
the best font okay so for programming I
would recommend DejaVu
especially on Linux okay so for
programming Daboo is a suit a suite or
how you put called sweet or pseudo font
so it's got several phones it got sense
serious it's got serif in its kimono
you know mah no space font so why do I
think this is great a teacher who is
great because it is one font that has
the most the most of them all the most
Unicode symbols for example for
mathematics of emoji in one single font
now today actually it's not you know
people usually usually ask you know we
which is the the most you know unicode
font i mean they have a concept concept
of unicode font they are thinking that
you know this one font will cover all
the characters in Unicode actually
that's not true I mean they are one was
such fund but it's really bad I mean so
basically the idea of one single font
that covers the entire character set of
Unicode is a bad idea
nobody does that so so what what people
do is that in general you have one
particular font that covers a few
languages you know basically so for
example for Egyptian usually you just
want have one particular font for
Egyptian but
you know but if you you may wonder so if
I'm showing a Egyptian page let's say
let's say I'm showing this page Unicode
croc you know so it's got a bunch of
emojis now there is this usually a font
designed just for emoji basically
there's a font that covers all emo
emojis Smiley's hands food love you know
clothing animals there is a font that
covers all emoji but however on this
page you can see I also have you know
English alphabet and actually I also
have Egyptians and every other symbols
so basically what happens today is that
computer you know the the browser what
it whatever the application they they
they check you know if a character is in
the current font if if it is not it will
use another forms for it so this
technology is called font substitution
and that is how you can have one page
containing several languages you know
and that it that is also the only the
only practical way yeah I think so I'm
pretty sure okay so font let's go back
to fund so I'm talking about
DejaVu so they travel so if you look at
the Unicode for example if you are okay
if you are you Emacs user or if you are
programmer often you know maybe you need
to write a lot math not or even for
example math let's go to math you know
maybe you need to write a lot of math
superscript subscript and so on and
sometimes you want to you know include a
heart or something so so that's why I
recommend it deja vu digital is a
general great fun that contains all the
most basic symbols
you need okay that stage I feel good for
programming but the other one is Google
note Oh
now Google note how is like huge Google
basically Google note oh now today they
they you can read it here
they designed so that they they have its
it's a font set so it it has like more
than 10 20 years and 30 fonts it's it's
intended to cover every character in
Unicode not in not in one font though
but you know many different form sets so
and supposedly they should be you know
they they will all be consistent so you
can find Egyptian stuff here Bengali or
linear be you know ancient you know
scripts or also Chinese ones I don't
think I've do we have Chinese I think so
but yeah I don't remember seeing it so
anyway so you can always you can
download google moto I think it covers
every everything yeah but one thing bad
is that you know you don't want to use
everything in Google because Google is
well so yeah did so Google note how you
can use and if you and there is also a
symbol symbol font symbol font is by
this guy by this guy I think he's from
quick quiz aus so here's his website he
provides same symbol symbolic covers or
the emoji and math symbols and others it
used to be like open source in fact they
used to be like public domain but last
year or two years ago for some reason he
changed or his licenses to be personal
use only non-commercial so but
but before that basically Linux or use
or uses his font okay let's let's go
back to Unicode hey guys so I'm gonna
talk about next let's talk about okay
download found have I have recovered it
enough so Google note oh yeah you can
use that symbol ah you can use that it's
kind of I think symbolic I mean today
it's kind of good you know it's it's
facing out because now it's big it has
became proprietary I mean it's only for
non-commercial uses and meanwhile Coogan
Auto is Apache licensed and you know
it's Google so it covers you know it's
getting big and high quality and covers
everything then the stage óbuda jabu is
good for programming for Emacs so
there's how to install found basically
for Microsoft Windows in Mac you just
double-click on it for Linux it's a bit
more complex you can read it here Linux
is always a bit complex
so now let's go back okay how to how do
you type Unicode okay let's let's talk
about that how to type Unicode okay the
the easy okay the easiest way I mean the
easiest is on a Mac on a Mac you
probably already know you just go to
here keyboard show emoji and symbols
then you have a Unicode viewer I'm not
sure I can you know CH this but anyway
if you go to your systems preference if
you don't have this menu showing you can
just go to systems preference and under
keyboard and
and and click this show keyboard and
emoji viewers in menu bar okay then then
you'll get this menu and you can just
show the Unicode panel you know so there
is all your Latin alphabets you can just
double click on it and you know you
actually insert the character for
example I mean here text edit
where did it go okay yeah just
double-click in your show and also
typically the application itself has a
humility in symbols okay that's on the
Mac it's it's the most easy the other
way there's another way which is a
little bit more limited is show keyboard
viewer you can press you can hold the
option key hold the option key and you
can insert these symbols okay yeah on
the Mac it's most easy but on Windows
you know you can really here I never
used Windows to insert Unicode and on
Linux it's also a bit more it's a bit
complicated but Emacs is the best you
know because well I type o my unicode
needs are typing Emacs for example one
of the things you can do is just type a
brief for example heart oh let's go to
my agree file
search for Unicode for example let's see
cat face space ok magnify magnify cat
face good you know you can set up
yourself and if you search for you just
you know if you want Emacs chips just
search for sorry
Emacs Unicode
so there is Unicode tutorial
and this page talks about everything
about Unicode in Emacs and if you want
abbreviation it's also mentioned here
there are so many ways to insert
characters in Unicode in Emacs many ways
to set it up you can also say set of
keys to insert Unicode but the one way I
find the most easy by abbreviation okay
so close that let's go back to
okay so I think next I'm going to talk
about introduction of Unicode for
programmers like you know what does it
mean the encoding what other you know
the just the basics
yeah character map is for Windows but I
I've tried it I think it's pretty lousy
also similarly on Linux there is also a
application similar to character map
that's also pretty lousy Mac is the best
so okay I'm going to give you an
introduction unicode to programmers so
let's talk about it I'm gonna just talk
about it so first of all there's a
concept concept of character set a
character set is just a set of
characters for example ABCD a to Z so
you know if you know for example the
older capital letters A to Z of English
of alphabet so that's a character set
now you can also include lowercase and
you can include digits 0 to 9 so 0 to 9
a to z lower case of capital case
altogether you can consider that one
character set so character set is just a
set of characters now a character set
can be you know you have many other
symbols such as trademark symbol
copyright symbol heart symbol tag sign
or summation some sign in math and you
can include that you know or you can
just have this you know five was five or
six characters as the character set so I
mean this is an important concept the
first of all there is a character set
now before programming before computer
languages that the concept of character
set exists for example when you well for
example when you teach English you have
English alphabets that's a character set
and and when you actually if you teach
Chinese or if you are you know Chinese
age
organization you need a character set
you know because Chinese has you know
including history they are like 10,000
characters so but basically you have
like a character standard character set
for you know for the general public you
know so you need to be six with specific
you know you need to list each of them
so there's a character set so that's the
first idea then you have the idea of
encoding because inputting computing
every character needs to be translated
into basically your number you know
basically one in zeros you know the
binary number so encoding so what is
encoding encoding is basically a map
between any specific character to a
binary number so that's the essential
idea of character encoding it maps a
number you know binary number you know
he's you know you can translate it to a
decimal number so let's just say it's an
integer so you can so a character
encoding is a map between any any
character to a former character set to a
number integer so that's character
encoding and okay there's an interesting
thing about character set and encoding
systems because these two are sometimes
gets confused because sometimes when we
say our character said we usually mean a
encoding system that's not true
for example in HTML you have these
syntax like meta you know content type
character set like char set equals to
something that's actually true because
that's actually not true because I mean
that's a misnomer
that's a badly named because when you
say char said equals to utf-8 it
actually means
encoding utf-8 not character set so
let's talk about encoding so encoding is
a map it's a map between you know a
number and character and there are
several different encodings for example
let's say the character a let's say
capital a you know should it be the
number of 56 or should it be you know 95
or maybe should it be 1000 you know who
is to say so there are several standards
I mean there are standards that specify
you know
okay the letter a should be 56 for
example or some other net number so so
there are these standards so first of
all you define a character set you know
a specific character set then you define
encoding a pot a specific particular
encoding that map each character in this
character set to a number so if you do
that you know you could call that you're
you know character encoding you know so
I mean you know throughout you know in
the past few 50 years or so people have
created many encodings ASCII is the most
basic ASCII has like 128 characters the
character said is 128 characters and
it's mapped to number 1 to 128 and then
you have unicode now Unicode is a
standard that's started in started in
the 1990s it defines a character set and
it defines several encodings not just
one you actually defined several
encodings so you have utf-8 utf-16 you
have utf-32 let's see utf-8 utf-16
utf-32
I think there's another one is that is
there another one
okay so so utf-8 but anyway utf-8 and
utf-16 is the most popular well wait a
second
utf-8 today is the most popular
basically it's like 95% of websites use
uses a utf-8 so basically that's the
most popular by far today so character
said character encoding okay you know
you know what I think I think I'm I'm
you know I'm kind of stuck you know
because I'm not you know usually I
become you know sometimes I get into a
point where I feel there's a pressure
that I have to cover these things like
formally and then I got I got stuck and
I become robotic so so anyway and when
that happens things just go wrong like I
I lost track you know where should I
talk about what should I talk about
so I yeah so you know and so anyway
let's this carry on so Unicode character
said any encoding systems so yeah so
let's cover some important things okay
so let's cover just some important
things so you have character said yeah
the the Unicode the character set for
Unicode basically covers every language
in a world in the past or present so it
covers you know all possible languages
or languages that has been ever written
written down so that's Unicode character
set and and these days Unicode has a new
version every year so every year it adds
adds some basically some asian languages
or and more emoji every year so
sometimes around june what you like so
anyway now now here's the important
point so so we got character set and we
got encoding and now this is a very
important point in code point this is
very important now in Unicode Unicode
gives every character an ID kind of a
you know a unique ID and that ID is
called code point and that is basically
a integer so for example the character
alpha the Greek Alpha it has a code
point code point 945 and because it is a
integer so you can express it in
hexadecimal which is 3 B 1 and Unicode
also give it a standard notation which
is you followed by a first sign followed
by the hexadecimal in all capital
letters so based but basically the most
important thing is the code point just
remember that every character
is identified by a unique ID a integer
okay that's one important thing point
the other important thing is character
name so again every character has a
character name you can see here so the
English alphabet capital a is called
Latin capital letter a so every
character has a character name and given
a character name is supposed to be
unique so if you see a character name it
will be unique
that means no other character will have
that name
however some characters has has more
than one name because unicode add some
you know it in unicode - I think they
changed the name of some characters so
some characters will have you know more
than one name but still even so it is
still true that every Unicode name will
be unique it would point to just one
character and also there's another
concept you know we talked about
characters when we talk about characters
we think of visible we think of visible
drives like these right but actually
there are many characters that's
invisible for example you have new line
newline character or the tab sign so
those are invisible characters and some
of them are code control characters and
there are other examples such as
non-breaking space which is like a space
but it's called non-breaking space
because if you have that's that
character between two visible characters
it tells the application to not you know
not instead the incident near line
between them so so remember that some
characters are invisible or you know and
another good example is left
right mark for example in Arabic script
Arabic language is written from left to
right so Sandra
sometimes you have to use that mark to
change the odor flow which is kind of
annoying actually I mean when you use it
in Emacs for example if I copy it here
let's see if I copy you see okay so so I
copy so you see that Direction is even
you see the my highlight Direction is
different from the usual because usual
usually I highlight from right to the to
the from left to right so if I copy this
open a new buffer pasting Emacs
magnify magnify you see they are you
know if if I press the right arrow key
oh right arrow key after our key okay so
that's still well anyway you can see
they are aligned from the yeah if I
press the right arrow key actually I'm
pressing the left arrow key it just go
into the different direction so it's
hard to work with if you know you this
is not new your native language and it's
especially confusing if you have English
mixed in for example let's say this is
confusing okay I don't even know where
my cursor should go so this you see it's
kind of strange like
okay so code point character name
encoding system so okay so what what is
the difference between utf-8 and utf-16
so so utf-8 and utf-16 both of them are
variable length encoding that means
given a character it in utf-8 for
example each character may have may take
one to four bytes but for Latin
characters like ABCD efg you know A to Z
each character correspond to just one
bite one by it means eight bits but you
know it depends on the character some
character for example this acrylic this
Russian from Russian alphabet so let's
try it so close this window new buffer
pasted in logic in logic in object image
and we can do describe cha in Emacs and
you can see enlarged so you can see this
character so here's a quote point you
know 1 0 46 in decimal
and that's hexadecimal 406 and you can
see Unicode name here this Y and oh yeah
so we want to see the encoding utf-8 so
let's say encoding there so this
character encoding in utf-8 is T 0 and
96 in hexadecimal so it takes two bytes
but this one face with tears of Joey the
most one of the its it is actually the
most used emoji I'm very sure something
like that face with tears of joy
so in utf-8 it's four bytes you can see
here so in utf-8 encoding each character
may have one or two or three or four
bytes no more than that now in utf-16
encoding each character will have two to
four bytes so the minimum is two so so
UTF is ASCII compatible that means if
you have a file that's encoded in ASCII
and it's the encoding utf-8 is is is
exactly the same no change at all
so encoding so encoding is converting a
character you know from two two numbers
and decoding is a reverse okay and found
an input method
okay font yeah of course you need a font
you need you need a right font to this
way it an input method input method is
another very interesting thing now input
method is very interesting because you
know if you are American then you just
type with your keyboard
there is no problem no problem this is
input you the input is what keys you
press you know the characters come out
but however if you want to type Chinese
then it's oh my god it's complicated
then you need a input method is called
input method so Chinese you need that
because there are several thousand
character
you know you cannot possibly have your
keyboard to do that actually there is no
well there's no you know you just have
to use an input method I mean I think
historically there were like typing
machines you know with thousands of
characters for printing but not today
well for printing yes I think you still
need to do that for mass printing like
many newspapers but anyway so you use
input methods so what does input method
mean basically it's just a method - yeah
obviously it's a method to type
characters for example you probably have
used input method yourself before
because because because because because
because because because let's go to
Safari and let's look here for example
emoji now how do you type this character
kiss with a heart sign smooch
well you type it by for example in
Twitter you want to treat and you say
you click on this smiley sign then you
have a bunch of things like clowns then
oh my god it's so slow what's going on
okay you click you got a dog face you
got a cat face something is wrong you
know it's getting slow in Twitter
recently I think I know why because I'm
using the brave browser you know great
browser is great I talked about it a few
days ago in my stream let's not repeat
that but anyway break browser is great
so anyway you see the so that's how I
input emoji and that is a input method
technically you know because you are not
just pressing keys on your keyboard you
have to you know deal with these icons
and stuff you know to input that that's
one you know you could call that a input
method so input method is just a method
close it yes I want to cancel so input
method is just a way for you to type you
know characters that's not not on your
keyboard and you know you have today we
have hundreds of emojis
you know emojis are it's actually such a
fascinating thing and in a Western world
it has also become political very
political thing okay it's let's look at
the emoji frequency you see this is
there are websites that actually
calculate statistics of you know how
what would you know which emoji people
use the most often mostly from Twitter
you know they have a caller that just
called Twitter and you know compute how
many you know which emoji people what
emoji people are using and this this
this face with tears of joy is most used
most of most frequently used especially
on Chinese website like everything is
like tears of joy you know the name is
also kind of funny because originally I
don't think it's it's not like you know
faced with tears of joy but rather I
would think it's like kind of like
sarcastic and and and laughing in the
sarcastic so anyway so that's the emoji
very interesting and of course there's
also history of emoji history you know
emoji came from Japan originally because
on their cell phones Japan have emoji
emoji basically evolved from emoticons
so what is emoticon you know these kind
of things are emoticon you see
we you are probably familiar with I mean
if you are older than you know
if you are younger maybe you don't know
but they began in 1980s and 1990s so you
have this emoticon then but in Japan or
Asia you have a different style style of
emoticon like that then then you know
then people just add more but anyway
emoji came from Japan so in the
beginning it's mostly Japanese oriented
stuff for example you can still see
signs of that
for example being in food for example
you know there's lots of Japanese you
know like right now like each year they
add new things you know the it becomes
political thing the Western people yeah
the Western the white people they wanna
they want this they want that they say
no that is wrong this is wrong anyway so
you know gee so you can you can tell so
from emoji food you can see many of them
are of Japanese or ancient for example
the you goddess or ten you got this
tango which is Japanese food then you
have these spinto box japanese sushi so
you see just for this you know there
there you have several Japanese foods
all these all of these are like more
than 10 years maybe 10 years old this
row but however most of the others for
example all these like they just they
just came out a few years ago the
western food the Western stuff so anyway
let's go back to input methods so yeah
so input method is way to input
characters and if you are interested you
can read these two articles this article
for example it will show you how to
input Chinese characters even if you
don't know Chinese you can actually try
it you know you can try it on a map
on Windows or and you can even try it in
Emacs I have a tutorial here you can you
know you can just try to see it you know
just just say curiosity point of view so
I think I've been talking for oh my god
I've been dunking for over one hour so
good I'm doing good how are you guys
doing you know sometimes my like I like
I like doing this talk show because I
enjoy talking and and I enjoy talking to
you guys in and I enjoy teaching people
about things and also my random rants
you know my opinions about things but
sometimes you know I know that because
sometimes like like if I'm doing it
formally or you know if if this is a
scheduled plan okay today because I is
going to teach something you know I I
get this pressure and sometimes when I
feel that I just became you know robotic
and you know it's like cannot talk about
anything so that is why I was like first
and for a moment anyway so input method
so this Chinese input method and you can
also look at Japanese input method now
by the way Japanese Japanese writing
system is the most complicated writing
system of of them all of all words
languages Japanese writing system is the
most complicated note this is about
writing system not about language now
this is very interesting linguistics
that each language does you know the
speech you know the list you know the
language you know you speak you
pronounce it you you know you talk to
other people that's the language however
the writing system is almost entirely
different thing it's like separate it
has no almost no connection so it's very
interesting
but anyway in for Japanese you know
Japanese does not have a writing system
but they borrowed from Chinese so you
know Japan in China are closed right so
you know people you know travel around
so they borrowed Chinese writing system
which is extremely complicated but
however you know the Japanese they they
learned from the Chinese characters then
it kind of okay they then you know
originally you know like several hundred
years ago like let's say five hundred
years ago if you read Japanese text you
know Japanese tech it's big it's all
Chinese every character every word is
all Chinese and basically it has the
same meaning as Chinese too so so you
know even Japanese do not speak Chinese
but when they write the entire thing on
essentially like 90% over 99% the entire
thing is Chinese and Chinese can also
understand it so but anyway in like I
think a few hundred years ago they they
kind of evolved so but anyway the
current Japanese writing system you know
you have this phonetics there are two
sets one is called hiragana and that's a
read that's hiragana and the the blue
one is katakana and they are phonetic
systems phonetic meaning that each of
these symbol represents a sound so you
put these characters together they are
kind of like alphabets you know that
kind is kind of like English alphabets
you put this you know together you have
you can pronounce it however however
that's only part of it so this these are
like pronunciation symbols but Japanese
also use Chinese so if you read so I so
for example this this is a paragraph
from Wikipedia about about keyboard and
you can see some of these characters are
very dense you see
this this one let's turn a little click
off and this one you know this one this
one this one this one the things I'm
point pointing out they are actually
Chinese characters and actually I
understand so even though I never
studied Chinese I read this I can
understand like thirty percent of it you
know I just I have idea what they are
talking about so so Japanese writing
system is made of Chinese characters
which they call kanji and the hiragana
and katakana are phonetic systems and
then punctuation spent punctuation czar
mostly just like English and digits you
know and and also it's funny that the
Japanese writing system also include
English alphabets
I think officially so so anyway you can
learn about so Japanese input method you
can actually type it on account your
computer it's it's complicated it's
fairly you know I work when I was
studying you know the Japanese input
system and also Japanese keyboards I
have it here somewhere Japanese keyboard
is it's it's very interesting but as
input impact for example this is an
Apple keyboard sold in Japan and you
know have Apple laptop you notice that
you know the Japanese input system and
also the Chinese input system they are
the most efficient in persistent
possible just like the English corty you
know like when you type when you are
into type he and he was you know there's
a quality and there's Warrick right but
Cody is very efficient but however we
just you know adopt it and you know it
never changed but if but if you look at
Japanese input system and Chinese input
system it's kind of worse and in fact
it's a situation for French as well for
for for French Germany but basically
every country they are
infant system you know or their
arrangement you know the layout is very
efficient in many cases more you know
for example French if you are French in
France using whatever standard layout
they use it's more inefficient to type
it then then English using quality so
it's pretty bad and it's you know it's
similarly it's worse for Chuck Chapman
Chuck Japan 4/4 time in Japanese so
anyway I think that you know that I
think that's about it for today I think
I've been talking for long and oh yeah
so I'm going to talk about so Unicode
basics you know it for programmers I
think I covered it so you know I I don't
want to be you know I think I have a
habit you know I am trying to improve
you know I have a habit of being
repetitive and but I've been doing
videos you know for like half a year now
I'm getting better and met many things
so you know you learn as you go so so we
have you know the encoding Unicode
introduction then you have Python
scripts okay show you let me yeah let me
show you some torso type some questions
then we will say goodbye okay I type
last chance type some questions so yeah
I'm going to show you some Python code
in JavaScript code yeah well I actually
just follow follow where the rainbow
lies just follow this where is it
fathers also wears it so I'm trying to
find Unicode for programmers yeah so I'm
gonna show you unicode for programmers
so introduction I don't have the link
here so where is it how to input Unicode
okay here so on this page unicode intro
so how do you find this unicode intro
but actually I don't have a link here
but I'm going to add a link somewhere
here so you can see but anyway on this
page Unicode introduction Unicode basics
character said at the bottom you will
see many useful tools if you are
programmers so Unicode basics so oh this
is interesting so this is a few years
ago I was studying which language
supports Unicode so I covered Ruby Perl
Python Python to Python 3 and JavaScript
email eMac this emag base is the best by
the way it's the most robust in
supporting Unicode now when you are on
this subject one of the most interesting
thing is that there are two aspects why
is supporting Unicode in string okay
almost all language does that the other
thing is whether you can use Unicode as
function name function name or variable
name you know identifiers now today most
languages support that today you know
not but not in back in 2010 today most
languages you can use unicode names in
acid identifiers you know like variable
names in function names however however
there say depending on the language
usually they have a restriction that is
you can you know Unicode characters
characters are allowed in function names
however the Unicode character must be a
letter like character so what does that
mean so in único each character has a
kind of a property and so a letter like
character basically is part of an
alphabet or a Chinese character or
something like that however a star for
example a star or a heart is not a
later like character therefore you
cannot use as a function name for
example let's say you'll be yeah for
example JavaScript you cannot you cannot
use a heart as a function name for
example and that's that's a little bit
problematic for example sometimes you
want to use the character math operators
for your function name for example son
you know you want to use some for your
function name but you cannot do that in
JavaScript for example but however there
is a trick over this in this case you
can use the Greek summation I mean the
Greek Sigma capital Sigma that is
identical I mean it looks similar to the
some character but anyway so that's
interesting to mention some function
names in some languages you cannot use a
character unicode character that is not
considered later but per okay but Perkin
Pro is like so it's like screwed up by
its nature so anyway I think that's it
okay yeah well I was going to cover some
of the okay I was going to cover how
different languages deal with Unicode
how they supported how you and also
there's some some of other interesting
things like how do you first of all if
you have a Unicode string how do you
process the Unicode that's one question
the other question is unicode each
character has for example you want to
find out the code point for a character
or given a code point you want to find
out a character or given a character you
want to find out the name or you want to
find you want to collect all characters
that are later like you know like we
mentioned before how do you
find out how do you you know get a set
of all characters that are later like so
in each languages they have tools based
basically usually in the unicorn module
that allows you to do that for example
yeah I have one for Python for example
but it's somewhere here it's it's not in
this box this box only cover the basics
but anyway I think that's it for today
so sorry for the my rambling and stuff
so let me read the questions and Derby
it for today so
so you can are you sayin
yep utf-16 is used by java and it's also
used by windows file system I think and
here in what's the name a Windows file
system I forgot the name at the moment
and it was also used by Mac HFS+ file
system but these days Mac has a new file
system so yeah but anyway you utf-8 is
the standard but I wouldn't say you know
this is okay let me talk about this
because that's interesting and it's
usually it's a it's a thing I want you
know it's my thing to talk about rent
that is complaint you know
bitching again it's the hacker type of
programmers you know the hacker type of
program is typically meaning UNIX and
Linux phonetics
they always they will always tell you
use utf-8 that's the best you know don't
use anything else that's but actually I
think that's you know utf-16
for example if you if your language is
Chinese and if you use utf-16 your file
size will be much smaller than utf-8 for
example okay I'm not saying you know
your file size will be smaller for
example twice as smaller in general and
also by the way there is a website the
Deo is a popular website you know it's
spread by hacker news and all that
typically you know I can use all these
geek geek websites they always have some
you know popular articles and basically
when I have when a particular article
became popular widespread then after a
while that idea is set then because
every geek will tell you all just do
these just do that and you know it's not
necessarily good correct you know
sometimes you know after a few years
then people say oh actually that's a bad
idea
so anyway there was a pretty widely
spread popular article that says you
know we should just stick to utf-8 and
in particular one of the example they
cite is that even in Chinese or Japanese
the most text you type ends up with
smaller file size if you are using utf-8
why because for example in HTML the
majority or at least half you know of
the Texas actually English characters
for example programming code you know
other characters are English but let me
what so so you know so that is why even
if you have Chinese but in HTML the the
file size of Chinese encoded in utf-8
may actually be smaller or equal to
utf-16 and the reason is that you know a
lot of characters in it is actually
English because programming languages
basically because HTML is you know from
USA so but that may be true but let me
just point out that's actually okay
today the proper term to call that is
western-centric okay you know because
you if you start with I that idea of
course that that is true but but that
let us say you know from the Chinese
point of view progressive let's say
that's called progressive you know in a
few years you know that the programming
language may not be English you know who
says that you know HTML will last
forever
you know polite you know ASCII died you
know so who knows but if you enforce
everyone to UTF now you know like you
want to spread your let's all you just
use utf-8 then
you may actually slow down the progress
of the Chinese character you know the
Chinese introduction of using basically
you'll cure other ideas about utf-16 or
and others but anyway I'm not you know
I'm not particularly biased biased for
these well I think utf-8 is pretty good
and by the way the other reason utf-8 is
hugely popular is do you know why is
because UNIX the most the worst
operating system and the worst you know
the holding a spec system that is UNIX
which became Linux that is why you know
utf-8 kind of become popular because
because you UNIX and Linux they are a
ski they are very slow to change you
know Mac and Windows switch to utf-16
long ago like 20 20 years ago but Linux
did not Linux you know because you know
it's open source nobody you know it
wants to put money everyone just use it
free so it's free software you know so
it's you know all the programs doesn't
work it doesn't support unit Unicode
when Windows and Mac support Unicode you
know it takes Linux you know like
comparatively 10 years later then unit
your Unix Linux supposed some Unicode
so the way they do that is that because
you you don't have a resource to rewrite
everything all the shared programs for
example bash so what they do is that
they rely on utf-8 compatibility with
ASCII
therefore they you know it's grateful
you meet Linux because you don't if if
if utf-8 is the standard then they save
huge amount of time you know basically
they saved Linux you know they don't
have to change much they just patch a
little bit you know to support
extensions so that that is one major
reason that utf-8 is popular okay in
this in the beginning also there is a
very popular you
your video that's actually just
propaganda YouTube you know and spread
by the hacker types kind of people this
idiot who talks about why utf-8 is you
should is the you know let me show you
you'll find it the first one this guy
now this guy at this this video is like
oh five years ago okay so this video let
me show you
now you probably have seen it if you you
know follow the news on around web this
is five years old now it's got seven
hundred thousand views close to a
million so so this guy when I saw when I
see this video the first time I was
wondering who the is this guy I
don't know but you know a few few months
ago actually I looked he's not you know
I thought he's some kind of expert you
know some kind of you know some experts
you know big big-time some major code or
something something but he turns out
he's not he's just almost a random ish
guy but in this video he talks about how
unicode how to utf-8 he's like magic you
know like you know he he talked about
the you know like almost a legend the
fable the the law how the UTF people who
is that guy the guy who created the co
language which is by the way Coco
language is a great language one of the
most it's the best language okay but
anyway the guy created the goal and
what's his name
okay anyone you know I kind of rambled a
lot you know I was I meant to finish
this video but anyway why not is just
the talk shows I'm just talking whenever
so you know feel free to go but I think
we're gonna finish in a moment so anyway
the
video is pretty bad you know is if you
look at this video you listen closely
and you you take out what's the
technical point now be he's got a few
technical point you know in supporting
his idea about how you teve utf-8 is
superior however then you look at the
rest of its like garbage you know it's
it's one of those things that UNIX or
the hacker types likes to spread like
you know you have videos like this or
articles the other articles like that
you know so every time for example on
Twitter or somewhere else you mentioned
you know Unicode you know which we space
encoding then an army of Linux phonetics
will just come up and point out point
point this video to you you know that's
why of these or despite bad ideas spread
no it's not kind Ken Thompson it's a
it's it's another guy it's what's his
name the guy who created :
he's also it's he's younger than Kim
Johnson his well anyway that there is a
legend that utf-8 is created on the back
of a napkin in a restaurant you know
this unit UNIX kind of things always
have this kind of lead you know this
kind of load to go with it Rob Pike
that's it
thank you yeah Rob Pike you know the Rob
Pike you know I know he's a heavy units
guy because he's he's one of the UNIX
guy who likes to talk a lot like you
know keep saying things you know how
UNIX is great how you know the UNIX
philosophy and so on so I always
despised him you know I didn't like him
even now even though I haven't read much
about him you know who is he I mean what
exactly he did but however since I
learned the gold language you know I
heard KO lang which went begin like ten
years ago you know and it's by Rob Pike
and my mind goes why do we need another
language and oh it's by this
in my guy I you know I'm not gonna like
you know I won't be looking into it
but however few years ago I started to
study goal and every idea of goal and I
agree with okay essentially almost like
every every idea you know so Rob Pike he
has written articles about it right so
so they have philosophy about goal and
why why you know why they created you
know what design considerations go into
: why they design : to be this way or
that way every idea I agree very much
you know that's that's you know that's
you know it surprised I surprised myself
because you know I didn't like the rob
guy bike guy because I thought he's just
a UNIX you know huge something like that
but it it turned my mind around so now I
respect you know whatever he says I I
pay attention and I like I respect so so
anyway so let's see there's any more
questions I wanna Japanese word is okay
so I think maybe I'll just skip the
question questions
okay Japanese word for escalator
Japanese flyscreen I think children is
his part counting bytes yeah there's
also another interesting about treat
treat limit Twitter limit like you it
used to be 200 I mean 120 or was it 128
but now it's something like 250 however
it applies an exception to Chinese
characters so if you type Chinese in
Twitter on Twitter the character limit
is still 128 very strange and I don't
know why they actually do that the way
you know there is an interesting
technical question because that is how
do they actually determine a treat is
using Chinese or just English because
often you you know I can mix both of
them so is it do they count it by
majority of characters you know like if
the Madrid in your trait if the majority
is Chinese then they consider it to be
Chinese then they use a Chinese
character limit rule which is 128 you
know maybe that's why they do it I mean
that's how they decide but it's an
interesting
well the Unicode okay so yeah we talking
so the Unicode the remember character
said you the Unicode character set is
keep increasing and increasing okay but
still the limit is less than 32 raised
to 2 raised to the 30 tooth that is 32
bits that's a maximum number of
characters in Unicode yeah but right now
Unicode has more than 68 characters so
some characters it was okay
especially emoji emoji characters or
these emoji
each one is you know if if you look at
their if you look at their code point
for example this one is U 1 F 6 0 6
which is more than 4 characters meaning
that which in turn means that it's the
the code point that is the integer is
beyond 16-bit you know one one two five
five one eight so anyway if the if in
the standard unicorn notation if it has
more than four hexa modest hexadecimal
digits then that character is beyond
16-bit that's one easy way to tell so
all the emojis you can see this one is
five characters basically most of the
emoji is beyond sixteen bits but these
two for example the first two they are
they are old they are you know in
Unicode before the emoji thing before
the emoji craze but so you can see that
this this two emoji the smiley are they
have four characters hexamer digit
representation so they are within 16-bit
oh yeah Oh Scott so Scott yeah I so your
question about me working on my website
yes I have lots of it
it's seen in my previous YouTube videos
like a lot of them
so I think so that's it for today so
thank you guys very much for coming have
a good day bye