Good morning guys. Good morning
everyone. Welcome to another episode of
talk show. We are going to code geometry
mathematics graphics programming using
wuam language.
Uh so if you are here say hi. Uh this is
like randomish. So I'm just going to
work on my website. You are looking at a
visual dictionary of special plane
curves. Search for it. You will find it.
This is mathematics, geometry. Pertinent
to those of you studying uh calculus or
college students,
elementary. This is like college level.
Um
if you are watching this offline, play
at 1.5 speed. Uh what I'm going to do is
just I'm just going to work on my
website and if you have questions um you
can ask me about programming about
mathematics
and otherwise you just um you just can
you can watch me code or
fall asleep something like ASMR stuff.
Okay. So we're gonna go slowly and
drink. So if you don't know already my
gears like Emacs the most advanced text
text editor and
okay if you don't my if you don't know
my gears well let me show you okay so
talk show today's talk show 2026
March 4th episode 774
so let's go down so we are in Emacs
delete that show in browser so now it's
better and delete that todo hack. Uh, so
I'm using this ultimate hacking keyboard
80. UHK80.
You can find it in my reviews
on YouTube. This keyboard. Okay. Uh K80.
And that's NAI
track.
Fantastic. That's my favorite
trackboard. And this one is Logitech.
uh very popular Logitech G502.
I have it for like by now seven years. I
think I've been using it for seven
years. Okay. And uh I'm using Emacs of
course.
And if you don't know already uh
actually show you know just show let me
show you visual dictionary of special
plane curves. Okay. And search for it
you'll find it. And we end. I'm using
SFly keys. The most efficient key
binding system in the universe more
efficient than Vim or Neo Vim. There are
videos you can watch and it's download.
It's free. It's for Emacs. Uh if you are
programmer, if you are a writer, this
would be most suitable.
Uh this is critical because it's going
to change your life if you are a writer
or a programmer because you're gonna you
know you need to write or codes and this
is the most efficient
fly keys emac
let's see and wam language I introduced
many times search for kasar wam language
for programmers kasali.info info my name
you'll find it
complete tutorial from the ground up for
programmers if you know Python or
JavaScript it's fantastic and you can
download it free since few years ago the
most advanced programming language by a
magnitude woof language okay so you can
download so and that's what we're going
to do uh so if you are looking at the
thumbnail of today's YouTube that's this
one Let's let's run. Okay. So, um
so shift shift enter. Okay. So, it
generates a new one. I I don't want this
one too big. Okay. Let's just um shift
enter
and what? Shift enter generates a a new
one. Okay, that's a code that is wam
language you're looking at.
Uh okay. So, wuam language download
introduction and um you can download you
can I have like 100 videos about wam
language. Okay, that's introduction
about wam language and what else? Let's
go back and today we're going to use a
lot of wam language packages for doing
plain curves. So, you can see uh it's
all free. It's on GitHub. So, just
search for it. Search for Wuam language
packages by my name. You can find all
these packages. Fantastic and beautiful.
Cheers. Red wine.
You see you're looking at this is
normals of of the curve deltoid.
Normals of the deltoid. Let me just go
over this. illustrate tangent.
Nomos of a deltoid. Nomos of a parabola.
Nomos of a asteroid. This star- shaped
thing is called asteroid. We talked
about in the past week. And the nomos of
a asteroid forms another asteroid. You
can you can see it forms another
asteroid in different orientation.
Fascinating.
This is normals of a cardioid. Cardioid
means heart-shaped
curve. This curve and the known of a
cardioid is another cardioid. You can
see it generates inside it a little this
this is like a ass curve because it
shape the shape looks like a S but they
call it heart because they you know like
the heart but you know they call it
cardioid and but it generates a smaller
cardioid inside. Uh I should have the
normal lines longer so you can actually
see it. But is that actually true or is
it just looks like you see in
mathematics you can't you cannot say
something is true just by the look of
it. You see in mathematics you have to
do proof. Okay. So but this visual tools
illustrates the truth or they can help
you find what is true. then you can do
proofs, okay? You know, um because when
something is obviously not true and when
you do a illustration, usually it just
doesn't work. You know, you can tell
right away it's not true. So anyway, so
this is this is normal normals of
ellipse.
Okay. Uh and they form a curve. Uh I'm
not sure there's a name for that curve.
that that thing in the middle
the envelope of the normals of ellipse.
Okay. And this one is the nor uh normals
of deltoid. Jesus, why do I always have
like normals? Okay. Anyway, so those all
the above are normals. Okay. Then use
normals are by the way normals are the
line that is perpendicular to tangent.
Okay. Now if you don't know, let me just
like I can explain this. So even if you
don't know any mathematics you will
understand
you know they they don't teach like that
in school. But so what is tangent?
Tangent is the most fundamental
intuitive idea. When you have a curve
like in a plane like for example this
one sign that's sign curve and any point
on the plane then there is a line
passing that point that is the most
fitting at that point you see that line
is called tangent
line line of the curve at that point.
Okay at the at the point on the curve is
C. So if the point is here the tangent
is this. If the point is there the
tangent is that you see there there is
one line such that it's like
mathematically it's the most fitting you
know there's one now how do you exactly
define that you know so anyway I'm
explaining to you the intuitive notion
of tangent tangent lines it's most it's
like the most fundamental idea in
differential geometry which is the
geometry for
uh relativity Okay, like most physics
differential geometry is um basically
when you study physics it is
differential geometry that is you would
be concerned about okay about the
universe okay so tangent is the most
fundamental idea so you got tangent
lines so you see so I I explained the
intuitive notion of tangent you see when
you have a curve like a smooth curve
there's and given a point on a curve
there's one line line that's most
fitting. You know there's one and only
one. Okay. So that's a intuitive notion.
But what what is it? How do you define
precisely mathematics?
Well, that's when you need to study
analytic geometry. You know that's what
that's what that's when you go to school
to study mathematics. You see you
started to have a coordinate you know
x-axis yaxis. Then you define you you
know you can specify a point by the x
you know a number x coordinate and y
coordinate and you can define a curve
now by giving a function you know like t
x equals to this function value y equals
to that function's value. So at any time
t you got two numbers x and y that
specify a point. So at any time you got
a point. So, so you started to have a
curve you see and if the curve is smooth
that's advanced idea. So, but
intuitively we we all think of curve as
smooth but anyway so then you can you
you you got a point on a curve you can
define you can have a
line is also a curve so you can have a
equation for a line. So you start
started to get um
precise you know like mathematics you
know you can define what is a line you
know so then okay but uh basically the
quick answer to the tangent is that
tangent is a derivative for the
functions of x and functions of y okay
now if you don't know calculus you don't
know what I mean but
that's you know then you can learn it
but the intuitive notion that I'm
explaining you know the tangent line.
Okay. And in in mathematics basically
that just means derivative
of the x component function and y
component. That's how you find the line.
Well, you find the tangent vector. Okay,
that's like a arrow on this point. You
know, the length of the arrow indicates
how fast the the the point is moving on
the curve. Okay.
Anyway, so we talked we talked about the
intuitive notion of tangent. Okay. Now,
what is a normal? Like we we showed we
we showed many normals. Normals are very
simple to understand. Once you got a
tangent, the normal
line of a point on the curve is the line
that passes the point and perpendicular
to the tangent.
Okay? So all you have to do is find the
tangent first. Then you draw a line
perpendicular perpendicular to the
tangent and pass in that point you know.
So for this one it would be like that.
For this tangent line it would be the
normal would be that the normal of the
curve at that point would be something
like that and that here and that here.
You see those are normal lines. Okay.
These are tangent. Okay. So um can we
actually plot it? Yes we can. you know,
you just type that you can
[laughter]
should I should should we plot it, you
know? So, actually we can, but I I I
have something else planned to do
anyway. So, actually let let's let's
plot it since we, you know, started to
talk about this um okay plane curve
plot. So let's go to um
okay so envelope let's just go to uh
let's just let me just do my things let
me just show you okay we already have
wam language open so oh yeah so you want
to plot it easy so let's see
so already paste it paste and magnify
please because otherwise it's too small
for people to t and what we want to plot
is this sign curve t and sine. So the
parameters are
here is just t and sign. Okay. So
actually we can plot it and see what
happened. Oh, it went crazy. So you know
so um so t and t from 0 to six. Okay. So
go back here t from 0 to six. So simple
not I don't want that you know super
complicated
um
delete T2 what six okay
six and uh costic style plot range
deleted
okay axis force deleted by default axis
will true is true we because we want to
see the axis background hue H 0 0 Hue 0
0 means black. I don't want black. Make
it white by default. Aspect ratio
automatic. That's good. Uh costic line
style. We don't want. What? By the way,
what does costic mean? Costic is a ray
from a light source. You see you got
this thing. This thing is a circle. You
see s cosine cosine s parametric
equation. That's the equation of a
circle. So here you got a circle
basically half of a circle because it
goes from
uh pi to 2 pi. You see it adds a little
number. You see we add that that those
tiny number to prevent like division by
zero and division by infinity something
like that. So that's why we add that
those but actually I don't think may not
be necessary. Let's try it again. You
see it's not necessary. So this tiny
number let's remove it. So in this case
we are plotting cosine and s
cosine t is the number for the x
coordinate a number. Okay sin t is a
number for the ycoordinate cosine and s.
Okay. And t is a t is time. You can
think of it as time. So t goes from pi
to 2 pi. And in steps of pi over 40. So
40 steps. Okay. So we go over half pi in
40 steps. Shift enter. Fantastic. And
beautiful. That's what it you see. So t
you know that curve is this one. And
what what what are the lines? The lines
are
light rays. Okay. Think of them as light
rays. So we got that which is called
costics. Okay. So we got this costic
origin from zero x coordinate is zero
and ycoordinate is 5,000. Basically it's
a vertical line. The light source is
very high above you know above these
graphics. Can you guys see me? Okay. If
you are uh enjoying this video say hi.
Okay. Say say in the comment.
Uh any questions comment you can see it.
Okay. So, so you got this light source
like somewhere above. Then it shoots a
light down to the circle. Then it
reflects off when it hits the circle.
That's reflects
and refract. You see some of them
reflect the the the yellow lines reflect
the red lines refract. That's how you
get this thing. Okay. Is that is that
beautiful? Does that make sense?
So that's that's this one. Okay. So
that's this this one. Okay. So costic
line style we say random you know we
actually say random uh two colors. Okay.
But here we wanted to show demonstrate
this uh tangent and normal. So
so we do we want to do s cosine t206.
Okay. Costic line length we don't care.
Uh costic or engine we don't care. line
length, we don't care. Plot dot force,
we don't care. Anyway, let's just draw
it. Let's see what happens. Okay. Oh,
you got this thing. Okay. So,
uh let's
delete that costic origin plot force.
What else we have here? Uh oh, you
missed you missed the comma. That's why.
Show. Okay. Nothing.
Okay. So, costic origin. So, power plot
plot dot force plot curve force. Oh, you
obviously you want to plot the curve.
Delete that. So, if we show here plot
curve, let's say, oh, you forgot the
comma. That's why.
Amazing. I forgot a comma there.
Uh,
fantastic. You see? Fantastic and
beautiful pl curve. Let's say true.
Okay, pl curve. True.
That's right. That's what we want. Shift
enter. Fantastic. And beautiful. I don't
like this color. So, let's do it again.
Shift enter.
Better. But let's try again. Shift
enter. Okay. I like this better. So,
costics.
costics means
the the light rays reflected from a
curve. So you can now you can see this
blue is a circle half of a circle and
the light parallel light rays hits it
from above then some of it reflected off
then you got this thing like ass shaped
thing that's called the costics of this
curve at
a parallel um rays okay that's called
catacostic and and this refraction
is called um
uh calacostic and what's the other word
um anyway that's called costics okay
that's like optics the study of optics
so anyway so we are trying to illustrate
about this uh normals and tangency we
are trying to explain what is a normal
so
what what do we have here shift enter so
why are we plotting all these. Uh oh,
you need
Okay, so you need um
you need plot range. Copy that.
Copy.
Okay. So, you want a plot range here.
Paste.
Okay. Plot range. Let's say zero. Let's
say -6
to 6. That's for x and y. Let's say
um
-3 to 3. Okay. Shift enter. Fantastic.
And beautiful. So we started to see u
that. Okay. Now we just delete all this.
Actually we don't need this. We don't
want costic. Delete it. Costic line
length. Delete it. Okay. Plot dots
force. Delete it. Okay. Delete. Delete.
Delete.
Plot range. Actually, plot range also.
Okay. Leave it. Curve style. We don't
care. Delete.
Okay. Now, delete. Shift. Enter.
Okay. We started to have a nice sign.
Okay. Now, plot range from zero to six.
X0.
Okay. Shift enter. Fantastic. Now we
talking. Now we wanted to show tangent
tangent line length. Okay. So let's give
our option
uh tangent line length
uh let's say 10. 20. Okay. 20 is good.
Good. Shift enter. Fantastic. Can you
see the tangent line at one that point
that point that point? Okay. Now you
need some um you want to specify
specific points for the tangent. Okay.
So you got to enter a point like that.
So let's see. Um you got to enter a
Okay. So let's say
1.5 or
1.5.
When the t parameter is 1.5, what you
get? Shift enter. Oh, there. Right
there. So that's your tangent line.
Okay. Now you also draw normal. Okay. So
normal
line
length. That's what you want. 20. Okay.
So you're going to draw a line
normal at that curve point. So let's do
it. Fantastic and beautiful. Can you
see? So now we have actually illustrated
the concepts of tangent and normal. So
let's change that again. So that makes
it more kind of um
make sense. Okay. Tangent and normal.
Fantastic.
So save this as untitled. Okay, let's
save it. Okay, so we were explaining the
tangent lines and normal lines of
intuitively
and so we we we talked about this uh so
review. Okay. So now you understand
tangent and normal. So you see these are
normal lines to this triangular shaped
thing called deltoid.
Okay. Now this is the blue is a parabola
and you draw all the normal lines to all
the points on the parabola you get this
you get this um you you get you they
form they form this V-shaped thing and I
believe that's called semicubic parabola
okay you see so we say that the envelope
of the um t the envelope of normals of
parabola is the semicubic
um
what was it called semicubic I forgot
anyway so anyway so so they form this
shape okay now this asteroid
in the middle this this star- shaped
thing ninja dot I call it ninja dot you
know so if you draw normals to all
points on this asteroid you at this
another asteroid. Fascinating. You see,
then you you draw the normals of that
asteroid is another asteroid, you know,
then then it's just bigger. So it's like
um
amazing properties. Okay.
Then this normals of the card you get
the smaller normal normal. So okay. So
actually did we you know we can actually
verify so you know so that the things we
are talking about this is this visual
dictionary of of special plane curves
they explain many of the plane curves
definition and properties visually so
you don't even have to know any
mathematics you can see and tell see and
tell you see this is the definition of
parabola can you can you like you
You you should re you should look at
this and immediately
like understand what is the meaning of
parabola parabola by looking at this uh
closely the meaning of parabola okay
uh
yeah any anyway so let's make that video
loop because uh
okay showing browser
go down. Go down. Go down. Let's play it
will loop. It will be better. Okay. So,
um yeah.
Cheers.
So, we talked for 30 minutes. We got a
lot to go because I was planning to
code, but I'm going to code. Okay. So,
but first of all, uh
what I've done is I
taught you guys some elementary geometry
of plank curves very the especially the
very interesting fascinating aspects
without having to know any ma
mathematics.
So for you programmers, you know, this
would be uh hopeful hopefully it's
interesting. Okay, we talked we talked
about tangents and uh tangents and
normal lines and so anyway visual pl uh
plank cups. Okay. So we I wanted to see
yeah we were wondering about um
uh you see we were talking about
cardioid the normals of a cardioid do
they form a is this actually cardioid we
can look at here. So cardioid um because
everything I wrote there you know I
verified it long ago. So this this curve
is cardioid. You see in this picture is
formed by all its tangents.
Okay. So anyway the cardioid is normally
defined as a curve rolling on another
curve
like that. Okay. Now now um now yes.
Okay. So you can see properties evolute
the evolute of a cardioid equals to
itself.
Fascinating. So it is indeed true that
is what we were illustrating in this
image in this you see this is to
illustrate that the evolute evolute is
another concept but anyway evolute is
kind of like the is kind of equivalent
to the envelope formed by all the normal
lines. So basically this this this thing
inside is a another cardioid. You see
this thing you see is a is called
cardioid meaning heart shaped but the
the the things inside that's another
cardioid. Okay. Fascinating.
So anyway we were talking about so so
and here so then we were talking about
okay normal survey deltoid then we we
started so these are seeant okay these
red lines are called seeant
okay we seeant is basically just given a
curve and given any two points on the
curve you draw a line between them
that's a seeant okay so seeant doesn't
have any like special meaning to a curve
meanwhile Now the tangent has very
significant meaning on a curve. Tangent
must be precise. Okay. And because it
has it tangent is basically the heart of
calculus. Okay. Like when you study
calculus from a geometric point of view
the entire calculus is just about
tangent. Okay. like how do you find so
so there's this line that approximate a
curve at that point that's a tangent
okay so the entire calculus from a from
a geometric point of view is is just
about tangent okay
that's one way to look at it one you
know one one way
um does that um you know I'm thinking
How accurate is it?
Uh I mean
so that's interesting. You see I was you
know I made a random observation
commentary
extended
that
from a from a geometric point of view
tangent is what calculus is all about.
So but are there part of calculus or
analysis that's like beyond
you know is is is not based on tangent
actually I don't think so you know
that's a quite significant commentary so
actually so let's check
um AI to verify okay so right now we
digress into the AI I let's see AI how
good is AI can AI verify my claim my
extle random observation so the claim is
from a geometric
point of view
tangent is what calculus it tangent is
the art of
calculus Okay.
Is this statement valid? Let's, you
know, let's ask. Okay. So, uh let's move
that here. So, that's that's like what
we were talking about today.
Um showing browser. So, this is this
page is today's talk show notes. Okay.
Those are links we talk we were talking
about. So, this is like what we were
doing right now. So, let's ask Guac
AI help me. I don't know anything. I'm a
zoomer.
[laughter]
From a geometric point of view, tangent
is the heart of calculus. Is this
statement valid?
Okay. Uh, let's magnify. Control
magnify. Let's see.
Okay.
Yes, the statement is quite valid
especially when viewed from a geometric
historical motivational perspective.
Okay. The concept of the tangent line
really is one of the deepest
deepest conceptual heart if not the
heart of calculus. You see particularly
in the way calculus was originally
discovered invented.
Amazing. Such a deep statement, you
know, such a deep observation.
Here are the main reasons why this view
is widely shared among mathematicians
and good teachers.
He say he says I'm a good teacher. Great
historical engine. The tangent problem
was one of the two birth places of
calculus. Oh, tangent problem.
uh given an arbitrary curve, how do you
define and find the tangent line at any
point? Okay. Okay. Anyway, it's so you
know you guys can read about this later
because we going to do some you know we
got more things to do but or you can ask
AI yourself but that proves my point.
Okay. So anyway, so what what is the
reason that let let's just go over
historical arrangement the tangent
problem was one of the first what was
one of the two birth places of calculus.
Okay, it says the derivative is
literally defined via tangent. That's
right.
You know geometry you have the tangent
but but if you do like algebra you know
that's basically that means uh
derivative. Okay, we we I talked about
before like uh 20 minutes ago. So local
linear approximation the most important
idea in all of differential calculus.
That's right. That's a tangent contrast
with integral calculus. Well, okay.
integral calculus you got the kind of
the area um notion like inf inf infinite
sum but they are related they are tied
together by the fundamental theorem of
calculus okay so let's see what it says
contrast with integral calculus uh I
dare you to ask I am what what is I am a
zoomer am [laughter] I a zoomer
Hello. Hello ACP.
So then then okay contrast with integral
calculus while the fundamental theorem
of calculus links differential
differentiation and integration the
geometric heart of integration is
usually considered to be the area under
the curve. Okay. So this um so you could
say you know so so they are talking
about the
you see normally calculus you can you
can separate it into like differential
uh diff derivative or differentiation
aspect versus the integration or
infinite sum aspect.
You see, so one one of them one part of
calculus you call it um
derivative you call it uh
you know you you call differential
calculus. The other part you call it
integral calculus you know like usually
you can classify calculus you can
separate calculus into like these two
branches but but that's shallow view but
you like usually in advanced calculus
you don't do that they are together
because they are tied together by the by
the fundamental theorem of the calculus
that's one of the most um fascinating
subject you
Like when when when you study
mathematics like sometimes you can when
you learn some theorem it sends chills
down your spine
for some certain people for me for
example
that's that's when you are extremely
obsessed about the topic because then
then you learn something that's just
amazing that's just incredible.
So one of the first you know so in my in
my life I have experienced a few of them
okay one of them is fundamental the
theorem of calculus okay that's amazing
so that's a amazing trip in mathematics
so I'm telling you guys you know so you
might get inspiration you might you know
you can see how I find this mathematics
So amazing, so fascinating. So you can
see um fascinating you know this
fundamental theorem of calculus
but I'm not going to tell you what that
is because then you it's like you know
then you you need you need to study
calculus okay so I give you some
motivation
um you know any and you know so but
because we you know we are doing
something else we got to code we got to
do code and
So you can you know there's a lot other
channels videos you can watch and
professors
you can go learn about calculus in
detail. Okay. But I'm I'm you know we
are doing um we are doing something a
different topic. Okay. copy the link and
go back to the talk show
and post. Uh, so let's remove that. Uh,
wait, remove that.
Okay, that's my question. And Gu
answers, yes, I'm correct what Gu says.
Fantastic. Okay.
Okay. So we talked about uh we we talked
we you know we kind of random went over
about or like the like basics of of of
playing curves okay tangent normals okay
let's go quickly so you know we
I'm just actually just beginning like
I'm trying to give you a introduction of
some of the
the plank things like why why are we
doing this but we even we haven't begin
to talk about what I wanted to do today.
Uh yeah. So you see you got quite a lot
to go. Even we only talked about
tangents.
Okay. Then we talked about normals. Then
we talked about seeant. Seeant is just
like any two points on the curve given
given then you can connect a line
between them. That line is called seeant
for you know between that two points on
the curve. Okay. So seeant is not very
significant. Okay, the sign significance
is is the tangent that like we what we
just talked about. That's that's like
the the the heart of calculus. Okay,
that's very significant. What about
normal? Well, normal is just just per
perpendicular to the tangent. Okay, so
normal is is basically like tangent.
Okay. So like is like another view you
know. So basically normal is just
tangent
I mean like tangent. Okay. So seeant
doesn't mean much. Seeant just you know
you you can generate pretty pictures.
Okay. For example this curve this this
this this
curve by the way is one of the
fascinating uh curve. uh it's called um
logarithmic spiral but a better name
would be equal angular spiral. It's also
known as equal angular spiral because
when you draw a angle from the center of
the spiral it hits the curve for any
point on a curve the angle is the same.
Okay? It doesn't matter where where you
know if you draw a line array point you
know when it intersects a curve doesn't
matter which line it always the angle is
the same. It's called equal angular
spiral. Okay. Uh of course it's also on
on my website uh visual dictionary of
special plane curves. Okay. You go
there,
you go to
spirals. Okay. So there this this one
equal angular spiral. And the
mathematician Jacob
says
he says
when I die I want this curve inscribed
on my tome.
Okay. This guy, this guy uh James Jax
Boni, you know, one of the mathematician
family. So, so in 1600s
they lived. So, you can you can go to
Wikipedia, you can actually see the
home, but I don't think that's a um
original, but you know, people rebuild
it because it became very famous.
uh you know let's search it I talked
about this before like a few years ago
two years ago or so uh but let's show it
again so you see this is Latin
means
although changed I arise the same okay
so that's a
tomb or how do you pronounce it tomb on
this this mathematician's grave but I I
think that's um
you know they they they remade you know
they they they
uh remade this just just to sustain this
this quote because that's what he
wanted. But
uh but also very interesting is that you
see they actually made a mistake.
The guy the guy
drew a spiral that is not equal angular
spiral. Okay. So you see equal angular
spiral has this property. Any line you
draw from passing the center of the
spiral intersect with the spiral in
in in the same angle in in the the the
the value
of the angle made by the intersection is
the same regardless what what is your
orientation of the line. Okay, that
defines
this spiral. Okay, it that's when this
spiral is called equal angular spiral
also known as logarithmic spiral because
the formula is a log logarithm. Okay.
uh somewhere okay you can you can you
know exponential
it's a log logarithmic spiral okay
somehow I don't have the formula here
annoying I need to I should add it
because because it's well known as a
logarithmic spiral in fact logarithmic
spiral is the name I believe more
popular than equal angular equal angular
spiral is a better name because it
describe the definition the definitive
name for this spiral it it tamount it
it's equivalent to the definition of the
spiral okay when you say logarithmic
spiral well that's because the formula
turns out is a logarithm because um if
you um
but that's not that's not a good name
okay
anyway so that's a definition of of this
spiral equal angular. Okay. So you can
see the property illustrated here. You
see any line passing the center
intersect the curve
at the same angle.
Okay. So this spiral is actually a
family of spiral. It's not like a it's
not a single specific one. There's like
a bunch of them defined by the angle. So
given an given an angle less than 90°
you got one equal angular spiral. Okay
that's a definition.
Now there are other spirals that's not
like that. So for example this
Archimedian spiral is not like that.
Okay, it you know you draw a line
passing the center it intersect the
curve depends on you know
you know the intersection have different
angles depending on how
you know your orientation of the line
okay so
so for this curve that's you know it's
not equal angular okay it has other
other properties okay other properties
that's why this is called archdium
spiral. But
but but the graveyard, you know, the
carpenter or whatever, he doesn't know
about the mathematics. So he drew an
Archimedian spiral on the grave. So
that's that's funny.
So you can read. So we talked, you know,
I talked about this like two years ago.
I told told this story. So you can go to
Wikipedia.
Uh this is Latin Adam motata
vircle something like that. So you can
you know you can see interesting uh
because it's a
it's interesting
mathematical
fact. Okay. So um
uh so anyway so that's that's a that's
the uh that's a guy Jacob Bernoli
one of the uh one of the great you know
uh mathematician okay
so Wikipedia of course Wikipedia has an
article on that Wikipedia got all sort
of articles okay there it is log read
you see they call logarithmic spiral but
it's better it's it's better the better
name would be equal angular spiral
because that name defines the spiral
that's a property of it okay so there it
is so you can see the logarithm
um
formula in Wikipedia uh do they do they
show it like the the formula would be um
there okay they you
>> [laughter]
>> that or that you see that's a
exponential
formula involving exponent
and here it you know you you rewrite it
so you become you got the logarithm
natural logarithm okay so that's why I
didn't include the formula I mean I have
the formula here so let's see where is
it archimemed not aramedian so we want
equal angular So equal angular. So you
go formula section
uh formula. So you got you see you got
the exponent
E is the E is the
uh
the special constant that
how do they call that constant? Was that
called Olo's constant? you know, it's
like
anyway, so
I, you know, m, you know, maybe you guys
get the idea. Okay, so anyway, I I I
think I kind of just rambled for an
hour.
Is it 50 minutes? Not an hour yet. But
we didn't get to do what we I wanted to
do. Oiler.
Okay. Is that is that called oilless
number uh oiler constant
oilers constant? Okay. Defined because
it could be no oil constant means
something else. You see it's a bit
tricky. You see oiler constant means
something else. Um
let's go there. You see oilers constant
means this oiler maceroni constant which
is 0.5 something that which is not the
other the the one we are looking we are
thinking of is the other I think
Wikipedia will mention it to avoid
confusion the one we are looking at is
called um
let's see
you know if you click on that not
logarithm
there you know the base e uh you'll get
to it
okay yeah so there it is
number okay so the number e is a
mathematical constant approximately
equal to 2.718
something that is the base of the
natural logarithm
and exponential function. It is
sometimes called Oiler's number. You
see, by the way, that's called Oiler. I
think that's pronounced Oiler. The guy's
name, Swiss mathematician, Leonard
Oiler,
but usually I like to pronounce it Ula
because that's how English pronounce it,
ula. Anyway, I think it's oiler
something.
But but anyway, you can see that
uh you can see that
you see this this this number
mathematical constant e is uh my wife is
back. I I should go to dinner soon. But
you can see that this this this
you see they they they don't have
actually they don't they don't have a
name. They should have you know but we
don't actually have a name for this
number. We we usually just say e you
know the you know the base of natural
logarithm
sometimes we say oilless number oilless
number but it's different from
it's different from this um
oilless constant you see this oilless
constant is equals to 0
uh five something you see very confusing
very confusing
Okay, I think you know my wife is back.
So, let me say hi to her.
Sweet family.
[laughter] You know, when you have a
wife, everything is good. Provided that
you have a good wife. You know, in
America society,
you get a girl, you got a wife, you
and you got you get divorce. you
got [laughter]
in America society, you got lots of
problems
um due to the huge amount of corruption
in the past like 20 or 30 years. Okay,
hold on a second. Let me say hi to my
wife
and we get we'll be back. Um,
Hold on a second.
Be right back.
Hello guys, I'm back.
Welcome back to the live streaming
stuff.
So, I'm having red wine.
My red wine is we are the red wine.
So So
this is the last struggle of the red
wine.
Okay,
we need to go by
so we were talking about the number
versus constant very confusing
actually I don't know what is the
constant I know it because of the uni
code uh because there's a unic code for
that for for this constant. It looks
like um anyway anyway so let's not go
over there. So but
but you see it's different from
this e so
number okay so like there is no I guess
the best name is just number but very
confusing with the constant okay
so you see Wikipedia title they even you
know they don't name it number they
actually the Wikipedia title is like
yeah the mathematical constant but they
named you know here they say's number
but
was it or something like that
so anyway this this number is
significant okay especially in calculus
because it um is sign significant
Okay. So we we talked about like we were
going over we were just going over
curves. Yeah. So we were talking about
this this uh logarithmic spiral equal
angular spiral
and we mentioned this mathematician you
know who has this on the grave and the
grave engraver got it wrong. You know
they got aimed spiral. [laughter]
quite funny. Okay,
but anyway, so
but why are we talking about the spiral?
That's because
Oh yeah. That's because of from this
illustration we happened to use seeant
to to draw pretty pictures of this
equal angular spiral. Okay. So that's
why we started to mention this this uh
jackup boni and logarithmic spiral you
know stuff.
Uh okay. So you see so
basically today we are actually just
going over my plane curve
uh package wam language package. You can
download it here and showing you the
example illustrations feature gallery.
And I was just going through them and
doing explanations on why they are
interesting. Okay, like these are the
fundamental
interesting concepts in analytic
geometry
with respect to calculus. Okay.
Uh so we talked about tangents, normals
and normals and seeants. Okay. an equal
angular spiral. And this is uh this star
shaped thing that's a hypotcoid
which means you roll a circle on another
circle inside another circle. We talked
about like yesterday many times uh in
the past week several videos [snorts]
and this you know just just generates
pretty pictures. Okay. and uh and uh uh
hypotrocoid. Okay. So also known as
spyroraph.
Okay. Then there's optical properties
like we talked about costics. Okay. Uh
of parabola parabola the most well known
uh for example we can see it in
flashlight
uh you know this par parabolic mirror.
Okay. Then then you know there are
several okay so optical properties uh of
ellipses uh you know have you guys seen
the elliptical
pool table
that's um
you know if you guys know interested in
mathematics you have seen this because
this is the most like interesting thing.
So, it's a poor table, but it's a
elliptical shape, you know, but if you
don't know mathematics, you you this you
probably never seen this before, but I'm
showing you for the first time. So, you
see, you got a pool table. You know, a
lot of people are interested in this.
But, but you if the table is shaped like
a ellipse, then you got properties such
that they reflect
from one point it will bounce off the
table to the other point. Those points
are called focal of the ellipse. Okay,
very interesting things. So there's a
lot pictures and people have buil
elliptical pool tables. Uh okay, so th
those are you know this for you nerds.
Anyway, so [sighs]
you know, it's like a common topic
talked about for
uh like 50 years or more. So anyway,
where am I? Where was I? So I'm kind of
I'm now right now 20% drunk.
So that means we're going to stop. Okay.
So So
as far as this package goes, this you
know so we we can talk about um costics.
One feature of the package is to draw
costics. So you can see costic length to
allow you to visualize
optical properties. So for example this
one we used in our thumbnail kind of
similar to that
then you can also draw osculating
circles. Now osculating circle is the
most interesting. Osculate means kiss.
Okay in Latin I believe
um
osculate means kiss in Latin. Osculate
is a versatile verb with meaning
spanning affection, biology and
mathematics. Okay. Affectionate
affection that kiss.
Osculate to mean kiss. Okay. So, but
what is origin? So
the word originates from Latin. Osculum
meaning little mouth or kiss. Okay. So
it from Latin but basically osculating
circle means that um where are we?
Okay that's osculating circle is like
tangent like the idea of tangent but
it's but it but it's a circle that is
the most fitting circle at that point on
the curve. So given a curve and given
any one point on the curve you have a
circle that kind of is the most
fitting
to that point. Okay. So that so for
example this point on this sign curve at
this point you got this circle. This
circle is called the osculating circle
at that point of this sign curve. Okay.
Now how is this curve defined? Basically
this circle I mean how is this circle
defined? The circle is basically the
most fitting circle that fits the point
which means basically the curvature
the concept of curvature.
Okay. So the curvature the concept of co
curvature means you know
which is very intuitive like if for
example here the curve is very more
tight then over here for example imagine
you are driving a car around this
ellipse. So over here when you pass you
don't you don't feel much you know sway
like but if you are driving at the same
speed when you pass over the major axis
then you feel like there's a like strong
sway sway right so that that's a concept
of curvature because at that point at
the major axis theure then then over
here
so you Guys, what see what I mean? So
that the concept of curvature is
captured by
this so-called osculating circle. Okay.
At any point on a curve, this is
fantastic concept. Um anyway, so then we
can draw the so ascaline circle also you
know you can just call it kissing
kissing circle. Okay, kissing circle of
a point on a curve. So you can draw that
for spirals and for um
for okay for cyclloid. Now this curve is
another fascinating property. You know
this curve is created when you draw a
circle on a line. So for example the
bicycle if you ride the bicycle at night
you know you attach a lead or reflector
on the wheel.
So as you ride along and and on look you
you'll see the light will trace out a
curve like that on the wheel. Okay on
the rim of the wheel. This curve is
called cyclloid. Okay that's called
cyclloid.
Why is this curve interesting? Because
th this curve happens to be the optimal
curve. If you want a ball
to fall down to roll down from one point
to another point on the ground, okay?
Like you can have a straight line or you
can have like a semiircle or you can
have however curve you want. If you want
the fastest curve according by gravity,
then the optimal path is this cyclloid.
Okay. And this cyclloid is defined by
rolling a circle on a line. Okay. So,
okay. So, uh so that's why
for example you can see an animation.
This this is why this visual dictionary
of special plane curves are so
interesting.
Uh that one cycle. Okay. So you can see
an animation there.
Okay. So why why is this interesting?
because that that is that's that's that
is the solution to the uh bracken
the problem called brackenome something.
Okay, that is the um like what what is
the path so that when you
face a marble it will fall down the
fastest. So if you search on the web
Wikipedia and you'll see lots of um
answers okay
cyclloid. So just search for the curve
cyclloid. Okay.
Uh and uh
okay that is the cyclloid curve and the
reason
we are talking about that is because you
know again this package can draw it. I
mean it can draw the evolute. Okay,
evolute is again is the um
locus of
kissing circles. Okay. So cyclloid which
is a curve traced out by rolling a
circle. Okay. It has a property such
that
such that the locus of its
of its kissing circles the center all
the centers of the kissing circles on
the curve is itself it's another
cyclloid okay you can see here so the
package just illustrate that okay so you
can type this and you'll show you draw
that anyway that's you know this is
called evolute
Uh anyway asteroid also has that
property. The evolute of asteroid is
itself. It creates another asteroid.
Asteroid. Okay. Anyway, so we started to
show you know we just talked about the
properties of this um you know so this
features of this package. Okay. So again
you can you can uh get it just go to
GitHub by search for wuam pack wam
language package packages by si and wuam
plank curve package you can get this
package it's on github okay
and we we basically today we
spend
70 minutes going over
um why this is interesting. So, let's
turn on JavaScript.
Okay, I think that's it for today. Uh,
actually,
uh, wait, don't I have any um,
wow, I didn't add any graphics.
What
did I did I not add any graphics?
Amazing. I didn't on the um
what I didn't uh interesting.
So, let's go to get
directory and uh
plank curve.
Let's go to plan curve
plur plot. So, here is the package. But
wow, I didn't include any uh images.
Amazing.
But I did include it on my website.
You see? Okay. So,
I got So, there's uh things to do there.
I need to update the GitHub.
Anyway, I think I'm like
20% drunk. Uh, and I don't
I need there's a lot coding I need to
do, but I don't feel like doing it right
now. So, this there's more to it. Okay.
So there's u as you know uh this cateic
optical properties there is the kissing
circles which creates evolutes
illustration
then there is there's more there is um
okay there's also radio which is very
much related to kissing circles okay I'm
not going to explain
because I'm kind of tired and drunk and
this neco
concoid of neomedes. Okay, that's
another
uh way to generate a curve. Okay, so
again it can be done by this package to
illustrate it.
Then there is conic inverse into lemicon
pascal
at their focus. Okay. So, oh there's
okay. So, there's inversion. So, you can
invert a curve with respect to a circle.
For example, this picture shows the
inversion of a parabola
with respect to the circle
centered at the vertex of the parabola.
Then you get these red dots. Okay,
that's a inversion.
of the parabola at the vertex of the
parabola what you get the red dots is
the seesoid of dacos
a variation curve like 2,00 or 3,000
years old so seesoid of dios uh what is
the property of the seisoid is this one
okay this curve I think it's a cubic
curve
what's the property I forgot okay But
you you but you can look up
let's see plank curves. So seesoid.
So you need to go to check uh seesoid.
Let's see Asian curve. Seesoid of diaos.
It's it's a curve created in 250 BC.
So about 2,000 years ago trying to solve
the um
trying to solve doubling the cube
problem. Okay. So anyway, so it looks
like that kind of like a ivory. That's
what seesoid means. Okay. So the name
seesoid means ivory, ivyshaped ivy,
which is a plant. Okay.
Anyway, so this curve is, you know, is
called seesoid of
diaos. you know, I'm not sure how to
pronounce the name Diaos, but anyway,
but anyway, this curve
is created 2,000 years ago. Okay? And
and what we are talking about is that
that parabola, the inversion of parabola
at the vertex of the parabola is a
cysoid of diagos. Very interesting.
Okay.
and uh inversion there's a lot of the
properties inversion of a hyperola um
lots of okay so we haven't
okay I'm not going to go over them
anyway so today we basically just went
over this package plank curve bot
package and why
why why it uh the features
why why why why it you know many of the
features does interesting illustrations
like fundamental to
curves geometry. Okay. Okay. That's it
for today.
Okay. Bye guys. Bye.