Hello, good morning beautiful. We are
going to code JavaScript today. Uh
technological demo. So make America
great again by coding, not by lawyering
and stuff. Okay. So if you are watching
this offline, play at 1.5 speed because
I ramble all over and skip around. If
you are here, say hi. Love to see your
comments. So can you see my screen?
Okay, JavaScript coding. So let me show
you what we're going to do. So you you
see this
um so um JavaScript coding. So this is
today's page.
Um let's open that file showing browser.
So this is a famous Disney movie, Let It
Go, Fantastic Song. So you can see I use
my mouse scroll wheel to show each image
frame by frame. I love this because I
love small slow motion so you can see
every details. Okay, so you can score
backward or forward. So let me just go
fast. Let's go to the beginning. Okay.
So, you know, you see
beautiful,
beautiful. She uh magically builds a
bridge, ice bridge, and walk across it
and builds a ice
palace.
Magic. It's amazing. You know, magic is
a fantasy. And this is such a power,
such a superpower. Imagine if you have
this power which is fictional of course
then she uh you know she now is free
becoming her own control of her destiny
and now she became this beautiful you
know throw away the formal clothing and
now swing swinging her hips. Oh my god,
that's so hot. And you see ice palace.
Beautiful. So you see, so what we do is
here we have a bunch of
images. So let's go. Uh so here's a
source code for the page. Can you see
it? Are you here? Say hi. Okay. So how
many people watching? Three. Okay.
Fantastic. So uh we So what we doing? So
um yeah so we so but so so this is the
page and if you go to the JavaScript
search
forjs you can see there's a JavaScript
open it so you can see here's a
JavaScript file in fact it is TypeScript
so let me delete the backup okay so you
can see better so you know here's a
TypeScript and it compiles to JavaScript
so let's open the TypeScript uh it's
pretty short so So it's
only 150 lines. Okay. So but most of it
is actually just you know a list. So you
got a list of image file path. Then you
got a uh image tag ID that is appears on
the page. So first of all we got this
image. So open it. So you can see this
image tag. Then below it you got two
buttons you know button left and
right. Okay. Then so showing browser. So
that's those. You can also click the
button to go to the next or previous or
use the arrow key, right
arrow, left arrow. So you know, so you
can go fast. The best is actually the
mouse scroll wheel. So because you can
go backward and forward easy. Fantastic.
So So those are the buttons. Then here's
the script, JavaScript. Then you open
it. It's a type script. Okay. So you got
the image tag which is the image tag ID
that tells the JavaScript this is the
image you want to change. Okay. Then you
got the left button uh ID and right
button ID. That's these you know two
IDs. So then you got a bunch of image
files. Then you have this F cycle image
function. So it takes two arguments. the
image path array of image file path then
image tag ID the the left button ID the
right button ID and that's it and this
is a function so here's a function
body it basically the function body just
set up the uh event handlers so that you
can click on the button it will change
the image backward or previous Or it
also sets up the keystroke event
handler. So when you press the right
arrow, it go forward. When you press the
uh left arrow, it goes backward. Okay?
Or the mouse wheel. Fantastic. You see
her transformation.
Beautiful. And so it sets up. So so so
um so let's go back here. So here is the
body of the function. Now go to the
bottom then you just call the function
you pass the image file
path the image tag ID the left button ID
right button ID uh which are defined
here so that's all you need these three
variables are came from the browser you
know this so that is how it works okay
so let's go let's explain how it
actually works so you you see you got
this function cycle image
Then you got um say hi. Okay, type
whatever. Then you uh so what what it
does is that when this function is
called, it sets up the it gets the image
um element. Okay, which is this one.
Okay, the image element. Get uh get
element by ID then set uh sets up the
index for the current image which is
starting with zero. Okay, then this part
preload the images you know the P image
path that's the
uh that is uh array. Okay, so my naming
convention variables starting with P
means they are parameters from a
function. So image path for each one you
you
basically preload the image. Um
yeah so that's how you do it. Okay. So
then you uh declare a inner function
switch to next image. So it's a arrow
function and the body will do uh let's
see constant next next image index
equals through current plus one and
modular arithmetics divided by the
length of image. So if it scrolls past
if you go to the end you press right
arrow go to the end then it start from
the beginning again. So you see go to
the end it start beginning. So it it's
like um cyclic a ring makes the array a
ring. So so the index cycles by modular
arithmetics which is just the remainder
gets a remainder of of the current index
divided by the length. Okay. Then you
set the attribute set the image tax
source attribute to the
uh to the file path of the current
index. Okay. Then you uh set the current
index to be the next. Okay. So let's
highlight that. Okay. That's switch to
next image. Then same thing with switch
to previous image. In this case you just
minus one. Okay. So you see length minus
one.
Okay. Then you then you add the keyboard
event handler. So, so this is a
function. So when the key down event key
code called 39 which is right arrow when
that
happens you call switch to next image.
Okay. Same thing with previous image for
left
arrow. Okay. So that's
keyboard key event handler. Okay. So now
where is that called? Let's
see. Yeah, you have to set up later
later. But let's see. But let's continue
to mouse event
handler. So similarly um that's for
uh let's see pre uh prevent default. So
that prevent default means when you do
normally when you scroll the mouse wheel
it will it will scroll the window. So
but you want to stop that. So that's why
the prevent default. Okay. So del if
deltay so x is the mouse scroll event
and deltay is how much it changes
change. So if it's positive you go to
the next image. If it's negative you go
to the previous image. Okay. Then you
get
um uh document get element by id get the
left button get the right button add
event event listener. So when it clicks
you switch to the next image. Similarly
for the left button. Okay. So those
these are event these are actually
adding adding event handlers. Okay. Then
on the image you also add a event
handler mouse wheel. So when mass wheel
is fired you call mask wheel event
handler. Okay. Then then you add a key
down
uh event. So when when the left key or
right uh left arrow or right arrow is
pressed you you call keyboard handler.
Okay that's how it works. Then finally
you just call it. Okay. So close that
show in browser again. Fantastic. Now
what I want to do so so now you see this
JavaScript file is kind of integrated
with this page. Uh so what you need is
this block. So on each HTML web page if
you want to have this functionality what
you have to do is you have
to you know create a image with the ID
image ID and button ID left right and
then you link to the
JavaScript but the thing is they are
integrated. So this file or this
JavaScript file cannot be used on other
any other page because on another page
then the image ID is different the left
button right button ID may be different
or the image path a list of them may be
different so you have to so you see so
this JavaScript is integrated to this
page what I want to do is let's make it
as a standalone library so any page
page. If you want a kind of this slight
feature of a bunch of images, you can
just load this library and load another
JavaScript function just to call it. So,
so it becomes modularized. So, that's
what we want to do. Okay. So, that's
what we want to do. So, make a back up
this page. So, let's see what we want to
do. Okay. So um we want to yeah modular
you know make it not
integrated. Do we have uh JavaScript
coders webdev here web monkeys say say
something. Okay so that's what we want
to do. Uh we know that already. So music
closed. So this is today's talk show.
Let's start to clean up. So we want to
begin to code
this modularize. Okay.
So, so how do we do it? Okay. First of
all, go to the uh directory, remove the
backup. And
now make a backup for each one of
them. Okay. And now we want to
modularize it. Okay. So, so first of
all, so you know we need to keep coding
in live stream uh cannot
think. So why don't we make it so that
so you got list of image file path.
Okay. So why don't we make it
um we need to create um yeah okay let's
create um a separate new file. Okay
let's not use that
file. So this file and the typescript we
need. Now let's just make a backup of
them. Remove the selection. And now
let's just start to rename this
file. Uh
wait,
refresh. Refresh. Okay. Um Okay.
Refresh. Now rename this file
to XX. So that's how you know we're
going to create a test file just for
today's
purposes. XX. Okay, refresh. So now open
that show in browser. So we got um it.
So let's rename everything
um JavaScript image slide test. Okay,
rename that that file show in browser
and remove the anything redundant. Okay.
So, let's remove. So, we going to
um video thumbnail. That's Disney.
Fantastic. Beautiful. Delete. Delete.
Delete. Okay. So, actually I have
there's also Chinese version of that
song. Uh they have that song in in like
20 languages. People have done it. It's
beautiful. So, delete that. Yeah. Delete
that. Delete that. Delete that. delete
that songs and humanity. Okay, it's also
remove that panel and the subfooter
remove uh literature annotate highlight
link remove show in browser. So now it's
simple. Okay. And then the JavaScript
file, this needs to be changed to
xx. Okay. Show in browser. Does it still
work? No, it broke.
Uh, you see it doesn't work. So, we
broke something. Oh, yeah. There's no
JavaScript. So, open it. It's empty. Uh,
but we got a
Typescript.XX dot TypeScript. Okay. So,
open
that. Uh, open that and compile it. So,
that would be tab
C. Fantastic. Now go to the buffer uh go
to the directory. So there is the
typescript I mean there is a javascript
compile. Now close close show in
browser. Now it works.
Beautiful. Okay. So now we going to like
start. Let's remove the button. Okay.
Remove the button. Remove the button. Uh
remove this
text. And uh so the whole text the whole
file remove that. Let's remove all
redundant things. Okay.
Uh Okay. Show in browser. That's that's
that's that's Oh, there it is. Okay. Uh
now it doesn't work anymore. Uh
wait. Oh, it doesn't work. You see here
is the problem because we removed the
buttons. Now shift control I to see the
console log.
Now the show the console log and uh
click on that
um arrow
uh
wait
debugger console log the error should
show okay but it's not showing so let's
open the
typescript okay so Now the left button
is
that. Okay. The left button is
that. Now let's this image file path.
Let's com compress it into one. And
actually there's too many. So let's not
let's reduce some of them. Okay. So um
now the left button
here you see this is where it's going to
error out because you cannot get element
by ID. It's um not found. So compile the
file. Okay. Close it. Show in browser.
Now shift control I to see the
um you know why why is it not printing
the
error. Okay so error one oh you need to
click arrow so there it is uncaught type
error document getelement by ID is new.
So it cannot get the buttons because we
deleted the
buttons. So open that and so this button
ID that doesn't
work. Okay. So now but let's comment out
the button ID. Okay. So these two button
ID comment
out and uh let's search for if it's
occur somewhere. So button ID it just
occur there once button ID occur there
and uh yeah so now compile it show the
ping window the ping window shows all my
command calls the command name and the
keystrokes so I'm
using keys and kas javascript mod you
can see
so so you can see I got this uh kasan
javascript script typescript compile
file. So you go to the source code
JavaScript mod and you can see this is
emac bisp. This compiles JavaScript
typescript to JavaScript using Deno.
Okay. So you can get this command if you
want it uh you know so it allows you to
compile TypeScript to JavaScript. It's
right here. Okay. Just go and grab the
code. So for you Emacs, Emacs users.
Fantastic. Okay. So, close
that. Close that. Close that. Or you can
actually you can pay me to get my
um my JavaScript type script mod. Okay.
But for now, let's put the link here.
Show today's talk show. There it
is. Okay. Now, go back to the uh Disney.
Okay. Go back to the um so go back to
close that. Go back to our test
page now. Yeah, now the button is gone.
You see now it works.
Fantastic. Let's remove some images.
Let's uh let's just
keep Okay. So go back to the JavaScript
file and for the images let's say remove
more. Okay. Uh now compile
it.
Refresh. Fantastic. Begin there.
Okay. Uh you know so wait. So
33. So, it's still got a lot of images.
Okay.
71. Okay. Let's remove um
more. So, now you just got like 10
images.
Okay. Compare it. Close it. Show in
browser. Fantastic. Okay. So, just few
images backward. Forward. forward,
backward.
Fantastic.
Now, now you see we don't want we want
to modul modularize
this this uh uh function.
So, so, so this this file JavaScript
file is going to be a library. So, in
the library, you don't hardcode these
things. So, these things needs to move.
So you're going to um so let's see how
we going to uh design this. Okay. So
basically this tag ID and and the images
they're going to move because they are
specific to a particular file. So
actually cut it
out. Remove the copyright. Save it. Make
a
backup. Close. And now in this place we
we kind of insert them there. Okay. So
what we need to do is
um how do you do that? Okay.
So so you need some kind of so okay so
this function let's open this function.
Now the function is just that
um it needs to get this ID. So this
function we it we don't even need button
left ID and button right id. Okay. So
let's see search. Yeah, we don't need
it. So delete it. Make it simpler.
Remove those two parameters we need. So
this is the image file path list of file
path. Then
um then we have the image ID tag.
Okay. Okay. So this function ends here
and uh calling the function also remove.
So this function
becomes you know a module just a
function. So save
it, compile it, close it. So now this is
calling the function. So this needs to
be in a separate JavaScript file. So
let's do
that. Copy that. So let's say uh xx pre
something just a random name. Okay. So
then cut this out.
Open the
pre and paste it there. Okay. Save it.
Make a backup. Go to the directory.
Refresh. Now rename this to
TypeScript.
Okay. Okay. Done. Open the TypeScript.
Okay. So, so that we can work in
Typescript. that allows us to have uh
type checking which is uh critical.
So we got So we got um so let's
see we need to make this close
that close that. So we got two so
um so first so first of all we need to
load the library. So xx is the
library that provide us this cycle image
function. Okay. Uh so compile it.
Reformat it. All looks good. Close it.
Okay. Then we call the function. Okay.
So So when we call the function actually
we don't so we just we don't need these
variable names. Okay. So let's
see. We you know so there's a lot uh
there's a art about making a module. you
you want
it as independent as possible and you
want it to be as easy to use as
possible. So the scenario is that for
for any HTML file if you want to have
this
function all you need to do is the load
the library but you also need to
specify you you need to
specify which image tag you want it to
you know go over and you also need to
specify a list of image file path. Okay.
So, so one thing is this list of image
file path you need to
specify. Uh so how do we so actually so
why don't we just cut um you know um we
can actually
uh so left button you don't need you
know the left button and right button
can be generated and inserted by the by
the JavaScript code.
So further simplify this function. You
don't need the left and right button.
Okay? All you need is a image ID that
specifies which image tag you want this
slide to
go and you need a list of images.
Okay.
So how do you design? So
actually yeah. So this is all we need
for now. Okay. to make this work. And we
can cut the whole thing, add a uh add a
uh curly braces and paste it inside and
predify the code. This
way, this way all these variables
becomes local to this file, which is
great when you have lots of JavaScript
files. Okay, so now this is great and in
fact we don't even need these two
variables because they are only used
once. We can put it
here. So and another thing we should
change is the ID should come before the
file path. Okay. Yeah, image ID should
come before file path. So we need to
change that function a little bit. Okay.
Now compile this code. Fantastic. Done.
uh close it and open this library. And
we need to fix a few things because
remember we switched the
parameters. Okay, make one line and uh
pify the code. Uh pify failed. Uh
let's pify the code. Okay. So now if
cycle image takes two arguments id and
image file path fantastic and the bo and
the body is just
um just that okay so let's uh let's
see
uh you know when you purify I'm using
deno deno is the best
javascript compiler okay I recommend
deno better than nodejs or whatever Deno
can compile out TypeScript and can
format code. For example, make this one
one line. Then you press a key, it
become all pretty formatted. So you
never have to manually like ditto with
each line like the typical Python coders
or C or
C++. So that's a pass because of the
Goland created this concept. You know,
press a key, it preformat the entire
code. So deno okay I recommend deno. So
now this function takes two arguments uh
that and uh that okay then uh preload
images and
uh create a inner function switch to
next switch to previous and keyboard
handler and mouse wheel handler. Then
they then it creates the
um event add the event handler to to
mouse wheel and to key down.
Okay. So that is the function. So by
compile it again I mean compile it
again. Okay.
Successful.
Um let's see what else we need to be
careful to be sure. Okay. So it looks
all good. So image tag ID is the
first parameter then the file path.
Okay, at least the file path. Okay,
that's seems good.
Close and double check this one. So this
one you just basically just call that
function. Okay, so compile it just to
make sure. Okay, done. Close. is now
showing
browser. Does it work? Yes. Fantastic.
Beautiful now. Okay. So, actually that's
that's what we need to do. So, this one
this xx will be renamed the library. You
know, name it cycle image or image slide
library. Then in any page you can just
load it. Then below that you just
specify you know what are the image tag
and image file path. I think that's
it. Okay. Fantastic. Now uh so why don't
we now grab the code and
uh grab the code close it and put in our
talk show. Okay. So so we can see the
code.
Um, okay. So, new JavaScript code. Uh,
wait, new TypeScript code. Yeah, paste
it there. And add another TypeScript.
Then you need to paste the content of
this file. I'll
close there. Okay. Show in browser.
There it is. Our code for today.
Fantastic. a
module of of JavaScript to do image
slide and press a key to syntax color.
Okay, now show in browser. So fantastic
and
beautiful. Okay, I think that's it. Now
there's extra things we can do now
because remember if we go back to the
original file
uh what is this byes compile so refresh
you see it got this left and right
button you can click now that is
important because that gives user it
tells user there's this feature going on
so you user can press right arrow or
left arrow or mouse wheel without this
button or without this text people don't
know. So in our case you know refresh
people don't know there is you know you
can score the wheel and stuff. So you
need to add that. So no so and and the
button is also important because on some
devices you don't have mouse wheel such
as
touchpad and on some devices you don't
have arrow keys. So you you want these
graphical user interface buttons there
too. Uh so can you see me? So you can
see me you know I can you know I can you
know click click you cannot see my
mouse. I mean you cannot see my pressing
the button but anyway. So this buttons
is important for as a indicator of
graphical user interface and this text
is important because it tells user
there's this feature going
on. So we can we uh we need to add that.
Yes, we need to add that show it. So we
need to add that in this library code so
that they automatically generate
uh you know generate this this this this
button and text. Okay, that's one
thing. The other thing is that you know
why is this feature great? because I can
show you, you know, we did this
yesterday uh two days ago
about about Wuam language generating
animations for these beautiful
spyroraph
pictures. Okay, so you can see. So why
do I want
um you know why why do I want this mouse
wheel um animation? Because if you go
here because you if you go here for for
example apple truck or it you see this
animation right now it's GIF so it's
static there is no interactive
control you know for for these cases the
the animation is pretty simple but when
when you look at complicated cases such
as this
on you know you want to be able to pause
right now you cannot you know this is
skip you want to pause it sometimes you
want to go back because you want to you
know especially for mathematics
sometimes is 3D image you want to see
exactly how it transforms okay but right
now this is a
GIF you cannot do that okay so the
alternative for example these are GIF
Uh this is also a
gift. Uh
so and this this one is more
complicated. Spectacular you
see. So another solution is you use a
you generate a meg 4 movie file.
So now once you have MPE 4 you can have
you know you can drag the slider and see
how they transform like frame by frame
if you want. Okay but the problem with
with both of them is that they they
create huge files huge file size. For
example open this page showing browser
you see go back here then go to this uh
search for MP4. So there is the collidal
glass collo kaleido glass which is this
one. Play
it. So this is MP4. You can drag back
and forth. But however you look at the
file, open
it. Go to
directory. This uh and show this is 4
megabyte. It easily become 20 megabyte
or more. you know when when when you
know when you have 3D or
whatever.
So a good solution for these line
graphics is that you turn each one each
frame into a SVG
image. Uh actually I can show you uh I
can show you by going to I you know
because I I was trying to do it. Okay.
So these are SVG images. Each one is
only 28 kilobytes. So open it. You can
you can see and show next. You can see
in Emacs I can do that. You can next
next. I'm using my mouse uh my mouse
wheel. Can you see this this thumb?
Okay. You can see right there. Next,
next. Okay. I can go to previous, next.
I can control the speed like go to the
previous fast or next next. So you can
you can go back and forth. So that's
fantastic. Or you can show it in a
dedicated
um Oh wait, I I started to launch the
SVG Inkscape view I
think. Anyway,
so so this SVG each frame you see I
started the Inkscape is start
slowly. Okay. So I don't want that. So,
so the point is that this these are SVG
files and you can look at the source
code uh by turning for example show use
HTML mod okay so this is what SVG files
look like SVG are basically XML okay so
uh so if you don't know SVG I have a
practical SVG tutorial and here you can
see how to write a clock and the source
code is just this like 20 30 lines of
code actually you can you can make it
like five lines by using animation
features in anyway but anyway basically
it's you know
SVG SVG basics they are just simply XML
tags okay so for example this this this
block create that line and and this
block create that rectangle. So SVG is
very short and they are scalable. That
means you can enlarge the graphics and
without losing res
resolution.
Fantastic. Okay. Practical SVG tutorial.
Go to the talk show. Go to today's talk
show. Let's add it there. Okay. So let's
actually add it there. show so you can
go to it later
on. Okay. So, SVG so so we want um so
document. So you see we got these SVG
files. Open it. Show us as XML. So this
SVG you know they are small.
Then you use the same
technique as that as this JavaScript
image slide. Then you can
control you know then you can control
use the mouse wheel or uh wait close it.
Okay. Hope you open it. You know you can
control backward or forward you know or
fast forward like this you know. So this
this kind of
control is very critical when you need
to watch something in detail and in slow
motion. And in fact there's a dedicated
device for it. Okay. So let me show you.
So uh keyboard blog just go
to.info my website keyboard blog and you
search for
uh joystick
and joystick and special input devices.
You go to knobs and wheels. Okay, there
it is. This device is specifically
designed for this. It's called um
shuttle, you know, shuttle wheel and
jock wheel. Shuttle ring and jock wheel.
So let they you know they let you
control when you when you want to watch
a
animation like forward and backward in
precision. Okay. So just like just like
the way we have it here.
So you see so I mean so this is actually
a thing industrial you know thing you
can buy these devices. Okay. So where is
it? Yeah. So let me copy that. So you
guys can go there and buy it.
Okay. So mouse wheel is kind of
emulation. I mean mouse wheel is can do
this but you know it's it's better if
you actually have a big wheel. if you do
going to do this professionally video
editing and
stuff. Okay. So, uh or you know there's
speed cameras you know you know
especially like when you um you want to
video insect flight you know like beles
you know their wings or or or bees you
want to record their for scientific
purposes you want to study how their
wings shape and so on. So, so you you
need you kind of need this and that's
why we are doing this. That's why I want
I really want this. I don't want you
know I don't want the meg 4 you know the
meg 4 is huge file size and you cannot
control well you know can you use
backward forward arrow
no you know so that's what this today's
talk show is about is this about this
okay so show uh close that close that
close that close that paste that link
linkify showing
browser there jock wheel and shuttle
ring. Okay, I think that's it for today.
You know, we can, you know, so we can
continue to add
um to, you know, to modify our code so
that we add the
buttons, you know, we add this um you
know, this button and this
text. But uh I think maybe I'll just do
it offline because it's 46 minutes. If
we add that it takes like five minutes
or 10 because then if I explain but
let's keep the video short because I
notice shorter video is better. Okay.
Really smart high style. I think that's
it for
today. Is it good? So if you like it
spread it, okay? like repost repost my
video on Twitter or on your blog
because because I don't do any marketing
you know like I don't say you know like
please thumb up this video like the
entire Google scam and then you have
today's you know zuma generation let's
add some clickbait let's say you know
instead of you know s talk show uh
JavaScript coding interactive like you
know JavaScript code you've never seen
before then then then the viewership it
will increase a lot actually like when I
have a video saying you you know the
crime of Unix oh my god then that video
is like 10,000
views yeah but I don't I don't want to
do that you know that's the that's that
that is
why you know today in USA you got the
collapse of USA then you got the bunch
of zumas Zuma idiot, you know, they just
like, you know, they do clips and
anyway, so if you enjoy my
show, tell your friends, post on your
Twitter or whatever and pay me, okay?
info. Go to the
bottom then Patreon me, Amazon gift card
me, PayPal me, or you can get my entire
website for
$300 about 6,000 files, about three
gigabytes of information on mathematics,
on programming languages, on hacker
culture, um programming languages. Okay,
that's it for today. Thank you guys.
You will not believe how JavaScript
um how JavaScript handles this
interactive slide for image. Yeah,
that's
right. And then I need to put a photo of
myself like
like the Zumas, the entire
corrupt USA deep state.
Okay, thank you guys for watching. Bye
guys. You know like like the classic one
who you know like like they are
everywhere. You know, if you go to
YouTube,
um, you know, let's go to
YouTube. You know, let's Venus tech
tips. You know, this guy, this this this
is a, you know, this schmuck. This is
what you call a jerbo. You know, squeak
squeakling
jerbo. Video. Oh, video games. This
super graphics card. Oh. Oh, China
something. Oh, buy 100 trillion
something. The face. You see this
face. They become rich. You know,
this is what deep state want you to do.
You know, rot your brain, you know.
Let's make Google be. Why is Google
promoting? I mean, you know, all this
crap, you know, this these shorts like
brainless shorts. You just click and
watch. They go one by one, you know,
like occupy, you know, they want to you
become addicted watching these brainless
Why Google promote it? Because
they make money. They know drama makes
people click and you know they they you
know the the most brandless things make
more money so they promote it. So Google
makes a lot of money and and whoever is
following Google the Zuma idiots, you
know, like they make a lot of money. So
this guy becomes now a
multi-millionaire, but he's he's a good
guy. Okay, he's not, you know, he's a
good
guy. The lin le linus tech tips. He's a
good guy. But but my point is, you see
the the
rot, you know, the rotting of American,
that's that's what happening, you
know, brainlessness.
Okay, bye
guys. Closing down in 30
seconds. Last sip of
tea. This is a longing tea. Dragon's
whale.