Good morning.
Welcome to another episode of
Kan Talk Show.
We are going to code JavaScript.
Fantastic and amazing and mainstream.
Okay. So, let me show my screen. If you
are here, say hi. Love to see your
comments. Pop this out. chat chat box
for people's for the mouth of human
animals
and here is my discord hello Andy and uh
so we're going to talk about webdev yeah
so basically webdev so programming blog
origin of unix bin spin slash user/bin
slash user local bing
history of why Unix the sucks. The
history of the Unix idiocy. Okay, that's
a new article. Anyway, so today we're
going to talk about JavaScript. Okay, so
that gives you a glimpse of what this
video style is about. So you if you find
that crazy, maybe this is not for you.
If you find that appetizing, this is for
you. Okay, so we're going to do
JavaScript advanced coding. No
frameworks, no JavaScript frameworks, no
nothing, no libraries, pure raw
JavaScript.
Okay. And let me introduce you to
kasali.info
where you can find the best JavaScript
tutorial on earth. That would be.info.
info and here JavaScript in depth. Okay,
there's about
800 pages. Okay. Uh let's go to it.
Let's see how many pages I forgot. So
webdev blog and you got HTML, you got
CSS. Fantastic. You got then you got uh
JavaScript here and you got JavaScript
object reference.
Am I talking? Am I alive? Alive. I think
I am. And uh I can hear myself. That's
good. So there it is. JavaScript in
depth. I recommend it. Okay.
Now if you are newbie, you might find
this interesting. Now if you are an
expert at Google, you might find this
interesting too.
Okay. So we're going to write some
JavaScript. So let's see. show in
browser. Uh, close that. Remember
JavaScript in depth. Okay. So, close
that. Actually, uh, to do close that,
you want to go to some talk show today
episode 798. Copy the file path back to
Emacs. Press press a command to open
whatever URL in the paste board showing
browser. That is the current page.
Fantastic. So the task is write a
JavaScript to add a table of colors of
increasing parameter value for OKLCH
color and others.
Okay. So OKLCH we talked about last week
also on YouTube a live stream the very
advanced and intu intuitive color space.
However, the technical aspect is not
quite intuitive because for example uh
okay so so does that make sense? No, I
don't think so. So let me explain. Okay,
so you go to color index you got the
color picker familiar to everyone. You
can you know drag your mouse and you
have hue and you have darkness. So this
this model is actually called hue
saturation
brightness. Okay. So hue is the rainbow
colors. You can see red, orange, yellow,
green, blue, violet, then red, back to
red. Okay, that's hue. Then you got
saturation. How, for example, you want
red, you can be uh let's say brightness
here. Okay, so very red or light red,
then almost no red, then gray. Okay, so
that's a saturation. And same thing for
other color you know green very green to
little green tiny green then gray okay
saturation then you got lightness
lightness you see let's say uh uh red so
very bright bright uh wait red okay okay
this model is a hue saturation value
okay so anyway so
anyway they're similar so the last value
is brightness so become white middle is
red then you become black. Okay. For
other colors well for example blue you
middle is pure blue then above is more
white and become pure white and below is
pure black. Okay so this is like a hue
saturation value model of color. There
are quite a few other models. The worst
[ __ ] possible is the Unix and C
[ __ ] They created this RGB
hexadismoal thing color. Okay. So, uh,
so here's a bunch of color names. If you
are here, say hi. Okay. So, here's a
bunch of color names. If you find it
this interesting, just tell me your
stories. Okay. So, am I still alive?
Check again. I'm good. Good. So, you got
these color names, named colors. Okay.
Now, there's Let me tell you an
interesting story. About 10 years ago,
they added a new color named color in
CSS. And that that color has a
surprising name
and cute name. It's called Rebecca.
So, where is it? Uh there it is. Rebecca
Purple. Okay. because one of the
developers
his daughter
uh died of cancer uh and this developer
is a very uh you know a heavy CS uh CSS
developer. So they the community voted
to create a named color after her
daughter's favorite color. So that's why
we got Rebecca purple. Okay, that's new
about 10 years ago. I just learned it
actually. uh last month.
So anyway, you got named colors. Okay.
So then then you got the RGB hexadisimal
idiocy from the C and Unix
[ __ ] Okay. They they you know
blame them. Everything wrong in
computing industry has have something to
do with them. C and Unix brainless
creatures.
they you know they qu on this earth they
created huge damage to computing
industry okay anyway so you see you
don't blame them because well the
technology back then it was not like so
powerful today so you you have to you
know be practical that you don't blame
them because you got coobo you got
forran you got list you got lots of
things that was designed at that time
may not be the best but you know Pascal
and so
But the C and Unix [ __ ] they brew a
coat and they insist they are the brand
way is the best way. This lie by the C
and Unix [ __ ] Okay. Now if you
find this video not interesting, maybe
this is not for you. Okay. You you get
you get a taste of what you know my my
uh live stream is about. Okay. Uh hello
AC ACP Rebecca Purple. Yeah. So anyway,
the So we got the RGB color, you know,
the the the incomprehensible
hexadisimal. By the way, you guys know
what he what's hexodimal, right?
Sometimes I have to explain to beginners
um you know, and uh young people, they
don't know. So every generation, it's
like it's surprising, you know, there
will always be people who don't know
what is calculus. Like every year a
professor has to teach the same thing
until the professor is dead.
Then next professor the professor son
and since their son son they have to
teach the same thing forever.
That is the nature of humanity. I didn't
know I didn't know that until you see
nobody knows that until you get old you
know like me. When you get old, you
realize why why are these people don't
know this? Oh, because they were young.
They, you know,
this cycle has to repeat forever. So, do
you guys know what is hexadisimal?
That's a very fundamental basics. Okay?
If you don't know computers, you know,
it takes takes some time to learn
hexadisimal. Okay? Um, and of course,
then you have to know binary. Uh, where
is it? Uh god upd
um
okay let's go back to colors uh color
picker okay so we were talking about RGB
color hexadimals uh then uh okay I
digress so much so anyway so
RGB is one of the color space that's
what they call it okay then you got RGB
function now this is a a minor
improvement you See instead of using the
incomprehensible hexadisimal they
improve it improved it. So it uses
integers
still it's like CD you know. So in you
know RGB color you have three integers
each one is from 0 to 256
actually 255
you know why the magic number 255.
Well that's just you know that's because
the hexadimal two hexodimal that's 256
total possible values. So anyway,
improved, more readable, but still kind
of silly two, you know, uh you got magic
number 256
just because it so happens that the
binary number, you know, you know, you
got this 25 256 magic number that's
eight bits, okay? Uh yeah, eight bits,
eight binary digits. Okay? So if you
don't know I recommend you guys to
revisit young people okay so you guys
young people you know maybe you are teen
something go to you know go read
Wikipedia or something what is hexadimal
and go read about binary numbers okay
this is so fundamental you need to know
okay so I I wrote a converter here
binary to hexadimal
uh why binary because computers Because
we happen to use electronic computers
which is electricity they are either on
or off. So it's not the most easy easily
represented by using binary numbers zero
or one. One means on zero means off the
electricity flow. Okay, that's so
happens but not but this is not
necessarily so when you got quantum
computers or when you got biological DNA
computers like your your your the atoms
you know that's amazing molecules they
you know DNA comput computation they do
computation like in mass like
by billions in parallel like like for
example you you you have a bag of
marbles let's Okay, you have a bag of
marbles, right? Then you you pull them,
you know, you you put them down, you
know, you you let them fall into a
bucket or whatever or to the ground.
Then the billions of micros they
automatically in parallel find their
place. You know, each each marble they
will find their place. Okay. So that is
like DNA computation by the molecules.
the molecules they you know certain
molecules they bind certain they don't
you know so billions and billions and
billions and gazillions and Google
zillions of them work in parallel that's
the DNA computation okay I don't know
much about it but that's the idea that's
how it works okay quantum quantum
computation is something else but there
you don't get the you you don't have the
binary [ __ ] okay like the C and Unix
[ __ ] their brain is just binary.
they don't know anything about actual
you know computation meaning of
okay so anyway so you know like when you
say uh a number based on let's say uh
nine decimal you know uh nine symbols
like they don't know what you're talking
about or based on 13 or 15 or any number
these people the C C++ and Unix
[ __ ]
their brand got washed
So because of the C you know print f
that's why they don't know about this
they they have no idea about the the
nature of this number basis okay anyway
getting into a rant so let's stop so you
have to learn okay so if you are young
uh you you know learn about binary
hexadimal okay fundamental that's
fundamental in computer meaning when you
uh do programming okay then you got
other models those color models. Okay.
So, RGB now, so they improved. So, you
can use decimals, I mean integers 255, 0
to 255 inclusive, but you can also use
percentage
that is a improvement. Okay. So, you see
this is superb improvement. This is the
this is the meaning of design. This is
why the Unix and C are the [ __ ]
Okay, now let me explain this one. You
see, so here you got a percentage for
each RGB value. Why is it good? Because
you don't you get rid of the magic
limited human limitation, the magic
numbers of 256 and limited. You can't go
more, you know, you can't go beyond 256,
right? So what happens when you when
your uh for example our monitor today
can display far more colors than 256
levels? Well, you got [ __ ] Okay,
that's because of the C and C++ and Unix
[ __ ] these people.
So you want remove that design limit.
This is a human, you know, this is a
human forced limit. Okay, you have to
remember oh 256 is 256 is special but so
remove that you so you have 1 to 100%
percent meaning you know percent means 0
to one okay any value from 0 to one
infinite num infinite number of values
okay that's that's a real number
including numbers that cannot be
represented in a computer you can even
have that because that's a mathemat
mathematical ideal real numbers okay
between zero and one. So by this design
a percentage you see you removed this
magic number and limit limitation of
quotation. Okay, fantastic. And this is,
you know, so in CSS about 10 years ago
or 15, we started to have this. Uh, this
is great. Okay. And
Wuam language I have showed you guys
many times before. I've done, you know,
I'm going to do a Wuam language again
soon. So, Wuam language, they have also
these color models. They got HSL, RGB,
and and and so on. Okay. But they don't
but they don't have um let's see if I
can open some of the fail to open. Okay,
I delete that file. Anyway, so I did I
done hundreds of videos on woof
language. So anyway, woof language also
have RGB. Can I show it? Yeah, actually
why not? Because it's always um good to
show uh Hugh for example.
Uh okay, we are digressing but that's
okay. That's what talk show is about.
You see hue, this is uh one of their wam
language functions. So you can see hue.
The first value is hue. The second value
is saturation. You see that s. So let's
say 0.5.
Well, let's say 0.9 high saturation. And
brightness. The last value is
brightness. Let's say uh 0.5. Okay.
Enter. You see you got you got kind of
dark hue. So let we can do a table.
Okay. So, so you can let me Okay. So,
let me I digressed. Okay. Uh, hold on a
second. So, I digressed. Where are we
going? So, let me talk about the Wuam
language a little bit and let's return
to this. Okay. So, let's do a like
little digression. Okay. So, search
section.
Um,
wra language. Oh my god, I haven't done
a wam language episode for a month.
Table. Fantastic. Put the hue there. Can
Can you guys see my screen?
Yes. Okay.
Are we good? Are we good, guys? Do you
guys enjoy what I'm saying? Say hi.
Okay. So, we got a hue. We want a hue
from let's say xx from Z uh 0 to one in
increment of 0.1. Okay. that that we'll
generate a a gradient of colors. Okay.
Shift enter to run it. So you can see
that's a rainbow color, but now it's
kind of dark. So let's uh make the
brightness one. Okay. So now it's it's a
very shiny. Okay. Uh shift enter. So you
can see
fantastic and beautiful. And wuam
language also have RGB models you know.
So you can you got RGB color uh and in
fact you got uh you got what is what is
this interactive
picker color picker. I haven't used this
before. So actually you got GUI to do
the color. Okay. So so anyway so W
language you go. So I got uh C Y MB
color. C Y uh C M Y K C M YK that's a
that's another color model. Okay. So
anyway, so we talking about color models
that's on topic today.
Okay. So um
yeah, so so what we doing? So so that's
it about wolf language for for today.
And let me just uh
let's just do a screenshot of this.
Okay,
why not?
Fantastic and beautiful.
Okay, so so back to CSS. Okay, so we
were talking about so uh yeah so uh
let's put this code back syntax color it
showing browser fantastic okay so let's
go back to the color so okay so we got
colors you got RGP so you see so what I
wanted to tell you guys is that you see
the value each value in this hue param
parameters they go from zero to one
there's no arbitrary very limitation
humanmade limitation like the 256
C and Unix [ __ ] thing okay no
arbitrary limitation that's design this
is a issue of design okay this is not
about issue of practicality
okay
anyway okay so let's move on so RGB so
you got RGB function they added that to
CSS you see uh they use percentage
you know, I I think it would be better.
Well,
in the in the So why why didn't they
just use 0ero to one? Well, because in
CSS, if you use 0ero to one, then you
got confusion with the, you know, the
RGB 256, you know, you can't tell
whether which which is which. So they
they use percentage, which is um kind of
the CSS style. You got lots of things in
percentage. Okay. But percentage
basically is another notation for a
value, a real number between zero and
one. Okay, you got that? So this is a
little math mathematics tip. Percentage
is a notation for the real number zero
and one between zero and one. Okay. So
anyway, so so that's RGB function. Then
you got then you got uh Okay. So wait.
So then you got HSL.
Fantastic random color. So HS uh HSL is
very intuitive because you know hue
let's go uh what
let's say saturation red saturation not
so much hue. Okay. So saturation high is
the color rainbow. You see red, yellow,
green. Uh let's bring the lightness to
uh middle. Okay. So red, yellow, green,
orange, uh green,
canon, blue, violet, purple, red. Okay.
HSL very um intuitive.
Now let's next. What is the next
actually? Uh so then you got these new
colors I talked about we talked about uh
a week ago. But what I want to do today
is actually so oh yeah so I was going to
explain so why is this okay LCH very
complex because you see so far we kind
of understand you know for RGB you know
you just got red green blue they make up
a color each one can be 0 to 256
if you you know cut them into 256 parts
or they can be from zero to one infinite
infinite levels of detail. Okay. So
that's RGB red, green, blue. Okay. So
then so you got HSL. It's also
intuitive. You got hue. You got
saturation lightness. Okay.
Then you got uh then you got okay. So go
down. Then you got HWB. This is new.
This stand for hue, white, black. So the
idea is that you start with a hue then
you can you can increase um
the what uh so here's a change of hue
you see they go by 360 that's another
design idiocy you see but you see here
they decided the hue goes from around
the circle 360 degrees
very inconsistent you know
like because we have you know the RGB
you You got a percentage, you got the um
0 to 255 magic number. Um but here they
they they they went with the degree like
0 to 360 idiotic. But however, you can
also use percentage. Okay. So let's see
is can you actually
uh hue? No. [ __ ] idiot. Jesus. So hu
goes from 0 to 360. You cannot use
percentage
[ __ ] idiot CSS.
You know the the reason. So again we are
talking about design. Des design is one
of my big focus. Okay. So I pay
attention. So this you know this design
issues they stand out to me. Okay. When
I see you know programming languages
whatever any design issues they they
they stand out jump they jump out at me.
was opposed to the C and C++ type of
people. Okay? Like those type of people,
they don't they don't see it. They like
they blind. They just care about coding
compile. My code is faster fat. You
know, that's what they care.
Uh okay. So,
hello dam. Okay. So, fantastic.
So anyway, so HBW
hue, whiteness, blackness, what the
name? So the idea is that you start with
a hue, a color, then you can like make
it more white, you know. So hue is like
that, then you can make it more white
like that or you can make it more black
like that. So that way, you know, that's
the idea. kind of simple but but this
model is not so great because when you
increase the white so what happens when
you increase both the white and the
black then you got this above when when
the blackness and the whiteness when
they are when they are sun is 100 or
more they all become gray you see like
in this case you increase the whiteness
and you increase the blackness they all
become gray even the numbers are
different but they are or just gray. So
anyway, this is a hue, whiteness,
blackness model. Okay.
Uh so you know, but it's still kind of
intuitive, you know, hue, whiteness,
blackness. But then you started to have
the wide color gamut. Okay, I you watch
my previous video, I explained some of
that basically.
Okay, so let me cover this for a minute.
So
you got what's called wide color gamut.
Why? Because in the traditional RGB
model
you got red, green, blue, right? RGB
red, green, blue. And in this model,
each color can have 256 levels. Okay?
From 0 to 255. Total of 256. So 256
levels for red and same for 256 levels
for green, 256 levels for blue. Now this
is called standard RGB. You know they
have to create a standard because for TV
for broadcasting you know a lots of work
uh with the computers, monitors
you have to follow this standard. Okay
levels for each color channel. This is
called standard RGB. Okay,
this is called standard RGB sRGB.
Remember that's a term that's a standard
name. Okay, but it turns out
the human eye can see much more colors
than that. Okay, the computer monitors
or TV up to about 215,
they cannot produce colors outside of
the standard RGB. However, our eyes can
see much more colors than the, you know,
than just 256,
you know, levels of a a mix of red,
green, blue. Okay? So, even though
this standard RGB 256 * 256 * 256 gives
you millions of colors, but but our eyes
can see much more. Okay? So that's why
so so beyond sRGB is called white color
gamut. Okay. And there's a standard
called display P3. Okay. So that's
beyond RGB,
beyond the sRGB. Okay. So for example,
my monitor cannot display colors beyond
sRGB. So you can you can go to check
your monitor. Okay. So like you can go
for example on Windows you can go to
display
and uh then you can go to advanced
display uh
then it'll tell you you see color format
RGB color space standard dynamic range
SDR okay so that's that's your monitor's
spec
color format RGB color space standard
the dynamic range SDR. What does that
mean? That means that basically means
sRGB, standard RGB. Okay, so it my
monitor cannot display colors beyond
the 256 levels for each color channel.
Okay.
So, but a lot color for example iPhone
since about 2015 or something they all
can display
white color gamut or called display P3
and a lot of huge TVs today you know you
go to Walmart you can see lots of huge
TVs they have you know very vivid vivid
colors okay so that's actually
technological progress you you got this,
you know, white color thing, but most
monitors still cannot display it.
So that's when this this this funky new
colors in CSS came from lab. I don't
quite understand. Very complex. Okay.
So, so and and then you got this um OK
LCH. Okay. They they are quite complex.
You see, you see for example,
you see this. Okay. RCH color
processes. God,
what the [ __ ]
Pressed the wrong key. So anyway, the
CSS the okay LCH you got three
parameters. Lightness, quama, hue. But
you see the qu you see lightness is a
percentage. Okay, zero to 100 100%. Qua
is a value that can
in theory goes goes to infinity. Okay,
but but anything beyond 3.75
is kind of beyond sRGB.
Okay. So you don't have like a definite
number like it's zero zero to one or
what you know you have this kind of
infinite number you can use but however
beyond 3.75
that's like
then it's beyond sRGB but but not
exactly it depends on other values you
see it's not exactly beyond 3.575
for quama then then then other monitor
cannot display it depends on what's your
hue and lightness you see. So this so
this gets a bit complex complex you know
it's not easy to understand okay so then
you got hu is the same three uh 0 to 360
again they use the circle degree okay so
you see the quama thing
you know it's like the exactly what you
know you don't have a specific range of
numbers
that's why I say this is you know this
is not intuitive That's why I want what
I want to do is today to write a
JavaScript so that I can increase these
parameters to see how they look. But
there's difficulties because
because first of all my monitor cannot
display colors outside of sRGB so I
can't see it. I have to go to uh use my
iPhone and stuff. Anyway, so that's
enough talk.
What I wanted to do is actually code
JavaScript. So,
uh, hello Fox Di.
Okay. Uh, that's enough talk. I think
let's start to, uh, do JavaScript. Okay.
You see CSS added more color functions.
I'm I'm still working on them. Uh, very
powerful color functions. Okay. Color
functions. And you got also color mix.
Okay. So now let's write some
JavaScript. I I want to do
let's see how many people five
single.
Okay. So let's see JavaScript. Okay. So
How long have I been talking? 35
minutes. Okay, that's 35 minute minutes.
Uh, how shall I say now? This is uh
English vocabulary literature part.
Okay, that's called Haran. 35 minutes of
Haran.
H A R A N G U. A new word for you
Zoomers. Haran, a long compass speech,
especially one delivered before a
gathering. Okay. A speech or piece of
writing characterized by strong feeling
or expression, a tirade.
[ __ ] Unix and Foxy.
Okay. So now JavaScript
is that right? JavaScript. Yeah. Okay.
So uh what we going to do? Okay. So
let's go here.
Um,
so we want to uh
we want to, you know, I want to use
JavaScript to create this uh kind of I
want to create the two-dimensional
gradient actually not just
onedimensional.
So do a bell says off topic.
Did you Okay. So the question is do you
consume much Chinese new media movie
shows? No, not really. when I was
younger. Yes. When I was younger,
uh when I was before 14, when you know,
when I was in Taiwan, I I was born in
Taiwan and grew up in Taiwan up to age
14. So,
I watch a lot movies. uh you know my
grand my grandma
from my uh mom's side would take me to
movies kung fu movies or whatever.
uh since I left Taiwan
I haven't actually so kind of long story
but in short since I since um after 14 I
have not watched any Chinese media no
movies you know little no movies no news
nothing
then so that went on for 20 years or
more then the YouTube began so you know
YouTube, you started to have video clips
and you have kung fu movies u and
sometimes TV shows shows old kung fu
movies. But anyway, the point is for
for 20 years after I'm 14, I have not
watched much
Chinese news, TV programs or movies or
anything. Okay. Then until YouTube
started to have them. Then you know like
20 years ago 2006
then then in the last in the past 10
years you because of the phone the
internationalization
the progress of technology communication
we have Twitter we have lots of things
you know so then you can talk to Chinese
you can see and on Twitter you have lots
of tons of I mean especially today you
have tons of Chinese clips like your
shorts or whatever or in or or even
YouTube you have Chinese official
Chinese news channel. Okay.
So I would say in the past five years I
have watched some
Chinese news you know chi Chinese news
is interesting because it gives you a
different perspective you know covering
wars for example. So I I have watched
some Chinese news or and there's also a
lot like like the influencer facts just
like in English you know like in English
you have lots of these random [ __ ] scums
in so-called influencers they either
many types okay they do makeups or they
fry drama they you know they talk about
oh trans or or mud or they some some of
them tell murder stories some of them
tell political stuff Oh, oh, Trump. Oh,
the the Democrats this or that or the
the Republican this, you know, like the
Tim Pool scum. Okay. And uh and many
others Tim became a scumbag
and he become very rich, you know,
frying drama, you know. So these
[ __ ] you know, like you you go to
YouTube, all these political, you know,
trash and today and today it's lots of
AI, you know, these programmers or and
Bitcoin, the crypto fuckets, the crypto
like they talk about, you know, oh, AI
is going to listen, you know, lots of
trash like 90% of YouTube or Twitter,
more than 90% is pure trash, fake news
and And of course then you got the
official government sponsored big, you
know, they got billions of dollars. They
have an army of fake news agents, okay?
They push things, you know, and you may
count CNN, Fox News, you know. So
anyway, so so so all these media uh lots
of fake news. So, but I and you know the
the influencers, YouTubers,
lots of them are just pure [ __ ]
So, what I want I was I was going to say
is that same thing for Chinese. Okay,
you go to YouTube, you'll see lots of
political commentators. Okay? Uh if you
like go to YouTube, YouTube.com,
you got lots of political commentators
in Chinese language. Okay.
Okay. So this so uh so so that's my talk
show live. Okay. So um so let's see what
some you know I don't go to YouTube on
this browser. So it's a Bach. Okay. I
listen to Bach music. That's that's a
fantastic one. Well tempered clavia
that my favorite fugue number four of
all songs in the universe. That song.
Okay. If you can only have one song in
the universe, that would be B
welltempered clavier fugue number four.
Uh book one. Okay. Then what is this? Uh
Tokyo. This is uh what is this?
Anime. Anime. That's a great movie. I
suppose is the greatest recording ever.
Mercury living presence music. I don't
know what that is. Then football. Of
course. A lot of people is oh it's
that's live
lot people are into football. Uh
then thoughts you there you go thoughts
you know girls with their tits they
compete to show
tits and ass and legs. Okay. Thoughts.
Then what is is this this Zuma fox
whatever startup hires an adult Zuma fox
doing their things and thoughts women
then oh wait is this repeated life live
okay so whatever
then [ __ ] this zoomers or whatever
[ __ ]
okay then piano okay so that's also like
interesting then music okay then what
what is this drama what whatever.
Okay. So, you see I I don't use this
browser. I never
uh I rarely I uh use this browser to go
to YouTube. But but after a while,
you'll see lots of [ __ ] you know, lots
of [ __ ] and political [ __ ] Okay.
So anyway, so what I'm telling you is
that there's massive number in Chinese
language too because if you do not speak
Chinese, you will not you you'll never
see it. Like you don't know, you have no
idea. But I I can tell you, okay, like
like once you speak, let's say, French
or Japanese, if you speak it, you you
open a new world, okay? You'll see
millions and millions of videos that you
never know existed.
Okay, that's a long digression.
So, why do you like this keyboard? Isn't
RO stagger bad? Yeah, ro stagger is not
ideal, but it's not too bad. Okay, it's
not too important. So, I learned, you
know, I don't want to talk about
keyboard right now, but but I can tell
you just one tip. The keyboard, you
know, all this after 10 years, the the
most important is actually just the key
switch.
Okay. The key switch and split and
tented. Okay. If you type a lot, you
need them tinted like this. Okay. So,
key switch, you want mechanical and
light. It's the most important. Then you
want them to be split so that you your
hands, you know, don't go um,
you know, like not like typical, you
know, traditional. So, you want them
split. Okay.
The third thing you want them tinted,
you know, not flat. Okay. So these three
the most important the other so you know
the curve or the stagger that's
less important. I would say it's still
good but it's less important. That's my
opinion. Okay. That's like the tip I'm
going to give you.
Okay. So that's okay. So we talked about
too so long about that.
I think we done. So but let's yeah let's
let's finish that. I mean let's let's
code the color. Okay.
God. So we already talked for 46
minutes.
So we haven't So let's code color. So
what we want to code? So um
let's just start here. Okay.
So go to the page. Yeah. Yeah. So go to
the page.
Go to the page. Where do you want to add
it? So you already have So this is
manually generated. Color samples. Okay.
Search for sample. Yeah. So this is
manually generated.
Okay. Let's just add somewhere here.
Okay. So, new section,
new dive, add a class, and add a random
class. Let's say root. Okay, root
something. You that's where we're going
to add our JavaScript.
Copy the file path of the current
buffer. Paste it. Change this to
JavaScript and make link that
automatically became this script tag.
Okay. Then uh then you want to copy
that. So that's a class. You don't want
a class. You want ID. Okay. So copy
that. So open that empty. That's good.
Com comment. Put a date. And you want to
select that. Okay. So you want to select
by ID. So get element by ID. Something
like that. And that's right.
And this uh doc
document. Okay. Oh, you need a constant.
Okay. So,
so I don't I don't want that. Uh I don't
want hyphen. Okay. I don't like you know
because if you use hyphen you cannot use
it in JavaScript incompatible because in
JavaScript
names function names and variables names
you cannot have a hyphen. Okay. So I
like to use low line instead. this
character in uni code is called low
line. Okay.
See, in traditionally it's called
underscore, but I don't like that name,
the ethmology of underscore. Anyway,
just call it low line that because
that's what it is. Low line. Okay. Now
go to go to JavaScript, paste that here.
Then you can paste that and that that
that that predify the code. Fantastic.
We we selected that element. What I want
to do so you want
what we what are we doing? So okay. So
we got a JavaScript going. Remove that
to do. Well, it's your to-do. Okay. So
let's keep it. So let's like um
Okay, let's copy that.
What we going to do here? Okay. So we we
want the JavaScript to insert something
like that. Okay, trivial. Uh but I
haven't called JavaScript for a long
time. So we want JavaScript to insert
something like this. So
create element.
So Gabriel, did I answer your question
about keyboard? If I did
say yes.
Okay. So, let's get back to the code.
So, I want to insert.
How do you want to do this? You can
in the HTML.
First of all, you need to create
element. Okay. I don't remember. Do you
remember? No, I don't remember a thing.
So, let's go to
JavaScript
scripting. So, what what do you want to
do? You want nodes and elements
note type get elements get parent child
sibling? No. Iterate nodes. No
element attribute. We don't care. List
remove class. No. Create element. That's
what we want there. So, document create
element.
Okay. Let's see uh examples. Let's see.
Create and insert example. Click me.
Hello. Hello. Hello.
Okay.
Okay. Let's just copy copy and paste
code. Paste here. Okay. So, that's a
button. So
you don't want you don't want the
button. Okay. So we don't care about
button. So here's a function. So the
function get elements.
Okay. That's a that's a new node. Append
child
create text node. No.
Okay. Here's what we do. Okay. So let's
just state type. Okay. Let's rename this
to function.
Oh god.
Just say insert. Okay. So we create a
new elements. Then what you then okay
don't append yet. No don't do that.
Okay. So
append child. Then you got this uh root
thing. That's right.
Uh yeah, you need to do that eventually.
And uh no event listener. No.
Yes, you want that.
So what you want is
so so
well,
so so you need to do a loop. Okay. So
what what you going to do?
So this
three parameters.
Gabriel, are you still here?
Uh, God.
Now I need to exercise my hands
by rolling this
stone balls.
Can you see?
Okay. So, I need to code. So,
you want to insert by first create a
dive element and add this into that dive
element. Okay. As a inner child. Okay.
Okay. But before then you need this
color style because that um
do you want that?
Don't know. Okay. So
let's say no.
So you need
you need a loop. Okay, you need a map or
loop or
let's see if I remember my JavaScript
array
uh array. Okay, array constructor.
Let's say uh
[ __ ] JavaScript is so annoying. array
constructor 10.
How many elements do I want?
something.
So you
So let's say one to 10 divided by five.
It's very annoying. There's no shortcut.
You have to go. So you go to JavaScript,
then you go to the array section.
Array. Okay. Then you go to the bottom
to to reach the navigation bar.
Then you got uh create array you know.
So you can click create array
and then you uh
that's not what we want. You want a
range function for array. Okay. Because
JavaScript do not have it building kind
of annoying. you go through these hacks
to to create a array. Okay. So So for
example, you can do this but the problem
with this is that it just give you a
range of integers and start from zero.
If you want say a range let's say from
10 to 20, you cannot do this. You have
to map. Okay? You can't you know why why
can't you just have a function 10 to 20?
Well, you can't. You cannot. That's why.
So very annoying. So what?
My browser is stuck.
What?
God. Okay. So, so I wrote this uh you
know range function that allows you to
have min, minimum, max and step. So step
can be 0.1 for example.
So, but I was thinking you know maybe we
can avoid using this because in this
case for example what we want here is
the parameters they they need to be
decimal. Okay.
Yeah. In in you know so in many cases
they need to be decimal or the degree
from 0 to 360.
So you ultimately need this uh function
kind of. Okay. So let's just put it
there. Okay. [ __ ] idiotic.
And uh so
so this is min max return array from min
to max inclusive increment of step.
Okay, for example,
and also lock
cas range. Can you do that please? And
uh let's say 0 to one instead step step
of 0.1.
Can you do that? Yes, you got that funky
because of the numerical analysis. the
binary cannot represent certain real
numbers in an exact way.
So you got that situation. So um but
anyway, so this um
that's how this function works. I mean I
mean there's a showcase of this range
function but uh but is that what is that
what we want? Yes, that's what we want.
Okay, so you need that.
Okay. So, so my array so
X range.
Okay. So,
constant
that X range. Okay. So, that gives you
that. Okay.
Then uh then what?
Pify
can predify.
Purify the code. Now you can pify. Okay.
So now
you got a range. Okay. Put this inside.
So you got a range. Then you want to go
through it. So
uh you can build it as a string
you know do a map or a loop then build a
string then
um then
use the you know set it def uh assign it
to inner HTML.
Okay. Or you can build each array
each element create each element.
Okay. So what
let's create each other element. Okay.
So,
so that means you need to have a um
we map or for each
for each. Okay. Then um
what are your top five programming
languages? That's like a repeated
question thousand times
annoying. Well, maybe because you are
new, but you know that's like
top five programming language. Okay. So,
top five Wam language Golan
uh Wolfam language Goland and uh um
and let's say F
and maybe Julia.
Uh
okay. you know that that's like the
short answer without any
qualification. Okay.
Okay. So let's uh so so so now
you you you know you you watch my older
videos there are thousands of them. I
talked about it in fact in fact two days
ago or three days ago.
uh but the thing is you are not going to
because they are buried
you know in my in my 1 hour uh talk so
for shallow I you know I'm not saying
you but a lot you know most people they
don't they don't really care like what
what do you mean like your favorite top
five you know it's like dram drama
questions
okay So uh as opposed to you know like
very technical detail why are they best
why do you like them that way be do you
actually know know them what's the
significance what's the practicality of
the question how do you judge you know
like in more indepth questions I'm new
what about this
uh well Lisp.
Lisp.
Lisp is so uh
common lisp is very bad. Skim list or
racket is also not so good. Common lisp
is bloated complicated. [ __ ] Okay.
Common lisp. Skim list is and or schem
or you know skim list or racket.
They are narrow niche forever loop in
you know tail recursion no going nowhere
after 40 years the idiots because this
you know we we need to be elegant this
this so they they have this very niche
going nowhere anytime
after 30 years 40 years in fact is it 40
or 50 they are like tail recursion going
nowhere any time so nobody nobody cares
about them
imp, you know, impractical scheme. They
they they they think they are the most
minimal and beautiful. That's [ __ ]
too. Anyway, it's better. It's far
better than commonly commonly the the
common list fanatics are [ __ ] just
like the C [ __ ] Okay. Now, so
that's about the most two most popular.
Then then there's EMAC bisp which is
what I do every day or you know Emac
bisp and so what eac bisp is not a
general purpose language it's only good
for in emacs okay when you do lots of
text processing
uh you are looking at emac this code
okay so lots of text processing it's
good like dling inside emacs it's good
it's useless useless as you know you you
can't rent you you can't you can't
really you know you can't rent you you
can't build Amazon you cannot build a
Google empire okay it's good for dealing
within a text editor okay and the Emacs
these idiots they refuse to change
there's no like for example any
respectable programming language Python
JavaScript or or any pearl ruby gol
Oland Java they have systematic library
names name space for the library you
know bundle in Emacs you don't you don't
have such a thing you you go by feelings
oh but oh I think you know there's a
network library should be here you know
like you know emac you know it's so the
end result of emac this is just it's
just good within Emacs you can do some
text processing but actually if you do
text processing it's better than any
It's better than pearl, better than
python, better than ruby.
Okay, because it has, you know, buffer
data structure, it has, you know, point
point data structure. It has, you know,
you can save places, you know. So for
text processing,
that's emac that's that's that's good
only for small scale. If your text file
is like one gigabyte, then you cannot do
it. Okay? Like
so Emac Bisp I have been coding for like
15 years almost every day. I I still
code it every day. Um but uh and I you
know but it's not it's it's it's a you
know it's just it's little language.
It's not
a respectable respectable language and
it's it's in terms of feature it's not
that great. Okay,
you know for example compared to common
lisp common list is a real industrial
programming language full of watts just
like C++
but it's used in the industry you can
create
Google empire you know they they they
they build uh Yahoo store with common
list program and you know they you know
you can build an empire but it's ugly
[ __ ] just like C++ common list scheme
list is very uh small but
uh but it's it's good you know I mean
it's niche okay
but Emac this it's just in EMAC okay no
that's it uh so
and feature wise it's you know not so
good compared to commonly sport scheme
so it's not really good Okay. Well, I've
been coding it for 15 years. That's kind
of too bad. See, it's like a waste kind
of, you know, you might say it's a time
wast waste wasted. Okay. I wasted my
life in Emacs.
Well, I you know, I I I became the
greatest like I created the softly keys,
the most efficient key binding system in
the universe in human history. Okay,
this is more efficient than vim neo vim
if you choose to use emacs. Okay, softly
keys. Okay, I talked about it many
times.
Well, that's that's about it, you know,
but so so so eacisp is a small scale.
It's it's it's not so very great.
So what about so that's my opinion about
lisp. So that's the three major lisp.
Okay, I talked about common disp
or racket and emac disp. Now the now the
other would be closure. Closure is the
one that's used in industry in computer
industry. Some company use it. That's
the best that's that's that's that's the
you know probably the best modern lisp.
Um
but I didn't like it so much because
it's intertwined with Java. It runs on
Java and it's like intertwined with
Java. You you know it's not a
independent language what they call it's
a hosted language. So it hosts on Java.
Java is the body. You know Java is the
mummy. It sucks the mummy. It lives
inside Java. Every documentation of
closure talks about Java. Talk about
Java object, Java sequence, Java data
structure. Oh, oh, closure in closure.
This is Java that this that is Java.
This [ __ ] Java. So, I don't like
closure. Okay. But otherwise, Closure is
like the the modern list, you know,
that's clo and and practical.
So that's about the all the major list
or another one you might consider wufam
language is a a list. Okay. Uh search my
old uh videos because I talked about
that why wuam language is a list. I
talked that about that for many hours
several videos.
Okay that's a large digression. Um
you know we going to not going to finish
this. Is my uh answer to you
satisfactory
newbie?
What does a language need to be
respectable? Okay. Well I'm going to go
back to code the JavaScript. Okay. So
you guys watch my old videos. There are
700 of them. Many of them talk about
these language programming language
issues.
So,
okay. So, actually let's do this
quickly.
It's getting hot summer.
God, I need a break now. Sitting here
too long for an hour and 12 minutes.
Okay.
For each what?
Okay, let's do this quickly. Okay, so
let's
so create a new n
style.
Uh
set attribute. Can we do actually do
that? [ __ ]
Sit attribute background think. So
can we do this my friend? Yeah, you can
do that. Not that
JavaScript
uh string the JavaScript template string
that's that's that okay and uh so
template string this uh you need to give
a value so which value here so this x
um so template string you need a dollar
sign like uh the mechanism
I don't remember the details so go to s
JavaScript in depth
range function to array. So open a new
tab, go to it. Uh that's all my custom
functions. But you want to go to
JavaScript in depth. You want to go to
string quote string. Then you want to go
to template string template string. And
what is the syntax? dollar sign curly
braces. That's correct.
Do I have it correct? Yes.
Okay. So, but um so that's a string. You
add the style then to the node then you
append child
something like that. Okay. You append
child to the um
which one?
Yeah. So this
So that's not the new Wait, you don't
Okay. Uh
let's call it box
Xbox. Okay.
So you got the Xbox then you create a
range then for each let's purify the
code do it. Okay. So you create a range
then for each then you create a new node
X node then you create a dive and for
the dive you add the style attribute
then you
then this attribute contains that that's
a string right the x is this value
that's right then uh for each
then you append it to the x node is that
right yeah append do that. No,
wait.
No, you append to the Xbox. That's
right. Then what is this? Then you
That's not there. Okay. So, that should
be
Okay, let's remove that for now.
Remove that.
Insert adjacent after end. No, not
after. That's just a pen child. Okay,
it's not insert a JSON. Okay, so
root
append child append the Xbox.
Okay. And this DD
wait delete. Okay. Prefy delete 35.
Good.
Wings
says, "Are you into electronics?" No.
I'm too old for that. I am interested,
but uh too many things to learn. You
like a guy who like tinkering with
electronics? Yes. When I was a teen,
like 12 years old, I did some soldiering
and uh and uh those um
capacitors and resistors, you know, I
played as some but
anyway,
turns out I just know computers and ma
in some mathematics, programming and
mathematics,
but otherwise I would I am interested in
physics, chemistry, electronics and all
these mechanics, uh robotics and lots of
these basically science sciences and
actually philosophy and linguistics
actually I know a bit about them and
psychology
and uh then yeah that those okay anyway
so so am I uh is this good this takes an
hour to write. So create uh so Xbox then
range then for each range uh for each
range you create a new dive you call it
node you set the style append try out
then you append that to the X node. So
let's so let's just then append um
then what
what's this function you need to call
this function okay
so you need to call this function Wait.
Yeah, I think I think so. So, let's um
Okay, I think that's it. So, can you
compile? Actually, make a copy. And uh
let's make this typescript. Okay.
TS.
Okay. Make a backup. Compile it.
Press this to compile.
Fantastic. It looks like it's working.
Close. Close. Okay. Uh yeah, this
created the JavaScript. Let's see. Open
that.
Okay. So now if we run this, it should
insert color here. Let's see. Showing
browser. Go to the bottom.
Uh
no, you see it should insert there. Uh
why is that? Because uh because select
uh by ID. Did we select by ID?
Get element by ID. So what is the do we
get
control shift I to see the developers
console?
Do we have a bug? Do we have error
messages? Refresh. No error. Okay. So
you got the root then you got that then
you uh oh because you didn't call the
function.
You need to call the function.
Compile it now. Refresh.
Refresh.
No, it didn't. Um,
what? Uh, let's see.
So the function is called
see for each
Is it not working? I don't understand.
Run it. There we have it. But it's not
in inserting.
Now wait.
If you say inner child
next node
in the html
equals to
let's say that
compile it.
Run it.
Fantastic. Now it adds there it is
actually successful. It didn't work
because the dive is empty. There's no
inner child. So when there's no content
by default the browser doesn't show
unless you add a width and height to the
type.
So anyway, so here we successful. This
is what I wanted to do. Okay. But um you
know we we need to refine it. Uh this is
not
you know because I want a uh nested loop
so that
uh but I think maybe we should close
down today because it's been an hour and
24 minutes.
So question
any reason you write TypeScript instead
of JavaScript since I'm not using any
types at all?
Well, yeah. So I mean so not much reason
basically TypeScript so it allows me to
catch more errors. So when the script
gets more complicated I can start to add
types. Uh for example, meme
this mean would be numb.
Uh can yeah so for example I can start
to annotate it uh something you know
compile it. Yeah just for the future you
know and also it it even if you don't
add types sometimes it catches some
errors when you compile. That's it.
That's it. That's all.
And hello today Claw Gold agent teach me
about item potent programming.
What what is that item potent? That's
what um
that that means the function returns you
know if you call the function twice it
doesn't hurt basically it returns the
same thing.
So what but what is item potent
programming? I think that's it for
today. Okay.
But this is silly. Okay. So, you did
this today,
but you didn't do much. You know, it
just it just, you know, prints that. Uh,
but
okay. Well, actually, you can get
better. So, for example, delete that.
Compile it.
Refresh. Wait, why is it uh Whoa. Oh,
here. Okay.
Compile it. Wait, not a key.
Okay, refresh. Now it's better. There's
no background. And then you need to
truncate those. Jesus. Okay. JavaScript.
Stupid JavaScript. How do you do that? I
don't remember. So you go to JavaScript,
you go to number section number then you
need to know about truncation or uh
wait what is it nan and infinity okay
input binary hexadimal or octto okay
number separator we don't care big int
that's a new feature decimal number
syntax we don't care we need the
truncation and uh
round. So arithmetic operators uh
arithmetic operators okay plus negation
mod ceiling flow around that's what we
want. So in this case um about the
colors what we want you want
those are this so you want you don't
want round so you want
uh actually you want round so let's see
mod
ceiling floor round okay
round towards Positive infinity runs
towards negative infinity.
So they run to a decimal number that I
mean to a integer. That's not what I
want.
I want
round to two decimal places. stupid
[ __ ] JavaScript.
Uh JavaScript you don't have a format
operator. JavaScript is very comp
complex,
right? So wait, what am I what I want to
do? I want to have two decimal places.
Okay. So, so normally in Python or Java
or other languages you use format
that you know you can format a number
turn a number to a string by the format
function. Okay. But JavaScript
does not have that.
So instead uh so I have written one.
So wait so let me think make sure you
know what we I can do is I can multiply
by
uh
you know by 100 then um
then just round. So what is this floor
ceiling
round?
Wait, does this round takes a second
argument because I want two decimal
numbers. This CD. So can you go to the
math operators to see the full
um
format number? So I got the format
number there.
Okay. So yeah. So you got
Yeah. So the new I mean the new function
is this international number format that
is new.
Uh
but I okay I need to write this. I
haven't
I don't have a tutorial of this
international number format method.
That's what I want. Okay.
But meanwhile I Yeah. Meanwhile, you
have two fixed.
Yeah. Two fixed. So you can use this uh
say two fixed tool. Okay.
This is like you can use that.
So
there there two fixed two and prettyify
compile the code back to the color
show
go down
there fantastic and Beautiful. You see
we got what we wanted.
Uh but not yet. I want you see. So now
this is changing the first parameter.
What what what is the first parameter?
The first parameter is lightness. Okay.
I want a nested loop so that
so that it can show a little squares of
when you change the second parameter
which is the chroma something.
Oh, anyway, I think that's it for bye
Samar
by
coin by
uh nobody clock. Okay. Yeah, I think
that's it for today. Yeah. So,
yeah, I'm going to work this offline.
you know JavaScript you see JavaScript
the code turns out you know it's like
nasty
all we wanted to do this is a single you
know simple
flat loop
uh but the code this is kind of
incomprehensible you know because you
have to create the dive
uh god then but but now if you want the
nested loop loop.
Oh god. So you need to like
So here is one loop. I'm using the for
each functional form. So if you want
nested loop, you kind of like um
you know somewhere you know do this
again
and JavaScript but I think that's it.
Okay. it, you know, for those of you
beginners, this is useful because you
don't, you know, you don't you don't use
the React, you know, the complicated
thing. This shows you the fundamentals.
Okay. Bye, guys.
Yeah. Okay. Bye.
See?
Yeah. I'm going to work out this
offline. Yeah.