Good everyone welcome to another episode
of bookan talk show we are going to code
wam language today mathematics geometry
plane curves and tangent lines. Okay,
now before we begin, let me show you my
keyboards. This is ultimate hacking
keyboard 80 UHK80.
Fantastic.
Search for my YouTube and you'll find
reviews. There are several like one hour
review and one hour unboxing and there's
also Ultimate Hacking Keyboard 60 before
that. It's quite a few. Okay, now switch
to my screenshot. I mean to my um
display and you can see my uh code. So
we are going to do coding. So this is
for those of you who are into
mathematics and uh wra language for
example we did yesterday this or two
days ago this episode on drawing
tangent. Okay let me show you some of
the you know so these are mathematics.
Okay that's what we are going to do
today. and coding it. Specifically, we
are going to code tangent. Now, if you
are watching this offline, play at 1.5
speed
if you will.
If you are watching this live, say hi.
Love to see your comments. Okay, so
double check. Am I alive? Video check.
Audio check. I think I'm alive.
Uh, let's see.
Okay. So I going to get recursive uh
voice if I turn this on. Anyway, so we
are alive. So this is mathematics
geometry. Okay. Basically uh basic
calculus.
So for especially good for you young
people. Okay. We're going to start to
code it. So showing browser. So actually
few days ago. So today uh
3 days ago episode 764 we did we did uh
we showed you how to actually code
uh tangent. Okay. So this is graphics
programming and I also improved the code
offline. So here's a code. You can get
the code by searching for my YouTube.
Uh for example, I showed the code here,
the updated code here. Um my website
kali.info
has having an issue in the past two
weeks. So I have not updated my website.
So you you cannot access this page. I
mean if you access it, it's it's like
404 not found because I have not been
able to update my website. But I will
fix it pretty soon. Okay. So anyway, so
for now you can get a code on my
Twitter. Just like look, search for
tangent lines um posted 2026 February
23rd. Okay, so this is fantastic wam
language code for tangent lines
and we're going to improve it. So let's
let's do that. Okay, so we did that. Uh
so what we want to do first of all um
cardioid okay so we're going to do so
you see this curve is called cardioid
and this curve is created by rolling a
circle around another circle okay it's
called cardioid and here in the
beginning we have the tangent and we
have the code here we live streamed
about a week ago but that is using my
package. So for example, let me show
you. So let's start wam language.
Now if you don't know the woofam
language, you can download for free
since few years ago at
wufam.com/developer.
Okay, go there download it for free.
It's like four or five gigabytes huge.
It's the most advanced programming
language on earth more than Haskell bisp
closure
um car or rust or whatever whatsoever
Julia okay most advanced because because
it is
it is kind of it's most high level okay
by the magnitude okay so download wam
language for free and you can also check
out my wuen language for programmers uh
complete tutorial video for the from the
ground up. Okay, on my website
everything you want to know, you need to
know to program Wuan language. Okay, so
x a h.info.
Go there and you'll find it. So that's
an introduction and uh so but so but now
let's go to cardioid. So we got this
code which requires my package. So let's
start wam language. It's uh new uh new
uh notebook. Uh paste the code and let's
magnify
150. If you have comments, say hi. Okay,
love to see your comments. Let's see.
Okay, so here's the code and uh shift
enter. So you can see we got the
graphics, but it requires my package
which is by the way free.
um you know wam language for programmers
you go there go to wuam language about
the author wam language in depth wam
language tutorial by video some of my
best videos in the past five years okay
there are hundreds of them uh and wam
language mod for mode for emacs we are
going we we are using emac the most
advanced text editor and there is wam
language packages uh somewhere here.
Okay. So
yeah, Wuang language packages by XR. So
uh plank up. So anyway, so that's how
you need you need this package in order
to do this. But however, we cod it
without requiring a package. We showed
it two days ago. I mean, yeah. So let's
do that. So let's get the code. The code
is here.
This one. Copy. So, let's go back to
let's do it. Okay.
Uh go here and go down here and uh go
down here and uh make a new section and
uh start a wolf frame language code.
Paste it. Okay. And delete the date.
Delete that. Copy it out. Copy it. Go to
here and go to the bottom. Paste it the
code. Here's the code. Shift enter. You
see that's a tangent of sign curve. And
you can press control shift N to make it
type set. You can see pi over 14. That's
fraction. And you can see it's a partial
derivative. You you see you got that
alpha kind of partial derivative symbol.
Okay. And same thing here. Shift control
shift N. So you can see type set
mathematics. Okay. So anyway, so now we
want to do this tangent of the cardioid
curve but without loading a package.
Okay. So what we need to do is you just
need to get the uh copy that. Okay. You
you just need the so the curve formula
you see the curve here is defined by
that sign curve. Sign curve is also
known as sinos syosoid. Okay, that's a
classic name senosoid.
Instead of saying sign curve, which is
kind of modern, but 200 years ago, they
say
senosoid. Okay, that's what they say
that, you know, that's a sign curve.
Okay, so close that back to here. Okay,
so anyway, so here is our new formula
that uh and remove the sign. Okay.
Okay, then copy all back to F language.
Paste. Paste the code. Shift enter.
Fantastic.
Cardioid. Okay, let's make it red.
Red. Shift enter. Beautiful. Now, let's
make the tangent lines longer.
Okay, so we want the tangent lines
longer. So, normalize. Uh,
yeah. So let's say two times. Okay, two
times. Let's see. Um, okay. So let's
press that. Shift enter. Fantastic.
Let's make it just long. Okay, let's say
nine. Shift enter.
Fantastic. Now you got lots of tangent.
Now let's limit the plot range to to
let's say um
what the plot range should be. So that's
5 4
-1 2
3. So limit the plot range. So
okay plot range and uh
range let's say
3 to 4 and uh -2 to 4 and here
uh let's say three
three -3 and three for the y axis. Shift
enter. Fantastic. So we getting better.
You see we are trying to um
do this cardioid. We want to make it
beautiful. That is the goal for this
beginning introductory image.
Okay. You see I want to make the code
independent without package because you
know when people go to the website they
look at cardio. Oh, beautiful. And they
copy the code. But oh, but you need this
package. How do you find it? Oh, you
have to go to the introduction to see
where to get the package. You know,
download, you know, working uh work in
progress miscellaneous reference um
somewhere here like wam language
packages. Okay. Mathematica packages for
plank curves. Then you Oh, you need this
one. It's tedious. Okay.
like 20 years ago when I did this that's
good you need packages but not today is
more like everything is just like
independent run by yourself okay so that
is why I need to change the code here so
now and we are creating the code here so
you see you copy this to any woof
language you run okay and uh you see as
long as the code is not too complicated
of course
project you need very complicated code
like thousand lines then you don't want
to like put thousand lines here okay but
for tangent it's easy it's trivial
okay any comments okay comments guys if
you have comments okay so we are doing
this so is this good enough no we wanted
to uh let's say cardioid now when what
is the range I mean what is the range of
the cardioid curve Let's say history
description.
Okay. So what is the formula? Parametric
formula.
Okay. So polar polar cartesian
idiotic par you know we want a
parametric formula. So I actually I need
to write this. But this is trivial to do
because to turn a polar equa polar
formula to a parametric uh formula all
you have to do is [snorts] you multiply
this this expression by cosine and sign.
Okay that's all you have to do. So this
multiply by cosine is the x. Okay. And
this multiplied by s is the y value.
Okay. then you get the parametric
formula but so anyway I wrote this 30
years ago so I need to update it so make
it more explicit
so anyway so this so what is it up to so
I mean I mean we want we need to know
okay so polar equation is basically to
two pi okay so basically zero to 2 pi so
let's change this to zero that will draw
half of the cardioid I'm pretty sure so
do it you see half of the cardio. So you
got to make it this to 2 pi. Okay. Shift
enter then full. Then then you want to
like the resolution. Let's increase this
to uh pi over let's say 20. Okay. Shift
enter. Better. That's beautiful. Okay.
Now is it [snorts] is it good? Is this
the final? You know, imagine you are the
director of a, you know, this project.
So, is this, you know, do you want to
have different thickness or I think it's
good. Perfect.
Okay. So, let's see. Yeah. So, I think
that's good. And uh let's delete that.
Okay. Let's just um
copy it. Go to the wra language. Go to
um Yeah. So, paste it. Okay. Now,
that's it. Okay. So, that's it. Put it
back. Uh
syntax cut the code. Go to cardio page
which is this page. You see? Now, go
back here. Search for pre. You see this
is the code. See this is this section
is
that section. Okay. Now you can um so
you can add your new code.
Actually we copy it. Okay. Now syntax go
show in browser.
You see now we got this this code
independent. Paste it. It'll work with
you know you don't have to you don't
need a package. Okay. So that is what I
will do. So, delete that. Okay, let's
see.
That's the one you want to delete. Yes,
delete that. And also update the
graphics. Do I need to? Actually, we
don't need to update graphics because
basically it's the same thing. You see?
Fantastic. Fantastic. And beautiful.
Let's leave it be.
Okay. So, let's check one more time.
Fantastic. We updated. Fantastic. the
code. Fantastic. Okay. Now, uh you see
these are Asian packages like Wuam
Notebook. We might want to update them
because they are
Let's see where where are they? Open it.
Go to the So, that's one of them. Open
it.
Continue to update by styling. Okay. So,
there it is.
Save it.
Okay. Yeah. So these are my old code.
You see many very interesting properties
about cardioid.
This is optical property. This property
you can see
uh in coffee cup. When you have a cup
and uh
where is it?
I have a photo. Okay. So where is it?
Let me show the photo. So this is
optical property. When you have a coffee
cup under the sunlight or under any
light, you'll see this kind of shape.
Okay.
Uh so I have a photo of that coffee cup.
But where is it?
Okay. I place it in I think I should
place it here, but I got it somewhere
else. Okay. So is this interesting?
Yeah. of you guys comment. Okay,
actually we got a lot to code. So where
is the plastic? Okay, so yeah and here
is interactive geometry ge algebra. So
you can move you you see you can move
the ray
source. You see this point you are
looking at I'm dragging you see this
point. O that's the ray
magnify. You see that's the source of
the light ray. Okay this point
you see and all these yellow lines are
reflection
uh reflection towards the circle. Okay.
So you see so if you have a light source
over here and you have a circle and the
light rays reflect you know around every
point on the circle
that's what you get that the then you
get the yellow lines you see the yellow
lines but you'll notice the yellow lines
forms a shape you see this like ass
shaped thing
that's called cardioid okay Actually,
you know, you you if you move the light
right on the circumference of the
circle, then that the resulting
reflection forms the cardioid. Cardioid
means hot
in Latin or something like that borrowed
from Latin or something means heart
shaped. Okay. So this is like a hot you
know it's like the girl's heart and so
when you move the light so fascinating
you see but what what if the light is
somewhere else so you can see
interactively how they shape how they
change it's more proper it's more like
you know just call it ass shaped curve
because it more descriptive
okay so anyway that's cardioid uh
history from about 400 years ago. I
think the first person who described who
did this is Olay Roma 1674
1674 400 years ago in a investigation
for the best form of gear teeth. Okay,
it so happens so you see the best form
of gear teeth is actually uh it turns
out it's called evolute.
the best form of gear teeth. Uh where is
it?
Okay. So, evolute it's kind of uh well
actually it's called imalude. Okay. So,
the best form of gear teeth is um
is um is a shape that is based on the
involute concept. Okay.
Am I going to explain? Well, so involute
is like when you have a curve and
suppose you have a string wrapped around
it, then you unwrap it. Unwrap it and
you pull the string tight. So you So if
you start with a ellisp or if you start
with a let's say circle,
you wrap a string around the circle,
then you unwrap it, but you keep the
string tight. Then you got you're going
to have this the trace of the end of the
string is called evolute.
It's called the evolute of the circle.
Okay. So evolute in general is a way to
create a new curve based on a given
curve.
So if you so one way to think of it is
like you unwrap a string. But how do you
describe this mathematically?
That is basically the tangent the end of
the tangent line
such that
um
such that the t tangent length increases
with corresponding to the curve length.
Uh another another way to describe it
better way is simply think of it is a
roulette of a line. You draw a line
around a curve. Okay. So anyway, so
so involute is
is a way to create a new curve based on
a given curve. So
so for a circle you have you can have
the involute of a circle. Okay. So that
would be this this kind of spiral like
curve. Okay. Now for a sign curve you
can also have imaloop. it would look
like you know like like this kind of
thing. Okay. So that's a concept of
involute.
Now for the gear shape for the gear
shape you know when you have you know
like when you have two mechanical gears
you know they they they roll around each
other right you know the the issue is
that is about friction.
Uh if you study mechanics you'll know
you see like typically we think of gears
like that right you know square uh teeth
but the problem in reality in real life
engineering this won't work because when
you have these teeth they they create
friction they don't roll smoothly
you know they they they jam they you
know they create friction okay so this
is like ideal you know simplified a gear
shape but in reality no gears their
teeth doesn't look like that. Okay. So
in reality the gear teeth looks like so
the question is how do you design a gear
teeth so that it's optimal it doesn't
uh it has minimal friction. Okay. So
gear so you search for gear teeth.
So hold on a second. Okay, be before we
search that, let's make a copy of this
screenshot. So So for so people know we
what we talked about. Okay. So now you
search for gear um
teeth shape.
Okay. So you started to see you see this
is a real life gear teeth shape like
that. Okay. So, here are the I think
this is a kind of like explanation.
You see, you started to get into
technical details. So, if you have the
gear shape, the teeth shape, it needs to
be shaped that way. So, it minimizes
friction. So, there's no friction. You
know, when when one gear push the other,
there's no like friction. I mean, if you
have square teeth, they they don't work
well. Okay. So minimum friction. So so
let's copy that. Uh so let's um
okay so this is mechanical engineering.
Very interesting.
Okay. So but how do you find this shape
mathematics? That's involute. It turns
out it is the you need to you know you
need to find the involute.
Now I don't know the details. I haven't
studied the detail but but but basically
uh you can look up Wikipedia
involute. Okay. Uh now Wikipedia is
better than my page by now because my I
created mine 30 years ago and in the
beginning Wikipedia just copied my page
like 20 years ago. Anyway, so so you can
read about Imolute on Wikipedia and you
can search for gear. I'm pretty sure
they mentioned their application. The
most common prop profiles of modern gear
teeth are involutes of a circle. Okay.
So they are saying that this this okay
so this shape you see this shape is
actually the the the shape the optimal
shape for gear teeth involute of a
circle. Okay. So anyway
so that's about imalute. So we were
digressing we were talking about um
uh yeah we were talking about cardioid.
Okay. So hold on a second. So let's turn
let's um
see
so we were talking about uh cardioid and
um
uh why are we talking about cardioid
because we were talking about the
history. So this guy Olay Roma 1674
began investigation
and uh cardioid shape came up but but
that's actually not optimal but so but I
don't know if he eventually found it or
you know it's so basically cardio came
up in a process of trying to find the
optimal shape for the gear teeth. Okay.
So remember 16 something 1600 that's the
years we are you know heavy mechanical
engineering and that's right before
steam engine I think
uh anyway
okay that's a history of uh cardioid so
we did that one so let's continue to do
what we have to do so yeah so We wanted
to update. We were talking about the
optical properties.
Uh,
okay.
No comments. Okay. So, let me just let
me just do something myself. Okay. Let's
see.
Make a backup. Open this.
Okay. So,
what I want to do is we did um
Okay, let's not worry about that. Let's
do this.
Now, next, the next thing I want to do
is to update this envelope, this image.
Okay, so this image is a bunch of
tangents. We're going to create a code
for that. Okay,
so let's do that. And there is also a
package. Um,
okay. So, here is my old code. This code
can be done by
um
Okay.
Okay, we need to update that. So, let's
add a code here.
Uh,
let's just
copy that. Let's Here's the old code.
Um,
let's see if that works. Shift enter.
Fantastic. Okay.
Now, is this uh is this aspect ratio?
Okay. The aspect ratio. I want the
aspect ratio to be true.
Aspect ratio.
Automatic. Okay.
Now, magnify.
Shift. Enter.
Okay. Delete. Delete it. Let's do it
again.
Shift.
Control N.
Shift enter.
Okay. Aspect ratio automatic. Okay. So,
shift enter. Okay. Evaluate any cells.
No.
Okay. But anyway, this is the graph we
want. So,
Same with the graphics. Let's try this.
That works. But um
and let's add a new images here.
That's gears. Okay.
Okay, this image is the new uh tangent.
So, let's rename it.
So, we name it
tangent rising sign something like that.
Okay.
Fantastic.
And uh then we um then um
Okay. Uh
well, that's old. So, we can delete it.
Okay. Then we got these two um gear
shape. Okay. Let's rename it.
Gear shape.
Gear shape. Okay. Copy it. Now copy the
URL. Extract the URL. Go to the talk
show. There is talk show. Go to the
bottom and uh let's uh new section.
Paste the URL.
Make make it into a figure image. Okay.
Same thing here. and uh change their
uh
location. Okay, move it to the current
uh there. Okay, and same thing that that
that that. So we have convenient command
that does lots of things. Okay, you can
kind of see them in the ping window.
Okay,
so you see so this is today's talk show
page and showing browser. So we have
documented the gear shape issue and that
is involute.
Okay, copy the file path and we talked
about involute and gear path.
Okay, that that is what those are for.
Mhm.
Go back to Emacs now. Actually
make it three. Let's add the title
there. Why not? Okay. Now go back to uh
close that. Go back to Yeah, this you
don't need anymore. Showing browser. So
now you got the new image pen slash.
This is how I call it p slash tangent
rising sign.
Uh
it was called pin splash but you know
pin splash by tangent.
Okay. So should I uh how should I name
it? Okay. So wait, you need to syntax
color that
um oh then and did we have the code? Did
you include the code? No. So you need to
include the codes.
Not that. Oh, we haven't. So let's let's
create a code ourself.
Um
so this is a code using the package. Now
let's uh close that. So what is this? Um
yeah. So now we need to code. Okay.
Pre uh wait search for pre. Yeah. So
actually that's a code. That's right.
And uh you what is the curve that you
want to draw the tangent of? The curve
would be
that.
Copy.
Okay, it's actually copy that. Actually,
just copy that.
So, paste there.
Delete that.
Uh this is the
uh curve. This is the range. Okay. And
so the curve will be cut
that.
Okay.
And here's the range. Now range is kind
of important because range is here.
Okay. So range from -5 to 10 in
increment of negative one. Okay. Did
that. Okay.
And now
now that's kind of the title. Uh then uh
plot range. Then you Okay. So you got
the plot range which is kind of
important. That's how like how much you
want to show. Okay. So
let's go here. Paste that. Delete that.
Okay. Then you have like this rainbow
coloring.
Well, we can do that later. Okay. So did
that. Did that. Okay. Comment that out.
So this is the like this is when you
want to generate a bunch of uh I can
show you. Okay. Run it. You'll return a
bunch of hue. So you you return a list
of hue and each hue is basically
rainbow. So the value is increment
corresponding to rainbow color. Okay. So
that's what what that generates. Okay.
Uh so we need to so but for now let's
just be that okay so if we copy that
and uh go here
paste it
shift enter
fantastic and beautiful okay now to be
sure let's add back the color okay I
mean the rainbow color because
let's D.
Okay, there's another issue. You see,
our tangent length is not big enough for
this picture.
It is desirable to have the tangent
length go outside, you know, feel the
the
canvas. Okay. So, let's modify our code.
So the tangent length here is will be um
the tangent length we have nine here it
can be actually 10 uh infinity okay so
let's say 20
copy
paste shift enter you see now it's
better now let's make the color okay so
if you want the color
uh now let's see how do you add a color
So you add the color. So width that
that. Okay. So you don't want to say
red.
So delete red.
Delete there. Okay. Now but in this line
you want to make it
a color here. Okay. And here is what you
want the color.
You basically want a hue
from Okay. So, God.
So you want a hue and you want uh
basically
-5 to 10
[sighs]
let's see let's say h you see the value
of hue needs needs to be between zero
and one. So you need some kind of map
that map that to zero and one. Well,
what you can do is um
t /ed by basically five. I think that
will do.
Well, and the um
actually you can just say t you you're
just u modular arithmetics. I think
does it actually automatically modular
arithmetics.
So looking up the documentation
but you see hue represents a color in
the HSB color space which with huh
anyway so hue
does it automatically
uh let's say 1.5 does it become.5
do modular arithmetics? No.
Uh but okay it doesn't but but does it
cut does the color display it does okay
so hue can be any the value actually can
be anything it will just automatically
kind of uh do a modular arithmetics
Okay, there's a lot of documentation you
have to read in detail.
I mean we can check you know what I want
to do. You see the parameters h the
parameters ss the parameters s
the parameters h sb and a must all be
between zero and one. Values of sb and a
outside this range can be clipped.
Values of h outside this range are
treated cyclically.
Fantastic. that is the
affirmation we are looking for. Okay.
So, so when we code just hue t that is
actually correct. We don't need to like
do a modular arithmetics ourself.
So anyway, so uh did we test it yet? No,
we didn't. So copy that. So paste it
here. Shift enter. Oh, we got the syntax
error somewhere. Oh yeah, there's that.
Uhhuh.
Okay. So, uh we done. So,
wait. Okay.
Wait. Uh you got the problem.
Oh, yeah. You got a problem. You You
made a mistake somewhere there. Undo.
Undo. Undo. Undo. Undo.
Undo.
You got You got this mistake.
Yeah. So that Yeah. So that that
that
at T. Okay.
Clean it. Copy it. Go to wuam language.
Paste it. Shift enter. Wait.
Shift enter. Fantastic. And beautiful.
Slightly different from our original.
You see our original. You see the
coloring is now different.
Can you see? because we didn't properly,
you know, adjust the hue even though
like it's kind of similar. I mean, so so
okay. So, so, so the reason is the hue
in the original version begins with
zero, which means red, you know, red,
orange, you know, um,
yellow and, you know, so on. But our but
our um
okay so we can do or we can we can
easily fix this by + 5 t + 5. Okay that
we'll move it to the beginning with red
is it okay not not exactly the same. Oh
that's where yeah that well because your
hue cycled a lot
you see. So actually so we need to
actually remap the hue. Okay. So let's
let's remap the hue. So this would be t
/ed by um
five I think kind of copy it.
Okay. So copy it. Let's just new one.
Okay. Shift enter.
Now that's better. You see just like
that. Fantastic and beautiful.
So this code this code is fantastic and
beautiful. This code
uh let's put that title there and that
and and put it back. Yes, put it back
and syntax and showing browser.
Oh, not here. Okay. So you need to I
mean so this is SAS talk show and you
can see
we have the code here but we need to
move this code to the um
to this envelope loop page. Okay. So
let's paste the code here showing
browser. So you can see updated graphics
and
updated code no requirement of package.
Fantastic and beautiful and I think
that's it. Uh should should that be it?
So I think that's it.
So let's do some clean up. Okay. So
let's make sure.
Should we delete the old one? You know
the old one.
You see we got detail. Um
you see the old one is not is more um
wide.
You see?
So I think the old one is more
beautiful.
So this has to do with aspect ratio.
You see? So I like the I like the old
one look. Okay. So it has to do with
aspect ratio. So what
um Okay. So let's let's uh update our
code to make that.
Okay. So plot range. Oh wait, did we say
aspect ratio? No.
Axis true.
Okay.
Uh
why is aspect ratio? No. Um
Okay.
So that Okay. So wait
and title that. Yeah, that's right. So
let's do that here. Paste. Shift enter.
Now what is the equation
2 * cosine plus t
so it rises.
So this is aspect ratio true.
cosine
sine cosine. Let's do sign. Okay.
Two times cosine. Let's see. Let's
update the graphics.
So like which one is more beautiful
doesn't really matter. It's like
so you see
and uh
okay I think that's it for today.
Let's see. How long have I been talking?
50 minutes.
So, we update the uh code. Yes, we did.
So, we I'm going to clean up myself
after the live stream. I'm going to
remove here. Uh update, you know. So,
anyway, we did what we wanted. Okay. So,
There's more to do. There's a lot more
to do. And also generate this one. Okay,
let's try that. Okay, because let's try
that, you know. So, save this first.
Save and title.
And uh this is this is this is my
Twitter. This is my Discord.
Do we have Leola? Okay.
Yeah, that's okay. So, let's do this
one. So, that one would be
that that involves osculating circle.
Okay. But we can do this one. This one
involves tangent.
You see um
where is the
okay close this
now do we uh envelope MP
here. Okay.
So, this we don't need anymore
really because
because we really do have easier code
there.
So, let's delete
anyway. So, let's do that.
Do we have it? No, we don't even have it
here.
Okay, I think that's it. That's it for
that today. So, just this.
Bye, guys. Fantastic.
Hello KHC. Bye.