foreign
day six I heard that this problem is
easy so I hope we can do it I'm gonna do
it fast and hopefully we can finish in
30 minutes or 20 part one part two then
I'm gonna start another video uh
possibly today possibly tomorrow on day
seven I heard that day seven is uh a bit
more difficult so I'm gonna code it in
Wolfram language uh
uh
uh a damn event of code okay day six so
let's begin uh let's double check a
video check audio check okay
and if you uh comments okay if you are
here comments and post questions on
wolfam language
okay so we are I'm gonna try to focus be
very focused and let's just uh code this
thing move fam language okay so uh who
found language
um yeah so let's begin it let's start
with fun language
okay new file start the kernel
we'll find language is free you can just
search for Sally wufam language you'll
find my complete tutorials about it and
the information about where to download
and stuff
okay well available code number three
uh okay so yeah ready
yeah ready okay so let's do it
the preparations are finally complete
you and the Elves leave camp on foot and
begin to make your way towards the star
fruit Grove oh my God finally As you
move through the dense undergrowth one
of the elves gives you a handheld device
gives you a handheld device he says the
idea has many fancy features but the
most important one is to set up right
now is the communication system however
because he's
heard you have significant experience
dealing with signal-based systems he
convinced the other elves that it would
be okay to give you their one man one
more functioning device surely you have
no problem fixing it so you need to fix
some device
about signal basis
as if you you know what do they link to
Jesus
oh leading to past
event of code problems okay let's see if
things as if inspired by commit comedic
timing the device emits a few colorful
Sparks
comedic timing okay Christmas to be able
to communicate with the elves the device
needs to log on to their signal okay the
signal is a series of seemingly random
characters that the device receives one
at a time so the device receives
seemingly random characters one
character at a time
okay to fix the communication system you
need to add a subroutine to the device
that detects a start of packet marker
okay in the data stream in the protocol
being used by the elves the start of a
packet is indicated by a sequence of
four characters that are all different
okay
in the protocol is used by the else the
start of the packet basically you your
device receives some signals a bunch of
characters and the the start of the the
start of a session is startup packet
there's a marker four characters
okay four different characters that
marks the Peak beginning of a session or
something the device will send you a
subroutine a data stream buffer your
personal input okay your subroutine
needs to identify the first position
where the four most recently received
characters were all different okay
okay specifically it needs to report the
number of characters from the beginning
of the buffer to the end of the first
search for character marker okay
for example suppose you receive the
following stream buffer basically your
string
a list of characters after the first
three characters mjq
uh
okay have been received there haven't
been another characters received yet to
find the marker
okay because it the marker is four
characters the first time a marker could
occur is after the fourth character is
received okay making the most recent
four characters mjqj
okay because J is repeated this isn't a
marker okay so you need to find
essentially the first
for unique
characters okay so
um
the first four unique characters
okay the first time a marker appears is
after the seventh character arrives okay
let's see one two three four five
six seven
so starting with G so previously you
have m j Q
m j Q
p
so you have more than four different
characters mjq p q
um
hello famio so uh so the so the first
time a marker appears is after the
seventh character arrives once it does
the last four characters received are j
p q m
okay jpqm
which are all different
jpqm which are all different in this
case your subroutine should report the
value 7.
okay
because the first start of packet marker
is complete after seven characters
okay
okay so basically for this input the
answer is seven
is complete after seven character seven
up to seven
okay here are a few more examples okay
so in this input the first marker after
character five okay
one two three four five let's magnify
okay one two three four five the first
marker after character five
so you want to find the first occurrence
of a sequence of four different
characters hello secondary account hello
Ryan
I believe Brian I have seen you before I
have seen all of you before
anyway back to the problem so so there
are some examples
Okay so
let's copy it okay let's copy it so we
go back to emacs so it's much easier
to
um
to see exactly what's going on
magnify
so it says Okay so
okay so let's see
so we got these problems
okay so it says one two three four five
okay
so
vwbj is the first occurrence so here is
six one two three four five
six
okay
so
let's let's mark them this way so in
this case is
pdvj
okay in this case 10 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
10.
okay in this case it's r f and T
uh and yeah okay in this case it's
eleven
one
one two three yeah
eleven Okay so
it's z q f r
let's see how it works
z c f z repeat f
repeat okay the first
four characters that's all different
that's all different from each other
and
okay is
so yeah okay so fzf that's not right
zfw Z that's not right because there's a
repeat now let's try this one
NZ and that's not right there's repeat Z
and R and repeat
okay so each time you look at four
characters as soon as there's four
different characters that counts
then at the end of that is your number
okay
that's that's the problem how many
characters need to be processed before
the first start of the packet marker is
detected okay so that is the problem
okay
that is a problem now let's think how to
use up this
um
you want the first four different
characters
the first four different characters
in sequence so
so you have to do is you check four
characters at a time
then you move on by one character
so check the first four characters then
check the second
for character starting with the second
index then start with the third index
okay so you just go through the index
the lengths of the string minus four or
something
you know you start with index zero if
the if your programming language let's
say the in Wolfram language the index
start with one okay so you start with
the first character then second
character up to the length of the string
minus four something like that or minus
three
so as soon as you find the four
characters are different you stop so
basically you write a loop okay so you
can write a loop to do that
um yeah so check check check check check
so given a string you check the check
check check check check yeah
okay let me show you a efficient way to
do this okay very efficient
okay first of all let's um
let's make this pretty okay so I'm going
to show you
uh
this is HTML mod I'm using emacs I'm
using Sapphire keys and this is Xposed
keyboard and this is what I got you can
search sa fly keys to find my emacs
package and you can search Sabi Xbox
keyboard to find my review detail I
recommend okay
so now
so you have to do here
let's make a definition list okay
so delete that delete that part
okay uh
okay that's our input
uh that's our input
and
okay so efficient coding with a language
let's do this quickly so input so first
of all you need the input okay so input
string
let's say the input X
input equals so let's just take one okay
that's a string okay I'm using subwoofer
mod which is the Emax mod that lets me
code Wolfram language I do that in emacs
because it's more efficient to type in
manipulate okay
um
okay so here's the input so you stream
partition let me let me show you how to
do this okay move from language this is
uh
okay that's a function we want and let's
look up the documentation it will just
take a string and uh
turns it into a list of strings and by
cutting each nth element so you know if
you have a b c d
then you say stream partition 2 he'll
return a list of a b and c d so if you
say 3 then it's gonna be ABC DEF
ghi you know if you have a long string
then you you can then you can add a uh
offset
so if you have a b c d e f g then you
say
partition two offset 1 the result is
a b b c
CD you know there's one character that
repeats so in this case we want to
partition it okay so let me show you
stream partition one Partition by four
with an offset of one okay
so this x two
let me show you how it shows rinsing
Wolfram language
there it is you see let's see b b f b
then
vwbj that's right then wbj
P that's right you see okay so now we so
now all we have to do is map a function
to see which one is uh four unique
characters okay this is who fan language
very
different in other languages you don't
have this string partition you have to
write a loop
which is also very easy but this is this
is a function of programming open
language very efficient so now you just
write a function that map to Okay so
you just map a function to this list X2
map level one we don't care it's so by
default this one so map function so what
the function will be
the function will be okay X is a string
you want to see if um
each character is one it is the same so
let me do let me show you uh how you
know normally you can just take the
index of a string
you know for example
stream index for example in Python that
then you compare
um
that you know then you do this for
for zero one you want to make sure all
of them are different
so you can turn it into a list and test
for intersection in python or many ways
but let me show you the efficient
Wolfram language way
so
a function yeah you make sure you want
to make sure the four different strings
are different okay string partition
okay so you can simply do an equal sign
so string partition again partition it
that with uh all string to list
now string to list these rifle so let's
let's do partition okay let's do
partition partition just by one
Let's test it
we can run this code in here so you see
there is the output
you see ABCD that's that's what these do
so so now
now you stream partition it now you just
want to apply the
equality test to them all
so
okay
let me show you so that's it I actually
that's it that is the solution
uh wait
same queue you need to yeah you need to
replace the head
you may not know what I'm doing but
um let's let me just get let me just
finish the problem quickly okay
if you have questions about this the
Wolfram language just ask me okay
so let's try
let's try this okay
same Q
uh
let's look up what's the reverse of same
Q uh
on the same queue okay
what
oh yeah the spelling is wrong so
on the same queue let's see
and same and same that that should
return
Force
that's right
so if you have
then if it's three that's true you see
in open language the equality test same
Q is the equality test okay it's like
javascripts equal equal or like pythons
double equal similar because the
equality is very complicated in
different languages because it depends
on the type or does it measure the
reference of a list or does it actually
test the content of at least things like
that so equality testing is very
complicated in different languages so in
inform language you have the same queue
let me show you okay
so if you go to uh not not English
okay
sorry
dot info
okay that's my website
okay so you go down go down go down
there's a Wolfram language complete
tutorial and uh and where you can
download it for free okay and then you
go to equality testing Boolean true
false equality test so here's all about
how do you test the quality in new fan
language and one particular thing of the
ecology test in Wolfram language is that
you can sequence them
which you cannot do in most languages
because for example in most languages
once you do for example a b you know you
cannot say C you cannot do that
because a and a equals to B they will
evaluate to true and false then true and
false
is it equals to C then of course not
because C is usually not so you cannot
do that but in Wolfram language you can
okay so that's a that's a interesting
aspect so that's why we can do this on
the same queue that takes tests
inequality
so for example it can be anything so all
of them if all of them none of them are
equal then it's true otherwise if you
have something equal it's false okay so
we can do this one shot and
and it will uh
get you the answer so let's run it
so for this
you see the here is true and
so that's it so
and you want to take the first one let's
just take the first one then
the first uh
the first element that's true okay
now the code the code I'm writing now is
not utmost sufficient
but you know I just want to solve the
problem first because if you you know
there are a lot of scenarios suppose the
string is one million characters in lots
of things like that uh
I'm not you know
I
I want to solve the problem quickly
because otherwise you know I have to
explain everything uh it takes too long
so so now you just want to find the
first element that's true how do you do
that you can you can do you can use the
function positions okay
let's see
extract position okay so you can use
extract or
get elements get elements part
um get parts by a field function no you
want to know the index of the first
occurrence so
cases okay get Elements by pattern okay
we want
um DVM and change them and sort member
there it is this function position so it
let me show you okay
so position let's say three four five
and if you say 4 it will return two
because the the pattern for occurs on
the index 2.
you see okay so
uh so you but you want the first one
because otherwise you of you want to be
efficient once you find the first one
stop okay so let's look up I think
there's the
now God what
is my internet down
hey Coffee House
okay here's position level spec in okay
keeps the position of the first n object
found so in Wolfram language if you just
need the first one item you need you
want to give that
uh argument because otherwise you know
it's inefficient so the level spec is
gonna be just first level
one and return the first item okay for
example it's
show this you see two and stop
but in case you have lots of force
you know you still return two but what
time language improved now you have you
can have now
extraneous comma actually uh
okay so but if you
if you don't have this one
you see you have many occurrences so so
this is what you want so essentially
just put that here
and you are done
okay so let's try again
you want to test for true yeah so true
here
two okay that's the that's the answer
now let's try the other parts okay
so
so back so this string is six okay
so this string is six
run it
three
okay what
what's uh
how code is incorrect
oh yeah so wait uh so
oh yeah so you need to add four yeah of
course you need to add four
because it wants the end of the position
not the beginning okay so let's try it
again
seven you want to add three because this
is off by one let's see
let's see yeah I'm sure at three but let
me uh that's not
the um
you know let's just get it to work let's
not be too logical and stuff okay so
this so check so the third example
should be 10
check see the bottom check okay the
fourth example
should be 11.
check okay see the bottom can you see
yeah okay so yeah
okay good we solved the first problem
now let's get the input okay hold on a
second let's put it back
and it's let's worry about that later so
let's get the input
I want to finish this quickly oh okay a
big one
this is the input
now this is a talk show okay
close reopen go to the bottom
New Page
search for Advent of code let's drop it
to diet
copy that save this the window code day
6 and
for today's date okay
okay so copy that cut wait we open copy
the link
final path make a link
okay there it is and now go back
copy the code okay and go back to from
language all we have to do is paste it
here
big string
big
Wheel of Fortune big Chun oh one
one zero zero are you sure yes I'm sure
let's just run it let's just do it one
one zero zero
yes shut the up that's the right
answer of course continue to part two
okay part two now uh now let's
yeah that's so that's the solution
colors syntax it showing browser again
so syntax code
so that's a solution
you know at least you can make it one
line
uh okay so next
so how long have they been has it been
30 minutes okay next
so the problem six is to be supposed to
be easy okay
so your device is communication system
is correctly detecting packets but still
isn't working it looks like it also
needs to look for messages a start of
message marker
so wait before it's what the what the
is the marker before the marker is
startup packet marker you know it is not
a good puzzle not a good start you know
a story like puzzle because when you do
this kind of thing especially for
advantage of code for Christmas you know
you want to make it not technical
because he's talking you know the way he
write the puzzle is
insinuating the Internet iptcp Protocol
you know you have packet you know like
what the is a packet you know then
then now he starts to talk about startup
message marker okay but
if your goal is to write something like
Christmas spirit you know you don't you
um
it's a minor issue but you know but
ideally you don't you want to avoid this
kind of
you know
specialized knowledge about packets
about handshake he didn't mention
handshake you know but uh you know
marker so anyway startup message marker
is just like a startup packet marker
except it consists of 14 distinct
characters rather than four okay and 14
okay so the second problem is trivial
okay
copy that now let's do part two
okay here's a code
and uh all you have to do is change it
to what 14
Okay so
instead of 4 is 14 and instead of 3 it's
13 here so
14 minus one okay
so let's check some input
okay so this input result is 19 let's
double check
run it
19. fantastic are you sure yes I'm sure
now let's get the
puzzle input okay
um okay where is it
copy cut
okay back to the Wolfram language code
now post humongous
okay it's uh the output buffer is long
oh my God the e-max
let's go to messages buffer and it's
gonna take a while when you know this is
the emacs problem when you have a huge
long line e Max becomes super super slow
like every operation takes several
seconds you know anyway so there it is
uh is that the answer
same answer hmm
19 okay I think that's the answer
okay close it
so you can do that do that that will
suppress the output okay run it again
oh there's the answer okay this one's
going somehow we yeah before it was too
long so the answer is that 2 4 21 okay
it's just
um
are you sure yeah I'm pretty sure let's
just do it
submit okay part two do it
that's the right answer complete
fantastic so
it's 40 minutes today so that's it for
today uh should I do another one problem
day seven today or should I
do it tomorrow
let's do it tomorrow
okay so that's it for today and uh let's
clean up our code so that
um
I don't want these long
thing okay so
let's just just run this okay let's so
the problem is 19. I mean the solution
okay pop this out pop this in so that's
today's talk show
then a window code is 6 in Wolfram
language and uh
let's make it one single line okay so
because uh so yeah so now let's talk
about something random fun okay
so I started a
uh I was talking I was chatting with um
the end of a code with ziofa you know he
mentioned uh something and uh very
interesting so you know he's uh skim
this
you know he showed
Solutions in scheme disk you know
so A View program you know interesting
languages you know check it out
and this uh crochet and this guy
actually
you know did something extra to draw the
things color them
that's interesting so anyway so
so we were talking about one line
programming and that's very interesting
so I actually
uh wrote some articles about it
one liner okay so check out you might
want to check out my Twitter
uh your CEO about one-liners and I have
a challenge you know my challenge is
that
for a band of code any day of this year
this year because last year you know I
didn't do any P4 so but I'm I know about
this year so let's go back to calendar
any of this problem including those I
haven't seen I can call them in one
single line
in either Wolfram language or in
JavaScript or I can also do it in scheme
disk okay but I request you pay me
uh fifty dollars if you want me to see
that you know
but I'm you know for but for Wolfram
language I'm doing it already anyway so
um so
so
but I want to mention yeah so it's
interesting problem okay
so I started to write an article you
know one line is you know because I do
this kind of thing all day and every day
in 1990s so these Advent of codes you
know this is very City to me actually
because I you know I've been there you
know I I was young before so
yeah but the coding you know so there's
one liner which is a very popular uh
thing uh you know you check for Speed
efficiency you check for Elegance you
know one liner can you do that in your
favorite language uh in this code Golf
and code obvious
obfuscation you probably have seen us so
code Golf and code obfuscation
their goal is that you want to write a
solution in your language to a problem
such that your code is minimum count of
characters
okay and it can get we can it can be
very it can be gets very extreme because
there's C code obfuscation competition
you know you you know this is amazing
but
code Golf and code obfuscation those
problems you know minimum accounts of
characters that's suitable for
procedural languages
such as C C plus plus Pearl
in particular because those languages
they have wild ad hocs syntax and they
have lots of Tricks cleverness because
their programming language is not
consistent so you do all sort of you
know a bitmap bitmap bit mask bit
operations you do all sorts of Tricks so
you you have a code something like that
you know garbage but it does it serve us
you know it solves something okay so
that's code golf code obfuscation very
popular okay
in year 2000 so I don't know about today
but I think they still exists
for example there's Vim golf which is
different but golf basically means the
shortest okay so but for functional
programming this kind of thing doesn't
apply much because functional
programming is usually very consistent
syntax there's not many tricks the way
like C or cleverness there's not many
crevice but there is a lot
advanced mathematics functional
programming currying Lambda calculus y
combinator combinator wire company
there's a lot of Advanced Computer
Science theoretical computer science
that apply so when you so for functional
programming you want to do
you want to try to do one line
which does not count the number of
characters but rather
your whole program is one single line
connected by either nested function or
function pipe to each other no separate
function definition okay no separate
variable that's what you want to do and
you can do that with functional language
the the two essential
necessary thing is that the function
language must be able to write a
function that takes a function as
argument and return a function as
argument and apply a function you know
with the argument Lambda and this
function must be anonymous
you know you you your language must have
the ability to Define
Anonymous functions and apply it on the
same line you know so that's the most
essential uh necessity for the for the
language to be able to do one liner and
this is this exercise one liner is very
interesting and critical okay so if you
are into scheme or fam language closure
closure can also do that I'm pretty sure
JavaScript also
they can do that you can combine
arbitrary you know big program into one
single line
so you want to try to challenge yourself
see if you can do it okay
for the Advent of code this year I would
say problem number five
is a key I mean it is starting to get
non-trivial problem one two three four
you can do in one line easily and also
number six you know number six is just
you know today we did so but problem
five
it it will take some Ingenuity it will
take your Mastery of that particular
language scheme within language or
closure but however common lisp and
communities and emag is cannot do it
okay I'm telling you this is interesting
fact so you can challenge me you know
show me you can you know
yeah common lists and email address
you again you can really do it because
um anyway so that's it for today thank
you guys for watching if you like my
stuff
go to my website okay uh pay me okay so
there's a
PayPal Amazon gift card you know or
patreon me Amazon keep gift card you
need to it needs to be Amazon USA not
Amazon
Germany friends so I because I cannot
get the money
okay thank you guys for watching bye
oh yeah so to make this one line all you
have to do is
uh you just move these two you know this
X2 here and and that's