not GTECH oh do you know do the right
thing
test
test so is the audio now
no it's good thank you so I'm going to
talk about okay the first of all I'm
going to change the topic I stream here
so I'm going to talk about that
select all paste tap ok santosh show
2019 March 6th I'm going to talk about
Emacs off like he's blocking vocabulary
basically I'm going to use Emacs to
create to write blogs so you see my
workflow with Emacs you see a demo of
scarf like ease you see my custom Emacs
command on the Left panel here so that's
my daily routine because you know I
write like 5 blogs
I write blogs on Emacs I'm programming
and web dev on keyboards are music and
literature you know a bunch of things so
I'm gonna do that today I'm you know I'm
just gonna going to show you how I do
that so this is my blog this is my
programming block so by the way you can
find my block by going to sorry dot info
okay wait
sorry dog sorry dog okay then you can
see I have several domains sorry dot
info ago a max sorry dot info is for
math and programming related stuff and
keyboard now ergo Emacs is for Emacs
Emacs blogs Emma Chris and everything in
ax now go back what English is for
literature writing linguistics stuff and
then I have music and art and in others
so so I'm going to do why don't I start
actually three people watching great
thank you guys for coming by so I'm
going to show you how I use Emacs to
write a blog then I'm going to okay
that's that's it basically that's it so
I'm going to add
first of all let's do a Korean page so
you know here's a Unicode you see I
talked about it yesterday Unicode it's
which is fascinating and what I'm going
to do you see in in the last week I
added several new pages so on the left
left panel you can see many pages so
what I added are these very interests
very interesting things let me show you
Chinese Japanese Arabic the mono Gary
something like that which is used by
Hindi in India and Bengali also used in
India
tamio also used in India Tibetan that's
very interesting one you are seeing a
minute and hero greif that's the
Egyptian stuff Linear B which is ancient
like ancient Greek and Kooning form that
is also very interesting so let me gonna
I'm going to show you the pages so
switch tab so I so this is Chinese and
if you know if you guys want I can show
you how to input Chinese you see this is
very fancy if you are not Chinese or
Japanese you know it might be very
interesting to you so I'm going to like
I'm going to show you how to I type
Chinese so this is Chinese page
this is Japanese page very complex
writing system this is Arabic very
interesting too you know Latin alphabet
language uses because it's from right to
left and so this is Devanagari something
like that or the varnak reason it's used
in it's used for several languages it's
used by Hindi one of the primary
language in India
and and a bunch of others actually quite
a few uses this script so there's
bangari which looks pretty similar also
used in India for several languages I
mean these are writing systems
tamio also using India very beautiful I
mean you got all these curves very
interesting and Tibetan also looks very
fancy you know it's like it's like you
know one of the languages you see in
Star Trek
you know Klingon all the stuff you know
actually to create a alien language it's
pretty easy you know all you do is you
change each English alphabet you know
ABC you change them to some other you
know characters symbols then immediately
like you have a you know alien looking
language in fact that's one of the some
of the video games - that Egyptian you
know let me show you okay so you guys
keep the comments coming okay so if you
have a question so anything you know you
know you want me to talk about just say
it so I'm going to show you yeah
actually what in English okay Zelda okay
let's go to such I'm gonna show you a
very interesting thing sorry
Zelda language
okay so the there is legend
drop the language it's not easy Oda
there it is inscriptions you see so
Zelda is a video game and in this video
again you have this alien looking all
Asians looking inscriptions by the way
Zelda is a great game but actually I
only played Zelda Ocarina back in 1999
1999 but oh my god that's my favorite
game you know because it's adventure and
stuff you know but anyway so in this
Zelda breath of the wild wild a wind I
think it should be wind breath of the
wild ok wild you have so you know you
have these doors that opens like that
and you have inscriptions on it and
someone someone actually deciphered it
you know you just change each symbol
basically they just take take the
English alphabet and change it to map it
to a strange you know art symbol then
you get these so if you put it together
it's like very silly dungeon tension he
just repeat dungeons you know so you
know so this is a map of the symbols in
alphabet and there's a video yeah so
anyway so if you want to create a
alien-looking language you know in
written form or ancient script that's
you know it's actually very easy to do
so back to unicode so you know you have
Egyptian stuff you have linear be Cunha
form okay let's close name cross cross
cross cross cross cross cross cross
cross
clothes go back to my Emacs lock reopen
in browser so I'm going to add a new
page Korean so let's begin okay first of
all actually I need to go to a Unicode
page so I'm going to add a Korean
somewhere here okay after Japanese so
first of all go here
copy the URL back to Emacs paste here
paste okay and link of Phi by the way
every command I call you Maxim is shown
on the left side you can see the command
name and the key I'm using I'm using a
ball rack keyboard layout and let's
magnify and I'm using also using soft
like he's okay now you can look at my
black keyboard layout by let's go to my
keyboard blog and you can see layout and
here you can study all about it you know
there's alternate alternative layout
this Cote
there's for AK so I'm going to just copy
it and show you here so back to way
close this so back here that that that
that showing browser and magnify okay so
I'm using vorak layout and I'm using
soft like he's so because of the Verilog
out you might see the letter strange and
also I'm using soft like ease which is
sufficient so you never see me press
ctrl key so anyway let's add the
Japanese so Japanese here I mean not
Japanese Korean so copy this link paste
and Unicode the new file name will be
Korean coffee that Unicode Korean TV
that that that that that that actually
that that closed that way
what's that frame okay capitalized
sentence okay so this is a new page it
doesn't exist yet I just created
so and I have this command I'm going to
call so meta X X our copy HTML by link
enter so what this does is that it just
copied this page the Japanese just
duplicated just copy it into this new
page so now if I press ENTER you can see
it's there now should show in browser
you can see it's just a copy of the
Japanese so back in Emacs now we're
going to change the title actually close
this move here select copy back to here
open change title select go
paste there okay now it says Korean now
update the date stamp
I have a date stamp here magnify so code
a command update our code date stamp so
now you can see it's today's date and
this is a new one so I'm gonna remove
that then over here we don't need it and
don't need it what's going on okay don't
need it delete delete delete delete
delete delete delete delete
slack slack slack slack select okay
delete delete delete delete delete
delete okay and delete now showing
browser now you can see it's empty so
basically I'm just like kind of copying
the template so now close this back to
my blog so now I actually need to add
Korean text so what I do okay this will
be fun I go to sorry wait okay so go
back to sorry info and magnify and
scroll down and go to Unicode
now in Unicode I can just type Kor it
upset it updates in real-time hi II
a n oh it doesn't so I'm trying to
search all Unicode characters that
contains the name Korean and it
basically showed up empty like this not
many characters it that contains the
what Korean but actually there are few
the first four doesn't show but the last
one is interesting actually so we're
gonna copy that because I'm gonna look
into what they are and you know it could
be very interesting and you know I'm
going to like dig study what they are
and you know so open the Korean page
magnify the page paste it here wait did
I oh okay
so it doesn't show in Emacs except the
last one
Korean standard the symbol that's very
interesting I haven't seen it before
okay but why is it no Korean you know in
Unicode because the Korean Korean
alphabet is called jum jumbo I think so
let's try that so let go
J u M oh okay so it's code okay so it's
called tango tango by the way Hanko
means Korean you know that's I know
because in Chinese the Korean country in
Chinese we is is called Hank or Hangul
so in English you know Hangul is so
apparently I'd say tango is the English
pronunciation of the Korean country and
which is similar to how Chinese code you
know Chinese Japanese Korean all these
countries are they share a large huge
amount culture and many of it are from
you know originated from China
you know because China is the big land
in Asian so anyway tango okay let's look
at the comments
the hey Vlad hey Brad I knew you before
so all runs once so this this runs from
Diablo someone even made a key cap set
based on them yes I've seen that I I
need to add that okay actually that's
let's add once today actually so I'm
gonna do that so add item so copy paste
copy paste add runs so if we have time
we're gonna add runs but now let's for
now it's back to Korean okay vectored
Korean back to the Korean page so we got
the Korean characters but actually these
are not all oh yeah because I just I
just search for Ju so actually I should
search for H a and G u L now this looks
like the whole set of Korean yes in its
book so by the way I wrote this
JavaScript that such Unicode so you can
use it you know this is the URL and tell
your friends blog about it you know I'd
be happy to get more users so it's
interactive everything you type the
result shows up here it's a JavaScript I
can I can sure it show the code to you
if you guys want just type the comments
let me know if we have time we're gonna
I'm gonna show that so but anyway so we
copy the Koreans put it here wait yeah
pull it here way and do paste new line
and now select this part actually yeah
okay select this narrow to region now
escape move to top now I'm going to
change space to new line so I call
command saw space to new line I wrote a
command that
that so there it is magnify now I'm
going to go am aqua so let me show you
what I'm going to do so first well widen
so you see this is my web page right I
mean let's look in browser so okay you
got a bunch of a Korean characters but
what actually what I want is is I call
the command look at the command on the
Left panel
you see that's called Casa HTML mark
Unicode so what it does is that it it it
puts a HTML mark tag around the
character character and also shows the
Unicode hexadecimal one one zero zero
and the Unicode character name now let's
show in browser so showing browser you
can see now it's big it's big there
because of CSS code now what I need to
do is I have to do this to all these
characters now why do i why do I use
this because once you have that then you
must Hoover over it he'll show it let me
show you okay so let me show you in
Safari so because in Safari I have
JavaScript turned on so let's go to
command Safari because I openly open in
Safari okay that's the command enter
there it is in Safari now if I move the
mouse over this character now you can
see that pop up to tip and it tells you
the Unicode name and the Unicode
hexadecimal for that character so I need
to add this to all these characters and
how do you do that you can do it this
way for example I'm going to show you
look look at the left panel for the
command I'm coding so do it move down to
it move down to it
move move down great okay so show in
browser so you see we got a few but this
is repetitive
so Emacs key Marco comes to the rescue
so let's see how how we use that so I'm
gonna select the whole block
okay I'm gonna narrow to region in order
to region you so that you can you know
you you limit your buffer to show only a
specific part you want so you can avoid
you know find and replace other parts
you don't want to change so anyway so we
are now on this so what I'm going to do
is start a macro recorder macro and
apply the macro to all the line lines so
look at again look at the left panel to
see to see the command I'm coding so I'm
going to start record macro move cursor
to the right call the command stop Marco
now I have one macro be coded now I'm
just going to apply that marker to all
these lines so first of all a comb or
the lines I want now I'm going to call
the command MX apply macro to
regionalize enter.we it's all done you
see it's all done now widen to see the
whole buffer okay and shrink the spaces
now I'm going to add a dive tag around
it so there it is because that showing
browser yay so it's essential
essentially done okay I'm gonna let's
show this in Safari refresh you see now
now if I move kusa around each character
it will it will show the pop up so this
is this page is almost done but not yet
okay let's look at the comments you see
any hey Jack hey Matthews okay if you
have any
questions just post it okay type it so
so now am i doing good so far so so now
I have with a you know I have this
Korean page almost done
not exactly yet but I'm gonna talk about
why yet but beef but there's one more
thing we need to do we need to add a
index on the Left panel
okay we need to add in the index on the
panel now the Left panel if you on on
this page if you scroll scroll down
let's okay let's go down you can see the
panel is at the bottom over here so it's
fairly long from line four zero six to
line four ninety so you see this this is
the panel the first one is Unicode Aman
emoticons the second one is Unicode hand
gestures and if you look at the browser
here you can see Monica emoti you know
emoji hand gestures in food so that is
this this this this part you know it's
long so I'm going to do so we need that
we need to add a Korean you know this
new page we just created Korean into
right after the Japanese here okay so
let's do that so first of all I'm gonna
copy this part okay show the left panel
I'm going to copy it copy and then I'm
going to call the command so find
we-fest
text gaza find replace text okay and i'm
going to paste it here it's a big one
okay remove the empty lines near the
bottom okay then enter okay and then
it's all going to ask me we're a stream
okay now I don't have the I don't know
what should we face string yet so let's
cancer it for now now I'm I'm going to
add that with a string so such
for Japanese wait
such j AP okay so this line is for
Japanese let's magnify so this line is
Japanese now I'm going to copy it new
line
paste so we just copied this line
Japanese now change this line to Korean
so copy file name so I'm going to just
let's just make this so it's easier to
see you see that the two lines of
Japanese are here so I'm going to so
this file name is Korean and okay and
this part we don't want but actually we
do want you see for the index here each
language each rating system there is one
unicode character that represented you
know if you know the unicode character
just so that people can easily see you
know oh this kind of this this shape is
interesting let's see what that is you
know it so it kind of represent the
whole script so we what we need to do
now is we need to choose one character
that kind of like represent Korean you
know now this is a little bit tricky
because because if you do not speak
Korean I mean if you do not know that
language sometimes you you could you
know pick a character that is just
totally wrong you know you know for
example if you are trying to do this for
Chinese and you pick you picked a
character you know let's say for example
you don't know what it means and
you put it there and when Chinese see
you know Chinese and it says you
know think that's bad but anyway for
Korean the correct Korean writing system
they are actually alphabets you know it
it does it does not look
like alphabets but actually they are
they are off of alphabets such that
unlike the English alphabet alphabet
where you know each character is just
side by side the Korean alphabet they
they can place you know they have these
you know squares in circles you place
one you know you put a few of them
together that forms one would that's how
Korean alphabet works you know I don't
actually know Korean so you know you
might go to Wikipedia and and actually a
lot YouTube YouTube videos that teach
you the basics of Korean but anyway so
forth for now I'm just going to pick
something I think that looks like Korean
very much you know actually I have to
change because you know usually so when
I do this page I will have to like take
one hour of reading to do that but for
now let's just say let's just use this
character okay so again mock Unicode and
we are done actually yes
so shrink the whitespace shrink the
whitespace shrink the white space show
in browser page down page down okay you
see the Korean there now we need to do
this for every page like ain't everyone
of this Unicode page for example let's
go to APL okay now if you scroll down
you see you don't see Korean here
because we haven't added yet now let's
add it so I'm going to select the
Japanese copy okay now now cokes are
find to replace text paste enter now
replace string okay I know what replace
string I want now so replace string is
going to be these two lines so replace
the Japanese
by the Japanese and Korean law
copy go to mini buffer paste okay that's
a repay string I want enter now what
directory I want to do the Find and
Replace okay that's the right track
directrix Audion for comp enter now file
path rejects HTML yes
enter Oh HTML files now right change to
file yes
fixed case in such yes fixed case in
replacement yes make backup yes
oh it's all done now it's very nice now
this you see this tool is super nice for
find/replace
and for programming language refactor
you know so you know you might try it
it's it's a package I wrote now if you
just search for this name so find
replace text Emacs you'll find you'll
find the package it's on me it's on my
Appa so anyway so this output this means
all these files
the pink line the pink lines are files
and the yellow lines are the occurrence
of the replacement so you can see I
wrote down you can see all these change
you know they are the same for every
file so all these files are changed now
close that show in browser again now
let's go to emoji scroll down scroll
down you can see Korean there it's so
it's done okay so this page is basically
essentially done but but I need to
upload to my website
okay let me read the comment for a
little bit
sometimes my Emacs okay so sometimes my
Emacs cannot show the Unicode especially
face icons yeah that is a common problem
first of all first of all make sure now
on Mac and Windows
if you always update your operating
system that should fix the problem
because unicode now every year there's a
new version of Unicode around June and
every so every year they add about maybe
a hundred characters or sometimes a few
hundred and these days every year they
also add new emoji you know like every
year you have maybe 10 more emoji so so
for example today's right now is 2019
and in coming June they will have like
more emojis and basically no font will
show it but until after after next year
then Microsoft in Apple's you know they
will update their fund and you know then
you will see the new emoji now on Linux
it's always a little bit problematic you
know you we are always missing a lot
you know many much you want to show this
month not much you can do but anyway so
on Linux
what you can do is you go to you know go
to my Unicode page scroll all the way
down and you will see download found
okay then there's this font you can
install Google note ho is a good one
because they try to cover every
character in Unicode so they have like
tens of ants you know so if you are
missing found make sure that you have
you know if Unicode is not showing on
your screen if you see squares and or
question marking stuff it's probably
first of all check if you have the font
installed so go to you know just install
Google note oh yeah
okay so but I want to know how to solve
it without replacing your font well when
when a Unicode is not showing up on your
screen there are several possible
problems and not just one not just
because of phone there are several
possible problems first of all is
because you don't have the font the
second reason is that even if you have
the correct font sometimes the okay the
the the whole situation is fairly
complex you know each application
you know the usually the operating
system provide a technology or mechanism
called font substitution technology now
for Mac and for Windows they have their
own names for that technology I don't
know what is and in for Linux you have
your you know you also have a font
substitution technology you know but
each one has their different names for
Mac or Windows or Linux so what the font
substitution technology is that on a
page you know you can mix different
languages or emoji right and if the
application do not see a particular
Unicode it tries to look in a font the
current found if that character is not
in a current fund then it tries to
search for a found that contains that
character then use you know that fonts
character food you know for the
character so that usually works but
sometimes it does not work for example
let me show you for example this is
Firefox I have I have this linear B now
linear b is a asian language you can see
this or unicode okay now if i copy the
URL and i go to i go through google
chrome paste the URL enter
oh it works okay so there's something
that doesn't work let me that means
Cunha foam yeah okay you see the Cunha
foam is not showing in Google Chrome
however in Firefox if I go to Cunha foam
it shows and if I go to Safari scroll
down Cunha foam it also works but it
does not work in Google Chrome so you
see that the reason it doesn't work is
usually very complex you know it's these
states the technology you know it's very
very complex you know I'm on the same
machine you know so it doesn't work so
it's the same situation on Linux it's
it's probably was and you know so anyway
so that's a state of art you know
something you know it not everything
works perfectly and you just have to try
to find out why so let's go back to read
some questions and I'm going to okay
hold on let me continue to let me
continue my final step for this unicode
page for in black archive don't mean to
curse that curse that curse that curse
at Japanese okay so we added a Korean
page but it's not on my website here yet
you see this is my ex audit our info URL
it's not here yet so I'm going to add it
so what I do is to Asia Asia is a shell
written in eMac excuse yeah excuse me I
just had pizza so issue is a shell
written in Emacs Lisp and what I do is I
call this command saw interactive a
brief so these are a briefs but with
interactivity you see now I first enter
our sink now I press Enter
that means to it so this will sync my
local files to my web server so I know I
need to type a password so I'm going to
type this secret password okay it's done
you see this this is done by the Emacs
commands I insert what which by the way
is not public obviously so now you see
it add it changed it uploaded all these
files you see all these files has
changed why because remember we change
the index you know for all these Unicode
files okay now let's close I shall close
I shall now go back to three browser and
sorry website yes and refresh okay
now scroll down Korean there it is
Korean yeah now it's done
okay so now it's finally done but now
I'm going to take you know I'm going to
read about Korean you know for one hours
so that you know this is not a good good
page I mean this is not final quality
because for people reading this you know
you want to organize these characters so
that they make sense to the Korean
language not just a bunch of you know
Unicode characters use you know for
Korean you want to organize them for
example alphabets you know maybe order
them and sometimes they also have have
digits like you know maybe if let's see
if I can guess which which one are
digits like 0 1 2 3 4 let me cheat and
see the pop-up
so I I don't know yeah usually like each
language they have some characters four
digits yeah I don't see it so anyways
yeah so I have to go and read about it
and organize them too but let's let's
cheat let's go through the Korean page
so here Korean let's say and go up
magnify go up see digit
oh they wait no that's not it okay it
looks like Korean doesn't I mean it
probably has digits but not not in a
characters I'm showing so I might be
missing some characters because not all
the Unicode characters use the used for
Korean start with the word hang hang GU
you know because right now all these
characters they start with the word
Hangu so you know and also these
characters I need to let this go here
these characters
if I Marco to regionalize okay yeah so
those characters I need to do something
about I think that's it that's about it
for today let's let's look at the
questions let go your way around and off
a bit
hi have you seen the Unicode update what
do you mean Unicode update yeah okay so
any any more questions about Unicode so
anyway that that's the way I walk with
my update my web pages for example for
example let me show you what I'm gonna
do
so you know I have updated I have just
created a new page for Unicode Korean so
I'm gonna copy the path and I'm going to
go here create a new section paste link
of I it and add a paragraph view in
browser you see I have a new section for
Korean and I'm going to call command
let's go here so called the command
Sonic atom entry so this create a atom
entry which is a web feed you know our
RSS web feed so you know that you know
it tells people I have a Korean page so
close that save go to issue a sink and
it's uploaded to my website you see now
when when people who are subscribed to
my programming block they all get a
notice you know there's a new page
Korean so that you know so this is how
you know I use emacs to do my daily
routine of writing blogs so I was
planning so we've done Korean so we
like cross it out I was planning to do
another page which is very different
it's for English vocabulary so I can do
that or I can do another page for runs
runs are also interesting you know I
need to add to my Unicode what else so
yeah so that's about it for today's
topic any any more questions so do you
like me to do the do you want me to do
another page which is an English
vocabulary page type it type questions
or else let's say do I want it do I want
to do it yeah let me know okay so let's
look at runs runs Wikipedia yes
yeah so I'm going to add you know I know
keyboard IO has runs yeah so it's very
fascinating runs you know these are
ancient scripts so anyway so and let's
look at X on the keyboard okay so this
is my keyboard website you know I'm just
starting to ramble so you know Saudi
Kibo website and there is a go Nam ik
keyboards and many of these are very
interesting and of course I am using you
know I'm using the I'm using this one ok
let's put it back so I'm using canoes
Kinesis advantage and well I was going
to show you some of the interesting okay
yeah so keyboard IO I think keyboard IO
has a custom key cap that that uses runs
that's what you are talking about I mean
you were talking about that so I don't
have a picture here but however I do
have another very interesting picture
that is that is the ultimate hacking
keyboard so you can see this guy
there
I believe that's runs yeah so you know
they say our keycaps you know for this
you can use runs you can use you know
you can use any by the way there are
many Westerners they use Japanese but
you know when a Japanese look at that is
usually it does not make much sense you
know like but it's a novelty you know
it's just interesting
so anything anything else ok that's it
for today thank you guys for watching
see you see you next one if you like
them I if you like my videos put some
money in my account I'm on patreon
Emma Amazon em on PayPal you know just
go there and drop me some bucks thank
you for watching I'll see you next time