good morning everyone
so i'm i'm live there's some technical
problems
so uh welcome to another episode of star
talk show today is
2020 august 29th
and it's ten o'clock
in morning san francisco time today
saturday
so uh there is one question i lost my
live chat so there's a question ju
juhani juhani i watched your video on
this
syntax i always thought a.b
and foo had weird syntax too language
designers have annoying habit of making
the same design mistakes in the name of
familiarity yeah that's about this
syntax so i have a talk show talking
about
these syntax
uh so what's up guys type something in
the chat box i
it looks like i missed there is
something missing let me
try
let me try to fix my stream okay sorry
about that
okay my chat is back good morning guys
informatic
good morning but say something so let me
know if i'm live
and we are going to do emacs list coding
today
so type something guys type type it
so let me just begin then
because well let me just begin so today
today's background image
is this one okay so let me show you so
keyboards you'll find this page on my
keyboard blog just search for some
keyboards
and uh so this is google this is
uh google keyboard very good this is
this is kinesis advantage 2 and well
today's
photo today's picture
is this one okay um
anyway that's a background image and
let's
let's start to do today's stuff
okay so i want i want to do let's
magnify
and on the on the on the pink window on
the right you can see all my keys and
commands i type in emacs
so show in browser let's see wait i
don't want to close it
magnify showing browser
so emacs modify exci html lines to dl
oh entity there there is one thing i
want to do so
let me open open notes file entity okay
this
this is what i want to do today actually
so let's paste it here and
show in browser so i have a command
the name of the command is html escape
chart to entity
so let me show you what that does okay
so if you let's say you copied something
from the web
okay let's say you copied something
let's copy that one okay
you copy it you paste it here and let's
say there are some characters
uh such as that and let's say there is
someone says atnt okay
so you copy to your website but you see
these characters
needs to be escaped into entity so i
have
a command and also these ampersand
characters so i have a command that does
uh that does that so let's show so
so i'm going to call the command i press
the key so the command is called
html escape chart to entity and you can
see
it changed those characters to that
let me do it again okay so let's copy it
here
let's do that so
so that's that's the that's the text and
i call the command
and it becomes that it's necessary in
html because if you show this in html
let me show it so you see it doesn't
show it becomes dot at t
because this you need to escape the less
than
and greater than sign in html so this
command does exactly that
and now if you show in browser refresh
then you see what it is now this command
is very useful because sometimes you
want to copy
a entire uh for example
new school posting you know someone you
know a big chunk of text
and you paste it you paste it to a
buffer
you know you have to find such
occurrences of greater than
sign and less than sign and also the
ampersand sign and you have to escape
them
so it's very tedious tedious so this
command is great
so i just press one key let's do it
again i
i press two keys and they they are
changed and if i want to do to the whole
buffer
we can do that too uh for example let's
say
let's say this for example uh
this section okay i press the key
and you can see they've all become a
bunch of that and if i show in browser
now
it becomes you know this kind of markup
so this this command is super useful but
i want to make some
um i want to make some
modification because once i call it so
let's do it again okay so suppose i
select all these chunks
and i do it you know if i have a huge
document document i don't know
i want it to highlight it you know i
want to i want
all the uh occurrences that's
changed to be highlighted so that's what
we are going to do today
so what we are so let's look at the
source code okay
uh show source code so what i do is i
call
describe key there's a shortcut to the
command describe key
then i just press the key for the
command so i press the key
so it tells me emacs tells me
delete comma runs the command
html escape chart to enter t okay that's
the one i want
and tab to the link here and press enter
to go to the source code so you can see
here is the source code
and we are going to modify this code
okay copy that
make a new buffer paste it save it okay
what
what name do i want to save it i want to
save that name okay
so uh start with xxx is my convention
for temp file
and putting a date also you see every
time i call the mini buffer
i want that i want the font to be large
so you know because when i'm doing live
stream
uh you know i want the font to be large
instead of
instead of manually changing it every
time and also i'm getting old so
it would be nice if i uh if it's
large so let's let's write that
and we might do that later okay so let's
write it down here
make you know
make the
font in mini buffer larger
so we'll find out how to do that
after we done the live coding okay so
now back to the code
because html mod that's the mod all
these commands are
in you can find it on my github just
search for
html mod
oh [ __ ]
i am am i uh [ __ ] so i guess i'm
not alive
yeah [ __ ]
okay so looks like i got i got a
streaming problems
[ __ ] stupid you you uh youtube google
so basically what happens is that you
you know
anyway so uh
i'm going to restart on a different
stream so
if you are watching me right now that's
gonna be dead
i'm gonna start at the stream the url
where i posted before
and you're basically starting over okay
and this one is going to be deleted so
bye bye guys