welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
oh this is episode 2019 1208 Sunday 12
o'clock afternoon San Francisco time
good morning oh and today's topic is
Emacs Emacs Lisp light coding
hey people come on e am i M&A is that
your real name or a fictional name am I
I am r.e.m ree M&A Oh Emery Amman okay I
think I remember I asked you how to
pronounce that before so good morning
rats through hey Yasu is from Scotland
am i right and good morning Matt to
Germany good morning Kathy to UK United
Kingdom hey also today we are going to
focus on eMac beasts we are going to
start coding Emacs Lisp the Lisp
language the granddaddy of artificial
intelligence the language for other
visual intelligence Ayman Amon okay so
it's Ayman they are Amri Amri Amman
Ayman okay I'm and I have to remember
that you have to remind me though Ayman
so so we are going to start to code eMac
B's okay so today we are going to code
we are going to write a command to
increase font yes
so let's begin let's no nonsense and
start right away so on the left window
you can see all the Emacs command I call
if you see what I am if you see I'm
doing something you can see the command
name there
then you search it you will find it
you'll find a code on my website and you
can use it just put in your emags in it
and I'm drinking tea so this is hot and
okay shall we begin
so yeah so first first thing is to
increase the phone you see I have this
buffer I can press a key to increase
font or I can shrink close it reopen
increase font but but this does not this
only increase funny in the current
buffer you see if when I increase it
only increasing this buffer not all the
others not if I have a new buffer for
example I copy that
I create a new buffer paste it's small I
wanted to be such that I can call
command then the font size is increased
globally in every window or frame so
close that we don't need we don't need
this frame so close that we open you see
so so I want to write a command to do
that and that is very easy so let's
begin okay so how do you do that so
let's begin let's see what is is
Startalk show let's go back Oh startup
show so this is today's talk show so
let's go to nothing
okay so a efficient way to open my
bookmark so open my bookmark Emacs
settings and this is basically this is
the code we want to borrow
okay so copy that close it and over here
we are going to first of all it seen in
logic okay so we gonna call this command
e mcLeese okay we added this tag then we
call command to put it into a buffer new
buffer so paste so we have the code here
so this code let me magnify so this code
this code will set the font size global
so you can see first of all it has a
condition condition okay hold on a
second
in this part we don't need this part is
about setting up a particular font for
certain unicode so we don't want that so
close that and what is this
let's see specify found for all Unicode
characters yes so we don't want this
part either so basically the main code
the heart of the code will be just this
part okay so delete that place it here
and delete any questions any questions
and comments comment ok post your
comments opinion keep them going coming
ok so here is basically the code you see
condition if it is some Linux then you
check if you have the deja vu sans mano
fun available if it's true then you you
call this line set friend font so so
this line set frame font this is the
function that does the job so it you set
the font globally for every window okay
so hold on a second so and then then
this line is about setting about using a
particular font when when the character
is Chinese we don't we don't care for
that okay so actually so DV that so
let's let's let's look at not it's much
cleaner so the hold on a second let me
clean up the code okay we don't need
this extraneous comment okay so here's
the code condition now if it's on
Windows
I mean if it's only notes then if the
deja boo' is available you set it
globally now if it's on Mac which is
Darwin
you said the font menlo 14 ok globally
then if it's on Windows then you just
say courier globally okay so we want to
so this is a code but we want to write a
function for it
hi Cup poutine [ __ ] I should have turned
this oh the microphone you might have to
adjust your volume again so anyway so we
are going to write a function so the fun
the function name will be saw increase
font let's just say big font big font
global okay so I'm going to make the
function name that's all that's my
function name and copy the whole code
here okay basically that is the command
now let's write the document ducks ducks
string okay make font size larger
globally okay something like that
then in a case of Mac if the Menlo font
is available mineral mineral found is
always available on the Mac so this line
is actually redundant so if menno is
available we want mineral 15 okay now
what about on Windows and Linux well you
see one of the nasty thing about font
today's phone technology is that if you
space that the size is dependent
dependent on font so for example menlo
15 will be visually different size than
deja boo' 15 or korea 15 you see so the
font size is not absolute it depends on
which fount it is so some font 15 size
be smaller than some other font size 14
that's a situation it's very annoying
okay but that's what we got
so anyway so in order to write our code
I know on the Mac 15 is the size I want
but I'm not sure on deja Vu's what size
should I use so let's let's just leave
Linux and windows be okay so since I'm
on the Mac let's just focus on the Mac
so actually this is the code this is so
actually DeeDee that we don't need the
LED TV delete so this is this is a code
evaluate the code we have it close it
okay paste the code here we paste it
wait reopen okay cut it and delete a
file paste it here and make it
syntax color showing browser so there we
have it magnified there is the code we
move the blank lines it in again so
there is a code so big font global and
now close this buffer reopen it you see
this is the default font now we are
going to call the command we are going
to code code the command big font Globo
you will see that this window this
buffer and also also the window on the
left you will see them increase size so
let's call it m x-x are big font Globo
okay now watch the windows watch the
phone size for both windows do it now
that's good so that is the command I
want and we have it that's fantastic
okay now I just want I need I just need
to put this command in my Emacs in it so
let's let's do that okay copy it okay
copy it and let's go to settings Emacs
settings actually let's go
to miscellaneous I want to put in a file
this file
sorry max miscellaneous command go to
the button paste it here so here is the
code we just wrote good morning capsules
kapustin Alexander good morning the new
language so we have written this code
it's done its success close it save it
close it close it showing browser we
have completed the task number one emag
bees write a command to increase font
for all frames and buffers we have
completed that that's fantastic
now we gonna go to the next next task I
forgot to put a date normally I put a
date there so let's let's do it quickly
okay now you can watch my left window
and see all the command I call so
showing a different buffer remove it
open my settings in it file open the
miscellaneous file and here is a code we
want to say version I want I usually
give a version number a date so that so
I keep track of what you know what
version is each command so copy that
close it save it close it paste it here
font fi it showing browser so that is
good so you can see the version we added
version so let's go to shall we go to
the next task
then what's up guys what's up so so rat
shoe rat shoe is that how you pronounce
it but by the way are you now you are a
white guy right you are a Scottish guy
right oh because I I see your names xu e
and i'm thinking perhaps you are a
Chinese descendant or something are you
and you are a Emacs user right so Daniel
says I was out mixing why mixing Y and
rum punch last night Oh rum punch
sanguis Oh and then I don't remember the
rest okay that's good that's yuzu yes
what do you mean what do you mean so I
think let's go to the next thing we want
to do so Emacs program to convert to
JPEG while in HTML buffer okay get on
coding it fast we do it one hour demo
okay yeah so so few days ago I did a
video that is a demo of a bunch of image
manipulation commands in Emacs so that
is few days ago so you guys should go
check it out so for example because you
know just such folks sorry YouTube okay
so Kassar me youtube go to my youtube
channel so rats uses Emacs and oh it's
only a coincidence through is a popular
Chinese name and by the way I mean I'm
going to experiment to begin to have
guest speakers in my in my son talk shop
so anyone want to do it anyone yeah
let's let's just do it let's try it
today okay so we I've talked for 40
minutes let's try it today so any one of
you who wants to go on online and talk
and you'll be broadcasted to my stream
so so any if anyone wants to do that
let's do it let's go to JIRA okay hold
on a second let me let me prepare online
guest
zerah okay wait closed
no saved reopen okay try out online
guests in San talk show okay let's let's
gonna try that out but before we do let
me finish the thought here so you go to
my YouTube 30 YouTube and you click on
videos I I'm doing one video a day since
about six months ago so I have like 200
videos or sort of topics programming
Emacs programming language design
closure how do i do how do i do my
website how do I write my website what
system do I use what do I think of oak
Mart
these are all common questions in
keyboards what keyboard is my favorite
what keyboard do I use what what a key
switches to alike you know I talked
about them often so if you are bored you
know if you guys are bored any one of
you you can just go to youtube and go to
my channel and such you'll probably find
you know because some of these are the
common topics in JavaScript and and what
do I think of JavaScript modern
frameworks so anyway so I'm I was going
to say so few days ago about last week
we did a demo of Emacs there it is okay
so this one one week ago let's open it
okay so let's open that so this is Emacs
demo of custom commands of image
manipulation resize crop convert PNG
JPEG renamed act so we did one hour of
that and this is November 27th 2019 so
you might go check out that today we are
not going to do a demo we are going to
start to code one of the thing
I'm going to show you okay yeah so that
that's the next thing we're gonna do
and meanwhile let's go to let's try the
JIRA thing that is a guest for not JIRA
okay so not JIRA so sorry blog you you
won't go through my programming block
and sorry programming blog and such for
video so there is a nice video voice
chat website and this is a URL
and secure fully featured and complete
free video conferencing okay so let's
begin a new stream start a new stream
Sal talk show guest okay
allow my microphone and allow my camera
okay
allow okay this is a big one now let's
see dial in okay so I'm gonna copy that
so let us try this okay I'm gonna post a
link and you can go there and possibly
you know so your talk with me will be
broadcasted live so here there is a link
I just posted and you can you know your
voice will be on for sure now if you
don't want to do video that's up to you
let's try the voice for now so anyone
wants to try it you come on and you know
let's do it for five minutes or so and
meanwhile let me go back to code the
eMac piece okay so what's the thing I
want to do the thing I want to do is
let's not let's hope we have someone
here fellow Jitsu what did I say
fellow JIT star so who are you say
report your name what did I grants
moderator right or something
disconnected well I don't want to share
my screen what is this let's show that
chat okay so this is me saw someone
disconnected
so anyway you go there and the weekend
and we can start to talk okay you know
don't be shy
yeah just go you know the thing of the
thing usually you know I don't interact
with people like when I interact with
people sometimes I get I don't get what
you are saying because I wasn't I'm not
a native English speaker so so in casual
context sometimes when you say something
I don't get it so you just have to I
have to ask you to can you repeat that
and sometimes that's embarrassing
so don't worry about that you know
because I don't really I didn't
understand what you was said so anyway
so go there if you want to let's try a
chat okay
so you did try that Kathy you go there
you have to then you have to turn your
microphone then you have to turn your
video so you know you will be prepared
it's not like by mistake you show your
face so what's what we're gonna do now
so eMac this right so we're gonna
program this code we're gonna program
this code okay so what what do I want to
do the the code the thing I want to do
is convert jpg quiring HTML buffer yeah
okay I know what that is okay so go to
some talk show let me show you okay so
we have some talk show and we have for
example this image now this image is in
PNG let's go to tired okay so let's go
to diet here is an image at the bottom
you can see there and that image is PNG
now I have a command I can convert to
jpg okay so suppose this you know so so
we have a PNG file here let me close
that so we have a PNG file here but
typically your photo you wanted to be in
jpg file because jpg file is like almost
10 times smaller than size without
almost without losing quality in a
visually detectable way so for a photo
kind of image you typically want it in
JPEG so now I have the problem now here
is a task you see I have this PNG file I
want to convert it to jpg and normally
the way I do it is like this okay let me
show you it's a bit tedious so I open it
I jump too tired jump to the to the
directory then I call command I call it
and that commands Satya to JPEG and you
see it creates created this new file
named
- - JPEG so open it you see it's exactly
the same same image but in now in JPEG
now I copy the file path close it close
tired close our internal PNG image then
I move the cursor I paste the path
here's a path and now I call another
command to link a file so you can see
the file name this is - - jpg and the
original is PNG here so now we have two
images here now I show in browser page
down so now you can see we got two
images then I opened the PNG file I
delete it
okay now it's it's good then I delete
the line let me show the command okay so
you can see the command I was coding
here
sorry become file and South Carolina
region so anyway so so now I have the
just JPEG version now I go back to
browser refresh you see that's how I
convert PNG to JPEG but it's kind of
tedious it involves involves many steps
you have to open the file go to tired to
the conversion close you know closed
closed closed them TV the PNG file go
back to HTML delete all engine or PNG
one insert the jpg one and linka Fayed
so it's a lot of steps I would rather
just press a key like right now I just
press a key then the whole thing will be
done okay
so that is the description of the
problem now we can proceed to code it
hold on a second let's revert back to
the original okay so here is our
internal fire we do
it lets but let's make it let's not
delete them so it's here open it
copy the file path close close close put
it here put it back and open a PNG DD
the PNG one okay and deleted I and
showing browser so now we are back to
the original PNG so that we can have we
can have some some image to test our
command command so far so good guys so
what so anyone coming nobody looks like
it's gonna be a lonely room because
people are afraid to go online Kathy you
want to go on we you know go on for a
minute so let's so now we now we want to
do the code so we have to start to write
a code okay so hmm
what we gonna do okay so I don't have to
make Kathy doesn't have a make hope
thanks that terrifies me oh my Ayman
Ayman doesn't have a microphone okay
right and it terrifies Kathy so we need
to code the email list now so when it's
okay let me let's do it okay so okay so
let's call the command but before we
call the command because I have another
comment let me show you the command okay
I have another command there that will
create a thumbnail of this image of what
it whatever image is under kusa so let
me show you okay
I call the command and that command is
uh create some thumbnail image you can
see the name on the left and now it asks
me what width so let's say 800 okay so
it's done so you see I just call one
command and it creates created a file on
disk and with the full path here so now
I have to do is just link of I it and
show in browser ok so it actually
created a larger file you see you see
that that so let me show it again ok so
open these close it let's do it again
now create thumbnail image ok 250 ok
link of I show in browser page now you
can see it creates an image I'm showing
you this command because this command
does not require you to go into diet go
into diet then you know code a command
then copy the file path then go back to
HTML the in paste it doesn't require
that it does everything in one shot you
know it just created a thumbnail of
whatever image is under the cursor so
that is actually what we want to do but
we don't want to create a thumbnail we
merely want to convert this PNG to JPEG
ok so but since we have a similar
command we can use that as a template so
let's yeah so that's why I'm showing you
this command so let's do it
so first of all let's delete these oops
let's delete this thumbnail we don't
need it ok
so the command is here is a code the
command name is so create them now image
and let's go to the code okay so here is
a code okay so this code is actually
quite large
okay copy it create a new buffer paste
it and copy the name and save it as saw
create saw convert to jpg okay
solve convert to jpg in line okay so
that's a file name now go to diet this
is a new file and we want to change the
name so that space becomes underscore so
I call command and that command is not
diary rename space - in the school so
you can see now it's on the scope now
open it and rename this okay
convert to jpg in line okay so let's
just say that okay so we're gonna create
this
okay so version so it says so we need to
put a documentation so you'll say
convert image and cruiser to JPEG
okay and usage in HTML file put kusa on
the image file path code a command then
then a then a JPEG version will be
created with file name with same call
file name in the center then and
relative path will inserted it before
the image tag okay and full path will be
inserted before the image tag so okay so
anyway this is a command ok so let me
show you what what it or do so far so
good
am I on the right right track so let's
see the comments
the party is here welcome that but but
did you watch yesterday's video is there
to talk behind the link what what behind
the link hey Bart so thank you saying
goes to you so am I so no ran today so
far that's that's yeah that's my design
yes so but you want to go online we are
going to try this
Oh rat easier [ __ ] that rat say
something can you fellow gist is having
connectivity issues that you have
connectivity issues and you can type
something type something here rat
so polo says yeah I also don't have a
weapon and my DAC and Mike are not with
me
so I was busy yesterday so but I you
should watch it yesterday's video
you know because well anyway I want to
say sorry because I was you know you
were mentioning about the Linux firewall
and I was flaming that for 10 minutes
you know so so let's see so we have a
new guy joining ok so wait so NSYNC
oh my media my video got screwed on a
second oh my god something
someone here say am i so our minds
videos off and and audio is of rats
audio is of and video is off come on
guys and we have another guy with videos
often but audio is on say say something
hello
there you are
who are you you talk some more and yeah
hold on a second wait let me turn you on
so other people can hear you
so are you are you Navi are you about
oh yes I so are you you were born in
Germany right oh so because I was
expecting I mean I you know I didn't
thought it's a German accent no it's not
yes you have a good accent I didn't hear
the joke because I thought its American
so so what we gonna so let's see what
what so what's interesting going on
there and what city are you from
do you mind saying that I forgot if you
told us or not okay yeah sure
I see cool so what time is it in Germany
nine o'clock
I see
cool and today is Sunday so what are you
up to
are you anything interesting you have
you been coding or you going out or
okay hold on slow down second part so
people are not healing you let me I
think I need to turn on something trick
something here hold on a second
yeah I know what's going on so hold on a
second I forgot okay so so you are
saying let's say you were you were
supposed to go out or what
cool so act so I'm trying to set your
voice so that people can hear it and
right now it's not not successful or not
so are you looking at the screen because
if you look at a screen you can see what
I'm doing with the OBS so what do I have
to do I thought last time you walked
wait
okay hold on second yeah I think I'd
create by mistake so so guys in my back
on me
okay okay no imma and guys you can hear
about right Nabby sound toxin sound
toxin but can you can you get Nabi and
sound toxin can you guys hear but you
know he's talking with me on GC oh yes
yes so this is success great but yeah so
that's a that's a I think that's a
fantastic idea because if you know
that's a fantastic idea for live talk
show because you know I do a talk show I
am here every day people get bored of
you you know every day it's kind of the
same so if I can invite people you know
like other programmers and things will
be interesting interesting since it's
hard to argue with people in the chance
or something and sometimes they talk
[ __ ] in the chat and you can't really I
mean you can respond really verbose
where whereas they can't really and
especially in this type of chat to this
YouTube chat which I find pretty
annoying to say the least
if you talk persons person or someone
else then you actually can have a
discussion especially if people like
your street
screams and people like to watch it like
Casey and the others then they will
respect you and they won't just say oh
this saw true oh he's talking [ __ ] again
and stuff like that so the
actually interested in a conversation so
if you would invite people like these
who are actually watching a stream even
though they disagree with a lot of what
you have to say then it's a much better
discussion then you and for example
someone saying something in the chant
and you're responding really verbose or
someone just ranting and you just read
back but yeah so in this way you can
actually have a real discussion I mean
not as real as actually meeting those
people but it still it's a million times
better than than just yes indeed but
lips let me fix I mean I want to get
this set up correctly so I want so
people can you guys hear about or ideas
like 100 percent be said you can turn to
my voice up by clicking the vertical
ellipses on a square
okay okay hold on
and
and I you know let's see what
[Applause]
so I think you know on the OBS your
voice I mean the guest voice is already
10 disabled aouda and and as you can see
the bar is coming in red I mean it's
it's even louder than my voice so if I
turn that up but more I think it's gonna
creep you know what they call creeping
that yeah I know I know but the jitsi I
mean the the voice from the chick goes
to my computer output so it's actually
feeding to the OBS I mean it's not via
my speaker that's what I'm that's what I
mean
but anyway oh yeah so I think yeah so
let me try that okay so yeah it's
already max so your voice is already max
there but anyway you look at my OBS
screen you can see you can you can see
the bottom that is you know that says
Mick oaks that is supposed to be
whatever from the computer's output to
you know to the live stream do you see
it yeah so you can see there's a 10
disabled you know the Bob when you see
when the bar goes red that means it's no
good yeah so you know you talk you talk
some you talk some in let's see I'm
gonna read the comments he has you read
the comments read the comments to
audience but anyway anywhere so polo has
a question for me I guess
I don't know how I would change my mic
sensitivity within jitsi I don't think
actually I don't think that I don't
think the oh okay I see
I don't think the problem is on your end
I think the problem is on my end because
you we you know it has to do with my
setup here and with the YouTube I don't
think it's your problem because I can
hear you clearly I can hear you how my
headphone clearly
okay let's try this one more thing okay
and see where they say
guess the point of what a beast right
says that you yourself should turn down
your voice and just okay now I turned my
voice a little bit low
is that better everyone so let me read
the comments
poro says X I've been using your math
plug-in today I'm trying to set up a
scratch pad to solve math problems do
you know if Emacs supports something
more complex like math ASCII hope
properly writing kissing so let me
answer post question first so Paul if
you want to type so the question is
about typing math equations formulas in
Emacs and unfortunately I don't know
easy way okay if your question is about
entering Unicode characters then you
know I have that solution we talked
about yesterday but for entering whole
math equations it's kind of tedious I
think you just have to you just have to
you know do it manually or something did
you see someone deep or something right
I heard something like a voice someone
left so anyway let's let's go to the
next question
you could have used e so what's your
question
right so can't you increase by half so
anyway I think I'm hearing echoes spot
are you using a headphone I think so
okay no no I think it's good now yeah I
think it's good now so I'm wondering
what to do next
no wait I hear the echo again I guess
every time anyway so I'm wondering what
to do next for today
maurices bet that's not that's not you
know settled I'm like exploring you know
this is yeah this is yeah yeah I so he s
Curry's interesting and I'm you know
exploring yeah yeah so I'm thinking what
so let me ask you guys so those those of
you who are watching so that says he's
just quieter than me and process will
yeah so I'm thinking maybe that's it for
today we try this voice in and maybe and
we'll try that again another day and
perhaps that's it for today well maybe I
don't know because yeah because well I
mean I have to get you know people are
talking about something interesting like
if we have a topic then you know if
something about you know
what's fixing what fixing yeah but yeah
that's the key thing I want to do in
this video so we can you know we have we
have that ready so and you know then so
I can you know so next time when I have
a guess I know what to do you know the
settings and all that and we tried that
today it seems not perfect but kind of
works I guess how do I switch buffers
without using so people are asking me
Emacs questions I should answer them so
but so let me answer the questions then
then it's the let's do this again okay
so let's see I from 10 probably from
time to time I mean I want to get you
know interesting Emacs programmers or
some other programmers you know they
they have particular thing that's
interesting and people want to hear it I
think that's that's a fan yeah yeah I
know I I don't know when is that you
know I I don't really have a plan to do
that I mean I am exploring but
[Applause]
yeah I know so so let me yes let me
answer the question spot then this this
chatter again and also let me ask you
one more thing last thing you know we
need to get in communication like you
know join this code this way you know do
you want to join this code or we have to
you know talk you are not right it's
fine you know disco is just fine so well
okay so okay okay okay but but so right
right so we have a argument and in fact
we can make that a proper topic you know
we can argue about that I can tell you
the reasons but anyway I'm thinking you
know people know but I don't get it what
went on why not I I kind of okay let me
answer the question spot
so let's this chat again okay yeah I
want to ask you because you know to to
get somewhere in some way we can talk so
you know we can sit up
jiya so we can talk 1 2 1 2 1 again I
mean I can't have you on the show just
to chat random you know you know because
I want I need to get you know answer
people's questions or whatever so I want
to
yeah so let's let's do these again but I
don't know I don't I don't really like
to use email but anyway that's its do
this again okay
yes maybe because I need to set up like
sometimes I want the guests
yes you know whenever I you know okay
okay yeah I'm gonna answer some
questions and yeah so yeah fantastic
bye bye
okay that is smart finally we we we
talked voice with Bart so that is
fantastic and now it's things this this
is somewhat walking and let me answer
there is a lot questions and let me
answer that and that'll be it for today
so for the video you know for the chat
I'm thinking you know we gonna I'm gonna
invite people to join the chat possibly
in the future and it can be casual like
today you know we have one day where we
just have you guys in you know any any
of you guys join and we can just chat
random but I think most of the time
still that would not be the case because
you just gonna have a bunch of people
getting together kind of like a friend
chatting and that's not going to be
interesting to most people so nobody
will watch the stream except you know a
few of us so but we will do that once in
a while I think just like today for the
live stream on the other hand I'm
thinking of inviting for example
programmers for example Emacs people
famous Emacs programmers we can I can
invite them and they then you know we
can you know then they can talk about
they can do a tutorial oka mod on tech
you know how do you use tech on in Emacs
you know many Emacs experts on that and
also possibly other X you know other my
friends or acquaintances acquaintances
who know the languages so I think that's
a plan in bar says just make a specific
topic and ask people to join who wants
to discuss the topic yes this would be
more interesting indeed
that is true but you see again I don't
know how it works yet
like you know because if you just invite
you will often you know it's
unpredictable you will end up with you
know five people joining some people
don't have voice and we spent you know
20 minutes fixing problems and talking
random that's that's no good so anyway
so let me answer the face of finally
today I think I'm gonna answer some of
the questions about Emacs and IOP it
ok so let's so poor polo so what are the
questions how can I switch buffers
without using arrow keys you can't you
can set a key to switch buffers for
example there is a command for example I
the way I switch buffer is I call this
command ok so this command is I do
switch buffer ok so you you can call
that command then you just type a name
then that's how you switch buffer does
that answer your question
Ayman Ayman
so there is a bunch of how can switch
buffers okay so Linux listen alright I
can't play the game with Unix
what came to you play the support grows
each day
yes Linux okay now Bianca we say that
your game
ok I think that's it guys for today we
were going to code that Emacs Lisp but
let's do it another day and so thank you
guys for coming thank you but great to
talk to you today and let's see who else
is in nobody ok so bye guys