Hello guys, welcome to another episode
of S talk show. We are going to talk
about functional programming uh in
multiple languages. Mostly we going to
talk about functional programming fold
and reduce. I'm going to demonstrate
them in wam language in JavaScript
fantastic and in JavaScript and uh in uh
JavaScript. Let's see JavaScript and in
e-magisp
and we're going to talk about what's the
difference. So the general purpose of
fold and reduce and what's the
difference between fold and reduce we
had a huge debate since about five
months ago on si discord uh a bunch of
nerds. So we are thinking you know
because in many programming languages
they have both fold and reduce and they
are slightly different. So we're going
to dive into why is that um and how they
differ and you know the origin of the
concept of fold and reduce. Okay so let
me tell you guys fold is the best thing.
Okay so programming language
documentation matters. Okay because I
learned
am I am I good? Am I good? If you are
here, say hi. If you are watching
offline, play at 1.5 speed. Okay, so let
me double check. Uh, so if you are here,
anyone here yet? Let me double check. So
it says error. My YouTube is not
receiving enough video. Okay, I don't
know if I'm smooth. So let me know.
Okay,
so fold and reduce the, you know, I I
learned I learned about fold about 30
years ago in the 1990s. the first time I
learn it in Wuam language. Okay. And I
was thinking so what is the purpose?
It's kind of odd because you you you you
kind of fold you know like why would
anyone want to do that? It seems
unnatural. So the documentation of a
programming language is supremely
important because
if now now I know you know after like 30
years I realized the power of fold or
also known as reduce it is basically
fold is a general
is a functional programming way to do
any loop. Okay. So any loop you want to
do in imperative languages, procedural
languages
uh you can do in functional way by using
bold. So what you do is that basically
you know when when you have a loop
doesn't matter in what language in your
for each you know for loop for loop is
most popular in C C++ Java Python you
know that kind of procedural and pearl
bash you know procedural crowd so but in
functional so so what do you do in for
loop is that usually typically for like
in JavaScript uh it's idiotic okay so
let's let's start to Um let's start a uh
JavaScript. Okay. So let's see if I have
a template for for loop. Okay. For
uh now I got a new keyboard. Can you
see? So this is ultimate hacking
keyboard at station. So I'm not too
familiar with it but anyway. So you can
you see the for loop in JavaScript.
Okay. So here is the typical form of for
loop. So let's say so you set I equals
to zero then I if I less than 9 then you
do I ++ which is increment I by one then
console log let's say and press uh print
I okay now let's run it
so you got 1 2 3 4 5 you know up to
eight so this is a typical for loop so
what do you so in so in general loop you
know that's a general loop in C C++ in F
in Java. So what you do is you you you
run a state and you you I mean you run a
loop and you change the state and and
tell it what to do in the body of the
loop. That's a for loop.
Very convenient. You know that's like a
that's a fundamental part of a
programming language. Like every
programming language allows you to loop
in to do loop in some way. Now how do
you do that in functional programming?
Okay. Now in functional programming of
course we got the map. Okay. So in
JavaScript let's say uh in JavaScript
let's say one uh okay new keyboard. So
what where is one? One is not that one
is here. One
two.
Ah god
new keyboard. You can't type one two
three anymore.
So are you guys here? So new keyboard,
new mouse. Nobody's here. Okay. So in
JavaScript, you got a list known as
array in JavaScript. So you say um
map. Okay. So you map then you pass a
function. So let's say uh console log
what uh console log print. So here is a
function. Okay. So this part is a
function. It just prints you know given
x it just print x. Then map is what you
do to represent the loop. So in this
case 1 2 3 is array you just print it.
Okay. So let's run that. Can we run
that? Okay. So
do that. So the first one uh what so
what do we uh oh there yeah here yeah
here yeah here yeah here yeah here yeah
here yeah here yeah here's the result.
So 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 that's a four from
the for loop. Then 1 2 3 is from our
map. Okay, that's a so map is a
functional way. But what if your um what
if you want to
you know take the index. So you know you
got a bunch of you know basically when
when the for loop gets complicated you
cannot use map because for example
sometimes you need to know the index of
an item. So let's say if the fif let's
say let's say let's say like that okay
let's say four 22
4 two okay that's a list now let's say
when the when it's a even indexed
element you know like we skip one then
take the this first one then skip one
then take that one then skip one take
another one every time it's a I mean
every time you you skip one then you it.
So in this case you cannot do it with
map. Okay, because map every time you
just uh give it an item. Uh actually in
JavaScript you can because the second
argument you can pass the index of
array. But anyway I'm not going
anywhere. So so my point is when the for
loop can become very complicated then
map usually uh sometimes may not be
appropriate or cannot do it. Okay. So,
but but but there is a one way
functional programming way that does not
involve updating any state value
variable local variable a global
variable and that would be reduce. Okay?
Because what you do in reduce is that is
that basically when you do a loop you
you you know in functional programming
way you want the function to represent
what you want to do with a body. But
every loop, every time you loop, there
is a state. For example, in the in a
typical for loop case, you have the uh
the I which is a kind of the state
variable every time it increment by one
typic typically. So you want to be able
to pass a state. Okay. And you you can
do that. That is the code fold or called
reduce.
Okay. So in uh in so what you do is that
you
so uh okay so this is emac this let's go
to JavaScript because JavaScript is more
popular you understand it so so what you
do is that you have this reduce function
that takes a function and this function
will be like your for loop body like it
represent what you want to do with it.
Okay. Then you take a initial value
that's a beginning state. Okay. That's a
way to understand reduce. Okay. Initial
value is a beginning state. The function
is the body of the loop. And every and
the array each time you feed it that
that's like the um extern external
input. Okay. So what the function do is
that the function each time it takes two
um the function takes two
two argument one is the previous result
that's kind of the uh the state that
represent the state from the previous
iteration of the loop and then takes an
input from the current uh array. So the
function takes two arguments. One is the
current input from the array. The other
value is the previous result that
represent the state. So what I'm trying
to say is that the fold or also known as
reduce is the
general way to represent any loop. Any
loop you can write with for loop. You
can do it with reduce. Okay, that is how
you should understand it.
now. Okay. So, anyone here with me?
Hello. Hello. GCS GCS IV5. Did you get
the new IV5 added? Are you the GCS kind
of? I thought I uh No.
So, okay. Am I doing good? Okay. GCS
answer. Am I like doing live? And uh it
says my um YouTube is you know having
stream issues. Am I doing good?
Okay, my so so if you are watching this
offline play play at 1.5 speed. Okay,
let me let me uh quickly get to the
point because actually I want to talk
about lots of things about fold and
reduce. So basically what I'm saying
here is that fold I mean I mean for loop
you have that in every language
procedural language now but in
functional programming you have map but
map is insufficient to represent
arbitrary for loop but you got for also
known as reduce that is a functional
programming way to represent to code any
form of loop. Okay.
So that's my point and whenever you want
to whenever you read you know whatever
programming language Python
uh Python, JavaScript uh uh um Emac this
you want to understand that it is the
general way functional programming form
of general purpose loop. Okay just
remember that that is that is the most
important. Now I learned you know I
learned about fold like 30 years ago in
the early 1990s in wuam language. So um
so actually let let me let me write some
um comments so people understand what
we're doing. For loop uh card
for loop uh
is
uh loop okay loop is fundamental
in programming languages.
Okay.
Um
God
typically
in procedural
programming languages or also known as
imperative aa
in imperative languages
the most popular
way of loop uh of loop
is
the or loop. Okay, that's most well
known. Okay,
now in functional programming
languages.
uh new keyboard
in functional programming languages.
The most well known form of loop
a loop is via map
function. So the map function takes a
function and and take a list and uh
apply the function to each item.
But
map is not a
general
purpose loop
because
for example
if you ah god you let's switch to um you
need to Let's see. Yeah, let's switch to
a buffer that does not have all these
abbreviations. Okay. So
let's write it here because for example
um if you
are given a list and you want to skip
every element
and apply a function to
that.
Okay. In this case
uh
in this case you can not use map usually
because you don't
have the index of the element. If you do
have the index, you can check you you
can just check the evenness of the
index. For example, if the index begin
with zero, zero is even, you can take
it. One is odd, skip,
uh then two is even, take it. Three is
odd, skip and so on. Or you can take
every third element, you know, whatever.
So in that case, map usually cannot be
done. you need the index but in the case
of Java JavaScript you can do that
because JavaScript actually pass the
function the index of the element as
well but that's Java JavaScript in
usually in other programming languages
whenever you have map such as Python's
map you cannot um you know that you you
don't know the index you you are only
passed the elements of the array
okay so so let's delete that so Let's
take let's put that back here. And uh uh
map is not general purpose loop because
for example if you are that that that
okay
uh now
now the
functional pro uh functional programming
form of a of a
General purpose
loop is
bold also known as reduce. Okay, that is
the point I want to make. Oh god, so
many
god.
Okay, let's put this back. Let's
syntax color and let's show in browser.
So that's kind of the explanation we
did. Okay, nobody's here, nobody's
watching. Okay. So,
okay, that's about
bold and reduce. Let's let's demo. Okay,
let's demo some uh bold. Okay, wam
language. Uh let me show you what bold
does.
Okay, f uh f is a function. Now uh
initial value let well let's forget
about initial value okay let's just say
range first of all let's generate a list
of numbers
range five range six okay run it okay we
need to run this and paste the result
after that so let's do that let's stop
this
oh Okay, this actually I should show
that. Okay, you're all confused today.
So, let's do it again. Okay, range uh
so range six returns 1 2 3 4 5 6. Okay.
Now,
now let's take the list. So, we say fold
and
run it.
Okay, here is what you get. Now, that
might be too complicated. Let's let's
make it smaller. Okay. Um I mean the
list may be too long, hard to
understand. Let's just say one, two,
three. Okay.
So that's what fold does. Okay. So let's
let's make it larger. Okay. Fold one two
three four.
Okay. Does that make sense? F the
function f every time takes two
arguments.
The first item is whatever
the input from the list. The second item
wait uh the the first item is a state.
Okay. The first item is the state. The
second item is the input from the list.
Okay.
So is that clear?
Uh
is that clear? Does that make sense?
Anyone is here say hi. Okay.
Now let's demonstrate um
the
another thing about fold is that you can
have a init initial value let's say
zero. Okay
run it.
So that means you begin with a state
zero. So every time the first time f is
given two arguments the state which is
zero then an input from the list which
is one. then pass that to f again and
the first element is the you know it's
it's the uh
is the previous result which is a state.
Then the second argument is input from
the list. Okay. So and so on. So fold is
the most general form to represent
any loop in a functional programming
way. Okay. So that's demonstration of
fold in wam language. Now let's um
actually I can show you
let there's something interesting okay
actually you can show all the history of
the result so in wam language that's
called fold list so if you look at this
you'll understand by just looking at the
result so we do instead of fold we say
fold list and then we get a bunch list.
So, let me reformat them so it's easier
to un to see.
So, can you see that? That's what that's
the result. Okay. So, let's get the the
way. Okay. That's a common.
Okay. So that's the general purpose
form in functional programming for loop.
Let's put it back. Um put it back.
Syntax color show in browser. So we
demonstrated. So here's the code we
demonstrated wam language fold. And did
we demonstrate JavaScript fold? No. So
let's do so. Okay. Uh let's do so now
with the keyboard now. How do you uh get
that? Yeah. So what uh
yeah. So let's do a JavaScript reduce.
Okay. JavaScript now. Now first of all
you need a list of items. Let's say one
two three
uh that's
one two three four five. Okay. So in
JavaScript because it's kind of using
the object way. So list that's you know
so um
let's say x array
equals true. Now where where is equal?
So equal
that then then you say x array
uh oh god.
Okay. So x then you say x array dot
that's how you do it reduce you call the
method on it then uh actually enter then
you see then here is a function
uh let's say initial value
optional okay let's so let's not use
initial value for now let's comment out
so for now just zero
Okay. And the function what did this do?
Uh let's say
let's make them string. Okay. Because
when it's string it's easier to see
because when you add add the numbers
together they become a different number.
It's hard to tell because then you have
to sum them up. But if they are string
and you do string join you can see pre
what's the previous value you know four
+ 5 is just four five 3 + 4 is just 34 a
string okay so we got array then array
reduce then this function lambda
function and and then you basically plus
is a way to join string so so if we do
that then let's say x result
and let's say equal Well, now where's my
equal key?
Okay. So,
okay then console log x result.
Um,
okay. Let's see what happens. Hopefully,
it works. No. So, you got a um
error and called reference array. X
array is not defined. Why is it not
defined? It's right here. No, wait. Oh,
JavaScript. Okay, I forgot JavaScript.
Uh, you need
Yeah. And you know, so JavaScript you
need
constant.
Okay. Run it. There is the result. Uh,
print log result is this one, two,
three, four, five.
And uh
does that make sense?
Am I making sense?
Okay. No, nobody is here. I think four
people. Okay. Say hi. If I make sense,
say hi. Okay. So, we are talking about
uh fold and reduce. We are just running
demonstrating them in wam language and
now JavaScript. So uh but this
JavaScript is not too clear. So actually
I have already written so many
tutorials. Let's let's see if we can
find a a good example of JavaScript
tutorials. So
no it just no it's a it's the same thing
I did.
Um yeah but you can you can do it this
way. So for example
uh let's say so here is a example where
where it makes more sense. So what this
do is that this array is 1 2 3 4 5 and
this function now we define a function.
The function takes two arguments x and y
and what and what it does is that it
creates a string. So those back tick
those are string. Okay, back tick is is
a string syntax. So but within the
string you evaluate x and you turn into
a string. You evaluate y you turn it
into a string. So you got to you so
basically you want to you you know
whenever f is given two arguments you
turn those two arguments into a string
and you put fn inside you know you know
wrap fn
um around it it returns a string okay so
when you run this then this is the
result you get okay so let's run it
so you see true okay so uh here true
Okay. So the result of that is true.
Okay. Here we demonstrated reduce in
JavaScript. I hope that is uh clear.
Syntax code show in browser. So we got
we got wam language. We got JavaScript
demonstration of of reduce. You know in
wam language it's called fold but in
JavaScript they call it reduce. Now why
is that? Let me explain because that's
there's more uh interesting details
about them
and we before that we explained why uh
fold or know as reduce they are the most
general form to rep functional way to
represent any loop. Okay. So we
demonstrate that. So so so what so what
is uh other things interesting? So we
explained uh so there is also emacisp
shall we demonstrate emac leisp okay you
know we can actually just copy it
yeah so let's just you know because I've
already written so many tutorials uh
let's yeah let's just demonstrate it
because it is interesting you know
because I talk about programming
languages so it's just interesting to
see so here's a eaglist you define a
variable xx that's a vector. Vector is
just like a list. It's it's like a
JavaScript array. Okay? You cannot add
elements to it. So it's like C array or
JavaScript uh well it's like C array but
it's not like JavaScript array because
in JavaScript array is actually dynamic
array. You can add elements. So in EMAC
this vector is like a C array or it's
like Python's tuple. Okay. So, so if so,
so then you have the function reduce and
the second argument to reduce is a is a
is a array vector. Okay. So, if we run
this, we get ABC. So, let's run it.
Okay, it ran but it didn't print. Well,
it printed. Um, so uh so let let's run
this way. Okay. So
run it. Okay. Now you can see at the
bottom it you know then here we
run it. You see the result is ABC.
Okay. So that's a demonstration of
lisp emac lisp. Okay. So next let's talk
about so that's uh wan language fold
javascript
reduce and uh eac list form reduce okay
now let's take the let's talk about you
know starting to get interesting because
um so by the way if you don't know wuam
language I've done
almost 100 videos about it just search
for
wuam language tutorial my named
oni.info.
Now remember the URL is HTTP. There's no
S. If the browser tells you, oh, there's
a security error. That's because they
try to censor, you know, they sensor
millions of websites. So just make sure
the HTTP there's no s. Okay. So Wam
language you can download it for free
since like few years ago. Uh it's the
most powerful programming language.
Okay. Okay. So, woofam language you know
I have like uh you know hundreds of
videos before. So, woofam language in
depth you can learn um from the ground
up. Uh let's let's make it larger. Okay.
uh complete tutorial for programmers
that is if you already have some
experience with a programming language
then you got you know bunch of like my
best videos general intro graphics
animation how to define a function and
miscellaneous okay I have like almost
100 videos so we demonstrate wam
language we demonstrated JavaScript we
demonstrated um let's go back we
demonstrated um
you know how it is a general form of for
loop then um what I want to show let's
say let's see woofam
wam got so many others okay nesting uh
like wam got
10 times more than 10 times like you
know 20 times more functions working on
list
okay programming language okay so here
is interesting thing
this we debated for a few months you
know on discord so let me just summarize
what's going on okay and that's it for
today so arrange so you know people say
that it became confusing because in some
programming language like like what
there's a question why why why is it
some languages call it reduce some
languages call it fold in fact many
programming language which they have
both in the language and they differ a
little bit. Okay. So why is that? And
the other question is what's the origin
of fold and reduce you know like which
language first had it is it from
theoretical computer science. Okay. So
here's a summary. Okay. The origin of
the concept of f reduce yes they are
from theoretical uh computer science.
They are from lambda calculus and from
recursion theory. they are they are
basically the s same uh subject
recursion the theory is also known as
computability theory okay lambda
calculus the origin of lamb lambda
calculus is is uh researching on
computability like what cannot be
computed okay so the arrangement of fold
and reduce they are the same thing they
are from lambda calculus and
computability theory Okay, that's your
arrangement. Now, so what is a fold in
general? Fold is just a function form of
a loop. That's it. Okay, this is the
best way to understand it. If you think
of it as something else, that's um that
would be misleading for you. Okay.
Uh hello hello nonsense name clipper.
And uh so but some programming language
name it fold and some programming
language name it reduce. Okay. Then
later on programming languages it you
know started to diversify such that for
example in G scheme lisp
and in F and in C++
they all have both fold and reduce in
their language. However, their fold and
reduce differ slightly. Basically, their
fold is like the fold we are doing but
it takes a initial value. Did I show a
example that takes a initial value? Yes.
Wam language. Okay. So
you know so let me let me make it make
this clear. Let me let me uh express
this in a clear way. Okay.
Some programming languages do not have
any fold or reduce at all. Okay,
some do. Almost all functional
programming languages has it. Okay, now
some of the languages name it fold. Some
of it some programming languages name it
reduce. Okay.
And some programming languages have them
both and they differ by they they make
kind of became they make a distinction.
They they the fold version the the
version they call fold takes an initial
value. Okay like this not optional you
know always have a initial value like
this example. Now the version in their
language that that's called reduce
usually do not like do not have a
initial value. It just take a function
and a list. Okay. So the programming
languages started to diversify to start
to you know to make a distinction. So
fold usually take initial value and and
their reduced version does not.
So why do they do that? you know they do
that kind of like for practical reasons
for example in in F and in skin I
suppose you know because when you when
you have optional optional value you
know according to the lang depending on
the language for example F is statically
typed language strongly typed so every
function you need to know how many
argument it takes in advance and they
also do cur ing you know it gets
complicated but basically so for simply
simp simplicity reasons for type
checking whatever they make it two two
different function one is fold that
takes three arguments a function initial
value and a list then the other one is
reduce takes just two arguments a
function and a list and it so happens
the list can be empty so it's easier to
deal with because if you have fold will
reduce and if the least argument happens
to be empty you got a problem because
what you going to return
because you don't have initial value.
So, so that so for practical reasons
according to each programming language
they they may have both both fold and
reduce and typically the fold is the one
that takes the initial value three
arguments total and reduce is the one
that only takes two arguments no initial
value. Okay. So that is
what I think
that this programming language
diversified. Okay. So that is in this
article
in this article I just written about.
Is it interesting? Am I still going?
Okay. So for reduce okay so arrangement
of the concept that's from lambda
calculus and recursion theory on
computability and diversify reduce
became a version of fold without the
initial value while fold has initial
value okay so they take different number
of arguments just uh as a convenience
for the programming language
uh now so yeah so I explained that
what so they do that because it's just
for comm for example in F you need to
type check you know the arity of a
function how many arguments so and in
C++ that's worse it's far worse because
C++ you have lots of
okay then so which is a better term
fold or reduce bold is a better term
because fold
canot you know It conveys give you a
sense of recursion fold like folding a
close you know it's recursion why is it
that better because because fold is the
essence of fold is a functional form of
any loop okay so you want to you know be
and it came from recursion theory so
fold the word fold give you a sense you
know it's changing structure it's like
um it's something
Meanwhile, reduce
is not so good a terminology for for
this because reduce what does it make
you think? It you know it make you think
reducing something. So to a lot of
programmers it just means oh given a
list you reduce it to one value. You
don't think of it as a general form of a
loop.
So reduce is is not a good terminology.
Okay, fold is better. Now
what why do JavaScript name call it
reduce in many languages? Because these
people, you know, when you when you use
reduce, you just think of, you know, you
got a list of numbers or values, you
just
turn them into one single value. So that
you know obviously that's reduce. So a
lot of people start to think of fold or
reduce as like just reduce a bunch of
numbers into one. That's not good
thinking because if you think of it that
way then you forgot the like the
arranging like the the the real purpose
of fold which is to represent any loop
in a functional programming way. No side
effects. Okay. No update global state or
local state.
So that's about the jargon. Fold is a
bit of jargon. Okay. Now some people say
what about parallel computation. Now
that's gets more complicated. Are you
guys watching anyone? Okay. I'm not
doing a good video because I uh Okay. So
let me explain the parallel computation
relation. Okay. But let me just tell you
directly what what is the answer. board
has nothing to do with par parallel
computation.
A lot of the C++
programmers, you know, they thought, oh,
reduce is actually related to uh
parallel computation. Wrong. That's
totally bad thinking. Okay, re fold has
nothing absolutely to do with parallel
computation because fold is a functional
form for loop. And when you do a loop
the sequential order is required is in
fact required that's the essence of
loop. Now remember the engine in
recursions theory in lambda calculus in
lambda church numerals numerals they are
all about recursion nesting and you
can't you know it it the sequential
order is absolutely necessary.
So why why is that some people think of
u you know they think of reduce as
parallel computation.
Here's why. Okay. Because
in some situations when you do fold you
can you can actually
ignore the sequential order. You can
compute them in any way you like. when
the operation you pass to reduce or fold
has some special property. Okay, let me
show you why. Um so what programming
language should I use to demonstrate
that uh wam language or did I um
actually
I didn't have woofam language there. So
let me um copy the wam language. So let
me show you here. Okay.
Um,
copy
uh,
paste. Okay. Shift enter to run it.
Okay. So, range returns 1 2 3 4 5 6.
Fold F1 2 3 4 5 6 returns that. And then
you can do fold list.
Okay. So, let me show that.
Uh
what you what is my key here? Here
shift enter.
So it shows you
um full list just shows you the whole
history of the computation. Okay. So
copy that paste paste it again. Now
let's show a example with a initial
initial value let's say zero. Okay shift
enter.
Okay
so that's a wra in wufam notebook.
So what I want to say oh yeah so
demonstration of the parallel
computation relation. Now if so happens
so if your function is such that the
argument order does not matter that
property is called communive okay you
say that operation is communive do I do
you guys understand what I'm saying is
it interesting uh what's going on here
okay undo so let me explain this. Okay,
let me just explain this. Um,
commutative
property
means
f a
b
equals to
um
ba. Okay. So,
so a function or operation have this
property that's called commutative
property. Okay. Now, another property
associative
property means
uh let's see uh actually I have written
um articles about it. So, let let me
just write it on here. Okay. So, F
A B Okay. So,
what
a b c
equals to
F
A B.
Okay, that's what associative property
means. Okay, so you got you got three
numbers or three elements such that you
apply. So let's reverse the order. Okay.
So, let's actually put this here because
it's more intuitive
that way. Uh,
okay. You got three numbers. Apply AB
then the result feed back to F then then
you know uh apply F with that result and
C. So if that is equals to apply
you know you do the BC first feed them
to F then the result feed them to F and
with that result.
So if the function or operation satisfy
this property that is called associative
you know you call that function
associative. So when a function has
associative property then and when the
function also have communive
commutative property
both of them basically is about order.
So commutative property is very easy to
understand it's just order of the
argument.
Okay the associative property is a bit
more complicated. it involves like
sequential application of the function
twice on three arguments. Okay. So when
a function has both of these properties
then when you do fold on the function uh
you know when you do fold like that on
the function
then it doesn't m matter which order you
take what what you can do is that you
can take f12
then do f45
then do f3 and six and every time you
got two results you feed back to f. So
basically all the list of numbers you
can think of them as fishes in a pound.
Every time you can just grab two fishes
and feed it to a function. So you can do
it in parallel. So grab two fish you
know come out result. Grab two fish come
out result another you know random fish
in the pound. Then every two result you
take them and feed back to the function.
So, so this way you reduce you know
every time you take two output one you
take two output one eventually you got
just one item okay so
you know you are doing this in a random
order almost
and the result will be correct if your
operation the function f has these two
properties commutative and associative
Okay. So,
so basically when when your oper
operation has these two properties, what
operation has that property?
Uh
so what operation has
the commutative property and the
associative property and that operation
would be
what?
What? Where is my question mark there?
Okay.
Example
plus. Why? Because
oops.
Because these two are equal. plus ab is
the same as plus ba and plus ab then
plus that result with c is the same as
plus bc then plus a and bc. Okay. So the
plus has that property
also multiplication
two. Okay. But what operation do not
have those property? Actually most
operations do not have that property.
Uh most most operations
are functions you know operation and
function is kind of the same operation
focus on the emphasis of the like the
operator. Okay. So for example the plus
you can write it as
can be also written as
um uh where is my plus sign
that okay so
so let me just write this quickly. Oh
god.
Uh, new keyboard. So, um, yeah. God,
this way. Okay. So,
and uh that is that just ABC. So, uh,
delete that.
Okay. Uh, so that wait. So that mean
what?
Okay. So that we want to write it.
Oh god.
So we want to write it like that. And
now just replace comma by a plus sign.
Do it there. There, there, there, there.
Okay. So this is way to this is another
way to write that. When we write it in
this way, we think of it as a functional
form. So we think of plus as a function.
When we write it this way, we think of
the plus as an operator. So operator is
kind of a syntax syntactical way to
represent a function. Okay, that's what
it means.
So plus sign the plus function has
commutative property and associative
property.
So does the multiplication. But most
operations
are not commutative
and not associative. Okay, most function
are not. For example, the minus uh for
example
uh minus
or for for example
matrix
multiplication.
Okay, do I make sense? So, so why are we
talking about these two properties?
Because when a function has these two
properties commutative and associative
then when you do fold on it the order
doesn't matter anymore. So that is why
that is why it started a confusion in
some of the programming languages where
is my page
that is why in some of the programming
language such as C++ okay C++ the worst
what in the computing industry in C++ in
their reduce they can specify you know
they started to let you do parallel
computation you see because when order
doesn't matter anymore more. So
you can do fold without following any
order only if your operation has this
commutative and associative properties.
Okay. So when you can do them in any
order then you can do you you no longer
need to do them sequentially. You can do
in parallel you know like bunch of
fishes in a pound. You can in parallel
grab two fish grab two fish feed to the
function. you got two new output you
know you just you can apply 1,00 uh you
know processes on grabbing two fishes
because order doesn't matter so you can
do them in parallel okay so this is the
relation this is why some people think
or in C++ they started to think that
reduce is some somehow connected to
parallelism
which is like very misleading and
utterly wrong
way of thinking because because fold and
reduce by their very nature they must be
sequential and not parallel. Okay. And
what made it worse is that about 10
years ago Google
Google started to market this thing
called map reduce.
So what you know so so we before we
explain the relation reduce to parallel
computing why are they uh connected in
fact they are not related because
because when you can do parallel two two
functions in uh with the commu
commutative and associative property
that means you can do it with for loop
too you know like when you do a for loop
like the the we we demonstrated for loop
like I = to zero, I minus 9, I less than
9 and I ++. Can you do them in random
order? No, obviously not because that's
the nature of for loop. You sequential
order is is required.
However,
if the body of your for loop is just
plus operation like one plus, you know,
whatever plus, then you can do them in
any order. But does that mean you
started to think oh for loop is actually
for parallel computation?
That would be very bad thinking. Okay.
Same thing applies to um fold or reduce.
It is not parallel. It's simply a four.
It's a loop. Okay.
But you but it's a par it's parallel.
When the operation you know have these
properties then you can you can kind of
do it. That's what C++ is leading people
to do to think you know that C++ led
people to think that way and what what
made it worse is that is that in the um
in there's a Google project you know
like hugely popular 10 years ago around
2010 you know they call it maps reduce
that's a that's a time when big data you
know data science big data and machine
learning became popular. Google is
pushing it. So they have map reduce. So
does map reduce means they are related
to parallel computation? No. Because
why? Because Google's map reduce is just
a product name. It's not computer
science. It's just a product name for
their you know for their platform.
And and why so but why do they call it
map reduce? Because that's exotic.
That's dramatic. You know when you when
when you say map reduce oh functional
programming what is functional
programming oh recussion oh science
that's oh lambda that's so advanced
that's what make people think so that's
a map marketing jargon you know they
call it map reduce and what they are
doing is actually parallel computation
but really but then it's not it's not
it's not map reduce it's not reduce okay
nothing with uh to do with
functional programming. Okay. Okay.
That's what I wanted to talk about
today. Uh basically about this like
these kind of issues. So we so we you
know a bunch of us on discord on discord
did I I I I I turned it off right now. I
don't want to start it because then it's
going to show uh private messages in the
beginning. Anyway, so we you know a
bunch of us started to talk debate about
this since few month ago and we asked AI
Gork AI. So Gork AI actually gave a lot
you know so
it helped uh
me understand a lot of things you know
you know in programming what's the
history of fold and reduce and work
explains origin in theory and early
computing for reduce uh you know uh
aggregate data from theory of lambda
calculus uh and you know and and uh uh
church numerals and and so so
Then early implementations in
programming languages then okay then
rise in functional programming 1980s to
1990s okay you then you have for left
and for right which we didn't cover they
are they are like trivial they they are
just like
four left just begin from from the left
for right begin from the right why do
you need them well you don't need them
you can just reverse at least just like
push and pop in a stack you know in in
many programming languages you have
a function called push and pop you know
like to a list so push means add item to
the end of list pop means take off that
item from the end of list so in Python
in pearl in Ruby I believe they are take
it from the end of the list but however
however in lisp programming language
which is the push and pop are doing it
to the front of the list. Okay. So,
so so so when you but if you want to do
it to the front and your language is
doing them at the end or you have you
know you can reverse the list but that's
you know that takes time. So you might
have another operation that works on the
front of the list. So in pearl for
example
and in Python I believe too. And in
JavaScript too, push and pop
does it to the end of the list. If you
wanted to do to the front of the list,
you use something called shift and
unshift. Okay, that's similar to push
and pop, but they operate on the front
of the list or array. Okay. So in a
similar way when you do fold
you know you you can you can you can
start with the front or start from the
end but sometimes it's convenient if you
want to start from the other side. So
that's why you have fold left and for
right or also known as reduce left and
reduce right. So that's what they are.
Okay. So again back to history rising
functional programming 1980s to 1990s
and there's more uh modern adoption and
distinction. So they started to have
like diff a difference diversity you
know uh between f and reduce
um c
and uh and weight. Okay. So,
so actually this is the wrong link to Gu
because I asked GU a lot more questions
about
about it relations to parallel
computation. Uh why did it not show? I
thought I got the latest link.
Okay, I might need to update the link.
Okay, so anyway, that's it for today.
Thank you guys for watching. So
uh yes and the many two one concept is
exactly what I think of when I use here
reduce. Yeah. Uh yeah that's a bad
that's a misleading that's very
misleading. Okay. Don't think about that
because because I was telling the story
when I learned it back in 30 years ago
you know you I learned from Mathematica
Wuam language you know. So you got this
fold. So I thought it's kind of strange
why why do you want to like it's kind of
odd because the function takes two
things and each time you you know you
take the result from previous iteration
then you feed it at one do you want to
do that you know it's kind of odd but if
you
think of it as you know you if you start
to think it is a general way to do loops
in a functional following way. Then you
realized why it is that way. Because the
function, why does the function takes
two items? Because one of the item is
the state from previous
iteration, you know, like in a loop,
every time you change a state, right?
When you do a loop, so if you want to do
it in a functional programming way, so
you save the state every time you have a
state, you feed back to the function. So
the function takes a previous you know
state then you takes a new argument
compute it got a result which is a new
state then you call the function again
so feed it back so that's that's why you
know it's a general form of loop
so but if you think of it as reduce you
know the the first person who named it
reduce is must be punished I think
that's a programming language you know
Grog I think Grog um talked about it. I
you know because when you if you have
the word reduce then you just think oh
you just take a bunch of things and make
it into one thing you lost the entire
essence the idea of fold of recursion
you know that the origin in lambda
calculus in computability okay so that's
it
bye guys
so did I how long did I talk for the uh
I think this video is very long and
rambling so anyone watching it must
watch in like
two times speed.
Bye guys.