good morning guys
welcome to another episode of exotic
show today is 2019
October 9th Wednesday niall o'clock 10
o'clock a.m.
San Francisco time and I have prepared
several topics today and that is let's
see what is in the comments so
Bartholomew is a fan of new share bottom
you kept telling me about new share new
Chou is written in rust I suppose PP
good morning D P DP is from Germany I
think so bathroom you says I'm a
secondhand source maybe you should visit
the first-hand source on github about
yeah but I don't get what are you saying
what are you saying about pipe so bottom
you says though the summarize the
command structure is the entire entirely
based on pipes you know you know what's
pipes based on pipes okay you know a new
shell oh not not shower new shell okay
so stupid stupid doctor go it went it
tries to search for nut shell okay so
let's go to new shell no shell website
apps by the way does anyone know for
example on discord they have a ad
version like they have you know they
tell me to download a desktop app so I
suppose the desktop app version is
better than the web site version is a
true so let's look at new shell you know
I'm too old for it you know when when
you are younger you you you switch your
round shells desktop you know win
system the Linux windowing system you
have you have so many you have xfce you
have let's look let's look at Linux ok
Linux website so when you are younger
you do that for example when I was
younger I looked you know back then the
source of shell shell was on UNIX you
have you have shell orange open shell
orange an open shell then you have bash
poem again shell which is a pun on the
christian poem again thing there and you
then you have seashell because sea
became popular then people want to have
C syntax then they have seashell and
it's one of the worst shell then you
have C sharp on shell c shell is very
early you know C char by the way is like
30 years old almost
zishe out today people are saying Bank
even back in ten years or ten years ago
people are saying oh you need to use Z
shells each of this order better
completion and so on yeah but when you
are younger you do that when you get
older those are not important those are
not important you know what's what's
important the important I mentioned this
many times the important thing is that
you write applications that people use
so you know yeah you know that you have
some nice features or something but you
know it's not an not it's not really
that important you know slowly
what is this welcome back please log in
to continue nutshell okay I don't want
nutshell no this is nutshell what is
this free trials pricing integration I
don't want nutshell ok go to new shell
new shell I suppose you've announced a
new shell and it's written in rust you
know what I can tell you why this is new
Chou is popular because it's written in
rust
now rust thank the language because it's
a deal with
memory it's kind of a modern Siri
placement so it has a lot of hacker
types they are all chanting about rust
everyday rust what do you think about
Russ oh you need to use rust
I don't like rust okay I don't like this
the type of languages that deal with low
level stuff such as C C++ rust that kind
of thing okay I'm into math modeling
things prove this is proof systems
so anyway worst and new shell because
it's written in verse therefore people I
you know these hacker types gets excited
about it you know this is important
because it's specifically this this is
hacker types this type of people only
these people they are not many by the
way they are kind of minority among
programmers these hacker types they want
they chant you know they sing the songs
they they talk about things they tell
you what to do so new shall new shall do
they have a a website or is just the
github okay so and and you know what so
back to the other thing I was saying you
know Windows desktop I mean Linux
Windows systems let's see yeah LXDE rxt
Windows systems and XFC Windows systems
then you have whitening window manager
sucks okay that alko is everywhere on
our chant forums in hacker news and read
it quite highly managers sucks X monad
rat poison
DWM and and and also this comment go
like this year for this five years it's
what's the hottest DWM o or d3 or
whatever you call them you know the next
five years is has Carmona know everyone
you need to have more net then then the
least rat poison and the what's this the
second version rat poison
you know people this this are not
important not
important yeah these are the things
hacker yeah and also Emacs wim Emacs
versus ring every day it's not really
important okay the important thing I
mean although it's the things we like we
tend to focus on these things which
which one is the most elegant things
like that but these are not really
important to society on the whole I
talked about this a few times so so yeah
so our Linux you have X you know L XP e
XFC actually I like them I like our l
x.v year and X X F see that there was my
window system on Linux and they are no
these two are known as the most minimal
and efficient they don't you know anyway
it comes when I start to talk about
Linux there's tons of stories it's
amazing this the Linux full of pain full
of 10 the denotes nothing works if
everything you do you have to spend
hours to get it to work for example for
example let me tell you a let me just
mention this okay on on UNIX
traditionally you have this top utility
t.o.p you type top okay you these beasts
or your processes what application how
much CPU they consume how much memory
they consume things like that and then
actually a better version a better
version is H tops you don't have it on a
Mac and you don't have it on Linux
neither you have to install it each top
okay I recommend it so let me show you
Linux you go to my Linux tutorial just
such folks sorry Linux okay and this is
a very practical tutorial on everything
command line based operation of Linux
that is what I teach you about all the
most frequently used commands you have
to use everyday you have to be familiar
with if you
doing anything with Linux at all so
that's my tutorial okay check it check
it out and then so for example let's
look at the top utility okay so you have
top you have PS and you have job control
okay these are the Linux processes tools
so this is what toughs looks like you
know you can change the color this is
what top looks like and top it's got
lots of problems and the Linux load
average oh I cannot talk about I cannot
start to talk about Linux or UNIX
because then all the memory surfaces
then I'm going to top 10 hours
flaming UNIX and Linux with all the
stories I can tell you top load average
the most idiotic metric for the
monitoring processes okay then you have
to dig into detail like let me ask you a
question you Linux UNIX fans what does
the load average number actually mean
answer okay you I can tell you that you
cannot answer it you don't know the
answer
wait in my life okay I can tell you
right off the bat you you don't know
what is the answer to know the answer
you have to spend our few hours into you
know guru Stack Overflow these days
people don't even that question anymore
that question was 10 years before you
know in 2019 nineteen hundred year 2000
you do to ask you know what does exactly
the load average number me very complex
and not just that it's extremely easy
attic you know as a system as a tour to
measure you know tell you telling you
about CPU is just idiotic the way the
reason they are idiotic we did they are
the way because the UNIX they are
everything in UNIX is is written in this
the most simplistic way possible
implementation wise okay like whichever
is the most easy to
do you just do that if they'd do it that
way no design whatever I mean whenever
there's a decision actually you don't
even think about design you don't you
don't it's like like most people say
program is a lot of trade-off like
whether you want to maximize disk
efficiency or memory efficiency or speed
things like that but but for the UNIX
operating system UNIX philosophy UNIX
stuff almost you don't design everything
is whatever which ever way is the
fastest and whichever way is the most
simple brainless to implement you do you
do not need to study for research for
hours you know into what architectures
system you just choose whatever is most
convenient that you can implement it
right away like C programming language
is like that then you just you see you
do it that and that is a result load
average is an example of such result the
most idiotic metric so anyway back to
our previous topic I was talking about
top the 2 or top and there is a better
tool called H top on Linux it's not
installed by default you know in my
opinion you should have replaced top
long ago but Linux people UNIX people
they have a thing with backward
compatibility so so oh the UNIX command
including shell the way you do things in
in Chou and
ctrl T to exit things like that they are
all like 40 years old 40 years old
doesn't make sense at all today but it's
the tradition yeah okay so you have h
top you have to install it on linux okay
this is how it looks like what why is it
better than top because first of all for
example it gives you a visual clue you
know like a visual you know the tech
space GUI that's what I call it
text-based GUI so it gives you this path
so you can see at the immigrants how
much memory has been used but the top
doesn't do that it's you know it's just
a bunch of numbers but act
but the most important thing about each
table better than top is because it can
show all the processes not just the top
okay another thing about unix is the
naming of things all the naming are
extreme idiotic and they think you know
the to the link nina linux people the
UNIX people they think it's fun if they
think it's fun they love the these or
these jargon so top cat
they love it less more you know you know
things like that and so anyway so why is
it named top because this tool only
lists lists the top processes that uses
the most most CPU but you know the
screen you know it's supposed to you
want to see more than you know what's
after that process you cannot do it you
can you it is impossible to do it with
these the this top tool okay impossible
impossible
you know the UNIX philosophy one of the
UNIX philosophy is oh to one thing nice
smooth used beautiful but do one thing
well they each UNIX utility do not do
one thing well ok this top you can not
least you can only have the top list of
processes you cannot see the rest of it
impossible ok if you want to see the
rest of it you have to use another tool
that is why then you have h table H
table the purpose is just like top but
you can also see you can see at least
all processes you know you show part of
it on a screen but you can see what's
the others so that's that's Linux the
story of Linux and and and also on the
Mac for example let me show you the Mac
let me show you the the Mac Activity
Monitor ok this one it's just I mean
although although its GUI this is real
GUI ok oh no second
okay so on the Mac you have this GUI
tool like you can you can sort processes
by CPU or you can sort it by memory okay
you can go and show memory okay actually
it's it's much more convenient even
though it's not a even even even though
it's not a text-based
tool anyway back to Linux so the reason
I mentioned it so you have top you have
edge table but the Linux people because
they do realize you know GUI is actually
important say so so so they also have
this GUI based lists the processes for
example on Chrome they have one on xfce
they have one on our xte they have their
own okay like this each each faction of
the linux create their own because they
anyway so so is you know it's very
confusing but anyway so you know one day
so i so i look into this kind of thing
you know like which which one is the
best I study them you know when you
launch on if you are using the Chrome
desktop or if you use the chrome version
that shows the processes that tool eats
all your memory okay you have six
gigabyte it has net who eats three
jjigae by something like that I can tell
you because I this is so this is it's so
fact and then you have Linux people
saying oh it's better than Windows is
incredible okay truly push it I'm not
going to start to get into a rant about
Linux topic because I was going to talk
about something else okay so so we
talked about top top and short code we
don't care
so yeah so I was saying when you were
younger you were into these things you
want to know which is the best and also
programming languages as well like
people you know want to know which one
is the best programming language : name
for example julia has cow you know and
also again that is a topic I love very
much that's a topic I love very much and
so do you guys but that again that is
not really important thing okay a really
important thing so I wanted to yeah I
was just going to I was just telling you
the chrome whatwhat's the version that's
the Gloam GUI that shows the shows the
processes let's see if I can find it
so bash terminal Linux desktop new Notes
desktop and the commercial version okay
so - desktop default set default app
shell command for GUI apps
okay shell command for you I absent UI
apps
I forgot what's a a most most useful to
you I have terminal file manager CPU
monitor and update manager G edit PDF
viewer vaio computer dictionary unicode
character viewer taskbar music players
audio control panel yeah the okay others
gnome power statistics norm control
center gnome system monitor I think
that's the one good gnome system monitor
you can see it you can try it okay if
you are on linux go launch or installed
no system monitor and go install the
xfce version and go inst go launch the
LXDE version you can then you can you
know in in them you can see compare how
much memory they are using the genome
one is is 10 it eating 10 times than the
GUI it's just impossible incredible to
believe and do you know and how do i
know this i spent you know you spend
days to look into this that's that's why
you you know linux unix they suck your
life you don't you forget about doing
your walk learning javascript and even
use everyday every day you spend our to
look to do these things like what like
like suppose you originally this suppose
you you know oh I'm just going to
install Ubuntu chrome okay I'll just get
on with my life I need to do things but
then that's not a case because when you
launch you are out of memory or
something then you have to know oh but
why is it out of memory what what's
going on you know then you started to
check which which app is eating your
memory or something so you spend like
half an hour below average half an hour
a day just to look around the Unix Linux
stuff
okay so that is a big digression I have
some topics I want to talk about
actually so let's kind of take a break
and let's see where we are
so this new Chou you know I suppose it's
good I suppose you know I okay I could
looking you know I would put to use it
when I if I were younger because in
general newer things are better so you
know I suppose this will have many new
features you know like like as time goes
on you tries to get away from the old
way you know it gradually it does happen
so I would self on the positive positive
side I would I believe new Chou is
probably better you know everyone should
switch to it so so Sanders this project
something something come be Orion
commands so anyway and and again
animation today you don't you don't do
shell anymore you don't do if you are a
programmer you know it it programming
industry practices how you do things
changes every like 10 years about 10
years they change actually every day but
in general like 10 years you can see a
big difference you don't so so back in
1990s 1980s 1990s to even to early 2000s
you shall is a very critical important
tool for programmers for UNIX you know
if you are on UNIX because everything
you need to do we you do you use the
shell to do it but not today today you
have you know you go you go by
serverless server less servers service
something ok man you have Dropbox each
one is a entire new environment you you
do things like that you don't you don't
you don't do shout much anymore you
don't do you know before you you have
used to you have
to be master of grab and grab TR and a
bunch of you know UNIX utilities Co a
you know things like a cat you don't do
that anymore much as a typical
programmer you know you you work on
something else
you okay so that is about say yeah so I
don't know about nutshell I suppose it's
it is good but let's get on to whatever
I was going to talk about today so let's
just copy
first of all copy the what we talked
about H top top H top Y tiny manager
sucks even though I didn't talk about
that so close that and GUI apps command
names okay showing browser okay so close
that close that how to switch to LXDE
and stuff because that because that okay
so actually it is this book meow cat
showed to me this book apparently it's
written by Stephan Hawking the guy the
physicist on Inc wheelchair you know
he's got some kind of disabled disease
and he died few years ago so fancy he
wrote this book God created the integers
the mathematical breakthroughs that
changed history he wrote this in 2007
2007 I didn't know about this so it
seems to be a good book okay because it
talked it gives you okay you need to
look at a table of contents anyway so if
you like it buy it okay let me just post
my math website
and then I'm going to read the comments
so that's my math block go there and buy
the book I'm not going to read a book
because I'm too old because when you are
this is not a technical math book I
don't think it's not really technique
it's it's kind of I think it's kind of
solid introduction of math they talk
about several great mathematicians and
their work for for example if you are
under undergraduate math student then
you read this book you'll be good
because when I was younger I read too
many of these books I've read you know
the times come and go you know normally
I I today I should have been like I'm a
professor you know a mathematician a
professor at some university I write
these books I write that's supposedly
what happens I'm too old yeah I'm still
talking about Oh what books is you
should write or you should be that's
kind of getting CD okay so so let's
let's get on the topics um so I wanted
to show you this Google Newspeak that
which is very evil but okay but but
there is let us check where I am
stop this video I have 18 Watchers
good morning and I have talked about I
have talked for 27 minutes and now it's
time to read the comments and I do it is
also time for me to take off my clothes
you
there I am
hold on a second thou shalt see
No then I take off take it off
so I out there and and I need to this is
a Magoo you guys know about this company
I actually went there and interview a
few years ago about three years ago four
years ago I went there for an interview
and okay so let's look at the comments
what are people saying people say what
they say let them say now this is the
right time to ask me questions post
questions and I'll answer it or talk
about it
magnify
unlike okay so I'm going to read the
comments
magnify magnify Sonu Shah is one of my
one of the few truly modern applications
okay maybe I'll give it a shot
you know the I'm doing the video it's
taking a lot of time it's almost like
every day it's zapping me out my energy
was due to the video even though it
doesn't look like much you know I just
talk for now in half but but it's like
it's it's it's like spending four hours
on other day and I haven't you know I
need to get back to get on with the
JavaScript with web pack and Paso and
lots of JavaScript things so look in the
description of the repository they
describe how the show natively passes
Jason okay I'll check it out and you
know I think is a good tool it just
doesn't look or feel like a show more
likely table-based is SQL command line
interface okay
yeah it's must be
you know something new so I suppose
these you know I suppose it is good your
brothers yo Nebo Nybo neighbor or Nebo
so bottom you say something new showing
enough support it's not mature enough
sponsor me says there are many crappy
apps but Musha is one of the exceptions
ok always finding new shell when
searching new shell
ok I finally found your function thank
God I found your functions what
functions it might be a matter of
personal preferences is often is Russ
Russ Russ it only needs 10 commit small
and repository has 1337 commits 1 3 3 7
is that meant to be a code word Costco
routine channels but I like us concept
data ownership our borrowing what do we
learn all the languages but the
functions are spending my any file they
are something something but the
functions are spending my in in fact
what functions hike saw green tech good
morning then stop talking about UNIX
taiga new show ok you know bottom here
what you should use you should use monad
there is this thing called monad and let
me show it to you ok
sorry powershell from your beloved
Microsoft now PowerShell was known as
monarch back in 2000 when he was still
in research stage bottom you you should
use PowerShell you know strengths spend
on our read my tutorial PowerShell
basics because the
is improvements of the UNIX pipe okay
because in UNIX pipe or you pipe every
day is text where but the in PowerShell
you got a real pipe system you don't
just pipe text you have you you pipe
objects okay then you can you can you
can format them into different text
formats okay so this is the proper yeah
you should try it from from your beloved
Microsoft the open source supporter the
greatest open source supporter no
compatibility with bash okay
usually shells they are not compatible
with each other usually sisha sisha
bash you know they are not compatible
with this with each other then you know
then the Linux also then then they also
created ash as you know they first of
all you have shell SH okay then you have
bash then Linux people created ash back
in mm I learned you know ash is kind of
a minimized bash you need that so that
they can start up when the machine
starts is faster things like that tech
space user interface okay yes that's
what they call you know the tech geeks
the proper name is supposed to be
text-based user interface i I just
called co-ed text-based GUI
okay that's because that's actually more
intuitive text-based UI okay similar VI
Greek meow cats quickly we we maintain
the shell without a formal design spec
is just way sometimes your progress
Greeks geeks
okay the text crew are more convenient
okay no comments that's why no MS known
to be super fat Linux is superb choices
okay a mother
stuff okay no comments you guys don't
have any comments in topics previous
uses but for these type of functions
okay so DPI says how helpful is the help
menu of Emacs on Mac the help menu
that's literally useless you never use
in Emacs okay that's what you're talking
about right so in Emacs you have the
help menu that's that's very it rather
extremely idiotic okay so let me show
you this thing so go to eMac eMac sprog
so I got several things I'm going just
going to talk about them okay so so
first of all let me show you about the
Emacs GUI menu so you go to sorry Emacs
blog then you go to click on the Emacs
modernization this is a collection of
articles that I that I described Emacs
problems one of them this is incredible
okay one of thing is this its infects
Emacs menu usability problem okay why am
i laughing because it's idiotic to the
most extreme now I said that many times
about UNIX but this in this case it's so
extreme that even a UNIX phonetics like
you guys okay you see my point but
however it's hopeless for the Emacs to
change it's like impossible they will
never change anything and so hold on a
second okay so let me just post let me
get my block fixed here okay book so
this is a book God created the integers
by the way that is a phrase God created
integers that is one of the
one phrase from this mathematician
Konica I think he's German mathematician
Kanaka very one of the big mathematician
now there's a story behind it so he said
God created the integers the rest is by
men okay men created okay why does he
say that this is this is a very popular
quote among mathematicians and math
communities because you know it's
dramatic dramatic you can code you can
say it's a meme okay it's a meme from
300 years ago it's of me God created the
integers the rest is the creation of men
so but what's the background contact why
does he say that because back then 300
years ago also there's a fight between
mathematicians because you know like
different schools of philosophy
just like today UNIX UNIX versus you
know the Haskell functional programming
versus over P this happens in math as
well so but so back then 300 years ago
do you have one school that believes
beliefs kind of that that integers is
should be the foundation of all
mathematics something like that okay on
the other side you have people who
believe kind of infer testimo and
calculus kind of thing they don't
believe you have to base everything on
integers okay that's basically the
background so that's that's so that's
how this phrase was very popular this is
part of math history so if you just
search the face map God created the
integers you'll find the story you
you're you know then you click the links
after link you probably find it on
Wikipedia I'm sure of that
so anyway so so yeah let me talk about
the Emacs menu usability problem so you
got this I am Not sure I'm even going to
talk about it because it's
you know if I'm going to talk about it
it's just I'm just going to show you and
you you will be convinced that how
extreme edie idiotic
it is the Emacs GUI menu to this day
it's you know I wrote this article in
back in 2009 to these states
it's insane okay it's pretty much the
same nothing has fixed and but and and
and I also by the way I was over the
burger repo back in 2000 2010 I wrote I
have sent like lots of turns of bug
reports to Emacs death and and after 10
years now after 15 years I'm getting
some replies like layouts they are
studying your leg last week I got
several replies about my past 10 years
old more than 10 years old Berkeley
reports you know oh okay we're gonna fix
that one we're gonna curse this one you
know that's what Emacs tab is like that
open source free software foundation you
don't they don't have a processor don't
care you know it's just like they do
whatever yeah it's a you you sending a
bug report after 10 years if they they
they send you a formulator you know it's
something that I mentioned this a few
times on Reddit and but people don't
believe it like people say are you sure
you people don't believe it but you
viewed you know you can just go scope go
to the website such sorry no dev bug you
will find it you know your your your
your see is in my email but I don't want
to show you my email you will see you
know the update you you will see what
I'm saying you know you you write a bug
report
then after 10 years now they reply they
respond to you know they trying to clean
out some why do they suddenly because
this last week that's few weeks this
month
okay that's last month I started to get
several of that 10 years old bug reports
I did say for several of them they are
talking it you know they see seed to me
you know they start to say oh this
should be fixed on
you know they start to talk about that
why because I started to do videos I'm
pretty sure you know some of my Emacs
followers some people started to see me
talk about things then then some you
know by indirect ways they you know some
of the Emacs tears started to fix or
something you know the tries to you know
it's a it's a you know what how does it
feel you know it's like metal tasting a
coin how do you feel
you know taste test
tasting putting put put a penny to your
mouth to your turn and then doing all
these years seniors people flame you and
stuff you know the Emacs people because
they don't like my you know think
because when you criticize which is so
man or Emacs community they don't like
you you get all kind of they attack you
all the time they smear you know smear
they say things that's not true about
you oh by the way that happened
unfortune yesterday we were looking at
4chan and that is this this incredible
let's let's have a look at that okay son
talk show yesterday okay we were talking
about 4chan and in one of these posts
okay is incredible these people they
they posted a screenshot of what's
supposed supposedly what I was saying
but actually that's not they faked it so
they take the time to fake a screenshot
so that makes me look bad but you know
something I didn't say they make it so
that as if I said it I have to find out
where is that okay so let's take a few
minutes to do that it's kind of
incredible people do that and people are
doing that on 4chan now you know
fortunately it's a long time you know
you cannot trust fortune by the way if
you don't know fortune has been around
for
fifteen 20 years almost now and you know
it's FBI CIA they are sitting on it for
since long ago
you don't since long ago they have
several lots of stories political or
otherwise so you see this guy says he
found us so what what does he say so he
showed his screenshot you know okay so
he says he's got my head sorry today at
10:37 he says fortune as of of
as of fast by the way is talking for
channel discord a problem brahbrah okay
so he posed that this post he is he
faked it the first you see so the real
one is this one someone saw actually
someone's one nice says you know why do
why did you modify the first line okay
so this is what it looks like this is my
post yesterday hung on this code okay
I say praise the Lords of fortune okay
by the way by the way is taking four
channel talking 4chan discord a problem
like this code gonna ban in stuff I read
on Wikipedia on this code apparently
some social justice can are hitting this
code that's what I said on this scored
yesterday and we can go to this code and
see the original message right here okay
this code is loading so yesterday 10 o
clock 1037 what well 137 not 1037
yesterday 137 so a.m. wait yesterday 137
am okay so it's above it's above where
did it go yesterday 11 a.m.
now if I cannot find it then I will
spend one hour to find it because now
this is yesterday yesterday yesterday
the 556 a.m. so the a.m. and p.m. they
are not ordered exactly 6:00
so
no I'm not this I'm not promoting no
so how do you such okay let's use the
search function so let's just such folks
sorry I only want to see my own posts
okay so this one okay and let's see oh
the result is here
bathroom you interactive chat is much
better than forum forum is kind of going
dead okay the the the you know the the
society is moving on forum you know a
text forum like reddit is kind of dead
you want instead you want interactive
forum with also with voice support okay
at this is idiotic I am not familiar
with this code yet but I need to find
that message so yesterday yesterday
start aiming it stop talk go yesterday
okay close that
there it is well the time changed okay
so each okay so I see that add on my
time wait what what what time are they
is using like GMT or something very
confusing so that's what I said praise
the Lord our message there so there are
people on 4chan and also on Twitter I
know for sure on Twitter so he would you
know spend the time to fake a message
you know but what is going on you know
with these kind of people and and also
note that he is doing this on 4chan
which is typically you know so that
means you know there are people on 4chan
who is trying to around you know
with with you guys that essentially you
know they or you can say it's
infiltration you know they you know what
what is this guy doing I mean why would
he do that
okay you know I'm not too big I'm not
very popular yet so so far you know the
social justice can they don't you know
chase me off yet but you will happen as
you know
matter most then use matter moans I
don't know what that what is that okay
so so let me check the comments a little
bit quickly and let's go on to the next
topic okay
the next topic let's talk about I want
to there are some interesting things
about keyboard and mouse okay now we
have 51 minutes we can talk to moment so
so the night is young okay close that
new shall close that power show okay and
okay so let's go back to the messages
and today's drink is apple juice okay
today's drink is apple juice so you can
see it
how do I join discord
oh yeah grab you ask Justine I've been
interesting so actually I have if you go
to Microsoft Hawk show page I put it in
a proper place on top so you can you see
this is the discord link so I think it's
this code is kind of fun so there it is
so okay so let me read the comments then
I go back to my topics so if you want an
interactive chat with a matter most then
use matter most
you know bathroom use if you recommend I
just post the URL because I don't know
what that is in nobody other people so
if just post the uart
URL directly don't worry and yeah but at
you know basically curb on this code
maybe still better than you know the
thing is bathroom you're like you have
to get on into the main stream you have
to fight they're not not run into a
sewage like a grub underground curb
that's what you are doing part of it at
least you know that's that's your
mentality you're just gonna dive into a
geek group that that's that is been
going on for 30 years I talked about
this so many times you know get get onto
Twitter get onto discord and fight
whatever you know put your opinions
there okay you don't go No okay great
you know because Tippecanoe you know in
the UNIX types you know these keek types
they've been doing that for 30 years
like Oh kioku cube fire oh you know this
tool or that tool for 30 years and today
that's what you get
Mayorkas they are young and naive
because I let them swing in the sewage
thank meow cat how old are you oh god
you are not much older okay so let's get
back to I want to talk let's talk about
some something okay google speak new
speak right on time just when we were
talking about these guys look at the
Google News speak okay now Google is
Google has this documentation a style
guide for you know programmers you know
thought you know developers you know at
developers.google.com style inclusive
documentation and they are telling you
how you should write documentation title
avoid ableist language ablest
okay not recommended before launch give
everyone a final sanity check okay
that's no you shouldn't do that
recommended is before launch give me
give everything a final check for
completeness in coyote okay so sanity
check is not allowed okay then another
one not recommended there are some crazy
outliers in the data no you shouldn't
say that you should say instead of you
should say there are some baffling
outliers in the data okay then another
not recommended is it creep hosts the
servers causing a poor user experience
until the key kriyas okay the way google
says you should say the new speak
language is you should say it slows down
the server's causing a poor user
experience and here the key crius okay
that's actually that's actually also
wrong you should not use the word poor
you know because poor implies poor
people it invokes the concept of poverty
you know so it's like you are
to normalize the poor people as a normal
state okay so that's not good okay you
should let me correct you Google let me
help you so you should not say causing a
poor user experience okay that's that's
that's privileged talking okay you guys
white people okay listen I'm a I'm a
people of color okay listen to me
so what you say instead of causing a
poor user experience you should say
causing a bad user experience okay let's
see the next item not recommended
we placed a dummy variable in this
example with appropriate variable okay
now the recommended way is replace the
placeholder variable in this example
with the appropriate variable so that is
Google's writing guide for documentation
for the developers the social justice
way cultural revolution for white people
now if you don't know what Newspeak is
you can read it here you can go to
Wikipedia basically in the novel 1984
dystopian novel they created a language
that controls your thought essentially
and and to wit we have this Google
example controlling thought language and
this novel 1984 is written by this guy
named what's his name George Orwell okay
so let's go to sorry George Orwell
George Orwell has written an essay
titled okay the some of these are
interesting okay George oh well the
author of 1984 has also written an essay
somewhat popular titled politics and the
English language okay so I wrote a
annotation of it in 2005 now
George Orwell's essay is written in 1946
so I wrote my annotation you know my
version my Critias not criticism but my
comment on it with annotations meaning
explaining what he is saying so I wrote
my you know annotation about that this
article is fairly long so you have to so
I think some of you are probably would
be interested so let me type it you know
if so you can read it later Google okay
so
there it is read it offline ok so what
else we talked about that we talked
about that George Orwell so that's about
a Google new speak and also let me
mention let me give you another example
of Newspeak I know about these things
because I study Coates I study Coates
their philosophy their tonight's their
rules how they grow how they you know
how do they do things how do they form a
code how can you how can someone create
all these how can someone teach that
people can fly or modern medicine is not
important or things like that
how can someone do that and become you
know the leader of a code and people die
for you how do you know I study these
kind of things so another perspective on
of the Newspeak which is controlled
language using a group a code typically
is for example Scientology ok sorry
Scientology Tom Cruise
now this you are probably from here with
it because so bottom you you have been
censored yo what is - okay come on in
given interesting so let's see going
clear Scientology and the priests and
belief Tom Cruise okay let's look at Tom
Cruise now this video has been very
popular on YouTube people posted on
YouTube so you can check it out and then
Scientology of course try to censor it
try to claim copyright and stuff but so
this is about two thousand eight or
something and Google decided to leave it
okay so Scientology's a is a code that
that I have been involved when I was 22
for for about three months because I
worked for them or rather contributed
unaware to me I thought I was working
for them but actually I was according to
the paper I signed I was volunteering
Church walk okay so I had two son I
talked about this in one my video for
half an hour
oh you can watch that Scientology just
search for Saudi Scientology on YouTube
and okay so and but also because I have
a interesting codes obsession about how
about though these related topics code
brainwashing propaganda marketing
persuasion tact psychology you know all
these are related about how for example
how do I persuade you to do something
how do I be a leader what type of
leaders are there that is all related in
intact tact meaning being smooth you
know like salesmen like sometimes you
have sales people they are fascinating
because they can talk so smoothly
basically they can talk so that they
they make you
believe or want to do what what I want
you know that there's a powerful skill
but anyway so salesman coat leaders they
are you know related they had code
leaders they or scammers or how they
code some some artists scam artists
what's the word see the his historical
topic up around linguistic franca
yeah supper wolf I talked about that for
one hour in my video in my past video
anyway so I study this kind of code of
thing and yeah so one of the thing about
CODIS control use of language okay so
and anyway so Tom Cruise the in this
video Tom Cruise is the famous
Scientologist so he you know he showed
this is kind of a propaganda okay Tom
Cruise is trying to help Scientology to
you know to make people join the
Scientology cult and Scientology
Scientology's is this organization it's
very they have control they have almost
like they have full control of your
language that like when I was there they
have they have entire encyclopedias
about the world okay they are all
encyclopedia so it's like everything you
do in your life everything you do
there is a scientific there is a
Scientology version of it that tells you
what should do or what you know how you
should decide that situation like they
have their own encyclopedia printed you
know like 10 volumes or something I'm
telling you because I know and they have
their own dictionary you know so and
they have their jargons for example this
a bunch of jargons you will actually see
Scientology when they talk to each other
they use including you see many of them
demonstrated in went on Tom Cruise stop
is talking so you have you know kW
KSW orgs out ethics put ethics in
criminal criminal criminal ok criminal
pts espy tech you know they have their
own meaning to certain words for example
tech tech to us it just means technology
but in Scientology's jargon it means our
edge technology it means all the
Scientology politic policies and rules
and mandates procedures ok yeah that's a
critical you see Scientology the
organization just like Church actually
even like Christian Church or Islamic
Church this coat and religion religion
are basically they are also kind of the
same thing typically what religions when
it's it's very big thing becomes
religion okay kind of kind of the same
thing it's actually not not too not as
simple to separate them coat in what
region you know like religion typically
is very big you have you know obedience
of believers and meanwhile coat
typically is smaller and typically has
negative connotation so when you become
very big you the negative connotation is
gone okay you have religion but anyways
religion is also very old because there
are reasons we why we have religion okay
so it's not totally it's not totally is
it's not like you know totally let's say
trash okay so anyway and you know and
it's a big topic you know that you have
a lot of people are talking about
religion what it is what should be you
know things like that anyway so in
Scientology they have this jargon Tek it
which means the Scientology tech which
means all the Scientologists policies
rules mandates procedures so why do you
have that because in what we when you
are in Scientology they have rules about
everything about your behavior about
what you should say what you should not
cannot say and and and and also these
jargons you you have to use these
jargons you know all these jargons and
also you know so they have you know
rules mandates procedures policies
almost like a law you know like for
example US law you have lower section
something in Chapter something you know
it's like you have to be you have to
study law for five years to understand
you know you have volumes of law written
down in the same way they have that in
Scientology like I mentioned policies
rules mandates procedures what happens
if someone for example me criticize
Scientology now someone criticize
Scientology I'm a Scientologist
what do I do about that they have they
have answers you know when she should
what you should you know it's steps to
follow so you know it's a big coat it's
they are beginning to die down now
because now that you have for example
that you have a movie documentation that
exposes Scientology you have a lot of
that on YouTube you know YouTube on you
know you have a lot but they Scientology
is so powerful that even if you are FBI
you cannot do something to it you know
they they are actually doing many things
now I don't want to get sued so I let me
say they alleged the to many illegal
things like even imprisoned people but
even even if you are US government you
are FBI at one you know you cannot do
you cannot just go you cannot do that
because they have they are very powerful
they have connections you know for
example they can tell you know they they
tell the FBI had you know don't do that
okay if you don't do that then FBI don't
do not do their to do that things like
that okay so very powerful and anyway
back to the about joggins and new speak
language control so Scientology's you
know they have music they have their own
systems of language and here is a small
collection jargons okay so I have
collected some of them you know all
these jargons okay
they have very specific meanings and you
know you go watch this video you'll see
what I'm talking about
and they also other website that
documents everything about Scientology I
mean this Scientology has been very you
know how they are bad has been very well
known so you probably you guys already
seen it and I heard you know it was
banned in some countries was it it's
being sued in Germany I think it was it
still running in Germany
okay so eric says that's a good question
eric says Eric Carson Kimani two
Scientologists really believe in
Scientology yes
I study so I studied Scientology a lot
and in that I mentioned there are many
many hundreds of YouTube's that exposed
Scientology or all let's not use the
word expose that that's that they were
Scientologists they came out and many
leaders top leader second second to the
head you know the the head is David
Miscavige okay second leader they become
they came out then they talked about you
know stories so I watched quite a lot of
it okay over the over the years
especially in in recent five years so do
Scientologists really believe in
Scientology yes basically yes in short
but but it's a bit more complex its
enemy so here's a simple way to
understand what's going on it's actually
just like religion okay so you could say
you can't you could ask to eat Islamic
people or to Christian people they do
they actually believe you know the what
whatever Christian or Islam is saying
yes in general okay in general yeah so
again you have some people do not
believe that much you know things like
that so but in general yes Scientology
believe it that's how and in fact that's
how how the
organization functions you know you all
the people must believe it but they
actually I mean they actually do to to
to to at least some degree and they
actually do believe it okay
so I think I talked a lot about stuff
today and maybe that is it okay one hour
and 12 minutes so maybe that's it we
talked about Scientology and stuff let's
see what's going on opinions on these
what is that
all right that's a video I have to watch
okay so let me read the comments and
maybe that's it so bottom you says
is it true when they did criminal stuff
yes that's absolutely they have killed
people what that one yeah yeah they have
well they have what you might say
second-degree murder or they they have
people disappeared in Scientology to
this day it's open information for
example Miscavige is wife okay you can
just like so you can go search it right
now you'll find there's there are
several website this one website that I
forgot what whose name is on also on
Twitter I follow so for his face for one
example okay
Miscavige his wife okay he has a wife
disappeared okay disappeared for for
like 10 years now nobody is ceasing her
it is supposedly known she is in this
one of these in a mountain you know some
some remote mountain and they have
priests they have you know they have so
they have buildings in this remote
mountain area they have also votes like
votes like they you know they did they
have land money like they you know very
powerful so so you can imagine you know
the PD on here just like the the other
guy who who suicide you in jail that guy
I don't want to mention the name you
know that guy
just like that guy that's that that
level of reach okay so they can be old
you know they can buy the whole island
things like that so they so they is
supposed to you know they they have they
can have they can have prisons they just
put it put you in nobody knows okay you
cannot prove you know the this yeah and
you know you read about Scientology you
read that you know you spent hours hours
you can see it and you you are you are
you are thinking you know why didn't
anyone call the cops you know like
because you are seeing this woman you
know so they have this remote country
let me show you some so sorry
Scientology fence
okay let's such is fence so they have
you know cottage or remote you know
castles or whatever and you know the
people Scientologists live there is
their you know building on house in a
remote mountains something but you see
things interesting if the same things
interesting is that so these two guys
they are
Mike Mike Rinder and Marty rappin
they were the top Scientologists at the
top working directly behind be you know
behind the guy and I just feed them you
know the same way they escaped so they
are out of Scientology now and Miscavige
his dad also went on to an interview on
this idiot guy you know the Joe Rogan
so you if you go such YouTube Joe Rogan
Scientology you will find Miscavige his
dad was interviewed by Joe Rogan I've
also watched that so you know so there's
lots of videos you can see here but
actually yeah watched all of them you
see look this this face okay now this
face he says the spiked fence of
Scientology CST
compound a GP at Twin Peaks okay yeah
and the specs are facing inward so you
see this is a fence in normally when you
have a fence the spec is the spike space
outside you know you don't want dog so
some other people coming right the
spikes are facing outside but this bit
this one
Scientology compound okay the specs are
facing inward what does that mean that
means people you know you you get you
get what it means you know you can guess
spikes facing what you do you know and
I've you know I so so wait wait we can't
you know someone call the cops look at
this you know remember remember this guy
this this people you know this guy are
bidding is something at that level FBI a
one-time they want to rate these so many
stories right so FBI FBI one time want
to rate you know some compound of
Scientology but they did they decided
not to you know something like because
this is about very high-level politics
you know I don't know what's going on
nobody knows what's going on he just
said Oh FBI stopped you know they don't
they don't do it anymore you know so
they have their own laws they call the
cops
only on Clearwater and they are peeing
into a house okay so okay so if you have
a question about something you want to
ask me post my name okay I'm just going
to we are about to stop in one minutes
for you know - yeah - few minutes I'm
gonna read the comments see okay yeah
this is the most famous Scientology
related video okay today I don't feel I
don't feel pressure about talking about
Scientology I mean not talking about it
because they are loud talking about it a
lot people you know it's kind of it's
not like this days less less of an issue
yeah Emacs fed is a problem
oh that's it oh yeah I forgot about I
wanted to talk about mouse and keyboard
there are something new let's do that
tomorrow you know one day I should show
actually I was you know I want to show
I'm going to do push-ups okay
Justine says have you watched document
documentary inside Bo spring about Bo
gates no I'm not too interested in Pio
gates you know I don't think he knows
much about anything other than being a
business businessman I don't I you know
unlike many UNIX people they hate P or
gates you know they I don't but also I
don't think Bo gates is is that smart
you know some programmers you know by
the way I also have window programmers
who follows me yeah yes so yeah windows
you know by the way you know Stack
Overflow is spewed on windows take okay
don't forget snack overflow it's not
it's not you know Python Ruby or Walden
whatever it's a Windows technology I
don't I don't remember what language or
but anyway it's a Windows running young
Windows server or something
so that's Stack Overflow and yeah so
about Bo gates you know so I have some
window developer you know you have F
sharp coders functional for me language
F sharp working on Windows and some of
them so they you know they Bo Gates is
supposed to he beat you know a book a
month or book a week you know he read a
lot books and some people are also like
that you know I have some of my
followers they say oh you should you
know they they also kind of follow this
this mindset of you need to read a lot
books you know like one book a month
okay I don't I think the many of them
are idiots they are they some of these
book chanting people
I mean also when I was young you know I
also have the thought you know you need
to read books you know a lot books one
book you know a few a month
something like that you know I also read
my favorite share but anyway so the
thing to remember is that you yeah the
purpose the goal of reading books is not
just to say oh I read this book or you
know it's about you want to grasp
whatever wisdom or knowledge from the
book okay so it's it needs not even be a
book so there are people who don't beat
much books but they know a lot of things
you know they are they know more than
professors you know there are such
people even mathematicians they don't
they don't read other people my other
great mathematicians book they are such
great mathematicians it is supposed to
be one of the greatest mathematicians
like that he doesn't read other people's
book anyway so what I what I'm saying is
that you don't want to be a bookworm
okay don't just read a book oh I need to
read a book every day like I for example
I don't read books these days almost I
haven't been reading any books for for
almost 15-20 years like reading actually
reading a book but I tend to you read P
P P yeah you can learn lots of things
from reading book is only one of the
many ways you kind of learn things okay
so don't you know they I mean so there
are these class of people quite a lot
also I know a lot of them are Chinese
China Chinese in China they have the
mentality of reading you need to read a
lot books because this knowledge but
don't know don't be stupid okay don't
don't you know read the book you learn
things reading book is not a thing okay
there are these school people they are
mind says that is that they just need to
read some books every month or something
and actually for those of people who
read a book a month I kind of I
immediately despise like whatever they
say it's probably idiotic
there are certain people on Twitter they
all say oh I'd read a book one a month
and this month is this is my book
immediately or sometimes they take photo
show their book you know these kind of
people immediately I know that's they
don't know they don't know things okay I
think that's it for today so thank you
for showing instruction on how to write
ablest sentences read some down
sentences Scientology okay rich and huge
coat they have their own laws okay
so deep he says current currently reads
infinite loop oh why am I not Muslim
okay so the Google censorship
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for coming
f-sharp yeah f-sharp is you know it's a
version of Oh camel or metal language
okay thank you for coming
I'm your cat but for me tomorrow same
time god father of MU I said ten o clock
for this whole week I mean had you I
must directly talk to you interacted
with you about that timing issue at
least twice in the past two days ten
o'clock every day for this week until
also including Sunday
okay so bye guys have a good day