hello guys welcome to another episode
ofan talk show we're going to do EAC L
and talk randomish a little bit about
the China's deep seek
AI uh incred incredible Phenom
phenomenon that the USA lost about 1
billion uh was it 1 billion 500 600 100
billion stocks Market okay because China
released a open-source AI bot deep
seek hello springle nights so if you are
here say hi I want to see your comments
and ask me questions I'll answer and if
you are not here skip around play at 1.5
speed okay so talk show is me a art ball
programmer been programming since 199
T3 and uh we I am just going to talk
about randomiz
stuff and by the way I'm half
drunk I had a cup of red wine uh okay
and we're going to code some emac disp
okay so let's see let's stop that what
are you
see uh you are seeing my screen okay so
let me show you my keyboards this is
glove at fantastic I recommend it I have
video reviews and text reviews on my
website just search for SAR keyboard
okay grav fantastic this is timate
hacking keyboard I also have video
reviews this is nulia track B nulia 506
or something I have a review video
review and uh text review and I'm going
to show this until one day I review it
so this is um God hold on a
second so you can see this is the uh oh
it actually you know it's active this is
the
um board s v a l b o a r d i got it last
year thanks to the guy who sent to me
and uh this is in my opinion
one of the
best uh fancy input device so this is a
entirely different B Park so but I'm
sorry I I just haven't started to learn
it so but as I said I will so I'm going
to show this every day in my live stream
until one day I uh actually start to
practice and use it okay SW board s v a
l b o a r d I have a review on my
YouTube and on my
website okay that's my keyboards okay so
let's switch to the text terminal and uh
I mean not not text terminal but my
screen and uh uh and uh let's start to
code and talk about stings
okay uh first of all let me show you
again my keyboard okay just search for
SAR keyboard block and you can Goa
keyboard
guide go TOA keyboard block can you see
it yes
indeed okay audio check video check yeah
so then here's my uh pen input I also
have reviews on pen input okay so some
keyboard blocks so you can see SP board
right there so you know all the details
and the big photos you can can see okay
fantastic and uh of course the glove at
and all that so go back to ergonomic
keyboard reviews ergonomic keyboard
reviews and there's glv all the details
you need to know and go back and there
are other keyboards I you know this
kesis 360 is also great and also this is
incoming uh
kesis mwave key keyboard and this expose
is always one of my favorite cheap tool
about
$100 uh and others okay and here is
automate hacking keyboard so each one of
them I have video reviews okay I give
you indepth reviews because I'm a
keyboard
expert so next what shall we talk about
so so Crystal say
okay so Crystal's got a question Crystal
uh long time follower crystal says uh
can you wear the same hoodies as my uh
YouTube head
shot no because I threw that away now
this hoodie so on YouTube you'll see my
head shot like
that and uh but that was doing
my extreme poverty days I found this
hoodie on the street in my neighborhood
you know it's just on the floor you know
just like on the corner of the street
and it seems brand new you know I just
found it nobody's there so I picked it
up now this is around 201 um 14 or
something okay
so you know so it been with me so I I
was very extreme poverty you wouldn't
understand that's more poverty than USA
poverty those who get food stamps like a
lot black people or Mexican so I'm a
level below that uh you wouldn't
understand you know I explain you
wouldn't understand but so I got this I
picked up this on the street and uh it
kept me warm for many Winters okay it
was you know I just picked it up and it
seem looks like it seems like it's from
a girl because it smells good there's
some uh perfumes on
it so anyway but I threw it away since
you know around
20121 I'm doing okay now so if you guys
are following me for a long time you
know the story but I'm doing okay now so
and it's old so I threw it away so now
you are seeing me with this hoodie now
this is from Costco American middle
class Elite that's what I call them
middle class Elite so Costco cheap you
you you know my wife bought it for me
this is
15 uh $16 I think but the hoodies with
my head shot that one is
G uh it marks a period of my life okay
so let's see next
comment uh how do you deal with default
mods
keybind okay for
example mods use n and p for next and
previous instead of Sly Keys i
k uh well so the question is about sof
Keys okay so I'm using emac editor as
you know showing browser this is a
source cure browser the most efficient
system I
have can you see it check check check
check you see I move my mouse I don't
have to click it's Hoover auto click uh
so you can find all these you know I
have like
1,000 1,000 articles on my keyboard side
literally 1 thou over 1,000 articles
written from starting about 2000
eight on keyboard on track boo on Mouse
on everything on key binding on uh
layout and everything so the question is
about how do you
so okay so that's about keyboard and I
also of course I'm a well known for my
emac
tutorial again over here you got 1,000
articles on practical emac tutorial emac
is a text editor usually it's used for
programmers or also known as Tech bra
you know the USA political
[ __ ] they cons they call a tech bra
you know like the political influences
you know uh lots of them you know they
talk about Trump MAA you know they they
talk about political movements all the
time and uh when it comes to Google
Faceook Facebook artificial intelligence
you know like the Silicon Valley of
course that tends to be left because
they do sensorship ex extreme scum
Google so of course they got a bad
impression of of this technology sector
so-called sector you
know so these people they you know over
because about two months ago December
2024 there is this H1B Visa issue where
a lot
Indians legally came to USA via the H1B
visa and uh this sub part subset of the
marot for Trump people got upset they
got pissed because they want a white
ethnos state for USA they don't want
Indians you know so it's a lot racial
issue so they got pissed so they then
they hear about you know how Ellen musk
saying that H1B Visa is important or the
VC guy which is also part of the MAA you
know part of the Trump team at least he
was you know the vi guy who also says
H1B Visa is important and he says americ
am got a problem because today America
is like thoughts you know you go to
Twitter Instagram or any other website
you see these thoughts you know the girl
the white typically white girls or white
Jewish girls basically I you know I
don't know the difference but basically
white girls they thoughts you know
knowers thoughts they make a scene like
every like half of the things you see on
Twitter on uh YouTube is them you know
YouTube shorts or Tik Tok you know like
talking about dating or
the you know like the Zuma Fox and then
the other half is the political grifter
you know like the
team team
pool who is a hybrid by the way team
pool guy okay I started to talk about
politics but
anyway Timo you know became became very
famous he was he was a underground
journalist doing good things American
okay his uh blood line is
hybrid uh his his parents is half Korean
I forgot his mom or dad uh I think
Korean yeah anyway he originally he was
a underground journalist doing reports
which is very good then around 2009
he kind of switched
to cooking up the cultural drama like
the social justice Warriors you know
like like he talks about those things
nonstop posting two or three videos per
day Tim pool okay so he became a grifter
in my eyes money because every time you
talk about drama St lots of viewers oh
my God she did is or what the dating or
girls or white girls or whatever [ __ ]
you know tinol so he become rich and
famous uh tin pool and lots of others
you know the among the MAA political
thing scene okay Tempo is just one of
them so so many others uh a lot of them
white people of course white guys so
these people they don't know prog I mean
they you know so when when the H1B Visa
issue came up they think they think us
they call us Tech bra oh Jesus Tech bra
we don't support Tech bra you know what
has Tech bra done to for America you
know this white fox you know these white
people they think they you know they
they they Invision uh USA state of
cowboys you know like 100 years ago
where USA is you know the the they are
like they are thinking of the pioneers
of the white people Cowboys or something
like that so they think you know they
they call us oh Tech bra blah blah
blah [ __ ]
idiots they still do to this day you
know they don't understand you know
because from my point of view or anyone
who is a first generation migrant to USA
you see it clearly the white people they
don't you know they they don't work much
they have rights this or that or
feminism rights for women they complain
all the time you know that like you know
they socalled privileged by the leftist
social justice Warrior scums you know it
became well know privileged why
privileged
so the social justice Warriors or the
BLM the or the trans sex you know or the
gay sex degenerate they are scums of
course so the white men the average
white men American middle class got
trashed who are who who who trashed them
they own people bden Joe Biden Nancy po
Pelosi
uh AOC which is a little p uh Alexandria
ctez you know and Nancy Pelosi but
Hillary Clinton these are the big guys
you know they [ __ ] up you white people
okay ESS others plus the pro Israel Jew
group
okay uh
so yeah I have some sympathies for you
guys but um but but but many of the
white Americans they don't you know they
don't
see they don't you know they don't see
the situation which I understand you
know it's
natural okay I started to talk about
politics so
this this live stream is already tented
you know maybe I'll get banned from
YouTube
anyway so so anyway let me go back to
Let's regroup let me go back to what's
the question
um oh yeah the question is about emac
actually technical question so how did I
start to
um yeah anyway so I'm using emac a great
text editor for programmers oh that's
where the digression begin Tech bra you
know this this political or lawyers you
know you know it's amazing in America in
you United States of America in past 10
years the profession of lawyers has
increased you know like sharp increase
you know
like a circus you know like like the the
circus of
lawsuits so that is part of my opinion
the American white people they got a
problem they got a cultural problem and
also the black people as
well the Jewish people by the way they
tends to be well educated they are well
off they are I don't know their details
exactly but for my impression they are
like tight need group they educate they
you know they they keep to themselves
they do
good but white people are not like that
no it's the black people white people is
like you you know like they're G to make
a scene they make a
scene all the time anyway it's
complicated issue okay there's a lot
racial issues so what I'm saying is that
the Tech bra so they call us Tech bra so
I think what you need to do what we
should do in America you know the math
you look at the math competition like
American education is so low and and
like I said any people first generation
migrant from Russia from China or from
India they came to USA they see
it they see it you know the American the
white so-called white people and the you
know then all the math they cannot do
math you know they have no idea what is
math they have no idea what is geography
you know where is India they don't know
where is Greenland you know Trump is
going to take take Greenland where is
Greenland they they have no idea you
know you just ask people on the street
they don't know mostly white
people uh so they but but these white
people think oh no no no we are you know
we are totally good we are Cowboys we
are the
Pioneers idiots and they they think you
know all the technology people they are
oh you guys are Tech bra [ __ ] Tech
bra these white
idiots without techra you don't have
missiles you don't have warships you
don't have Rockets you don't have
satellites you don't have GPS
you don't have nice cars okay you white
idiots so what you we what we need to do
change is stop this thoughts and social
media scumbags the political like one
one million political grifters each one
got a 1 million followers they Babble
about you know oh Trump or this you know
they about things you know these
people they should um they should take
Notch
down while we should promote engineers
mathematicians scientists okay and also
among you white
Christians take a notch down promote go
into programming physics mathematics
okay if you want make America great
again
so back to the question about emac so
emac is a great text editor for mostly
useful for programmers which is what I'm
using so you are looking at it so uh so
the and I also created cofly Keys okay
if you don't know already let me show
you cofly Keys here's a source code
4,000 lines go to the top and here's the
link open it showing browser Sly Keys uh
introduction so this is a efficient key
binding system for emac so if you are
using emac text editor this will be
great for you because it will save you
about 30% of keystrokes so you don't
have to type so much like control meta
control o something you don't have to do
that so save you keystrokes so that you
don't you don't get rep ative strin
injury which I did you know hurt my
hands you became a [ __ ] okay so if
you really code a lot or work with
computers in a professional way this is
a good thing you know it's a good thing
to learn emac and is also uh and you
might try Sly Keys okay so the essence
of Sly Keys is this layout diagram you
are see so in you know undo Mark uh move
cursor or single key press you don't
have to press control key so that's the
essence ofi Keys saves you key strokes
to
prevent repetitive strain injury prevent
hand pain that is the essence of what s
Keys is about it's for emac
and your question is very specific and
Technical about uh how do you deal with
default mods key binding for example uh
you know that that's has been explained
I'm not sure exactly what is a question
because okay we get into technical
details for example in the add mod in
emx by default you can press M to Mark a
file so for example I press arrow down M
Mark a file m m you know I can Mark a
file without pressing control or meta
right so in like this all you have to do
is go to insert mod and you can do that
so so you can see I'm going to insert
modaf insert mod command mod activate
and uh the there's insert mod activate
so anyway go to insert mod and I again
then whatever
key is the emx
default so your question how do you deal
with default mods key binding you know
you just switch to insert mod okay uh
are you new to softly keys because that
seems to be
a like a new
complete newb
question okay next crystal says how did
oo emx team respond to you proposing X
Sly Keys did any of them switch please
explain the different the differing
philosophies behind why you were
dissatisfied
Crystal uh uro emx uro emx I created uro
emx okay so if you just go to sofly Keys
homepage just search for it you'll find
it emac sofly keys and you go
down you will see go down to the
frequently Asked question
section okay go
down uh s like is frequently Asked
question uh how do you how does it
compare us to uro emx
mod uro emx mod is another key binding
mod similar to sofly Keys which I I
started okay okay so and the difference
so let me show you a page
okay so go to emac S emac tutorial go to
the Emax Keys section everything you
ever needed to know about emac
keys so you go down you go down then you
will see uro emx or you can just search
for uro emx okay
uh let's see where is it how to avoid
command swap uh emac
pinky uh let's see if I can find it oo
emx search for Ergo emx okay not here
okay I removed the link from the main
index but but I can show you okay so
just just search for oo emac so uh so
there is the uro emx
logo
um uh but where is my original page okay
so hold on a second
so you can see all the emac articles
about 20 of them that I wrote so Oro emx
I begin in 2018 okay so emx key overview
so where is the
homage um
where is it I what is thisx
okay
uh so anyway you can see my original
design uh for example here's a document
on my original design of oo
emx uh here is
a page about ago emx complete list of
keybind
so uh so where is my Ogo IMX original uh
page homepage let me let me show you
somewhere
okay uho emx I begin in
2008 something 2007 then in
2013 I started Sly
keys and uh Sly Keys is a model system
so you have insert mod and command mod
so you don't have to press control
anymore in Oro emx you have you still
have to press control however the keys
are designed so that the most frequent
Keys have a uh connected associated with
the most frequently used command so any
command you do when you edit text delete
you know move move Cruiser if it's most
frequently used it has the most easy key
however you still need to press control
like the traditional way you know
control something so that's ago emx mod
okay so uh there I believe this is
original homepage there it is okay
so okay so this is original homepage you
can still find it on sadi.com info just
search for oo
emx
so so I created it but so the you can
see a picture of the keys design and but
in
2013 I started to do the sly
Keys UHA Keys model system so the
difference is that you no longer to has
have to press any control key or any any
old key or
meta so it's like Vim okay
so 2013 I started s keys so the Ogo
emac uh is I gave it to Matthew L finder
so he is the current maintainer okay so
you can you can click the GitHub so this
is the oo emx so I don't think you are
user
oo emx because you if you actually read
any the documentation you'll see lots of
links to you know lots of my you know
actually all of these are written by me
originally about the details of the
design and so and so on so but Matthew
uh so this guy Matthew helped a lot and
another guy who helped a lot is David
Capal Capello okay David Capello he's a
guy in Argentina okay Matthew is
American
USA so if you read my articles you can
you know you can find My Links about
them so many you know like so many links
to them uh so they helped David Capello
helped me with emac Ogo emac was the
most popular emac Distribution on
Windows from 2008 to to about
2012 okay originally it was a entire
dist dist so you download the zip file
you have the entire emac it's not
separate from you know you you know you
don't have to download emx and download
the package then install the package and
so on it's one thing ago emx
okay but then you know I 2013 I started
s keys and you know but now it's just a
package uh a lot history okay so let's
see okay so lots of talking so are we
what are you guys no
comments so I expanded okay okay so I
believe I explained that question am I
still
going
yeah okay so in regards to keyboards
have you ever heard of the Russian
dictor keyboards
layout uh no I don't remember okay so
let's look at
uh okay so search
again Russian Dio okay let's see if I
seeing it this is a keybo layout for
Russian language that that is based on
the same principles as as vorak okay uh
no I haven't heard of it I might have
but I forgot I don't know much about
about
it so uh so essentially it's a efficient
keyboard layout for for russan okay
thank you for telling me about
it I will read about
it let's put it to
to-do and uh
let's show my keyboard page so keyboard
guide uh then keyboard block then go to
keyboard
layout uh which is here so you can see
all the different layout which I talked
about many times in my past videos so
you got the normal quy you got the vorak
you got comac you
got Workman you got Norman you know they
show
the heat map of the letter frequency the
bigger the circle the more frequent that
letter is used so you can kind of see
the difference this is quy the standard
this is vorax so you can see all the big
circles on the home
row and uh then then you can change so
there is one Russian layout so this one
is standard Russian layout
Jen something okay so and you can change
the letter frequency to Russian then you
see the circles so you you see the
standard Russian layout is not very
efficient so if you are touch tyer for
the Russian language then basically you
you have to jump around all the
time so this
dial layout will fix that okay I don't
know about it thank you for telling
me okay that's about that those
questions
okay the Russian s has a image okay
so um yeah it's kind of annoying you
know they don't have an
image then you go to you know why don't
they put a you know image on the English
page yeah so every time there's a
foreign language I don't speak like
Russian it's it's very difficult to
create you know for example I I might
want to add it here but if they don't
have English it's very difficult you can
use translation but if you know it's
basically
is it's a lot pain to to understand what
they
are so anyway that's about that anything
else so we talked about for 30 we talked
about for 30 minutes already so let me
talk about let's let's not code emac
list okay so because I don't see many
Act iMac this people
here uh I mean I'm I'm not seeing lots
of uh yeah Nancy pososi inside the
trading and stuff tiny had bate I don't
know what is that so instead of using n
and p in diet you just use arrow
keys no okay not exactly you go to diet
switch to insert mod okay let me show
you okay go to diet switch to insert mod
so you can
see insert mod activate are you seeing
it yes okay so insert mod then you can
press n you see I'm pressing n you see
on the pink window I'm pressing n it
goes down I press P it goes up okay any
default emac Keys is as they
are so it is not true I have to use
arrow keys but usually I do use arrow
keys okay well in part because I'm on
this Batman keyboard fancy keyboard I
don't like the anyway so anyway you you
got the
answer so we talked about um you know so
I'm not seeing people wanting to do EAC
list so let me talk about the Deep seek
okay deep
seek which is a China AI bot uh that got
released about four days ago it's
amazing because why is it critical it's
on the news all
over because about 1 trillion US Dollars
disappeared
overnight okay you know the Deep seek a
CH AI bought a competitor to chat GPT of
the open AI Corporation so China
released deep
seek and within a day USA stocks you
know Nvidia Advanced Micro
and and and lots of others okay they
lost like Nvidia lost about 600
billion dollars
in one day in one single [ __ ] day6
billion dollar
gun okay so where let me let me um you
know you you can you can find it okay so
you can just search news you'll find it6
billion dollar skun in one day why
because China released the Deep seek
amazing then it became political issue
and of course racial issue on one hand
of course a lot of the white guys the
white Americans they got pissed you know
China bad CCP communist they sto us they
they they steal out stuff they steal out
data and blah blah blah you know lots of
lots of and including the mainstream
Force mainstream fake news Factory
turning out articles China open AI
accuses China deep seek sealing
information but they forgot you lots of
things like that but they forgot where
does steep seeks where does the open AI
this is open ai's Logo chat gbt where
did they get their data form
stolen because they are under lawsuit
lots of law you from YouTube from Reddit
or from you know from all the online
websit they don't have a license you
know it's a big thing but that then then
then there's another issue somebody dead
you know someone walked for open AI he
killed
himself he killed himself like the epon
you know somehow someone killed
himself so there's a lot of political
Intrigue going
on uh you know
so you know but anyway the massive stock
dollars loss that's significant because
these people doing stocks they are not
idiots okay they don't care about who
stole who they only care about money
okay so when when you
see some stock market big change that
means something is real real [ __ ] is
happening you know they don't really
care about who is actually doing bad but
you
know this deep seek is very significant
okay very important it's not just some
like random troll like you know you know
doing
things critical uh by the way I want to
show you the video where the Deep seek
tries to comment where their data come
confirm this one okay let me show you uh
a little bit yeah let me play that
video Let's see if I
can what data was used to train Sora we
used publicly available data and license
data so videos on
YouTube I'm actually not sure about that
okay videos
from Facebook Instagram
you know if they were publicly available
um available yeah publicly available to
use um there might be that data but um
I'm I'm not sure I'm not confident about
it what about shutter stock I know you
guys have a deal with
them I'm I'm just not going to go into
the details of of the data that was that
was used but it was publicly available
or licensed data what data was used to
train so that girl that check is
supposedly that this the
CTO of open AI of the chat GPT you know
it's quite amazing you know looks like
she doesn't really actually know a thing
so where did you get the data did you
grab all the
YouTubes oh oh oh uh actually uh I can
[Laughter]
say do you think chat gbt grabbed
YouTube of course they did of
course but she can't say of course
because legal
issues so you got you know the you know
so but the thing about deep seek why why
did they actually cost some 600 actually
like almost like one trillion or over
you know 600 billion is just Nidia is it
billion so let me make sure okay
is it 600 million or or what uh million
uh I
think hold on a second let me
see oh by the way there's
massive DDOS attack on deep seek you
know so this deep seek is not just a
technology issue there's a lot powerful
political you know USA government May
are involved they got 230
million doll attack per second every
second 230
million requests for the past three days
okay I know I experient myself because
when I heard Deep seek I tried to go to
their website and I say you know I
noticed uh registration is not currently
available because something does attack
you know
you know so 230 million do attack
request per
second
okay uh then you know so by the way if
you don't know if you follow me you kind
of know but if you don't know if you are
new here you see this all the talks
about AI every day you know in the past
several years about everything they are
all crap okay you only you really have
to
trust someone who you know they who they
are and they are you know they need to
be smart okay don't follow all these
troll or grifting
accounts um so let me find just exactly
what how much is the um
money is lost in deep seek on the first
day okay it's really this is really that
this is actually a historical incident
incident okay it's as important as that
a historical
moment in stock market in in Tech stock
stock market
okay uh so so this another you know six
billion wait no not this one okay
so I want to and also another thing is
that you see I you know we were talking
about the white Americans right they
think oh nothing is wrong with us
actually we are great uh make America
great again but actually you look at all
the you know people who are doing the AI
you know so here's the China deep seek
team team they are all Chinese of course
Chinese blood and then when you look at
the open AI team like half of them are
all Chinese you look at Google you look
at Elam musk s okay team also half of
them are Chinese
blood okay so this white people you got
you got a problem okay you got a problem
you got to fix that
instead of focusing on your racial
issues and uh you know one thing that
pisses me personally is that many of
these people especially I noticed the
pro-israel people pro-israel Jewish
people they will say they will like
redirect the hate towards Chinese like
for example the Deep seek they will say
oh CCP is our enemy
CCP you know they right now there's a
racial tension between the white people
and Jews but on the Jew side they'll
just say no no no let's blame the CCP
instead let's blame the
Chinese [ __ ]
them okay so regarding deep seek you
know if you really want to know stuff
you have to dive deep you have to be a
engineer okay if you are just a
political
talkad you know whatever you say is not
really significant
okay that's it that's about it
today billion oh my God yeah here is a
confirmation okay I wrote it because I
checked just Nvidia alone it lost
$560 billion dollar in one day okay just
Nvidia
alone so this is very significant this
is not
[ __ ] okay that's it for
today CH Ching thank you
Crystal who's L opening deep seek scrap
for open AI so uh AI talks are bad yeah
the SK sky is blue I don't follow on any
social media other than
YouTube okay thoughts on avif image
format and the AAC O Okay uh I don't
know much about that topics uh AAC audio
is a AAC audio is basically Apple
spanding of the of part of the m
uh began around like by now almost 20
years
ago so starting you know the audio codec
the audio file
formats they became the digital formats
became a thing around 2000 okay year
2000 or year 2001 because of the piracy
of song from CD okay of course CD is
dead today so many of you guys don't
know about these
things so you know we have you know CD
was the format for a while before that
it's record and tape and so on but
anyway CD around year you know in the
1990s late
1990s compa compact dis CD is the kind
of the most popular format for songs you
have to buy them of course
music uh but then MP3 came up then
people started to you know rip it's
soall rip rip from the CD meaning that
you make a copy of the song from the CD
into a computer file
MP3 and and you can play it on your
computer so you don't have to pay I mean
so you can so you can send it to your
friends so you know they don't have to
buy CD so it becomes a big huge
some billion dollars you know big you
know loss so MP3 okay so
then anyway that's history so that's
around year 2000 then
Apple this excuse me Steve Jobs is a
great innovator he saw the problem you
know CD is really a Problem MP3 the
digital VES is a new thing so he wanted
to make
it a legal way for people to enjoy
music via digital files because of the
internet you know the the progression of
technology so why should you you know
still buy a physical you know medium you
can you know so Steve Jobs pushed that
he made it he he he's a great Pioneer he
started you know he talked to the music
corporations the copyright the you know
the
Hollywood then created a online store
that sells
music Apple
begin so you can buy music digitally
legally like today it becomes normal
right be but before but 20 years ago
it's not normal Steve Jobs began that
okay so that was the beginning of
MP3 era it began as piracy massive
piracy still happen today today of
course you still can you know pirate
like almost every song but anyway so MP3
then Apple also started to sell you know
physical devices for playing
MP3 called
iPad iPod i p o d iPod okay like 20
years ago
then so but then the music compression
file format for audio also changed of
course because of technological progress
so there is this
AAC which has better compression better
quality in general so Apple started to
use that instead of MP3 Apple don't you
know this is 20 years ago so a but a is
just Apple's branding it's part of the M
something it becomes very complex okay
all this all these music and video
format so that's that's what I know
so and a if that's that's video format
you know it gets very complex I don't
know much about
it okay anything else that's it for
today I think I'm going to uh that's it
for today so copy that
okay so that's today's talk show copy
that uh paste it
here okay so copy that website this is
the this is the Russian key binding
paste it here linky close
that close that and and what is this
this is the history of ago emx layout
okay close that and this is the current
ago emac
website okay and this is some kind of
historical page okay this is another
important
page uh which is about how I began to
create the uro emac key
binding
um this is actually this is not you know
this is part two so part you know so you
can see this is my original kind
of uh part one so part one here
2012 so 2 so 2012 that's where I started
to kind of kind of started the idea of
soft keys okay but oo emx goes back to
2007 okay 2007 is oo
emx so let me just paste that that's it
okay donate to me guys close that oo emx
logo this logo is created by David
Capello okay he's also an
artist and David Capello is a C++
programmer he's he's a fan of
C++ okay in contrast to me and he is
most famous for creating ASP aspite as
aspite which is a application that
creates uh pixel art pixel animations
for game for for classic game games
okay uh you know so it's kind of well
known
I've been smoking too much I need to
stop okay so there's video you can check
so let's go to David
Capello copy
that okay David Capello Oro emx close
close asite Oro emx logo got
it okay anything
else apply Keys frequently asked
questions because practical emac
tutorial close oh and this classic
sh okay no comment how disappointing bye
guys support me go to
kinfo okay do
or Sali
doino go to all the way to the bottom
you have lots of programming tutorials
in
mathematics mathematics and I started to
do a
lot uh update on this my plan curve a
visual dictionary of special plan curves
30 years old project I started to do
updates so go to the bottom of s doino
pay patreon Amazon gift card PayPal