Good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Kar Talk Show. We are
doing advent of code 2025
day one
part two problem two take two continuing
from yesterday. So yesterday we got
stuck on a bug for like 3 hours. We
coded live stream for like three four
hours because
uh that's pretty bad. I'm kind of sick.
So there come So we we just going to be
relaxed and have fun. Uh this is might
be boring for you. I'm going to code wam
language. So if you don't know just
search for my website kasali. Uh you'll
find everything. I'll say X a H
uh let's say Xi L E
uh Wam Wam language. Okay. So you you
you search it, you'll find everything
about my website. Then you can go to the
homepage
uh my programming tutorials
hacker code everything about hackers
about type set type type setting about
programming languages programming
language design oh I got a CSS issue
there
about unic code about symbols about user
interface design and all that and pro
and mathematics okay code so anyway wam
language so there's a question so what
do you Think of hardway translation of
Arabianites. Burton seems to be too
flamboyant. That's true. So Arabianites.
So you for that you go to wordy blog
from the hearty emotions of lexicon,
stylistic concerns, decipherment of
grammar and idioms, linguisticality,
literature and logicality. Okay, that's
my word blog. disorder of a man of
letters
letters.
So, so this is all about English
literature and stuff. So, you click to
the you go to the homepage at the bottom
navigation bar, then literature
classics. Then the first one is Arabian
Nights. One of my favorite literature
uh top 10 maybe Arabian Knights by Sir
Richard Burton. He's a scholar. He's a
multi-talented
what they call polymath.
Okay. So I learned you know I didn't
know but you know one day like around
I started to learn about I wanted to
know more about humanities prompted by
future reason that is you know with AI
robotics
uh genetic engineering where are we
going to go
so before 2005 I was just math and
computer and programming a nerd
and um you know mechanics, academic,
hard sciences you know science and
engineering but then starting with the
futurism I started to look into like
literature, history,
society,
uh sociology, geography, different
countries and and all sort of things. So
I started to read ar the Arabian Knights
and I discovered Sir Richard Burton.
Okay. A polymath.
Uh, now I don't know too much about him,
but there's like a whole about a whole
bunch of history about, you know, he's a
Brit. Uh, is he a knight? I I forgot. I
don't know. So, Richard Button, it's
funny. They locked the article. You see,
there's a lot lot of things going on on
Wikipedia. Semi protected. Okay. Uh, so,
uh, stupid formatting. God.
Oh, so Richard. Sir Richard Burton looks
uh young when he was young. Looks
handsome. A brit.
A white man. White man. Okay. But he's a
uh wait. Well, not this guy. [ __ ]
[ __ ] idiotic.
Uh not that guy. Okay.
Sir Richard Burton.
Sir.
Yeah. Richard Francis Burton. Okay,
that's a guy. So, you go there.
Now, why is this font? Oh god, this this
this stupid um you know, because I have
super large font. So, he
uh Sam says, "Is your website enough for
pass a junior backend developer
interview?"
What do you mean enough? My website
kasali.info, info, it's enough for you
to get a PhD.
Okay, seriously, if you read everything
about it, there's like 10,000 pages on
mathematics. So, it's it's enough well,
not PhD PhD, but it's enough for you to
the information there. It contains
amount of tutorial is equivalent to
the textbook you would read to get a at
least a bachelor's degree. Okay. So,
it's not like junior backend developer
interview.
Uh, okay. Anyway, back to Richard
Francis Burton. Okay. This guy, he's
also a expert at uh sword fighting.
and he um anyway so he's a polymath.
Okay. So I discovered this book Arabian
Nights. Now let's put this uh page back.
Arabian Nights. Fantastic. Fantastical
stories. Okay.
Now it's very elaborate and actually I
like it that way. I didn't know you
know. So I read I read it. I look up
every word I do not understand. Verily,
therefore,
be tided,
farmed. Wait, there's no annotation for
that one. Admonition.
So, the no annot annotation means, you
know, I already know the word, but the
one with underscore uh there's a
annotation
means that uh most people wouldn't know.
Okay. Verily there from besided. So it
it's using very elaborate uh as you say
very elaborate and uh flamboyant
English.
Um in a way sometimes people criticize
him as not being you know not
grammatical and you know he's just like
doing [ __ ] with with English.
But anyway
so I annotated.
Now the whole book is very thick you
know it's like three volumes or
something the Arabian Knights okay so I
you know I so I only have like 10
stories I annotated
so I did this like for two years uh and
the story is not you know when you see
when you when you read about Arabian
knights you think of let's say the tale
of the bull and the ass you might have
heard of this one but the more famous is
the fisherman and the genie. Okay, you
might have seen it in Disney movies.
Okay, so for example, in Disney movies,
they tell you the um
they tell you the uh where is it?
Arabian nights. Uh
am I doing good comments, guys? Okay,
how many people watching live? Am I Am I
Am I alive? Okay, three people. The
poverty of my show.
Um, so when you are
uh Aladdin, you know, you might have
heard
Arabian Nights, you hear about Aladdin,
right? You know, the the Disney movie.
So, it turned out the Arabian Knight is
nothing like that. It's like it's it's
nothing like the Disney story they try
to tell you.
It's filled with sex. Okay, let's just
to be blunt. It's filled the Arabian
Knights is filled. You know the easiest
way to understand the nature of the work
at at least on the surface is just look
at the galleries. Okay, these are the
galleries illustrations of the Arabian
Knights. So the nature you see so you
got to look carefully. Okay.
Uh the nature of the book is about sex
girls,
slaves,
young hot slave, sex slaves and uh uh
tits as fornication
uh and you know there. So there you go.
Slaves and queen and uh
and monsters. Okay. monsters and this
part you are probably familiar. So and
prince and princess from the Islamic
world from Persian. Okay. Persian um
kind of and and heavily Islamic. Okay.
So the origin of these stories came from
uh so I read about it on Wikipedia. They
they started around year 600 something.
So it's pieces of stories people
collected around like in Iraq or Iran
somewhere there. Okay. Something you
know something of that nature because
these myth mythologies and fables you
know they have lots of history. So but
anyway so it's about
1,500 years ago. So you got you know
look at these pictures. Okay that's what
this this this these stories is about.
uh Arabian Knights and uh then you know
there's plenty plenty of plenty of tits
and ass okay it's like modern you know
today you go to social network media you
see tits and ass well back then that's
also true you cannot deny it you don't
want to deny it okay then monsters okay
dragons uh travel boats genie okay so
you Moini is a particular
mythological creature from the from that
region.
Okay. So that's an introduction to
Arabian Knights. So the writing uh to
your question, the writing of this
version by Sir Richard Burton is
extremely uh flamboyant and lots of you
know use lots of these kind of um
obsolate English. Uh they say you know
with
in addition therew with okay held pool
archaic yeah archaic English there at at
that event on account of that extempor
of my favorite word talk show extempolo
nothing is prepared I do it live for you
extemp
so so I learned all these words you know
English you I vocabulary is one of my
thing. So very elaborate and you know if
you don't look up it's kind of more
difficult to understand. Okay. So uh but
I kind of like I love it. I love you
know you so so toyo and moyo that's
another phrase I love toyo. Okay I
learned you know I toyo and moyo on the
computer all day day and night.
So, and fisher the fisherman and the
genie is a great story. Okay. Actually,
the the selections I picked all those
are great stories. Um, so you can start
with the story of King Sha Ra and his
brother something. But you can start
with the tale of the bo and the ass and
the fisherman and the genie. Okay, the
fisherman. You see? So, here's a genie
and here's a fisherman and in and there
it is Solomon. I learned this word King
Solomon when I was like 10 in Taiwan. I
don't know what it is, you know, like
back then you just learned about Sol.
Solomon is some kind of great king.
Okay. And today [laughter]
in the past two years because of
politics I learned more about about this
Solomon and other things. Okay. Solomon,
you know,
that changed your perspective. Anyway,
so you got this uh the, you know,
fantastic tales and also you see you can
read them just for the fun of it, you
know, fantasy or girls or whatever um
like a story, but you can also look into
like English, like you know, you look up
every word of it. So and the ethmology
or or whatever then then you will learn
a lot about the
evolution or trans transformation of
English you know this uh archaic English
or and you will also learn about history
and of you know uh and and for example
Solomon it mentioned Solomon like what
what the [ __ ] is Solomon? Well, you look
up. Okay, you look up. Then you learned
something about history. Part of it is
real history, part of it is fiction. But
anyway, that's how stories are.
Then you also learn about uh so vocabul
vocabulary English writing style and uh
um history and uh and their
particular moor
and uh
moor
meaning morality ethics of certain
region or or or a fictional account of
it. Or you learn about how they think
about women like today it's a big issue
like today you know under under the oice
opus of USA United States of America
under the opice of the white man we have
debates about feminism like every day
like every [ __ ] day in USA for the
past at least 30 years. Oh, feminism.
Oh, he and she. Should you when you
write, should you also say she? Then it
became that that was 30 years ago. Then
it became, oh, um,
[laughter]
feminism, right? You know, you hear it
every day at work, at school, uh, you
know, uh,
dating, date, rape, and whatever, you
know, the everything to do with women. I
mean you can't you can't escape it
because men and women they are you know
we are here and then you have trans you
know sex okay it's all like related to
sex
so you learn about their perception or
or what whatever the region or fictional
version of it
1500 years ago um about women they talk
about women all over okay uh they and
then you learn about um
ethology
uh you know things like that.
So that's Arabian Nights by Richard uh
Burton, Sir Richard Burton. Okay, I
enjoyed it very much. Now so but if you
read if you just want to read about the
story so I learned later many years
later I learned this new versions by
Hussein Hatway
so according to reviews it's more
it's it simply tells the story it
doesn't elaborate it doesn't add fluffs
like the Richard uh Sir Richard Burton
does like some criticism
of Sir Richard Burton. By the way, when
he when he translated this, it was
banned
book in, you know, censored, not allowed
to publish because because some people
say it's just porn. It's a [ __ ] porn.
Pornography
banned in UK, United Kingdom.
Uh so and and some criticism. It's it's
it's just like you know pornography.
Uh but then so I learned so this this
version by uh some people claim that
Richard uh Richard S Burton focus too
much more on the sex part you know lots
of sex stuff they he he he emphasized
it.
So, so this this new version by uh
Hussean Hatway supposedly
is more truthful. It doesn't elaborate
about any, you know, sexual part or
whatever or doesn't use uh archaic
English.
So if you really just want to read about
the Arabian Knights as it was collected
back then you might enjoy these two this
version by Hussein Hardway. So I don't
have it so I don't know uh I haven't
read it I don't know. Okay that's
digression into Arabian Nights. I think
we already talked for 30 minutes. Are we
still coding today?
Uh, apparently Aladdin isn't in the
original Arabic manuscripts. That's
correct. You know, because I started to
write about this and annotate it since
like 20 years ago. Then one of the
question is one of the most famous story
is the Aladdin. So where is it? So,
so I started to so I learned Aladdin is
actually not in original Arabian Nights.
Um,
and and but then I start to read it uh
which is also the version by Rich uh uh
sir sir Richard Burton. Okay. Yeah. This
is unbolderized
version of sir Richard Burton's
translation. Okay. Now, now another
interesting word unbolderized.
So back then 100 years ago or something
they used the word embolderized which
basically just means uncensored but but
but they use the word embolderized.
But actually I don't know what's what is
the ethmology of that like what so I I
suppose borderized was a person's name
who started to do some censorship
related to you know something.
So anyway this Aladdin story I read sir
Richard Burton's version and it turns
out so it begin with the poor person. Uh
in fact the whole thing is just like one
there's no sections but I I I separated
them into sections by myself you know so
this is like the edited edition by Kali
Aladdin translated by Sir Richard Burton
edited by Kali yours truly. Okay, I put
them into these sections because
otherwise it's like just one one one big
um
page
and then after I read it, this this
story, the Aladdin or the wonderful lamp
is the worst. Okay, the least
interesting the least interesting among
all these Arabianites.
That's my imp impression. The big one.
Okay, because you know when you when you
when you hear about Arabian nights, you
thought Aladdin is one of the most
popular, right? But then I had read that
it's the least interesting. Okay, like
the most boring one among among among
these stories.
So that's interesting to know.
Uh,
so Moar says I read the Jonathan Scott's
translation first, but but
when I found out the censored the erotic
material, I started again with the
Burton one law though I prefer Scott's
pros in language. Yeah. Yeah. I don't
know Jonathan Scott but I you know I I
know it's like this like most of the
versions are censored censored either
for adults or for children like vast
majority of the Arabianites
because you don't you know you don't you
don't you don't see uh tits and [ __ ]
if you read Arabianites
and you didn't see any tits and [ __ ]
you know what's this story about this
this is the story of the first story.
Okay. She [laughter]
Well, I'm not going to go into it. Okay.
So, you see, if you don't see tits and
[ __ ] in Arabian Nights, that's not
Arabian Knights. Okay. Basically,
so all these are illustrations. Okay.
Now, look at this one. Decipher it for a
moment.
Uh
yeah. Okay.
Now you see they talk about things we
talk about even today in USA America you
know like if you guys are online people
uh or you if you guys read 4chan stuff
you you know about the word coke right
they talk these teens this te and zuma
idiots they talk about it all the time
coke that's what this is okay that's
what this Arabians was talking about
okay I show these pictures I don't know
if YouTube is going to like give me like
warning
you know you you violate comm community
guidelines we going to
uh I don't know you know oh oh my god
this one is spectacular story okay this
this is this story this prince his legs
became stone
Okay. Because of the s sorcerer, you
know, made his legs into a stone. So,
it's a fantastic story. I love it. Um,
and that story you can re read
that's about um, so that's after the
fisherman and the genie. You see the
story is like a recursion. Okay. So,
like the end it doesn't really end. So
you see there upon the youth began right
wondrous and marvelous is my case that
and that of these fishes and who eat
graven
with graver a warner to whoo so would be
warned
takes a while to understand how is that
asked the king and the young man began
to tell the tale of The inscurred
prince. Okay, that is a story where the
prince his
lower body parts became a stone. So it
continues. You see the story is like a
recursion you know story within a story.
Okay. So that that is the uh
tale of the ins inscer. Okay. Yeah.
Here.
Fantastic story. Okay. Okay. Anyway,
concurrent viewers 10. So, I talk about
random stuff. I got more viewers. Uh, so
let's see.
I guess I hope everything is having a
good evening.
I my code is still lingering.
So, I'm still sick somewhat. So, today,
you know,
uh yeah. Well, do we should we code?
Yeah. Um,
you know, so yesterday we we we stuck on
a problem, a little bug that should be
easy to fix. Uh, but but I think let's
not do code today because I already
talked for like 40 minutes about some
other thing. So, let's not talk about
code. Let's talk about random. Okay,
this if you have random questions about
society, about your life, about the
meaning of life, about your religion,
about whatever, about love, you can ask
me. I give you my wisdom
and then we do next video on coding. So,
separate them. So, I was going to say
Yeah, you know, so let me tell you guys
this story. You know,
you probably have heard of the term
STEM. STM
is stand for science, technology,
engineering, and mathematics.
If you are young, you must have heard of
it. You see, because that term is
created by deep state.
It's one of the tactics
Why do they create that term? Well,
supposedly so that women and minorities
can be part of it.
Very funny. You know, STEM, STM,
science, technology, engineering,
mathematics,
women, girls, you need to go into STEM,
you know, STEM, cryptic.
Um, so I thought we should have another
acronym that's called LIVA. Y I V O W
Viva. It stand for linguistics,
literature, vocabulary, and writing.
Okay. Leva
so that women and minorities can get
into these fields.
That's, you know, it's funny.
Um, okay. What else?
Do you believe in God?
That's a good question. Well, that
depends on who is asking like what do
you know about religion? Okay. So, like
how much do you know about religion?
How much do you know about religion?
Uh in the academic sense
like in the word of earthlings, us
earthlings,
we human animals on this earth
there is a thing called religion
which is roughly defined as a like
system of belief.
Okay, roughly defined that way. But you
know uh and it
relates to it you know contains things
like the ultimate you know it contains
relates to the uh part of it is
lifestyle.
Part of it is like certain ultimate
answer.
What is the meaning of life? Why are you
here? Part of it is about cosmology
will we like what happen when we die
about you know so that's roughly
religion okay so do you know how much do
you know about that how many religions
are there what are they what is their
characteristics
what is their
ontology or classification
cate categorize category what type of
you
So what what you know
so next question Sam says no I need to
know if you believe that this world has
a creator or not you believe yeah that
like I said that depends on what you
know first okay let me let me just
answer instead of going about okay like
the what you know one of my personal
hero
uh is Bertron Russell. Okay. Another
British guy, Brit, the white man.
Now, you younglings, you probably you
may not know. So, let me just show you
this guy, Bertron Russell. Okay, let's
open a new um
uh new tab. And let's also look at the
pictures. And he's got lots of videos,
too. There's lots of videos of Bertron
Russell. Okay. Now he is one of the guy
I would say top three that has greatest
influence on my life on the way I see
the world on my thinking including on my
views about religion. Okay he's in short
you can say he's one of my idol
Bertrron Russell.
So what what is he? He is a uh well he's
quite a few he's alcohol
person. He is a one of the founder in
mathematical logic. He's a mathematician
logician. Okay. One of the founder um
of mathematics. one of the you know
let's say
the top
one among the top 50 most important
mathematicians in the past 100 years
let's say so he's one of that and he's
also one of the greatest philosopher in
western society Bertrron Russell okay so
do you guys know if you don't know I'm
giving you a introduction okay one of
the greatest logician mathematician
uh and one and and also known as the one
of the greatest philosopher of western
society. Okay, western philosophy
that is what he's most well known for
and he also won Nobel Prize by the way
for literature which is kind of silly
but he you know he won Nobel Prize for
literature.
Uh, and the other thing he's known for
is a peace fighter. You know, he he uh
he and Einstein signed a letter to stop
nuke bombs. Okay. Anyway, that's what
he's mostly known for. And he also been
put to jail by whom? By Christians.
Okay. Bon Russell
got put to jail by Christians.
Now I think you probably can guess what
is my stance about Christian. Okay. Um
so Bertron Russell
he's a um if you ask him if he's
religious that depends
if you don't know anything about
religion if you are a Christian like
vast majority of Christians or the other
the other Abrahamic religions like uh
Judaism or Islam people Muhamadans
also also known as
then
Bertron Russell is an atheist. So am I.
No, I don't believe in God. Okay. Now,
well, you can go elaborate. Well, I do
believe in God. Okay.
If you know, like, do you believe in
God? If you say no, you're going to die.
We're gonna kill you. Okay. that you
know some of the people
uh a lot of those people had that
stance. Okay. So well then no I believe
in God just not your god. Okay.
So
you can be an atheist or
more correctly
am agnostic
which means
the question about God is not knowable.
You cannot know it. Okay? You know it's
just like you don't know there's there's
no way to know. So that is more
technically correct
in some sense. But on the whole the
question is just like city
uh you know there's no like you cannot
talk logic about these kind of issues.
So let's see what's the next did I miss
any questions? So I think maybe that's
it for today or is there any other
questions?
Am I going well? Do you guys enjoy the
show?
Okay. So, you are right about learning
evolution of words. For example, instead
of him was in hisstead, which I like
more. Okay. Hikar. Hi, Chad.
Uh, simple postman. Hi, Sam. Yeah,
you're right. What do you think about
idealism? Idealism, that's classic
philosophy.
Uh
so analyzing religion from a
sociological perspective doesn't answer
anything.
He ain't going to give clear answer. I
don't think so. Okay. [laughter]
What do you think about friendship at
your age? My life experience shows that
it's just a matter of conveniences for
the va v vast majority of people not
real lifelong connection. Okay. About
friendship.
Okay. Well, I can tell you something
about my you know my experience. So I my
personality
as it so happens partly because of my
gene partly because of my environment my
family which is quite [ __ ] up. Okay so
my personality I'm a skezoid
which is a topic I have talked about
often.
Okay, that is the word skezoid.
Technically, uh, wait, no, stupid Emacs.
No, uh, go back. Technically, it's
called skezoid.
Skizoid personality disorder. Now you
can, now let let's show the power of
Emacs. Okay, press press. It goes to
search.
So schizoidic personality disorder mayor
clinic then Wikipedia.
Now you can also search Wikipedia
directly. Press press press press. There
it is. Wikipedia.
Okay. Blah blah blah blah blah blah blah
blah blah. Now press press. Now we go to
Guipipedia
which is Ellen Musk's new thing. Bak
dark theme
and skisoid personality disorder which I
believe the content is actually exactly
the same as Wikipedia
for now. So anyway,
what does it mean? So I'm I'm a mild
skezoid. So what does that mean? Skizoid
personality. First of all, it's a
personality. Okay. Now what about the
disorder? Well, it's a disorder when
when you have a personality to a severe
degree, you cannot function in society.
Then you say it's dis disorder. Okay.
There are many type there are many types
of personality disorder. For example,
there is um histrionic histrionic
where people needs to make drama
attention. Hey here, oh what happened
here? you know something something
people are like that okay
uh histrionic then there's borderline
like women most mostly women they they
need to cut themselves they cannot form
proper relationships you know there's
quite a few okay
personality okay it's it's just a
personality but if you have such a trait
in a severe degree it affected your
ability to form home, normal
relationships or wife or husband's
friendship or work.
Then they say it's disorder.
Okay, remember that that's like the
meaning. Okay, everyone has a
personality. Everyone, all of you has a
personality. But some some sometimes you
have such like strong way as particular
personality in a severe degree then you
say it's like disorder. Okay.
So my so me I am a ski resort. I'm a
minor one.
Am I functional? Well you could say yes.
You could say no. Okay. Yes. Because
well I'm talking to you. I'm doing
YouTube. I'm great. You know I'm good
coder. uh I can teach people. I can you
know but in in a way you could say I'm
not I'm not exactly functional because
uh well a lot of you think you know like
I'm crazy. I'm a n job you know
[laughter]
and uh in fact I haven't worked in a
like corporation environment for mo most
of my life and during one time about 15
years ago I was about to die of hunger
in USA
so in a sense I'm not exactly you know
I'm not normal for sure and you could
say I'm kind of dysfunctional
okay So is it a disorder? Well, it's a
matter of degree, okay? Like who is to
judge?
So, so what I'm telling you is that I am
a schizoid personality. Okay? M a mild
one, not severe one. There are severe
ones I know. So what but what exactly is
skezoid? That's like like in short it's
people who are loners
especially you you guys probably know
you know among programmers or scientists
there's a lot loners
they prefer to do things alone
uh you know
uh they they just you know they they
they don't make friends they they you
know they don't enjoy like going out for
example when I go to a bar I feel very
nervous like I don't know what to do,
what to say like or some people you guys
you know let's say you know you have
like guys nights what whatever you know
go to watch football I I I cannot
imagine you know I feel I would feel
very uncomfortable
or if I feel very uncomfortable to talk
any small talks okay if you want to talk
about mathematics computers sciences
psychology sociology academic subjects I
can talk a river. I can talk nonstop.
But if you want to talk small talks like
how how are you today? How is your um
you know what what did you do? You know
that I cannot do that. Okay. I I get I
get nervous.
I don't know what to say. Okay. So it's
a loner personality. Okay. That's me.
Loner. So in general, so back to your
question. Okay. I don't make friends all
my life. I basically I haven't you know
I don't make I don't have friends
because I don't make them. I don't you
know what I do every day is like
mathematics very cold
mathematics truth society or whatever I
study literature
uh technology sciences okay I I don't do
small talks I don't establish friendship
that's just me
okay so I'm a skisoid so your question
about do you make friends. Now,
as I get older, I can tell you it is
important to make friends. Okay?
You want to make long-term friends.
Long-term friends who can help you like
establish long-term friends to so that
the person can help you. You can help
each other
in life.
Okay? Not not just like going out for
movies or uh have a dinner together, not
like that, but long-term friends when
you have crisis or whatever.
You want friends, so
do what you can. You know, every every
person is different. So do what you can.
I would recommend
if you are a teen, you don't care,
right? I mean, whatever happens and you
don't know what's going on anyway. But
as you get older, when you are like 30s
or 40s, you you want to, you know, pick
friends, make establish long-term good
friends.
That's what I say. Okay. Okay. I think
that maybe that's it. I've been talking
for an hour almost.
So that's the question. That's my answer
about what do you think about
friendship?
Okay. As for me, I'm close to 60. I
still don't have much friends. Um,
you know that well in part because I'm
I'm a skezoid by nature. It's it's in
it's it's in my brain. Okay. I cannot
like talk chithat
like some of you join kasawa forum. You
might realize too like who who is this?
Wait, this is AI generated picture of
me. Some stupid guy did that. So,
so let's go to uh programming. So, we
are doing uh advant of code. So, a lot
of people actually are doing it to
advant of code in G scheme and others.
Anyway, so
you know, I'm I you know, I turned out
that way.
Uh I do what I can to fix my
shortcomings,
but some other part of me I cannot
change. That's just the way I am. Okay?
So I don't I don't actually have much
friends. Okay? And I don't I don't
really make them.
Okay? So, do I have kids? I wish, but
no. You know, I'm getting to a edge. If
if I don't make kids now, I will not
have kids. Uh, so hard to say, you know.
Uh, J, I could not stay at home for hour
a day. No, how you do it? Yeah. So, each
person is different. Okay. For me, I can
stay by myself 24 hours a day for 10
years. No problem. In fact, that's what
I did. Like like what like I talked
about this before like what you see I
sitting in front of a computer 10 hours
a day for 10 years. In fact, I did this
almost all my life, but very severe from
2010 to 2020.
that the degree of severity of me just
sitting in front of computer doing you
know reading about programming languages
or math is to a degree that I would say
I'm in the like genius like genesis
record you know of the person who sits
in front of a computer the longest on
average for 10 years in USA I would
claim I'm among the top 100 that's the
severe degree you know I can explain to
you guys but you guys wouldn't
understand but anyway the the thing
about skiso personality is that we just
loners okay we just
um
prepare things to do things alone okay
so there's a summary
Simple postman says schizoid is a
personality disorder characterized by a
lack of interest in social
relationships. Correct. A tendency
towards a solitary or sheltered
lifestyle. That's correct.
Secretiveness.
Uh that's kind of correct. Well, I mean
uh and emotional coldness and
detachment. That's correct roughly. But
you see every skezoid is different you
know after all you cannot summarize like
what a person's personality is every
person is like different so but in
general you know you can you can read
Wikipedia or you can ask AI you know
because Wikipedia they became so
academic and mumbo jumbo like you don't
know
you know Wikipedia in the past 10 20
years they they mutated at it into like
a academic mumbo jumbo style. So they
use lots of jarens you like you read it
you don't understand what he's saying
but today you can ask AI
that will give you much better picture
okay so let's let me do it for you guys
explain schizoid
now personality personality
disorder okay let me magnify now in
personality disorder there are several
for other
names that's similar but they are
entirely different. There is also
schizoooido personality. Okay. And
there's also schizophrenic.
Schizophrenic is not a personality
disorder. Schizophrenic is is your brain
is [ __ ] Okay. You see illusions. So
it's like totally different. Okay. It's
very confusing. So you know uh and skis
skisoid skisoido personality is is that
they are like they are mystics
like they talk about like they saw God
you know I saw God today I talked to God
you know they everything they see they
see like they see things they see
spirits they you know like those are
shamans those are schizoidal disorder
personality. Okay. And we on discord we
have a we have we have someone like
that. I have I have all kind of people
on my discord. So anyway, so you can see
here is a guork AI summary
explain schizoid explain schizoid
personality disorder. personality
disorder is a mental health condition
classified as a cluster a odd or eentric
personality disorder in the DSM
something something something something
manual it involves a pervasive pattern
of detachment from social relationships
and restricted range of emotional
expression that's true in interpersonal
settings
people with schizoid personality ity
disorder typically prefer solitary
activities, show little interest in
close relationships, including with
family, and appear indifferent to
praise, criticism, or opinion of others.
That's true. You see, that describes me,
you know, like you can praise me, you
can criticize me. I don't give a [ __ ]
Like what? You don't know. [ __ ]
[laughter]
That's true. So anyway, here you know
here's a summary from from AI. So key
symptoms and diagn diagnostic criteria
neither desire or enjoy close
relationships including being part of a
family.
Again you know these characteristics
each person is different. So not every
characteristics apply to every so-called
skisoid. Okay. So then almost always
choose solitary activities. Okay. Has
little if any interest in sexual
experience with another person. Okay.
That's interesting one.
Uh takes pleasure in few if any
activities. Okay. Lacks close friendship
or com confidants other than firstderee
relatives. Okay. Appears indifferent to
the praise or criticism of others. shows
emotional coldness, detachment or
flattened effect, limited emotional
expression. That's true. You know, lots
of these items apply to me. Okay, I
think that's it. Anything else? Um,
have I have you ever worked at fan
companies? What is fan companies?
Okay, I think that's it for today. Uh,
okay. Bye guys. Uh,
that's it for today. Uh if you guys like
my stuff, okay,
donate, okay, sponsorship by you.
So you just go to go to kali.info
codeali.info.
So go to the bottom
patreon me, Amazon gift card, PayPal me.
Okay.
Uh then we shut down in one minute.
my lingering code. I hope I hope it goes
away maybe by today.
Oh, big five tech companies.
Facebook, Microsoft, Netflix. know the
well the biggest corporation I worked
for kind of is Wuam Wuam Research and uh
Net General uh was it called Net General
or Ntopia?
Uh Ntopia
got bought by Motorola
but by that time I was no longer with
Ntopia. So, so anyway that was like in
the dotcom days. So around year 2000
[sighs]