good morning guys
welcome to another episode of saw talk
show and
here's to mathematics and good life so
today I'm going to talk about these
topics when you see your topic here just
type in the comments and I'll talk about
it so there is you know these topics I
can talk about Emacs or math in Python
okay so let's see if people are here no
one's here yet I'm gonna you know I have
these Emacs Sophocles and they are a lot
issues pairing up because I haven't been
doing them for the past two weeks and
apparently because I'm doing videos so
there are more users starting to use it
so there's more comments so there's a
one poor request by dan dan lang glow is
I'm going to look into this weekend and
there are also issues there are new
issues you know few few new issues in
the past few days so I'm going to get to
them okay just be patient with me hi
guys hi is it Dionne or Diane here's to
good life
so again
today's topic is any one of these any of
any one of these you just pick a topic
and type it and I'll talk about it if
you don't type it I'm just going to
start random so I'm probably going to
start by yeah let's start one of the
things demo generate generate sitemap
and update show random page so I'm going
to start with Emacs DeYoung okay deal
young breed bridge preacher preacher
right okay so let me show let me start
to show the okay so before I do that
let's turn on sauce start command log
mod so as you know I've talked about
this many times this window will show
all of the Emacs command I call so you
can see on the left now I'm going to
show you how to generate set map okay if
you don't know what is a sitemap let me
show you sorry sorry sitemap so there is
yeah okay so sorry sitemap - sounds good
so again if you want any of these topics
you want me to talk about it just type
it in the window type in the comment
just keep keep the comments going okay
so okay sitemap so what is sitemap I'm
gonna show you create a sitemap in Emacs
Lisp so I wrote this script to create a
sitemap now if you don't know what's
aside map basically if you run a website
like you know like I do for example or
go Emacs so let's go to my Emacs blog
let's go to the directory you can see
I don't want to magnify uh you know so
you see this is my Emacs website
directory and I go up one one one level
of directory and you can see there is my
sitemap file so I open it not this one
okay sitemap XML sitemap XML this one so
I open it and you can see they are just
it's just an XML file the XML file and
each line contains a path to your
website so the purpose of the sitemap
file is that web crawlers such as Google
you know being and others you know with
such you know they can just read this
file and they they all know all the
files on your website so they don't have
to call anymore I mean that's the idea
you know save saves them time you know
cuoco Google I think Google and some
others but anyway Google is one of the
primary guys who created it created this
idea this about ten years ago male ten
years ago and it's no good basically you
see these companies they do all sort of
things to actually to make you to help
them so they you know they worded nicely
they create the situation so that you
know if you are a programmer you run a
website oh you hear about sitemap and
you think oh that's a great idea I want
to you know create a sitemap but
actually what you are doing is you are
helping them you know they benefit it
doesn't benefit you because you spend
time to do all these stuff the Google
benefit that's how companies work you
know they create this all these things
then the geeks the programmers all fair
for it like oh great sitemap and you
know and it's open source you know and
Google of course they have a website
they help you like you know what
language to use to create a sitemap and
so on you know
what actually should should be is that
google if they run a such engine right
you know do the stuff by yourself you
know I don't care I must you know
website creator I don't want to you know
do things for you
that's that should be you know what
happens but that's not you know but you
know of course Google push it you know
by saying oh this is small efficient
yeah it's true you know and this is more
efficient you know so all the
programmers webmasters you know fail for
it but anyway so I have a I have this
side map you can see this is my set map
for my a go Emacs website so how is this
done I have a Emacs script that
generated for example let's open you
know my set map and I delete the file
you can see the command I just caught on
the left so I just deleted the file you
can see it's done okay and now I run
this command look at the left panel
you'll see the command sitemap Southside
generate sitemap so I press enter you
ask me which website I want to generate
a sitemap for so ago Emacs enter you
take like five seconds so it's done so
you see it's all done and if you go to
the directory you can see it generates a
new file if I didn't delete that file
you know basically just to make a pack
pack up and replace it so anyway so
that's sitemap and if you are running
your own website I don't think much of
many of you are because most of you are
probably using blogs and some sort of
you know oke mod or you know and that I
think I think they probably have you
know generates the sitemap for you but
so you don't have to but anyway so this
Emacs script the command is this it's
not January sitemap
now let's describe function control H
control H F
there this describe function and I can
go to my command this one so let's open
that and you can see this is such
insight mapped out yeah so this is a
script that I use to create a sitemap
and it's only 99 Tila lines okay so yeah
and do I have this on the website I
think so yeah so I also created the
website over Emacs you can see it's
right here that's the URL and and if you
want to create a script yourself you can
just follow this you know I have like
instructions how it ought to you how do
you write this in Emacs Lisp okay that's
that's a sitemap so let's close this
close that we don't need it anymore
close it close it back to my Emacs prog
so sitemap okay let me check the
comments you vote for six okay let's see
what's six six language design Python
context dependent semantics okay I'm
gonna talk about that so let's finish
the sitemap so yeah so you see you I
have a Emacs script that generate a
sitemap here's two mathematics this is
my roommates whiskey my roommates
cheap whiskey he drinks everyday I don't
really drink
I you know once because he's drinking so
I not drink maybe once a month okay we
got sitemap what else I want to talk
about sigh maps egg map site map he is
okay said maybe is good let's see so we
got Emacs sitemap
eMac B's so you can you know this is the
road to eMac Lisp you can see how great
it is and you see well you can do that
and you start to write and you start to
learn eMac this as well that's that's it
that's great oh I want to mention
another thing
so besides eMac this I also wrote
another version in go so let's go to it
Golan let's let me show you so I go to
my bookmark replace go go to the
directory now remember the left panel
here this window always shows what
command I'm using so if you are
wondering what commanded he code to do
that you know and then you can just look
you can just find the command name on
the left then you can just such a web
typically they are on my website I have
like the code and instructions so anyway
so sitemap change sitemap go so this is
the file this one and it's written : I
tend to you know when I love a new
language you know in the past Python you
know I began with Perl Python you know
well a new language I typically write
some of these scripts for my own use and
that's also how I start to learn the
language so here's a script in go
language that generates my site map so
here let's see the to process actually
you generate all my domains about you
max what in English you know some RT and
so on but that's for now let's comment
those out it's this show you know I'm
gonna show you how I ran these so I'm
gonna run this when the command is
Sargon current file you can see on the
Left panel so it's running and it's done
so it says file saved to you know ago
you may accept sitemap you know it's
just like is that identical to before
but if you got
the directory you can see oh it doesn't
it doesn't create a backup but anyway
does that society map so this is in :
closest so this is this is in goal and
by the way it's also on a website
oh I don't have the URL here so let's
add it so let's go to sorry
goal and now let's let me check the
comments okay keep the comments coming
okay so goal and so let's go through
goal and tutorial and it scroll down its
generate sitemap right here okay so what
I'm going to do is copy the URL go back
to Emacs go back go back to Emacs and
put it here so comment out yeah so
that's my script so here is a code and
yeah okay that's it about go that's
that's it about a sitemap so let's close
this close close close Emacs brog close
no view my programming block okay
sitemap is good covered no oh yeah
there's another thing I want to talk
about should I
why not so on microwave site you can see
if you go to the you you know go back to
the top and go back to Kali info and
near the bottom if you scroll down your
see sitemap okay and you click on that
you will see actually all the articles
on my website
they are like $3,000 calls
you know so basically this this this is
all the articles on my website and you
can click this button to random nice you
know like each time you click it it
shows you know it reorders them randomly
so why do I create this page actually I
created this page because I I go to
Twitter and other social networks and
every you know every day I need to treat
treat some treat and you know some of my
articles so but also you know because I
have like three thousand articles like
if you go to the bottom of the page
you know it's thirty five thousand
articles and basically daily I just
maintained them like be viewed at like
something like they get they get old you
know some articles I haven't updated for
you know years I maintain them we read
them review them update them you know so
for example so this JavaScript
autohotkey key syntax the problems of
traditional math notation this article
got into hacker news few month ago
Mathematica logo history IBM model M
keyboard which is a hackers you know in
the hackers law so let's look at some of
these so this page is about JavaScript
get set up properties getter in setters
by the way if you are JavaScript code
you you may or may not know that Gator
in setters are not actually use this
don't use it you know don't use it
so although hotkey syntax is very
practical or the hotkey is a software to
create key shortcuts on Microsoft
Windows things like that and so I have
you know or a hockey tutorial
you know the key syntax is different on
every keyboard software there is no
standardized way so each language is
each kind of the script create their own
for example Emacs Emacs this has its own
you know X mode map has its own key
syntax you know and other tools every
tool has its own key syntax anyway so
you know I'm just showing you some of
the articles and here is the problems of
traditional math notation and by the way
you know if you look at math notations
math notations music notations like the
staff you know the music notations or
programming language syntax you all are
natural languages like English you know
French Italian or Chinese so on almost
always they are bag of you know
they are like extremely extremely
illogical inconsistent and so on and the
the reason it's that way it's just just
because natural is history it's the
growth you know that's how things evolve
and we get used to it and and by habit
you know we we got stuck stuck with it
basically and and in all these areas
music notation math notation programming
language syntax natural languages
throughout time there are always
movements to rectify rectify them like
you know create a version that is
logical consistent regular easier to
learn you know more efficient to read
and so on and almost always they are
failures for example English they are
quite they are quite a few many many
instance of that you know and and are
many different aspects there's a you
know rectification for enunciation there
is for you know regular regularization
of sparing there is basic English
so-called basic English you can look up
on Wikipedia basic English and so on
they are quite a lot others and at the
time you know when a movement began
usually there are a few you know popular
writers you know authors or even
politicians like US presidents that that
that approve you know push for it but
yeah they always fail they almost they
always failed so anyway so these
problems of traditional notation there
is okay this this one is mathematical
logo history right American local
history this one is actually the most
beautiful this is not version two in
1991 and IBM model M keyboard you know
these hackers you know most favorite
language I mean the hackers they talk
about this keyboard all the time and you
can hear the keystrokes how it sounds
those are mechanical keyboards okay so I
straight I straight let's get get back
to the comments ok let's talk about
topic number six so how many people are
watching three okay this is right now
it's Friday two o'clock you know Friday
is usually people you know people go out
and have fun and stuff at least in
America in USA ok language design Python
context dependent semantics ok let's
talk about that so in this case let's go
to ok let's just go to my blog okay
sorry dot info programming
[Music]
and if you go to semantic Newdow here
okay it's a syntax OOP if you go to the
syntax OOP
you can see this Arco now this page
syntax to soup they are collection of
essays related to syntax programming
language syntax now I'm going to talk
about these now first of all I mean I
died let me show you this one I just
created
I just wrote wrote it yesterday now in
Python you have these two syntax for
importing a module you know from a a
import PB for example and the other
statement is import cc now these two
different statements they they both
contain the clause import something you
know import the name you know import the
name and import the name here but
however notice they have different
meanings that is the semantics is
different so in in the first case from a
a import PB the PB here means a function
a function name now in a second
second case in for CC the CC here means
a module name so you can see that here
even both of them does syntactically
they are exactly the same thing import
you know so much something in for
something but they have different
meaning so this is what I I call context
dependent semantics so I'm not sure
what's a good good name for it and I
don't know if there's is a standardized
you know the jargon or phrase to to
refer to this situation you know I could
see you know context dependent semantics
that's not exactly a good description
because it's it's context dependent
syntax
but I because this is you know these are
syntax but however they are its the
difference is not the syntax it's
actually the semantics so it's kind of
like context context dependent semantics
of the syntax is something like that
okay so I don't know if there's a
standard term
do you guys know so by the way any
anyone is sweet watching you know keep
the comments coming okay so you know I
know you know what whatever you know
when I'm saying something you just say
your opinions or ask the questions keep
the comments coming
let me type it here actually keep the
comments going so so so here's a
situation where you have this syntax
dependent context dependent syntaxes in
semantics now I don't want to use the
word context dependent syntax because
that has already that has already
meaning impasses in compilers you know I
might cover that later it's you know if
like if you are familiar with writing
compilers or studying or pauses which is
computer science there's a concept
called regular syntax or context-free
syntax yeah that's a that's a red-faced
context-free syntax now that word has a
specific meaning which is different from
what I'm talking about here I might
cover that so if you if you want to hear
me talk about that I'll talk about that
that's that's about parsing compilers in
parsing and which is computer science
you know it's it's not something typical
average programmers would know so anyway
so I have you know I'm studying
languages you know language design or
any issues on my own so I see all these
different kind of things that's not
typically discussed
in in let's say no more literature but I
also want to mention I'm not a compiler
or passer Expo expert not at all you
know I haven't written any pauses passes
or compilers so I began to do that but
if you dive into the past writing passes
you know computer science aspect of it
and writing compilers they are actually
a lot you know things you know and then
papers you know publish in your academia
so you know so I'm saying that because
you know some of my perceptions could be
wrong but anyway these are not the
things you you are finding hacker news
tip you know they are very rare because
if you read hacker news you know you
might say oh they say this that way
anyway so anyway here's a you know
example of current context dependent
semantics let's just cover that now
here's another example in Python so in
Python you have this syntax X in list
that tells you whether the X elements
you know some some element is is in the
list and you also have this syntax X not
in list now this is you know fairly
stupid you know I don't like Python at
all and so of course this is created by
keidel you know Kaito created a Python
language his ideas he said opinions is
always you know I don't like them at all
but anyway so in these two cases you can
see that you know Python code is in as
an operator and this not in two words
together they cook they also call it
I believe Python Co is an operator you
know the concept of operator is also
very confusing in programming languages
because first of all from a math
perspective and the form you know the
earlier days of you know earlier
languages when you have an operator it's
almost always a symbol for example the
first sign the star sign asterisk
you know the for multiplication or the
caret sign you know it's usually used
for power you know to raise two three
you know when you think of operators you
know in a math at least operators is
basically it's just a notation for a
function you know and usually they are
represented in writing or some kind of
symbol like you know star or plus or
circle plus you know or triangle but in
computer languages the concept of
operator gets they get kind of expanded
and more confusing for example in in
JavaScript okay let's go back one page
it's open that okay okay so let's you
know look at this article javascript in
javascript actually they're the the
javascript specification they actually
say you know so in JavaScript you have
this syntax peeing OH which returns true
if if P is a property of oh okay so in
JavaScript technically speaking this
word in you know if you look up the
JavaScript eggman script specification
you know the JavaScript suspect for the
language the the world in they actually
call it an operator so here we have an
example where the operator is not just a
symbol it's actually a you know a string
like an English word okay so so back
into Python so we have something similar
in Python okay so okay but what what I'm
getting into what I want to say here is
about the context-dependent syntax you
know syntax OOP so you can see this in
is an
operator or a syntax okay so X in list
is an operator you know you know it
means something but however here we have
not in you know X not in list which is
equivalent to equal equivalent to you
know not X in Beast now this is getting
interesting because the key word the
word not is the the word not is also an
operator in Python it's just a negation
it's a boolean negation so you see you
see how here it's it's getting
complicated because the word in is an
operator and the word not in with the
space in between oh you can't have more
actually you can have multiple spaces I
believe it's actually also an operator
but however you see the the word not is
also an operator the word in is also not
affected so it's also an operated so
here you know it's confusing you know so
what I'm saying is that they are not
logically orthogonal so you know for
example if you look at these two
examples so it appears you know it
appears you can combine operators to
form new operators but in fact that's
not actually the case
in fact what actually happens is just
that you know Python just say you know
this is one statement and this is one
statement there is no there's no a
systematic way you know to generate you
know for for example all possible
operators it's not the case it's just
that you know the gyda just says you
know you can do this this way and you
can do it that way so it's so it's like
extremely irregular it's ad hoc you know
he you know he just think you know for
doing this you he just create a syntax
for that for doing that he just create
another syntax of that you know so
there's the
this is no systematic basis for all
these you know that's why I say it's a
syntax soup so that is one example in in
and not in but they're small you know in
Python you also have these syntax you
know for something in something that is
part of the syntax for country of what's
called list comprehensions so let's look
at that so it's so here's a list
comprehension
for example this you know this is a
Python code so you have s equals to
something for something in something you
know so again you see the word in used
again but however however the in the
word in here is different from the word
in here and it's also different from the
word in here so so you see what I mean
by context dependent syntax swoop so
that's one of my issues with with
computer languages in general this
happens in quite a lot languages not
just Python but Python is one of the
particular that's was there has lots of
these things so so this issue you know
this issue is part of the language
design of course language design you
asked different language you know
different people they have different
opinions but also I want to mention like
I said before this issue you almost
never see people talk about in fact I
have never seen anyone talk about it
doesn't matter where you read not even I
haven't seen people talk about in
compiler you know the community or
partner process community so I'm not
sure exactly you know what is the
situation by that I mean you know by
that I mean you know I have this point
of view right I have this
of this issue I bring up about this
context-dependent syntax soup but I have
not seen it discussed elsewhere you know
so I would like to see it you know
discussed you know maybe some computer
scientist has has you know wrote an
article about it maybe some academic
papers you know they discuss that issue
but I have not seen so it's something
for me you know to look into you know in
the coming you know years so I like to
know about the situation so you know if
some if some people have discussed
already you know I like to see their
opinions you know what what is the
situation why you know it's this way
better or why is it not that way you
know I I have right now I don't even
know if there is a turn you know a
terminology to describe you know what
I'm thinking so if you any of you guys
know about that issues you know let me
know oh you know after you know after
livestream if anyone is watching this
video make a comment so you know I can
learn something about that and okay and
let me you know keep the comments coming
okay so I'm going to read it every now
and then so Norman Norman says Python
syntax has many Python syntax has many
problems I find it annoying yeah I agree
I concur we concur I totally agree I
don't like Python at all you know so I
have I have also so so this syntax soup
is the collection of articles all
related to the issues I find about
computer computer language syntax issues
they now have another correction about
Python sucks you know I don't like
Python so naughty
I hate it had so much bugs because of my
idiocy of using it okay so that's about
Python issues and JavaScript is not
better it's much in fact JavaScript
syntax is much worse was
you know for example the the issue we
just talked about
it happens in JavaScript to to example
here you have PE o but you have also for
VAR p in o in something you know the
second case the force var peeing or
something that is actually a loop that
goes through a properties of a object
you know but however the the word in
happens in both cases like peeing oh but
they have completely different meaning
so you know most programmers they don't
know nothing about this and even yeah
anyway that's that's another issue you
know what I'm trying to get is you know
you go to how can you so many of these
elite hackers you know like like they
tell you what you should do you should
do it this way or that way
they never in their life thought about
these issues like they don't know you
know they are elite hackers like oh I'm
the creator of jQuery I'm the creator of
react you know reactor yes they don't
know you know they like you know that so
that's one of my complaint you know I
have all these commits content you know
I write about it I post and whenever I
mean discussion you know like let's say
Python community or Emacs this community
or the common is they attack me you know
they say you are stupid you know yeah I
don't know what you know so I almost
like never get quality comments on on
these issues you know I wish if if
someone you know they are a lot better
smarter you know they made a better
programmer than me and more experiencing
you know I wish someone you know who has
written competitors if they run into
math then you know I wish they can tell
me okay
have you you know maybe they have run
into this issue maybe they have seen
articles about this issue and they can
point it out
then I learned something but typically I
post this you know if I you know puts
these two Emacs or Python communities
they I just get attack
you know these idiots endless attacks
okay so so okay so that that is the
issue I you know I want to talk about
about the Python context-dependent
syntax ooh okay there's another other
related issue about regular syntax in
parsley and Grandma yeah so I was me I
mentioned before if you study passes you
know there is a standard phrase called
code context-free grammar or
context-free languages I don't know if
you guys want me to talk about that I
can talk about that I can give you an
introduction you know just an
introduction of what does context-free
language or context-free grammar means
it has a specific specific meaning you
know it's part of computer science and
also again mean any of these topics if
you want me to talk about it you know
just type it out - oh yeah change the
life title thank you you know this you
know I'm still learning about the
streaming stuff so let me do that it's
turn on the auto click ok let's paste XR
talk-show 2019 March 15th so actually I
don't know what's the topics yet and
here we are done so we've been talking
for finished 14 40 40 minutes already so
ok what else let's see
let me read another comment distinction
between statements and expressions
create creates syntactic confusion as
well exactly
yeah let me mention about that issue
because let me mention okay so so guys
if you see your topic you want me to go
into just type it otherwise I'll
probably just you know pick random
things like whatever I feel like so
let's talk about you know computer
language syntax issues so let's go back
to syntax OOP so there is yeah okay see
ya there's you know you know in
programming languages you have
statements you have expressions and
depending on the language sometimes you
have directives you know a so called
what's called directives for example in
Perl you can you you you have like use
strict in JavaScript you have oh you
also have yeah I think it's new strict
let's see if that's right so I create a
new buffer switch to such of a sweet mod
use strict yeah so in JavaScript you
have this this line you know it's just a
string it's just a string it's like it
doesn't do anything but actually I mean
in JavaScript if you just create a
string you know it doesn't do anything
but this string has meaning when you
have this string in JavaScript you
strict that actually tells the
JavaScript compared us to pass your code
in a different way
basically you know Java Street
JavaScript is a extreme mess but
basically you know JavaScript it you
know like 20-30 years ago almost you
know 25 years ago but it didn't it it
was a lousy language designed for you
know the non coders but around 2008 it
becomes extremely popular and critical
and important so they try to fix the
language you know they try to fix the
language
because you know all the code you know
out there in browsers so they decided to
make it compatible I mean the decision
is that any change you add to JavaScript
you want to maintain compatibility so
that all the old old web sites we are
still run you know that that's a
decision you know that you have to make
a decision
you know Inc in contrast you know the
Java the Python you know Python
community guide oh he also want to fix
problems in Python but he created Python
three which is incompatible with Python
2 the result is nobody uses uses it you
know after almost 10 years Python 3
adaption is pretty bad it's like you
know maybe 40 40 percent let's see but
it's it's reality you know it's like you
know so so here's a page where you know
every every few years I look into how
you know the Python status of Python 3
adaption and it's pretty bad you know so
in Python so in 2018 Python 3 is you
know ok there are 5 percent of the top
360 libraries still don't use Python 3
you know that yeah 5 percent you know
but basically Python 3 you know it's not
widely adopted you know people are still
using Python 2 and in fact Google
created a goal and project that just
transpired onto into goal and and and
they created this image it's so fun you
know here goes in Python and comes out
goal and yeah so Python 3 is kind of a
failure I mean partly speaking I mean
but I guess eventually will happen you
or take you know
years you know it's been 10 years
already so anyway back to JavaScript so
JavaScript they decided the JavaScript
community decided they want to you know
be compatible so they so they created
this used strict stream so when you have
this string the parser will treat the
code slightly differently basically some
improvements of the semantics you know
the syntax yeah yeah you know things
like that you know I'm not going I'm not
going to go into it because it's rather
the fairly complex you know because
javascript is very messed up you know
it's very many complexities you know you
cannot you cannot just explain easily
you know to explain one thing you have
to mention oh because you know this
object because that that that and in
turn because that that therefore you
know when you have this and this happens
but only if you have that or you know in
before that you know things like that so
anyway so javascript guys created this
new strict but after a few years they
abandon abandoned it again you know
they decided okay we are now going to
introduce anymore you strict you know
things like that so it's very its
entirety is quite screwed up you know
there are people you know they wish me
to not use swearing in my videos and
that's sensible because you know there
are a lot of people you know common
people they don't you know when you have
swearing your videos first of all it you
know they don't you know it's it's not
really good you know and also it reduces
your audience you know like they cannot
share they can you know they want to
share your video to their friends but
you know maybe their friends is very you
know sensitive about that so they did
you know so maybe I'll try to you know
we face the f-word by just screw up you
know things like that you know me or how
I would try that so anyway the point I'm
the reason I'm mentioning you strict is
that
I don't know I don't know what's the
technical term for this thing but but in
Perl it's called a directive
it's called directive the IRAC tive
so in Perl is called directive keep the
comments going okay I'm going to read it
and answer questions and so on so impo
it's called directive so but what
happened is that let me put it here so
what happen is that you see so in
languages we have so let me put that
here and it's copy that what happens so
if we have expressions statements so in
languages we have expressions we have
statements we have directive directives
now let me ask you the question what
else are there Kenny can you can anyone
answer so programming languages you have
expression statements directives what I
all saw there so let me let me read the
comments a bit temperature change this
live tanker so with Python with Python
and Jupiter
now using pi/3 maybe some people are
going to use it yeah Python so you know
Jupiter
looks like becoming a big thing and I
Python too but actually I never had the
experience with him but recently I just
installed on our Kandra let me get back
to the topic so in foreign languages you
have expression statements and you know
you have also directives what else are
there that is the question that is very
interesting question so when I'm
studying languages you know you want to
know okay in
when you design a programming language
okay I've seen I mean as as far as
experience goes you know you might have
many experiences with different
programming languages
you notice that okay you know some
languages you know you have expressions
you know statements directives but what
else are there so the question is what
are the possible things that makes up a
makes up a language you know you know
that's an interesting question use the
logical question you know and and what
what makes them you know so you have
statements and expressions okay so what
defines I mean what you know I mean
keeping a language let's say Python we
know what's the difference between
expressions and statements we know and
you know or even in in Java JavaScript
you know hello Java or C we easily we
know we understand what it what's the
difference but what are the you know
abstract definition for them you know
what makes you know what what makes them
what makes them you might be wondering
you know okay so let's go you know if we
think about it we can go one step
further
so apparently expressions are those
things that returns a value and
statements are those things that does
not return a value okay okay
but then we have direct okay so that
seems to make sense
but then we have directives you know
then how does that fit in okay so you
know so far we have you know you know
things that returns the statement
I mean returns a value that's one thing
doesn't return a value that's another
thing okay we call that statement then
we have another thing that's directives
you know okay so and what is that that
okay that that kind of change the
compilers you know how it passes your
code okay so now we have three things so
I mean the question is how can you
formalize this whole
how can you like put the whole the all
these different ideas into a consistent
whole like criterion or you know you
know in other words what are the things
that makes a language that makes up you
know I don't know how do you say it
makes up the maybe semantics of language
you know or you know or the syntax I
mean obviously it's not just purely
syntax because the expression returns a
value that's semantics that's not syntax
so you know what are the things that
composes a language or the language
design so that's my question
so does it does anyone know that so I've
you know I've been studying you know
programming languages and and computer
science you know
I casually you know that's my one of my
interest and and actually I don't know
the answer so let's look up the article
enforceable okay formal definition of
systematic grammar
okay constructed languages computer
languages and their grammar complexity
okay composable syntax okay syntax
algebra okay
syntactic meaning of variable okay now
these articles are all very interesting
I like to talk about them but anyway let
me find the other thing I want to
mention I mean the the the thing I'm
talking about you know the what what
makes up what are the you know the
formal context that makes up you know
the different things in programming
language so I think it's somewhere here
I have an article
okay this one
what is ontology of programming
languages now you you might know the
word ontology means meaning like all the
different things that makes up something
okay let me give you an example for
example if you ask a child you know what
is a car I mean the child can point it
to you that's a car you know that's
that's that's that is a car but if you
ask him what is a sedan what is a coupe
what is a flying car what is a real car
what is a NASCAR
what is a truck what's what's what's a
vampers omnibus automobile
transportation cheap motor car vehicle
he don't know I mean the child would not
know he get confused but you understand
you know you understand the relations
between them you know not NASCAR NASCAR
is actually not a car it's a car race
you know it's a particular car race they
go at NASCAR and so on you know truck
you know the difference is you know a
truck then bus okay truck and van are
you know different type of cars you know
they have different shape you know
different purpose
bus bus is another type of car they have
a different purpose but however truck
then you know truck in van and purse
they are not the same category of words
because bus they purely bus purely
describe the purpose of a car however
truck and van they they are not just
describing the purpose but they also
described the kind of slightly different
shape and things like that you know what
I mean an omnibus is another thing on
omnibus is you know you can refer to a
type of transportation you know type of
public transportation
then this automobile is another context
you know I hope you describe you know
you get idea you know so so I thought
you understand that we interrelations
between them now that's
the ontology you know that's ontology so
we can say you you know you understand
what is a car the child does not
understand what a car
what is a car now similarly that's what
I'm you know one to mention so in
programming languages you know yeah we
know they are different you know you
know I know there are many different
programming languages functional or P or
imperative you know we know per Java you
know JavaScript Python list you know but
you have to understand you know you want
you want if you you know you you go one
step further you want to understand the
relations you know you want to
understand the entire relationship
between them the context you know the
context the word is used which one are
in the same category you know and so on
for example functional programming oh
okay they are kind of priming paradigms
so these two words belong to one
category where you have two branches you
know over here is over here over here is
functional on the other hand expression
and statements they are not programming
paradigms they are like they are a
jargon that describe a particular kind
of elements in programming languages you
know so what I'm saying is that you want
to understand the whole relationship
between all these things and and that's
you know what that's what I call
ontology so from so for me you know
that's you know that's interesting you
know for me so I haven't found you know
so so I mean so this is a direction I'm
going I'm describing you know I'm giving
you the general idea you know what I'm
talking about you know what do you mean
you know so but back to the particular
context you know the expression
statements directives what else are
there and what makes them you know what
defines them I kind of want you know or
like to have you know wish to have some
kind of a formal idea you know but you
so I have you know
know the ideas you know exactly what
makes them you know how can you I mean
for example so is suppose you are
creating a new language is it possible
to create something else that's not
that's other than expression and
statements and directives is it possible
white white when and if not why not you
know you want to find the logical answer
to it you know give the logical answer
like concrete
you know descriptive answer why Cannot
you have something else other than
expressions and statements and
directives you know in order to do that
it prepares you to understand because
you have to you know I'm not able to
give it you know so that's what I'm
getting at you know that's that's my
point you know I wish to you know maybe
some computer science scientist has
written about that you know but you know
it's more study so you know if you are
interested you know if you are
interested in programming languages I'm
guessing you will probably also find
this in this topic interesting we want
to seek answers you know so far from
from what I know my understanding is is
that I cannot describe it well but my
understanding of the situation is that
there is yeah I well there is no there's
no way to describe this or in other
words you have to look from another
perspective to to give a good logical
explanation of what exactly is going on
about these expressions its statements
and directives so I I cannot you know I
cannot give you the answer I got but you
know that's so that's the issue I'm
mentioning so I've been talking for over
one hour now so is there any questions
type it tab it I'm out of drinks and
type type type
so am I making myself I mean is it does
that make sense
say it does it make sense does it not
make sense
is it like totally stupid idea is it too
philosophical I mean decide do you
anything you know it's funny that you
know when you are a speaker you know or
a showman
you know sure you know in showbiz you
know one time I remember back in
Montreal you know like 30 years ago
you know sometimes you see people do
live shows right you know or maybe even
you know power or a dance club or you
know you know singer so you know so they
are singing when you are singing you
know you want to get audience response
so you know even celebrities singers you
know you want to get the audience
response you want to get them you know
to cheer for you
you want them to applaud I mean I mean
for singers as well as speakers you know
like you know if you are giving a talk
at some conference you know about
programming you want to get the audience
interaction because otherwise you know
everyone just see it sit there quiet and
you monologue basically yeah and that's
that's discouraging for discouraging for
you and as well you your audience as
well you want to get them to maybe smile
ah ha ha this is funny you know so they
have like people have all sort of tricks
you know to do that so I remember back
then you know this girl is singing and
then then she says hey today is my
birthday you know something like that
and then they then a crowd you know
responding and have crow who you know
they shout out hoo hoo you know but
actually that's not her birthday you
know that day is not her birthday but
the point is you know they do that I
mean it doesn't matter I mean it's not
like you know you just have to like get
things going you know that's so that's
one thing I noticed so for me languages
can be so there's a common primary
languages
can be at many different levels of
abstraction can the same type of
analysis apply to of all of them I don't
know I think I'm not sure exactly what
you mean but meanwhile I mean the very
topic itself is kind of fuzzy I mean the
things we are talking about so so
programming languages can be at many
different levels of abstraction can the
same type of analysis apply to them or
yeah I don't know it may be we have to
you know show actual examples to talk
about that so you could treat math
notations as a programming language if
it expresses a computation yeah yeah
yeah I think so I don't know if that
answer the question though I don't know
you've had you know yeah I don't I don't
know it's interesting I mean treat math
notations is a programming language yeah
you see you know that's the thing you
know we want you know we are starting to
get programming languages too we are
starting to have I mean in the math
community I mean it's most specifically
the proof systems you know the other
autom automated proof systems or the you
know same semi automatic you know human
help improve systems such as cog GOG
they we began to have perming languages
such as that co co q that help that
that that function not just as a
notation but actually helps compute
helps proofs I mean we I think we I mean
we are starting to have that but the
science of that is still like in the
very early days and that's what I want
to get into you know proof systems by
computer it's it's
that is a huge topic I mean you can
study that for like you know more than
four years that's that's you know you go
to into proof systems and homotopy type
theory let's let's see if I so let's go
to semantic noodle it's such four
so yeah the homotopy type theory is a
new foundation for mathematics that
sprung up in the past ten years it's
pretty new so so how much of you type
theory is for mathematicians you know in
general mathematicians you know the
typical
professional mathematicians they are not
interested in computer rising
mathematics I mean they I mean typically
they are not interesting it you know the
all the professional mathematicians you
know including all the you know the top
you know let's say 1000 the world's top
on you know 1000 madman did it
mathematicians they are not interested
in in computerizing the foundation of
math or you know automated proof systems
but you know some mathematicians there's
a subculture you know they are they are
really trying to push it you know they
are pushed pushing the frontier and then
there is this guy who won rewards who is
a very big hit he died like two years
ago what's his name this guy vadoma
watski he is a field medal winner you
know he created he essentially he
invented the homotopy type theory
because you know he was you know he said
you know before all these he's a
traditional mathematician you know you
know very you know one of the top you
know mathematicians so but he's
interested his interest is to use a
computer to
to do math proofs so he and he tries to
do that via via the traditional way you
know there's a you know foundation of
math there's different branches this
logic is you know you know moto logic
and demon you know different symbolic
logic and predicate logic and so on and
he found that it is essentially
impossible extremely extremely difficult
basically impossible and he realized the
the reason it is almost impossible or
very difficult tremendously you know
difficult is because the traditional
foundation of math via logic or Bertrand
Russell's you know the logic system it's
basically not suitable you know like
wrong you know is is is if you try to do
that it's just extremely difficult so he
created a new foundation for logic you
know so the traditional way is like by a
viral set theory say theory and
predicate logic okay that's the
traditional math foundation so he find
it you know he discovered that just
doesn't work so he created a new
foundation what's what is now called
homotopy type theory so why are this
theory very this foundation you can
actually create you know you write
programs just like we do you know
programming languages you write programs
to actually prove math not just you know
solve an integral or you know find
solution to equations that that's a
different thing we are talking about
proof proving
mathematics you know what mathematicians
do so the so you have this homotopy type
theory it's very interesting to us
programmers also because you know in
recent years this haskell right it
became fairly popular among you know
southern google people functional
programming pushed to the extreme then
you have haskell then but if you are you
know i know i don't actually have
experiencing haskell but but if if you
know Haskell you are learn you know in
Haskell communities they you know you
find you know many issues or problems
you know you cannot do this you know
they are issues in Haskell so so they
are more advancement that there are more
things you know you there are more
directions to explore you know how can
we make it so first Wow so anyway and
there are also languages like well
let's just let me example let me show
the coq is one example now see you coq
is the language to do proofs in
mathematics and if you are high schoo
programa you probably have heard of it
and there is no there are several others
for example there is also let me try to
l here so there is ACTA Idris Martita
I haven't heard of albatross I haven't
heard of so let's look at them so ACTA
is another a new programming language is
kind of like the next generation when I
mean after Haskell so it you know it
tries to you know do something you know
to exploring in one direction and
there's also Idris is somewhat popular
today so it's like it's again another
direction from Haskell you know they try
to push some other things and there are
some some others I haven't heard of
Martita before and I haven't heard of
albatross before so anyway so all these
languages and they also they all have to
do with they also have to do with the
homotopy type theory they are they are
related in many ways I mean you know you
can you can say that homotopy type
theory is their foundation actually you
know in type theory there are many
branch
of type theory homotopy type theory is
one of them I think roughly and as you
know Haskell is very strongly typed
language is based on you know idea the
type theory in math so anyway so this
direction there's this lots of things to
do you know lots lots of things to learn
and research you know it's ongoing and
I'm very interested in this and I'm I'm
you know I'm trying to study it it's not
easy to read this by the way now by the
way homotopy type theory now if you are
a programmer if you are coming from a
programmers background yeah you wouldn't
understand the thing you you you will
need to you will need to yeah well I'm
this is probably probably not the book
for you but anyway what I'm trying to
say also I'm what I'm trying to say is
that much of a type theory is actually
if you are a traditional mathematician
let's say you have a master's degree at
least okay at least in math majoring in
math then you can you can try to read
homotopy type theory then then you you
know you you might get something out of
it and also this is also related to
category theory I don't know much about
category theory but I've tried to study
it it's basically it's not really it's
not something I'm too interested but on
the other hand the type theory and
homotopy type theory I'm much more
interested you know the category theory
I also you know it's like the Haskell
guys they are everyday is that go
category theory category theory is kind
of like the I don't like it too much
I've tried to look into it part you know
part of the reason I don't like it is is
that you know this pop you know pops you
know popular you know this fashion you
know it's it's it's one of the fashion
things among the Haskell coders and in
general what happened when you
when something becomes fashionable
becomes pop popularized you know what
happens is that basically all the things
that shows up online about it is all
just garbage
no because they are created by this you
know fashion you know people kids or you
know they don't know nothing about math
they don't have the background but the
you know they read one thing Oh
everything is a mod you know everything
is a is a a you know a category theory
so you end up you know all these
articles online that pops up every day
every day you know it's basic up
basically garbage okay so let me read a
few comments in nothing I think they'll
be here today is so we got a few
comments now it's not my birthday yay
integral is
[Laughter]
Dion Dion says mathematicians trying to
computerize mathematics would be like
factory workers pushing for robotic
factories that's true actually I never
thought of that
yeah that's really interesting I never
yeah it's it's amazing to me actually
how you know why I haven't thought of
that before yeah in the tradition of
mathematicians they don't like you know
they don't like the computerized
foundation of math I mean it's has it
has been like for - for 200 or 300 years
you know the you know in philosophy of
mathematics you know one of the guy
Bertrand Russell
he is a guy who pushes for what is
called logic largest ISM and there's
also Hubert he is his idea of formalism
both of these are trying to push
mathematics into some kind of mechanical
form you know they want to reduce math
you know the mathematics into some kind
of mechanical form like a computer
language you know so they began this
philosophy you know
Hubert formalism you can look at you can
look it up let me just type it hubert
formalism
yeah formalism philosophy of mathematics
and you can also type our us s e-g IC is
M Bertrand Russell logic logis ISM here
on Wikipedia so they are they are two of
the major philosophies of mathematics I
mean everything's got a philosophy you
know almost I mean in math I mean the
philosophy of math is about you know why
for example why is math valid why does
it just walk what is the nature of math
in what in what direction or style of
math should we go into you know maybe
this kind of thinking will push us you
know further we will benefit us more you
know things like that you know that's
that's the philosophy of mathematics you
know you know people study that so
anyway Bertrand Russell is a the almost
the father or the proponent Bertrand
Russell this guy is of logis ism he
believes that the entire mathematics can
be reduced to logic you know like like
you know if if if if men are stupid and
I'm a man therefore I'm stupid
you know that's logic you know things
like that so he believes that the whole
math can be reduced to met logic and
Hubert formalism by this Hilbert guy he
the philosophy is that math math has no
meaning math is simply just manipulating
of the manipulation of you know symbols
like a sequence of symbols like a
programming language you know so you
know see speech so anyway so these are
the early days like 300 years ago you
know so they began these ideas and there
are many schools they pursue it they try
to push it you know they try to create
more theories about it and eventually
then we have the idea of proof you know
made automatic you know improved systems
then we have Haskell we have you know
we have predicate logic we have symbolic
logic we have modal logic you know
things squirrel you know that's how we
study you know the you know the field of
knowledge then we have in programming
then we have lambda calculus then we
have typed lambda calculus then we have
you know we also have type theory then
someone created Lisp you know which is
based on math you know least bits then
we have scheme then we have you know
based on lambda calculus we have then we
have Haskell which is based on a pure
kind of money they want more pure form
of functions lambdas you know then you
have terms rewriting systems you know
which is like Mathematica and you have
graph that you know so all these things
you know that's how we get here today
then today you know we have then few
years ago we have the homotopy type
theory then we have category theory
about 30 about 30 or 40 years ago
category theory category theory which
can also serve as a foundation of math
then we have you know then the latest is
this
this is speaketh a big thing homotopy
type theory I really I wish to learn it
I wish to actually know it before I die
you know I give you know I give myself
five five more years let's see how I do
so yeah okay it's a few more questions
let's see it's weird that set theoretic
foundation should be so difficult for
computers to reason with ya know there's
some these problems you know way ok so
last year when I was studying this for
example there's one simple example I can
explain why the set theory foundation of
math that just doesn't work you cannot
make
you cannot turn it into programming
languages you cannot you just can't
there's one seem very simple example let
me show you group theory now group
theory is the most basic part of algebra
the most fundamental part of math let's
see so well you don't have to know it to
understand one what I'm talking about
but I'm going to give you an example you
will see what I mean
if know if you don't know already so let
me find a good face where I can show
this ok so now I know you may or may not
know group theory but basically here is
a definition a group is a set G together
with an operation dot code the group law
good called the group law of G ok so
it's a set and operation that combines
any two elements in the set to form a
new element so that's a group but
however the operation must satisfy the
following four things one is closure
wines associate TVT one is identity
element
another one is inverse element now you
know you don't have to go into detail
but let's look at one of them let's say
inverse element okay so inverse element
it says for each element a in G there
exist an element P in G such that 8 RP
equals to P dot a equals to e and E is
an identity element ok I forgot to
mention identity element but anyway the
point here is that it says for each a in
G
exist something P in G such that such
that you know some equation holds now
notice the word they exist now if you
are going to define a group in a
programming language you know you Gong
you are going to define a group this
word exists is problematic you cannot
define basically you cannot you know you
cannot define something there exist you
know what it's like what do you mean
they exist
you know like try it you know you know
you got me the group definition you know
you you might want to learn Google Fiat
you know groups you know there are many
intro is about Google theory you know
you read a few page but anyways with a
definition it's very very simple it's
just you know it's just a set with an
operation and the operation if the
operation satisfy these four things then
it's a group then what do you do with it
you know there's a lot you know group
theories is one of the most fundamental
thing in in math so so you can see the
definition but if you try to define your
own programming language there is this
thing there exists that's you know that
they are throw throws you off you cannot
do it you know you just basically you
cannot do it you well you might be able
to do it for finite groups that is the
set G is finite especially if it's small
you know 100 elements you know maybe you
can try to check every element you know
to see if it exists or not but groovy is
also valid for infinite elements let's
say the set of all integers so you see
there are problems with the definition
there exist but however this definition
is a traditional definition based on set
theory so in set theory you know the
traditional mathematician you can say
there exist okay whether there exists or
not you know you know you don't have to
compute it you just can say okay it
exists you know so it works there but it
doesn't work if you want to use
computers try to you know automate this
definition
so this there exists is with the one of
the essential problem so that's that's
part of the reason for the existence of
the homotopy type theory you know this
is one of the thing that doesn't work
so in homotopy type theory or others
okay I don't know the subject myself but
basically they you know math you know
mathematicians who tries to computerized
math they discovered you know the
problems like like this so they create
so instead of there exist they create
another way which is equation 'l anyway
they use equations instead so instead of
there exist they have a function they
define a function such a one argument
function they define a function that if
it returns this then then it qualifies
you know there exists you know things
like that so that's one of the ways I
mean actually you can actually read it I
mean you can see it in Wikipedia if you
start to read about type theory and and
logic actually in group theory maybe
they say you know they I mean they are
like literally a few thousand articles
but you will see it you know if you
explore the topic
fetches idea of sins okay I'll check it
out I don't know I don't know what is
this about since in reference in the
philosophy of language the distinction
between sense and reference okay that's
I think this is philosophy the realm of
philosophy proper it's okay there's some
okay anyway so I think okay you might be
right Dion Dion yeah
there exists X X such that Y something X
in sense Y as a reference yeah you might
be right I don't know I don't know how
much about this subject
I'm learning it so thank you guys for
coming keep the conversation going
you know like my video or share it with
friends
I'll see you next time bye