good evening welcome to another episode
of saw talk show and today I'm going to
do a live coding of JavaScript I'm going
to use a look at this page look at this
page you see so this stage is about
arrow keys efficiency vim hjkl versus
ijkl you know how in vim you know the
editor vim you use the hjkl keys as
arrow keys kusa movement keys but
however a typical arab position you know
on a standard pc keyboard is like
inverted T so and that maps to ijkl on
QWERTY layout ijkl so you are wondering
you know which one is more efficient is
hjk out like the vim style or ijkl so we
are going to find out and so on this
page in my essay you can find it on the
web
here's a URL here's my local version
sorry that info it's just such such the
title then so we are going to find out
and on this page I have an essay that
discuss how do you compute the
efficiency that you know how do you
calculate the fish efficiency and you
can see you know I give you you know
basically you assign your score to each
key based on the is to press the key for
example the index finger and pointing
finger would be would have highest score
and also keys on the home row such as
you know JKL will have higher score and
for the I for the key I you have to move
your finger up so that's lower score for
the key edge you have to move your index
you're pointing finger index finger to
the left so that's even lower score so
basically you assign a score to each key
you know the higher score means it's
easier to press so obviously K would be
the highest have the higher score you
know
so you're saying up score to each key
then then then then then basically
that's it I mean well also you assign
the frequency of the need to press those
keys for example from my Emacs
statistics gathered from several people
the most pressed key are the down arrow
key then that's about seventy 17% of all
commands the second less the the second
most-used arrow key is the previous line
you know the up key which used for 15%
then the left arrow and right arrow are
relatively relatively low you know they
have left arrow is three percent red
arrow is five percent something so you
multiply the frequency of the the need
for the arrow key by the score of that
key then you sum that you sum it up you
add them up then what you get is the
total score for a particular arrangement
you know the fish efficiency you know
for the key binding so yeah again the
question is whether the VIS beams key
binding hjkl
is more efficient or less efficient than
ijkl for up-down left-right so this page
you know i give the formula then i you
have this javascript code you can copy
it and paste in your browser and you can
find out this find out the answer for
example let's copy it so copy the code
and in in firefox i press command option
i to get me to the console the browser
console and i just paste the code the
javascript code then i press enter then
you can you see the then it prints VI
score is three thirty six point
something and inverted T score is 36
point something so according to this
calculation to this formula they are
about the same efficiency but however it
is not true if you you know so according
to this formula it's about the same
however you can adjust if you adjust the
command frequency but because that's
that varies a little bit but anyway one
thing interesting interesting is that if
you make the up-down left-right
frequency or equal then the then the
then the inverted inverted T actually
wings for example let me show you let's
try that for example the command
frequency okay let's reassign the
numbers to or to 1 so 1 1 1 1 and run it
in browser ok how you assign it new
numbers now I run these two lines to get
me the score of the let's see so now I
run these two lines
okay copy them and go to browser and
paste it now you can see the VI score is
three point zero nine the inverted T
score is three point four so inverted T
is actually more efficient and actually
if you consider other issues such as by
grams
such as the frequency of pressing two
consecutive arrow keys not repeating the
same key so for example when you play
pac-man you move you you want to turn
right when you are going up you turn
left for example so you press up and
left
so is that would that be easier on the
ijkl would or would it be easier on the
VIMS
h hjkl so you have to consider by grams
now if you can see the by grams then
then the inverted T key binding is a
kiss becomes even more efficient so in
general the VI key binding that
tradition is actually not as good
compared to inverted T so I got for
people watching great a lot comment
already let me pop the comments out and
let's see what they are but okay so let
me let me talk about one more thing okay
so on this page so so you you notice
that when we want to compute the skull
you know we suppose we want to change
the frequency oh if you want to assign a
keys a different number to the key score
it's kind of tedious so what I'm going
to do today is to create a JavaScript
web application like you have input
boxes where you just type the numbers
and you know then then the score will
show as you type the numbers as you
change in numbers you know interactively
so that's what I'm going to do today you
know so if you
do not know JavaScript you know if you
have no idea about web applications this
is a good video to watch you know good
opportunity to to learn something
something about JavaScript and even if
you have no interest in JavaScript it's
still a good good thing to learn you
know as a programmer it's a curiosity to
see how things works you know the web
application okay so let me I'm going to
do that today it will be thirty minutes
I think should should be done holus I
hope so
so let me check the comments come Oni
Isaac
good morning break the loop good morning
so break the loop says I went shopping
for a good Mouse today at Fry's
Electronics oh that's good and it's hard
to find a good mouse that takes
everything I'm looking for I've been
using your mouse page as a guide okay
what I'm trying to say is that the mouse
market is a bad state right now feels
like a stagnant market really I don't
get that sense though I think why I mean
it seems to me the mouse market is
primarily driven by gaming market gamers
you know and and game cameras been
thriving for the past 10 years so
because you know that you know the
gamers you know they are thriving you
know lots of youtubers you know Kemah
they make youtube videos and they become
millionaires that's quite a few of them
what they do is paying play games all
day
so anyway gamers and also the mechanical
keyboard today's it has become
incredibly popular since about five
years ago
okay so mechanical keyboard is extremely
popular and part of the reason also has
a lot to do with gamers because skimmers
is a man that drives the market you know
the he cameras usually you know
teenagers they want to play
they have money I don't know where their
money came from your their parents or
whatever they have money they play games
you know and they buy keyboards and so
they and my mechanical keyboard became a
thing now of course many programmers
such as us or me you know for example we
are also very much into keyboards and
mechanical keyboard is is a good one but
however you know you feel if you compare
the number of programmers to gamers it's
like one to ten or one two hundred more
likely one two hundred for each
programmer you have 100 gamers or even
more so so it is a gamers that drives
the market for Mouse and mechanical
keyboards and also so a lot this I think
is failure we could say they're recent
reasonably a lot innovation in Mouse you
know they dig chemists they they they
want fancy technology and not some
pattern so so why so let me read break
the loops question so sorry did you go
anywhere last weekend when you were
offline
yes so why so what is the problem with
your finding the right mouse for you I
mean is there anything in particular you
are not finding the right mouse for you
so last week so I was offline for two
weeks okay so and I went to Las Vegas
with my roommate you know my roommate I
have been to Las Vegas like 15 years ago
back in 2005 or something i back yeah
2005 or 2006 so it's like 13 years ago
and so I went to you know back then you
know I I did the talk show like last
week talking about Las Vegas I'm not
sure you are here but anyway so Las
Vegas you know I wrote a blog that's the
interesting topic sorry
Las Vegas okay just such folks are DDoS
Vegas you'll find my website Las Vegas
travelogue a encompassing travelogue on
the city of cinn okay so I was there in
2003 and I stayed in a motel for like
about four days so during that four days
I visited almost every big hotel casinos
and I you know go inside I take photos I
take photos of all the statues and all
the all the lamps
you know lamps is one of the fascinating
thing you know all the statues in and in
lighting fixtures why lighting fixtures
because lighting fixtures is one of the
most fascinating thing you know you know
there's a chandelier you know which is a
fancy fancy lighting fixture anyway
lighting fixture fixtures you know
lighting or light bulb so you know
different lighting technologies such as
today's LED or you know fluorescent or
you know that always fascinates me so so
when I went to other casinos and took
photos of different sculptures lighting
fixtures you see these different lamps
lamps they are very very you know they
look they're delicate you know Depp and
decorated you know fancy lighting
fixtures and all the sculptures and I
try also try to find out what those
sculptures represent you know for
example if it's a replica of Roman god
or Roman goddess you know in in Caesars
Palace you know which is one of the
casino you can see here Caesars Palace
you know Monte Carlo Aladdin Caesars
Palace you know you got several
sculptures of gods and goddesses so
anyway I was talk about these Las Vegas
last week or so in another episode of
soccer but anyway so yeah I was there in
2003 and you know I stayed for four days
and I gambled of course you know I'm a
schizoid and I am a nerd and I you know
so when I Campbell is well it's it's
like a typical ski so yeah unlike normal
people okay so what I can go is like
kind of like a mathematic logicians
mindset you know I don't really get
excited about you know I don't get
emotional you know rather I can but I
just want to win so so anyway I did
gamble
I studied the you know different
gambling stuff you know the arts you
know used of course involves statistics
and probability which is math and that
excites me so anyway I gambled actually
you know among other games in casino the
the best arts if you if your soul is to
win okay the best game to play is the is
craps
there's a game called craps where you
throw two dice is you know which is
actually one of the most I think is one
of the most popular game showing in
movies you know you thought to dices
penny way it's called craps so back then
in 2003 I won like three one one few
thousand dollars I forgotten you know a
couple of thousand dollars but today but
anyway so my roommate they are from
China so they haven't been to Las Vegas
and they want to go so they you know
they took me so I went with them and you
know so I revisited Las Vegas and things
have changed of course now of course the
social justice the rise of the social
justice has consequences of course you
know woman's write and write this in
that
so back then you can see this MGM Grand
the theme of MGM Grand
the Casino Hotel back in 2003 is
basically your slaves you know so you
got these you know and I would say it's
rather beautiful okay you know just in
case by the way slaves are a tradition
of you know Asian times in um for
example but anyway so so the MGM Grand
Casino Hotel their theme was basically
you can say it's kind of slaves look at
this you know muscular guy holding a
lamp for you and you know and then you
have that you know then you have that
then you have that then you have that so
I went there you know just to check how
things are whether things have changed
so all these are good you don't have
this anymore and and also you see this
lady dancing on tabletops so back back
in 2003 in Las Vegas you have quite a
lot of ads like these you know kind of
very attractive sexualized females you
know whether it's dancing or whether
it's something else you know there's a
lot by the way of course Las Vegas is
known for showgirls and you know so
there are lots of these ads or
billboards
you know so-called billboards over the
face you know showing ladies in stuff
and that is also good you don't see that
anymore
and but in general so in general so you
know you don't have these things anymore
because you know I suppose because due
to the you know you know I do to
feminism stuff you know you know the
rights this ain't that
by the way by the way let me just say
that they are they disappeared however
of course the sexuality sexuality and
prostitution and all the very the
essence of these things lives you know
of course they live they thrive more the
far more more than ever they just hidden
from the surface that's what the social
justice can you know they that's what
they do are doing they want these things
disappear from the surface but
underneath it's evermore in you know
just like like you know like PN okay I'm
not gonna say the word but just like the
PN they they you know four letters or
you know abbreviation of something
something nog Rafi okay that is thriving
more than ever two times three times ten
times you know and anyway so so so back
to the LasVegas change so these things
are gone on the surface and you don't
see you know ladies anymore but but some
of these are still there for example
anyway so the over my overall impression
is that it kind of it actually became
Las Vegas you know it it is crass to
begin with because Las Vegas is you know
the city you know you might say it's a
city of sin you know with respect to
conservatives you know with respect to
religious people it's a city of sin you
know the the the the dark corner does
the seed you know the agree things you
know kind of things like that so but on
the superficially it's it's like a
beautiful in love
curious for example like you know they
have replicas you know they have Luxor
Hotel which is which is a pyramid you
know a modern building in a shape of a
pyramid they emulate the Egyptian
pyramids with you know the Luxor Hotel
so they they also got a Sphinx
you know like a minute miniature you
know so they emulate you know the
Egyptian you know you know the Asian
Egyptian stuff then you got you got for
example Caesars Palace you know you have
replicas of all these woman famous
sculptures
you know Asian sculptures 1000 years ago
2,000 years ago you know they are
replicas you know modern replicas and
you can you have this Venetian Hotel
Venetian Hotel which is a kind of
miniature emulation of Venus you know
the Venus scenery in Europe you know you
have this they had a coded gondolas so
you know so but all these are just cheap
emulations you know they are they are
truly they are just cheap modern
technological emulations of the you know
of the great auto history you know of
the past so Las Vegas is crass that's
the word you describe it
let's see crass I think that's the
that's the word the proper word
definition of crass okay so definition
of crass means without refinement
delicacy or sensitivity he exactly was
obtuse stupid yes that that's what to
describe Las Vegas you know on the
surface it's all shiny and luxurious you
know hey money money is doing the
talking you have money you go there you
live in fancy hotels you know girl's
deliver food to your door or to your
your mouth and you know oh these mini
miniatures sculptures miniatures you
know replicas of ancient you know old
art or stuff yeah but it's it's all just
a show as the you know show the show
business but look at how much money they
spend this Bellagio hotel okay but at
your hotel is known with this huge
artificial lake in front of the building
you see you see how big is this lake it
is you know if you walk from one end to
the other end you know take ten minutes
15 minutes so you know so it's big so
but by the way Las Vegas is in is is a
taste desert you know it's in the middle
of a desert but however they you you
know they put money to be all this
artificial lake you find you know Lakes
like these over Las Vegas like beautiful
fountains you know with water flowing
smoothly sometimes like over the world
like this one for example for example
this is for example this one this
surface you see this fish-scale surface
they are covered by water you know just
a very thin water so as a engineer to be
honest you have to make sure you know
the water does not you know the water
must cover all the surface so you it
must be very level and and the surface
must not have any any flaws like it must
be smooth you know you you want to
ensure that when the water overflows the
entire flat surface it covers the entire
surface you know I don't know how much
water is evaporated but to be sure you
know I know it's very expensive because
Las Vegas
is desert it's very dry you know so but
you know it's a business and it's a show
business so anyway yeah Las Vegas is
crass and it's cheap but however today
compared to 13 you know compared to 2003
it's worse okay it was the so on the
surface the women things like sexy women
on Bo boats
those are good like I don't see it
anyway I don't see it you don't see it
much anymore the showgirls you know
there are lots of showgirls shows for
example in you know what Jubilee Jubilee
is one of the famous you know showgirls
you know they showgirls but basically
they take off their clothes you know
it's like a striptease strip dancing but
with some kind of dance and singing you
know it's called cabaret you know well
depending on the style sometimes called
cabaret you know if they have some
comedy and stuff so anyway so Las Vegas
you have these showgirls you know it's a
show where these girls half-naked girls
dance and sing they are quite a few but
it's still there of course these kind of
things are still there but however you
just don't see the advertisements you
know as much before so anyway so so yeah
and today's our Las Vegas it has become
more crass in the tip oh my god the
tourists you know tourists is kind of
like this despicable you know I I kind
of despised to is you know like you know
that first well first of all there are
normal people
okay then they go there you know they
you know nothing has spent their money
they they go wow well lots of tourists
of course and they are all dressed
TV you know ya know like no coffee and
they don't you know they go there they
spend their money they have fun so did i
gamble this time well yeah I gambled
$100 on a roulette you know put your
money down black or red and I won so and
that's it so I took the hundred dollars
and that's it what did my room a think
well it's fun for them I mean they are
not nerds okay they are not nerd know
are they programmers I mean they are
they are what you might call blue label
label laborers blue label workers so
they work in restaurants they are not
you know they don't they don't have a
college degree for example so you know
they go they all have fun so he drove
you know my roommate drove we stayed in
a motel so that's enough about Las Vegas
I mean unless unless you guys have
questions I mean let's maybe we should
go get back to the JavaScript thing
let's see six people watching okay so
let me read some comments so did you go
anywhere yeah okay so let me read the
comments hi Zack say sorry but I hate
mechanical keyboards I can not
concentrate for my life when my roommate
uses it that's too bad
well they make noises noises so well the
best thing is to not have roommates you
know make money move out
our house by the way how old are you
exact but like what oh yeah you are
student right yeah so eventually you
know you will have your own house buy a
big house go make yourself a millionaire
you know as a programmer you have the
you have what it takes
and Norman says I visited Las Vegas in
1990s and early 2000s for computer
conference now fantasize see I'm not a
gambler though yeah I'm not a gambler
neither you know I don't you know I
don't gamble right you'd you know and
Ikes
you know a lot of people for example
they are gambler addicts
you know gamblers you know they have to
like actually one of my roommate is like
that oh my god he's you know he has
whatever money if he go to a casino he
gambled oh and here he have no like like
until he has no 1 cent left then he
started to try to borrow money from from
you my I have another roommate he's like
that and actually it seems like a lot
Chinese people into gambling like more
in kind then let's say Westerners you
know some for some reason Chinese people
they have a lot of them they are more
somehow they are addicted to or they are
into gambling so like if you go to Las
Vegas you see a large Chinese or Asian
people
Oh so ho consumer electronics so
opposite of that they used to have adult
Expo I see yeah well yeah I said you
know I supposedly those are still you
know going hung there all the time like
the point industry you know they they
always have things you know it's not
going away the point uh streets like ten
times more than you know i i've been
observing okay that's just okay i'm not
going to talk about that topics but
anyway i being absurdly it since since
let's say fifteen you know thirty years
ago
and and you know it just grow and grow
and grow and in fact you know if you
look at the celebrities today
celebrities on stage you know all the
big stars female stars they are
basically you know the way they dress
it's it's it's more you know it's yeah
yeah i'm not sure i'm gonna talk about
that but you know it's small it's more
than half naked these these singers you
know this today that's today's situation
you know yeah marco yeah my roommate is
actually from that area my you know they
from china but let's get back to
actually we already kind of like spend a
lot of time on the las vegas in 30
minutes okay so in next 30 minutes
let's hope to finish this let's call
this javascript thing shall we let's see
so let's go to a keyboard I mean I want
to go to my let's go to this page and
let's start to create the application so
open the page open the page and
okay first of all let's make a
JavaScript code so let's see go to the
directory change it to J's link of Phi
and okay I don't want to long a name
okay so open it
create new same rows so he
you
kill it and close it and open the
javascript file paste it here okay and
close it and remove that showing browser
okay so I have kind of I have removed
the code in fact the code lives in this
JavaScript file now if I run if I open
this in Safari let's see so I go here
let's close of re-entry because I don't
want to open too many browsers so I go
here I paste the URL open the page and
open the console you can see it prints
know you know the it computes the skal
VI score is this and inverted TISCO is
that you know it's actually running the
JavaScript code that's good
so what I want to do now is actually I
want to create input boxes so people can
input the numbers so so input the boxes
so I am gonna let's see input okay now I
don't remember the HTML form in order to
have input boxes you need to have HTML
form so I go to my website
Tom's scripting tutorial and HTML form
and go to input tag okay
then I copy that okay so put it here
let's magnify okay and so I have input
and jjjj
TJ Tex max length max length 1 2 3 4
name username name is KJ j okay
same as ID value is let's say so I need
the input box so let's see value is J is
0.9 okay now show in browser let's see
what it does
there he you can can you see that there
it is the input box so I created one
input box and now in JavaScript I just
need to capture that and put that value
here okay so let's see the comment
so okay so value is so key key ID so how
do I get the value so I on the HTML I
have this input form which lets people
put in numbers and in JavaScript I need
to capture that input form so what I
want to do is now get element from ID
okay wait okay okay I don't remember
what it is so let's go back to Tom's
scripting get elements by ID that's
right so get element by ID okay and
documents okay good element by ID and
the ID which will be that one okay and
let J J equals through that okay JJ uh
box JJ okay let's say parks J okay so
get element by ID what that does is
actually that grabs this HTML element
then the value would be box J dot value
I think
does anyone okay so do you guys code
JavaScript I guess you guys don't cuz
him in few of my videos when I talk
about JavaScript you know he people
becomes quiet
I know break the roof did some
JavaScript but so anyway so I got a
element they I want to get a value so
how do I do that
so let's go back to dumb scripting
tutorial then I have an introduction
change not content let's see
anyway I don't remember so let's one
easy way is to look at my existing code
then I can just you know that's so go to
Unicode site go to the diet directory so
such Ford rjs okay unicode pop up such
again so that's the one so get element
by ID and dot value that is it there dot
value so so dot value will return the
value so actually so actually I can put
it here you know so actually that we
walk I'm pretty sure so let's try it
so back to the Chrome browser and let's
show the console
so now let's reload let's reload ok
let's try eight okay it doesn't work
because there is no checking of the
event I need to check the event but
anyway so but anyway let's just
duplicate these so high JKL high JKL
okay so
i J hi JK hell edge
okay hi JK i hi j KL h and i j k l inch
so that gets me the elements of course
we need to add elements here paste paste
paste actually i j k l edge
okay let's showing browser great now you
can see we got these boxes now the name
is incorrect let's put the name key i
okay
GJ
okay so wait you need to close that okay
TJ hi JK hell inch so go back to browser
reload okay now that's better now again
there is something let's make it a list
okay go back to browser reload that's
better i j k l h okay
and now let's change the values so i j i
is 0.8 by default okay so by default 0.8
j is 0.9 okay k is 1 okay
case 1 l is 0.7 okay h is 0.5 okay and
let's reload let's see the score will be
different okay
should be no okay something is wrong
type text size 20 size should be size
should be 4 so size means the width of
the text display so let's say 4 helps
wait
okay and value
oh yeah yeah so the score remains the
same because we did not change the
numbers but however let's see if we
change the numbers for example let's
make H key heavy penalty so instead of
instead of 0.1 let's make it 0.1 you
know heavy penalty for moving the
fingers sideways so and refresh okay I'm
not sure it worked so yeah it didn't
work obviously because we did not change
we did not change the value here yet so
let's do that
copy
okay so box ijk i j k hell inch okay
let's try it again
yay so it actually worked
you see now user can actually change the
numbers and recompute so but however if
you if I change the number here let's
say if I change to one there is no event
I did not set up a event so that when I
press ENTER it will recompute it I
didn't do that B so so therefore it does
not recompute so I need to do that in
order to do that we need to so you need
to set up a event listener but first of
all let's see how we're gonna do this
so command frequency let's remove that
so um submit on submit we don't want to
answer it unchanged we want to so ever
this these value changes we should do a
computation so so we want to set up a
event so that so when it when the value
changes we want to call the function to
compute it so actually so let's yeah so
let's do that add event okay
add event listener okay and box I okay
event listener and I think it's
unchanged so now we need to look at the
event name to see which one is for
change you know Tom you know web
scripting the Dom is a mess so what is
an event name so let's see you know
there are hundreds of kind of events a
mouse mouse click mouse Hoover you know
Mouse left button push the mouse left
button up you know and write that a
middle button and you know score scoring
all kind of change window size
everything is an event so right now our
task is to get event name when a value
changed so we can find that by let's see
don't dumb what is object longer add
remove event handler so let's see here
so I have a link here list of event
names which is a Mozilla page you know
Mozilla is good in this way there are
hundreds of events you know so let's see
resource events no network events no
focus events no WebSocket session
history CSS animation CSS transition
form events
yes but text text composition view event
creep or event key event
massive and drag-and-drop event media
event progress even storage event up
event value change event here so let's
see which one value change so big break
the loop says there are some very
expensive poker games yeah on line 5 I
think you are getting the wrong item an
ID for box I oh thank you yeah you are
right
IJ Koh okay
so event at event let's add event
okay that's not hit I remember it's
something on change has changed input
has changed
okay yeah it's input so value name event
name is input and wait what oh and here
is a function so function so compute
okay so here's our function name so now
we have set up a event for the Box I so
when it changes the it will call the
function computes call and we need to
define our function so let's see let's
say arrow it's me okay so arrow function
constant arrow function okay computes go
and it takes no arguments and what it
does is okay it basically does this
console on let us just say that for now
okay so when when this function is
called you just print to the console
about the scores that's good that should
do it
let's try it so this is sparks I so
let's go back to browser and see if it
works
reload okay uncut reference arrow
computes Co is not defined that's
correct because if you are using arrow
function there is no hosting there is no
name hosting meaning that you need to
put this before you call it you know the
function definition must happen before
you call it but also I think I got the
name wrong yes computer school let's
let's do that
well yeah okay so so we got compute
score wait wait wait hold on a second
it's oh yeah computes go away print
let's print it let's say print it
so when the event changes it will call
printed and the printed actually will
that's right the printed function will
actually call the computes call function
to actually computer school so that
should be it so if we reload reference
arrow printed is not defined oh yeah
again we need to move to the top
remember so let's move it to the top we
need to actually put it here and move
the event to the bottom so now go back
to the browser reload now let's try to
change this okay zero point eight let's
say oh it worked
let's say zero point let's say wait 11
okay the event is walking because
whenever it changes it does a print
however for some reason the value is not
changing because we probably made an
error here the value is not changing
because it's not taking the value 11
there
[Music]
oh yeah so I think I know why okay so
because it's not being updated because
once this document get get element by ID
then you get the value here assigned to
the key school the key score variable
hash table never gets updated so what
you need to do is actually you need to
well one way to do is you know one way
to do is is is to take out the whole
thing and put it here you know for
example and see like that you know we
are let's try it
reload
okay uncaught reference arrow Kisco is
not defined okay Kisco is not defined
yeah because of obviously okay so let's
put the compute score inside the
function - now we are you know now we
are right now we are not concerned about
correct code code structure or
architecture you know we just want to
get it to work you know just put
everything wherever you know so it works
then we are think about you know about
the structure and stuff
so now reload now let's change it to
nine it worked yes you see let's change
it to 11
you see now the inverted TISCO is 194
it's way above so you see so this means
if we assign a key I so suppose the the
key I ISM is so easy to press that it's
it's score is like 10 times more than
the others it's you know then then the
inverted T arrangement key binding we
will be like four times better than the
than the VI way okay so that works now
what we need to do is to add more events
so we we only add event to one of the
Box you know the box I so we need to add
4 ijk as well so i j k pitch so that now
we can change any of these number in
your work
so if key k is 11 now we also got a
different score so now you see now if we
change all of them to the same
number let's say one let's see what's go
we get one one one one
you see wait
no that's not right something is wrong
because if if the ease of kisko oh that
yeah that's right okay so if all the
keys have the same score is oppressed
and of obviously doesn't matter how you
bind the keys they they have the same
score that's right
so reload so we've done that actually so
this is not done this is like only half
done so we also need to add these input
boxes for command frequency so that
users can adjust you know what you know
depending on his or her you know his way
of thinking which key is used more often
you know depending on his statistics so
so people can adjust that command
frequency then that's good basically
yeah we need to do that but yeah well
this well it won't take too long
actually I think I don't think so we you
know right now we are just doing this
quickly but we eventually we need to
refine it for for example so that these
boxes are aligned in in the in the shape
of the layout you know i j k l an edge
over here so that you know so it's
easier to see also you'll be nice to
plot a graph or chart you know when
people type automatically plotted like
two bars the higher higher means better
but anyway let's fix this key i
frequency so so let's see i
okay okay so I added formal boxes for
key frequency okay so I need to adjust
that if AFR equ E&C
Y space and actually not there
so you can see key frequency and we need
to adjust the key frequency let's do
that
so keep command frequency up down left
right so actually all these are wrong
left left left right right right right
up down left right so switch to browser
reload you see we have creep key
frequency for up down left right that's
correct and what should be what should
be the numbers the default numbers they
should be something like that let's
let's say let's say fifteen seventeen
three five fifteen seventeen three five
point five okay refresh browser okay now
now you see when we refresh your browser
it doesn't do a computation we actually
need to call it code printed one time to
compute it so actually it's code here so
printed code the function you know so
back to browser refresh you see now it
works so now let's try to change so
let's say up key is used
99 times okay now we again we need to
add events this is you know coding
coding is so much work so event let's
add more events yeah we don't care about
efficiency right now let's just you know
get the prototype to work so event add
event listener
this would be box okay so before we can
add event actually we need to add yeah
we need to add the type elements to get
their ID so okay more more work then
okay so so up down basically up down
left right so actually let's delete the
key Frank frequency so it's simpler up
down left right so this will be up down
left right
left so now we got the elements then we
need to add event for them okay event so
up down left right so you be up down
left right so let's hope it works
refresh yes now let's try to change the
up to 19 yes wait let's try to 900 no it
didn't work because the value did not
get updated that is because obviously
because we did not update it here so
what we need to do is to go here command
frequency cut it and put it here that's
right
I'm using kasaa JavaScript mod and I did
not implement automatic indentation so
yet so that's why I'm doing it manually
so anyway so this will be up value okay
so this will be up down left right okay
that should be that should work refresh
now let's try change up to 99 yes
now let's try change down to 99 key
frequency let's change left to 99 okay
now let's change right to 1992 you see
when when the key frequency is all the
same for up down left right you know if
you don't assign frequency to the keys
then then again the inverted T will be
much more efficient than the VI the VI
style H hjkl
so in general that basically the VI
style is is less efficient the inverted
T is more efficient but anyway so so far
so far that is you know we have actually
we pretty much have this done let's see
for watching well ok so we have this
code done what is left is to actually
pretty okay we need to pretty it up
actually you know it's not proper to use
the console for output you need to add a
count you know you need to add
the output on the page not you know not
in a console console is just for
debugging so so let's so let's do that
quickly it can be easily done so let's
go back to the HTML page and all we have
to do is just add one more tag for
school so so I'm gonna do a dive okay
and this is display display VI school
okay let's say that okay so I added this
element type element and the score will
be displayed you know over here and in
vertical okay so and the in vertical we
would be displayed over here and they
will so these are IDs okay and back to
JavaScript's then I need to get admin
again VI this way okay let's just
simplify this for na VI this right here
okay
and this way VI
okay now we got these two elements which
are these in that and the reason we want
to grab the element is that we can when
we displace coal we can put a value
there instead of instead of trending to
the console so these two lines we all
need to change its so VI ska so let's
just say okay VI score is
inverted t-score is okay and and so is
anyone still watching
am i like doing good am i doing good
so display that VI in a text in a text
in a text okay equals to that's it
and this rate here in at x equals two
that's it I hope it works yep
[Music]
so let's reload reload okay let's try to
change this
it works so easy we don't need the
console anymore let's refresh we don't
need a console anymore so you can see
the skull is already here so pH is 5
yeah that's actually that that that
works now what's left to do is actually
to prettify three to five these actually
we can you can try to do that so anyone
is anyone so other interest in
JavaScript or are you guys all like all
sleepy so let's see how many people are
watching so you know if you guys are
watching say something but you know but
basically we are done so what's left to
do is to prettify this page let's
prettify prettify meaning meaning that i
go back to HTML page now this instead of
a list I need to instead of being a list
I need to make it you know shaped like a
inverted T and edge there so the way to
do that is is is via pre tag we can do
it with pre tag so let's do that
yeah so okay narrow two region remove
that remove that remove okay delete or
our tag okay then so H first well I
first then hjkl okay then the whole
thing will be your pre not dive three
okay and actually it will be style
style font size - I am let's say now
widen back to browser refresh okay
no way there's more to do here
oh yeah so this needs to be all in a
single line okay and this will be like
like that something like that okay
refresh oh yeah okay so we are almost
good
we are very good he is so that's key is
and let's we face remove the colon okay
then I need to remove the key
[Music]
okay and make it capital
you know that this is just kind of a
hack just to get idea but it's not it's
not the best way because you are using
the free tag you know it kind of just
works so that's that wait am I still
broadcasting or not
oh I am okay okay well that that's about
it today that's about let me finish just
finish you know well that's about it so
I'll just finish it offline then any any
questions comment questions comment
questions
check check check check no man break the
loop Isaac let's see what else what else
anything so and I'm I need to make these
bigger but yeah I that that's that
that's it for today so that's it for
today so thank you guys for watching I
hope to see you next time bye