good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
welcome to another another another
episode of star talk show
today is today's
december 2nd 2020
we have 28 more days to go
then it's 2021.
how are you guys it's been a while so
you
you today we are going to demonstrate
have a look at this keyboard and
comments okay comments guys
comment so you're gonna look at you're
gonna see
this keyboard i ipod
and i'm going to give you guys a review
super thing you see
this is microsoft's this is
microsoft stewing microsoft they're
doing things this is
actually pretty old uh snap
on uh zest you see oh
okay you see it's a snap on rest
magnetic high technology good morning
emily
great to have you emily emily is our
major force
in the casa forum uh good morning to uk
and good morning uh fuzzing fasting
uh i was using your python tutorial
thank you so you guys like my tutorial
buy it okay so today we're gonna talk
about that keyboard
and we are going to uh talk about some
emac stuff
fantastic emac stuff stuff so look at
the
look at my window so on the right the
purple window md scholar
and you can see all my key commands and
commands and keys so if you don't know
what i'm doing you can check out the
commands and and search them and you can
get the code
so first stop okay so let's start
talking so let's
first stop let's go to my emacs blog so
today
the topic is gonna going to be random
i'm going to go through my emacs blog
and
talk about several interesting things
you see this
is i'm going to become a [ __ ] you see
right here right here
uh repetitive strangers so so i'm going
to go through my emacs blog and talk
about random emacs
and emac list stuff then i'm going to
go to my keyboard blog and talk about uh
uh some interesting keyboard stuff and
in particular we are going to review
this microsoft scope
okay and uh okay luis good morning so
let's begin okay let's stop this
uh i haven't been doing videos for a
while for a month
because i've been busy doing a project a
uh
well i'm doing a philosophy and a
psychology project
some kind of writing okay
uh so how do i check well well i started
we okay so let's begin okay so
so emacs okay so let's go to emacs the
first stop
emacs emacs pinky okay so
i in the past you know one month i wrote
this comment uh i wrote this about
uh today actually yesterday so reformat
sentence two lines okay let me show you
what what what
why do we need that okay so go to uh
worthy english blog this is my blog on
english
uh link literature linguistics grammar
and so on
linguisticality idioms okay so magnify
and we are going to you're gonna see why
i'm going to
go to this page so we are going to go to
the literature
section arabian nights okay arabian
nights and
let's uh okay let's say arabian nights
now this is a fantastic story i've
talked about a few times
praise the lord praise praise be to
allah
the beneficent king the creator of the
universe lord of the three words
who set up the permanent without pillars
in instead
okay fantastic article so i press a key
copy the ui one single key press because
okay so uh because because because
because because let me show you you see
now every time i have to show this this
is like kinesis advantage to keyboard
this is my main power drive this is
you are looking at my power station and
this is the ultimate hacking keyboard
okay
pd2 that that is my actually are using
it as
my mac marker pad okay marco keypad
and this is the new edition the
microsoft this is
you see why do i need this i'm going to
talk about it later but
the reason is that because because
because
because i need a wireless okay that's
why now i have discovered the solution
to the uh stealing password problem
when using wireless keyboards that is
the solution is whenever you need to
type
the password do not use your keyboard
bring up the online keyboard
you see then you then you do that
whenever you need to type keyboard
if you are using wireless keyboard then
you just bring up the online
the software keyboard then type your
keyboard then you can go back to the
wireless keyboard maybe bluetooth or usb
you know they uh you cannot really trust
them
uh you know suppose you are a spy of
russia or usa you cannot trust them but
if you are going to do your bank account
uh well if you have a million dollars
you cannot trust it
so anyway so back to emacs okay let me
show you okay so
so this page i press one single key copy
the url
press one single key again back to emacs
and i press three keys to open this file
this local file so you can see
so you can see here uh
let me magnify okay you can see magnify
again
press to allah okay so so
you see we have a tremendous amount of
text here you know
uh so what
let me show you let me just call that
command okay then you'll see what's
going on so
actually let me magnify more so you can
see this we have this whole block of
text
how to read you know well you can read
it in html you know in browser for
example
i press the key it shows in browser then
it's easier to read then you can press a
key to magnify
or but if you are a
you know phd student or something or if
you are a writer or editor or journalist
whatever
that means the journalist [ __ ]
you know the then then you have to you
have to do a lot of writing
a lot editing you know so you are
working with the
emacs emacs is fantastic okay it beats
all the others but then you have to read
you know this
there's 100 000 words you know
when you are doing this kind of thing
writers or whatever
then uh you want to let's call the
command let me show you okay call
the command uh sentence
lines start reformat two sentence lines
okay
enter you see what it does is that now
each line uh let me show you uh let me
show you a
diversity okay so two windows let's open
two windows so this is original
paste it here magnify
uh okay then magnify here too
okay let's go full screen so you can see
the full glory okay so
now we have the same identical version
now under
on the on on this the second panel and
let me call the command okay cause i
reformat two sentence lines
then you can see the difference the
difference is that you see this
this uh block there is no structure
but on the other on the second one each
line
is a sentence by itself you see
but at the end the 20th 20th
12th the 20th 12th month
now that that's old english that's a old
style of english
the elder king yearned for a sight of
his younger brother
and failed felt that he must look upon
him
once more okay so each line is a
sentence by itself
so this way you have the structure in in
the formatting you know you have
structure so it's
uh kind of easier if when you need to
edit lots of text
okay that is the demo of that command
okay
close that uh close that don't save
uh yeah so this is this is uh this is
the arabian nights story of king
and his brother fantastic a fantastic
story go read it okay
arabian nights you know maybe if you
have
heard of it before or you maybe have
watched alibaba the movie or
disney's version those are crap okay
those are another real thing you want to
read
this version by sir richard burton this
is a
united kingdom person emily you know
this guy
this this guy is a scholar okay from the
1800s this
is a multi-talented
polymath poli
polymath you know uh
and he is sir he's a knight
so let's see what you guys are saying no
comments
say something guys sergio good morning
sergio hi good morning
good afternoon and cortes
fancy no new glasses okay let me explain
okay
so my my glass broke okay
my glass broke
without glasses i cannot see [ __ ]
now i'm getting old okay so you are
looking at the old guy so i have now two
glasses now this is new
but actually you know i i got this new
one about five
seven uh ten ten months ago
and it's crap it's from costco you know
and it's crap and they made it so that
it's very sharp
but when if i wear these glasses i
cannot see uh
things close you know i cannot i can
barely see my screen
then i need this one this is the mag
this is kind of
basically a magnifying glass so now
i put this double so now i can see
well i i need to get a new glasses this
is [ __ ]
uh i know of button okay so emily knows
of him i thought i saw
two glasses exactly
yeah so this is uh no good i need to get
a new pair of glasses uh costco uh you
know american
uh i don't know about uk but in america
the grasses are [ __ ] quality
compared to taiwan to taiwan or china
you know in usa the price for the
glasses
is like three four times more but the
crowd quality is four times
worse truly because in taiwan the asean
countries they it's like forty percent
of them wear glasses
so there's so many glass shops and it's
super
cheap and high quality okay so that's
about emacs that's about that command
okay so let's go
back to emacs as a refresher
so you can see a sentence
okay i call it too many commands
okay so anyway uh
showing browser so so that is that
command
three format sentence two lines okay you
can copy it i wrote that
on the spot yesterday uh and let me show
you another one i just wrote on the spot
okay so this one so emac this add period
to line
end this one i don't have i haven't uh
created the page for itself yet
so what this one does is that for
example
uh for example chat okay you see when
you are
chatting online usually you don't type
the ending period because it's
convenient you don't need it
you don't need to you just press enter
for example on discord but
you know i type a lot you know on
discord or chatting or on twitter
so you have all these bunch of uh
uh messages okay hold on a second
uh let me convert
to line break to single okay so
uh do that and do that again uh
okay so you got a bunch of text people
are talking you know usually
i i'm writing a lot of stuff opinions
about user interface about emacs about
you know what
whatever so but sometimes i i wrote a
lot spontaneously i want to copy and
make it into my blog
so for example let's say this is what i
wrote i want to put on my blog
so i copy it go to my let's say
programming blog
and here you can see my programming blog
let me let me magnify okay magnify so
you can see better
so now i add a section you can see a new
section
and show in browser
so you see this is a new section
december second
okay now back in emacs now
uh now i can paste here so you see
paste here
now there are several things i need to
do you see you first of all
for example if you just make a paragraph
you know the whole thing
make make a paragraph it of it showing
browser refresh it doesn't work it
becomes one or
you know one single line so you want a
period
so let's just call the command add
uh wait let me show the pink window so
the purple window so
so add meta x add period
okay add add period to end line end okay
enter so you see it adds a period to
each line end now you go back to the
browser magnify and refresh
now the sentences make sense
uh because you know you get idea so
you know so so that is convenient
because otherwise you have to do it
manually that's you know you have to
start to do find replace uh type a line
return
and then replace by
by a period and then line return
and yes yes yes yes then you have to you
know too much
uh trouble so you rather just call one
command
so that is that command let's
okay so close close back to browser
close
so that is this command add period to
lion
okay i think that's about it that's it
that's it for emacs let me maybe talk
about the
repetitive strain injury thing
uh because that's uh more interesting so
any comments
comments nicolo uh good morning
so i go i got 13 people watching
fantastic so
people say things okay now after this
i'm gonna talk about keyboard now this
uh emax pinky okay so i have this
problem i have pain right now like right
now
i have pain you know slight oh look
look crystal balls you know so i what i
do is i do this i knock on it
it feels comfort you know it's a kind of
massage
so for you know i started to have this
uh kind of
you know minor pain about 2017
three years ago and i cannot figure out
how you know because i have all these
fantastic ergonomic keyboards and habits
and fantastic you know stuff like keys
the
minimal more efficient than veeam
whatever theme you know the are
quite a few uh steps more efficient than
beam
so anyway i got this pin i i cannot i
don't i don't understand i cannot figure
out why but eventually i know
that is because i press the number three
key
number three key on top of the left hand
too much
you know i've been doing that for like
ten years the number three key because
the number three key
in starfly keys by default it splits
window okay let me show you
for example i have like uh you know lots
of split
so you can just press one key to to
remove those split
so in soft light keys it was the number
three key you know it
it is the number three key but i changed
it for myself
because i've been pressing that for 10
years that's that's causing the problem
eventually i find out you know when you
have a rsi
you always want to try to find out
exactly what's causing it
so in the past uh 15 years you know i
you know i have full detail of my rsi
stories
uh back in beginning in 2005. you can go
around
and see my articles and each time when
it happens about every three years i
have a new thing
you know it's like i solve the problem
no problem then after three years or
something
two or three years there's another issue
so so this one since 2017 i have this
pain i cannot figure out for a long time
for
for for two years eventually i realized
it's this
uh you know this pressing the number
three
key too much you know because i keep
moving this
so so the solution so i found a solution
of course don't stop pressing the number
three key
you know make it some other key to do
because i need to
you know splitting window is one of the
most
frequently used command because every
time you need you need uh you know
describe function or whatever
emacs split your windows so you want to
expand them
remove the split so so eventually i
found out but how do i know how do i
know that is the cost because every time
you know once you find out the the cost
you do you repeat that movement you'll
feel because
if i if i move my finger like that you
know when i press number three i can
feel the exact is
exactly here you know try it right now
you know try it try to
move your finger like that and put your
hand here
and you can feel this uh tendons like
shifting around here so it's pain
uh well too bad you know and i'm getting
old so so that is the problem
for this case so i have full
documentation of my rsi
uh problems for example uh you can see
back to my uh my typing rsi
experience a summary you know
i started typing touch type in 1998
okay electric typewriter electric
typewriter
and in 1992 i work as a data entry clerk
okay 1992. 1994 i started to use vorack
okay 1998 i started to
uh use emacs okay
uh 1998 tonight to 2005. no problem
you know i use emacs in text terminal no
no extra key bindings just plain glue
default keybinding emacs fantastic
you know why do i mention this because
there are many emax
phonetics you know when they see
microsoft flag keys or the wild ways i
talk
and they think oh this is stupid they
you know he doesn't know how to use
emacs
he's a windows guy he's a wind windows
idiot you know like
mac oh in windows he doesn't know unix
these people are idiots these [ __ ]
emacs phonetics [ __ ] idiots
so for 10 years 10 years are using emacs
in plain text terminal
not even x11 because i don't want that
you know i don't want the gui
you know back then i uh
the terminal is more efficient okay lots
of history you know i can tell you why
and xemax and so on anyway for the first
10 years of me using emacs i haven't
used any gui or
no have i changed any key binding well
except one because i'm using vorax so i
changed the meta x to
meta t but that's much later anyway
for 10 years you know for for more than
10 years from since
1988 1988
to 2005 i'm typing i'm a touch typist
every day
i typed more than more than 10
programmers combined
because for two years i was a data entry
clerk do you know
you know today young people you probably
don't know what what what what the [ __ ]
is data entry
data entry clock means you sit there
typing is your job okay you have a
data letter sales managers you just keep
typing
that's your job so i've been doing that
you know i
somehow i love typing in piano i love
kind of the finger work
so anyway so for 10 years for for 15
years i had
17 years i'm a touch typist i don't have
a problem with
uh any typing at all and in fact i read
so much about typing back then there's
no internet you go read books you know
vorack you know quarterly layout veriz
you learn them i created my
ownvo rack on the mac back in 1994
so but until 2005
which which is i document here okay 2005
i started to have rsi problem
first brush with us rsi and why i can
tell you why because
uh because let's see where let me show
you a photo okay
well in short because i was using a
laptop
that's the first time i'm using a you
know laptop becoming popular back then
i'm using a laptop exclusively
no nothing else on laptop exclusively
for two years
that's my you know i started to feel
something is weird you know
something is weird with my you know i
don't feel comfortable then
but i know you know back then because i
read so much about typing i already know
oh
oh i gotta be careful i gotta you know i
started
you know i started to get a microsoft
i started to get this keyboard this
microsoft natural but anyway
it's similar to this okay
because i know you know i yeah you know
i should
use uh maybe i should use the urban arm
ergonomic keyboard because before that
i hated ergonomic keyboards why because
for several reasons
you know the ergonomic keyboard they put
the b
on the left side but if you are a touch
typer the b is supposed to to be typed
on your right hand i follow the standard
type you know touch typing
so i don't like i don't like these b you
know that you know they move it to the
other side
and the other thing is the six key
microsoft also move it to the other side
so i never liked i never liked the
ergonomic keyboard you know
it's weird just like most people like
like a lot of you guys you know oh
god i don't want the ergonomic that's
just weird
but anyway back then i had problems i i
switched but
after i switched i love ergonomic
keyboards okay
you know i you have to force yourself to
use it because
because if you don't have a problem you
don't want it you know right
but once you have you think maybe you
have a problem then you
you have to put effort you know to
to use ergonomic keyboard but so once i
use that i
i i don't go back to the flag keyboard
anymore because the flag keyboard
immediately your your you know once you
use the ergonomic for a while you'll
realize on a flat
immediately your hand you know ergonomic
ergonomic keyboard your hand is like
enough
like that on a flat keyboard then you
you know the
the impression is very uh
strong you know you you right away
realize your hand is
you know in a [ __ ] up position
so anyway that's my first rsi 2005 and
the reason is because i'm using a laptop
for two years
okay so in fact i can show you
the i can show you the exact laptop i'm
using okay
i still have it actually i need to throw
it away i need to take out the hard disk
and destroy it and throw it away uh but
the
but the key the i have a photo of
uh of it okay let me show you the photo
of my
the laptop i was using okay it's not
here [ __ ]
too many articles okay i have too many
articles i have to find ways that
how to avoid emac pinky okay i have so
many
uh advices about how to use keyboard
wait anyway the one so this is the
laptop i was using for two years that's
cost
that that gave me eyesight for the first
time
then after that every three years
there's something else happened you know
then
actually i started to type a lot more
you know more than anyone
on on this earth i'm telling you as a
fact okay
well let's say top 100
in in in in in united states states
you know for for for five years or so
the amount of typing because i was
i was you know pretty extreme strange
guy
so anyway that so for each uh instance
of my eyes i talked about it okay that's
that's about it about that
how long have i been talking so
hey good morning scott scott says i had
similar issues with the b
and 6 keys on the on the microsoft
keyboard yeah
i heard i heard you telling about that
many people have that issue as well
so uh
dinner time and okay so i think maybe
with that's
we about to end i'm gonna talk about
keyboard about this new keyboard then
that's it
for today this uh it's been a while
let's see how long have i been talking
okay
uh okay i only talked for 30 minutes
okay i can talk for
a long time apparently i can talk
non-stop for a long time
okay so what's so let me tell you about
this keyboard then
so this is um so i have a review you
know just search
uh uh focus only keyboards i have a
review of everything
so let's go to star talk show
go to some talk show today's talk show
and let's go to keyboard okay microsoft
keyboard
so this keyboard okay the design
is fantastic it's truly fantastic look
look at the huge you know the huge
control
uh controls uh window key you know
modifier keys they're fantastic okay
one of the greatest design ergonomic
design okay the micros that's why they
are successful you know microsoft
you know apple did most of the
innovations in computer industry in
computers
but at but microsoft has a strong a few
okay one of them is microsoft the
ergonomic keyboard
apple also made one but it failed
miserably
you can you can find my articles you
know talking about the apple what
apple's ergonomic keyboard in 1990
uh in 2000 what what year is it
actually i can show it here ergo history
okay
so here is ergonomic keyboard history
then apple made one that's a
spectacular failure 1993.
the worst [ __ ] ever made the ergonomic
keyboard they think oh they we are the
innovators but they created
crap in the same year 1994
1993 the microsoft created
uh you know their ergonomic and that
revolutionized
revolution nice the keyboard industry
okay where is it
microsoft there 1994 you know
because it catch it caught on you know
then
since then a lot of people use the urban
army keyboard the
the the idea uh began to spread
and and they did a good job it's really
this is a fantastic keyboard microsoft
ergonomic natural they call it
so after the after the years now it's
over like
almost 20 years now let's see night this
is
this beginning 1994 so it's like
25 years history uh 25 years of
ergonomics so today and okay so this
version is pretty bad okay i have you
know let me tell you so this is my first
one
in 2005 i got this one
uh yeah and it's it's great it's great
then in then later on they had a new
version
then i got this one theoretically it's
an improvement
in many places but actually it's it's
this one is worse okay because there's
it's got a stiff stiff spacebar problem
and so on
so eventually i you know so here is paul
graham
the famous least uh programmer commonly
programmer
uh and hacker news you know he becomes
rich
you know he's using this keyboard
uh and okay so so but now
i you i of course now so today so
i bought this uh uh two days ago it
arrived two days ago
super thin okay so it's a great design
but
it is actually pretty heavy it's heavier
than
than i expected because i thought it's
really thin but actually it's heavy
because there are there are a lot of
magnets
showed you before there are uh
you know magnets around so this is a
front riser you know
you know this is another innovation for
microsoft okay we can
attribute that to microsoft you know
usually we don't think of microsoft but
usually normally keyboard are like that
and usually you have legs on the back so
you
pop up like that and you you know that's
idiotic you know and
but the proper way is actually it should
be tilted this way
so you have this thing called fundraiser
and this
is the usb uh dongle
wireless i bought this because i need i
really need a wireless keyboard
okay okay so so you see so so
so this way is you know normally you
would uh bend up like that your hand
that's no good and but this way your
hand
you know the the wrist remains straight
your your fingers just dip down you see
so this is a good thing so why do i buy
this well because i need
you know i have a surface tablet
sometimes i lie in bed or
i take it i walk for 30 minutes because
i need to get up
you know otherwise i've been sitting
from you know wake up to the
to until i sleep so i need to wake up i
need to walk
for 30 minutes every two or three hours
so i take my surface
tablet and walk around and some so
anyway i need the wireless
so i have you know i don't have wireless
so i so
so eventually i got this one so the the
design is great but the key feel is not
that great you know it's rubber dome
so it's not suitable for prolonged
typing so if you type a lot in
office or whatever uh this is
this is not a good one but otherwise
it's you know
so here is my surface tablet
uh okay and uh that's that's it
anything else that's it for today i
think maybe
so i'm gonna talk random so let's see
what you guys saying
it's been a while i you know i did a
talk show
and uh how are you guys
uh
yeah i used two miles you know since
like 1993 i always i you know
but not now but right now i just used my
mouse um
but i would still use two mouse actually
you know if i
yeah i would i just
right now it's just not too necessary
for me because
you know the way i have you know i
talked about this many times the way
the way i have the mouse is that i never
i almost never click it's
it's a hoover click and that is really
fantastic
a hand saver but you have to the problem
is that you have to get used to it
so all these i talked about you know
they are on my blog so you just go to my
blog okay
so for example keyboard
guide i talked about so there is uh and
function keys we can talk about that
uh function keys versus keyboard you
know when i talk about
emac programming emac disk or keyboard
i'm going to flame the hacker types you
know i'm i'm going to swear at the
hackers non-stop almost non-stop
because their opinions every
every their opinions is [ __ ] idiotic
and they just
they just spread and spread for example
uh swap the
capsule key with control you know that's
one of their things oh you should swap
the
capsule out to control idiotic [ __ ]
so one of the things you know for
example one of the these hacker types
you know one of their thing is that you
you know
you know they will say you don't need
the function keys who uses
you know you don't want function keys
they they like
emily emily you know i tell you let me
tell you what they like you know they
like
this um for example happy hacking this
is the most famous hackers thing
they don't even have function keys okay
lots of problems with happy hacking
uh not just happy hacking okay let me
show you some of the other one you know
the hip
these are the hip keyboards okay this
one
key crown becoming popular you know for
example this one you see they
they do have function keys but the you
know but it's like
in a contiguous continuous world no gaps
oh my god these people they don't know
what they're doing they don't know they
don't know
they think this is compact you know
that's what they want this is these
hacker types and nice flume okay
so they so they you know
they like this kind of thing and also
especially let me
let me tell you some famous ones the leo
part okay
no function keys uh and
you know these are very expensive uh
keyboards
okay but but let me tell you why why do
you need um
function keys okay uh where is it okay
function keys is the most useful thing
in the universe
you know is it it saves you rsi or
whatever you know these linux people
these [ __ ]
linux or emacs or vim people they say oh
you don't need this
i don't want to use the mouse oh you
don't need function keys because control
you know
then they are into the uh uh window
managers on linux you know the
window managers [ __ ] idiots
why are they idiots because their way
you know what they say
they tell you what to do you know the
swapping caps lock to control
you know whatever or no function keys or
not using a mouse
they're you know what they say is
actually idiotic because they are
actually
let me put it this properly they are
scientifically
it can be demonstrated by scientific
means you know
measuring statistics and all that their
ways actually most
the more their way is more inefficient
okay
their way is more inefficient and
you know just bad in many ways depending
on which which thing
so for example one of their things about
the function keys you know many of these
nerds they don't want function keys they
say oh there's that
function keys is the most useful the
most if you want
to avoid isi you want function keys for
many reasons
so i give details here okay
uh and and okay one one of the things
they say is that
here's one of their thing they're the
[ __ ] idiots these [ __ ] idiots
one of the things they they the reason
the reason they give for
not wanting you uh function keys is that
key code is you know function keys is
too far they think oh you have to move
your hand you know
they want their hands to be on the home
row
[ __ ] idiots let me tell you so
so so here we have a question we this
question can be answered scientifically
these [ __ ] idiots
when it comes to science they ignore you
know when it comes to
like uh literate programming you know
like
news you know they say oh that's great
when it comes to font they say oh that's
great you know because science
but when it comes to this they forgot
all about science you know
so so they think that the key chord
control t
control control f you know is better
than the function key because
they don't have to move your hand their
hands of the homeworld
but this question can be can be um
can be okay
we can find out the answer which one is
more efficient via science okay
so what do you mean so i have an article
uh you know
exploring that question function key
versus kiko
code which is healthier and which is
faster
and this you know these nerds they talk
about fast which one is fast
these [ __ ] idiots
so i wrote this article so so let's talk
about you know
let's say star versus these notes you
know they think you don't need function
keys they
because they don't want to move the
fingers off the
home row so so which one is better which
one is more efficient
that's one one of the first question we
can ask scientifically
second which one is more healthy for
your hand long term okay so if
suppose you are going to use you know
this either function keys or the key
code
for three years let's say you're gonna
press them one hour a day
which which group of people will have
have more
rsi at the end of three years this can
be proven
scientifically these [ __ ] eddie
idiotic nerds
linux emax vi [ __ ]
so i give you a overview you know how do
you compare and also
one of the important things which
keyboard are we talking about
are we talking about you know if you
want to compare the key code versus the
function keys
which first of all you have to uh
be clear on what exactly keyboard are
you using
for example here is a traditional uh
layout you know ibm
pc keyboard okay then there is the
laptop keys this is a mac
you know laptop keys or there is this
uh you know this this one you know this
one i
you know i just bought
so you see the keyboard the the answer
to the question
is different depending on which keyboard
you use you know first of all
you have to be specific about that these
notes never talk
about that these nuts you know they just
say
they never you know they just they just
talk about their habits okay these nuts
hacking
i despise hackers that is why you know
the unix starting with the unix
philosophy the people who love unix then
it becomes linux and you know
then then today's male engine no even
less
millennials so
so you uh okay so that's my that i guess
that's one of my rant okay why function
keys
uh what's the deal with function keys
uh in in general yeah you do you do want
uh to have that okay so
i have okay i think that's it for today
uh so how long have i been talking so
i'm gonna read comments and that's it
okay so
uh you you like my stuff buy my stuff
okay
so you can buy let me tell you okay so
emacs
so you go to my emacs tutorial and go to
uh e-max tutorial
and you go to
buy emacs tutorial okay so you can buy
that and also
the other thing i think is great
worth of your money is my
javascript tutorial javascript in depth
in fact this is more in depth than my
emac this
tutorial javascript in depth okay so you
uh if you like my stuff then
then you go buy it okay thank you guys
uh
let's see what questions i'm gonna
answer questions
oh i have 20 viewers now more and more
okay so
decided to start working as junior java
developer oh
java java is the worst language i'm
i'm the wrong guy to ask for java okay
but java is the industrial language is
the most
popular you know it's not going to go
away so yeah you
um so you do java you know you go make
money
but if you are you know as a hobby
for you know java is not a language that
uh most people programmers love
it's it's an industrial language and
also
java projects written in java is usually
boring you know database
financial stuff you know
okay so i have the original microsoft
elite okay so
the reverse any questions any more
questions
then that's it we say goodbye in five
minutes i think
any questions ask okay so
would you suggest your javascript guide
of course
what kind of question is that my
javascript guide i can tell okay
we maybe i can uh expand on why
why you know there are so many
javascript tutorials why should you buy
why should you even read this this
you know this wild kasari javascript
tutorial
this non-standard you know well
uh yeah i can talk about that because
well the reason is because uh
have you talked about your recent uh
social justice studies
uh no uh let's talk about some other day
okay so
recently i did a project
that is basically a history you know how
you know
basically the it's about you know it's
about studying
philosophy and psychology
uh of the past 100 years you know since
okay since 1900s
uh philosophy and and psychology
that led to today's
you know you might call social justice
way of thinking
you know in usa for example you know you
know even not in usa
united kingdom or other typically in
white countries
you have what you might call social
justice or left left
rather extreme leftist okay they talk
about
yeah actually i don't want to talk too
much about that on youtube
because they're gonna censor you know
that's one of their thing
they're gonna censor you they're gonna
say you you know
so anyway i studied about the philosophy
and psychology of that
this of the past 100 years
that and and and that and
that they are basically the
you know these philosophy they are they
are a specific
kind of branch of philosophy that led to
these
uh what i would say today's social
justice kind of
thing and i think it's very bad it's the
collapse of the white culture okay
collapse of the you guys uh you know the
collapse of the white nations the
western society
the collapse of the western society so
if you are white people you know i
if you are you know yeah white basically
you know what
by that mean i mean if you are american
you know white american or
european you know let's say a decent
okay
germany or uh or even anyway
you know what i mean white people okay
just generally
that that that was actually pretty bad
word you know the wide race you know
that's actually one of the
the jargon invented by the social
justice scan okay
but anyway but anyway so
fight the social justice i did ideas
okay ideology that those
are no good because your country your
people are dying you
you know collapsing that's what i think
that's what i
that's my opinion i think it's the
the social justice may eventually go
away either that
or the western society is collapsing you
know so
so what happens when if the western
society collapse
well china russia and the middle east
countries they they rise
that's what happens and in fact i think
it's
already happening especially that you
know usa
used to be the greatest country and also
uh
you know the technology the buildings
the bridges you know the best things
but not so today
they're stagnating it's stagnating and
also usa
but still usa has got the most powerful
military
so anyway that's so i've been studying
in the past month i've been studying
these philosophies and the psychology
that
you know there's a there's kind of a
branch of them
there are several of them that led to
today's social justice
uh i can talk about that some other day
so javascript my javascript you should
buy it because that's
truly in depth and in a technical manner
and also
this my javascript guide for example you
know
beginning with the beginners you know if
you are a beginner it's also useful
but if you let's say you work for google
you know you are a googler google
you know you are a great programmer at
google you think you know the stuff
javascript
but no you don't [ __ ] compared to what i
know about javascript
so if you are a googler coding
javascript is your day job
professionally
for two years let's say not no more than
two
you will also learn tremendous number of
stuff
about javascript for my javascript in
depth
okay because well because i cover it in
depth okay let me tell you
a few of the reasons okay it's in depth
okay it's based on the javascript
uh spec okay javascript is
javascript spec is extremely complicated
and javascript is the most one of the
most complicated complex
language it's not a good language
uh so i cover it in in depth okay
according to spec
not according to some mozilla you know
reference
the monsieur reference it's one of
it's not so good especially their
tutorial well it depends
i can talk about this for one hour okay
so anyway so
so you so you will learn in javascript
in depth that's one thing
and you will learn them in the most easy
to understand way okay i
i i treat the javascript the way i teach
is treating it almost as a piece of
mathematics
okay when you hear that maybe you think
oh no i don't want it because you
don't like math you don't understand
what no but you know
basically what that that means you know
you will understand things in the most
clear uh precise manner okay
unlike any other you know python
documentation then
lots of documentation are pretty bad uh
you know industry
especially the hackers type of languages
okay
anyway so simplicity okay in depth
and also no jargons okay you will you if
you read my
uh tutorial you will learn one thing and
one thing only javascript you
you will understand the language
javascript the language in depth
but you will not hear things about oh uh
how oop is something great
how patterns you should use patterns so
you should use you know this
junk is this idiotic nonsensical you
know complicated you know useless
rather you know no good job jargons the
and you will not hear like
ninja or zen or you know the the [ __ ]
idiot [ __ ]
you know dojo you know this you know
especially the you know
programmers like that oh zen you know
rubies and or whatever terminology they
have
and you don't and you will not learn
about frameworks well i have some
tutorials about frameworks but you don't
need it
okay react react you know you know
angular or not or other frameworks you
know this
that's you don't you don't so i don't
teach that
okay i do have some tutorials about that
but i don't teach that i teach
i teach you the pure foundational
javascript
the language okay then you have you also
have reference
of all the all the javascript objects
and functions and stuff
you know reference section uh and also
including regular expression you know
the whole thing
and then i also teach you about dom so
you can program dom
for example let's show some pretty um
thing uh let's see
okay let's show this pretty thing ooh
snow okay i show you how to like this
this this is pretty you know this
kind of thing is very old like 20 years
old since to year 2000
but if you look around their code is
like 20 years old
that's not modern javascript this is
modern javascript
you know how do you use that to do this
you know so anyway so that's why you
so if you like my stuff buy my stuff
uh just go to my website okay and check
it out
so i think that's it uh bye guys
bye scott and
would i be able to build a modern
website you know
uh
that depends on what you mean because
when you when you're talking about build
a modern website
you know that depends on what you mean
if you are you know
because a modern application it's not
just javascript anymore
you you know that's why they have these
frameworks you know
elect electron you know i don't teach
electron at all
but electron is one of the javascript
well it's not it's it's it's beyond a
framework it's not just you know you
have
you know javascript technology changes
all the time there's you have so many
things but anyway
you you know the javascript in depth
that's what you need to know
even if you use any of the frameworks
okay thank you guys for watching that's
it for today
bye guys
you