good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of c talk show today's is
2021 January 3rd Sunday 5:00 p.m. San
Francisco time and we are going to do
emac L coding the first 30 minutes or we
are going to do emac L coding nonstop
then after that we going to talk
random okay so let's begin quickly so uh
actually let me just uh let me put in
the uh comment box H [ __ ] I have to go
to YouTube I'm going to type okay
so first 30 minutes eisp coding then
random okay so I go to my S Talk Show
YouTube
studio and uh comments questions put it
put it there okay say
hi so first 30 minutes emac list coding
and we're going to do this quickly so
let's see let's go there and uh
okay oh the back so the background image
is this
one this is fantastic beautiful image
stary eyed all so this is uh so this all
is blind and uh I found it on this
website okay so let's uh let's do emac
this talk uh coding so so what we're
going to do so on the right window the
pink window you can see all my emac this
commands Okay and
uh and you guys comment
okay okay Freddy good morning Freddy and
uh night for Europe okay uh CZ good
morning are you are you training your
left eye yeah so this is a patch I
talked about you know I had some cross
eye slight cross eye when I was
uh young I think
you know and my eyes are getting
worse so let me just cover
it so so okay so what we going to do we
GNA uh uh okay let me show you okay
notes
emx
uh here is the command Okay so the
command we are going to write is a write
a command to delete HTML
tag the the tag under Cruiser the tag
pay under Cruiser okay and let me show
you some
examples
example uh let's see link
okay let's
see okay showing browser so we have a
link let's see google.com
Okay
google.com Okay let's let's go here copy
the URL back to emac paste it here
linky uh remove the link show magnify
magnify so you can see this there's a um
list okay with a link that's this line
okay now I have several commands to
remove the TX for example I can press a
key I I have several commands Okay so
let me show
you
uh okay First Command this one this will
remove every tag in any tag so that
command is called remove HTML remove
HTML TX it removes everything so undo so
look look again okay so actually let's
copy it
here let's copy actually several uh
versions
okay so you can see so this
command so this is original and I call
it and becomes that remove every tag of
the current block of text okay then
there is a command to uh here's a
command I'm going to show you okay do it
you see it turns into a text form you
see originally there's a link now if you
remove every tag the link is gone but if
you call this command instead and that
command is called um this one okay HTML
HTML to text and it will turn the
current block of text removing the Tex
but however
preserve uh links I mean it tries to uh
turn it into a text format so now you
can copy this on Twitter you know post
to Twitter and so on so that's uh
another
one and uh okay so
actually actually let me let me let me
copy the command Okay so so the first
one
is the first one is this command
Okay okay then what that do is it
becomes that then the second one is this
command okay then what it does is it
turns into a text format okay then the
next one sometimes I have a list I want
to remove just a list I want to uh
remove just the UL and Li TX so that
command
is s
tml uh remove
list remove this TX okay do it so it
looks like that so you you see each one
is very
different so this command is is this
one this one okay
put it here okay so shrink so you can
see we have several commands then we
have this
one uh okay so we have this one remove
everything this one remove uh change it
to
text this one just remove the list TX
now we are going to write a new command
we are going to write a command such
that um
we will call
it remove
tag
under CER remove tags tag pair under
crer okay something like that now I want
to change it with hyphen so this is the
command we're going to write okay so
first of all go to my
HTML uh source
code so
okay so jump to it here's the source
code forar HTML mod okay so we have we
are going to write a new command indeed
so so let's
defund let's do this quickly okay
defend uh wa wait so what is the command
will be called the command will be
called that one so instead of a defund
let's I mean let's create a new file
okay magnify save it paste that and put
today's
date. okay so go to the diet so this is
a new file magnify and we want to rename
it so instead of space we want a
underscore we don't want space in our
file name so I just press a key done so
that command is called look at the pink
window uh rename space toore okay so now
this is the file so open
it magnify and we want to write this
function okay
Define okay
Define define this
name and dark string okay let's write
dark string version today's
State uh this will be remove the
tag uh possibly a pair of them because
in HTML some some tags there's no ending
tag so remove tags under
Cruiser remove
the current tag under crer so that's
that's what this command will
do so uh how do we do so so let's uh so
let's write down the the steps to um
complete this what do we need to
do okay good morning good night uh
second that uh would you do unboxing new
computer stream
later I not the type to do the
unboxing uh
computers I just got a
basically
$900 gaming machine from Costco you know
I bought it online so it's just
um yeah I don't think I can't do that I
mean I'm
not you know it's gaming machine I don't
know that much about it would be fun but
it's it's not not my thing unboxing you
know that's a new term from the malen
genen unboxing
things okay so so we need to write down
the algorithm
okay steps so first of all first
find what is the tag under Cruiser
then find if it is beginning tag or
ending tag or without ending tag
okay once we do that then remove the TX
okay so that's the steps we need to do
so first step is first find what is the
tag under Cruiser
um okay so how do we do
that okay so this is uh this this is
getting this is immediately getting
complex because I have to first of all
okay uh are we going to do this are we
going to complete this because I can see
it's going to be boring for you guys I
can see that we're going to you know
it's going to be 30 minutes and uh it's
going to be boring for you
guys because if I go fast if I go fast
you wouldn't know what I'm doing but if
I go slow it's going to take one hour
just to do very simple things because I
have to explain every uh each step and
this
is okay so first of all find what is the
tag under Cruiser uh
okay let's open a new window okay so
let's go back to
HTML so we
can so how do you find what is a tag
under Cruiser for example if our Cruiser
is here the tag is the a
right
um uh there is you see one of the
critical thing for this command is this
one HTML skip tag
forward but
um finding you first of all you have to
find what is ATT tack under Cruiser okay
so that you know I this is going to be a
big problem it's going to take one more
more than one hour you know there's uh
one simple way okay first of all
p 0 okay so let's define a uh P0 is a
variable that is a current Cru of
position
okay so set P0 Point okay so we store
the current cluer position then search
backward okay uh this is
not probably not efficient but let's you
know let me just go through and show
show some of the basic emac list
uh functions and workflow so you can see
so so right now we want to find what is
a tag under curer so this is how you do
it so first of all save the current
position the point the current position
of the curer then search
backward search backward for the uh that
sign okay and B no
error uh count okay let's not worry
about details for now uh then once you
find it
you want uh move the cruiser to the
right one character okay forward chart
okay
one
then then you want to grab the current
word okay
so so for example if if our Cruiser is
here for example there might be a class
something like
that
okay and the so if our Cruiser is right
here it will first search for the for
the this character right it will search
for this character then move Cruiser
right word to the right one character
then you you just want to grab the
current word okay that that is how you
do
it
um wait in the case this is if the
cruiser is here for example if the
cruiser is here use search backward to
this card this chat character then you
move CER rightward here then the way you
determine whether it's a beginning tag
or end tag is by by whether you know you
check to see if there's a slash so you
can yeah so we can do
that okay so go back to our code
[Music]
here uh should we write it down Okay so
okay so forward chart one so we now now
we want to so the cruiser is to the
right of the of the left angle brackets
you want to know the character under the
cruiser is a slash or not so how do you
find what is the character in the
slash uh well there is a
command I think current char
uh there is a command
I I don't remember what is a command so
let's go to my emac lisp tutorial okay
let's see if we can find it
there emac lisp tutorial okay so we want
to find we want to find the command that
tell us what is the character under
[Music]
Cruiser so basic functions Cruiser
position here are functions about C
position
uh
and here's uh functions about editing Ed
editing text
okay so where do I find that command
thing at Point
um I have to think about it because I
know Chai at
Point uh
[Music]
okay comment okay comment chy
Point CH at Point
yeah I have to think because uh I know I
remember I know there is a command
um find the current character under
Cruiser let's see thing yet thing at
point no not thing at
Point uh get text
[Music]
block I don't remember so let's go to
emac this you know there are so many
ways to find what is a function for
example another way is by you go to IMX
tutorial and search documentation for
example you can use the a propose
command you
want okay control
U control h
a then you type Point okay then emac
will show all
functions with the word
point then you can just search it
there Char at point I'm pretty sure the
command name is Char at Point okay
uh CH at
Point describe function CH point
no so we want to find the function that
Returns the character under Cruiser
does anyone know list at
point point at beginning of
line Point Max uh number Point okay
so okay so it's I don't know so maybe
it's current CH okay let's see current
CH I don't think that's a
one describe function no search function
so let's do it again uh control U
control h a a propose command now
type uh Char okay now it will list all
commands with the word chart in it
backward chart
uh C into char
Char equal okay that's a function we
will need Char
equal and
uh there it is you see uh fruitful our
efforts has been fruitful Char after and
Char before that's our that's the
function we
want so we enter and we can see here's a
documentation Char after okay so great
CH after is what we need we okay ch ch
after uh this CH okay set this
chart equals to chart
after Okay so
so that returns so this chart is the
character under the cruiser right now
okay and now we do CH
equal
okay now here we need to represent a
character that is the uh that is a back
slash that is the slash okay we want to
see if it's a slash so I believe that's
how you represent the character so let's
test it okay first of all pred defy the
code okay so here's the whole
code we can test it okay so let's let's
do
yeah it's not okay
so so let's just uh let's just do this
okay if that then
message yes okay else message
no okay so so far this is our function
this function what it does it will move
Cruiser to the to the left
to the left angle bracket then we'll
move cluer to the right one character
then it will check if that character is
a slash or not if it is say yes
otherwise say no okay so run the code
now this function is evaluated okay so
now let's call call it uh let's say
let's so let's put the cruiser here and
let's see what happens what it say so
let's call the command meta X HTM HTML
remove tag BL blah blah call it and it
says yes you see look at the mini buffer
um oops so let's go to the message
buffer you see it says yes so apparently
this command is working now let's try to
put the uh Cruiser here okay so let's
call the
command it says no so that means our
code so far this code is working great
great uh so if
it so now let's add another
variable begin tag P okay
so this is a buing this variable will be
either true or false if it's true that
means the cruiser is in a bracket that's
the beginning of the tag or otherwise
it's end of tags okay so let's
set set beginning of tag beginning of
tag to um basically to
this okay so in fact we don't
need we don't need this uh CH
variable you see so this deter our CER
is in the beginning of tag or end of tag
okay now the next step is if if it's
beginning
okay if beginning of tag is true by the
way the dash P if a function ends in P
that's iMac this convention to mean that
this
variable uh value is either true or
false in imex that means uh t or NE
so if if it's a cruiser is in the
beginning of tag then what we do is we
call this command okay let me let me
find
um let's call this command HTML skip CH
skip tag forward okay let's go to the
source code and so you can
see so it actually calls this uh
building function s sgml skip tag
forward okay let's just just try that
try that okay let's just use
it so if it's a beginning of
tag wait before we call this we need to
do something else
[Music]
uh so if it's a beginning of tag hold on
a second
[Music]
so you see we are starting we want to
delete those tags so in order to delete
the
tags for example let me let me go to go
back to HTML
page you see in order so we suppose we
are in the beginning of tag in order to
delete this tag we need to find the
beginning position and you know of the
angle bracket and end position of the
angle bracket so we need to uh set the
position
here so so actually we already know the
position beginning position there so
actually let's say begin
tag
begin P1
okay tag be P1 is the beginning position
P2 is the end
position and
uh and we also need tag end P1 p two
okay
[Music]
so so here we need to set tag be in P1
Point
okay
okay okay and uh search
forward that
[Music]
then
set tag
begin P2 okay Point
okay so we have set tag begin
P1 and tag begin
P2 okay that's
the that is the
that is position there you know that's
the these positions
okay
[Music]
now okay now we can we are almost done
okay so uh any
comments no
comments Okay so so we almost done
so so let's not do that yet so let's
search
for search for
word and not search for
wood Okay so
so this will move the uh let's
see okay so I know what's going on so
skip chart
forward so now we jump to the end tag so
if we are at the beginning of if the
current tag under Cruiser is the
beginning tag then we jump to the end
tag then set
point tag
end right that's the closing tag of the
ending
tag Point okay then search back word for
that then set tag
and
P1 Point
okay so now we have the now we have the
beginning
TX opening I mean we have the beginning
tax uh you know beginning position end
position now we also have the
UHS end TXS beginning and end
position okay now in the case if the if
our tag is not on
the beginning tag if our tag is on the
end tag it's similar okay so we need to
do this block of
code in fact we can just copy that paste
it
here uh beginning back word
[Music]
okay H what's going on
here is the code we
need Yeah we actually we don't no
um this is this is we got a
problem
uh we got a
problem so so far so good is are you
guys uh seeing what I'm doing with the
EAC lisp are you like are you guys emac
lisp
fans am I making sense here
we have actually a lot to do with you
know whenever you code online live you
have to explain a lot of things because
otherwise people don't know what you're
talking
about but you know for every small
detail you have to take you know a
minute or two to explain
it uh so that slows down
significantly and also you know is so
online coding is hard because then new
people comes in they they have no idea
what you are doing because they missed
whatever comes
before so anyways uh we want to skip tag
backward uh skip tag backward okay so
let's let's write this tag uh this first
we actually we have to rewrite this
because I already found out something is
wrong uh
skip tag backward okay
so okay let's try skip tag backward yeah
so
uh
P1 then search for word
okay so our code looks like that but
this is incorrect because in the you
know when we start we search backward
for the left angle
bracket and then we set tag beginning
okay uh you know we set tag
beginning but that's not necessarily
right because so if we are at the end
tag for example if our curer is here
then we search backward we are you know
that position the pos position over here
is not the beginning of tag you know
that's the actually the beginning of the
end tag not the beginning of
the of the beginning tag
so so in order to so you know so then
here we determine you know in this line
we determine whether the cruiser is the
in the beginning tag or end tag once we
find that out if the cruiser is actually
in the beginning tag then so far this
code are correct but if the CER is the
at the end tag then the variable mean uh
the name doesn't mean uh it's not
incorrect it's incorrect
okay so so what we do now is we can
um do I make
sense okay no
comment let's put it here so I can see
okay
so let me think okay I have to think so
in the so first first of all we set it
to a variable then we find out it's a
beginning tag or end tag
then then okay
so okay so here's what we do let's just
say so here's our variable let's shrink
a little bit okay P1 P2 okay so instead
of this so we say
P1 P2 okay do that do that and this line
determines whether the the tag and the
curer is beginning or end Okay then if
it's a beginning okay let's copy the
whole thing let's uh rewrite the whole
thing okay so if it's a
beginning if it's a beginning
then then if it's a beginning then
okay
then P1
okay P2 simple okay
otherwise otherwise that okay
then so so it's a beginning of tag okay
so P1 P2 then search uh
then then this
okay then skip tag forward
yeah
correct okay so if it's so we are
getting
closer this is our correct
code so this is uh this this seems to be
the correct
code let me double check so if it's
beginning tag
then then set beginning P1 P2 then skip
to then move the CER to the ending tag
then set end tag end
position then search backward then set
and tag beginning position that's
correct okay then but if it's not if the
cruiser is not the beginning tag then
what we what we do is
we set end tag end tag then move the CER
to the beginning tag then set the
beginning uh tags beginning and end
position that's correct so now all we
have to do is just um delete region okay
we are almost done delete region tag and
P1 P2 okay delete that first
then then just delete uh
there that that is our
code for the simple cases this this code
will work
okay uh let's clean clean up the code
yeah let's clean up the code that that's
it uh let's let's shrink
this okay so that's the code eval the
buff let's just try it okay EV buffer so
copy the code and we're going to try to
do it
okay shrink okay so now let first of all
let's try the cruiser is on here the
beginning tag so let's call the command
after the command is called it should
remove that and also remove that okay
let's try it call
it HTML remove tag pay under Cruiser do
it okay incorrect
you see it it's it's incorrect okay so
let's undo let's try it
again put a curser here do
it yeah it deleted something
incorrect now what if it's a the end so
let's try it
again no it's also incorrect okay so
something is
wrong uh let's see search tag backward
oh God this this command is
uh fairly complicated to write and this
is only covering the simple case we
haven't dealed with cases where there is
no ending tag yet because in that case
you need to move the crer to the end to
determine if there is the
slash uh
okay complex complex code okay comments
happy New Year B base haven't seen you
for a while
base Freddy Freeman says s off topic but
what do you like about poers shell you
say it's good it was designed unlik bash
uh what do you mean by this did you
watch my uh yesterday's
video I think I you know I explained
there I said Powers
shell should be better should be the uh
better shell because it's created uh 10
years after bash so in general the later
Technologies are better and Powershell
you know the reason is that so that's
that's my thought okay I mean I don't
really have experienced coding Powers
shell not much I only spent like several
two month a month to learn it and roll a
tutorial so
um and I think it should be better
because Powershell is designed now the
Unix things Unix shelves they are not
designed they are just sloppy you know
they just works oh it works and it's
fast that's the story of Unix on the
other hand you know and with h tons of
jargons you know cat you know the Unix
more or less all the these Unix um puns
you know they they think they are doing
they think they are Unix people but on
the other hand you can compare the
powers shell the Microsoft things they
they don't do that you know you don't
have have like cat grap set you know you
don't have that you have abbreviation
proper abbreviation called adasis and
the abbreviation is based on you
know for reasons for good you know it's
thought thoughtful they design it and
poell you know every command name is
full fully spelled full words you know
long
words and you save typing by using
completion you know proper completion
you have you have an entire system power
shell is designed so you have an entire
system abbreviation you know to solve
the problem of too much typing then you
have uh you have uh proper you know
systematic ways of options every option
name is Long names you know so you can
see you once you see the option name you
know what it does that's Powershell
every you know every Lang anything in
Computing if it's by Design you have
that characteristics property okay on
the other hand Unix is one [ __ ] you know
Unix everything you know option
everything is esoteric and you have to
you know read the man page which is
incomprehensible then then you realize
oh this man page you know they have the
Jon man page you know everything is like
sloppy Jon they they are happy that's a
Unix thing and it's incomprehensible
then you then once you learn everything
is everyone is saying oh that's a
fantastic best
thing that's the nature of Unix okay so
so so in my opinion power
shell uh is the is much better shell
than bash corn shell seashell and so on
I talked about this yesterday uh you
know for for
long uh yeah so um and uh so any you
know so that's my reason uh but in
practice I I don't have experience
coding Powers shell
so
so you know some people you know some
Unix people they will say oh actually
power shell sucks but I don't think
so the thing about Unix is that you know
so hey thank you cordz for the money I'm
going to answer your question in a
minute the thing about Unix is that you
know it's incomprehensible it's a one
[ __ ] up [ __ ] but every Unix Fanatics
you know they have slogans and jogg Unix
philosophy kiss you know uh and and dry
you know this philos this coders [ __ ]
idiots they love these incomprehensible
Jons you know dry you know this this
this is cool you know this hip so they
do that so uh uh what's my point so so
then for someone for example me and
quite a lot of people you know if you
argue with these Unix people or the C
coders you know C coders we have a big
argument in Discord about references
list versus
array jagen I don't know if jagen is
still here maybe he got angry me ranting
on him you know so so the Unix people or
you know these hacker types hacker types
okay so when I have an argument with
them you know okay so I say for example
uh Power sh is better okay but then they
CH you know they of course they disagree
they think you they say you are an idiot
you know I say they are idiot they say
you are idiot so you have to resolve the
issue you know so what's your reason you
know so they ask you H have you ever
coded Powers shell and my answer is uh
uh no actually no so they say okay so
therefore you are an idiot that is the
Unix phonetics that that's what they do
but the thing is you know that you know
Unix is esoteric incomprehensible but
once you study some particular issue for
example array versus list I studied that
for 20 years and also I studied Unix for
20 years by now you know so many issues
but Powers shell I haven't spent time to
code Powers shell but anyway every time
you argue with Unix people they will say
you don't know because you know you
don't know C you don't know C++ to this
day I don't know C okay then they say
yeah okay then you don't know so
therefore you don't know you know you
talking [ __ ] therefore Unix is
better that's the typical Unix and
archetypes in
general but you your life you know you
you have only finite time you don't have
time to study everything you know there
are 1,000 programming languages 1,000
shells you don't have time but every
time when you study Unix things such as
you know I have I studied you know so
many Unix things eventually you know
actually the Unix not just sucks they
suck stunky ass they are the worst [ __ ]
possible in documentation you know so
many things I my argument with the Unix
people I have details I have 1,000
articles I've
written on every subject you know so far
I have like 6,000
essays they don't read it by the way
they don't they don't you know they just
want to say whatever you know so anyway
so right now there's an issue I claim
that powers shell is much better because
it's designed and so on then the Unix
idiots the Unix the hacker [ __ ]
they will say oh this guy don't know you
know he hasn't coded Powell therefore
he's
wrong which is um you know that that
that is you know that is is it is not
wrong to say that of course you need to
have experience to have you know ideas
but however in programming you know each
programmer including the hacker types
you have 1,000 opinions but in your life
even if you are a professor or expert
coder you only have you know maybe you
only coded five things but there are
1,000 issues out there you only have you
only have experience with five things
you know languages or whatever you know
pretty much very small because
exponential growth of
Technology but all these Unix philosophy
you know they
they they is you know they just
um in the end you know they the
phenomenon the reason that happens is
that they are just a Cod you know that's
that's why you know the the Unix
phonetics and and and Linux and open
source it's all you know related you
know if you are a Unix fanatics you also
tends to be open source Fanatics and and
similar likewise so these these people
um these people Bush you know they don't
know things and typically and Al also
you know one one thing that frustrate me
is that they don't you know they [ __ ]
around and you know in in 10 years or
five years they are gone you don't hear
them anymore they disappeared on the
face of Earth maybe they become managers
or they they got married they are busy
with their life you know they they don't
they don't they stop doing coding
anymore and they are all the thousands
of the [ __ ] crap they posted online
it's all forgotten now they are the
manager of something you know they don't
code
anymore so I you know this this you know
so for 20 years I argued with Unix this
Unix philosophies and things change so
now today we have new generation they
don't know and all the all the crap you
know the Unix Fanatics has said and the
PE people has said today nobody knows
you know I
want I want a society that you know you
said these things you come out you are
you should be responsible it okay I want
f [ __ ] uh sting you for whatever they
have said you know they they just
disappeared you don't you cannot find
those people anymore but you can you can
still find all this crap these people
have said if you spend time to search
for it because today's generation they
are concerned about other
things that's that's how things work you
know history so it become history so
when I ranting about you know now I if I
run about Pearl or some of the uni
things today's people like oh uh what
he's talking about history history
nobody cares like like these people
today's people they have no idea what's
you know what's Netscape you know they
heard of it they don't know what's going
on they heard of a pearl they don't know
what oh yeah Pearl you know it's what
you know they don't no then I start to
run about it they oh yeah this guy is
talking about history but they don't
really care because it's history history
is usually irrelevant to what you know
your interest
today so all these Unix [ __ ] they
said tremendous every day you know like
every day online they they said Unix
philosophy this all that and you know
CRA these people they they usually just
um uh uh disappears you know they they
they are not responsible that's the
thing you know when you say something
you know when you uh
opinions you know you should have
responsibility but anyway I'm just
renting okay because who you know
everyone just Post opinions and so what
you know this is I'm just renting about
the Unix
[ __ ] so anyway I uh I was going I
was coding this emac list but coding
live
coding always usually ends up boring uh
so so I guess we digressed and more
people is watching now and now I'm
getting
hot I'm going to take off my
clothes and see what people are saying
so
I so
so C says how is goine easier to learn
than python python seems much more
simple to
me coland is much easier significantly
easier to learn than python how um so CZ
thank you for $5 so I'm going to answer
your question but but how do you have
that question in the first place did you
spend time so CZ answer okay I I asked
you questions you answer because I'm
going to answer your question now so the
question is how is Goan easier to learn
than python python seems much more
simple simple to me did you actually try
to learn
both
uh okay let me try to explain that
okay go Goan is you know uh in my
opinion but I'm 100% confident I I mean
this is a certainty there's no question
about it Goan is a is not just simpler
to learn than python but it's a
magnitude it's a magnitude easier to
learn than python because goand the
language is significantly you know let's
say twice or three time you know you you
can't really put a scale you know
quantity on it but it's s Goan is
significantly easier simpler because
it's simpler the than python so it's
easier to learn why is it simpler
because every programming language you
have usually it's implicit you have a
kind of a model how the language works
for example let me give you uh example
for example lisp lisp languages emac
lisp scheme lisp racket lisp closure uh
common lisp you know lisp languages they
have some characteristics parenthesis
and so on but basically they have a
model so the model for list language is
list processing basically list
processing that's the that's in the name
lisp so in the Lis language everything
is just about everything is a list you
all you do is processing lists so that
that is kind of the model of the lisp
languages you know so my point here is
that every language have a a model that
how the language works now this model is
usually implicit you know there's no
spec for this model but it's just
implicit you you just you can feel it
you know for example so I explained lisp
list processing for lisp that's one
example
okay okay so uh CZ you have a question
so let me explain so so so you get it so
right so lisp the model of lisp language
is Lis processing when you call lisp
family of languages typically it's all
lists okay on on the on the other hand C
language C very popular you know C and
C++ their model is some kind is is
basically a uh Hardware the
pdp1 okay like that's a that's a machine
that's a computer uh 20 years ago in
fact I have an article you
know so anyway the C language and C++ is
a d derivative of C language the C the
model of C language is basically about
man manipulating certain memory add
address is you
know things like that it's uh it's the
model is based on Hardware see you know
more specifically the PDP pdp1 machine
okay uh I have article on that okay so
let me so anyway let's stop uh emac this
coding so let's start to uh
rent so you go to my uh sad programming
tutorial then you go to um
programming languages and their
computational models okay so let's let's
let's go to S today's talk
show okay programming languages and
their computational models let's just
post
um
let's wait what uh What uh anyway this
this is the article okay programming
language uh and they are computational
models okay
now okay let me let me get back to focus
so I was saying each language has a
model uh it it works on a a computer
language needs a hardware so all
language has a a model it works on so I
mentioned list you know you work with
lists so C you work with a kind of
specific Hardware design memory
addresses and so on
and CPU instructions you know uh for
example let's say python okay python
what is the model of python python the
model of python is some is kind of op
object oriented it's a it's high level
okay so and um so that's a model python
works on I you know I cannot give you
too much detail
because because this is actually
implicit you know that's another one of
my gripes when you you know
they for many reasons it's implicit
because you you you know for example if
you read python documentation you
don't they don't they don't exactly talk
about the exactly what's a model but we
but once you learn a few language you'll
know it you you know you you know for
sure I think you know C is very
different from python right you see is
you know completely different from
python why because and different you
know list C python they are three
entirely totally different languages I
mean so what what's what's their
difference you know if you can say in
one word that's because their model you
know their comp Computing model is
different okay now exactly what's the
what's the model are they defined
specified somewhere no you know that's
just how things are okay we can we can
explain about why another time why why
don't have you know where they never
talk about their model they sometimes
mention they sometimes say you know in
if you read this documentation they will
say you know this you know we do you
know they process lists everything
becomes a list uh so python the model of
python is mostly o okay for example for
example let me give you another example
bash okay sh scripting now in sh
scripting again it's very different from
python very different from python this
or C why because in sh scripting you can
see for example in sh scripting you
never have the concept of references on
the other hand the concept of references
or pointers exist in lisp exist in
Python exist in uh C okay especially C
you have the concept of references but
in sh scripting bash you like you don't
have that
concept on the other hand in sh script
bash you have the concept of Globs very
important you know it glob you know file
Globs it is kind of uh pattern matching
for file names but that concept does not
exist in Python C or lisp instead
instead of you have regular expression I
mean but it's not it's just like you
don't have to have it you know so it's
not the core of the language for example
this Python and C they don't need Reg
expression you know it's not core
concept of their language you don't need
regular expression or glove file gloves
but in bash you know file glovs is part
of the core of the language you know
it's a important concept f file glovs so
my point here is that each language they
have they essentially they have a model
of their computation they you know the
uh model and this model is usually
implicit but you can you you know it you
know
so the so back to the question so why is
skoland uh easier to learn in than
python that is because
Goan the the language model of Goan is
very simple okay you can you know and
and this is also confirmed you know if
you read other people's blogs you see a
lot of people say it okay you almost
every blog they will say oh my God go
line is extremely easy to pick up
python you know goland model um I'm not
sure if I can explain goland model
goland model is
very um I'm not sure what's the how do
you simply explain what is the model you
know of
goand yeah it it doesn't it there's not
many Concept you know variables
functions then uh struct and interface
and that's about it you know that's
that's about it variables
functions and array of course array and
slice you know array and stroke type and
interface that's about it for Goan okay
so for those of you who don't
know I have a goine tutorial you go
there and read it okay so goine is very
simple because why because the model is
very simple now python is not okay so P
python
well uh let's go to python okay my
Python
tutorial okay so you can also Learn
Python from my tutorial uh Python 3 in
hour in one hour or you know so so this
is uh you know this is overview of the
entire language you know you have
variables you have strings you have how
to quote strings you have then uh you
have arithmetics then you have true and
forse buing in Python then you have
condition conditional if then else and
loop and list then we start to get into
data structures list Temple uh sequence
types dictionary uh you know this is a
Python tutorial in one hour okay and
then you have uh modules and functions
but anyway then you have details okay uh
building help you know so you can go and
study Learn Python for my tutorial okay
and there a poem okay there's a poem I
wrote for Python and if you go to my
Ruby tutorial there's also a poem and if
you go to my PE tutorial there's also a
poem okay so let me read out the poem
there is a python pyy Mighty Lim and
Tabby algorithm it Puffs conundrum it
snuffs and cherished by those
Savvy now this poem is written in
contrast to Pearl okay so let me show
you so there's Ruby and there is uh
Pearl okay Pearl Pearl is kind of
dead so Pearl there is a poem too there
is a camel cookie ugly loome unly
hacking it supports Tim toy It Sports
and transports Ste withs fancy okay now
there there are a lot puns puns in this
uh in this uh verse if you are a pearl
coder then you you you you understand
what it means because some of these are
you know the Pearl jargons Tim toy and
dream de
with okay and then you know uh then
pythons there's also a uh poem for
Ruby there's a germ called Ruby shiny
and pretty object objectively beautiful
functionally magical makes real of web
happy now there's is also uh in inside
the references because uh Ruby is both
object you know object oriented also
functional very functional Ruby okay and
then of course you have Ruby rails which
made Ruby the most popular back in
2008 uh then then you have the python po
okay python po so anyway so I was saying
each programming language they have a
model implicit model of how they works
now as a example you have lisp python sh
script C these four languages have very
entirely different models you know they
they work on top of and uh and so so
Goan has has you know so Goan why is
goand easier than python because
goolan it's a its model is very simple
and you can learn it you can actually
not just learn it you can Master the
entire language
in in a few days in three days you know
if you are experienced programmer you
can Master okay here's this is important
you can Master the entirety the entire
go language in three three days okay
three days or a week depending on how
you know what kind of detail you mean
but but you you can actually Master the
entire you can know everything about
Goan the language in detail in in a week
in in one in two days in a week
depending on what you mean by uh Master
okay because you can also read the goand
spec there's a goand spec it's very
short okay I can actually show you the
goand spec the language
spec but on the other hand for python
that's not the case the python is it's
actually a fairly complicated fact okay
I personally I don't like python okay uh
but I try to not when I say you know
what I just said I try to not be biased
okay I think it is true that python
objectively is I mean it's it's
absolutely true python is more complex
than Goan okay that is for sure you know
I don't want even to I don't even want
to debate it but but python whether
python is uh comp you know I think
python is fairly complicated okay
because
um for example okay CES you know I
suppose you've been coding
python um let's see where are you
suppose CZ CZ you've been coding python
you know you have some experience coding
python right I can ask you a few
questions right now and you wouldn't
know what's the
answer that is the meaning of the
complexity of the language I have quite
a few I can ask you quite a few
questions that you will be any of you
okay let's say you have one years one
year experience of coding python I can
ask you guys right now okay I'm going to
do it you know a few python questions I
bet you would not be able to explain it
properly you either don't know have no
idea or unable to answer it properly on
the other hand for Goan you cannot do
that because go you know people who
coded Goan for one year you basically
you know everything about the language
okay that's the that's the difference
the big difference between the
Simplicity of Goan and python python is
fa complex now let me ask you a few
questions okay about python this is to
demonstrate why it is complex but before
we do that let me show you my article
about why python sucks okay I don't
python there are a lot of questions
about python okay
um first of all there's why python
documentation sucks Python's
documentation sucks donkey ass it's one
of the worst documentation in Computing
industry I talked about this yesterday
and and then there's a collection of
articles about why python the language
sucks it sucks in many
ways uh the syntax and semantics okay so
let me ask you a question uh so what is
a question so so so what let me ask you
a first of first question
okay what is the difference
between here here's a question look read
it okay you assign a diction you assign
a dictionary to a empty dictionary so
that's one way to clear a dictionary
another way is you assign a dictionary
to you know dick do clear parenthesis
you know you call a method of the
dictionary what's the difference what is
the difference between them what's the
consequence answer do you know or do you
don't know that's one of the complexity
actually this this issue exist in goand
too uh
but you know but but python has a lot
more okay so let me explain let me let
me try to find some
um
um python scope complexity okay you know
I haven't I haven't coded python for uh
5 years at
least uh you know for about 10 years I
code python every day but I haven't been
coding python for uh for the past five
years because I I now switch to go land
if I need something uh you know
scripting I do go land okay
so uh okay uh copy this Shadow copy deep
copy there's a huge amount of complexity
in that but actually um let me there's a
article I want to find okay actually
it's not
here okay so actually there's another
article okay so actually let me open
python why python documentation sus and
Y python 6 okay first of all copy the
URL and put into my uh talk show today
so we have a record of what we talking
about then why python six okay also put
it here then okay here is the
um you know python has the main stanza
okay so here's the question let me ask
you if you have you know coding
experience in Python what is the main
what is the underscore underscore Main
in Python try to explain that okay try
to explain that in a way you know um you
know see if you you know try to answer
that question yourself maybe you can Ty
the answer in the in the comment box or
just think about it so anyway my point
you know I was trying to say python has
a lot of
complexities so I think that's it for
today uh yeah we how long have I been
talking so we end up talking for oh my
God 1 hour and 22 minutes oh [ __ ] now my
talk show is getting longer and longer
so
CZ do you understand end my answer so is
my answer satisfactory so let me answer
a few more questions and that's it for
today
I dinner is ready my wife is cooking
dinner is ready I'm going to go
eat why do you eat uh by the way I
saw I saw B mu hey B good uh Happy New
Year great to see you
again uh
so I gotta actually I gotta go so that's
it that's it for today so you guys go
read my Python tutorial go read my goand
tutorial go buy my my emac tutorial
okay you can you know I yeah you
don't
I uh okay well so here is my emac this
emag list practical emag lisp you go buy
my tutorial okay thank you very much and
you go to you go buy my JavaScript
tutorial that is the my best tutorial
okay my best tutorial is the the
JavaScript in
depth uh okay so I'm going to read a few
questions and uh then that's it for
today we close in five more minutes
three
minutes Jackson Bennett okay hot under
Unix color Mac was a hair almost BOS
okay so why why do I use a Mac because I
got this Mac in
2017 this is Mac mini
2014 so it's six years old I got it
three years ago ago as a gift okay
because I was very poor I got it threee
that's why uh as far as johani so I
talked about Mac versus Linux versus
Windows for quite a few times you know
that's one of the dramatic question
everyone wants to ask why are you using
a Mac or which is better should you know
Linux is better or Windows you know it's
a very frequently Asked question and I
talked about that uh two or three times
and I have article on that search for
why I switched
from Mac to Windows okay just you know
just go read my website search s why I
switch Mac for to Windows I have the
detailed
account about which is better uh you
know and so
on I'm learning a little Python and I
looked up a bit in your goine yeah so I
recommend so python you know python
today is very very very popular more
popular than Goan why it's because
Google you know because Google started
to do you know because python is one of
Google's language and Google is doing
lots of AI with python so python becomes
the main interface to go Google's AI
stuff so everyone is talking about AI
you know machine learning [ __ ] you know
so so python becomes very hugely popular
you know one of the top five languages
that is why python become popular not
because python is a great language
because Google python become popular
basically because Google two times the
first time in 2000 year 2K when Google
choose python to be their scripting
language okay that is when people
started to know about python look hey
Google is using python what what's
language what language Google is using
oh it's python oh what is python you
know that's that's a rise of python
programmers began to know there's a
language python then the second time is
around
2010 when yeah when when the machine
learning become comes you know more more
and critical you know that then then
Google is pushing python that is why you
know python is you
know you know python is not a good
language okay so Ruby is much better
Ruby is much more elegant and much more
also simpler than python to learn okay
Ruby Ruby is they are about the same
Ruby and Python and PHP and pearl they
are of the same class they do basically
the same thing Ruby PHP
python uh uh uh Pearl okay they are the
same class they do the same thing they
have about the same speed they have
about the same uh expressibility the
power of expression okay uh same high
levelness but among them Ruby is the
better one Ruby is far much better than
python more elegant and so on and
simpler to learn as well and Ruby became
very popular around 20 8 because Ruby on
Rails
however Ruby is not so popular today
because of because Google you know
Google this is this giant Empire you
know because when they push python then
python is just everywhere it's going to
be the number one language because
Google is using
it and the Geo GAO is idiotic so I I I
did a talk show about the idiocy of guo
Van rosam okay the python design that is
a good uh video about ago let just
search for you know my YouTube python uh
I don't remember which name but there's
one that I dive in depth about python I
talked about python a lot in my video so
but there's one one or two videos I
talked in depth about how Gan rosam you
know he's you know many thing many uh
you know many of the complexities of
python bad designs
I okay so uh Malik says Scotland does
pythonic better than python one way to
uh do things exactly that's a great
point you know python one of the Python
code you know python is a code you know
python is one of the language that has a
kind of a code following very strong
just like Vim Vim emx disp python
um and closure you know this for example
this language
very Cy you know these people the
community they will tell you what to do
they will tell you what you should do
what you should not do you know blah
blah every day on the other hand in comp
comparison what languages are not Cy at
all no code that was JavaScript for for
the first 20 years of its existence
JavaScript PHP no code okay PHP every
[ __ ] hacker hates PHP but PHP become
the most popular JavaScript PHP Visual
Basic no code okay they're also very
popular this you know anyway so uh so
what's a what yeah so python as a c
language you know python likes to say oh
we you know
python okay I'm getting uh into a lot
history in fact I talked about this
before python when when python became
popular back in year 2K its enemy was
Pearl because Pearl is the number one
the most basically the only one the
scripting
language and pearl slogan is there are
more than one way to do it okay there
are more than one way to do it Tim toi
that's a you know that's a Tim toy
that's the that's their
jargon uh so python when python is
around there's no comparison to Pearl
Pearl because Pearl everyone is using
Pearl nobody knows python why should I
learn python but because of Google
because Google Google becomes you know
very big company and and great it was a
great you know search engine you know
better than all of the rest and not evil
you know Google do do no evil back then
today Google is the most evil company
but back then you know how things turns
you know very sad back then Google is do
no evil and so on so Google is very uh
respected company among the hackers
among we programmers and Google's you
know Google so what what technology what
language are Google using oh they are
using Nino and Java and python okay so
Google made Java and python extremely
popular Google you know because everyone
was wants to know what pop stars what
What shirt are they wearing you know
what what shirt am I wearing they want
to know so Google is wearing python
shirt and Java so Google has a huge
Google is the one
responsible for making python uh uh uh
known you know by program
Pras and so when python began you know
python is trying to you know Pro is the
main one so python slogan is that they
you know they they have a slogan we are
uh we we are going to um you know
everything should there should be only
one way to do it you know in in contrast
to PO Pearl okay there are more than one
way to do it because Pearl the language
you know this very sloppy it's a Unix
tradition the Unix philosophy tradition
it's a very very extremely sloppy [ __ ]
you know there's no structure no you
know they they they love this J they
know whatever whatever that's that's
their that's their philosophy Unix
philosophy Pearl is like that so python
come python you know python the P gu of
rosom particular because of him he is
this kind of you know he is a
mathematician anyway yeah he he's a
mathematician but he his thinking is
very you know the way he write you know
his writing style his his uh personality
online at least you know is very
dogmatic very formal you know he tried
to you know he have a structure for
example you have the pep you know the
structure of python Community pep you
know that and they explain why the
design why you should do this and you
know they try try to do that so so come
up python his idea is that g van rosam
his idea is that in contrast to Pearl
everything there should be only just one
way to do it so that's a part of the
Python uh slogan but in fact python this
actually they are more than one way it's
not a good you know they tryed to do
that but they they they failed okay so
go
land you know actually the question you
know many languages in computer science
it's uh generally considered a great
property if in a language when you have
a task there's only one way to do it
there's no other way other way to write
it there's only this way this is a great
property many uh you know this is a
sought after property for a computer
language because once you have a that
property usually is called orthogonal
you know like everything does just one
thing if you need to do this thing you
you you you you the only way is to use
this function so when you have this
property everything is clear you know
every you know your your code is all
clear every you know it's clear what
they are doing you know orthogonal
property there's only one way to do it
so python tried to you know say they are
like like that actually they failed per
goine is more like that goine is very
much more like that you know when you
want to do something something there's
only one way to do it you Goan okay but
actually you know but you know but but
but by the way that's it's um it's
actually impossible to just have two
just to have one way to do it okay
because depending on what you mean uh
anyway so uh another question uh Ruby is
sufficient is Ruby a sufficient this
okay um I can talk about these kind of
things for 10 hours okay but that's it
for today now uh if you want to if you
want to heal my rent Ching put money on
my account and I'll talk about that okay
thank you uh CZ and see you guys Happy
New Year bye
oh let me just one mention one more
thing you know some of you have patroned
me thank you for that uh but I don't log
into patreon that much so if you have a
question patreon me okay then you can uh
message me on Twitter or Discord you
know join my
Discord or you can even email but you
know just say that you Patron me so then
I'll answer your question okay thank you
bye