good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of sound talk show today we are
going to code emac lisp we are going to
write a command to do empty trash
um Windows or Mac on Linux or
delete empty directories list empty
directories list empty files
list emacs backup delete emacs backup
so this kind of commands so it's going
to be emacs this coding good morning or
flamio and Smoky okay let's begin so let
me show my keyboard This is glove 80. I
have reviews on my website just search
for my name
glove 80. this one and this one is
Ultimate hacking keyboard both of them
are fantastic okay so let's show my
screen
yeah okay I'm good to go so let's begin
let's begin coding emac Beast now I'm
using some flag keys and you can see the
pink window is all my command course and
keystrokes on the left
okay let's uh enlarge it a little bit
okay let's let's begin coding for
example I delete this
block of text and you can see that uh
command is there if you search on the
web you'll usually find the code they
are almost all in soft like Keys it's on
GitHub okay so let's start the First
Command delete empty trash okay I'm
using stuff like this and Warrior
keyboard layout and I'm using uh HTML
mod so
okay so let's begin so the First Command
we're gonna write let's see how many we
can do it's gonna be 40 minutes
something okay emac Beast okay let's
begin
emac this code so different we want to
delete trash okay so
empty trash now how do you do it okay I
already have a command for
um
uh
uh for
um Powershell in Powershell so
search for empty
search for trash so you can see
here is the Powershell command so let's
copy it here and let's see
okay so it's very simple it's clear
recycle bin clear recycle bin is a
Powershell command
uh okay so let me show you so here is
the basically
this part is the and you can I'm using
some Powershell mod so you type
Edge tab H then it will go to Powershell
documentation
to JavaScript
and you can see clear recycle bin
so that is the command provide so all we
have to do is call this okay so call
this from emacs empty trash
you see normally I go to I turn on the
uh
you know I go through my terminal on
Windows and I can say empty
EMP EMP
the the command is actually just named
empty trash not because I empty trash so
usually I just call that and you're
empty trash but
I you know I want to do it in emacs so I
can call it the emx directly uh
alternatively you can start a Shell
let's see you see now you can start the
Powershell you can say emacs tempter
okay I don't want it there
so for example you go to uh you know you
go to you go to a
go to
the add diet
okay so actually yeah you know the
window is not wide enough let's let's
just make it wide so you go to diet and
you start the shell meta X shell and you
got Powershell and you can say duh which
is a Powershell command uh you know
things like that so
and I can now call empty trash here
and it'll do the same thing so I'm
running Powershell inside emacs
kill it yes but now today we are going
to write the emacs command so I just
meta X empty trash I don't have to go to
a shout
okay so now the trick all you have to do
basically all you have to do is call
this uh
Powershell command now the tricky part
is how do you call a Powershell command
inside emac bisp okay
and that for that
um
we can simply do
let me try this okay
shell command Okay shell command uh
let's Okay so this is the
string let's see if that works no
I don't want
special purpose so let's describe
function to look at the Shell command
documentation let's see what is the
default output buffer
uh as commands output buffer
the option or second argument I would
buffer if naneo says to Upper buffer in
some other buffer so otherwise it's
um
kids oh yeah it usually output default
to some shell output buffer okay so
anyway let's try this okay clean up the
code
uh
okay let's let's do that
now
okay
now actually first of all go to diet and
open this directory now my trash is
empty
how can I show
my trash is empty
uh it doesn't show trash here
desktop no
uh
I want to show trash
Okay so
okay there it is recycle bin okay so
let's put some stuff there
now all these are my temp files so let's
uh delete do you want to delete yes so
there's one file in recycle bin
okay and now what what to do now we yeah
render command so now
you can see Eva last six now emacs know
the command now meta XR empty trash okay
once we press enter this file should be
good let's let's see
let's see if that works
what oh you have to complete empty trash
clear recycle bin is not recognized as a
internal or external command here okay
that's expected because when you call
Shell command it's actually
um
it is
what the exactly show is it calling
I don't know but uh but we can
we can do what we want by
there are many ways okay by actually
looking at
so I want to empty trash basically now
the problem is I want to
call a Powershell command Within emacs
so how do you do I have examples I have
written code before so for example I
want to open this buffer in vs code so I
can do meta X
open vs code
okay so this file is open in vs code so
how does that command work so we can
just look up describe function uh
open vs code okay
now here's a documentation for that
command and it's in soft like keys so
this is this is how you do it in
how you call Powershell so you can see
so you have to do is
okay this is not a good example because
it's simply called code.cmd
uh
but in our case we want to call a
command in Powershell so actually I know
what's what to do
actually it's PWD uh
pwsh so let's try that
actually trial and error that's not good
actually so the best thing to do is to
go into one of my uh
my package because our diet so that
package contains
what's going on contains a lot functions
so these matching lines function so you
can see all these functions and many of
them
for example opening inkscape opening
opening iPhone view which is image
viewer on windows open in krita image
editor opening Ms paint over in text
edit so
one of these commands will do so
actually let's see opening is inkscape
so if it's windows then
okay okay this is getting complicated
we are using it's using start start
process which is more efficient than
just the shell function
uh
so let's see
yeah okay so let's uh so let's go to
some flight Keys actually
and simply search for pwsh Okay because
I've written commands for this before
oh yeah so here it is
so here is uh what you want to do shell
command and do that okay now go back to
the recycle bin
and uh
so we want to do
show command format psh pwsh
command so here is the command
instead of start process it's going to
be
hmm
uh not start process so it's just that
and no argument okay
argument we don't need
so that
okay basically eval buffer
now let's check the recycle beam there's
one file there and The Meta X
same T trash do it
fantastic you can see the trash is good
so
we completed that so this is basically
this is just this command
so far so good
uh documentation okay let's put some
documentation
version
today's date
now right now this function only works
for Windows
so you want to add some kind of
condition so that on Windows you call
this command on Linux you call some
other command Okay so so what you want
to do is
condition so this gives you several
options so first of all
uh
system type
so if system type is equals to let's see
what is the available system type that's
a variable so you describe variable
and you can see the documentation so
that is the type so if the season type
is Windows Dash NT then
this is what you want to do
fantastic otherwise
um otherwise
and let's put some more so
so otherwise if it's canoe Linux not
Linux but canol Linux then you do
something new okay for now
now if it's mag which is the system type
is Darwin city name
by the free software Foundation people
they don't want to name it Mac OS well
that Darwin is kind of the open source
version of Mac OS so if so if it's Mac
then you do something
now I don't remember exactly what is the
directory for trash on Linux you know I
think it may depend on distro so if we
can just leave it for now okay so if
none of this match then you just say
true then do nothing new okay
so basically here is a complete Command
for empty trash
now we if you are on Linux you can add
you know what to do on Linux
okay I think that's it
uh empty trash
um
Linux
mag
okay that is a complete code now back to
the HTML showing browser
there it is back to emacs
format them back to browser refresh
fantastic we have one command let's
continue to next command
or flamio says
there's a shell variable uh trash
okay what do you think about obsidian
I forgot what that is
okay it's a stone
this ambiguation
it's a software something
oh a note-taking software I'm not into
note taking software and I'm not much
into not taking itself because it's one
of the fashion you know there are many
systems that tells you open mind or My
Mind Tree mind graph or whatever
My Philosophy is that
if you need to do note taking
then you are procrastinator okay how do
you reach how do you deal with
procrastination you don't deal with it
that's the final solution
procrastination the first thing you want
you you deal with it is that you
you know you are a procrastinator
accepted then
you know just do what you have to do
that's you know that's
all these self-help things you they
usually do not help the most important
thing is you have to set your mindset
right
you know you have to make yourself
uh realize that you have potential or
you are necessary or you want to do
something
you have a desire then you don't need
all this self-help because the innermost
power is come from came from your desire
which in part is your personality so if
you have if you have problems with uh
that kind of thing you want just to
relax
uh
you know seek friends who can help you
or who appreciate you you know you want
encouragement
uh you know that
might help okay so obsidian is not
taking yeah I I'm too old to look into
these different softwares so for some
circumstances such as when you're
studying mathematics
proof Theory type Theory homotopy type
Theory then you want to take notes or
when you are learning emacs you know or
programming language python Golan so on
Powershell so in those cases you want to
take notes
uh but otherwise I don't like
to do you know the to do kind of stuff
unless you are you know a businessman or
Professor you have a lot of schedules
then yeah but otherwise I don't do that
so anyway we finished one command let's
continue to next command
let's see which one we want to write uh
empty directory
okay DD emacs backup okay
so
okay so we have emacs backup
we have released backup delete backup
either way okay so let's let's write a
TV backup okay
uh emac Beast so we start another
function define
delete
Emax back up okay
version
today's date
and some documentation
DD emx
back up files
okay with a Toyota
in current recursively
okay because normally if you just want
to delete
the font is too large actually so let me
just shrink it
okay so maybe that's better
so normally if you are in the ad diet
and you have some files you want to
delete you can simply press the what
you can simply press the
Toyota sign and it will highlight all of
them then you can just
press X
then you ask you do you want to delete
them to say yes say yes and they are all
gone so but that doesn't work for nested
directories so if you have necessary
directories that doesn't work so that's
what this command will do
Okay so
in order to do that
so we want to delete them in current so
this command will be con convenient so
you just delete all necessary
directories of the current wherever this
file is at uh you don't have to go into
shell or diode
so okay so first of all
default okay default
um not DD directory
default
the
default directory is a variable that
contains the directory your current
buffer or file reset for example we can
evaluate it
uh Eva last sex
you can see
right now my current directory is that
okay so that is the variable and you
want to Traverse okay so let's write it
down
Traverse the default list or names
ending in Toyota okay then
delete them okay that's that's what we
want to do okay so now we want to
Traverse the how do you do that
I don't remember offhand so you search
for Sardi lisp
emac Beast Basics you'll find how to so
in this case you want to go to emacs
list practical emac disp and you want to
go to
text processing get user input files and
buffers file and directory work
directory that's what you want so this
is the file you want
I mean this is a function you want
directory files okay
okay so but this function does not
recurse into subdirectories so if you
want subdirectories you want this
function directory files recursively
okay so great
directory files recursively there it is
we have a shortcut fantastic so the
directory will be
default directory and the regular
expression will be
uh anything
ends in a Toyota sign
okay and optional include directories so
what does the optional include
directories mean
include directories option argument
include directories the Neo means also
include in the output directories whose
name
all right
local slash share uh download code slash
share slash trash that's a trash
location on Linux thank you
uh so what is so what is this uh
oh that means so the includes
directories means should the output
include directory so as opposed to files
yeah we don't want okay so we just want
files Okay so
that will give uh so so here's what we
to do we declare a variable
so at least the path and set a list of
path to be that
uh what am I doing
so let's let's make them larger okay
okay so we have a bunch of
file path
now we want to map a function to all
these file path basically delete them
okay but before we do that we can simply
run this code to make sure it runs
correctly before we go further Okay so
leave out the
about the
um
even less says sex
and uh then we just call this command
Okay copy it
okay it should return a list of files
now
now let's
in the in this current directory so
let's make a new directory first
um
so new directory XX okay
uh
okay then create some random files
okay go to the directory so that's a
random file close it make a backup
and make make backup okay so anyway we
have several
now go up one directory
close it close it okay now if we call
delete
we call it it should list them okay
let's try it
so there's a new feature in emacs 29
where you press Ctrl U 0 first then you
call
uh
coalesced six
do that so you get the full list result
in the buffer okay now let's change them
into lines so you can see it worked
because it included
subdirectories okay now you got the
files now it's very easy all you have to
do is to
map a function
okay and what function you want to map
to delete files so the sequence is the
sequence is the bunch of file paths and
what the function what do you uh what
the function do you want DVD file okay
so let's look up the documentation for
delete file
delete file file name optional trash
okay delete file file name optional
trash okay so that's gonna be just X
uh in fact you just
there
it will map the function delete file to
each and every of these so let's try it
okay
Eva eval
okay and now let's go to the directory
let's open this directory
refresh it's all good fantastic
okay it's fantastic now
in fact we are done but what we want is
to
um
let's see uh
what we want is to let's see
let's make a backup again
close that
we want when we call this command x.d
Max backup we wanted to print a list of
files that's deleted
to to the message buffer yeah okay so
the question now is what delete file
does what does it return Okay so
okay so let's try
copy final path close close okay we're
gonna test this delete file function
delete file okay
okay now we want to know what does it
returns so run it
it returns new okay so let's see yeah it
returns new so it doesn't return the
file path so in that case what you have
to do is okay you just put file path at
the bottom
uh actually
you know in case some file didn't get
deleted then the return value will be
wrong
so rather so let's modify this instead
we use a Lambda
okay
Lambda so so what does Lambda do the
Lambda will delete the file okay then
then return it
if it's successful now how do we know if
it's successful let's look up the
documentation for delete file again
DD file named that if it's a Sim link
remove the sim link if it's multiple
names continue to exist okay trash in
the neon means that we call
interactively uh change into the other
okay
it doesn't say successful or not
and this is written in C code it it
doesn't
it does not give you an indication where
the delete X is successful or not
yeah okay so
okay there's nothing you can do so yeah
in that case we just
return that okay so in fact let's
so let's remove that in fact we want to
print each one of them
uh
do we want to print each one of them
usually there's gonna be hundreds like
in my use case usually this this hundred
so do we want to print them or not
I guess not let's just returned value
okay so actually this this is it
this is the function uh and uh
Okay so
let's make sure it still works okay
evaluated remove this
uh and now
meta X star DD emacs backup do it
okay what does it return it doesn't
return anything
uh
wait why does it not return anything
oh okay because you I was using the
metallics so go to the directory again
you know so it's good right
okay so this is the this is the delete
Emax backup
uh
okay so that's successful now this
should be cleaned up because
there is the issue of whether you want
to print
those files that are deleted or not
um
anyway so that's the you know the first
draft okay so go back to HTML color it
show in browser
so we got two commands
done
okay let's try another command then
empty trash least empty the uh
okay list empty the will be
slightly tricky
how am I doing how are you guys doing
oh yeah so you guys are talking about
the trash in Linux you know actually I
have an article on that
Linux trash but it's fairly old uh kind
of outdated by a few years so Rita in
2013 so you have the command gvfs trash
that will uh oh wait this is uh deleting
a file to trash
okay now on Linux you know the gvfs
was standing stand for Canon
virtual fire system something but they
kept changing so I don't know if it
still exists anyway the trash directory
is yeah these locations
again I don't know if it's up to date or
not but the dot local share trash is
probably still
but anyway the the trash and Linux
system is very bad very very bad because
I remember 10 years ago I was trying to
delete a few hundred files on a USB
stick and it just stuck stuck there it's
like
um anyway
uh so
so we have so what we want to write so
yeah what's a comment
usual path Okay so hexa
ice mods isomat
I got myself a glove 80 fantastic and it
feels like I'm relearning to type again
reminds me the times that I was learning
Haskell
fantastic
when's the next rant uh you pay me I'll
do a rent you know
PayPal meat you know or Super Chat
something and uh put up a topic of rent
and I'll give it to you
okay
so how long have we been 40 minutes
already so what else we want to write
let's see
um
yeah so we can we can you know we can
write another command
list empty files okay
yeah okay let's try that this anti this
npt files okay
okay emacs this
show Pink window
pop out
the fun
list
empty files
okay and let's copy some of the
documentation so we don't have to type
everything again
okay
uh
list empty
files in current directory recursively
that's correct
okay
so okay so but basically just like
before
so let's copy the code just like before
we have two
recursively dive into directory
okay
and in this time
this time
this time the
empty files so empty files you don't
have a regular expression anything will
we want everything so let's look up
documentation for directory files
recursively
so regular expression is
required option required required
parameter
okay so regular expression is a required
parameter so in that case it's just Dot
a DOT matches anything
uh
yeah I suppose
so now what we do now so we have a list
of files
let's show it
Okay so
do you need that we can actually try it
so go to the diet
go to this we just made open it delete
the text save it go back to diet refresh
now we can see it's zero bytes empty so
we have one empty file
okay make a copy make a copy so you see
all these empty files okay
close wait uh
let's copy the directory name close
close and paste the directory name here
so we can open it easily
by jumping to it
that's the command is Excel open file at
Cruiser now in emacs if you are using
plain glue emacs you have a command
called
find file at point which is basically
the same thing
okay close that
now so we got a bunch of file paths so
let's just show it okay
Eva buffer so now emacs no the command
now eval is
uh
oh so okay it returned a lot results
okay so let me do it again
control
U 0 Eva last six so here is a complete
result list it's huge
okay now
make them into a line lines
so you can see all these files are
supposed to be empty so let's check
actually it's correct because you see
this file we created it's empty so we
can open this one
okay it's incorrect
see it's not empty oh yeah obviously
because you you did not check for uh the
file size yet so you need to check file
size okay
so let's see
what's the function for file size
oh we don't wait so we need a function
for file size
so let's go back to emacs this tutorial
file and directory
I don't think I ever used
a function that gives you the file size
so we need to look up emacs manual let's
see
fire path
yeah so let's look up emacs manual file
information about files
file attributes there
file attributes
oh God this is gonna be
okay I think I think after we write this
and that'll be it today
file endings right now we need a
function that tells us the file size
thank you
her family is paying for someone else's
topic so
so who's got the topic
Spade
it's just a problem with USB stick
okay
now what is that so okay so now we need
a function that Returns the file size
so maybe it's these file attributes
I have never
in emac bisp
tried to do this before
so you got there it is file attribute
size the size of file in bytes okay
so this is a function file attributes
and returns a list of attributes of file
okay if the uh
let's just try file attributes file name
in optional ID format okay let's just
try it
there it is that's what we want okay so
file attribute now let's try it so let's
just paste it here copy the current
buffers file path put it here and let's
run it and see what it returns okay so
Ctrl U
okay so oh God this is nasty
okay so I guess
yeah
this is rather nasty
so you have to so this is what it
returns so but you have to
decrypt it like you want to get the part
that's file size
so the element of the listing order are
okay in order so size is number seven
okay
size number seven so you can say nth
seven okay so there it is
oh seven not two
okay you can see let's try again
there it is twenty six three five four
go to diet there it is indeed true so
that's the
so we got the file size okay so this is
how you do file size okay
now
okay now you need to integrate it into
this function here
so for each path
so you want to map function
if the file
the size is zero then
okay then you want to delete those okay
so now we create another variable X
empty okay
empty files let's just give it a better
name
so set empty files equal to
equals to You're Gonna Do
map uh how you're gonna do this
so we want to Traverse we want to map a
function to all X path
for each one you check the file size
okay so if it's equal
it's let's see uh three three yeah so we
can use equal EQ to check integer
comparison so if
it's zero
okay
and over here
it's
x file that X means the file okay so if
that's it's uh if that is true you want
to return it
okay so one way is one way to do this is
you you declare empty files to be a
empty list okay
uh so
instead of set you you don't set okay so
let me do it this way
yeah because you cannot map to it uh
actually you can but let's let's do it
this way okay so let's do it
this is kind of
not a functional way but it is a lisp
idiom
let me show you okay so what you do is
you map
for side effect you map a function to a
bunch of file paths and for each
function Lambda you check
you check if this is true okay so if
instead of if we can just just say when
when this is true then you push
that file to
to the list of empty files okay
so this is how you do it okay so let's
actually do more cleanup yeah this is
hideous and anyway so you know this so
much indentation
so anyway so this
will do it
uh in fact this part actually we can
just move it here too
so that's more symmetric so we have two
variables
okay then we map if it's zero size we
push it to empty files then we return
empty files okay
so
evaluate the function
call it there it is now
let's let's do it again okay so remove
this part
control
U 0 Co last sixth
okay it's still huge I think we still
got it wrong
let's open this file oh that's correct
let's go to the diet zero you see
correct
let's open this file it's empty correct
open this file empty correct so if you
go to diode you see right now let's
shrink okay so you can see
now they are arranged the file are
arranged by name by file name so this
this these are my 10 files
every time I have a buffer that's not
empty and I close it it will be saved
into this temp directory just in case I
want it back so periodically I delete
you know a whole bunch of files here but
in the past some of the file is zero
size you see zero zero so I want to sort
this dial directory to see on you know
to sort them by file size so I can call
a command
uh I have egg sauce salt
diet Salt yeah
let's do it again
diet sword okay
do it and okay complete sort by
size
okay so now you can see all the files
are sorted by size now if we go all the
way to the bottom
you can see we have all these zero
uh file of size zero okay so now we go
back to our code
oh we have so this code is basically
correct let's check a few
open it it's empty
open it it's empty so it's all basically
all correct okay so now remove that
basically this is our code okay let's
clean up
this is uh this you know you know this
it's got this issue so anyway this let's
put it this way
so Eva that so now one more thing we
need to do we want to map a
delete file oh this is actually just
these empty files okay so
yeah this command is just this uh this
empty files so we just so that's that's
it
that's it actually we can print them so
let's print them okay
so instead so we don't have to like
manually you know do stuff so let's
print them
okay map function
to
empty files
actually we want to return empty files
map car
actually map C so map function so all we
have to do is just
message it okay
uh
evaluate it and
delete that code
list empty files do it okay now go to
messages buffer now you can see
these are
all the files
fantastic okay now let's meanwhile let's
just write another command to delete
them okay so
delete
TV empty files so all we have to do now
is just to call the list
map a function to it and this function
will delete it
okay so this function will just
DD the file okay
that's it
okay so we first of all get the list and
let's let's just call it okay
evaluate it and now
X start delete empty files do it okay
now drop to directory add
can you see all these empty files at the
bottom now type G to refresh do it it's
all good
fantastic
okay so now we got two files
this I mean we got two functions
color it show in HTML so today we wrote
basically three functions okay let's
look what do you think of Norman
wee buggers criticism of the real number
system
it's a tough question
or Flavio I don't know the answer okay
because I don't even know
my weed Burger criticism of the real
number system let's see who he is
Divine proportions rational trigonometry
to Universal trigonometry
tangential thoughts
mathematical ruminations you know that
so far this guy looks like a crackpot
you know in mathematics there are a huge
number of crack parts
you know but so far the way you know
these titles this homepage you know it
sounds like a crackpot but we don't know
for sure so we let's look at
um
this Wikipedia and what is his name
Norman wilburg okay let's search for
Norman
okay so so
Divine proportions rational trigonometry
to Universal trigonometry is a 2005 book
by the mathematician Norman J wielberg
on a proposed alternative approach to
euclidean geometry and trigonometry
called rational trigonometry okay so
it's a proposed alternative approach to
euclidean geometry and trigonometry okay
Ukrainian geometry and trigonometry so
it's a low level high school level
geometry
but it's taking a he's trying to
use a alternative approach probably
meaning teaching
you know is it teaching or Foundation
we'll find out
and
currently it's proposed okay so that's
why I say it's a crackpot like I mean
this is not part of the
established mathematics but let's read
on the book Advocates replacing the
usual basic quantities of trigonometry
euclidean distance and angle measure
by square the distance and the square of
the sign of the angle
okay so you replace the concept of
distance the you know the standard
concept of distance in euclidean
Geometry by the squared distance okay
and you replace the standard concept of
angle by the sign of the angle okay and
this is logically equivalent to the
standard standard development
as the replacement of quantities can be
expressed in terms of standard once in
vice versa
yeah okay the author claims his approach
holds some advantages such as avoiding
the need for irrational numbers okay I
can see
um
you know so he basically want to replace
the
cons the sense of Distance by square
distance and the sense of angle by
by sine of the angle
while everything Remains the Same so you
know it's just the extra
step
so but his argument is that when you do
this
things will become simpler in particular
you will avoid
irrational numbers okay
okay so so the book was essentially
essentially self-published okay that's
typically what
crackpots do
uh but I mean not necessarily bad I mean
he you know but anyway overall this is
Trivial I mean this is not a like a
significant advancement it's actually
it's just
it's nothing much you know it's just
um nothing much it's not a theory
he just believes that if you do this
Things become simpler you avoid
irrational numbers
um
uh I guess that was so that means you
avoid
you will avoid irrational numbers in in
distances
right so because normally for example if
you have a right angle let's say a
triangle of equal
you know with two angles at right angle
and they are the same length and the
other part is hypotenuse you know
hypotenuse something so the distance of
that is x squared plus y squared
and square root right
but now if you use his way his approach
where the distance is replaced by square
of the distance
so if you use his approach then then the
distance of the hypotenuse is no longer
the square root it's just x x squared
plus y squared
right so in that way you get rid of
irrational numbers
um
you know but we have to think about what
are the consequences I mean okay so
overview the main the idea of divine
proportion is to replace Distance by
that and and which he calls it quadrants
okay and to replace angle by
by the squares of their signs Oh by
squares of the signs okay
oh yeah by the square of sine not just
sine okay
and which he calls spread you know this
these scrap Parts usually have a lot of
jargons okay so Divine proportions
Define both of these concept okay
for real Burger a finite test this
replacement has a purported advantage of
advantage of avoiding the concept limits
actually Infinity use in divining real
numbers okay
okay uh organization and topics okay
audience critical reception okay let's
see
okay it's mostly positively
received okay what is your question
so what do I think of it
Open Access only 12 pages okay
okay so let's let's quickly see what is
overall picture so
let's see this critical exact uh
critical reception
so but overall this is Elementary
geometry I mean there's no big theory
about it
uh
okay uh
this you know he will take a a while to
actually review yeah but so far it's
just the basic
geometry so it says an advantage of
wheel Burgers methods noted by Hindi is
that because they involve only simple
algebra the proofs are both easy to
follow and easy to our computer to
verify however He suggests that the
book's claim of Greater Simplicity in
its overall Theory less than a force
comparison in which quadrants in spread
are
waited not against the corresponding
classical concept of distance angles and
signs but the much wider set of tools
from classical trigonometry he also
pointed out to a student with a
scientific calculator I don't think it's
I don't think it's good
yeah so in general in summary my quick
review is that this is nothing but as
the as today's
slang it doesn't do anything
it's not a new Theory it's not a new
field it's simply that he thinks by this
extra calculation you
you avoid irrationals but
to what degree I'm not even sure you can
yeah
so anyway that's the that's the article
okay so apparently there is another book
or article real numbers a critique and
the way forward okay let's look at that
maybe
okay so so far my impression this is
this is
um is this is kind of Crack part thing
okay I don't think you should buy it uh
this is kind of you know doesn't do
anything I mean even though you
mentioned you know real numbers critique
and forward that's crap you know because
that idea he's talking about real
numbers you know he's already he's kind
of already showing it here so he's
saying that if you don't want irrational
numbers this is what you do but that's
that's just you know that's just adding
an extra computation
you know
um
so now what I am interested so far is to
look into the background of this sky
so you know he self-published this book
and this is his home page and he's uh
you know it doesn't does it say he's a
professor of anywhere
oh he is a professor okay
so let's look at his uh so he's a
professor so I mean he's not a you know
some crazy
guy but
he's a professor of mathematic
mathematics he teaches mathematics but
he has this idea
which is you know he he's got this idea
that he think he's better in
okay so he has written
yeah anyway so he's a mathematician
right he's a
you know uh
at least he's a recognized mathematician
a professor
so there is nothing wrong what with what
he says
but
I think it's not necessarily
you know the
significant
welcome to algebraic Calculus 1 2001
hello algebraic calculus one course lot
live so of flamio I need you watch a lot
math videos is
amazing but are you I think you know I I
think you know if you are really
interested you want to dive into
Hands-On become a mathematician
because otherwise what you're gonna do
with this you know like
um
same thing with programming
okay so an elementary course in pure
method mathematics meant for a very
broad audience okay he so he write a lot
but
but you know judging on these titles you
know it's just like going nowhere
Archimedes parabolic area formula for
cubics okay
pimpton
primp 10 322 and
Babylonian exact sexy small trigonometry
okay
yeah this you know he is let's endanger
our children you know this
you know they are not important theories
or
upcoming talk on Google gold back
conjecture okay some exciting news I
will next month be giving a talk okay
we'll resolve the gold back conjecture
that is a rather famous conjecture okay
the talk will be in pure mathematics
colloquium on November 2016 at
University
yeah he's you know it's not significant
you know it's like
you know but it's not yeah but you know
it's
I wouldn't you know I I would not for me
I would not spend time to look into it
yeah that's my that's what I think
no finally let's look at that real
number book let's see
so he's one of the big math fan
foreign
this is just a single natural number to
get a fraction we need two natural
numbers separated by forward slash
how
okay that's how he looks he's got quite
a few videos
yeah but basically
and see inside into mathematics let's
click on his
home page
box arithmetics
staff notation
uh old guy sharp in Flats music
box arithmetics
uh yeah so mostly just elementary math
yep
so that's my opinion I don't think it's
significant and I would not that's not a
Direction I want to go if I'm gonna
study more math
okay that's it for today
oh 70 minutes okay thank you guys for
watching
bye
so we wrote three commands three or four
okay