good morning welcome to another episode
of sun talk show today's topic is random
so you ask me questions I answer okay
hello guys so don't forget to PayPal me
okay or uh Super Chat you know PayPal is
better because when you do Super Chat
Google takes almost half 30 or 40
percent
so any questions no questions so no
questions I'm just going to talk about
you know what I have been doing uh in
past month it's been a while
since my last video it's been like uh
first uh okay it's been uh almost a
month okay so let's talk about let me
let me talk up let me show you my
keyboard first again again this is glove
80 keyboard I have a review on my
website glove 80s just search for
excited and this is Ultimate hacking
keyboard version two I also have a
review fantastic what's up dude so okay
so questions okay questions and pay me
PayPal me and say you paid or Super Chat
okay so emacs so I did a lot emacs a
you know Excel packages you know I have
a lot of packages in the so smart
packages you can see there's quite a lot
packages and quite a lot update in the
past month or two
uh and uh you know one of my most famous
package is stuff like keys this is a
fantastic efficient emacs key binding
system uh the stadium feature is that
you don't have to press Ctrl or meta
almost none
and this is my most popular packages so
if you have not already if you are emacs
user try it okay and the the news is
that there are a few change of keys
about four of them
so that their keys are not more
efficient ergonomic based
so one question have you ever worked at
Google or big name like that no well I
happen to not have worked for the past
20 years more or less in you know but
before that I work at uffam research
kind of for half a year and notopia uh
uh General networks the company which is
changed to something else then web order
that's a that's around year 2000 1998
starting uh startups and the web order
uh that that is the first online
store for example like Yahoo store like
like Amazon but we create the the
backbone the server that lets other big
companies like Yahoo others to support a
online store
so
Yahoo search Yahoo Verizon bought a
product web order web order Okay so
so I started you know a few companies
but the most the big one is weborder.com
which got bought by notopia.com notopia
is famous for making a MAG it mag screen
sharing you know remember this is 1999
1990s not like today internet is super
slow and you don't have much like live
stream you don't have that so back then
if you want to share your screen across
uh among two people for example one is
in a different state you know remotely
you can share your screen that and that
is available on the Mac the product is
called Timbuk2 that's one of the most
popular product on the Mac screen
sharing that that's like the the killer
app you know because there's none like
that so you can share your screen and
work together on the same you know on a
computer so Timbuk2 is made by notopia
notopia but web order which is the
company I work for then
then then 2002 I I got laid off then
around 2004 2006
notopia got bought by Motorola okay so
there's a lot changes companies dying
come and go so and basically since 2002
I have not really worked in a
corporation
it just just so happens you know uh with
my life
being like that
so yes I was in Champaign Illinois I was
actually there for half a year yeah
uh that's how I met Stefan Wolfram and
that's how I you know because during the
1990s I was going to be a you know
mathematics is the one thing I love so I
studied a lot math and I bought the
Wolfram the Mathematica the product of
Wolfram research uh and uh so I mastered
it you know literally like I'm one of
the top master of Mathematica back then
it's called Mathematica
then about 10 years ago they changed
they added the name wolfam language that
described the language Mathematica uses
but basically essentially it's the same
thing Mathematica and Wolfram language
uh so that's how I got into woofam uh
you know and so I actually lived there
Illinois Champaign Illinois you know
that's a countdown cow done country
when you uh when you wake up in the
morning the first thing you smell is
done
uh that that was then and it's pretty
much still the same
Champagne Illinois Okay so
so Google Google is a sad story but
anyway I did apply one time uh that was
during 2010
13 or so I was pretty bad I was
um you know I was about to die for lack
of food
literally uh and uh I didn't do well but
anyway the the Google interviewer we I
got a
idiotic Indian the interview experience
is extremely bad you know I don't have a
phone I don't even have a phone I don't
have money to pay you know twenty
dollars a month I don't have a cell
phone or anything
so I told them I cannot use the phone I
want to use internet but they forgot
they you know the
I was talking to the interviewer women
usually you know I mean I mean the the
the
um
the the person the Headhunter the person
who
who got me into to to take the interview
is uh
a woman
so I told her I I you know the interview
the date and we are going to use the
internet
um
some online software but then the actual
date the guy who happens to be a idiotic
Indian very very insulting you know and
he he did he he forgot he doesn't know
yeah I mean he wasn't told or something
like it's totally completely bad
experience
so uh what else have you considered
kensington's slim blade
Pearl
a good Mouse
uh yes so let's go to my Excel keyboard
okay so let's let me show you let me
share your uh share screen so you can
see my swing Saudi keyboard now let's uh
let's
uh let's see
wait where's the whole key let me turn
on
um
slim slim blade yeah that's the
trackboard so let me show you let me
talk about that that's for so first but
first of all let's enlarge the font size
okay so keyboard blog
and uh search it and you'll find it so
trackball let me talk about trackball I
talked about this a thousand times
already in my past videos so far you
know by now I've done actually a lot
videos like if you look at here I've
done like
about 300 videos uh most of them live
stream I started to do live streams
since about a year ago
exclusively live stream because I think
that's a better
I don't want scripted you know I prefer
real life talking to you guys I don't
like scripted video which tends to uh
become fake and uh
not spontaneous so anyway by now I've
done like for example let's count okay
so let's count how many uh
how many
554 so about oh my God 500 videos so
sometimes I got a comment you know like
two days ago I got comment you know my
of one of my old video and they say oh
this or that but usually I don't
remember what is the context what is the
topic exactly so if you're gonna comment
I do please do comment okay but
post the date the timestamp so I know
exactly what you are talking about
but usually I don't reply uh because you
know people online they don't they don't
they don't spend time they don't have a
brain and the same question you're gonna
answer a thousand times uh you know that
which is actually normal I mean I can't
blame the people because that's that's
normal who is gonna watch your 100
videos one hour each month you know each
um so yeah I have done a lot of videos
so so about trackball I talked about it
many times sometimes the whole hour
dedicated to track both so the question
is about slime Blade no slime blade so
this this mouse okay so I would say that
this top three so the L track
okay this one and the Kensington expert
this one and the Slime blade this one
okay and uh and then this Ella
huge trackball this fall
I would consider in general they are
generally considered the best trackball
the best big ball trackball okay each
one of them is about 55 milligo
millimeters ball they are about the size
of a um billiable you know the American
period so but
you know so so for a trackball usually
the bigger the ball is the better so
these four are generally considered by
all the people of the best because I've
read literally read hundred thousands
of everything said about them online
because I used to
in the past you know uh
five years or so in the past not not
you know around
2010 to 2018 let's say I read everything
there is you know like for example this
re for this example this trackball on
Amazon usually there are hundreds of
reviews you know you know little
comments I read
every one of them you know for for all
these 100 trackballs so that's why I
know and not just Amazon because they
are also you know uh desk Authority
which is Hackers kind of very nerd
online Forum talking about keyboard and
trackboards so usually they have good
information and they also have great
information about how to hack you know
for example there are many
um how they call mod
modification you know do it yourself
modification of the trackball and how
the trackball you know they take it
apart for example this guy is one of the
top experts with rickster
I'm not sure he's still active but
ripster is one of the top let's say top
five
uh person who knows about keyboard and
mouse and he so for example here this
picture is his picture of his photo and
he modified the l-track track ball so
that it lights up and also added two
extra buttons and also he modified this
track but that that one that one what's
her name that one is dt225 okay uh that
one is also the best okay but hard to
buy so this one actually has a uh
bearings you know most of these track
well they don't have bearings anyway so
he modified it so you can see also he
modified this um
space Navigator device with a IBM
selectric typo that's that's another
hackers thing
the IBM's electric typo you know very
popular one of the hacker law
IBM's electric because IBM's electric is
is one of the best
typewriter you know the best actually
the best typewriter with the with the
with the ball which is a complete
Innovation the new you know it types by
by by twisting the boat I actually I
used it in uh around 1990
to 1992 when I was my first job as a
secretary you know helping the
corporations helping the sales marketing
you know typing letters and stuff so my
first job is actually data entry and
they dictate you know the sales person
they dictate and I type it out usually
they type they they they they want to
write the sales letter you know D or
something something your situation your
claim or whatever uh because uh that
they type they they speak it and I type
it so this is around 1990 one
for about two years I was a
secretary actually secretary so yeah
IBM's electric so you can see this
Reaper guy so you know so I have got I
got tons of fancy photos Kinesis
Advantage a great keyboard
um
yeah ripster is one of the top expert
I'm not sure if he's still active so you
can also see the mechanisms you know
these nuts they take it apart they show
you what's inside
so this this is one of the best
trackball
okay so which one exactly is the best of
them all that is not a settled question
because different people have different
preferences but in general these four
okay so your question so
so of these uh the L track is actually
very old this l-track is not new it's
actually 30 years old or 40 even so
let's see yeah here you can see
it was called
micro speed PC track trackball 1991 it
looks like that you know basically the
same thing night you know you see the
floppy disk 1991 that's right and the ad
on PC
um what what is this magazine I think
this is PC Magazine or something
so you can see you know the old act so
so anyway the point is this trackball is
very old uh over the the past 30 years
the company changed hands so actually
it's no longer made you know like two
years ago they got sold again to
you know it was made by CST but they got
sold again to X Keys now X Keys is
another famous company
okay I started to digress but X Keys is
another uh
uh very famous famous kind of popular in
1990s and 2000s they make keyboard
marquels
this is before like today you know today
you have a lot of software you know
after all you we are in the AI age
artificial intelligence so we have a lot
of technology and do it yourself and you
can create your own chips I mean not
create but buy chips and assemble
yourself but this is 1990s okay x-keys
macro keypad I recommend it you can go
and buy it from one of these you know I
I show you I tell you which one is the
best programmable keypad review okay now
let's go back so trackball
so so right now they sold to the X Keys
company so that's that's the L track so
about slim blade slim blade I actually I
never used it I never owned it but
that's considered one of the best okay
that's all I have to say I don't really
know uh
yeah so I do have a trackball but right
now my trackball is
I I have this one for example is
the this one the physical design it's
one of the best okay but however this
thing is like 30 20 years old they have
not upgraded so actually I do not
recommend this one okay and it's pretty
cheap today but if you want to buy one I
actually I can recommend this one okay
this one is widely widely considered one
of the best but the ball is not a huge
one
I don't have it but I do have the one I
have now is uh I have both of these okay
I have this one you know the one you
know I have all these three so
so
okay so I I have that one but I don't
use it but it's
um you know because I have so many
devices now uh and this one I had I
bought about two years ago is
it's okay okay it's not it's not that
great I would I wouldn't say but it's
great especially
I'm using it in uh when lying in bed
that's this this one I'm using
so but anyway I recommend if you ask me
to recommend one trackball for you right
now I I would say this one okay
Kensington orbit trackable with square
ring important with important this one
okay look at the picture because there
if you search Kensington orbit there's
quite a lot because a lot of them named
orbit
uh I can show you I have a tribal
history page but anyway look at this one
so this guy modified the the square ring
to be spinning so it can spin fantastic
okay so anyway so
when you buy a trackball one of the most
um great thing is that you want the ball
to spin
essentially none of them do that but but
ideally you want to be able to push it
and it just spins keep spinning for you
know four or five seconds but none of
them does that
uh but however it's possible it's just
that nobody made it because I have a
video
I collected over the past 10 years I
collected all videos that shows spinning
trackball so let me show you where okay
so let me find it uh
trackball versus mouse how to how to
choose a trackball that's one article
best trackball so here's the you know
like I said some of the best one
uh then there is an article about
spinning ball so let me find it
trackballs trackballs that can spin so
here's a collection of videos so this
one really spins
you know you push it it can spin for
five ten seconds fantastic but nobody
actually made it so I if you know what
happened to this one this is a concept
but
uh I don't think anyone ever made it so
anyway so here's a collection of you
know so collection of trackball videos
or information about spinning trackballs
so
and some of them are made by do it
yourself for example this one he
modified it if you want the ball to spin
the one thing you have to do is that you
have to ins you have to install ball
bearings
uh that's like this one okay so for
example this one this guy modified it so
it also spins this is Slim blade
you see fantastic that's the most
beautiful so but but nobody is making it
now I mean there's no actual ones as far
as I know uh that actually does spin
uh this actually this one is actually
used ball bearings but this one is
another one that's hard to buy this i t
a c tripod it's hard to buy it that one
actually spins uh ball bearing
okay I think that's about trackball okay
so you can
um so that's my opinion so let me read
other questions comments okay
hello from Brazil sick turn would you
consider okay so next question
Sid Stefan Wolfram yeah so I'm going to
go back to do Stefan wolfen's you know
do mathematical wolfam language it's
been three months I haven't done any
what's my monitor resolution okay so for
that you just search for xali
monitor resolution you'll find several
articles
okay so here is one article show your
emacs screen saw this emac screen
now Asus Pro are displayed that's my
current display okay so there you can
see the uh
monitor resolution now let's search for
Sally JavaScript
screen with okay
uh then you'll find CSS with
okay so it's not here
sorry
[Music]
find window size JavaScript find window
size okay open that so let me show you a
few pages I have so this one is about
JavaScript technology
uh how do you find out the window size
the viewport size the screen resolution
you can do it by this this this way okay
so for those of you webtap so for
example here it says my viewport size is
800 by 685 now as I adjust you can see
it change in real time see fantastic so
you have viewport size viewport is the
the the actually it's this area it's
inside the window so it's a bit
complicated because it also consider
whether you count the score bar or
whether you count the menu bar so it
actually
it's full package you know 20 30 years
of baggage and these names are idiotic
but anyway that's how some of the
you know you can read and you can find
out so you have view process you have
the window size this is the window
window size and how do you find out
display resolution so mine is 1920 by
1080. now display resolution also
changes a lot I mean depending on for
example like today monitor has so large
different sizes so you can
you can adjust the
you know depending for example my
resolution the monitor resolution is
actually
2560 times 1440.
okay so where does it say so does it say
here
viewport size window size display
resolution
okay this is incorrect
no it doesn't say you see so there's a
lot adjustments so anyway it's a bit
complex but my actual resolution is
2560 times 1440.
okay so that's one thing and so the
other thing is yeah emac screen
this is about my workflow
I'm telling you about how the optimal
way to
to should you have multiple windows or
should you have multiple frames in emacs
that's my
kind of what I'm
saying not you know but anyway you can
read it or you can you know some people
prefer to have one full screen
window then you have little you split
windows that's not good okay if you use
emacs don't do this this is the worst
because then you have a lot issues about
oh emacs suddenly closed my pen how do
you revert to my configuration lots of
lots of problems you you can it's a up
here battle so do not do this okay if
you use emacs
what I suggest you just
open a window what emacs called frame
you know 102 because emacs will never
change the size of your
emacs fin or code window
okay so that's about that then if you
are wondering about my monitor that's
this one okay you can go there go to my
website and buy it Okay click on
I make two bucks also
so that's that question
so can I show the command how many okay
so emacs so Emax has a command called
how many okay so if you describe
function
you can see the documentation of that
okay so how many uh so it's actually so
you know that basically tells you how
many
how many times something occurs some
string occur okay
so we talked for 30 minutes already so
[Music]
how it seems to me a lot of people in
Wolfram research are phds in math that's
true in physics not too much pure
programmers exactly that's true or
hackers it was like that when you were
there at ufam research yes that's one of
the that's a great question
and that's an important a good question
let me explain
you know as you may know if you watch my
a lot of my videos I despise the
programmers especially the elite hacker
types you know this program is working
industry you know at Google and Facebook
and whatever whatever Oracle you know
database you know this Elite hacker
types [ __ ] idiots these programmers
even great even great ones you know for
example uh some lead programmer at
Google for example just for example even
them you know they tell you what to do
every day you know the the guy who
created rust or the guy who created CSS
a scan you know that that you know
anyway so another these people these
programmers in general they they are
idiotic okay they they did they don't
know nothing they don't know nothing
about the world they only know of coding
very narrow but however the problem is
that they think they know they think
they are God okay they also make a lot
of money okay these programmers
uh industry programmers and they don't
they don't know math okay
99.9 percent of programmers let's say
let's just focus on Google as an example
so you get more specific concrete 99 I
would say this is a at least 99
of programmers at Google you you know
some of you have Google friends you know
you you ask them are you a programmer
you know we don't count sales people or
others or managers just can't program us
you ask them are you a programmer at
Google yes do you know math no okay 99
of them like they don't know
trigonometry they forgot you know they
calculus data but they they dribble they
think they you know programmers the most
idiot idiotic facts okay programmers
now a wolf am it's not like that at all
and also they don't require a degree
although half of them have PhD degree in
math or physics okay but wolfam and also
the wolf Stefan wolf I'm the person the
guy which I came to know a lot because
he's one of the guy I study a lot he he
want he don't he don't want these idiots
you know who just know specialize in one
thing you don't want that he want his
people he hire he control his company to
this day you know it's not public who
from this research is not a public
company because he has a vision he's
Stefan Wolfram guy he he want to tightly
control almost every aspect of it of it
so he's still doing you know live CEO
you know and he's still doing live
stream videos every week so you can go
watch him I watched a lot of his stuff
so his idea is that you know he don't
want these
you know Niche specialized coders rather
not he wants people who have general
idea who knows a lot of things who can
code who can do this who know
mathematics who can do research
mathematics and who know
Society writing General like history and
all those all things okay knowledge in
general knowledgeable about the world
that's what he likes Stefan wolfan
okay so most people so every almost
every P per person a wolf and research
he basically he he he you know he look
over to see what they are so you know
so that's why Wolfram researched their
company their cooperation their people
are like that it's not it's it's not
it's in general it's not just
a a coder you know the the typical Elite
hacker types idiots
and the other thing I want to say so
Wolfram controls his company as opposed
to like most million billionaires you
know once they they sell the company so
it becomes public start stock trading
and you have bored of you know whatever
and then you have CEO then then the
company usually almost
usually when a company become public it
degrade it becomes a scam like Google
like Facebook okay like Microsoft like
Oracle it becomes just [ __ ]
so and and the people who created the
founded the company they are happy you
know because they got money they got
money and they are happy
so so that's why
we'll find research and Stefan Wolfram
is one of the few people I highly
respect
okay
so why do Chinese speaking uh why do
Chinese speak in tongue twisters
so much sometimes
I want why do Chinese speaker why do
Chinese speak in tongue twisters well
that's because you don't understand
Chinese
so next question track the guitar I
ordered a girl 80 without switches and I
soldiered Red Pro linear switch is
fantastic I replaced 10 switches with
blue 25 gram wow that's even lighter it
is even better I will replace overhead
Pro by Blue oh my God that you are
extreme you know so right now I'm using
Pro red switch
when the time the time I got it you know
the time they gave me this keyboard that
switch is not available but today it's
available you can buy it you can order
it with a switch on their website so
this switch is a the one I have is
red switch which is linear and 35 grams
Advocate at Activa
activation okay Force 35 grams which is
lighter than Cherry Cherry MX red Okay
so
fine it's just fantastic you know so
I've been using this square of 80 uh by
now for four months every day and uh
doing 405 so during this month you know
in a specially in past month or two I
have been heavy typing you know a lot of
typing and usually when I do that I my
isi comes up you know I feel so
especially here but not today
so it's fantastic because I so light
switch is one of the most in my opinion
you know different people depending on
you
isi happen to different people for
different courses and there are
different ways to humiliate
to make it better to help you but for me
one of the increa one of the critical
things light switch they must be a slide
at least Cherry MX red linear and not
even quiet the the quiet version so
so that's critically important that
becomes one of the my most important
thing so that key switch like key switch
is the most important now then the
ergonomic shape you know so this one for
example this this ultimate hacking
keyboard
I'm using the both of this screen okay
so this one they also send me I
requested you know I requested uh I
forgot what is exactly is the switch but
it's also super light 35 gram or
something so this one I also can use
long term fantastic okay so that's why
both of them so let me
speaking of keyboard let me mention one
thing okay so there is another keyboard
I like to recommend
so we talked about trackball the best
ones now for keyboard so glove 80
fantastic okay Kinesis Advantage 2 also
one of the great I've been using for the
past
I don't know if you can see it
see so I've been using the for four
years okay every day but anyway so so
it's that's a great one so kinesics V60
I still you know I the one I have is
brown switch so I cannot use long term
so
but I plan to do a review on this I just
haven't got time yet so these three and
the other one I really want to recommend
is this one expose night okay I have it
over there
you can watch my past videos about half
a year ago so lots of videos I'm using
this keyboard also fantastic and I also
have a very light switch get around
switch okay so I have a get around red I
believe
I have uh I I mentioned it somewhere
here okay so this one is also pure joy
so I highly recommend it and this one is
the cheapest among them
150 or something uh much cheaper so and
then this one ultimate hacking that's
that's that one okay that's great so can
you see it
yeah okay so yeah
okay so these are the keyboard I
recommend okay
go search my website if you like it you
know pay me remember
PayPal me okay
so this one 35 grams so but you went
even lighter that's amazing I I don't
think I want to go lighter because this
is light so it's so light already
uh what are your thoughts on the recent
Riot's uh environments in France okay
that's a political topic but Gemma and
Abby okay I've seen you before so I
would I really love to talk about uh
politics I would like to dedicate one of
my live stream and talk about politics
for one hour but YouTube is probably not
the right place because YouTube will
censor you and you know so and a lot of
people get turned off when you talk
politics because politics religion these
are kind of sensitive topics each each
person they don't go by Logic you know
each person when you if you are born a
Christian
then then you must then then you we you
will not like any opinion that's you
know that doesn't support your idea or
is Islam or you that Judaism Jews or
whatever whatever
anyway so what's my opinion about five
uh French uh Riot yeah it's pretty bad
it's one of the worst in past 10 years
or something uh so I think you know
there's rumor that says that
funded by USA okay this rumor but I
cannot confirm there's no
uh evidence this you know so as far as I
know but anyway that's all I have to say
I don't really know uh the detail
okay so anything else okay I think maybe
that's it uh
your opinion on your heart okay I don't
actually know who
who that is geohud you know so
I remember someone just mentioned your
heart I think I I don't know I don't
really know who he is I'm I think I read
about him a little bit recently in the
past year
so supposedly he is president of comma
AI founder of tiny grad I don't know
neither one of them uh so I don't know
about who is that
railu says what do you currently do for
a living how is your website set up
thanks for the film section I saw one of
your recommendations yesterday yeah so
you know that's uh
common question how do you make your
money how do you make money
I don't make money I I did basically I
don't make money okay my money is thank
you guys for donation
so again I'd like to thank Alan
Alan and uh
Alan and Dion who has basically gave me
two thousand dollars each
you know Dion for the past three years
and Alan just gave me one shot two
thousand dollars and so I really like to
thank them
uh you know I speaking of that topic I
really get pissed because so the open
source
comes you know on the surface you know
they they like open source and so blah
blah blah but they don't they don't they
don't you know open source you cannot
survive I don't I don't get I get no
money okay
if you are wondering in my YouTube you
know I make oh you know three dollars a
month
or something you know the best one
dollar per video
and uh too much pain to talk about my
past experience when I was dying of
hunger you know all my stuff is free
for tech for over 10 years on emacs you
know in fact the entire tutorial I put
in a zip file you can download free for
10 years but nobody gave a [ __ ] the uh
this open source scumbags
so
maybe that's about it so let's go back
to the comments uh
next time I'm able to get more
specialized keyboards at the moment
and am limited to General consumer ones
what do you think is the best way to be
available
from Brands such as Logitech or
Microsoft okay I recommend you just I
said this many times in my video okay I
recommend you go out buy one of those
Chinese Cheapo mechanical keyboard right
now
don't ask questions don't do anything
just go to Amazon those cost forty
dollars okay forty dollars buy one forty
dollars mechanical keyboard so I would
recommend if you can choose choose a
Cherry MX red silent switch okay do it
right now or you can you can get a brown
if you never had a mechanical keyboard
before but the first thing is just to do
that get a mechanical switch keyboard
not mechanical feel that's you know
marketing crap you know and forty
dollars just buy one okay on Amazon you
can buy right now
then you can talk about later on after a
year or two you can talk about
ergonomics or maybe maybe you like
different switches and so on okay next
question just
to
run aways hello sorry I found your
website through a Google search because
I was very curious about keyboard
shortcuts in ergonomics very fascinating
stuff you have thank you
Johnny XP says hi from Greece hello
sorry for saying that my absolute best
is when you rant about Linux and Unix
yes
yeah that's that's uh you know that's um
that's one of the that's tends to be
dramatic and when you are dramatic you
tend to get more people following you uh
in some sense that's not good because
you get that's what Twitter and uh
that's all the crap fashionable [ __ ]
happens you know because rust for
example current heart thing is rust
programming language wise and then on
political topics you know it's uh God
it's a
in America it's about guns about Trends
about you know
abortion for 10 years for 20 years for
30 years it's all about that every day
drama
okay so I think maybe that's it
so I talked for 15 minutes so I guess
there's no
so I feel today is kind of wasted
because all the things I talked about
today has been repeated so many times in
the past
um
okay so that's it for today I was I
wanted to mention about
um
my emacs blog since I've worked on uh
let's see so a lot work on my packages
uh
uh yeah a lot code we write a lot and I
also put up the code on my website so
you guys can just grab it or you can use
software Keys most of the functions are
in software Keys Okay so
lots of huh so anything else
check so I'm about to stop okay
let's check yeah I'm about to stop
that's it for today I think
about keywords emacs
oh yeah about movies so let's show some
movie stuff
so
so this is more general population I
mean General
um
you know this is not programming related
so you get wider audience so this one is
a kind of
ballet like dance not ballet but some uh
some kind of dance I don't know how to
how do you call it but beautiful okay
uh but anyway what I want to mention is
that I start
um
so in the past week I've been working or
be working on my website on Sally
favorite movies
so these are things anyone can
appreciate and I also have a lot of
movie screenshots
uh Logan's Run
this this is interesting Logan's Run is
a size
sci-fi movie about 40 years ago long ago
1976 okay it's a great movie
but it's about dystofia sci-fi dystopia
you know how things become bad
you know the you know the idea is Utopia
where sometimes in the future this
actually described today okay in fact
sometimes in the future you have
beautiful city you have no diseases
everything is cured you you can live
forever uh but it tends uh then or you
they you don't you know you don't you no
longer have to work or you day all you
do every day is just eat and have sex
you know beautiful people Everyone is
beautiful and look at you know this hot
sexy you know that's how you dress in
the future that's kind of like today
okay
today you know as you know there's tons
of Pawns there's tons of girls teens
they do online they do live stream they
get you know then you look at Hollywood
movie stars on stage they are all like
how they dress they dress like that you
know on Holly on stage you know all the
music videos uh
most of them okay so it's like Utopia
in in a way so This Is 40 years ago some
somehow it came true you know you can
have sex like people don't care about
Regina t or marriage no more you know
like you go online they did 1018 sites
you have you just [ __ ] around then you
then then you have tried you then you
have case you can [ __ ] the ass you can
[ __ ] with another guy or you can have
threesome you can have then you have
trans which is which is one level up
then you have puppies and furries okay
Anything Goes that's a sex that's you
know that's reality in America
in in most White
countries okay
but then
so are we like in Utopia it doesn't look
like actually then then you if you pay
attention to society to politics you
realize we are
you know censorship it's over
magnitude
severe than 10 years ago then you know
the career politicians then you have
Ukraine war what does that mean Ukraine
war you know hundreds of people get
killed every day do you guys have have
you guys seen the videos you know how
people get killed you know the bloody
videos
uh yeah you then you have Joe Biden you
have Hunter Biden with his laptop which
he obsessively obsessively record every
prostitute he visited like hundreds
hundreds of them like he has to make a
video and take photos and record his
drug habit you know
and uh
it's not just in in corruption going go
to Ukraine he become the you know the
head of some giant Corporation gets a
million a month something like that
and do nothing he doesn't have to do
nothing because you know who is my dad
my dad is Joe Biden
you know so USA Americans we went to
Ukraine
Hunter beta is just an example he
happened you know he's [ __ ] sloppy
guy he do this all these crimes and he
leave his laptop
right there
so we have a full complete record of the
what the Corruptions going on
then
yeah nothing happens you know oh we need
to put Trump in jail that's what happens
and then he you know so 100 and then we
build biological weapon Laboratories in
Ukraine not in USA because oh that's
illegal so we let's build it in Ukraine
let's build it in China kovit 19. coffee
is 19 that's another amazing
uh incident you know you you know Utopia
we are living in Utopia yeah you can
have sex sex is free
then covid-19 Millions dead literally
and turns out you know I don't know if
you guys know but if you are you know if
any of you are actually looking into
this
incidents you know it's a big surprise
to me because I have been fooled
19 turns out it's basically USA
biological weapon research went wrong
okay why you know they do it in China
Wuhan why didn't they do it in USA
because that's illegal you know that's
illegal so let's move let's do it in
China
and uh literally it is a biological
weapon research
uh and uh you know that's um
the origin you know and that's
that's something you cannot accept
you know that happened
um
okay so that's it for today thank you
guys for watching bye guys
pirate so this guy's excess I'm
definitely going to Pirate this movie
right now
no you shouldn't do that okay don't do
that if you well unless you are a poor
you know very very poor student or
something then you you do that but if
you have a job if you have some money
don't pirate that's not a good thing
okay
you know go to Amazon pay for it if you
can
because you don't you know don't [ __ ]
around don't that's how Society become
like today you know you announce or you
are hanging on 4chan you know you but UK
what do you care let's just [ __ ] around
look at look look at Biden it's so bad
look at Google look at Facebook they are
all [ __ ] around look at Hollywood so
I'm gonna [ __ ] around too no
that's not what you should do you know
like
don't do that
I support the current thing
[Laughter]
bye guys