good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
today is 2020 uh uh
october 3rd saturday so we have a lot of
talk to do and we are going to today i'm
going to
show these uh do matt
dunman demand dk 6 keyboards
and emac this live coding and javascript
live coding probably and some font
setup font choices and programmers
idiocy
about fonts okay so we have a lot to
talk about
and so let's begin so good morning alan
matt
and uh bots if body and kung shao guang
hello
uh conscious so okay so let's begin okay
let's stop that and go to so this is
today's talk show page and i want to go
to
uh obs and hide this so let's begin
doing stuff
uh if you have comments comments okay
comments and okay so first
first stop is these keyboards now this
this is the one bot
told me about and a few other peoples so
this is two man
dk6 keyboard this is configurable
keyboard
that means you can place the keys
anywhere any position position you want
this keyboard is made in china it's from
a chinese
shenzhen company and they you know china
is doing great they have a lot of
innovations in
in the past few years you know a lot
tons of things
keywords from china so this is
configurable keyboard that means
so you buy this you can place positions
keys anywhere you want
and the keys are magnet they are you
know based on magnet
and it's very strong by the way the
magnet is very strong
so you once you position it on the board
you cannot
uh easily move it and
you know the keys are set into a box so
the
electronics the key code and all that
come with the key so each key
is actually a unit uh so the electronics
is not
on the board on on the on the you know
slab
so that's some of the features and and i
want to thank this chinese guy
james and i who sent me these photos and
told me about the details of this
keyboard
now my opinion of this keyboard is
not that great i mean let me qualify
qualify okay
i mean this is a fantastic keyboard for
uh keyboard experiments for example if
you are into
do it yourself you if you are a giant
keyboard nerds
then you can buy this keyboard and by
the way the feet
can be uh can be changed into any one of
the four positions
so you can tint it like that or you can
have it tilt you know or till
from from to back or back to front you
know uh adjustable feet or you take the
feet off it's flat
uh i'm not sure the height of the feet
is adjustable
but you can you know there are probably
information on the web
there are a lot you know at the bottom
of my page you can see
links to uh other websites the official
websites and so on
so that's a feat so and
so check check it out you know many of
you guys are interested in keywords
uh so my opinion about this keyboard is
that
it's a fantastic keyboard for
experiments
you know if you are designing your
layout if you are trying to figure out
which kind of physical layout you like
then this is great but
i it's not so great if you are if you
just want a keyboard for typing you know
if you just want an ergonomic keyboard
for typing because
you don't want to spend time to adjust
these keys you know you rather pick one
pick a configuration you like you know
and get on with it get on with your life
because this configurable keyboard
is gonna cost you money and time for
example
the you know if you are into do do it
yourself they are
i mean if you are into orgo on emacs
ergonomic keyboards
you know there are a lot choices you can
uh read my reviews and pick the one you
like and
stick with it you know they are pretty
much they are all great okay
depending on your need uh there are
different
types for example whether you if you
want it to be portable
or whether you prefer it to be split
into two
physical pieces or you rather just
prefer one
you know single piece it's easier to
carry and tend it you know
for example or you prefer for example
i'm using kinesis i show this many times
in my video
uh let's show it again in every video
uh okay so let me show it
so you are looking at my kinesis
keyboard and
above that is the uh
you ultimate hacking keyboard i'm using
it as a
marker keypad okay yeah there
so i don't use the left part right now
i'm just using you know there are
enough marker keys so okay
so let's put the camera back
so you can see me okay so that's
my keyboard for example you may not want
this because
it's uh it's rather large okay
it's you know it's about the same size
as
a full-sized keyboard but it's
uh it's rather smaller than the
microsoft's
ergonomic natural keyboard so there are
so many so many choices and plus
and if you want to uh do it yourself
you have you have tremendous
amount of choices so you do not
necessarily have to go with the
you know the configurable let me show
you where that is here
okay so flat one piece so these are flat
one piece
they are not tinted uh tented is quite
important if you are if you type a lot
so oh okay i i uh the image is not
showing let's fix that
okay so it should be there okay so let's
fix that
so i'm going to show you my emacs
workflow then
two-piece split so it should be this one
okay so
copy the url back to emacs open that
page
magnify and on the right pink window the
purple window you can see all my key
strokes and commands
so here is the
here is the domain dk6 okay i need to
fix the image link which is here
so it's actually because i changed the
directory so it
should be i d i y okay so open it
it shows now back to browser refresh
there okay so i think that's
about that keyboard i don't actually
have it but
you know i gave you my opinions
uh okay so you know if you are the
chinese if you are the maker of this
keyboard send me one okay i'm going to
do great reviews and you're gonna
you're gonna sell your keyboards
okay so so that is about keywords let's
go back to
let's go back to today's talk show okay
go to today's talk show page and
okay so let's comment out the video here
magnify comment out the video showing
browser
okay do man keyword by the way do man
the word do man in chinese that
means that's pronounced okay
in english you you say do man
d-u-m-a-n-g
but in chinese the proper pronunciation
is with turns
so it is pronounced
let me let me repeat them do man versus
okay so what does dumont mean well it
actually means
poisonous poisonous python okay
so the naming of this keyboard is you
know it's
it it's it has the style of for the
gamers you know gamer likes those kind
of things for example the razer's got
three snakes
for the gamers teenage no nothing gamers
okay so back to so let me read the
comments and let's begin to talk about
the next topic we're going to talk about
is let's see
either font or emax or javascript
uh let's talk about font a little bit
douma that's right alan allen is a
linguistic
allen knows chinese japanese and
korean and of course english allen is a
linguistics
uh linguist here in our group sabah says
uh what do you mean not here
i already posted the question in the
chat what what
what chat but but
your problem is and let me show you
about your problem
because i type your name for example i
type allen okay
you see there's a pop-up and i press tab
and i can say hi alan now i tried your
name
now it shows okay before it's what it
was not showing it was not showing
because you are you are somewhere else
yeah that's that's why
okay so uh so let's start to talk about
um
probably good foe4 hey hey guys
so let's talk about uh next topic okay
which is
uh about let's see
uh font okay so
let's let's get this uh let's talk about
font first
then we are going to code some emac this
okay
so showing bro so i was uh
i i was
i a safe car i saved car font
this is one of the font you know
programmer
programmer idiots they love talking
about fonts they love fonts they you
know you go to programmers forum where
the mecca of programmers such as
uh hacker news slash dot
or reddit you know you a sub forums
subreddit or programmers they they are
driving about fonts these
programmer idiots let me explain
why i hate i despise fonts so much you
know the programmers
you know this happens for 20 years for
20 years and every
every every every day every year your
you'll see programmers they dribble
about
which one is better or what my my
preferred font you know
they they um
and and also ligatures and typography in
general and these
these topics all together are the most
lame idiotic [ __ ] possible
but first of all let me let me give you
a concrete reason why i despise this
talking about fonts
you know programmers for example emacs
people or veeam you know
often when they talk about emacs or the
things they love
such as lisabo haskell they they talk
about functionality you know features
because they power you know powerful you
know my language
you know uh lisp or haskell my language
is most powerful
things like that or emacs you know but
when it comes to font
they turned around you know they these
idiots they turned around
and they they stopped talking about
functionality but rather they
just talk about pure [ __ ] appearances
you know what i'm talking about you know
you go to the these programmer forums
these notes
notes gathering makeup [ __ ] you
know
you'll see that uh they they they talk
about that you know they don't like ui
user interface design you know they
they think that's for girls they think
it's for female you know they don't
they don't care about the design you
know uh the coloring or they
usually usually they they don't like
that but rather rather they like the
back end or the programming you know how
it works the mechanism you know things
the hardcore
but when it comes to font these idiots
they forgot about functionality they all
they are concerned
about is kind of like preferences
appearances like you prefer the
font looks this way i prefer that way
it's [ __ ] idiots let me give you a
concrete example
now concrete example okay i you know let
me show you a concrete example okay uh
let's see uh 1000 articles
i have
and the one i'm looking for is not even
listed here
okay so actually i need to go to emac
this
my emacs blog and let me show you okay
there it is
best font for unicode okay so you look
at this article
i'm gonna give you a concrete example
of why i think these programs are
conflicting with
with themselves their usual preferences
they did
you know they are contradictory so when
it comes to font
my concern okay my concern is that you
should have
found that display all these unicode
math characters math
sim symbols symbolics you see you see
this greek
you see these tremendously useful uh uh
brackets it's magnified let's see the
complete
beauty of these characters okay you see
these greek
alphabets they are used in science you
know science math
math and science you you you often see
alpha beta you know gamma gamma rays you
know x-ray
and v and pi you know and zeta zeta is
usually uh
you know in for complex numbers the
anyway the lambda you know all
functional programmers love
the character lambda right that's the
greek character often used
then you have the you know currency
signs you have copyright okay
registration
trademark signs and you have paragraph
sections
you know dagger double dagger
and reference mark this this one is a uh
ac chinese reference mark okay
you you won't see that character in
english uh text but you you often see it
in japanese or chinese but anyway then
you have
dagger and double dagger now this this
groove this kind of uh
often used in printing you know the
before modern before computers in print
impress you know
you you have you need those uh
characters then you have stars
squares you know unicode signs then you
have the phonetic symbols or
old letters alphabets you know
you know this european language or music
symbols
anyway then you have a bunch of math
symbols you know for example
partial uh partial inter partial
derivative
uh and square root and uh
uh colon equal usually is used for
define you you know if you want to
define for example in computer languages
when you want to define a sign you use a
single equal
but if you want to test for equality use
you use
a double equal sign
you know why is that because uh
programming languages
they they were invented in the ascii age
you know like 40 years ago
so you don't have this unicode yet it's
it's tedious to you know use but today
we have
today today we have unicode so you have
colon equal
usually is used for
assignment or definition okay then you
have a bunch of math
symbols you know end of proof you know
qed
or end of proof or uh for all you know
sets uh subset uh
a member of a set and all that math math
symbols okay then you have
and so on and arrows okay so you can see
so today we have all these symbols
you know it's becoming uh very practical
everyone's using unicode as
you know especially emoji you know these
idiots
idiots they love emoji i don't love
emoji
okay okay we have two emoji here most
basic emoji
smiley and frown those are the first uh
emojis
uh available anyway so symbols
you know so font what is the purpose of
a font
the purpose of font is to display
symbols so when you do math as
you know programming is part of math you
know in a sense in
in lots of ways computer science you
know so you have you need these symbols
so you you want you want to font
the purpose of a font the functionality
the power of a font is to
to to be able to display these symbols
okay these unicode symbols
but when it comes to the programmer you
know the elite programming [ __ ]
these emacs people win people every day
they are like oh even imax versus spin
emacs versus being
or type versus space you know formatting
by the way two days ago
or a few days ago i did a great
video talk show about formatting you
should every programmer should read that
it should watch that okay
so this idiot elite you know typically
the e-max
veeam the unix philosophy the unix
people the linux people
these um and and also see
pearl you know uh haskell these
people and including also python people
these people you know this i call them
elites
kind of they are traditionally they are
called hackers
okay hacker types of programmers
they they it is them they they have kind
of a mindset you know again
uh i'm i'm trying to give you i'm giving
you
a view a gander of the mindset the
culture of the
hacker culture these people so when it
comes to funds these people
they you know typically they they care
about functionality but when it comes to
fun they they forgot all about
functionality
all they care is is is the appearance
the
[ __ ] idiots incredible that
to me okay you know i argue with them
all the time for the past 20 years
to me they are like incredible idiots
and they call me a troll you know oh
is a troll what the [ __ ] is wrong with
him
you know don't don't don't you agree
does anyone does not agree
that font you know do i make sense do i
do i make sense
oh am i am i a troll do i make sense
uh okay so what's uh what's going on
with my live chat
chat okay so there i'm gonna read the
comments okay do i make any sense to
to you guys right so i so i
i want font oh of course i also want
beautiful ones beautiful ones i don't
want courier you know the courier
the mono space courier you know the the
classic
mono space font that's pretty ugly i
want beauty too but first
but first of all first of all my concern
is about
the ability to display these unicode
characters the symbols
but when when you look at all the chat
among these elite hacker types you know
on their online
they they they none of them like
basically uh
like like one in ten thousand
one in one thousand we'll talk about you
know the ability you know the
what i'm talking about but most of them
they they will talk about appearances
and
fiercely too fiercely like oh this must
this is the best font you should
download this phone
this is the [ __ ] idiots this is the
pain this is the pain in my ass you know
that's why i have you know for some
reason
you know i i i guess i can dive into the
reasons you know
doing a psychoanalysis of myself you
know
first but for some reason i have you
know i always have kind of the
um different opinions with these hacker
types i i
really truly despise these hacker types
in every
like about everything computing every
technical
uh issue then they they just call me a
troll and
all the programming forums i don't i
don't i don't
i don't understand
[Laughter]
i know nothing i don't understand what's
going on with their with their idiocy
then then of course comes smooth okay
so let me finish your topic okay so
that's a you know so
so that's a concrete reason i why how i
find these
hacker types programmers their uh their
obsession we found idiotic extreme
idiotic
okay so and there are other uh things
okay so let me show you okay uh
programming uh computer blog uh
so anyway that's one uh kind of topic
that's that's uh
uh one section of my talk show about
why i don't like uh you know these
typical programmers uh opinions then
also they have other things for example
they they like
ligatures
you guys know what is the ligature you
know look at you let's go to wikipedia
okay
let me talk about that for a moment
let's go to the proper reference okay
wikipedia
in case in case this idiotic programmer
says oh no because it's wrong again
okay ligature okay not not not
wictionary we want
wikipedia okay there we uh wikipedia
ligature okay ligature in medicine
ligature in music uh and orthographic
literature okay that's the proper way
that's a proper phrase
orthographic literature
okay so you know what is the ligature
you know ligature this is like a
ligature okay for example if you have a
lettuce
f i and for some reason okay
there's a huge history of typography for
for reasons in the past when you have
fi they want to combine they want to put
the two letters
closer together so they create a font a
typeface you know
this is this metal thing they have to
put them together
in their opinion uh it is more beautiful
that way it's more you know it the the
texts come out more flawless
more fluid more smooth something like
that
you know i i don't know the detailed
history of
typography okay i'm talking about
detailed history
most chances are i know more about
history of typography
than any one of these hacker types
[ __ ] programming idiots on hacker
news okay
but anyway i don't know the the the the
the detail of
uh detailed history of typography you
know it's there's a
i bet there's a book you know and by the
way
let me also mention donald gluth the guy
created
tech and who wrote the other programming
computer programming
okay that uh renowned computer scientist
almo
we could almost say he's the most famous
uh computer scientist in this century
okay donald gruth
of course in this century because
computer wasn't invented before
anyway donald goose has written all this
you know out of programming
and and he also wrote part of the uh
tech is meta font and he also wrote a
book on typography okay
let me tell you i have read them oh yeah
i have read them
well not i haven't read the whole thing
but i read quite a lot of them
back in 1990s early 1990s because i
you know although i criticize the hacker
types a lot i'm also kind of
uh the hacker type you know i'm in the
same class that's why you guys
watch my video you guys are also most of
you are
hacker types you know anyway
so i have read you know lots of donald
grunts writing on typography not just
sim but other you know typographic
books on typography in 1990 you know in
the
early 1990s there's no internet you know
not like today
you go to library i go to library every
day to read
about you know typography so i've read
quite a lot
five books on typography okay and
there's uh
magazines and so i i read them but
anyway
ligature okay so now you know what is
ligature uh
the most famous literature in the
western society in
english language is the fi that's the
most prototypical
you know they want to they they they
cook
they call they call it uh micro uh
uh turning uh right uh kerning kerning
okay kerny the [ __ ] another idiotic
concept from the typography
[ __ ] typography is actually a [ __ ]
typography should be banned
you know by the way let me mention
another thing there is a class of
people who are like hate and
heightened souls you know they are the
typographers they they are the
you know they you know in typography
they just it's almost like a cult okay
it's just like
english grammar you know there's there's
a uh
guilt you know uh guild guild okay
typography guild
the you know typographers they they have
names like house
uh foundry you know those people who
create typography you know
uh creating uh uh font faces fonts uh
type typeface fonts are called foundry
okay they are called foundry
the [ __ ] code okay
you know anyway typography is a big
thing okay
so anyway um so what i'm talking about
so you can see here the fi
you know ligature and by the way unicode
also have literature but however there's
under
and i have so many things to say okay
let's let's let's um let's not
ramble too much over okay so so so
you know let's focus on uh one thing so
anyway that's literature so
programmers a lot of them have this
obsession about
ligatures and uh er and micro kerning
you know what is kerning you know that's
spelled
uh k-e-r-n okay current
okay that's a term in typography kerning
okay let's let's look up
and uh it's i think it's in css2 it's
coming to css
kerny that is micro adjustments
of the positions of the letters
look look at look at this this this
idiocy
you know so normally you have av okay
you have the letters av then you just
you know
you put them together av but in the
you know the in the fine point of view
of typographers they
consider that ugly so they when you have
a and b
v comes after a you need to put them
closer together
that's called kerning basically it's a
micro
adjustments of the position of letters
kerning okay so type type that's one
thing in typography
uh my opinion of that is that they
should be banned
[ __ ] idiocy that's fuzzy for nothing
that's that's
that's fuzzy for nothing okay that's
fluff
that's icing on the cake uh
salt and peppers no no no substance
this this is what typographers are
concerned about
you know these typographers typographers
they are similar to the
grammarians okay grammarians used to be
popular among
the hacker types you know like in the
1990s not so much today because today
the hacker types are almost extinct they
are overrun by the
social justice idiots the millennial
generation idiots
they are they are even worse
anyway back in 1990s
grammar okay it used to be a thing among
hackers you know something
you know hackers will talk about grammar
or your grammar is wrong
so typography you know in some ways like
grammar you know they
they have a code you know for example
for grammar you have you know the
chicago style guide
chicago style guide the the the ap
the ap press you know style guide you
know you know you have different style
guilds
of style guides from different uh
publishing houses
but most of them they are somewhat
idiotic and they don't they don't agree
okay
so according to a chicago style guy they
say uh
you shouldn't have say let's say
me show you one okay um
oxford karma okay
oxford karma kassadi okay uh wait
worthy english that's my brand name for
my blog on english related things
literature
so search for wordy english oxford comma
comma [ __ ]
it's not showing my page there it is
okay oh wait uh
it's a different page but we can go
there so
this page is my page about introduction
to chinese punctuation
but let's go to the oxford coma comma uh
wait is it here oh x oh uh there it is
you know this is one of the one of the
mean you you can call it meme today
about uh grammar it's funny you know
oxford comma
so let me read it you know this is me so
with the oxford
coma comma with the oxford comma
we invited the strippers jfk
and stalin okay they invited the
strippers
jfk and stalin then then
then without the oxford comma
then you have we invited the strippers
jfa and stalin okay so
so the point of this meme is that the
the whether
the the whether you have a coma or not
comma or not
changes the meaning of the sentence okay
and the
amount among the uh you know the style
guides you know the
these haughty style guides they have
different opinions
on whether you should have the oxford
comma or not so it you know it's a
it's a fun thing people say
so anyway so grammarians you know these
these style guides use this style guide
guilds you know the writing guilds they
are kind of like a
coat okay it used to be not not so much
today
you know these are kind of so anyways so
and also the typographers
uh in they are similar in that way
they are kind of a cult they control
things but anyway
um i so they i think they are not
the reason they they exist
is is i think it's because back then
let's say 100 200 years ago
when you don't have internet you don't
have you know when the printing
is not as easy as today
so this this uh typography and these
writing guilds
they are they are very powerful
organizations you know they are
almost like almost like the god
believing
uh religions even
longer ago they you know they control
things that's why they have they form
these uh ima
that's that's my guess okay i don't know
for sure
so anyway ligature kerning we talked
about let's go to
let's go to my talk show and paste it
here so we can um
uh we can we can have a record of what
we talked about
okay let's go back to talk show so
that's
some rambling about the font let me show
you okay so wait
what ah [ __ ] okay so these links are
incorrect let me get the correct link
okay
so these three links are incorrect they
should be
uh let's go to my emacs blog they should
be
let's copy the url let me let me show
you what i'm doing okay for you emacs
users
so i uh so i put a cursor somewhere in
this block
okay and i press a key
then the file path for each of the link
is is extracted you can see in the mini
buffer okay
so for example i go i go i open a new
buffer i paste
you can see the full file path
and that command is uh that command is
this
site html extract url okay so like i
copy that back to my
son talk show page paste it here you can
see here
then press a key to make them into a
list
okay remove the url and then delete the
old links
okay then show in browser okay so back
to
the start talk show page so uh
best font for programmers
so the on this page i was talking about
what's the best one for programmers
according to my criterion which is
you know the font should be mono space
and you know and should have
distinguished uh 0 or capital o
or lowercase o and also l lowercase l
the number one and uh capital case i
you know besides that it should have
lots of unicode characters
so so that's my criterion so according
to this criterion
the best font is deja vu
okay i recommend deja vu deja vu is a
font
sweet so they did i mean it's a set
that's what they call sweet
idiot english anyway it's a set of fonts
so anyway i recommend deja vu
because that's a font that's it's
beautiful too
you know this is beautiful and by the
way it's also open source
and it contains the most unicode
characters
to this day i so so far as i know it's
still
it is the font that contains the most
unicode characters within the font
itself
by the way today's technology you have
like today
on mac or windows or linux you have
what's called font substitution tech
that is in your browser or in your
editor i mean basically the operating
system when it found
when it finds a character that's not in
your current font
it will try to find a font that contains
that character and display it
so for example for example this uh this
bunch of unicode characters
the the deja vu does not have all of
them
okay uh sum up does not have i mean deja
vu doesn't have
uh i i don't remember for sure i have to
check
so when deja vu font does not connect
contain that character the browser the
mac os we automatically try to find
another font
and use it so you so in a sense you
cannot tell you know all
characters are displayed you can tell
but the problem is
when that's done too much or then you
know the font substitution is not done
well
you have ugly glitches you know you have
style crashes like some part of it
you'll become
thin some part of it will become white
things like that or big
so that's a that's why that is why
it's preferable to have a font that just
contains lots of
uh unicode symbols okay and by the way
no
no font contains all unicode characters
there are some fonts that tries to do
that but that's rather idiotic
because unicode has you know all
characters in human uh history
you know 10 millions you know i'm not
going to
get tell you the exact numbers i know it
of course but that's about unicode
anyway
so that's so and okay so that's about
deja vu font
okay and there's another one that's
pretty good okay that's pretty good
which i learned
just last week okay that's called um
that's called uh i'll save car
you know i'm not sure how to pronounce
it but but but they are
somewhat idiotic you know usually it's
known as lose
lose lose car lose vocab because the
first letter i
is often mistaken for l you know
lowercase l so loose forecast sometimes
if
for example if you search twitter for
lucifer
l o s e v k a you'll find quite a few
you know post but actually the first
letter is i and
in fact yesterday i looked at the page
it shows uh
it shows in a different font that shows
l and i criticized it
and maybe i'm thinking maybe they heard
me
and they changed it today because
yesterday it doesn't look like
like this uh let me show you my
criticism okay i
i i am i doing okay
do i make sense am i am i am i relevant
am i relevant to you millennial
generations
am i losing your interest okay i have 20
current users so
so viewers so that means i'm doing okay
i'm going to read the comment in a bit
okay
so so let me show you okay my comment on
on the loose vaca or io you know
so there are few idiocies about about
this font okay
so i say here lucifer car fund is now a
fail
i thought it's lucifer car but it is
actually ios evka
you know ios car
and i say you know the fact that the
website uses a version of lucifer car
fund
that does not distinguish
capital i with lowercase l
much as if you know they do not
distinguish that is a fail
because when people go to your website
they see
lucifer card but it's actually ios evka
so that's
you know you shouldn't do it you should
you know you should either use a font
so that people so so the uh
lowercase l is very clearly
distinguished from i
so people do not make make a mistake
about your name your [ __ ] idiotic you
know
name or you shouldn't have a name that
have this ambiguity you know either way
you are idiotic you you made a
make mistake so that's a fail okay
so i then i say the choice of uh i for
name for the names found names first
letter is also a fail
and having a million version of the font
is another fail you know the
lucifer card they have like 100 versions
you know that
they have 100 versions of their font you
have loser card you have lucifer cartoon
lucifer car fixed uh lucifer car slab
and lucifer car turn slab a fake slab
and
aisle and e tower and sparkle the [ __ ]
[ __ ] [ __ ]
complexity [ __ ] you know so
and then but besides this each one has a
bold version regular version and
and italic version you know by the way
the typography is very idiotic
you might think you know bold is
actually just making each letter
thicker but that's actually not true if
you want to go
by the fine points of typographers but
the bold font is actually
specifically designed so like you have
an entire set
of letters that's for both you don't
just you don't just increase the
thickness of each
uh stroke you know that same thing for
italics and so on
you know the typographers they have
reasons because they they think it's
that makes it more beautiful
but it's like uh it's but it's it's more
like much ado about nothing it's idiots
much ado about nothing nothing why don't
why don't you go study mathematics
you got you you idiots the the the font
obsesses idiots why don't you go study
mathematics
okay so that's so lucifer cut so i try
actually i tried the font let me show
you okay so
for example you are looking at uh
now i'm going to show emacs commands
that that that
that changed the font okay i'm just
going to press one single
button first of all magnify okay so
watch
let's go to talk show page okay um
yeah so so so first of all show in
browser so you are looking at microsoft
talk show page now back to emacs
okay i'm gonna press the button and that
will change the font between
the one i'm using which is uh which is
uh menlo
minnow is between menlo and lucifer
okay watch press
that's lucifer car you can see at the
bottom you know the mini buffer okay
now that's lucifer now that's menlo
okay lucifer menlo
now let's go to the top of page okay so
you can let's try again
lucifer wait what uh
go to the top of the page okay lucifer
khan
menlo lucifer
menlo okay let's
okay so that anyway i just want to show
you that
um there are some nice features of
lucifer car okay i'm not going to talk
about them because
you know you just go to their website
you might like it i think it's not bad
okay i think it's pretty good
and lucifer also has has lots of unicode
um characters but i i think it's not as
much
not as many as the deja vu
uh so anyway lucifer car so so
let's drink it again okay so let me show
you
okay so let's try again
menlo lucifer car now let's go to let's
show a python code okay
go lan okay actually let's go to golan
uh wait
go land uh
wait let's go to find
go let me show you a python
code so because i'm choosing python
because
python requires mono space
okay so that's the python code so let's
magnify okay
so let's go down let's go down so you
can see
you know some python code so now let me
try to change the font okay
now that's menlo lucifer
menlo lucifer okay
so and also you can see it entirely too
okay let me delete those uh backup files
okay
so magnify the browser
menlo
is pretty good it has some interesting
features uh but
it also tries to do lots of kerning fig
you know ligature
and koni i mean lucika has a large
version right so
one of the version has the ligature they
try to use ligature and stuff
i don't like that okay
that's that's about lucifer card font
and let's go back to
uh okay so another thing let me show now
show you
what is a command i use uh two cycle
fonts so that is this okay
so cycle font so if you want to
experiment with fonts
then this command cycle font will be
tremendously useful
because then you can compare fonts you
know just by pressing a button
you know you can compare them uh
and uh you know otherwise you have to
you know you have to either run some
list code or go to the options and click
the menu
you know the select current font for
example
uh set default font
this is how you do it on a mac then you
got this pop-up
then you you know it's tedious so you
rather have some
for example three fonts or two fonts you
want to compare them
then then this command is very useful
okay cycle font
now let me show you the uh code
okay describe key so here is the
documentation for
cycle font and here is the source code
that's in my emacs ini file so
magnify so
here is a function okay
and there is a website okay so let's
just go to
my website and show in browser
so if you yeah so go and download this
in your init file and you can
uh play with fonts you know i i i play
with fonts
because i on one hand i criticize these
people but
you have to you know you have to study
so i study a lot about fonts you know
i compare all the fonts i look you know
hundreds of hours
since like 10 years ago 15 15 years ago
this command is written long ago
this command is written in 2010
you know so anyway
okay that's that's about that maybe we
should shut down
and uh you know there we have some other
uh topics uh let's see
let me read the comments okay
am i doing okay so check let's take a
break
intermission okay let's see
uh my obs so i have been talking for
50 minutes okay we we could shut down
now let me read the comments
i found it's just for cans camel case
okay
bar says what is that a word in that
font
why don't you study mathematics that's
right
uh looks all the same to me no okay matt
so so the one of
let me talk about one of the feature the
the primary the defining feature of the
lucifer car
by the way the the name is really
idiotic because i don't know how to
pronounce that io save
car uh name let well i'll just call it
luzwaka
so you know lucifer they have a problem
i mean
they have one feature that stands out
that's their selling point that is
they lose of a coupon let me show you
okay so
show lucifer lucifer card found is
uh very narrow they right now i'm using
a
mono space version of lucifer and and
basically
the way you describe this is that you
compare to chinese characters you know
you have using chinese characters uh
okay let's go to
let's go to wordy block worthy
blog from the hearty emotions of lexicon
stylistic concerns defies decipherment
of grammar and idioms
linguisticality literature and
logicality
that's my literature linguistics
grammar writing style related related
blog
so in here you can click on chinese
zone bg and you have
chinese characters okay
the most frequently used chinese
characters
500 of them okay these are the most used
chinese
frequently used chinese characters so so
you can see
they are all mono space i mean that's
the nature of chinese characters you
know each
each character including punctuation
they occupy the
same width and hate so lucifer
is actually created in china by some
chinese guy so they have the feature
that each character of lucifer
monospace they are half width of a
chinese character so they are kind of
thing
but for some characters such as dash
okay let me show you okay uh let me show
you
okay so i have a lot to show okay uh
dash
uh m dash okay
so let's magnify okay so this character
is called
m dash okay it's one of the
okay e dash okay here you can by the way
you can look up wikipedia
just search for em dash that's a
that's just a dash basically that's just
a long dash okay
now if you are a printer for example
your job is to print books or if you are
a typographer
you want to use that i mean because they
are different type of dash
sometimes some of them are longer some
are shorter
some are even shorter and some are used
for hyphen some some are used for minor
sign
some are used for uh dash punctuation uh
each one have a different uh position
you know
you know the fine details of typography
so anyway there's em dash and there's
another en
dash okay let's try okay let me show you
okay so there's em dash and there's uh
uh yeah uh en dash
okay so so right now you are looking at
them they look
they look exactly the same but actually
they are not
because when you show them in
proportional font
the em dash is much longer so let's uh
so right now i'm showing them in menlo
okay now i'm going to switch to lucifer
then you'll see a difference okay now
lucifer
you can see can you see that the the em
dash is now twice as long
so this is the this is uh the defining
feature of the loose of the car fund
so for some so so even though there are
there are still mono space but however
it's not technically mono space because
some characters are twice
as uh white but it still has the
property where if you you know your
um your text uh has you know have
aligned so that you can use this in
python for example
and but but but it has the advantage
where you know for some characters it
has
a proper um width for example
one of the another example is arrow i
think
yeah there it is you see uh
this is this is called right arrow okay
uh for example let's do it again let's
uh
let me switch font okay so so look
now watch okay watch the size of this
arrow
now this is lucifer now main low
okay so in melo they all become the same
lucifer so that's one of the
uh feature of lucifer
okay i think that's that's it okay so um
imagine being son i would be so smart
what comedian or comedy movie shows do
you enjoy
uh let's talk about that next time so we
have the topics aligned
so alan says you must address the narrow
practical aspect
of lucifer of your analysis or your
analysis
is incomplete okay so i guess i just did
that
i hope i hope i did uh you know the
defining feature of loose worker
bus is amazing amazing how lucifer card
changes to
lucifer car in a couple of minutes that
is the magic of
sardi uh
okay so i think we are done today so
thank you guys for watching
and the most important thing is you pay
me
okay this comes the unpleasant part
do you do you love wikipedia you you
love wikipedia right
you go there then there's ads please
don't close this tab please don't close
this page
please if everyone just donate one one
dollar
then wikipedia will provide the greatest
information to the world for the better
award
so you you pay me now okay
you can pay by paypal you can buy my
emac this tutorial
you can buy my javascript tutorial
javascript in depth
okay uh and you can buy you can just
paypal you can you can you can bitcoin
me or you can buy my amazon you know get
amazon gifts
it's all just on my website you know
where to look okay just
go to my website then you'll see the
wait the the pay now button
okay so let's see you cannot and
subscribe
please uh things like that crap you know
[ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] youtube
you cannot receive an experience like
star from another person
okay okay yeah yeah i will proceed to
snap my full size keyboard
in half creating my first split keyboard
yes i see the difference now the actual
big difference there some games use
double
hyphen to simulate em dash indeed
that's what people do when they don't
have unicode yet
uh window users okay mac users uh window
users you can use win plus semicolon
uh okay to select to do em e and dash
okay
by the way the the e and e m let me show
you another article okay
[Laughter]
the
uh moro necessity
of thai paragraphy
okay shrink shrink the moronicity of
typography
search show me the magic
there it is the moronicities of
typography hyphen dash quotation marks
and apostrophe so this is the other guy
i wrote in 2007
okay i give you my experience of my
my qualifications on commenting on
typography okay
i'm not a typographer so i'm not a
professional
typographer or from photographer
you know those fancy words but but i
have my opinions
and you should know it okay just like
every programmer
so hyper and dash you know you know so
so here you have a gander of all the
different
hyphen dashes you have hyphen miners you
have em dash
e n then you have figure dash
figure dash is it must be used when you
have a
bunch of figures you must use figure
dash okay
then you have minus sign you have a
dedicated minor
dedicated minus sign okay so it's uh you
know that's what it is that's that's
what
uh typographers are concerned about
and you have the moral necessities of
the quotation marks you know the
oh my god this that this this i can talk
about uh one hour okay but that's it for
today
uh why not write for publisher like ap a
press or pack
well i'm not going to write for
publisher greeting for peru
pandemic hey pandemic from peru
okay i think that's it uh thank you guys
for watching
bye
we shut down in one minute okay one
minute
closing remarks should be placed
at this time that would be appropriate
so
opinion should be more mainstream and
the rich wide audience in the
attempts to correct the infantile
teeth circles circles influence
spreading throughout the world in
a like a plaque i hope so
but you know you cannot fight the powers
that be
the powers that be that is the
mainstream you know you can study the
history how it forms you know the
formation
of you know society and how the the
formation of mainstream
you know you might ask you know it's an
interesting question you know for
those of you um
curious types you know how does
mainstream ideas form
you know why why isn't the mainstream
for example my
why why doesn't my opinion become the
mainstream there are reasons okay there
are reasons
they become the mainstream but if i
i haven't thought about this you know
but if i
if i want to comment the reason is
mostly
you know the reason is basically mostly
money and power that is how
you know as they say money turns the
world around
money makes the world uh turn that is
actually
a very apt uh
analogy money makes the world go around
it's money you know it's money going why
why money
money is food in other words it's food
why certain things become certain
concept or practice become mainstream
you know you might say oh because that's
actually better you know
that that's true in some way it's it's
but that's not the fundamental reason
there's a lower level you can go deeper
it's so as
it's for example many some practices are
not the best practice but however they
become the mainstream
yeah every everyone thinks that's the
best practice but actually they are not
but you know after 10 years then things
may turn then
people realize oh actually actually
that's not
you know that's not a good thing to do
but people you know 100 years ago people
are thinking
earth is flat or so long so you know so
on and on
you know so what what what concept what
practice actually become mainstream you
know
you might say oh because they are best
practice not not really
you know partly but not there's deeper
reason
the the deepest reason from
us as far as as i study it's just money
it's just power
food in other words food i want i want
the bigger piece of
pizza than you okay you want a bigger
pizza than me
so we you know we we we power we do
power struggle
implicitly or explicitly you know we
fight for girlfriends
we fight you know if there's a pile of
money on the on
on the road we fight for it you know we
fight in almost every way
so that i have better growth than you i
have better food than you
things like that so and that's how the
politics you know mostly
but but but this reason you know oh
because money that
it's not interesting but that's actually
how things are
in in many sense
uh okay so that's it so i i want to
see what's the other things i have
installed yeah ligature kerning
javascript coding chart
challenge okay let me let me give you
this javascript coding challenge
i'm not going to do it okay we are
already over one hour but um
but okay let me show you the javascript
coding challenge
so you go today go read the program okay
and let me tell you a program okay so
the the
the challenge is uh this okay javascript
coding challenge today read the python
write a python python zip function in
javascript
javascript doesn't have this function
but python does
and these languages they also have so
this
so this zip function is basically like a
map
okay map you map a function to an array
but what
what if you want to map a function to
more than one array
that is in other words you want to apply
a function to the first elements of each
array
then apply the function to the second
one second elements of each
array third then apply it to the third
elements of all your arrays
you know so you basically you have a map
but normally the map function is only
one
array but now you want you have several
arrays you want to
you want to apply the function to each
element in array in parallel
and return uh return
a uh
return array you know you apply the
function you take the first array as
first argument second array
element or the second option the
elements of third array is third
argument to your function so you return
a single array
so that is the zip function of python so
in other languages in this it's just
called map
in least in many of these languages map
can take multiple
lists as arguments so in mathematica
it's called map
thread okay so let me show you
mathematica code
let's go to um
okay so here is the link map thread
let's go to it
so we are looking at the documentation
of mathematica the greatest
language in my opinion so this is a map
thread
so the problem is for you to write a
map you know zip function python zip
or map or map thread in javascript okay
javascript does not have
that function you have to write it now
there's an extra bonus point
now this problem everyone can do okay
you can do it so
do it okay do it and show me on discord
join this code if
you haven't already joined my discord
exactly discord you know
you can find it on my website the link
so every so you can write a javascript
version of zip or map function but
there's a bonus point okay whoever do
done this have my respect my highest
respect that is the problem is the bonus
point okay this is not just a point
bonus point this is a big giant point
this is a
almost like a research this is a
difficult problem okay
write write a function in javascript
that emulates the mathematic
mathematica's version of zip called map
thread
that is it takes a third argument
that indicates at which part of the
level of the expression of a tree level
of a tree okay
i'm not going to explain this in detail
i have quite a few articles on that
written 20 years ago but you can search
for mathematica tree exactly
mathematical tree
i'm not going to do it now but anyway
you you you do your research yourself
and
you know whoever can write this it's not
trivial okay
it'll take you a few days to get it
right
and it must be efficient of course you
you cannot write a you know
proof of concept you know kind of thing
because that
because it it
anyway even if you can do that that's
that i would i would pay attention i
would say oh so you know how to code
okay write a version that does
mathematica's map thing
bye guys
you