hello guys welcome welcome
welcome welcome to another episode of
star talk show today we are going to do
emacs coding so from the vote you guys
want emacs
uh instead of wufam language today so
tomorrow you know tomorrow probably i'm
gonna do some language so today emacs we
are so there are two
there are few choices if you look at my
screen
so emacs lives so emac list we are going
to
first choice write a command to turn
markdown to html so you guys uh here
you know pick a choice the first choice
write a command to turn
markdown to html that's one
or
i'm going to go over emac list string
functions
so this is choice number two pick a
topic okay type in the chat so the
choice number two uh going over stream
functions i'm going to demonstrate how i
work in html with and demonstration of
html mod and also give you lots of
tutorials about emac this string
functions basically i'm going to work on
this page
so you're going to see my workflow
and learn some imac these streams
so
which
topic do you like so say it now okay
so am i a live check so audio check yeah
audio check video
check good yeah i'm i'm good okay so
pick a topic now so uh
hi guys oscar and uh
um
hello guys
so meanwhile so you are looking at my
keyboard
i talked about um
two days ago so let me show you okay so
this keyboard this is k move
let's see
the
keyboard
okay so you go to my keyboard blog there
it is
click on that
keyboard guide and go to my blog
and turn on javascript so you can see
all the videos
so
that keyboard you are looking at this
one is k move k68 butterfly this is a
new one they have they came out
so let me
let me
show you the full glory fantastic okay
they sent it uh to me for review and i
like it very much now normally you know
as you see i'm not a
pc keyboard guy i need ergonomic
keyboard you know with lots of thumb
keys but however this is greatly useful
when i lie on bed like in bed you know
when i um
lying bad so this is uh so check it out
okay and they just came out in fact they
just came out you know so
uh you know read my reviews and they
just came out
with see yeah so i did a video a few
days ago on this
so you go to their website uh click on
that
then
shrink
turn on javascript
they started to do a kickstart so you
can um
you know you go to their website and uh
they did a kickstart where is it
uh at the bottom
connections hot swappable yes a feature
which i do not use you know if you don't
like the switches you can buy switches
and swap them
i've never actually uh tried to do that
so anyway you go to their website you'll
find the links where to buy okay
okay so that is about the keyboard okay
so let me show you
now let's go back to so look at my
workflow emac this workflow
so
so okay so
let's go down here so which topic is it
uh not that not yeah that
and the show in browser
fantastic today's topic
okay nobody
is saying what topic okay so let me just
do uh
let me just do random there i mean i'm
gonna make a choice so i'm going to
start to do
emacs
on working on my web page on the string
functions okay
there is a lot to do or i can write a
markdown
where they mark down to html let's work
on my string functions
because it's been a while
today's video
as far as focus topic goes it's already
wasted
because i already talked for like uh
10 minutes almost
yeah i don't know i undecided that's
my okay let's work on this uh this page
emac these string functions okay
so
i'm using this keyboard this is caps
lock and now i need to change the caps
locks to the home key
so what you do is you
go
okay you copy this url back to emacs and
put the url there there it is already
and make it
it's
uh
what
okay so
that okay so now show the current
close this window show the current show
the highlight the current line
and what you want to do is go to the xrd
keyboard blog
go to the
software how to
and everything you need to know about
key binding on windows then there is
this power microsoft power toys this is
the
best tool this is the first stop if you
are on windows if you want to remap keys
okay so i have it installed so i'm just
going to turn i'm going to uh
bring it to front and go to the keyboard
manager and turn it on so i have caps
locked to home
now in some flat keys i can now
yeah so i can
yeah so i can switch my mods okay
so
uh string functions okay so
you need to go here
and copy all the url
highlighted
do that
show in browser so i'm gonna work on
emac stream functions
okay that okay so
so on this page is uh basically
essentially that
uh my tutorial on all
emac these string functions and
it needs some work
basic string functions substring length
substring joining string speed string
string 2 from number
string to buffer so
in the regular expression in string
regular expression replacing string
okay
trim string and others and essentially
here is a complete list
of string functions now some of them are
kind of weird
set case table what is this
select a new case table for the current
buffer
select a new standard case
table for current buffer
okay i'm not sure what that is
a
case table for new buffers c set case
table so it's related to
uppercase and lowercase
characters uc
and llc uppercase in lowercase a pair
of intercase converting letters
yeah so all these functions are related
to
case
you might be wondering why are they so
uh complex why are there so many
functions on you know setting up a case
well that's because unicode because in
unicode
you have more than 26
letters of the english alphabet so you
have
you know greek russian you know and
so i suppose that's what these are so
let's look at the emac this
documentation
case conversion in this the character
case functions change the case of single
characters or
of the contents of strings the functions
normally convert only alphabetic
characters okay other characters are not
altered you can specify a different case
conversion mapping by specifying a case
table
okay
but i suppose by default it works on
greek later letters right so for example
let's try
let's try alpha okay so here we have a
alpha
yeah
so here we have a greek alpha now let's
change the case it works
you know so let's try pi for example
pi
change the case yeah so by default it
works on the
on the you know normal
commonly used alphabets you don't have
to do anything special
so
so why is this page let's go back okay
let's open actually open a new buffer
case conversion table so these functions
actually should not be here
because this tutorial page is
for people who are coding emac lisp and
those case table functions is rarely
used
you know this this page is designed for
people who want just
to look at string functions
okay so now we understand
uh
so this section we don't
want
these case tables
and then down case capitalize those are
important functions string functions
number two string string to number those
are also important concat is for join
string
v concat is
turning a string into a vector
a pen string to a list okay
so you see what i need to do is document
them reformat them and document them and
give examples
you know uh there is already
you see emacs this manual so you can go
to emac this menu
uh
you know they
so you are looking at emac this manual
they are documenting not too bad you
know
so why do i need to
why do i need to kind of rewrite them
for my own page
let me explain okay
it's
still needed
because
this page you know my tutorial is uh you
know it's a tutorial
while the emacs manual is kind of more
elaborate because for a beginner you
you know first of all very few people
reach
emacs manual and they are organized
in a very
difficult to understand way so for
example here you are looking at the emac
base manual
normally you in a programming language
you know python java
let's say python php or most other
languages
you have a section on all
functions that work on string
but that's not the case with emac this
manual because well emac this manual is
written with the mindset of 1980s 1990s
so
imac this manual for example let's let's
see string
i want to know all string functions so
you have string type syntax for string
text property for string
let's search for string
search
string
string type okay
text properties in string you know for
most people like you have no idea what
those are
then strings and characters okay string
and character basics comparison of
characters and strings creating strings
smart device strings okay
formatting strings okay so those are
some of the string functions you'll find
in there
okay so
so if you
click on that conversion of characters
and string
yeah anyway so it's not as convenient to
use because all the string function
functions are scattered over
and also some of them
like you rarely use for example
predicate for strings you know you have
string p
which tests whether if uh you know if if
something expression is a string or not
this is
rarely very rarely used you know and
this one string or no p
uh
you know i never used it before this
this function returns t if object is a
string or neo
okay so if it's a string it returns true
but if it's a neo it also returns true
you know
it's almost never used you know because
because you can do it easily by
uh for example it's
you can do it easily by or
string p
you know let let's make it um e like
this okay so let's
we can so we are going to start you
might be smart so you can do
x
you know this is
uh
no x
yeah you you know so basically
essentially that's what this does
uh okay my copy my mouse doesn't work
my mouse marquees
so let's see let's look at the
documentation of this uh string or no p
okay so you can see it's a high level
function because it's written in this
you can see
it's defined in sub-r dot e-l so let's
go to it so now we can see the
source code it's exactly
how i have written it you know so this
function is you know
it would be interesting to look at the
history you know this is like probably
30 years ago why
people created this function i mean
what's the situation what's the context
when they created this it's interesting
but but you know you can do it just by
writing it yourself
so close that close that so
so you see my point is if you read emacs
manual or some of these you know
especially for beginners you don't need
to know them like they are kind of
redundant so what is this one ciao
string p
yeah okay so
okay this one is useful
comments no comments okay
okay so
so some of the string functions so
yeah so my point is that's why
i'm writing my own tutorial which is
kind of more convenient
okay let's let's begin to write it okay
so let's close that
get it put it back here
and shrink
okay
t
let's see
font
17 okay okay
so
select ddtd
okay so what we are going to do uh we
need to go to this
uh page
make a backup
and now
and update the date you see
this is february
4th
now it's updated
okay
so
let's see what
what's the overall what the how the
things i need to change okay basic
string functions
uh join string split string
okay so first of all
you see all these syntax highlighting
you know this html make it impossible to
read
so let's remove them so now it's easier
to read and now
let's
so now you go to the browser
and you look at this part or this part
refresh
you can see now there's no more syntax
coloring
and what i need to do is basic string
functions okay
switch string join string
okay
now
i'm reading this page to see what is the
um
things and how do i want to modify this
page
basically this page needs a overhaul
and here buffer two text uh string
so
this page needs an overhaul
so these
these sections with
they needs to become a definition list
okay
so these are the most commonly used
functions that's what i cover on the in
the beginning
then you have get buffer to stream
okay so get buffer stream
[Music]
which is you want to you know turn part
of the buffer to the stream
okay
so that's important that's a separate
page so how you gonna do that
um
you know so this is an organizational
problem so if i want this page
now originally this page is a
beginner's tutorial to emac bisp so
you know in the beginning like 10 years
ago it just covered the most basic
string functions so you know how to use
them and that's it
and when you want to know more advanced
string functions basically you are you
know where to look because once you know
the basic syntax you can you know you
don't need
you know my own version of documentation
you can directly you know go to
you know you can just disrupt describe
function and get you know the
information but over the years
over the you know the years i started to
make them more complete and
comprehensive
so
so that's the evolution of my tutorial
pages basically over the years i changed
them
so and now this page
so
so the plan is that to turn you know
this page right now is kind of a mess
because in the beginning you
i teach you some of the most basic
stream functions
but then
let's see then string to buffer
okay this is how do you this is a great
this is a very useful tip to turn a
string into a buffer
because in emac this
often times you want to work with the
buffer
because in a buffer data type you have
cruiser position you have the cursor you
have cruiser position you can delete
part of it you can insert
you know other parts
you will have
uh it's much more powerful than directly
working with strings
so oftentimes you want to
convert a string to a buffer
and there is no building function to do
that
and the way you do that is you know
via this code so this is extremely
useful
but you see but now you run into a
problem you know if i want to
convert this page into some kind of a
list
you know a document a list of or string
functions then
you have an issue you know you know so
where does this string two buffer fit
fitting because it's not a function
so this this is
you know the issues i need to
work out you know how how am i going to
uh
do it am i going to leave the page as is
you know or
you know because if i'm going to turn
this page into a basically a list of
string functions
then you have an issue of where are you
gonna put this
right so you have a kind of you know
kind of consistency issue
okay so that's another issue um and the
other issue we mentioned before is that
we could turn all this into a definition
list
that's more in a style of list of
functions okay
so
and i'm going over to see what i'm gonna
do okay so then you have match string to
regular expression
so this can be a definition list like
that
uh then you have get substring by
regular expression okay
now you that's
you have match string
which is a function written in c
and here's how you use them but you also
have match string dash
p
which returns either true or false
um and i didn't list that because man
you know here's something interesting
for example i can show you so for
example let's go to um
a new buffer
switch to xr emacly smart then
match stream okay so here's the syntax
for match stream and now you can do
describe function match string and you
can see the documentation you see
now you can see oh match string is
actually not written in c match string
is written in emac bisp
okay but anyway so there is another
function called match string p okay
so oh the and there's also match string
no properties
um
[Music]
and match substitute replacement what is
is i never used this before
wow match substitute substitute
replacement
god
so what are you guys help son do you
still use kinesis keyboard yes i do
i'm using this keyboard you are seeing
right now just because you know i want
to demonstrate i want to give a plug for
for them because they you know they send
it to me for review
okay no comments so what am i um
let's see
okay so um
so match stream okay so let's go back
so let's do a list matching functions on
defense so we can see a list of all
functions defined in this sub-r
dot e-l
you can see this this bunch of crazy
functions car cutter
cutter cutter car
cutter
this this is one of the problem of lisp
okay because this is based on coins
you know and uh you know it's
interesting to know that um
they are written in you know in in you
know in e-mail
as opposed to implemented in c
this is one of the you know this
list problem based on cons one of the
fundamental problem of list
of of lisp languages including commonly
schemed this emac
except closure closure did it correctly
closure you know closure no longer based
their least on cons
so basically what does this do because
you know car
car just gets the first part of the cons
and carter gets the second part of the
cons so car car
you know this caar is basically
nested car okay so let me show you so if
you open it the profile is killed okay
so describe function car let's go to it
again so you see this is basically just
car and car car car okay and car
duh is basically car in carter
so basically it gets the second part of
the car's list then it gets the first
part so you have this
idiotic you know combinatorial
function names you know card cutter and
you know back 20 years ago i asked
how many you know how many are there
like just how long can it be you know
because
theoretically could be infinite but
because you can have uh for example you
can have a function that's
any uh combination of
you know
this idiocy of the lisp
but these people don't know it they you
know they think cars is the
you know the best thing since sliced
bread the this phonetics
so anyway that's interesting digression
so okay so you can see them
and then
you know the proper way to for this car
cutter is basically nth
okay
uh nth
okay so let me switch to emac this mod
okay
you see that is the proper way
not the the car and cutter craziness
okay so and also you know this got a
problem uh so we are digressing a lot
for example this last
for example you know it's supposed to
return the last element okay
but however it doesn't really okay
so yeah
so for example let me show you okay so
let me show you
last
okay i don't even have a
so for example you have a
list okay
one two three
so suppose you do last it should return
three right but it doesn't it doesn't
really okay
for example evaluate
you can see
let me magnify let's do it again
evaluate
and let's go to the message buffer you
can see
it returns parenthesis three
why is that because it actually returns
you know let me show you what it returns
exactly it actually returns
this
cons three meal
okay
this is equivalent to that okay let me
show you okay
uh equal
now this is hard to do because
because in this you get into the
complexity of
i'm not sure you can even
let's try that okay
true
you see
you see the mini buffer it says true you
see
now but this is not intuitive you know
what you expect expect is that it simply
return the number three
so if you actually want it to return the
number three
you have to do
you know
car
car last three okay so let's let me show
you
okay so um
equal
three
then that okay now if you evaluate this
uh let's hold on a second it's pretty
fine now if you evaluate it you can see
it's true
so now it's true
you see and this is also true okay so
that's uh that's you know something
interesting about the this cons okay i'm
digressing over
so what we're gonna do so copy that cut
that close that go to the talk show
and
go jump to today's talk show and
create a new emac this code template
paste it here
showing browser
so
that's a digression
and now
syntax color the code
refresh
okay that's a digression so now let's go
back to
[Music]
close that close that
close that let's go back to yeah so we
were looking at all the functions in the
sub r dot el
package
woohoo
ben holtzmann thank you very much do you
have a question
you know
uh payment is a great time to ask a
question so i'm gonna you know go into
if you have a question
okay so so so we are looking you know we
have been looking so let's get let's
open the file again
so we've been looking into this package
you know sub-r
dot e-l and the list matching lines
again
so we can we we've been look uh we are
looking at all the functions defined in
this package now how many you know so
how many lines are there 6 000 lines of
code
this sub r
you know this sub r is kind of very
fundamental
uh this the purpose of this file let's
go to diet you can see this is the file
this is in the directory emac this
bundled emac this code
now this sub uh file is essential
because it defines many of the
basically
core functions of
emacs lisp
essentially even the core function of
lisp
so instead of defining them in c they
define them here so let's do uh
let's this matching line is different
again so we can see
this car and cutter are essential and
zero p is also essential function it
returns you know it checks whether
the function is zero
i mean the value or number is zero and
also you see this error
um
is also a fundamental
function in emac list
when you
you know when you want to return an
error
so this sub r is like
uh this sub
file is very
essential part of you know fundamental
part of e-magnesis
so we are looking at you know as part of
you know we are digressing and looking
into this um
this file
so the reason we talked about this file
is because we are looking into we are
looking at string functions and uh
okay let's continue okay so
you know this
so it also define keyboard as all
critical function
that when you
need to define keyboard you know global
set keys local set keys
yeah or
you know the core part of
emac this
okay even you know you also define start
process this is also fundamental
this is when you call a shell script
i mean when you want to write a command
that calls a javascript that's what you
call
that you know you need to uh call for
example okay let's show
let's go to emacs you know for example
let's go to my emacs blog show in
browser
let's go to some
let's say
set up standard copy cut paste keys
okay
so
let's go to the page
there is a page and search for png
so here is the image file here's the
image tag
let's undo what did i do okay let's open
it you can see that file is this file
and i want to open this in the default
image viewer in opening system so i can
do that
so you see
on windows i my default image viewer is
iphone view a classic best image viewer
from 1990s
now cancel escape okay so you see i just
called the command to open this in my
external
viewer
you know that's
so what is this command the command i
called you can see is called excel
opening external app and now if we
describe key
and press the key you can see
uh oh wait not this one okay hold on a
second
describe key and press the key
you can see it says star opening
external app is defining soft light keys
here and now
enter to open it
you can see here is a source code for
for
open in external app
okay now this that's narrow to different
so we can just focus on this code so you
can see and it's calling um
there it is start process you see
now depending on uh whether you are on
windows or on mac so if you are um um
if you are on windows
you
you know
that you know i call a shell command
then i call powershell
but if you are on darwin which is mac
then you also call a shell command but
if you are on linux
what i do is i call start process
anyway that's another detail so what's
the difference well
well if you
the if you call you know start process
is more efficient
to
launch a external command
while shell command is more convenient
for for writing you know called emacs
this code for example right now i'm on
on windows so i call shell command and
the shell command actually called
powershell
um
but you know the start process has its
own problems because you know i i yeah
for example my open
external app i tried to use start
process on windows you know you got the
other issues so anyway let's start
process okay so if you now describe
function
and
go to start process
you can see the
documentation for start process and you
can jump to the source code
so it's in sub r
dot el so this anyway so this is a very
fundamental call
function
also defined in sub uh
now let's look at you know i'm just
curious how they
how they actually um
implement it okay so they call make
process which is more fundamental
okay so now let's describe function
uh make process there it is so you see
make process is a building function in c
source code
that is the more core you know the most
core
i mean the more fundamental of the
command
okay so we have lots of digressions and
let's do
let's list matching lines on different
again
so we know okay so we know this is very
fundamental this sub are all these
functions sub r dot el package
now i'm curious now did is the sub r
actually defined as a package
a feature or not
let's go down
okay it's not even
it's not even defined as a feature let
me explain okay so let's see
uh search for require
these matching lines require okay
uh
okay what's the word what's the function
i'm looking for
go to starfly keys go to the bottom
provide okay the keyword i'm looking for
is provide so back to subr dot el these
matching lines
provide
okay
so you can see they don't have a line
that says provide sub r dot e l
you see so what what is this provide and
require let me explain okay so when you
define a
package you know actually i have it all
emacs
provide okay so you can search for
you know i have a tutorial on explaining
on what is
emac this when you code emac this
writing a package what is provide what
is required what is features so
basically they are a mechanism
in emacs
that
defines a package okay
different from python php and javascript
others others you know modern languages
you have the concept of a package or
module
that is connected to namespace you know
when you define the module you
essentially create a namespace that can
be imported and you can specify what
function names what symbols you want to
import or export
but in e-max it is you don't have that
you have a kind of more primitive
you know
basically it's lousy okay so you
you know read this page if you want to
understand
but essentially it tries to do the same
thing you know basically when you want
to import
a package you say require
and when you write a package you have to
say provide at the end
so
so when you so other people when you you
call recall
you can load the package something like
that okay
so anyway so that's why i'm trying to
look for
you know in this
r.e.l file i'm trying to look for the
provide keyword you know list matching
lines to see all
lines that contain provide you can see
because normally at the end of a package
for example let's go to
tml mod okay
normally at the end of a package if it's
a package you will see the line provides
something something
okay that means this file is trying to
define a package
then
another list code can say require or
user init file emacs in a file can say
record require
you know
something something
but in the case of the sub dot el
in the case of sub dot e l
it doesn't even have that
so that means the sub dot el is not even
a package
it actually just a
very you know it's just a file
that emac this emax loads when it starts
up so it's
actually more fundamental because all
these functions in here
all these functions in here they are not
part of a package they are part of emac
lisp
core
okay so okay i understand that now okay
so now
now let's go back to
to how we started to look for these
functions
because we were trying to look for
string match oh yeah okay
so let's see
match
okay yeah so we can see
we have several string functions are
defined here including match string
match string note properties
and split string
which turns the string into a list
very fundamental
functions and we also have string
replace okay
okay that's how we got into here
now
okay
now i'm not doing a good job
of
working on my page because i've been
rambling all over the place
and haven't even started to
change this page
but anyway but it is true you are
looking at my workflow because that's
what i do spend hours to work to work on
this tutorial
because i cannot you know you cannot
just start to change things because you
need to know what you're going to change
them into
are you going to have just a list of
string functions are you or are you
going to have
you know like more
more essay oriented you know tutorial
style
uh each one has problems
so that's anyway
you see at the reason i want i need to
look into where is this defined is that
because later on
okay once you go over once you covered
all the
like basic functions but later on
you are run into functions that
that are not
part of core emacs for example here
for example string join
okay string drawing is edr let's let's
say string trim okay
now string trim is a very useful
command in almost every programming
language you want to remove the white
spaces before and after a string
now in e max you don't have that
function unless
if you want that you have to require
sub r dash x
okay now this is one of my major gripe
now these functions you know this
trin stream function they came out
around 2015
and they are
they are placed into the
sub art dash x package you know very odd
let me explain okay so for example if
you want to trans train stream in emacs
okay let's type it
uh okay so let's describe function
string
trim okay there it is
so you can see oh it's finally fixed
thanks to emax28
fixed this from a
major this is another major thing
god we discovered okay this is you know
a giant digression but anyway
so train stream
it's now
is now in um wait what what's going on
it's now in the package sub r dot e l
okay
now that's new
now when did it i suppose this is a
change in emacs 28 so let's look at
let's press ctrl
h
n
to go to the gnu emacs news
okay now let's this function
i mean this
the matching lines
type string
trim
okay not found let's try again
sub r
okay not found oh
maybe it's changing e max 27
what
let's uh
this matching is sub r
okay there's a one mention
uh sub r so that it's available by
default okay you see so sub uh anything
is sub r
dot e l is now you know
it's available you don't have to load
the package
okay but when did the
when did the trim stream
change from sub r dash x to sub r that's
it's an important question
finally they fixed this
oh god i've been complaining about this
for like 10 years
you know like
you don't have a trim stream function
until 2015
like that that's that's incredible
but in but in 2015
emac
you know i have an article on this you
know in in 2000
in 2014 okay emacs 24.4
they finally added train stream
string trim function and all the others
or string reverse okay string joint
you know string joint is a cd 80s you
know because you already have concact
anyway they introduced string stream
in imax 24.4
in year 2014 but however they made it so
that
you have to require you have to load the
package
sub r dash x
and what's server
dash x that's the x stand for
experimental
so let's see what happened to sub uh
x if you still have it no you don't have
it
wow that's amazing you don't even you
don't you know you don't have that file
anymore
so what happens if you actually
run the code require
server
this is this is important okay so let's
find out
what happens to
close that
what happens if you let's go to my talk
show page
uh how is it talk
okay go to start talk show
emac this template
expand it out
paste it
magnify
now what happens if i load it
run it
wow it's um
[Music]
it's loaded for compatibility reasons i
think
so you lovely little trick
what
what does it mean
um so we
so i you know right now we have a puzzle
okay this is the important
this is important to know because
because for about five years you have
this package sub r dash x
which are required if you want to train
stream
stream okay
but now
apparently
it's no longer there but however if you
run the code there's no error so
so first of all you need to find out
what is the mechanism
that kind of alias you know let's see
describe function as sub odds let's see
wait so
you know what what is the mechanism that
kind of ads sub r2 sub or something like
that you know this
very uh we have to find out
uh god my my mouse
button doesn't work because i'm now on
vorac
[Music]
layout use via windows
um so
let's let's describe function on this
okay
oh they okay there there it is it still
exists
stream blank p is a compile e magnesium
function in sub r dot e l okay the file
still exists
now let's jump to diet
uh
okay they are in different directory uh
what what
so this sub r dot dot x is in the
directory
wait what's the other so let's let's see
let's um speed window
let's go back to
let's describe function
string trim okay
okay
now jump to
jump to diet here is sub-r
and it's in a in the directory
wait they are oh
what
they are in the same directory oh oh
oh
one is lisp and one is e magnifice
okay so you you see the sub r is in the
list directory
there
but but then there is another so yeah so
okay so
so if you go to if you go up there so
there's a list directory you go there
and then there is a
emac this directory subdirectory in it
then in this directory
you will find sub r dash x okay
now another thing we need to
find out is that
oh okay so now i understand completely
okay so
so you see
trin
string trim
is considered critical now
it has been moved to the
sub r dot e l okay
but some of the others such as string
join
it's not critical because string drawing
is just
let me show you okay so
string string join already existing emac
this is called concact
so okay let me show you okay so
showing uh okay so
cancel this matching lines showing
you see
you see string join
in emac this there's already
a function that does string join and
that function is called
concact or map concat okay
either way so
um
so you know it's called that because
that's a lisp tradition like 40 30 40
years ago
but however to the modern people
you know you feel like every function
stream function needs to begin with the
word string or something like that
that's why you have that's why they add
a string join
so they added that in this
sub r dot ex file okay so that makes
okay so that's the situation
so you so you can see
in order to write you know today we are
rewriting this page my tutorial on
string functions in order in order to
like reorganize or
or update this page you know actually
there's a lot to do because
as we just happened you know we noticed
these changes
and you have you have to rewrite them
you have to tell the users what's going
on
so i have to spend another
actually an hour
or two to look into which one has been
moved to where
and also notice they didn't they don't
you know they didn't even document it in
emacs news
for example let's try again
c uh control h n
so we are looking at the gnu e max
you know news in e-max 28
and search for
trim
it's not mentioned
you know they didn't mention oh there's
a new function by the way in e-max core
they didn't mention it now maybe it's in
emacs 27 so let's go to emacs 27 news
this matching line stream
no mention of it
let's see let's go back to emacs 26
let's mention trim
oh okay so they did mention it in emacs
26 did it
so functions string trim left string
trim right and stream trim now accept
optional argument okay no
okay not here
now
in ex25 let's go to emax25
feature
feature list okay let's search for trim
no mention it no mention of it no
mention of the change
of string trim let's go to e max 24
trim
no mention
jesus
this is imax 24 right uh trim split
string now takes the optional argument
three
so
they did not
you see the point i want to make here is
that
in emacs news which is release notes
you know string trim is introduced in e
max 24 okay 24.4 but however
you do not find it mentioned anywhere
let's try it again string trim okay so
let's make sure
uh let's see
describe function string trim
you see
they mentioned in imax 24 new library
sub
sub r dash x
with these functions okay let's mention
in emacs 24 okay
however sometimes between
between
uh then and now they
move it they move some of these small
critical functions such as string trim
into the emac disc core
so did they mention it
let's see
okay not here not in mx25
not in e max 26
okay
not in e max 27
not in max 28 so nowhere they mentioned
it moved so anyway the point is you
don't now you no longer need to know
this
experimental package okay
thank you oflammo
so pharma it's got i think that's it for
today uh yeah i'm getting tired
uh offline says have you ever tried
chuck
the concurrent strongly timed audio
programming language now
now uh god my mouse button doesn't work
uh no
so any any other questions i
audio chuck is that what it is
oh here
chuck
strongly timed concurrent and on-the-fly
music programming language
strongly timed okay
no don't know what that means
concurrent okay and on the fly okay what
music programming language okay a bunch
of questions
uh
so first of all what is a music
programming language
i suppose some kind of generate
notes
uh
and also all these
adjectives doesn't
make sense to me so chuck is a priming
language for real time sound synthesis
okay that makes sense and music creation
okay real time sound
synthesis okay that means it generates
sounds like a synthesizer
but
but not by tricking knobs and wheels or
sliders but you do it by
you know uh
proving language okay that's great by
the way wufang language can do that okay
i want to show you this quickly
[Laughter]
okay so
sound it's let you know
so you are looking at uh wufam language
okay
sign
so what what what is that how do you use
the sound function
so you have quite a few functions for
sound
oh yeah sound is not what i want i want
play
yeah so i want to play
sine function
okay i want to play the sine function
sign evaluated at
um i got my new keyboard
and x
and x goes from
to let's say 20.
so this is going to play a pure tone
okay
it generates a pure sine wave okay you
can play it
okay what is this uh 20 seconds oh
that's playing for 20 seconds that's too
long let's say 5 seconds
and
this is
8k hertz
[Music]
times five okay let's see
uh you need to get it right
okay 44 oh yeah so you need to uh get
the face
you want to times pi that's right i
forgot
okay let's see what it is
so yeah okay let's say 400 times 440
that's um
that's a standard note a below the
middle c okay let's try it
[Laughter]
there it is pure sine wave for five
seconds can you guys hear it
who found language so you can you know
there's someone
who uh
who wrote
a synthesizer entirely in wufang
language
let's see if you guys can hear it
there it is
and let's let's multiply it by tangent
okay because you know you can play you
can you can get lots of fancy sounds um
let's see if they have a fancy example
there it is okay i'm just gonna play it
fantastic
okay that's what i want to show
um
you know as a
digression wait
i got my copy key
my mouse copy button doesn't work
because normally i'm using a vora
keyboard you know physical very keyboard
kinesis over there
but now i'm using this and i haven't yet
programmed it into a vora keyboard so
i'm using windows you see windows vlog
layout
but if i do that but my mouse this
button is
ctrl c
but if i press it it's
the operating system
convert the c into something else
convert the
quantity c into the wolverak um
j so now my copy button on the mouse
becomes ctrl j
and we and we can we can i can show that
in emacs okay so let's
show another great feature of emacs so
now i press
describe key
and now i press the mouse button okay so
this one
you see it says c comma is undefined
that's right because
because the
wait what he's trying to convert it it
tries to convert
quality to vol rack
okay so
so it tries to convert quality c
to work anyway it's complex but it end
up
it end up
um
wait i
this is always very confusing okay uh
this is
uh
quality comma
c
anyway
so i'm just trying to say my mouse
buttons for copy doesn't work now
[Music]
okay let's go back so that's it for
today i think so
on this question this music programming
language i don't know i haven't i've
never actually
tried any
synthesizer programming language would
be interesting
i don't know anything about it
okay i think that's it
so there's a question is it true that
emacs on window is slow well compared to
linux it's slightly slower but it's not
practically no i wouldn't say not today
if if on windows if you are using emacs
on window you and if it's slow you have
some setup wrong okay
like there are certain um configurations
for example if you
like you know if you have lots of long
lines it's slow if you have lots of
weird fonts
uh you know unicode characters of weird
uh
egyptian characters for example if you
have lots of for example let's go to so
let me let me type it okay i'm hungry
and i'm gonna
uh
okay let me show you some of the reasons
e-max is slow
if you have
a line that's thousands of chars okay
if you
have
tab
pass mod
at least
used to be
10 years ago
now tableau mod is not part of emacs but
it became part of emacs
around 2015 or something but it used to
be when you turn it on is significantly
slowed down emax okay
now this may be history
now another thing is still today is that
if you have lots of unicode charts
if
your buffer have lots of unicode
lots of charts that's from rarely
used unicode charts such as egyptian
egyptian or islamic arabic
for example if you for example you can
i'm going to demonstrate this right now
if you call the function
hello
view hello file
by default you can
this command view hello file is
connected to the key
ch
h
i think
okay but i i turn it off because
sometimes by mistake i press that then
you have to wait for once two seconds
for it to show i'm gonna show you right
now okay do it
you see
two seconds
three seconds is not still not showing
four seconds
five seconds
wait did i press enter yes i did
by now it's ten seconds it's stuck
but eventually you'll come up okay
oh god no okay so after 10 seconds it
showed up so what is this file this is
kind of a demo file that contains lots
of uh different languages you know
trying to show off emacs ability of all
these languages it takes
10 seconds to start up
i'm pretty sure it probably
i don't know for sure for on linux it
probably the same okay
why is it slow because when emacs
encounter different you know characters
it have to find
out what font to use and so it has to do
lots of search things like that
let's close this let's do it again
maybe the second time it shows yeah you
see the first time it takes 10 seconds
the second time it shows
okay so i gotta go so i'm thirsty and i
hope i answered all the questions that's
it for today thank you guys for watching
and i'm going to
like today i'm going to make a um
schedule
for the next few
youtube so you can see what time they
will start
so i'm going to schedule that
okay bye guys thanks for watching
you