good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santos show today is 2019
October 8th Tuesday San Francisco time
California kennel o'clock a.m. in the
morning good morning Bartholomew good
morning Jose and good morning people on
this cold can don't good morning Z Tron
crazy so again let me show my discord
channel so this is some sort of some fan
club and you know you can go there and
chat to me or to other people okay let
me paste that and today good morning
green deck and and this is what this
goal looks like it's pretty nice I'm
still learning it I just started to use
it two days ago
ou should check out paste name okay so
in this code you know the funny thing
about the the I think the great thing
about this code is that it actually also
supports voice channels and video as
well I don't know about video but at
least it supports voice channels just
like teamspeak so that if you are a
gamer you know you can you can use this
code to talk to your teammates and
apparently it is one of the original
goal of discord so I suppose I suppose
it is very good and I'm going to try it
voice Channel yeah so okay that's about
this code and did I paste the link yes I
did okay I have some topics prepared I'm
going to talk today and if you guys do
have
questions just post it okay with with my
name on it
but I will start to talk now now I'm
going to for a change
today ladies and gentlemen good morning
DP I'm going to do a pleasant talk with
melodious voice
and no more you know you know you know
what is melodious voice you know so I'm
going to stop that I'm going to try to
stop that and as Yoda said there is no
try just do and I will do so no more you
know things like that and I will try to
be not repetitive like I just said
already you know no more no more you
know and don't say it again
excuse me and so that is what I'm going
to do I you know you when you do a video
you have to think about your audience
and this also applies to blog blogging
if you have not done blogging before or
if you don't do YouTube before you may
not know but if you are a blogger you
know that typically if you want to
become popular I don't mean like
abusively popular but you know if you
want like people if you want more people
to follow you one of the things you have
to think about is that you are writing
or you are doing something for them like
always think about your audience
perspective like what they want to know
instead instead of just going on about
yourself like what you did today what I
did today what I I thought about what
what I think things like that so I'm
going to try to do that today and there
will be no swearing today so this
episode is we
be very safe for work very safe for work
lower the speed of your talking to ask
you have to lower it and what are you
talking very slow so let me answer
bathroom you say something I hate you
for promoting this code listen there is
nothing I can do about that it's like
YouTube you know okay it's like it's
like YouTube okay so I want to do
something I want to talk about so let me
just start get going okay so every time
I did a video after after about two
hours it will show up the live stream
will show up on YouTube and usually it's
a pain when you have a long video such
as one hour it is a pain to know at what
point you started to talk about which
subject this is often the problem for
example sometimes I go to visit you know
for example sometimes I watch Jordan
Peterson's video and often it is very
long one hour or two hours but what I
want to know is like a breakdown of
topics at what time timestamp for each
topic and that turns out that is
extremely consuming to do because I have
tried to do that for my past videos and
if the if the video is one hour
typically you will end up spending two
or more hours just to get the timestamps
because when you are talking you know it
is not simply jumping around and to get
the timestamp but also you have to
dissect the whole flower talk to find
out which which is the topics to break
them down things like that
so that is very time-consuming so if you
guys watch my video I know some of you
do after like the livestream so it would
be nice you know to to put timestamps in
the YouTube comments
if you do that that would be great
they'll be appreciated so that is about
that
the next topic and also feel free to to
edit my videos and put on your own
channel okay feel free to do that you
can post video clips on other websites I
don't mind when you have a long video
usually people are impatient especially
today they are impatient but however
some part of the video is good
so you want to typically when you are
popular like some of these popular
youtubers they have a different account
that are just the creeps of the cream of
the video so I like to have that but I
don't have time to do that and I don't
know video editing so well so but yeah I
know some some people do that often so
if you like to do that feel free okay
the next topic is so on Mike's our talk
show page you go to my website you will
see Microsoft actual page I did some
there's a kind of new interface so you
can see my YouTube account link started
top ok my donation box and Bitcoin and
so on and then there's my youtube link
my dis code link and here are some talks
your topics brain this is basically my
scratch pad for what topics I'm going to
talk about it is not in a in any way it
is just a my own scratch pad but you can
go there if you find anything
interesting
just type it I'll talk about that so
that is about that and the next thing
let's talk about for channel because I
noticed since about half a years ago my
name appears on several chann websites
often like every month
hold on the the garbage truck is passing
by again so my name is mentioned in many
several of the chant channels including
Fortune H and there is also a tiny
chance okay so I thought it would be
interesting to talk about them you know
in the past week my name has been on
4chan three times okay so before we do
that let's read the comments through
early and see what's up with you guys
so bathroom bathroom uses discord
discord also officially supports giving
all your data to NSA well who doesn't
that includes Twitter Facebook it if you
use the web that happens today okay
bottom you say is to take to take more
time to form your sentences this helps
in avoiding your petition yes nibel says
my Emacs config is coming along have
some questions though related to Emacs
and other shoot type it you know it's
always better like this also happens in
online forums for my herbs observation
in the past twenty years you know
usually it's better better if you
directly just just shoot out the
question instead of meta question unless
the forum has some kind of rules things
like that but those rules that they went
away because that's not what we
people want yeah so this is another
topic you know in the past for example
let's go to so let me let me show you
this page about hacker code okay
hacker code and this page I talked I
made a video talking about this page two
days ago three days ago
netiquette anthropology tales of tech
kickers now netiquette is a very popular
term throughout 1990s and almost
throughout mm netiquette but that term
has gone away because that's not what
people want but however back then every
program every hacker type of programmers
meaning you know the UNIX people or you
know hacker types you know the people
programmers who talked a lot online they
tell you what to do they tell you
programming styles they tell you
programming idioms they tell you what
language you should use you know this
type of people they it's very popular
among these type of people
netiquette netiquette if you don't know
it is basically a set of rules that
these people has formed that they tell
everyone they should follow for example
one of the rules when you go to a new
school for the first time do not just
jump in and start to post your question
don't do that
instead you should spend like one week
working that's another jargon back then
use use you should spend some days
reading what people say and read and
read the frequently asked questions
that's another thing before you start to
add ask questions so that is one of the
network word back then and there are
huge amount of flame wars and fight
about these just like today but
eventually
netiquette the concept of netiquette
itself instead because that's not what
people want you know that the
programmers are thinking the world
should be this way but actually they
don't know reality so eventually the
network or concept died and today you
know we have Twitter Facebook they they
become far worse then then what this
hacker typer people wanted so netiquette
so that's about netiquette let me keep
reading the comments ok yeah so if you
have a question about Emacs nibel just
post it will be fun for repetition I
write loop print bra the message helpful
review i sexually identify as trans
pranaam ignorant oops i should not read
that part of me says there is nothing I
can do about it why are you so near near
near allistic be more flowery and do you
spy Thommo or anything ok so let me
answer the question
so bother me says I use the web and it
does not happen because I'm conscious of
what I use recently I switched to my own
next cloud instance how am i selling my
own data ok yes you are special bathroom
you you are special and a lot of hacker
types are like that but we lost the war
ok I don't want to talk about this topic
because because I talked about this so
often in the past but anyway my point is
you know we have been like that for the
past 30 years and basically and look at
what today's society has become an
especially in the programming community
where did the window go the chat window
just disappeared okay just because I
clicked a link
okay let's restore chat and pop it out
again
okay so I don't know what is next crowd
let's see Wikipedia it should be
interesting
next cloud is a suite of client server
software for creating and using file
hosting services next next cloud
application functionally is similar to
Dropbox Oh like Dropbox next cloud does
not offer off premises by our storage
hosting next cloud is free and open
source which means that anyone is
allowed to install and operate it on
their own private server devices in
contrast to proprietary services like
Dropbox the open architecture allows
adding functionality to the server in
the form of applications and enables
users to have full control of their data
ok I still don't get what exactly it is
ok back to the comments
the social media of a phony ransom
shivering good morning David Kona after
setting up the instance I was inspired
to write at least one up for next cloud
okay okay let's talk about let's talk
about 4chan there are some messages I
want to mention I I'm not sure it's a
good topic to talk about but you know
since people aren't talking about me I
might answer some of it so there are
three posts on 4chan about me so let's
just look at them and see if there is
something fun I read it today yesterday
so this post is about ok fed archive
cannot reply anymore
this is two days ago October 5th so it
says it's Mathematica really better than
Lisp is it really worth $1,500 a year I
always thought it was aiming but it
looks really nice actually
so does it we actually cost fifteen
thousand a year that's I don't think
that's that much you pay like two
thousand dollars I think you buy the
whole thing you buy it and you can use
it's not based on subscription but I
think they are sub sub Street
subscription services but I don't think
it's $15,000 a year
but anyway so 4chan people they are
talking about me and so I see shouts
here and I see max rater name mention
here by the way for Chan as you know is
very you cannot trust fortune because
fortune or anything goes it's anonymous
you don't know who is who you don't know
who they are
but there is this comment which is kind
of seedy so he says please take
everything sorry says with a grain of
salt I'm going to criticize his comments
okay so he says he continues his
obsession with Mathematica is probably
the most bizarre of his many bizarre
opinions
he keeps comparing it to general-purpose
programming languages without realizing
such a comparison is meaningless as its
effectively applies to oranges
effectively Apple to oranges okay
he is incorrect he continues Mathematica
is an amazing tool with no equal in its
field but it is not nor was it ever
intended to be a general purpose
programming language wrong that's why I
wondering whether it's better or worse
than Lisp or any general-purpose
programming language is a meaningless
question okay sorry is an ethnic mark to
me he is genuinely knowledgeable about
things such as keyboard in mice history
and Emacs and yet he often holds
autistic opinions that no sin over 40
years old would have not to mention many
of them are poorly argumented at best
still an alright guy overall though
so-so
a man fortune post you would say this
one would be the extreme extreme way all
said you know because typically hoped
for Champa's they are brainless garbage
and this one would be extreme you will
see a post like this one in 10,000 okay
so I'm going to address this one so
basically his point is that Mathematica
is not a general purpose language
meanwhile he says math America he agrees
Mathematica is in his words an amazing
tool with no equal in its field Oh
so firstly you know in a sense he is
basically saying I'm right
okay he is basically saying yeah sorry
is right okay but his crib oh is that
Mathematica is not a general-purpose
language now that is incorrect first of
all that is not incorrect if you have to
say whether it has is is meaningful at
all because first of all there is no
scientific precise definition of what
general purpose programming language
means for example C C++ Java closure
Haskell they are all considered general
purpose programming languages also Perl
Python Ruby JavaScript these scripting
languages are also considered
general-purpose languages but however if
you compare a C for example to Python
for example they are entirely in
different category right so so what do
you so let me ask you this
try to define try to give a definition
of what is a general-purpose language
right now try to think think try to
think right now what is what is what
would you say is the definition of
general-purpose or if you are not
academic simply think about so for
example give me a language that is not
general-purpose language try to think of
it so basically what I'm saying is that
what is your concept of general-purpose
language if you actually think about
this then you will you will see that you
will see that you will see that this his
proposition is kind of silly doesn't
make sense because
because first of all we cannot even
define you don't even have a general
idea of what is what does it mean to
have a general general purpose language
first of all that term is you only throw
about by programmers all the time but
what is a general purpose language right
and so if C is a general purpose
language and then python is a general
purpose purpose language
why is mathematic another general
purpose language now let me give you
another reason the least data type such
as pearls list or or list in Ruby in
Python in JavaScript they have different
names and some some color list some code
array okay
but basically Perl is basically the
first language high-level language to
have list datatype such that you can
manipulate add items remove items remove
items in the middle of the list things
like that pearl this is in 1995 pearl
begin with that so many people went
whimper was around many lispers many
people including Lisbeth's start to say
they begin to say usually no not
actually disperse don't say that but
many programmers begin to say pearl is a
lease now this concept pearl is a lisp
or some language is a lisp became very
popular because ten years later people
say Python is a lisp Python is a lisp
this this very idea pet you know who
says pattern is a lisp Peter Novick okay
Peter Novick the lisp master who is a
expert of classic AI he wrote books
about these companies Peter Novick
said he Peter Novick is the first person
in lisp community that that
advocate Python in fact he you know this
is very well known this is back in two
thousand five two thousand four among
list programmers especially in comedies
Peter Novick pushed Python to become to
tell the lispers to use Python okay
then later on when when ruby became
popular
many people say Ruby is Lisp tongue
right you know this is a funny face this
you know something something turn right
so people says people start to say
Ruby's a lisp Ruby's a lisp and right
why because Ruby is based on two
languages eMac Lisp and Perl Ruby is
based on email is in Pro so people start
to say Ruby's Lisp tonight
so so you see as time goes on
programming languages becomes generally
higher level higher higher in level so
Pro is the first language to allow
programmers to freely manipulate least
as higher-order budgets by functions
without worrying a worrying about memory
addresses things like that so this these
these are all general purpose languages
now Mathematica let me talk about math
Makati Mathematica contains you know
okay
let me say this today many languages
support Pig noms
do you know what big numbers are big
noms are such that numbers with infinite
precision for example you want to find
the one billionth prime number now the
number of digits of that number is too
too many to fit into four bytes or five
or eight bytes it's you know very large
you have to for example let's say you
want to compute the digit of pi you want
to break the record
now suppose now if you save that number
you have
- it feels few gigabytes of this space
you cannot fit that number into memory
so what do you so how do you what do you
do when you want to compute such a
number you have the concept of big noms
which is also known as infinite
precision number okay so today many
languages actually has that feature in
Python I know I know you have that
package and in JavaScript it's coming to
JavaScript in next version also - 2020
or something like that it's it's coming
to JavaScript so but bignum the concept
of infinite precision numbers are in
Mathematica since 1996 also 1999 also so
what I'm saying is that you see through
the evolution programming language is
more more and more advanced features are
becoming part of a language by default
out of the box
so when you say Mathematica is not a
general-purpose language whatwhat does
that mean at all because Mathematica can
do anything your language can do it can
do anything
Perl Python Ruby Java can do so those
are general-purpose wise Mathematica not
general purpose Mathematica just has
more features that's more for example
solving equations for example let me
give you another example so we have big
numbers that's one example we have lists
that's another example let's do another
example solving equations suppose you
have an equation let's say a simple one
X sub polynomial equations okay X 3
third power plus 1 equals to zero you
want to know what X is symbolically
let's say nothing malloc C symbolic
let's just say numerically you want to
know what X is in many of today's
languages you can do that you can do
that in Python
you can do that in Python because Python
has love now a lot of math libraries you
can do it in Julia for example you can
do it in any language lots of MATLAB any
many languages can solve this
numerically at least so mathematic
Mathematica can do that since 1990 1980s
so why what is the reason today's
language let's say goal an or let's say
Haskell
let's say closure any any of the read
today's new languages why should that
language not have this building for
example you just type for example let me
show you Mathematica solve Sao lve okay
this is how you solve it in Mathematica
okay you type this in Mathematica press
ENTER it will give you a symbolic
solution not numerical okay actually
will give you a symbolic solution now if
you want a numerical solution you do
that okay now let's look up mathematic
card documentation just just to show
that Mathematica solve function so this
is a function you just type it you give
you answer okay sub-expression verbal
attempts to solve the system expression
of equations or inequalities for the
variable bus okay that's solve now let's
look at n sub-nought remember the result
of this function is symbolic it's not
just number it's symbolic okay now let's
try another n sub now in sub are just
like saab except it gives you numerical
solutions okay so so what is a reason
for a programming language not to have
these or derivative let's say derivative
or integral sobbing you know give you
to reviewing what what what is the
reason basically you don't have any good
reason I mean as long as our resources
squirrel you know the hard disk squirrel
computing power the power of a computer
language grows there's really no reason
to not have this and in fact they are
starting to have it in Python for
example as packages you download this on
a contra something scientific thing then
you have the Audis out of the box not
all but some of it so that's my point
so he says Mathematica is not you know
for first language that's just that's
just wrong what you could say is that
what you could say is that Mathematica
is not a language designed like c2 to be
to be to be embedded in CPUs that is
true okay that is true but then again
let's just see C C++ Java you you guys
do that but that's not true for Python
Perl Ruby closure for example it is
Python Ruby for example but they are
still general-purpose okay that is about
that topic
good morning Scott so okay what what is
the next topic so I didn't miss anything
interesting comments so Bartholomew says
okay but when you say some things Polly
what when he says it's basically like a
crowd where you save all your stuff
monitoring your servers okay bathroom
you is talking about next crowd that
thing okay I saw that it cost about two
thousand a year no you can buy a you can
buy the software maybe you are I don't
think that's true not a year Mathematica
so nibble says and what was watching one
of your videos
the tenure girl new one I found a post
related to it but he was so long can you
talk about that article oh yeah
so I have a that's about poetry music
and culture and also about women okay
sensitive topic but let's see where we
go with that so I wrote this article
this article is about a song in a movie
lost caution you may or may not know
about it it's very popular back in this
movie is around 2008 I think lost
caution that's the English title and
this movie is made in China it is about
World War 2 era World War 2 China versus
Japan you know Japan is invading in
China in Shanghai
around the city Shanghai and there is a
traitor
Chinese traitor is a common thing theme
in modern Chinese history you have
traders because Japanese are invading
China and they want to
you know the they want people who speak
Chinese to help them control the cities
and places so you have these traitors
they they get they take money from from
Japanese and they help the Japanese
control Chinese people so and one of one
they are several of them are very famous
popular these traders in Chinese history
and this movie is talking about one of
them where you have this then you have
this rebel group they are trying to kill
this traitor so that is this movie is
about actually that's a background story
that's a context of this movie the movie
is about this girl she is part of the
rebel group young young they were
students young people typically did all
these kind of things are young people so
she is part of the group who are trying
to assassin this this traitor you know
very rich usually this trade some
traders are very rich you know they take
money from the Japanese so but instead
of okay should I give you the should I
what they say the should I tell you the
ending but anyway so this is the story
she become a spy she it's quite an
interesting story in psychology as well
she so she became a spy and she fell in
love with the traitor
it's all planned okay she fell in love
with a traitor it's all according to
plan but then something happened
that's those that that is the story of
this movie lust caution so
so do you have a question about that new
nimbo
okay so what guys say something so what
are we talking about now we we have been
talking for only 40 minutes the night is
young
Windex says anything new about home
comfort for tests yeah there's lots of
stories that's getting it's really bad
but nothing changed they getting violent
and more violent every day the not more
but it's it's very violent they break
all the subway stations metros and all
that so neat Nebo Nebo you asked about
that question do you ask you asked about
that website do you have any specific
questions you want me to say about that
about that these articles so oh yeah so
let me read the title so the wandering
of some stress can you trust women you
know um
obviously that's a census sensitive
topic you know fortune
I've seen people are saying I'm a
misogynist okay
now that's a big topic that's this a lot
to talk about that so I'm not sure I
want to dive into because to talk about
that it's gonna be this one hour I'm
gonna do that one day not today today we
already talked 14 minutes about it so
anyway back to this article this so this
this is a movie okay this this this is
tremendous form at least from the way I
you know when I watch a movie and like
when I watch a movie I typically for
example even superhero movies Batman
spider-man Thor when I watch movies you
know suppose it's a two hour two hours
movie but typically I spent six hours on
it so two hour two hours is spent on
read on watching a movie but four hours
we spent studying everything else about
a movie so
typically I will always almost always go
Wikipedia read about the story what's
the background and any issues about that
things like that so I watch this movie
it's not just about this movie it's
about the world war two history Chinese
modern history the relations of people
they you know many things about this the
story of the movie this women failing in
love with this traitor the meaning of
love for example the human relations the
spy what is a spy the history of spy
what is what is double spy
what are some examples in a world human
history that that is kind of the things
I look into okay and the reason I wrote
this article this article specifically
is about this song now I have some
YouTube clips here you can go there and
you will see it because I don't have
JavaScript on here so let's go to let's
go to Chrome this movie so in one of the
scene she is singing a song to this
traitor this disguise well no okay it's
his name-o you know this is a kind of
history based movie so all that all the
names you will find on Wikipedia so the
the guy let's caution okay like you can
just go to Wikipedia and search for lost
caution then you'll see the historical
background and typically Wikipedia will
also give you all the the real
characters in a history of this movie so
that's the poster that's one of the
poster for for Western audiences I think
for example on Wikipedia you can also go
to Chinese version of Wikipedia
so yeah so this is a poster for Chinese
Chinese poster typically Chinese fall so
in Western they are different because
the bottom line of Baba movies too is to
make money and to make money for example
typically if you use Chinese posters the
Westerners the Westerners don't get it
you know they don't find it find it
attractive they don't see let's see what
what is this I mean you know they don't
you have to fit in the culture so in
Western society you have to for example
they they have marked marketing
researchers things like that so they
created this poster instead so it shows
I guess a guy you know a man and woman
and thus caution you know that's kind of
more fitting now this one on the other
hand this is Shanghai era
shapow you know the American the social
justice they are talking about that at
one time cheaper which is which is
actually not Chinese tradition but
anyway it's very popular back thing it's
it's a high fashion fashion clothing
style thing for women especially for the
rich and with much Western influence you
know it's Shanghai is the city that's
it's like Paris especially back then
1950s also it's much you know if you
look at the landscape the skyline of
Shanghai it's always some buildings when
I was young I look at Shanghai Shanghai
all the Western buildings because you
see all the you know western-style
buildings all over the Shanghai Bay so I
was wondering about that you know of
course now I know but anyway so this
this movie so you can see the history
historical characters for example Hong
Kong 1938 this is a part during the
second sino-japanese war or shy in and
so on
Shanghai 19 1942
and they will mention the characters
okay you know they will mention the
historical characters but anyway so back
to my article so in this film this girl
at one time one of the scene is sing
singing a song to this guy and this song
here's the lyrics they they are quite a
lot interesting thing going on about
this so this song is a very popular song
and the back thing in this during his
time in Shanghai they have a particular
they are quite a large songs that's very
sad
okay so the lyrics is interesting and
the singing style the the the singing
style is also very particular back then
did you have this Shanghai very
high-pitched sound particular style and
also the the singer of this song back
then that made this song popular she is
a superstar this is her name so Chien
and you can also find her on Wikipedia
and and she she has extremely
interesting story because she was often
and but she became a superstar back
there so she is one she's she is
basically the number one superstar back
then so she became became very rich and
she tried to find her parents which she
can find it but eventually she she she
went crazy and supposedly she she killed
herself or something and then the the
music the the guy who wrote this music
is this guy okay now as I you know as
I'm reading this article I'm you know
I'm you know the learning finding
information about them so you find the
author of the lyrics I mean to me the
lyrics and
so the music they are different person
and this a lot of interesting stories
about them for example when the China
took over I think one of them I forgot
which one got killed they got they got
you know in the Cultural Revolution
things like that like today is social
justice can so they got killed and
things like that
so anyway that about the song the song
is very sad it's very common during that
time and then okay so here is a scene
this here's a song actually I died like
I crept it so let me show that for a
moment let me mute the muse the music so
that so that Google will not sue me for
copyright so she is singing a song a
very popular song to this guy trader
range and by the way both her and this
guy this guy is a superstar movie star
you know today and and she because of
this film she also became a star so
anyway that's she singing this song in
this Japanese face this this is a
Japanese face and so the so here is more
history okay so here is the history
about the guy who wrote the music and
also the history about a guy who wrote
the lyrics so yeah so this guy doing the
Cultural Revolution he got
he got I'm not sure what's his fate but
he's got you know okay so one of them
died one of them died in prison anyway
so the question so that's the this is
this this part this part is what people
want me to talk about you know on 4chan
or what whoa whoa or today's American
white white Americans see see these are
Co they will they will pay no attention
to everything else they just want me to
talk about this thing this part the
question of trust in females I'm not
sure I should talk about that I mean I
could I could but let's talk about
beanie being a spy okay being a spy is
very anyway so let me read the comments
first let's see where this this is going
so I've been talking for 15 minutes and
here is the disco let's see what's
happening on this code livestream yes
general stream okay so let's see oh yeah
by the way feel free to comment on this
code if you don't want to do it on
YouTube actually do it on YouTube why
not no so we have one place to to look
at all the comments
should wear this dress sorry should wear
this dress are you religious
I'm not Regis okay I'm I'm kind of
agnostic okay
so green deck say okay so no comments
actually so no comments
so nito nito what are you trying to
okay so Nebo says okay that might be
controversial but what is that song she
is singing okay so let's let's talk more
about this
okay now mythology that's a great topic
that's a big topic Missa misogyny okay
this social justice [ __ ] okay wait
today this today's talk show is not
supposed to be any swearing so yeah so
this social justice people are very bad
people today they they are totally
ignorant and whatever the things they
say are completely it's not it's not
just it's not correct just to say they
are wrong they are they are come they
are they are they are like a coat they
are like they are designed just like
cultural revolution they are designed so
that they can kill any people they want
that that is about that is about the
social justice people and there are
opinions whatever you know there are
things that is what they want basically
it's a principle it's a philosophy
designed so that they can become more
and more powerful in without any
anything they they don't like you know
they don't like you they you disappear
that's that's what this social justice
people are doing so they have created
many things related to sex many ideas
related to sex to women to women and you
know and and trans and and typically the
white people
okay not okay yeah white people exactly
that's that's the social justice term
you know a lot of people see my videos
because I started to use the word white
people a lot I've never used that word
before
but since maybe two months ago I started
to use that word and I find that that
word quite fitting and also I have seen
you know so in the past three days okay
let me get back to this so on three chan
this all happened in past three days
people started to talk about my videos
because I started to do videos once you
do videos people started to see you it's
very interesting because I've been
writing blogs for 20 years and the since
blog died you know nobody nobody knows
your stuff he's guy and also Google
Twitter they are controlling everything
Twitter wants to trigger once the social
network you know to be popular in
Facebook they don't want Prague to be
popular same thing with Google Google
tried Google+ and Google tried to force
you to login to Google+ to force every
youtuber to be part of Google+ to force
you to use real names and their that all
failed Google+ shut down two years ago
last year also things like that so when
Prague is dead my blog you know people
don't don't know um you know so today
almost like the only way to get hurt is
to go on you know Twitter not masterda
not not any of these open source niche
stuff you go on Twitter then you just
loudmouth post every opinions every hour
that's how you get hurt that's how you
get popular and that is how some many of
these social justice on one side you
have this social justice people every
day they are crying about na z o na c is
happening everywhere they get more and
more popular on the other side starting
used you are you have mee mee mee maws
and gamers you know you just suppose
means and and you know since three years
ago you started to have more
conservatives people
try to fight the Socialist Justice which
I support fully I support the religious
fever okay you know that you started to
to have that so basically all these in
my opinion it's it's it's the problem
one of the major problem I would say
almost the number one the most important
the issue the problem is is this evil
take corporate corporations Twitter and
Facebook they create this situation they
create the bubble anyway so back to what
I was saying so I was saying it's almost
today you you want to you know you have
this if you talk reason nobody nobody
cares nobody cares what do you want is
you know what you want you you want the
likes you know you want everyone to hit
your likes so in order to do that you
want to become brainless you want to eat
it you know for example post memes you
know something like ticks people cat
pictures or something angry that's what
you want to do that then you get people
then people like people like then
treated broadcast you know spread you
know tries to then your post becomes
more widespread then you get then you
start to become famous then you make
money so that so it is Twitter and
Facebook they are creating this
situation you know any reason any
rationale any reasonable people you get
you get buried nobody care of hockey
about your opinion so but so back to
what I was saying so since I started to
do video video is actually a great thing
because people see your face did you see
you what what you are saying you know
they get they get it instead of text
text is kind of like hidden you can say
anything but but with video peoples you
know video is the primary communication
of human animals it's it's primal
text as opposed to writing and reading
that takes study that takes years of 10
years of education to be able to read
and write stuff like that so video is
primal so since I started through to
video so you know so more people
to not get to know me so anyway on 4chan
because of the current culture the
instance people and also because the of
the nature of 4chan you know on 4chan
it's not like you go there to post your
true opinions or something or maybe you
know for Chinese you know people like to
say oh four channels where no censorship
right but it's more it's also lots of
other things but anyway anyway one thing
about 4chan is that you have a
particular style you go there you to you
know people called shitposting yoga
shitposting i don't like i don't even
like the term okay so what does should
pose to me that means you don't you
don't care about anything just post
garbage like you know just do whatever
anyway that that has become a style of
fortune so when you participate in
fortune actually you you you tend to
want to go into that style so instead of
saying so yeah so you want you you tend
to want to want to exaggerate things so
say you know sudden writing styles
wording like you have to use fortune
jagan job joggins like shitposting
thought you know you have to kind of do
that then then you are in group they are
then you are oh this guy is you know I
like this guy disguise its accepted
member of the group so anyway alpha for
chance
so I also noticed new awesome so people
started to say you know the women issue
anyway so I digressed through several
levels but okay let's talk about the
lyrics okay what is this video that is
good oh go yeah go now that's the last
five minutes of the video of the of this
movie the last you know there are five
minutes sing at the end near the end of
the movie and that five minutes scene
captures the entire movie that is the
essence of this movie is about okay I'm
telling you that as a kind of a film
analysis
you know in my typical style in my email
in my point of view okay that fight five
minutes that near the end is the essence
I I think this this video actually I did
this video I clipped it back ten ten
years ago that's my first first Youtube
upload I think something like that this
but then then Google says oh you violate
copyright this or that so I think I
removed it I just deleted so the movie
is also the lyrics the lyrics is about
okay let's read the lyrics so the lyrics
is in Chinese okay but there is an
English translation now who translated
this okay so this translation is from
the DVD so he says from the end of the
earth to the father to the father
father's see I searched for my heart's
companion young girls seen a young girl
since while he's while he accompanies
her your heart is my heart look north
okay now that's my that's the first
paragraph the second the second how they
co-ed the poems they the second stanza
okay poets call them stanza or things
like that the second son's eyes is is is
getting serious okay now it says looking
north from my mountain nest my tears
fall and wet my blouse missing him I
will not rest only love that lasts too
hard time is true now white what does I
mean that because that that that is
talking about what white white looking
North because North is occupied by Japan
so the last stanza says in life who does
not cherish cherish the springtime of
youth a young girl to her men is like
bread is like threat to its needle my
beautiful man we are like a threaded
needle never to be separated so that
that is the song that that is so okay so
what what else today so oh yeah so
another interesting so you know another
interesting about this song is the music
notation you see these numbers now that
is an music notation that music that
notation is called numbered musical
notation apparently this music so I
started to look into this music notation
is fairly popular in China okay
also in Taiwan because I have seen it
when I was you know 10 years old in time
1 so it is youths numbers not not staffs
and notes it used numbers and and
wikipedia has an article on this
notation so this is called so let me
read it
the numbered musical notation is a
musical notation system widely used in
music publications in China not to be
confused with the integer notation okay
then it says it dates back to the system
designed by Pierre Galan known as Canon
Paris Ave system it is comparable to the
conscious notation from the 1010 Tang
Dynasty okay so anyway so it's invented
by these people in Germany okay I think
so so bottom you have you ever seen this
music notation
so anyway so you know this story is
about Shanghai you know my dad my dad my
mom came from China you you know I was
born in Taiwan so you know from what I
know my dad has a sister who was one
years old or three years old and died in
Shanghai doing Bao me so that is why I
kind of kind of get emotional somewhat
you know be you know okay I never seen
it before
okay so I think that's maybe that's it
for today so let's get a drink or
something oh
so today's drink maybe not so so today
is a milk with coffee powder
so how many people asked you're watching
at sea
22 people wow it's the guy I'm getting
popular posted
what posed it my piano practice books
had them later changed to a standard
notation hope so DP you are from German
Germany right good morning Scott so
what's still here until 2:30 okay so
let's talk a bit more so what's up Scott
so let me show you today I'm drinking
coffe well it's just coffee coffee with
it's nothing to show actually you know
the crystal coffee crystals they that's
what they call the proper term is coffee
crystals it just powdered it's just
powdered coffee okay okay so DP is from
Germany so let's see what are some
interesting comments that I can block on
Twitter SeaMonkey so DV says do you use
RSS and what are your thoughts about it
yeah I do but no ii so if you go through
my any of my blog for example a
programming blog you see this RSS file
you can click it and that is the that is
the RSS file and you know that that well
yeah this is my RSS file and the the
format I'm using there are several Isis
formats the one I'm using is called atom
so so I showed this before but for
example let me show you let me show you
another one so so I have a bunch of what
are these comments okay so anyway so for
example you see this is
2019 October 4th that is this one so I
have a picture about pazzo pazzo is a
JavaScript library you can see this line
that's a picture you can open it you see
so so this page is that page so now
suppose I want at let's go here I create
a new one okay I create a new one and
say something so ok make a paragraph
show in browser you will see it here now
I need to add it to the ISS file so I
again I have a command if you look at
the left top window you will see it so
let me call it I press a key I mean it
opens this ISIF RSS file my Isis file
which is xmf XML file and it
automatically added this section so it's
autumn is automatically added so now I
have to do actually I need to change the
title because I don't have a title for
this so let's say something so ok save
it close it then I go to e shall I call
command to sync to my web server or sync
type the password and you will see ok
actually you will see it added this file
and it added these two files now the
other the others are just directories
like I deleted some backup files they
didn't been a directory will show up
like that so anyway so so it's updated
to my web server so now if you go to
sorry sorry blog - I mean blog okay one
of my blog is programming blog so this
one
and scroll down you see that see entry
so that's how I do is I have ISS for my
Emacs blog and other Bronx yeah so does
that make sense decide yeah so I do have
that
so all those commands are on my Emacs
website by the way so saw Adam make Adam
okay so such because I make Adam entry
you you will see it okay I do have a
Adam web feeds tutorial okay maybe it's
it's on my okay I actually I did a video
about it I think yeah I can actually I
did a video about that
so what else let's see yes this movie is
interesting so she is a star she became
a star ten way haha you know I noticed a
lot China Chinese people in China I
never been to China by the way so I
notice a lot Chinese people in China
says she is the most sexy girl and this
guy this this guy did this this guy is a
superstar but in this picture he doesn't
look so good okay so he looked like that
I guess but anyway he's a well-known
he's 57 now he's a superstar by the way
another interesting thing about this
this movie is that I think it's true
okay supposedly they have a love scene
make like make make like [ __ ] [ __ ]
okay [ __ ] scene naked so the director
angry is very famous now because he has
directed many western movies like some
of the superhero movies one of the early
hook movies by him I think so he has
step directed several Hollywood movies
anyway the director says you know they
want them to be real like actually so
these two actors actually [ __ ] each
other when when in the in the film
that's real that's not you know fake or
body part things like that so so so this
movie is also famous for that and
there's another thing oh yeah
interesting thing okay so this girl is
also a historical figure you know she's
a spy so her name is yeah this girl so
this apparently this is a real photo of
the woman so this this is a modern
history of China okay as such they are a
lot fans you know a lot of Chinese
people
they study they talk about it on you
know on on TV oh you know Oh books
written this like this a lot
obsession kind of almost like with it
you know like in Khmer comparatively in
a similar way it's very similar to
American Civil War in America okay you
have a bunch of white people talking
about it all the time like how how slave
is freed or you know I I don't
understand that you know too much about
that but you know you have a lot of
people obsessed obsessed about it
everyday and in the same way in germany
i guess you know i yeah i know you have
Nazi so again the German party people
talk about it every day every day okay
so Scott says I think the question might
be also my Osby what you use for
following RSS feed oh yeah I don't I I
talked about this that someone asked me
about this but actually I don't I well
you know there are several bloggers or
people I do really want to read like
there are several people I mentioned
before Stefan wolf and for example his
blog and this kind of used Stevie X you
must you probably know nice Stevie X he
is a very popular Emacs user he worked
for Amazon he also worked for Google but
he quit Google like two or three years
ago it's another kind of story he he
used to be a very big fan of Google
saying saying that you know Google is to
know Eva but he also quit two years ago
he is on Twitter where waste Steve yak
okay so his name is Steve yak ye Gigi Oh
maybe there's a s I forgot anyway it's
easy to find Steve yeah okay he's a very
well known Emacs Prager so they are okay
he's also on Wikipedia so there are a
few people for example his blog I would
read every day but however I just never
I actually never got into the the habit
of using RSS you know I don't use RSS
readers I don't I go get so so instead
of that I typically just whenever I feel
like reading I go around look at their
website you know and read all their past
past articles so there is new discord
messages I hear it I can hear it I would
watch but I'm at work would really like
to hear your thoughts on name that's
another popular question I talk about
that often the name is like very fast
modern language it's like Python kind of
based on Python same syntax so I think
it's great it's the same niche let's go
host but better and with Python syntax
yeah exactly so I don't really know much
about name and I don't plan it I don't
plan to learn it though because because
I'm just going to stick with goal and
because they are too many languages and
I need to do other things such as I need
to get on to learn understand homotopy
type theory proof proof theory
differential geometry things like that
and also my JavaScript project so yeah
so maybe that's it for today yeah that's
so anything else let's see
part of me says I can answer a couple of
questions on name
Ok Go has bathroom you you know let me
mention let me also just say I have some
kind of I don't know it's psychological
what issues ok like when I have its you
know ok so let me put it this way you
know that today is social justice people
they like to they like to victim they
like to talk about victim right
victimization
no you know things like that they like
to chant about victims so one of their
chant you know one of the things they
like to talk about is post-traumatic
stress syndrome okay post-traumatic
stress syndrome let's see how do you
post-traumatic stress syndrome PD SS
wait that doesn't sound right
but anyway that's that's one of the
thing they talk about especially for
example rape victims
okay rape victims they like to talk
about it all the time Oh post-traumatic
stress syndrome now so so what I wanted
you know there is something with me I
think that's that's been going on with
dying because my dad and stuff okay
anyway so I think that's actually that
that's kind I think that's a symptom I
have I have that okay yeah if you want
to talk about that if you know these
social justice people so sometimes I
just get like all of a sudden very sad
that things like that and well yeah
pdsd right post post-traumatic stress
the something anyway I forgot
okay David corner PTSD okay what what
the [ __ ] that does I stand for
let's see disorder Oh disorder you know
and these people you know they have
they're talking about oh yeah
post-traumatic stress disorder this is
you know you know that reminds me let me
show you this okay then let me show you
this comics comics book on a second okay
actually let me see if I can find it
anyway I don't let's see I think that's
it for today that's it then
so what I let's see what so I'm going to
delete these sections because I don't
need it and go back to my XML file and
delete what we just done so I don't want
that okay so first we open back to shell
upload again okay that clears out the
these
these something's song today refresh so
it's good so let's go back to talk show
okay so let's see what else actually I
think that's it today
so Oh successor to tempo OS yeah some of
the 4chan things you know which is funny
so so Jan so this one we talked about
you know the Mathematica is mathematical
really better than this okay you just
have to pay that so if you don't mind
paying so this one yet this one and
transportation so G never chosen a
successor kasaa has high intellect is a
bit crazy has mental issues and creates
a lot of stuff stuff like ease and wrote
a lot of books that are all free so has
a lot of long video streams act does not
work for big company because of issues
what do you guys think so they need a
successor of Terry you know Terry is
this schizophrenic guy who who is who
went crazy who is a genius creating
created this temple OS and in the end he
died he two years ago or so he killed by
a train it's unclear whether he eats a
suicide but anyway that's pretty sad
Terry this Terry guy temper OS but then
yeah so I forgot what is if there is
something I want to oh yeah so this this
I I saw this criticism of me and I
wanted to criticize I want to comment so
anyway this guy says none of us suppose
the accomplishments are anywhere near
the knowledge and technical ability
needed to create an entire innovative OS
together with its dedicated from a me
language from scratch that is true that
is actually true
the the temper always like eidetic you
know
and also he says as much as as much of
me it is tempo s is actually a very
interesting piece of software yeah the
very fact that everything was okay
whatever so so maybe one day we will
finally overcome the UNIX poo
phase in technology and stuff and the
last line last line exactly what the
[ __ ] did Sato wrote a couple of Emacs
packages and troll with ease and troll
with his often in in opinion so for over
20 years okay yeah well that's what he
what he said is true you see what he
said he's actually true I never hand
also I never claimed I was great you
know I never even claimed that yeah yeah
I never even claimed that was a great
program not even just great I never even
claimed that but however he's you know
he's not getting the there are other
things he's not kidding you know you can
see you can tell by the you don't get
things anyway okay so let me follow
through okay he for example for example
let me give you example what is wrong
with this guy is common okay first first
of all this is just for chance oh
there's nothing wrong with it I mean
people just go there everyone's
anonymous you make fun and you post
whatever is in your mind or something
bothering you you know you just say it
you maybe you feel good so there's
nothing wrong with it okay and this is
actually really fairly reasonable post
again it's one of the extreme on 4chan
you will not see such elaborate and well
welcome post post on 4chan like that
okay so that's pretty good and so so he
says okay yeah I cannot compare to
version that's true totally true but
there is something he is missing I mean
if we take his post see
there is something he is just missing
okay for example what I mean by that I
mean let me tell you an example for
example the let's say political parties
you know how in politics you have
parties fighting with each other a and B
party a let's just say party a and party
B party Athens they are right about
everything
party B's things thinks they are right
about everything so part party a we
oppose something statistics you know
some statistics about income in income
disparity or payment gap between
different age group or male/female
something like that they would they were
just posted so party a posts that and
they said they you know to to them this
they think you know look look at this
this here is a factor or scientific
piece of statistics it says we are right
you know the party a he says everything
we are right okay now but party B party
B post something something else some
another statics statistics let's say
let's say about the the person's income
with respect to his age let's say that
okay so they they have a graph graph you
know a statistic and into the party B
people they say look look at this
factual scientific accurate you know
statistics it says party B is right we
are right you know so what base so what
you know you call this cherry-picking
okay that that's a phrase you know you
this I don't I don't want to follow
phrase because once you follow this
chart joggins it doesn't mean anything
anymore but anyway the the situation I
described what people are normally
called
cherry-picking so you pick something
that represent you know that that seems
you are good about everything and and
and your opposition does the same thing
but if you are in this group or in a
group if you are in emacs code you only
see the part that is right you know you
don't see everything else so what so
what I'm saying my criticism of his
criticism about me
is that he
he's missing you know he just want to
and first of all i never said i was
better than Terry you know this tempo OS
kayo i never said i was better
programmer than any programmer actually
you look at my thousands not thousands
you are you yes thousands of articles
all my past six years video you will not
see i ever say that i'm better than this
program or that program never said any
thing like that but however what I have
said is that oh these programmers they
are idiotic they are wrong about some
particular thing about programming
language design about Mathematica for
example the other guy say who says
Mathematica is not a general-purpose
language you cannot compare to it you
know that I'd you know I did criticize
II you know in my opinion he's incorrect
so I criticize lots of these things
Python how Python design things
meanwhile how they refused or denied
some other things so I quick criticize I
have lot of non-standard non mainstream
opinions that's correct
but I never said that I'm better than
this program or something just like that
never unless I have I was talking about
something else to give the background
okay so but even I will say now in
general and you know I like I said this
you know yesterday or a few days ago
more than one time twice in different
videos I'm not in general I'm not a
maybe I'm average above average
programmer for sure but not because of
my programming skills actually my
programming ability is so-so okay
but however I do have much far more
better understanding knowledge about
programming okay about any even a
particular specific technology such as
Perl JavaScript eMac B's for example in
JavaScript for example you have turns of
Google working at Google Facebook they
call JavaScript they make two thousand
twenty thousand dollars a month I make
one thousand dollars a month but I know
JavaScript the language better than all
of them
like well oh it's a traumatic okay let's
say I know I know JavaScript the
language
now remember this is very specific
specific JavaScript the language not how
you write a program not react.js not
every JavaScript the language according
to JavaScript language SPECT ACMA script
spec ok I know the JavaScript language
better then let's say let me put it 95
okay
95% of all programmers at Facebook Oh
Google ok let me just put it that way
that I claim okay if you for example
this guy this guy on 4chan or any or any
person if you disagree on that then you
can say you know notice all these
[ __ ] then we can talk okay but but
what i'm saying is i never said i was
better than anyone you know i don't
think i have great programming skills ok
and i also mentioning not a lot my
videos a lot of people have great forum
in skills ok i'm not not that quick but
but better than average for sure ok like
depends on what you mean by average then
we can now we can talk about
scientifically what is average
okay i can tell you what i mean by
average okay so let's say anyway so
that's another thing so anyway so this
guy he wanted to you know he's you know
what see another was you can say he's
doing a Stroman okay he says you know he
says I'm no better than Terry and then
the last line you see the last night
exactly what [ __ ] did Sato
wrote a cup of Emacs packages and road
with his often in in opinions for 20
years that is kind of silly I mean
that's that's not a serious comment you
know does the CVD actually meant to say
something with that okay so in general
what does heat me okay so in general if
we take it seriously what he means is
that okay so he what he means that in
general me sorry have not done much in
my life that is significant okay that's
basic
what he means okay at least at least for
sure what he means that whatever I've
done in my life is not comparable to
Terry this temporary guy
now do I accept that no I don't even
like I don't accept that
okay so even if he says that I don't
even accept that because I I can get
into that okay so first of all I don't
even accept that so if what he means
that Saudi of my life's work is nothing
oh it's not comparable to Terry the
tempo OS guy I do I do not agree okay so
let me just talk about that so why not
so for example let me say let me put it
this way tempo is what does thing what
does he do
I mean he created this kind of toy
operating system yeah it's very advanced
you know it's he's like a genius but
it's of no use it's actually no use
nobody ever is it has no practical
impact in society how many people
actually used it in the whole world
everyone is talking about him well maybe
listen 1,000 something like that oh
let's say be generous a few thousand
people have ever even just tried it who
has looked into the source code and also
let me ask address the question we owe
his code you know his life's work tempo
OS we owe that have some even some a
little bit impact to society like maybe
universities will teach one course about
it or something in general no in general
no well maybe
yeah some fans and fan clubs yeah so
what he did so he did he created this
niche OS you know that's that that
tickles the minds of the hacker the tech
because like ignite this guy okay that's
you know can you say I cannot use it for
anything on the other hand I Casali
yeah I haven't done much well I brought
a lot tutorials I wrote my special plane
curves that is the most popular website
for 10 years from 1998 to let's say 2005
the most popular I got emails from
professors from University students from
PhD students from carpenters you know
they asked my permissions to can use my
image to use it in their lecture I did
have that special plane curves that's my
math project I created a go Emacs
package that's being around used by a
lot people let's save a few thousand
let's say at least four five years ago
Emacs distribution then I created like
stuff like ease I guess at least maybe
once out let's say the minimum of 1000
people uses something like that or even
less they are created kasa Emacs website
tutorial a lot of people in fact it is
the only resource of all the things
including published books this in my
Emacs this tutorial is basically the
only solid kind of complete the most
comprehensive compared to all this is by
far the tutorial our Emacs Lisp so
that's some use okay oh yeah that's you
know so this guy is you know it's these
fortune people you don't know nothing
okay that so the last you know I don't I
don't add the ID and you know that okay
so that's it actually today that's for
today I don't I didn't this today's
video is not supposed to I wanted I
wanted to avoid you know to become a
mega megalomania so Scott says Scott
says it's almost 2:30 okay so yeah so
that's it thank you guys and how
expensive is the last internet in San
Francisco area I pay I pay like eighty
dollars a month
and my speed is only 24 megabits per
second
yes so you know it's not it's not
compare you know I think you know I I am
very competitive competitive okay so to
the degree actually you you could say
it's a character flaw I mean it's Bo
Dean it's you know pain you know it is
pain that that I'm alive it's you know
I'm alive because of pain I'm very
competitive and I'm so therefore I'm
also extremely sensitive if you want to
talk about oh you don't know something
old you know I don't know something you
know I'm extremely competitive and I
spent you know years to study things
yeah okay so um so okay that's it about
today thank you guys for coming by I'm
gonna shut down in women
one minute I'm gonna shut down in one
minute okay that's it so I'm gonna shut
down