start command log
mod good morning everyone welcome to
another episode of
star talk show today is 2020 september
13th sunday 11 o'clock in the morning
and we are going to do emacs list
coding and other random chats so if you
have
any questions type in the comments and
let's begin
let's begin today's day so this is my
emacs let's go to talk show
and on the right window that's a pink
window you can see all my command name
command names and keys commands that i
call in emacs
so showing browser today's live stream
magnify now let's talk about the
background image
this background image is a fantastic
image
it's of course by azure mc asia
now this uh this the title of this
artwork is called stars
it's got a symmetric um
polyhedron regular polyhedron now i'm
not sure what's the
technical name for this polyhedron let's
see
uh so you got a tetrahedron here two
tetrahedrons okay it's uh
some sort of tetrahedron stars
and so this is artwork by m.c escher in
1948 and it's a wood
engraving uh fantastic this is the real
art
unlike today's memes crap
by the millennial generation although
millennial generation it creates crap
okay so so starts by azure chameleon
polyhedron
and you know this animal is chameleon
quite uh fascinating
animal then in second life second life
someone created
a a replica uh emulation you know they
recreated the scene
this is in second life which is kind of
like a
real 3d game so you can be in it well i
was in it
to take these screenshots you can look
at this thing from different angles you
can
even walk around depending on how big is
this thing you can actually
for example you can be an ant very
tiny working on this huge giant
uh structure
and in fact that's what this guy
a girl uh kind of my friend my
acquaintance
she has done so she has created this
huge giant structure in second life
so let's play it a little bit
so that's her you can see that's her and
she's
you know playing the camera so this is a
huge
giant structure and
her name is wheezy gynoid
ginode you know she is pretty strange
you know like most of my followers my
friends
we are strange guys she is one of those
pretty strange
guys okay so you can see this
huge structure now this is the firm part
of second life this is why i love second
life
sally second life i talked about many
times
about my adventure of second life there
are some videos
uh let's see second life second life
blog fantastic
okay so we are talking about
you know second life there are diverse
subjects topics so we are talking about
math in second life fantastic
okay so that that is about the
background image
okay now let's go shall we begin to do
emac these
any questions and comments comments in
comments okay
jose says hey good day from ecuador hey
jose ecuador
anush cortez and
dubanet jabanet
something like that okay so we're gonna
do
emac bisp okay then
then we're gonna talk random after that
some
more emac this or some other coding so
emac is shown in browser so polyhedron
uh chameleon polyhedron ashes
hook so what we are going to do is um
let me show you okay so i've been
working on my javascript
tutorial so you have
uh you have sample code
okay let me let me show you properly
what's going on so you show in browser
so this
is this page you can see this html this
is a sample code of javascript
it trying to illustrate
uh the tostring method
applied to a function what does it
return
basically it returns a string
representation of the function
so if you say array dot to string it
says
function array native code you know
the result are not necessarily runnable
because
some of them anyway anyway that's a
that's the example code of javascript
so in my when i write my javascript
tutorial you can see 1 thousands of them
here
because i have been working on my
javascript tutorial in the past
uh three days so you can see javascript
array prototype slice and this uh
not this one okay css this way so array
prototype slice
what is this okay jquery tutorial this
is a
fantastic fantastic introduction
functions
argument object how to convert
javascript
5 to javascript 2015
array prototype sorts you know i've been
working on these
hundreds of pages you can see
okay so when i work on my javascript
tutorial i have these issues often
sometimes
uh it i want to let me show you
i want to you see this i use console.log
okay so let me show you go back to the
html page so you can see
there's a bunch of console log
you know so let's format it so it's
clear let's copy it
put it here and let's
let's make it this way so
it will be actually easy to see
so you see you have four lines of
console log
now but sometimes i want to remove these
uh
console log lines i want it to be just
like that so it's rather tedious to
remove them manually
you know i you know so i want to be able
to select
a block of code and press a button and
have the console log removed
how do you do that well normally
people programmers will think oh let's
we can do this by regular expression
and the answer is wrong
now regular expression if you don't know
regular expression has a his
you know it came from um
it's actually you know the technical
term
about that is automata it's related to
passing
it's related to generating grammars okay
it's a
kind of a theory okay regular expression
by definition by the very
name regular expression you know what
what does it mean regular
like most people don't know what do you
mean regular
like most of most of the time when we
use regular expression
the expression is not regular at all you
know for example
you know these so what do you do well
regular expression came from
a theory in um
in in
in in grammar generation okay in passing
grammar generation related automata
uh it's called state machine
anyway don't don't quote me for it it's
related topics it's a theoretical it's
part of theoretical
theoretical computer science and regular
expression
the very meaning of regular it means it
means it cannot match
anything that's nested when you have
nested that's not
regular that's uh that's uh one
that's a technical uh meaning of regular
in
grammar okay you have regular grammar
for languages that's based on regular
grammar you have regular languages so
that's what regular means
basically it just means there's no
nesting
so when you have a nesting you it is
technically impossible to use regular
expression to pass it
but however today's regular expression
is not
really those theoretical regular
expressions there are some
abilities to do um two parts nested but
but really it's just not suitable but
anyway so
we are going to write a command to
remove the uh
the the console log okay
so far so good randy hey from north
carolina
north carolina that's uh that's the
that's
that's the country states right i mean
that's the
red state or something like that okay so
we are going to write a
let's start okay let's instead of
talking let's start
to uh put code in your mouth
then you'll see what we are doing so so
okay show in browser first
let's copy this line as an example in
our documentation of it
so we are going to define a function
different
yes yes you want to defend yes wait
different okay defend
f uh wait hold on so dog string
dog string we want to
okay remove
the
console.log what
curly quote you can you see that i like
i want curly quote
remove console.log in
text selection or
current text block
okay in current text
block or text selection okay so let's
clean up wait
remove the console log
in context blog or text selection let's
do it quickly so i don't
waste time just talking about
verbalization
okay today's version code so that's a
dark string
and that's the function name will be
remove console log okay let's just say
that
let's say okay wait
let's you know naming of things is
usually difficult because you want to
name it so that it's
extremely easy when people read the name
they will understand
what the function does but that's not so
easy because usually a function does
it's hard to describe in one or two
words
but anyway for now let's just say that
remove console.log
okay then we can rename you know that's
how i work rename it later so remove
console.log so
we so what we want to do so
let's go back so let's um what are we
doing so yeah we are coding of course
we want to um we check
video check audio check
coco how are you doing my friend's dog
is here
so okay so what are we going to do we
want to remove the console log
okay there's a trick i'm going to show
you guys about
emac this trick because if you cannot
use regular expression to do this then
how do you
how are you going to do it well there's
a tricky image
without regular expression so first of
all we go to the
top of the buffer uh go to
wait let's let's um if
use region p okay that means if there is
a region
then let's declare two variables
p1 p2 that that's position one position
two
you want to find the position of the
region you want to work with
that's the first task so
so if there is a region then use the
region then then
then we say then we say
set p1 region beginning
that's right set p2 to region end
that's right if there's a region now if
there's no region
then what we want to do is we want to
get the
block that is kind of like a paragraph
eliminated by empty lines so we want to
find the empty lines before and after
the cruiser and that will be our region
so what we do
let's do this quickly save excursion
just look up
on my tutorial you'll see explanations
about functions you don't know or
uh just use describe function okay
so save excursion search backward we
we're gonna do this quickly so because
i've been doing this
in the past few days as well past week
search backward
search backward for two empty lines uh
bound near no error true count we don't
care
then search forward
um
okay then let's just do this
way so it's fast okay search backward
and search forward
then set point one
point set point so when you search
forward or backward that moves the
cruiser
so you search backward to two empty
lines then search
for to empty lines that means you're
moving the
cruiser like if the cruiser is here
first of all you search backward to
empty lines so that means the cruiser
cannot be there then you search for
forward to empty lines that kusa is here
that's that's the position you want
because that's the paragraph beginning a
paragraph so then we set
p1 equals to the point now
for point two position two is about the
same so
if we search forward first and search
back backward then
0.2 okay predefine the code that's
it that's the py and p2 is the beginning
and end position
of our stuff
okay so let's see uh what are we doing
so far so good okay so
so we got the position let's see what we
want to do
[Music]
narrow then region okay narrow to region
p1 p2 so that we ignore anything that's
above p1 and above below p2 and
when you do that you want to say save
restriction
you want to say that because
when your command is done emacs will
revert
the buffer's region i mean you will
it we will remove the narrow to region
so narrow to region is a command you can
call interactively
interactively for example for example
let's say i'm working on this
this uh let's say i'm working on this
part of code
and there are lots of things above and
below it i don't care
so i want let's suppose i want to do
some find
only in this region so i can i can say
narrow to region you see now the buffer
it appears
you know that's the o there it is in the
buffer
but actually there are more things but
you are only you are narrow to the
region
so to remove the now to region you call
the command called widen
okay so you can see in the pink window
widen so now we can see the whole
thing again okay so that's that's uh
that's the thing so
now we got the point p1 p2
and we want to narrow to region and now
we go to
move the cruiser to the beginning of
buffer go
to chart point me okay that's what we
want
go to the beginning of buffer and search
for word
console.log that's right i want to
search for what
let's say i want to use the regular
expression to search
search for word why because
sometimes there is a space after the dot
console log
so i want to catch that
and you know i want to catch a space and
uh
for period is in regular expression is
that
okay uh double backslash
period for a literal period
okay so we want to search console log
okay bound neo no arrow
uh no error true we don't care if
there's zero
that means if it's not found now
normally if it's not found
then e my emacs will stop saying oh it's
not found
error but in our case we don't want
error because if it's not found that's
fine because that means the buffer
doesn't contain
console.log so you want to give this
parameter argument no error option
so predefined the codes so we go to the
beginning of buffer
then we search forward by regular
expression search for the console log
that's right then
then then we want let's say
we want i want two more positions let's
say p3 and p4
then you want to set p3
i want to remember position i want to
remember the beginning position
of the console okay so
set p3
position number three i want it to be
uh match
beginning okay match beginning zero
so match beginning returns the position
of the beginning of the match
and it takes one argument
which is a number zero means the whole
regular expression
so in our case it just returns the
position the
beginning position of this this console
log okay
so that's p3 so that's a p3
so we got a beginning position then what
we do is uh wait
we this needs to be inside uh
save this restriction yeah so
yeah okay so we got the beginning of
console.log
then search then search for
word for the left parenthesis
now uh in emax okay
anyway so let's search for what left
parentheses
bound neo no arrow
uh no error actually we want error
because
because uh wait what what's going on
uh because when we search console.log
you know this you see we
remember uh we are trying to remove the
console log this
trend statement in javascript so when we
find
a when we found a console log we
actually want
you know it should go with a parenthesis
if there's no parenthesis
just the console log then that's not
what we want then that's probably not a
print statement that's not what we want
so we always there is always a left
parenthesis
so search forward for that
once you found um
set point set set position okay
set p4 okay let's not call it p4
uh pers let's say position
left paren okay
so let's rename this uh
and let's rename p3 to be
let's rename p3 to be position
begin console
there it is position begin console
then you set position left paren
point minus one okay so you need
minus one
now is there a function named -1
no wait try again
what uh hold on a second describe
function
minus one
no there is no search function named
minus one but there is a first one
though
for example describe function uh
oh wait uh one minus uh wait let's try
again
describe function one minus yeah there
it is
there is a function named y y minus it
just
minus one so one minus point
because we want the left of the paren
because when you search for word emacs
will place the cursor at the end
of the search string so in this case
he'll place the cursor
at the right of the left parentheses
so anyway let's let's we are getting too
long here let's
quickly get this to work so far so good
am i doing
fantastic or am i doing kind of boring
let me know okay
uh okay so what so we got left paren we
got
then now we need the right parent
so you see so you know what we doing so
far
we got the position of the console
beginning
and now we got the position of the left
paren
and what we do we we want to delete that
part okay
yeah we want to delete that
oh in that case we then
go go no
okay my dog is getting onto the bed
he shouldn't so anyway position
left paren okay let's just say delete
region delete region then we are going
to run the code so that we don't
waste too much time we can see some
actual
action there it is
delete region delete region okay so
shall we run the code run the code go
back to
go back to my talk show page go back to
the talk show page
where is it here okay
now show this in a separate
buffer okay now we
are going to call our code and it should
remove
that at least okay let's call our code
remove console.log okay
enter fantastic it worked as
expected because our code currently just
removed that part it doesn't
it doesn't remove you know it should
remove that
as well
okay so far so good yes yes it is so far
it is
good now we go back to the code we need
to
we need we need to find the we need to
find
let's see let's let's put this this way
okay
we need to find the matching parenthesis
you see we cannot simply search for the
right parent because
that's necessary thing we that's not
what we want we want
we want a parenthesis that matches that
one so how do i do that how do you do
that
you do that by go to
emacs
practical emac lisp tutorial
then you go to emac list write a major
mod
then there is a section
let's see down here somewhere that
that lets you find the matching
parenthesis
you see this is not trivial to do
because because normally if you want to
if you are going to code it yourself you
need to do some kind of passing you need
to
find all the nested parentheses if
there's a match
skip it skip it then you know then
until you find you know the one you want
but if you are using emac bisp
you are in luck there it is the last
item
find matching bracket character
so solution uh solution
you know here it is a solution but we
are not going to look at the code we are
just going to
um
well i i will explain the code okay but
but let me let me get it first
oh actually this code is not
relevant actually we that's not what we
want
this code is actually um
returning the matching character for
example
if you give it a left paren it will
return a right paren
if you give it a right square bracket it
will return the left
square bracket it returns the matching
character
now in e-mac this in e-max you can
define arbitrary matching characters so
anyway so this is not what we want
we simply want to go to the matching
bracket so what what is the command well
that
that command is actually easy okay let's
say
let me show you okay describe key
z here it is go to matching bracket
let's look at the source code
so here is a source code
and what we want is you know they
actually this is what we want okay
here is the code let's copy the whole
code so we can
play with it copy it let's go back to
our lisp code
what is this uh
let's go back to our lisp code and put
it here
okay so we we paste it here
we don't need and i'm going to explain
okay so don't worry
let me just
we are going to explain the code
[Music]
um
yeah so
forward sex is what we want
let's see
hold on second let me try something
what
[Music]
yeah forward sex is what we want let's
let's do it then
okay don't don't worry about it it's
just um
that's our function so uh we want
so we have a parenthesis here
[Music]
so hold on a second okay so
okay before we delete the region we want
to
backward char one move cursor backward
one character so that
the so the cursor is on the left
of the parenthesis then we say forward
sixth that will move to the
cruiser to the matching line like here
okay so let's let's try it for example
yeah you'll move to the after okay so
okay so so once you move forward
sex you want to
backward
so delete character probably introduce a
dd character delete the following
n characters so delete character
negative one remove that parent
okay so
predefine the code let's summarize
we search forward the console string
we found it then we set it to the
beginning
position begin console we set it then we
search forward for the left
paren then we
backward char
wait wait we search for the left paren
we then we set the
uh the point
to position left paren okay then we move
backward
one character so the character is on the
left of the parent
then we call forward sex which will move
the cursor to the
matching parenthesis
then we delete one character that means
delete
the matching parenthesis then we delete
the region then we delete the region
position beginning
and uh you know beginning of the console
to the to the end of the
left parenthesis okay that's it
run the code back to the html let's put
the koozai at the beginning let's call
the command
and see if it worked do
it no search field
uh search field
left paren okay so back to our code
let's see where did we
do wrong
so far so good we got 12 people watching
uh go back to the code so backward char
so backward char
so search for word that
set position left paren
[Music]
okay so wait we move backwards
wait
we move backward chart one four
six let's see let's look at four work
set
six
yeah forward six move
forward across one balanced expression
uh x s e x
p symbolic expression
that's what lisp calls the parenthesis
uh so forward sex
is does it require an argument no
option okay forward
six delete char back record one
okay there's some
thing i'm not doing correctly
anyone know what is going on the region
when you are confused you do send
something inconsequential
what
what what is going on
eval again let's do it let's just call
it again let's see
search failed okay i don't know what's
going on let's debug
okay so i call the command
toggle debug on arrow okay so that's the
that's the command toggle debug on error
then now i'm going to call our function
again so
it say so we can see what more detailed
error messages
so call it custom remove console.log
so there we have the more detailed
error message so actually it says
actually it says uh let's try it again
okay
uh basically search forward failed you
see this second line so that's a
that's simple search field
search for the left paren failed so go
back to our list code
so this line search forward why is it
failed
console.log right wait why is it failed
so did this fail i mean the question is
if this
failed so okay so let's do this
if
if search forward for the console log
if that is true then we
then we set the position begin console
and then we continue okay
because if otherwise if that failed then
we basically do nothing
so if it failed do nothing so let's
change this to when
okay so basically this means
the whole code will run only if you
found
an instance of of the console
log
so when that okay when that
happens then
then you set it then you um
then you search forward then you
okay and let's move the whole thing
inside and
like that so when this search is found
then you
then you do that okay eval buffer let's
just run a code
move to the beginning of uh buffer and
chord cuz
remove console log
what's going on let's do it again no
arrow and nothing happens that means
so that means there's a progress that
means basically this
research forward is not working
now did we spell the wrong console log
okay let's forget about this um
let's forget about this this thing
let's not use regular expression let's
just use
plain let's not get too fancy okay
comment that out so we just use plain
search string
search forward console log without
worrying about
whether there's a space in between now
by the way if you have a space after the
dot that's legal syntax
okay that's legal syntax so so in fact
this
is what you should do but we have
problems so let's ignore it now
learner code back to the javascript code
uh co-op command start remove
console.log do it
no arrow and no nothing what the is
going on
oh okay so i see what's going on yeah
let's let's
put some yeah we need empty lines
above okay
how do i explain that let's try it okay
yeah it worked you see finally it worked
we
you see it moved it also removed the
removed the ending um
square the ending parent so let's try it
again okay
now it's not working well it's not
working because it only works on the
current
block remember so now if we put a cursor
in this text block
it will work so do it you see
it worked now one more thing to fix
now it you see it only works
for one occurrence it doesn't work for
the second
occurrence so let's go back to the code
and let's make it a loop a repeat so
make it
while instead of when so while
well this is true and now we can
actually return this one
uh because we know what was the error
before so now let's
you know we return our code here
run the code it's pretty fine okay let's
okay so run the code back to the
javascript now if we call the command
if we work on this text block that means
it will
remove this part and the this part and
also the second occurrence here and
and here okay so put a cursor somewhere
here
call the command do it fantastic
successful
so actually so so that's it for today
uh well yeah that's it that our function
is successful let's
clean up the last stage of writing code
you know purify clean up you know
remove whatever garbage you put there or
comments
and also enhance it we should enhance it
if we have time so and improve the
inline documentation it says
remove the console.log in the
current.line
in the current textblock or text
selection that's correct
yeah let's do yeah yeah that's so so far
so good
looks like so far that that's
looks like that's a pretty clean code
so deleted
we are going to put the code in in our
talk show page now
put it here and wait
let's undo okay yeah so wait
magnify put the code here show in
browser
back to emacs go to the top
out today's video show in browser
full screen so you can see the
javascript code
there then you can see the emax code
back to emacs go to the code
predefine the code show in browser
there it is our code of the day
so i think that's it how long have we
been talking and that's it
47 minutes okay
anything else guys anything
comments we're gonna shut down in two
minutes
if there's no more questions just about
we just gonna chat random
so if you like my tutorial go buy it
okay so you can see a
practical emac list you'll learn emac
lists
from the ground up pretty easy
okay so you you go you click on that and
buy it
donation is accepted of course patreon
or amazon
or even bitcoin
and you can join my discord
you can join my discord you can find uh
on my
discord talk page okay we are done okay
i'm going to
just do random okay you uh class
dismissed i'm going to do random i'm
going to you know every time i do a
video
i have to spend like more than one hour
to clean up too you know that's
there's lots of work to do so today for
example this
is my talk show page on my website so
every time
i do a talk show on video on youtube
i have a course corresponding page
with links or code or whatnot
so you know you i have to do it so
today's
the talk show page title will be
like usually i wouldn't know what's the
title until it's done
then usually i have to watch the video
my own video so
today's talk show 2020 september 13th
uh then we coded about
this this what's the name of our code
uh remove yeah remove console.log
so so we
so yeah so here so the title will be
emac this coding emac this remove
console log
okay emac this start remove console log
okay then live coding first tutorial
that's what i say okay
then remove the random chat and so on so
make it one line
copy it actually cut it and now i
i need to change the title let's show
the
pink window i need to change the title
and also the title here
so i have a convenient command code
type the new title press enter so you
can see this title line
is changed but also this hr line is
changed
so so now also copy that and put in the
video
talk show page so it's here so now show
in browser
you see we got the proper title emac
this
remove console log
okay and then this sample code we don't
need
so this you are looking at my emacs
workflow right now
so switch window now this is our
javascript temp file do we need it
no delete it okay
now back to our code so live stream live
stream in 3.5 hours we don't need any
we don't need it anymore removed
today's background image azure chameleon
polyhedron
and
and the javascript code you know the
javascript console log
okay so we have to write a description
write a e this command
to remove
console log
remove that text okay
but keep keep the body part
right keep the body inside so make a
paragraph
show in browser page down
you can see it says here now we want to
color it
so press the key
syntax coloring showing browser refresh
there it is okay the javascript code
we don't need it anymore deleted remove
and back to browser showing browser and
also we want to
syntax color that refresh
that is what we have well
except we want to change this into a
list
so
call the command remove paragraph
tags okay and call another command to
make it one single line
and make it a list and combine it with
the last list
showing browser page down
so we got there it is
bye bye bye