hello welcome to another episode of
soundtalk show
today we are going to do emacs lisp
coding emacs leaves
this coding live plus tutorial i'm going
to explain as i go through so today's
task is passing url
so here's a url and this is a different
uh parts of the url the you know the
protocol the
the protocol the host
the port number the path
and this is the query string part
and this is a fragmentation or hash
hash part
so we are going to use emaclis to pass
it now we did a video before uh
about two or three videos uh
july 22nd so we did a video before and
that video is an hour long and so but
today we are going to use a different
algorithm okay so let me copy these uh
copy these so we we're gonna start to
code it so let's start to code it now
okay
so show today's uh talk show page let's
start to code it uh alternative
algorithm and today why am i doing it
again because today because i actually
need it needed in my uh
hta
html mod okay let me let me show you
uh
in a second
so paste it there syntax highlighted so
you can see this is the code we did
before this is how you pass a url
that is given a url you want to split it
into different parts why do you need to
do that because
uh because for example
okay so for example if i have a command
for example here is a file path right
it's a file path copied from there
now
in emacs you have a command called
find file at point okay find file at
point that's the emax command
okay describe function
you can see ffap
is an ads for find file a point that's
just a shortcut the short name so you
call this command and it will open
whatever the file path or url
at the coolest position so let's
demonstrate so let's let's see
let's say um
and let's see google let's say google
okay google.com okay
google the evil empire
okay so we have a url there and you can
say
you know meta x f f a p
and
it will just open that url why is it
taking so long
find file or url yeah so it tries to
confirm is do you really want to open
that yes okay you see let's do it again
close google back to emacs call ffap
find file a point do you really want to
open that one yes okay you see
now
so you can do it similarly for for a
local file for example let's do it again
ffap
okay do you really want to open that yes
okay so it opens this file i'll show in
browser and that's my local uh file for
this you know it opened the file that's
a point fap
for okay let's this let's write it out
okay so let's write it out quickly
uh
is an alias
okay so this is e-max
f-a-f-f-a-p is an alias for five file at
point it just open the file at the
cruiser position okay and here are two
url examples and local file examples now
why do you want why do you need to for
example let's try
let's see if it works okay so let's put
a
fragment something okay
then okay let's do
ffap
do you really want to open that yes okay
it opened it correctly so you see so
this function
you know
the file name is this file name right
but
but then you have the hashtag hashtag so
the function needs to
remove the
tag because that's not part of the file
name then open that so
so part of the source code
of fap
must pass the url it must take the url
and remove the hashtag
and then open it
now if it's a case of url
you know not local file if it's a url
um
then it doesn't matter you know it
doesn't matter i don't think i mean yes
it doesn't matter so for example let's
put a random
random string here so
ffap
it confirms you know do you really want
to open that one you know it just opened
that with the hashtag okay but the point
is that sometimes you need to get rid of
the
fragmentation or
and sometimes you need to get rid of the
also for example let's both the
fragmentation in both the query string
let's see if this works okay so i got
the file path with a
query string there and fragmentation
okay so
ffap enter
so it does it correctly you see it
removes the query
string and the fragment fragment
so
so that is why you do need to pass an
url sometimes you know especially
especially the fragmentation the hashtag
and the query string
um
so let's look at the source code let's
see how this function does it okay so
uh describe function find file at point
okay and jump to the source code fab
ffap okay here's the source code define
alias okay so
you want to find that function okay
where is it
where is the definition
okay i don't know describe function
let's try it
there it is there okay so we jump to the
uh source code so
let's narrow to defend so this function
is 42 lines now let's look at where do
they pass the url
uh let's see let's search for url
okay uh fetch
so where is the let's see where is the
file
somewhere they must have removed the
hashtag and the query string
[Music]
okay so you actually need to look at
this code
okay it's too large your phone let me
shrink it
ffap pass wildcards to diet a phone call
directory finder file name
now so actually
now where do they pass the file name
is it expand file name
oh god we need to look at the code now
so hello guys good afternoon
i would like to hear you talk about risk
xv6 unix history okay i don't know what
is risk five reduce instruction
uh something something cpu
okay i don't know much about cpus
actually so what is this
github mi tv
is 54
xv6 is a modern
re-implementation of sixth
edition unix
unix you want to know my opinion about
unix
okay it's a modern implementation of
sixth edition unix in ncc
why do you why do you need to
re-implement it for
multiprocessor x86 and risk
5 systems it was created for pedagogical
purposes
in 2006
re-implementation on that cv
okay i don't know nothing about it unix
history i i um
okay unix you know i can
i can talk a little bit about unix
history but operating system is not my
thing all i have to say is that i think
unix is a crime
unix is a
the operating system that did the most
damage to computing history including
line truncation the shell back you know
a bunch of shell back the nicknames cat
grip you know find you know these
cryptic nicknames the hacker culture
it's a unix is a
operating system that did the most
harm long term in computing industry for
the past 30 years at least
okay and this by the way this is the
antithesis this lisp
the this community ai community
including emacs is against the unix
philosophy you know so-called philosophy
it's actually not a philosophy it's just
a latch on you know
post the fact adding you know like unix
is a hack okay okay here's my story
about unix
you know i don't really know the actual
history the detail you know the
the academic history of unix but like
but i can tell you that the unix is um
um
unix
well i'm not i i don't think um
okay go to
saudi.info so if you want to hear my
unix rant just search for unix
philosophy
i have like over 10 over 100 over over
50 articles about unix okay about how
harmful unix is so you can start by
search for unix philosophy
okay
unix philosophy fast food the unix way
this article is like 30 years old you
know i got it from the web you can see
from so this is a humor this is a funny
story
unix philosophy fast food fast food the
unix way
written around uh written around 1984 or
before okay i cannot find the actual
author but 1984 or before okay the
author might be bob
bob
pierce pierce
he might be uh someone working at xerox
i don't know
so this humor humorous article is
writing written in 1980s early 1980s and
by reading this article you can tell you
can kind of get a sense how it was
how suck how sucky unix was how insecure
the most insecure operating system that
is unix okay to you know the
unix and linux is filled with lies you
know it's acne it's not technically it's
called cult you know they have a cult
just like religion scientology falun
gong if you are outside with a cult you
hear them of even christianity to send
to to a lot of degrees and
islam okay so when you are outside of
religion you you hear these people say
about
whatever and you can see
it's
it's a cult you know they they talk
about things that's just not true okay
in the same way
in the same way when you read this
article written in 1984 you know unix so
so what why is unix um
you know i claim unix is the most
insecure operating system unix is
operating system that created okay it
created the unix community the unix
operating system the unix people the
hackers the unix philosophy those type
of people and today linux or the all the
the
the circus you know whatever the window
manager this type of people this
community they created the hacker the
the cracker the the the breaking into
computers type of uh
mentality it is same okay and today all
the spammers you know the other
spammers everywhere you go the
spammers the
the botnet you know that's that's
who of them
do you think they they are written by
microsoft
fans no mostly they are working in unix
linux okay the unix is is
the most harmful to uh did the most harm
okay so you start to read okay so if you
want to know my unix right i talked
about this
over so many times in my past two years
so you can start with um
okay that
this story okay read that story uh and
read this one okay the and uh and then
you have you can see lots of my talk
shows about unix unix philosophy and
hacker idiots
okay that is my true opinion okay is you
know people hear my opinion they oh
it's just a troll he wants to make
himself known you know he he wants to be
uh you know he he has a need to be
to be hurt you know
idiots okay
so the nature of eunuch's philosophy you
might have heard of these term but today
eunuch's philosophy is kind of dead okay
it's replaced by the zuma generation and
the social justice warriors you know
they they
they are not the
you know the the classic hackers of the
unix philosophy is the
the the the representative we can say
the representative of the unix
philosophy people is esr eric
s raymond okay who created the cathedral
and bazaar the who who is the leader of
the open source philosophy which is a
branch you know offshoot from the schism
from the free software foundation you
know the esr
he's well known okay not not so much
today you know because generation you
know come and go
so esr he wrote the book unix philosophy
or the art of unix you know programming
he wrote a bunch of books and he also
created the hacker logo okay
so i'm talking about these things these
things today's generation don't know
much because this is mostly
um uh not that one you see when you
search for the image even
you know the logo doesn't come up you
know the hacker logo
it should come up
because it's kind of you know just like
celebrities you know the singers pop
stars
every 20 years they come and go so new
generation have no idea who are the most
popular stars
30 years ago
and but meanwhile when they are the star
you hear them every everyone knows you
know everyone knows who is
michael jackson for example my
generation michael jackson prince
david bowie uh these are you know the
big madonna and big stars but today uh
new generation so new thing but back but
when when you are at the point
you know when you are young at the
current generation
that's all you hear every day so in a
similar way
hacker logo is one of the things
everyone knows
but not so much today so let's type unix
okay
oh god you you can't even find that okay
so you can even
find it now uh esr hacker logo okay
there it is okay this one you see um
you see that you see this sometimes
you'll see people use that as a profile
of uh photo okay and this is this guy is
esr okay you know you can also search on
my site you can find
esr okay so um
yes uh
he has um
yeah that guy so
hacker aki type you know that's the he
is a representative of the hacker
culture okay esr
so anyway esr so
unix philosophy so
um so i'm so i'm saying that you know
unix philosophy
kind of died you know today not many
people know about it except you know
very few uh and uh and esr is um
uh what what am i saying so
so the unix
philosophy is um
is post-effect thing okay it's you know
the unix the nature the nature of unix
is such that
it's just a sloppy a bunch of students
who don't know things who don't know
design you just you know make things go
and after refine you know refine a
little refinement every day make it
correct
correct the incorrectness you know then
after 30 years that's what unix became
that's how that's the nature of unix
okay when you use unix you wonder why so
the complexities the man page
that's unix okay no design
no philosophy
a bunch of people who don't know who
have no
who just want to make things work
quickly hack you know hack hack is the
essence of the unix thing hack including
c c is a unix language c unix perl these
are representative of the unix
technology okay see
the nature the design if you want to
think about think of what what is the
the the the guideline the philosophy the
mindset of unix things then you can look
into c
c plus plus
i would include unix
and pearl for example that's that's a
prototypical unix
technology okay
and they could and they
um then then you have the word unix
philosophy
now
there's a wikipedia article on that you
can read into okay so unix philosophy
it's it's not really it's not like
um you begin with a philosophy approach
to design it's not really like that unix
philosophy is more like
after after the fact you know after 20
years of unix after 10 20 years of unix
then
the unix fan fanboys the unix phonetics
they they they try to
come up with a philosophy like a jargon
you know
because once you have a jargon it helps
your coat it spread you know especially
dramatic jargon just such as unix
philosophy the unix kind of thing they
love jargons you know for example all
the ls script
said
bison you know the terms of them you
know they love you know this it's like
the word to describe them is juvenile
humor that that is what unix is juvenile
humor it describes lots of their
these type of people sloppy sloppy they
they never they are not the type who are
architects who
who design who think about things who
think about extensibility about ease of
use about
about the correct correctness of the
program about what program should be
that's the opposite of the unix type of
people okay that's the opposite
now these type of people are represented
by lisp people
richard snowman
the scheme
these people the racket people the you
know they are totally opposite okay
so you know it's a little fact you know
today most people don't know about that
but back in the
80s that's even before my time
and and somewhat in 90s
the unix camp and lisp camp are
at war at war
with each other okay so unix philosophy
is just pure [ __ ] okay
so you can read my articles if you want
that okay today i guess today we um
forget about emacs since we started to
talk about your unix forget about it and
so we already talked for what um
23 minutes um
let's see uh where do i continue so
so let's forget about emacs yeah
since i already digressed so much
so let's forget about emac this coding
then
uh let me just talk about your unix okay
so if you have a question about unix ask
me then
so
yeah so you start to read those articles
let me show you a few um
unix philosophy so
[Music]
okay so read that uh the nature of unix
philosophy there's tons you know there's
tons of it then then you know i i mean
i have written tons of tons of basically
that's my life you know renting again is
the unix one plus one equals to three
you know that's what unix that's what
unix is to me a cult phenomenon
now i want to be fair okay i want to
you know i want to say that
i think
okay let me be precise okay i think that
that unix operating system and
associated things such as the code for
example the jargon unix philosophy pearl
which has been
the most popular language on earth for
over for 10 years pearl pearl is a
direct for pro is a
part of the unix philosophy
group okay
so they have i mean in my opinion the
unix operating system and associated
things such as the
the kind of community unix philosophy
and pearl and c the c programming
language and and all the things
associated with unix such as truncation
line truncation and everything should be
represented as a as a
text file you know that's part of the
unix thing
so unix in my opinion has an associated
things has done huge
damage to the computing industry okay
huge even today even today for example
one of the the things i'm
i
complain about uh okay hold on a second
let me let me copy
what we talked about today so we have a
log of um
that i want i want to i i need to finish
coding the
emac list okay so we talked about eric
um
raymond
okay so
let's just copy let me copy that okay
the nature of unix philosophy and let me
show you a few articles and the esr okay
esr is a prototype the representative of
the
unix hacker culture okay esr everything
about esr
eric s raymond okay he's the founder of
the
open source one one of the
founder
okay so let's uh and
and and so i was saying even today
the eunuch is so many
there are still so many things that is a
remnant of the damage caused by unix
okay for example the line truncation
okay let me let me tell you about line
truncation
okay so i have you know like i said i
have like over 50 or 100 articles
ranting against unix okay so so for
example um
this is this one is the earliest okay so
i also did a video unix rfc
now today you guys may not know what is
ifc ifc stand for really [ __ ] common
okay it actually stands for
request for comment
no no no no no look at this jargon okay
this is part of the unix mentality
this is the example of the unix
code
the type of term or jargon they use okay
rfc really [ __ ] common
request for comment okay now so what
does that mean it's a precursor to the
open source mentality communism okay
today so it's
like they for example they want to
create a spec for protocol email http or
whatever so they created this request
for comment
among their community meaning that you
know kind of uh
loving you know the word is you know
it's it's um
requests for common it's
how do you describe it it's a you know
part of hippie part of the
you know i would just call it
i would describe it as a communist kind
of communist and
trap okay it's a trap it's a kind of a
help the world
mentality which
which
in the end often creates the most evil
okay
so anyway rfc requests for comments so
what so basically it's a
request for common so it they publish it
so everyone who have some thought about
certain protocols they can they can
comment and help you know help design
the protocol that's what it is so it's
similar to today's
you can say similar to today's github
pull uh pull request you know lots of
things similar okay so
it's a mentality okay anyway request for
comment it's very widely popular not so
much today but but it's it's still going
on okay
and uh
the requests for comment and long term
so line truncation okay unix you know
unix unix tools now i'm not on unix
uh i'm not on unix so you cannot so i
can i i don't have the i cannot show you
um
right now but unix commands
in the beginning
when you're lying whatever for example
on unix you can do ps okay ps is list
processes now
the ps you see here is actually
powershell
that's um
that's a alias
for get process so that's a powershell
command but anyway on unix you have the
ps command which does these processes
similar to what you see here okay so
so this command usually the line output
are very long when you do ps for example
psa uw
wx and and the unix options like the
incredible incredible [ __ ] the unix
to back option you know inconsistent you
know
everything is just ad hoc just like c
language there's no consistent design
there's no design at all everything is
just sloppy or whatever you know it
works now and it's fast fast fast is one
of their advantage that's what they are
concerned
so so you so when you so the unix ps
command they truncate your lines okay so
when you if you want to find if you
started some script
so you type unix and and type it to grab
you know this is my this is my
experience since 1990
nine on solaris you type grab grab for
example
script
you know let's say bash you know the
exhaust script
you know bash usually don't end with a
file name extension anyway
so let's say you do that
and the result is empty
but however
you know
that you actually started that command
so what happened well the reason is that
because when the ps when the output on
unix on every oh just you know on lots
of unix commands when the output when
the line is more than 80 characters they
silently truncate it okay that's unix
it's unix factors
so
i want to say you know so it's not it's
not just a flaw you know when our
technology
technology programming languages
protocols always have some flaw or
mistakes you know that's human
but
the emphasis i want to make is that when
it comes to unix
they
yeah every every you know every
programming language every operating
system has flaws and they can improve it
gradually such as dos or whatever
but
in the unix case they
they you know it's it's not just that
they have flaws every technology has
flaws or mistakes but in the unix case
they have a code they have a code such
that they
such that they do not
you know they they do not consider they
have flaws in inf
you know but instead they turn around
they say this is this is the best way
okay
for example this line truncation
is
is incompassing we still suffer from
this problem today okay for example
in back in 1980s email protocol you know
you know you guys probably don't know
today's generation you know you have the
email email protocol the unix people
will create you know rfc they created
the email you know so for example you
can look at this unix and inbox email
format written in 2002 okay
uh that's 20 years ago when i was young
i was like you guys okay
there's no spec you know you read the
spec it's like
fuzzy and it describes nothing unix
inbox inbox is original email format in
fact there's no spec okay every each
each email
program in unix kind of
kind of create their own you know
incompatible you cannot for example you
can like back then it's very common and
even today you might want to transfer
all your emails from one
one um
from one um
email company to another right so
and and this is before you have internet
email like google gmail you know before
gmail began around 2002 or something
before it's just uh you use a mail
application to connect to a email server
then it downloads all your email
in your application so
almost always your emails are sitting on
your disk locally so it's just a bunch
of files you know i i i can i still have
archive of my old email 20 years ago
so basically a bunch of files and they
are in a particular format which is
called mbox okay
so oftentimes you want to switch a mail
server you know so you might you know
grab your
mail and uh
i forgot what exactly but basically you
want to
upload to another email service
something like that i you know if you i
if i read it i don't know the details i
forgot
it's been 20 years so
so in order to do that basically you
have to know you have to know the exact
format of the inbox how email is
okay for example why for example
sometimes you
someone write an email you reply with a
quote right so you you need to pass
those quote to be correct otherwise it's
and also email the inbox is just one
single file very large so you have
hundreds of males emails in inside one
file okay so you do so you use that's
why you need to know the inbox
to determine
how what how is each email separated you
know that so you need the email spec
inbox
but there's no there's no search okay
like every is inconsistent
each one each email server is different
that's unix okay that is this is
one of the damage of unix
not just this and then
then the e the the unix people
because their operating operating system
everything is based on lines and a line
cannot be more than 80 characters that's
their tradition the unix [ __ ] they
they told they tell everyone in the
world that you they created the email
protocol
you can see rfc something okay i can i
probably have a link here
um you know i i have a link uh
mail let's see
which um where is the mail protocol rfc
you know and these are several pro
programs that pass this email
which is uh all [ __ ] up okay here
rfc1149 what is this one uh
ifc1149 okay let's search for it
now that's a joke that's a silly joke
always repeat it
uh
anyway i i have this you can you can
just find it on it's on wikipedia email
political okay ifc something or number
so
so you unix told you unix told everyone
in the world that you must in email you
must truncate your lines okay
so they forced this line truncation into
the email protocol so so everyone every
email processor
you know software must truncate their
lines just like unix
and what is the consequence of that a
lot that's when you see and also e
um unix adopted this
this
correct
character four quote okay
even we are using it today for example
uh in markdown in markdown you use this
four quote
basically you have to do it on every and
each line okay so let me show you okay
copy
so
and for example this is a long line
that's not accepted by
by unix you have to
you have to do this okay let me show you
okay so this is a long line you have to
feel column
what is the field column that's the
jargon emac these so emac this created
the command
so that you can confirm to the unix way
of cutting lines you know so let's see
show white space now
now remember this is very different from
soft rap okay for example let's make
them one line okay one line
but
you can
like some of the unix idiots they
they'll complain oh but long line is
difficult to read the [ __ ] idiots
for example let me show you
so
there's a concept of margin okay you see
that
this is this is this is not multiple
lines this is still one single line but
it's easy to read
why because you have the soft wrap
concept
and you have the margin concept emacs
also have margin okay
i'm not gonna show it but um
you can set emacs so that it actually
have a margin just just like microsoft
word okay for example let's um
can we do that so let's start word
uh i don't want microsoft word let's
start wordpad okay so paste it so let's
magnify so you can see but you have the
margin concept okay wait
uh i haven't used this program
oh the margin wait what where is the
there it is okay so that's the margin
okay
and
the line is still single line for
example if i copy this
go back to emacs
new buffer paste it it's still one
single line okay but you have the margin
concept but the unix [ __ ] they don't
know they don't know you know
so
so they forced email they forced the
truncation line into every email program
and then
and what's the problem so so
then you have the quoting problem for
lots of you know for example you want to
quote all these lines so what you do is
you
first of all this is one single line
okay so
this is how you quote but when you have
multiple lines
let's hot wrap okay
um
okay now it's hot wrapped you see some
some of the unix people might complain
oh what's wrong with hot rap this is one
example
what is wrong with hot rap
or the emacs would call feel feel column
feel their ass
the unix [ __ ] created this
situation so every software has to
create a function to to do this line
truncation then you have this actual
problem this is this is a problem that
will not go away you see it depends you
know the hot when you have a hot
formatted
you know line truncation like that then
it depends on your window size because
right now my window size that is like
that and each line is you know like that
it's
that's not good that's harder to read
meanwhile if you look at this
one single line it's easy to read and it
adjusts with your window okay
the [ __ ] unix [ __ ]
they want the line truncation you know
normally normally you have to do it
manually like hit enter
type typed hit enter then they say oh
but your editor should create a
you know a function that does that yeah
so that means every
editor every text editor has to create a
function just to do that but even even
then but then you have the problem
of
is you know like if you're fine you know
depends on your font size because if now
the font size is small now they are like
nice again okay you see
uh let's
let's uh
let's
redo this okay copy this line let's
remove the quote there copy this line
paste it now feel it okay now it depends
on font size you see now in when you
know when it's font size is small or the
window
so depends on lots of things so when the
font size is large then you got this
crap
this
this is a damage
of the unix [ __ ] okay to this day
people still do this like on on
when you commit code you know there's
code coding style guide formatting guide
you know every language pearl python you
know they have that they will tell you
that oh your line shouldn't be more than
80 characters when you have more than 80
characters please hot rabbit the [ __ ]
[ __ ] unix
this is one of the harm of unix you know
but you
but unix created the code such that they
brainwashed people they don't know like
i
like i did a full-time video this this
is eric raymond okay that's a guy aaron
agreement he's getting old
now i did a full video on the unix line
truncation okay
but you know just like just like right
now you know i explain the detail but i
have a
kind of friend and not not so much but
he because we disagreed we we we
separated our ways kind of
he he watched my video and he and his
opinion he he he just think oh because
it's just trolling oh because you are
being evil you happy you are just like
you know i don't understand
do you do you see
okay now let me ask you guys do you see
am i making sense
is there a logic this is just one one
one case of the unix damage there's so
much
right now i'm talking about line
truncation do you see do i make sense
you know i talked about 20 minutes on
these
but the the problem is when the unix
people when when they see this
it flew by their head okay really truly
because i argued with so many unix
[ __ ]
you know on
on on forum by writing by video like
right now by live stream you know after
you talk to so many logical reasons you
tell them why you know truncate lines is
no good and by the way what's the origin
where does this truncation
truncating lines came from welcome came
from punch cards because they are 80
holes okay lots of things in history
the way they are is because historical
reasons okay
but the problem with the unix is that
every operating system every technology
every programming language has flaws and
make mistakes sure
we progress we fix them right
but
but why am i particularly hate about the
unix [ __ ]
because
the unix k in the unix case they are not
they are not you know just
normally you know oh yeah we made a
mistake we progress yeah
it's not like that they have a coat they
have a coat you know spreading fake news
saying that unix is the most secure
operating system that's the most that's
the opposite from the light that's the
biggest lie you know saying that unix is
good great and and this in particular
this case line truncation
they think it's good to this day most
programmers they don't know they blindly
follow all the all the programming
language in python in golan
in perl you know the
style guide they tell you
especially in emacs too e max 2 because
the [ __ ] magic you know when you have
a line when you make a commit
commit
uh line when your line is more than 80
characters
the magic guy you know he's a nice guy
but we had argument but you know he
the magic will tell you warning warning
your line is more than 80 characters
blah blah blah
[ __ ] waste my time [ __ ] it telling me
to do something i'm doing things
correctly and he tells me to [ __ ] it up
this is this
why does all these things happen because
of unix philosophy the unix code the
unix [ __ ]
they created this situation
okay so so today mostly most of the time
i'm you know so like that's not all so
so many so okay so we we we are talking
about line truncation but so so many so
much more
because of unix
because not recent okay
basically starting you know
in the 1990s then every programming
language became
line based language
okay
now this will take some time to explain
i don't know if you can you understand
beginning around you know because since
the popularity of unix then linux linux
around the year 2000 okay
every programming language
the the mentality the designer the
thinking of the the people they have no
idea of alternatives they are every
language including c c plus plus python
java ruby pearl
um
uh golan
especially gold and golem is part of the
sea you know rob pike rock pike is one
of the big unix people
okay but golan is a great language he
he's he's he's very smart okay rob pike
uh and uh
so anyway my here okay let me focus so
every language they become a line based
language what does that mean that means
their syntax is
um
how do i put this
okay you know i wasn't so so let's
search for it so let me show you okay so
so let me first of all copy this into my
talk show and that's it for today
so let me show you okay so
this is white space okay this is
regarding white space
so i have a lot of um
yeah all these are problems you know the
e-max in e-max the white space mod
each case in computing what exactly is
white space okay
and this interesting unicode white space
representation
and this is article i want to talk about
what does it mean when a programming
claims when a programming language
claims that white space is insignificant
okay
and uh make white space visible that's e
max that's what we have done like this
command you know so we can exactly see
when there are white space or not for
example let me do it again
normal
show white space so you can actually see
where is the line return you see you see
that thing that's a line return
and the
okay tips
okay so let me show you a few articles
so so many articles so um
emacs white space smart you know from
these hacker idiots you see
okay let me let me explain them one by
one so emacs in emacs you have a white
space mod now in my case i customize it
a lot so you don't normally you would
see
something like that okay by default when
you turn white space mod it will show
you something like that colorful
the spectac you know be wildly colorful
so it's gonna tell you you have trading
white space then you have the
you know
um
white space in front then you also have
the case of white space mixed with tab
then you have long lines you know when
you have a line that's more than 80 76
characters or so it colors them in a
special way [ __ ] idiocy
problems okay a lot of problems so
so you can customize it so it shows like
that like like the way i have it okay
why is this a problem because
let's focus on long line okay so the the
other thing is let's say they are
acceptable because sometimes you want to
distinguish trading white space versus
the white space happening before but why
should they color long lines
well that's because of the unix
tradition which spread to every
programming language
so that's why in emacs in the white
space smart when you turn it on to show
white spaces
it also
will color
in a special color for lines that that
are long even though it really doesn't
have anything to do with white space why
does it color because it's trying to
warn you you know as a good gesture as a
good you know uh tool that your lines oh
your line is more than 80 characters
maybe you should
truncate it like the unix buckets
okay this this this is this is wrong
okay so this so so this tool in emacs in
imax this tool white space mod is
helping spreading the unix
[ __ ] idiotic idea
you know because
no more people you know you don't know
the history you don't know these details
so you see this oh oh white space oh oh
long line that's no good oh okay i'm a
good you know i'm a young student yeah i
want to follow the proper you know the
the
the you know the proper way
created by you know the people [ __ ]
you know that's a so that's one hum of
unix philosophy in emacs okay then
there's more okay and i was i was
talking about the
how
unix
line short lines created a situation
where every programming language their
syntax it became quite space-based okay
that's
that's another topic that's gonna be
another hours okay so
so in order to know that
so if you want to know about
that thing
then what you have to do is you read
another 10 articles on that issue okay
so you want to know about okay so
syntax so let me show you a few article
so there it is okay
let's just say
um
okay let's just go here and go to so
this section is all about
this syntax okay
uh and in here you can find articles
related articles that
talks about the idea
of what does it mean
when your programming languages syntax
is line based now this is very
significant okay very
deep and wait time wasting
significant impact to the programming
industry why because for example diff
you know you know about diff right every
time you do github or whatever come
command you you want to know what which
part of the code has changed so you use
the div tool in unix you have the div in
powershell you also have
div which is
a shortcut for
an edius for compare object you know
that's a style of powershell naming
compare object which is diff unique
stiff you see
when you use unix diff
what's the problem the problem is unix
every every unix tool including grab the
[ __ ] grab and rip and grab you know
they are line based that means they only
they they must every unit must be
aligned you know they can for example if
you want to search for example
i want to search all occurrences of this
block of text
can you do it on unix no
why because
the the the text you want to search the
sequence of characters you want to
search you want to search is more than
one line
unix tools does not work with things
that's more than one line unix tool
everything must be a line based so when
you grab this you get fail
because that's
you know that's of unix [ __ ]
they created a damage to the computing
industry
with a code such that nobody and nobody
knows this nobody no nobody thought
about it
then then there's the unix thief
why can't you do so
which in turn made a lot programming
language style guide that tells you
never reformat your code you know your
code just don't reformat it
so every line becomes line based line
basis becomes a unit instead you should
what you should have you should have a
programming language that's not
line is should not be a syntactical unit
it should be what it should be
properties it should be a bracket or
parenthesis okay so so you can have
semantic diff so you can actually
find
the differences of actual changes to to
to your programming language okay
on a semantic unit
not a formatting unit that's a lie
that's a unix focus created damage to
the computing industry now this is like
such a language but this
doesn't go all the way because this you
know in because in this the the
the
common syntax is a line based it's
pervasive because
not just in this in python in bash in
ruby in powershell you know it's you you
all have the line based comment
okay
what it should be is something like that
okay for example let's say uh let's say
let's say that
okay or
that and you can have multiple lines you
know you should have a
that's a proper design okay and xml is a
good example in in that sense xml this
wufam language okay those are good those
are not
line based
syntax
okay meanwhile
c c plus plus java golan rust ruby
python
not so much ruby but you know e and then
python is specifically line based okay
but they are
that's bad okay that's bad
because
in a line based programming language it
you have problems for example why a loop
okay while loop
um okay we don't want uh so we don't
want a list so while loop for example
where for example this is a
this is a syntax of c
c javascript
in a lot of languages you know you have
while loop
now so so the unix speaker will tell you
that you should format it this way right
not not in one single line no you cannot
do that so you you need to you know you
know they have names for different
styles of indentation so anyway so you
follow their guide so you should format
your lines this way
but but then you got a problem because
all unix tools they are line based so
they consider this line as a unit
okay and they they consider this in the
bracket as a unit
but that's but that's not the semantic
unit of the
of the programming language you know
that's just a formatting unit
what does it matter you know
so so you have a conflict so all the
great tools they [ __ ] up they
they
you know they they don't they don't show
the difference between semantic unit but
just lines
so what you so what we get what we do as
a programmer is that we follow this
unix [ __ ] idiocy and we just make
do so we have rules and guides about
okay
make sure your lines are no more indica
no more than any characters and don't
you know don't just you know add extra
space or don't you know don't you know
and you must follow a particular
indentation style
so that you know
so that
unix diff and grip works
okay that's it
pasik passex is the worst fact
of the unix lineage it's pasik okay
posix is like
good good for nothing use useless you
know it's it's just for the type of
people who think spec is a good thing
actually no no not useful
okay that's it for today if you like my
things pay me okay
so you can go to my patreon
go to my patreon
pay me five dollars
or amazon gift card or paypal
okay thank you guys for watching
that's it for today
now i shut down in in a minute
let's copy that and put in my talk show
i need to get up and walk
so this block of text it's um
so
um
do
all right
what's the key for visual line mod okay
space nv
okay showing browser
so we got a lot of things that's not
cleaned up where is it
actually
make a
make a screenshot of this
page
the unix people they have
they don't know the concept of margin
how amazing
you know it's not like they don't know
you know like for example on twitter
on discord you know do you actually
type you know oh but my line reached 80
characters i type a return first do you
actually do that no they don't do that
you know on twitter or discord or any
anywhere
but however when it when when it's in
when it's in terminal
in source code they they uh they do that
they they forgot all about the automatic
line wrap