hello guys welcome to another episode of
sound talk show so we are going to start
we are going to do today Wolfram
language coding okay so I'm just going
to code wufan language graphics and we
are going to do this geometric inversion
uh last time we did this we did a video
on geometric inversion so it's a
geometric process basically you apply a
function so you can turn this squid into
that okay so this is a geometric
inversion and this is a two-dimensional
case very simple you just
you know map a function to another Point
giving a point on the plane you map it
to another Point by this function this
function is called geometric inversion
okay so it can this function is
available in uh in Vector space of any
Dimension so you can be 2D you know or
it can be so all these are 2D case you
start with a different grid this is 2D
case and here's another 2D case you
begin with a
regular polygon polygon instead of
squares you know squares is a regular
polygon of four sides so you start with
the regular polygon of six sides then
you get six or seven then you get this
you know so that's all these are two
dimensional case then you can
then you can augment the 2D Case by
adding a thickness so you got this
beautiful Tire tile geometric inversion
so here is a code for example let's
let's copy the code and let's just start
to show it
uh what we are going to do today is to
do a tube version so starting with a
language a new uh new new notebook
run it
okay uh hold on a second so let me put
this into the right place my windows
so let's put here and let's magnify then
say 150 150 is good so we can see here's
the code and this is a beginning
configuration so after transformation by
the geometric inversion you get you get
these two 2D case
now you see it's still on the plane it's
two-dimensional then you just add more
code to add a thickness to it so you get
this so we did the video uh about a year
ago so if you go to YouTube search for
Sally you know YouTube geometric version
you'll see the video we did actually I
have a link here somewhere
um
so anyway so that's a 2d case okay so we
did the 2D case then we then then you
see the tiles when they are near the
center they be they become infinitely
small
so if you are going to plan to do this
as a garden tile then that wouldn't be
good because you cannot have infinitely
small squares so you want to
modify the function such that when the
points gets to the middle they don't
become infinite it's infinitely small
rather you want constant shape but
however you want to remain the kind of
the style of of this you know nesting
circles this pattern so what you do is
you change the function so this involves
mathematics if you have studied calculus
well then you would know how to change
the function so we did that so we change
the function and we begin
rather you don't change the function you
change the beginning configuration so if
you begin with this configuration on
left then you apply the geometric
geometric transformation then you got
this uh figure on the right side
beautiful okay to me this is one of the
work I'm very proud of you know so you
can see you can still see the many
circular patterns nested circles however
each of the tile is kind of the same
size okay
so and here is a so again we add a
height to it so we got this beautiful
tile so let's try it so here is the code
the code is pretty short okay so so
let's go back to wufam language so you
see this is previous this is
transformation of a bunch of squares on
the plane and now let's paste this code
and run it so this is we begin with this
figure then we apply transformation we
get that then all we have to do is we
are we want to add
uh
oh the code is not here you know it's
still 2D so we want a 3D case yeah so 3D
case Okay so the code is here
so let's copy it
copy the code
go down here paste it okay the code is
not you know about 50 lines now let's
you can press Ctrl shift n to turn them
into a uh to turn them into a
traditional formula for example
let's do it okay so let me make a copy
so we can see the difference before and
after so select it Ctrl shift n so you
see this is a automatic type setting in
Wolfram language and uh you know it's
fantastic and you can shrink if you
window size is smaller or wider the
formatting changes accordingly even with
complicated fractions and nested
fractions and radicals you see you see
there's a radical there so this is the
Wolfram language fantastic okay and you
can download it free
you know if you watch my video I talked
about it many times so today's you know
here's today's talk show I'm Gonna Keep
notes here so later on you can click on
the YouTube description and go to this
page and you can see all the code so
here's a link to the geometric inversion
which we were talking about and click on
this to go to Star Warframe Language
tutorial you can search it and you'll
find that find it so here's a download
for free so you can download and you can
have this
free okay so now and actually so now
let's actually run the code okay so put
a cruiser here
shift enter to run it okay shift enter
so you see let's magnify okay like
actually
so you see we got that we begin with
this figure then apply the geometry
geometric transformation we got this
figure beautiful then we extend it we
add a z coordinate to it so we got a 3D
uh configuration of that planar figure
okay now all we have to do is we add you
know thickness to it
so all this is graphical you know
graphical programming uh very
interesting and very different in nature
from from what typical industrial
programmer are excited about which is
game programming opengl webgl those are
very different nature and those are very
cumbersome so if you want to do this so
you know we created this thing
let's see if we can let's magnify okay
so we created this thing
uh
how many lines of code about 50 okay
about 50 lines of code
uh if you want to do this in opengl or
something that's going to be 1000 lines
of code
so that's the that is the
advantage of Wolfram language it allows
you to quickly see
you know visualization or concept very
fast
okay and the language is uh fairly easy
to learn you know you know it's it's
very different from C or Java or python
if you came from those but
but if you don't have those you know
experienced Wolfram language is actually
rather very easy you you may find it
hard to learn because it's very
different from java CC plus plus python
Golan you know very different from them
so so so here's how you download Wolfram
language and you go back and you can see
I did many videos you know over 20 so
you go to this page these are some of
the best videos so if you are learning
wufan language watch them okay
comments and questions relevant
questions about Wolfram language posted
there okay and I'm gonna answer later so
watch this video okay so now today
let's go back today uh let's go back so
we talked about geometric inversion
which is the function applied to a
two-dimensional grid you know
two-dimensional version okay then all
these are two dimensional you know
although this looks like 3D but it
actually is just a height the function
is still two dimensional
uh then the function the geometric
function is also a three-dimensional
function you know in in fact geometric
inversion Works in any Vector space of
any Dimension so here we have a
three-dimensional example very uh
beautiful okay so and here's a code the
code is even shorter so what let me
explain what it what this is so you know
before we begin with a two-dimensional
grid you know if you scroll the you know
we start with a bunch of
squares right now in a 3D case we begin
with a bunch of Cubes okay then we do
the geometric transformation then you
got this figure okay so let's render the
code and
let's run the code
okay
so you can see fantastic let's magnify
and let's see the full Glory of it
okay so you got this piece you know you
can see you know the nested Circle
structure beautiful you know as they get
closer to the center they each of the
cube becomes smaller infinitely small
when they reach the center so but but
anyway you can see it's you know so this
is the three-dimensional case of
geometric inversion
now if you are studying math geometric
inversion is is related for example in
complex analysis if you study complex
numbers then 1 over
X where okay
1 over X where X is a complex number
that is a geometric inversion okay
that's exactly the same thing well
except except that it flips the plane
okay anyway it's basically the same
thing 1 over X
where X is a complex number okay
okay so that's a geometric inversion
actually we did the video so you can you
can find the video and uh and what we're
gonna do today
is to apply geometric inversions similar
idea but a variation computer Graphics
you know Graphics programming so you can
see what we want to do today is that you
can see
you know before we begin with a grid
then each line becomes kind of a circle
kind you know it becomes you know you
transform each point on the grid right
now instead of the you know line
we are going to use a tube so we got a
bunch of tubes so this is kind of like a
3D case but still 2D but you know so we
got a grid of tubes then we do the
geometric inversion then it becomes
you know it should be tubes so we can
rotate it and see so let's see how it
looks you know you know I'm hoping it's
gonna be beautiful uh just like this
case that's what we are going to do so
we already spent 10 minutes to talk
about all these uh
Prelude so I hope we can you know it'll
take a while I I would say another 40
minutes okay at least 50 minutes even
so I'm I'm going to try to do
as fast as we can
so first of all start the Wolfram
language now I'm coding wufam language
in um
in for example let's say range
uh let's say 10 the net
okay uh actually run it
you can see the answer is you know one
two three four five you know we generate
a list of numbers so I'm running wufam
language in emacs
because in emacs you know I have my
system it allows me to edit modify work
with the code much faster so
I'm using Wolfram language star Warframe
language mod so it's free it's on GitHub
it's open source and it's sponsored by
wolfam language wufam research the
company so let me show you the code
okay so you just describe function uh
wolf and mod then you can jump to the
source code so here is a source code the
whole thing is about
2600 lines of code and if you go to the
beginning go to the beginning then
here's the URL go to it open it show in
browser uh you can search for it Subway
from mod and you can get it for free so
you can download it's on GitHub yeah so
here is a video where we last time we we
were coding this geometric inversion
so you can download it on GitHub okay so
it's a GitHub you know it's there
so download wolfam engine you know it's
free and download this and if you are
using emacs you you are good to go
so question uh
your name your name Paul
real Nepal
how much math background do you
recommend before learning wufam language
or can it be used as a math learning
tool okay so yes you know you don't need
any background let me explain let me
spend two minutes weeks answer that
question
wolfam language is a programming
language that originated from doing
computer algebra you know it's it's it's
it's called computer algebra system okay
so originally about 35 or about 40 you
know wolfam language beginning in
1986 I think so about
35 years ago
uh 35 years ago wolfam language began as
a tool for mathematicians in physics
physicists
to do mathematics okay so you you know
you know physics mathematicians and
Engineers you know you need to do a lot
a lot mathematics for example Space X
NASA you know if you are designing a jet
a rocket you know going to space you
need to huge amount of calculus and you
know engineering so you need to solve a
lot of equations integrals so in the
beginning movement language was created
it was the product is called Mathematica
okay like math you know Mathematica
because it's a tool to to help you do
mathematics solve all the equations or
theoretical physics you know black hole
how far is you know how you know you
know things like that
so
is the product is called Mathematica and
the and the the it's a tool okay to do
mathematics
however
what does the tool looks like the tool
is actually just a programming language
you know so
if you have seen the code here you know
just like uh you know like in the say
python JavaScript you know you type some
code each code has specific you know
arguments you know then then then your
output as you have seen I can also run
it in here
so you know just like python let's close
this for example I run this you can see
the answer at the bottom you know I can
actually make it more complicated let's
say uh table
uh table x squared okay so X from 1 to
let's say five when it
you know so you got the answer at the
bottom so you can see it's there
so
Mathematica is a product 35 years ago he
was intended intended to do mathematics
and how do you use it what you know it's
a programming language basically it's a
very full featured you know highly
Advanced beyond all others because you
can see here you have Graphics there
most computer language you look you
cannot Java C C plus plus C sharp python
JavaScript there's no Graphics you know
this is not you can talk about Graphics
yeah if you want Graphics you need to
have external package that generate
graphic very complex okay
so Wolfram language is a programming
language that has all these features and
also you know symbolic you know type
setting symbolic computation okay
so originally it's designed to do math
but it's not just math it's just any
kind of programming any programming
okay except low level you know you don't
really for example you don't use wufem
language to write a operating system
kernel like Linux you know that that
that is not not
you can you you cannot because it would
be too slow it would be not it doesn't
fit there okay so if you want to do
embedded systems you know drivers you
know like programming microchips on your
micro
on your microwave oven or on your watch
that's not ufam language okay if you
want to do high level mathematics
physics you know Advanced protocol
designer keyboard uh design a car
engineering you know or audio systems
synthesizers you know you can you can do
that with Wolfram language actually I
talk too much about this you know watch
my previous video uh introduction to fun
language okay so anyway to answer your
question so Wolfram language is a
programming language and is also do math
so you do you need to do no math no just
like python just like python JavaScript
do you need to know math to do them not
really you know you can code you can
manipulate streams you can generate list
you know turbos vectors you know uh hash
table you know programming so you don't
need any mathematics at all on the other
hand if you are already a mathematician
fantastic okay fantastic tool or if you
are a student you are interested in
mathematics but you don't know much
mathematics yet
language helps you for example you want
to do calculus let's say limit okay so
limit
let's say 1 over X
X then X goes to uh let's let's say x
what let's go to x goes to Infinity
in Infinity okay so let's see what is
the limit so that limit is zero
so that's calculus you know and
derivatives you know differential
equations linear algebra you know uh
integrals and all that
so you don't need to know any math to
use it because it's a programming
language if you're a mathematician you
can use it to help you a lot or the
physics or engineer and if you're a math
student it will help you significantly
learn mathematics because you can you
know just for example if you want to
expand let me show you just another
example and we start to code Okay so
uh let's say x X Plus y
let's say 40th power okay let's say you
know we can make it more complex minus
two okay
you know so this you know this you
cannot do in Python although it's pretty
simple you know you want to multiply
this by itself 40 times you cannot do it
in Python but in Wolfram language you
know that helps you
uh uh learn math a lot
and you can simplify you know given this
huge output you can say you know like
you have no idea what those are so you
can say simplify
and
the Ampersand stand for previous
expression or you can press Ctrl L you
know
so actually let's do Ctrl shift l so we
get the whole thing so you see
so suppose you are a physicist or a
mathematician you got this expression
you have no idea what it is you know so
you have to do is you just say simplify
okay so let's run it
okay here's the output you know it
factors it factors a polynomial that's
what
happening okay
uh thank you thank you guys for watching
uh so now let's let's let's start to
code this thing uh the the thing we
wanted to code okay so let's start to
code
uh so we talked about uh we we actually
gave us a small intro to fam language
and now
uh now that's the subwoof Emma let's
start to code there's a lot to code it's
gonna be 40 minutes okay close let's
begin to do it okay let's code so what
so what we want to do okay so actually
copy this go back here and paste this
link here so the so we have a record of
what we talked about okay close close so
we're gonna code this now
so
so uh so
we haven't even um well I haven't I
haven't explained what's a geometric
inversion I mean what does the function
actually do so but this is a function
okay so in you know you you probably
don't understand what that is but
uh okay I would say just watch my
previous video okay you watch you know I
showed it before watch my previous video
I expand you know for 20 minutes on what
what is of geometric immersion so so
basically so we defined it you see we
defined it here and the base but let me
just show you how it uh runs so you
given
given a point let's say
three four you know that's x equals to
three y equals to four so you run it
that's the result so it takes a point it
returns another Point okay that's
basically us that's what it is that's
all
okay so I'm now going to explain exactly
what it does actually you know that
is very extremely interesting okay so
for example all these are geometric let
me just go briefly go to it
so all these are geometric inversion and
if you want to understand it uh
you know and it's also there is a uh
there is a Wikipedia article on it of
course just search for geometric
inversion uh okay so where is the
okay so you can see it here
uh geometric version Oh yeah this page
okay so so it explains
here okay yeah you know watch my
previous video we explained that before
all you have to do no now is is that it
takes a point and returns another Point
okay just the function
so now we want to begin to do tubes okay
uh okay where are we we want to you know
remember
let's let's DD this output this huge
output
delete okay now remember we begin with
um
we begin with a grid or squares so now
we want tubes
so
so first of all how do you create a
graphics of troops okay let's see
uh I don't I don't remember
Now wufam language has 7 000 functions
building by default okay so here is how
you represent a tube okay
so let's go to
um let's copy that
okay so let's start to code here
Cube okay so let's
press Ctrl H no press tab Edge to look
up the tubes documentation so here's the
Wolfram language website
documentation on tube okay so here is
how do you represent the tube so it's
just that uh actually not that
um
you know it because it generates this
now this is annoying
so actually you just copy it
tube okay given given a
three-dimensional point oh it requires
three-dimensional point
uh you know a bunch of Representative 3D
tube around the line joining a sequence
of points okay so the arguments is the
least and each component of least is a
point in 3D space
you know three numbers these are three
numbers so you have a bunch of points in
space
then it generates a tube connecting
around those points okay that's how you
represent the two
okay and then you can give a second
argument that's the radius okay so first
first thing we want to do is let's say
uh so each one of the element is a
three-dimensional thing okay let's
generate the tube let's generate a
circle okay
so circle is sine cosine okay cosine
PSI okay
cosine PSI let's say x and the third
component zero zero is a z we don't want
it to move so zero so cosine sine so let
me let me do this table okay table takes
true argument cosine sine and zero then
X goes from
0 to 6 let's say in steps of
6 divided by
20 okay so that will return
let's let's
that will return this thing
okay
so you return a list
each element is a list again and in the
at least in that list is three numbers
basically the whole thing is the list of
points in 3D okay so that is the um
okay that is a bunch of points now we
just say tube okay
then gives that
okay so copy that back to Fan language
paste it
run it okay anyway shift return
okay so we got we got this okay now we
just say Graphics we want to put
graphics
3D in front of it okay it's three
okay then
the last expression okay
fantastic we got a tube a circle
represented by a tube not just you know
line
okay so that's basically how you get a
tube okay and now what we want is we
want this
um
you know here's a bunch of squares but
we actually what we want is a grid
represented by a tube okay
okay let's do this quickly oh God it's
gonna be 30 minutes more
um
so we want a tube now remember the
syntax forward tube so we got
first of all we generate a bunch of
points of the grid you know point point
point point point point point point
point point
okay then between each point we we use a
tube to connect them to represent the
tube so there's a tube tube tube okay
tube tube tube and also vertically two
okay so we got you know each you know
each each between points is a segment of
a tube okay then we apply the
transformation the geometric
transformation okay that
that changes all the endpoints or the
vertices
then then the tube will accordingly
change you know so that's what we want
to do
uh so far so good am I doing good
so okay I thought you're gonna use glove
80. not yet you know I have to set it up
so uh
you know I was thinking of using it but
then you know sometimes I you know I
don't know the key I have to you know I
want to focus so
it's stayed focused on you know this
video is just Wolfram language
we have a lot to do so um so let's start
to um generate um
so this one is example of a tube of
circle okay
so let's put it back to um
okay that's and and we're missing
Graphics okay
and
yeah okay so get that there there okay
so that is the you know you can open it
you know see
uh oh we spelled it wrong
it's not graph it's graphics 3D
okay so that that okay copy
magnify this
paste it there
doing it you know okay so this is the
example of tube of circle okay so put it
back here now let's start a new one
a new one is what we're gonna do
um okay so now we know how to do a tube
now we we now the first thing we're
gonna do now is generate a bunch of
um grid points okay
so that is going to be table
uh table
okay this table is going to be
X and Y
uh and Z so you need three points okay Z
is zero always okay then the second
element for the the second argument for
the table is going to be X going from
negative let's say five to five instead
in step of one okay then y goes from
same thing negative five to five instead
in steps of one this will this will
create
a list of numbers okay let me show you
okay this is a three-dimensional nested
list of numbers
so that is essentially the grid points
okay
yeah you can see
you see zero five zero negative I
negative five negative five negative
four negative five negative three you
know okay so we got these points now we
need to
um
for each
between every two points we need to put
a q tube so if between every two points
it would be it needs to be tube and and
those two arguments okay okay so God
um
okay why don't we okay why don't we do
this okay so instead of that okay so
let's say let's just let's just say uh
tube here okay
yeah not step
tube and not stub
Cube
there okay so tube
takes at least
okay one point and two points and the
second point will be
you know from one point to the next
point
so the second point will be let's say X
plus one
okay so that's one tube okay so actually
we're gonna generate a list okay so the
list will contain two tubes okay like
that so the second tube will be X then
two y plus one okay I think that's it
this this will give us a bunch of tubes
let's just try it okay
uh does that make sense to you guys Ctrl
shift n let's make it okay it doesn't do
anything it's run it okay so you can see
Cube so that's one tube you know that
goes like that
and the second tube
is going vertical
okay let's double check
zero five x negative 5 then 2 negative
four that's correct
the Y and Z are the same okay now the
second Cube negative five negative five
that's one point
negative five negative four Y is one
less
you know one more so so we got kind of Q
like that okay then the next part is
just the next one so we got a bunch of
that that's what we want fantastic we
got you know this is not efficient code
because you can see the arithmetics they
kind of repeat it but let's just push up
you know the the the the thing about
Wolfram language is that you get you
know you do things
that you spent the minimal amount of
time to to to have a product a protocol
you know to to to create something then
you worry about Computing speed later
okay that's I mean that's the proper
that's the most proper taking advantage
of the wufan language
uh you worry about
optimization later
so you got that so so actually we can
show the tube so actually so let's say
uh
tube segments okay
let's say lots tubes
you know let's just be brain is let's
just say lots of tubes okay so we Define
that
then we say okay then we don't need this
uh whole thing anymore then we just say
Graphics okay and lots of tubes
okay I think that we will okay
let's remove that copy the whole thing
back to Wolfram language okay I got this
okay select all
paste
shift enter
run it
please show me the beautiful graphics
success
successful beautiful is it is that
beautiful how many lines
how many lines of code oh two
fantastic
and you can rotate it in real time
try to do that in python or skim this
okay
okay fantastic now we're going we are
going to now we have this it's extremely
easy all we have to do is apply our
geometric transformation function
which is just this line to all the
points to all the points
so easy so easy
I thought I'm going to oh my God 30
minutes something but never now
okay no no no let's do this is a
function we Define it okay geometric
inversion
then okay this this function yeah this
is good so this function
we need to apply that function to to all
these points okay
now it's very easy to do so here is a
structure okay so all you have to so we
are going to use pattern matching so
here's what we are going to do
how imagine now imagine doing that in C
plus plus you said it first true
zebras was the worst the worst damage to
Computing industry
you know starting with C and Unix you
know they begin then they spread the
virus then it rots every program of
Sprint because when you show these to
the to the programmers in the industry
they don't understand they all say oh oh
that's nice
but tomorrow they forgot all about it
they are back to memory rust you know or
memory
malloc you know memory that's that's
what the C references you know pointers
oh oh they're gonna do that that you
know that's what the most industrial
programmers are like you know because
they accustomed they they they their
brain for the past 40 years their brain
is kind of like
being trained into that way of looking
at things you know they when they see
these they say oh that's nice but after
five minutes they forgot they forgot all
about it they did and yeah most
programmers they are not interested in
math neither
so anyway so let's go back so let me
show you what we are going to do very
easy okay just one line one line we'll
have it we'll have we'll have this
geometry you know we'll have this
geometric inversion of a bunch of tubes
okay how are we gonna do so we going to
so right now I'll um the task is that
you have this data structure you want to
apply a function to each of these
points okay each of these points you
want to apply this this geometric
inversion function how do you do very
many ways okay but we are going to use a
pattern matching so this is unusual this
you will not see in this python see you
know you will not see anywhere you know
you'll see it a little bit in ascal
language
okay you'll see okay or camel for
example a little bit but nothing like
uframe language okay I'm gonna show you
so that's what we're gonna do apply this
function to each of these
points okay
then you'll be done okay so we are going
to use pattern matching so what we do is
that we
suppose uh
tube uh
tube graphics
okay we Define you know first of all we
Define lots of tubes
okay then we Define two Graphics you
know then we Define this function we
need to apply to those points then
then we just say
tube graphics
replace this means replace okay let me
let me use let me use the easy to
understand way okay so let's say replace
or
okay that's small
I'm going to use you know this is a
shortcut notation but let's not you do
that
normally if you are programming wufan
language that's what you wanna that's
what you usually type but let's let's
use the easy to understand uh syntax so
what you say is you could replace or
function it takes two arguments the
first argument is whatever expression
you want to do the replace then the
second argument is a rule basically uh
that find
you know what kind of pattern you want
to find and what to replace it with okay
so you can say find
uh replace
okay that's basically that's a Syntax
for the replacer so okay so fine so what
do you want to find I want to find a
list of three things okay and each one
of them is um
actually I want to find a tube
so let's just let's put it here so I
want to find these things so let's let's
okay so I want to find a pattern where
um
here is you know 3D points okay P1 let's
just say P1 anything P1 okay anything we
give it a name P1
and here similar
P2 so two points okay now you want what
you want to replace actually let's
change this Arrow to
to colon arrow that way it's delayed
anyway that that means we you know
uh that means
don't evaluate the right hand side right
away
only evaluated only when you find the
pattern why because the right hand side
we are need we need to apply this
function
because otherwise if you evaluate right
away when the function don't have any
arguments yet you know it doesn't work
you need to
replace this data by this pattern tube
something
and and by so what's the result you want
so let me show you so what you want is
you want this okay
geometric inversion applied to P1 okay
and same thing here
okay that that should be it
that should be it so actually we just
copy all
new new uh new notebook
okay let's magnify 150 that's it run it
okay dude please show me
okay it didn't work
uh
so oh oh I know why because our function
wait
I don't know
um let's try so if we call our function
with
[Music]
um
let's see tube
tube takes at least
uh let's let's see what happens if we
call our function like that
okay
okay that returns that
now what if that's a function that's a
geometric inversion okay yeah that's
correct so it works in any Dimension you
know so
uh weight
[Music]
do you actually need the bracket or not
yes you do I think
[Music]
uh what
yeah you do need the bracket so why is
it not working
let's try one two three
okay so you actually do need the braces
one two yeah so that's the number one
two five you know that's the number you
do need the
uh curly brake brackets
Okay so
so why is it you know these pattern
transformation didn't
work so
oh I got the syntax wrongs instead of
underscore P1 it should be P1 underscore
what
yeah P1 underscore okay I got the syntax
wrong it should be like that okay
all
select all
paste
run it
yeah
Arrow
oh we got Pi wait yeah
type Arrow so we got we wrote Pi instead
of P1 so let's try it again copy all
Senegal
paste it run it
go down go down go down go down
fantastic
so I think
I'm glad I think okay so we did just one
hour for 15 minutes we did this
fantastic and
that's it for today
um yeah I don't want that you know let's
keep it short you know and let's not put
on so this is what the final result
okay the final result that's what we
want that's
successful
okay you can see the image is not too
symmetric
you know why well the reason is that
because you see remember the way we
generated the grid you know we have
these things poking out
that can be easily fixed
you know
you know you can fix it in several ways
so okay let's do five more minutes to to
make it nice okay
yeah but this is a result actually I'm
happy
uh
you know
so one way to you know yeah we can fix
it you you just add you know more
segments at the end
uh but that would be yeah you can't do
that there are many ways but this is one
of those case where you have off by one
case you know when you have nested at
least
you know you have the special issue
special case of the end point so you
know you can
you can manually fix it by adding you
know or you can do more elegant way you
know it's it's a bit you know it's a
kind of tedious thing
another way to alternatively to fix this
is that instead of line segment we can
just make them each a square that way
you don't have the poking out thing
but it wouldn't be exactly the same as
that we can do the square let's let's
try Okay okay so this is done
you know this code you know just
actually four lines of code you know
three lines it's done okay so let's pop
it back copy it paste it again now let's
this time we're gonna do the enclosed
you know we start with squares instead
of in squares
instead of the
grid okay so to have a square
you know we just we just do four cubes
okay one two three four four
tubes
uh yeah actually we don't need actually
we can just have one single tube okay
one single tube you know it will go
around like that so you need one two
three four four points you know this
Cube this this tube one single tube will
represent a square
okay
so tube takes one argument and in this
argument it will be I mean it's a list
and and it's going to be this list will
have four components okay one two three
four
so the first point is 0 0 x y zero okay
now
X Plus 1 y 0.
then
X Plus 1
y plus 1 0 then
X and the Y plus one zero so okay so you
got going around forming a square okay
and that's it that's it let's try it
is that is that it I think so let's try
it
yeah we got no
uh what's the new one okay so tube uh
okay so I know what's going on so there
is a tube
okay so there is a tube now you got this
new it won't be correct the reason is
because your data structure changed
remember before the it's a tube of two
points now you got tube of Four Points
so what you have to do is easy okay
change the pattern here so now the
pattern is you know we can actually just
do this P3
uh
P4 this is kind of manual
you can alternatively you can do it in
one shot doesn't matter how many points
let's just do it manual because
for Simplicity you know so
so P3
P4 this is not efficient code but anyway
that's the allows you to do things very
fast okay let's paste it I think that's
it
isn't it
yeah no okay
P1 P2 so
least iterator no okay why am I getting
a new
okay sounds
p1p2p3p4
PMB to HPV for what
so we got a tube
we got tube right okay let's just let's
let's
double check our code
huh we got a new one somewhere
yeah we got you see the problem is we
got extra comma repeated comma
Wu fam language doesn't like that you
see one comma here one comma here
repeated comma okay who fan language
doesn't like that so that copy it
select all paste it run it
fantastic scroll down
fantastic
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching now uh
yeah there is still not perfectly fixed
you can see
you know the reason it's not
wait we're missing
oh one two three
four you need to connect it back okay so
what
yeah okay so let's just re uh let's just
repeat that okay
okay this is not efficient code but
let's just do it
copy it okay oh wait five
copy it
select or paste red
fantastic beautiful that's it that's it
for today
uh wait this is still wrong because
the whole thing is now not centered okay
so we can we can fix that by
by starting at
5.5 5.5
to
uh instead in step of one okay so 5.5
instead of one okay select all
Circle paste run it okay let's
suppress the output by putting a
semicolon okay select or paste run it
fantastic
no is that right yes that is correct
okay that's it for today this is is this
correct yes this is beautiful
thank you guys for watching bye
fam language okay
please make a video on g502 it's a macro
and each Mark will you use for
efficiency well 358 g502 you are talking
about this mouse right you're talking
about this mouse there's not much to it
you know there's tons of other people
doing that so
okay that's it for today I'm shutting
down I'm shutting down
I'm shutting down now
uh and if you like my video you know go
to you know go to
go to my website donate to me okay so
you can see you can patreon me or Amazon
gift card me
five dollars five dollars a month
support me or uh you know 20 bucks one
shot
thank you
bye