welcome to another episode of talk show
and today I'm gonna talk about Emacs
lots of Emacs stuff so the topic today
is going to be Emacs Emacs they mocks a
move image file and eMac this ok I'm
gonna do some move image file I'm gonna
demo demonstrate that then there are
several other topics now which one
topics we're gonna go into depends on
you so you just type in the chat box and
we can talk about that topic now let me
get the browser ready let me pop pop
this pop the chat out and okay so let's
let's let's begin then let's begin with
the let's begin in the beginning so exam
move image file so I'm gonna do a demo
of this Emacs command I have and first
of all okay so let's show sauce start
command log mod now this window as you
know it will show all the commands I
type in Emacs so if you see something
I'm doing
you can look what command it is so okay
so so let's do let's start with a
keyboard so I have this page
alright I need to start the browsers
okay it's not the break browser and I
have this page about keyboard now I'm
going to show you a Emacs command that
so when you if you write blogs you are
going to do a lot screen captures you
know possibly I do because for example I
need to capture this image and sometimes
you need to capture Twitter images you
know or whatever but for now I'm going
to
to this image so let's open it ok turn
on the JavaScript script aloud okay so
let's look at the image
hopefully oh this is actually a video
I don't want video okay so so we
don't want video let's let's stop the
JavaScript in okay so I'm going to just
click that open imaging a new tab okay
that's what I want now let's save it now
I'm going to save it with any with a
file name in my download folder
downloads for the starting with EE so
this is going to be saved into my
download folder so I do that okay it's
saved close it back to Emacs and let's
go through my keyboard blog you can see
in browser this is my keyboard bug and
I'm going to go here add a new section
and then now I want to add image now
normally what you do is that you go to
the download folder you know then you
copy the file pair thing you know it's
tedious let me just show you so I call
this command excite move image file and
you ask me what directory I'll just say
I and you see this file name is already
here this file name is actually in the
download directory so let's just say
enter okay
and showing browser it's like that
because it is actually a
this is not a normal image file this is
some kind of weapon you know yeah okay
that's a failure okay so let's do it
another one then let's see how many
people are watching five people away yay
say hi guys say hi so this image failed
let me let's just use another image okay
let's go to saw wotty
okay this is my english and literature
and linguistics blog so there's this
body page you go to body blog and you
can see casas tongue national anthem now
okay
this country kazahstan you you almost
never hear it in US news
well anyway it's like you know near
russia russian culture and it looks like
it's a great country and they have a
great national anthem actually but
anyway our job is to save an image okay
to demo this image so let me show you
let's copy that go to a new tab paste it
we want to go to wikipedia high green
tag a green tag have you ever been to
kazahstan hey Isaac so Kazakhstan we are
going to demo you know Yura max whoops
okay so let's let's magnify go down and
go down go down go down go down go down
there is a
there is some beautiful pictures of the
city that okay let's open that one and
okay this is taking more time than I
wanted to sorry about that
but okay here this is a picture I want
let me show you so so this is a great
architecture photo let's open that you
know some kind of art museum or library
so we want let me demo demonstrate this
and let me answer the questions this
will be quick
so I'm gonna save this file again start
with EE okay
the name file name start must start with
EE okay save it then I go to okay let's
go through some hearts actually open saw
hearts
okay now solids is my one of my website
and which contains many architectural
photos for example architectural
beauties you know I kind of collect them
okay something is wrong why is that
everything I tried to do some demo
something went wrong you see this this
is not correctly formatted some CSS is
not loading or something reload I don't
okay well anyway this page collects
architectural photos so actually I want
to add a page to here so let's go
through some arts okay whoops
hot art blog okay this is my art blog it
contains you know random ish funny oh
you know beautiful art stuff so I'm
going to add
the page here for now so go to here add
a new section then I'm going to coax a
move image file okay where do I want to
move it took to the directory I okay
press enter and you ask me your name you
see here Palace of Arts Chabot
something like that okay inter so now
it's added now look at you see that that
is the command now that is a command saw
where did our code here some move image
file here you can see it's this one so
what it does is that whenever you do a
screenshot it work also walk-ons for
screenshot for example it's oops
for example let's let's say I want to do
a screenshot let's say this okay now
it's swing shot you know screenshot is
usually saved in some like on a Mac it's
usually you can you can control where it
saves but on the Mac I think it's safe
to desktop or something but now look I'm
gonna call that command again so a new
directory some moving image file it
asked me where it was
do I want to save it let's say hi okay
and the name is by default is screenshot
let's say yes okay then it's
automatically when it's PNG file it
automatically click cause up TP M G of T
PNG which reduces the image file so
anyway you can see it's here now let's
view in browser you see so this this
command is very super convenient because
then because you don't have to go
through the you know where whatever the
directory to find the file then you try
to move it to the directory of your blog
then you try to add the image tag you
know to
you know all of these are Tanja's with
one command you know or two keys you
know I have it said to two keys so you
see it's very good now we don't need
this image files let's open it delete it
now delete that TV delete that
wait yeah delete EDT showing browser
this image I want but this image
actually I want to put it in the
architecture wait wait wait geodesic
dome yeah architectural beauties okay
obviously obviously something is wrong
here I don't like that let's let's fix
it let's try to fix it shall we
so open open you see okay so I have just
demonstrated kasam move image file now
let me show you another thing so this is
a local file the URL you can see at the
top so I copy the URL go to copy the URL
go to Emacs
and I want to open that local file so I
can just do this command look at left
panel it's opened so it that command is
open file from clipboard you know and
you can see if I this that this is the
path of the fire just opened you know
including the URL prefix file you know a
colon slash slash so you know that
command will take care of that you know
it will just open whatever path you are
in a so I open the file so let
let's me yeah let's do let's fix this
somehow it got broken I think it's
probably CS CSS has any something to do
with CSS okay let's look at the comments
Quinn deck no of unfortune so you
haven't been to that country that Kassar
something
hit this country okay that's this
country kazahstan but I know a couple of
people from there okay huh so Isaac's
says I had a question I was thinking
about all day that I was going to ask
you but I have forgotten it okay that's
a good question
mooch didn't says hello come raid hello
come raid okay so so the topic now the
topic meandered into how do you fix you
know in my daily life of you know
working on my website or programming
languages you know so now I have this
problem
this site is not broken it shouldn't be
like that
so now I need to find out what's going
on so let's maybe let's just do that
then
so exact go to a wait so first of all
let's check the header so I got the it's
magnified header no it's not header okay
so oh I know why because remember last
week like a week ago so I changed you
know like I was doing a video I changed
this main tag it used to be it used to
be this it used to be like that okay and
I change it to that and that is why I'm
pretty sure that is why it's broken
we can find out by go to the top open
the CSS file open it and such for men
list matching lines
okay there is none
okay so all these pages
okay let's search for dive okay yeah
here is a problem no that's not the
problem so I don't actually know what is
going on and I'm wondering currently
whether I should continue to fix this
page Jesus should I continue fixing his
page or should we get into some other
interesting topics you know I can
so these are some topics I was thinking
of talking about today and okay so let's
go back here and actually today's date
let's get the title correct so that new
people come in Oh today is 5th that's
correct
No the title is correct okay so so okay
so guys let me know ok so I want to fix
this page you see this is basically I
know what is going on because I'm
missing you see each one of these for
example this one is Yan demigoddess
if you look at browser that's the first
one here so this block block this block
is is the first one and in CSS it should
be set to inline in inline block okay
there's a display CSS display property
it should should be set to inline block
but that didn't that's not happening
that that is why you are seeing this
kind of
think so
display:inline-block okay so let's go
back let's go to the CSS again search
for men okay that
okay I don't know offhand why it's wrong
yeah because I'm wondering if I should
continue because because you know it
this might be you know take 20 minutes
or 10 minutes then it's a waste time for
you guys so let's just try to add that
so we added a dive here and looking
browser yeah so it's missing a dive
okay let's for now let's just for the
diving let's put it died
so put a die yeah that looks much better
okay let's show a shell powerful issue
and and cuz I interactive a brief okay
now it's uploaded to my website so green
day okay so if you go back to my web
site let's see
sorry texture and reload you see now it
looks much better you can max maximize
with the window then you're okay that's
one command then that's so that's so
what we have shown is our talk show it's
quite key this key then you have the
command some move image file let's go to
the file okay
yeah the urs here so if you like to have
this command you can just go to my
website and use it okay that's one thing
that's one topic done so let's see what
else Emacs demo so the next one is Emacs
Lisp I can do Emacs Lisp demo of this
command so copy HTML by link so if you
you know I'm you know
so this is a live talk show you know
type like which topic you want me to
cover and we do that so this one emag
based you know I'm going to demo this
command and this command there's
something else I need to add you know I
need to modify it so in the process you
can see how I you know work on eMac base
you can then I can explain some eMac B's
you know stuff like tutorial or
something so Emacs Unicode add a hub
root page yeah we can do that emag you a
Unicode utf-8 history yeah and
introduction to Unicode for programmers
I can talk about that
because last a few days ago we did that
but I'm not sure it's very good so we
can do that again and other topics so
any other topics so how are you guys you
know say something let me know where to
go let's see go back six feet were
watching yeah you know just type
something here okay let me you know let
me know what what should we talk about
so I sag did you remember what what's
the thing Unicode intro okay let's do
that
thank you so I'm going to give you an
introduction to Unicode for programmers
okay let's close that so now I just have
one browser so it should be faster so
let's go - sorry unicode and you can see
unicode okay this is my unicode
characters page and and my unicode pages
are actually most popular among all my
pages they are like more than 50% of
traffic on my web site for some reason
because the the easiest the brainless
things people like you know people like
emojis people like you know
actually the most popular page is this
unicode arrows because you don't find
this information anywhere else so on
this page I have basic I have all the
Unicode arrows
you know collected and in one groups
grouped them in the in pie style you
don't find this anywhere I mean usually
if you go you know use such other other
page other Unicode pages they are
typically they are just typically
grouping by the Unicode code point you
know which is very bad because the
arrows are scattered over the face so
okay so so here's my unicode page once
you find it you found that you can go to
the bottom there's a Unicode for
programmers now you go there and you can
see you can see these Unicode books now
this is this is a the Ken lund a he's in
California he's actually I think in San
Jose close to where I live you know what
40-million stripe so he he wrote the
alrighty book called CJK let's eat
Chinese Vietnamese Korean Japanese CV KJ
or something you know book alrighty
intro you know that's an introduction to
processing you know Chinese characters
Japanese you know by Unicode so he wrote
that book and I read that book back in
2000 year 2000 2001 but anyway so he's
got you know this bunch of Unicode
boogie he works for Adobe and oops let's
close that shrink it he works for Adobe
but back then back in 2000 I also read
this book about this book the Unicode
standard version 3 it's it's pretty
thick it's like this thick but actually
have half
the book content is just a list of
Chinese characters but still so I bought
this book Unicode standard version three
back in 2000 and I read you know I read
you know pretty much the whole thing you
know except the table of Chinese
characters that's all just Chinese
characters so anyway so on this page
Unicode for programmers you can these
are articles about Unicode for
programmers for example first of all
there's an introduction Unicode basics
character set encoding utf-8 you know
what is the coat point and things like
that then I have for example let's see
okay what encoding do to Chinese website
use you know best unicode for font for
programmers unicode history UTF history
yeah this page actually added you TF is
created by Rob Pike and and and Thomas
what's his name Oh Marcus can Marcus can
passed away by the way Marcus Khan is
also one of the early internet engineer
sorry and he's also a Emacs user he said
and he one day he wrote a where did I
confuse him with someone else I could be
confused with him with someone else
I okay so anyway so rough pike created
utf-8 and he is also he created with
another guy
UNIX UNIX guy Thomas anyone remembered
what what's the name anyway anyway so
that's that's a history you probably
don't I mean I mean you want the basic
introduction to Unicode so we're gonna
do that then let but let me see the
comments the question was about Barack I
remember now
assuming you used quote he before did
your speed increase or is it simply for
comfortable to type now speed do not
increase okay should i iii-vi let me
answer that quickly okay then let's go
back to introduction to unicode okay XR
Devo rack so I have like five articles
about low rack you can learn everything
you what you want to know all your
questions about vu rack here so where
our keyboard is you know it's a vision
layout but anyway if you go down all the
way down they are actually several
articles about ball rack okay actually
answer the questions here for example my
experience my experience of Cody and
ball rack I tell you the story how I
learned it when I learned I learned in
1994 we over act make you type faster no
basically basically no period but it
will make you the typing will be much
more comfortable and that's basically it
yeah comfortable so that so then there's
a question should you I mean most people
you know when they think of Iraq they
they think oh you'll make them type
faster no no not not really if you'd
already type Cote you want type faster
in fact you probably USB will probably
then when you were typing quality at
least for the first year but if you do
not touch type then you try to learn
more ACK
and you know then of course your speed
will be much faster
simply because you you are now a touch
type so there's always the question you
know so should you should you switch to
Borak does this okay the other question
is does for AK prevents repetitive
strain injury not really okay
the the answer is not really if you have
hand pain you know if you have you know
RSI issues first of all get a mechanical
keyboard get an ergonomic keyboard you
know with middle middle higher than the
than the edges you know the so-called
tented keyboard mechanical keys you know
get an egg ergonomic keyboard so if you
are using normal keyboard and you think
switching to ball rack it will not
basically will have no effect on your
you know typing injury stuff so even the
final question is should you switch to
black it's like yes and no so you know
I've been using more borax since 1994 I
was quite a typist since 1988 also okay
so I it's a tremendous pain to learn
more work it took me two months painful
pain for two months you know because
every time you type you know you got you
know it's wrong you know then you have
to figure out where is the key so it's
extremely painful if you already type
Corti and you you want to switch to work
okay and once you so yeah it's painful
to switch so so once you learn more AG
you know it's it's good you know it's
more comfortable but should you switch
that's up to you actually so this you
know I wouldn't say you know yes
everyone should switch because there are
lots of issues
with using water because you go to the
library you cannot you cannot type
because everywhere it's you know corty
you have to bring your keyboard to work
or something like that or you have to go
to the operating system you know like go
here and switch to Iraq and you know
little or no annoyances like that you
know so so you know it's really up to
you if you are really concerned about
efficiency yes of course
varrock is absolutely more efficient
than quality ok efficient in a sense
your your fingers move less you know
much less but why does it not help
reduce RSI because for the cost causes
of RSI actually there are lots of other
things that's more problem that's
causing your hand pain for example the
normal keyboard you have the pronation
with donation and you know owner
deviation and things like that so you
know so anyways yeah so the final
question is you know it's it's really up
to you if you are really concerned about
you know you want the best you know
elegant system efficient then you know
vorak is good for you so web dog I know
web dog you try to learn what works so
can't you give up so so web dogs they
says web dog says is there any easy
Emacs or command to copy key or the
output of an interactive command kill
the output of an interactive command
like what you mean web dog says I spent
two weeks trying to live over again gave
up two weeks is not enough you had two
weeks of 10 you need more pain okay
let's go back to Unicode so Unicode is
this you know what you know what Unicode
is these are characters so first of all
so so okay you can read this article but
I'm I'm now going to look at look so
this Arco introduces you what Unicode is
what what
- said is what character encoding is you
know what what character said in
encoding systems and and what utf-8 what
are you TF 16 you know unicode character
said code point and oops let's go back
ko point and so I so you can read this
article but I'm not going to because you
shooting well why I try to read the
article I start to kind of just reading
it which is no good so it's not look at
that so I'm going to just to explain
what you Unicode is for a programmer
okay
first of all you need a character set
you define a character set I mean even
before the computing area you have a
character set
what's a character set for example
English alphabets A to Z capital K is in
lowercase that's a character set you
know you you kind of have need to define
it you know for English you may not need
to because there's just 26 alphabets
lowercase and uppercase you know
everyone knows that
so you don't need to define it because
everyone know it already then you need
you have punctuation
you know period comma you know semi semi
colon question mark you know you need to
include that as a character set then you
also need numbers one two three four you
know in parentheses in brackets you know
so on you you know so you have the
concept of a character set
now that's one important concept okay
why is this important because for
example in China in Chinese you know we
have 5,000 to 10,000 characters
depending on you know how you count like
which you know you need like three
thousand characters to to read
newspapers to have a basic understanding
of newspapers so so also each characters
has many variations you know maybe you
know so so for Chinese for example it's
far more important to have a character
set like meaning that the government
design and the Education Department you
know design a character set telling you
okay this is the standard basic
set of let's say 5000 characters then
you know high school or college you know
can teach these in you know so we have
some kind of you know like a standard
even before computing okay now so so and
and similarly for Spanish French you
know latin-based language or Indian
language overall Russian you know you
need a character set you need you know
government or something in strength the
standard body designer character set so
you can agree on you know what are the
characters you have now character set is
very important in computing or you know
it becomes essential because because if
you don't have the standardized
character set then you don't know which
character you're talking about you know
because you know right so so so folk
imputing you know the character said you
need to define character set so in the
1960s over 50s you have a character set
called ASCII okay a so let's go to
hacker code no let's go back to Unicode
so let's go to Unicode and let's go to a
ski so a ski is one of the early
character set created by USA is called
American standardized character
information something let's see American
I don't have the full name here but
anyway it's called character ski so
asking act s key so s key it defines
hundred 128 characters you can see
character a ABC you have ABC capital ABC
you have lowercase basically a hundred
twenty eight of them the first one is is
called Noir it's actually not a
character we at word will talk about
that so anyway you have a character
said then you also need encoding what
does encoding me encoding basically
turns a character you know let's say
capital case a to a number assign a sign
but integer to it so a is 65 Inc in
ASCII B is 66 the pressure mod mark is
63 for example so that's encoding
that's what encoding well that's not
encoding yet but but anyway you need to
assign assign a integer as some kind of
ID to a character so each character has
a unique ID that identifies it it's
called in Unicode this is called code
point so this is very important concept
remember code point
it's called code point code point is a
integer that identifies the character in
Unicode okay so he asking you also have
that 65 by the way ASCII Unicode for the
ASCII characters so unicode contains all
the words characters you know including
Asian languages Asian writing systems
and it of course includes or ASCII
characters 1 to 128 you know 137 0 to
127 and by the way the code point
between ASCII and Unicode is identical
so it remains compatible in that sense
so why you know the lowercase Y in ASCII
is 121 so that but in the same way in
Unicode the lowercase Y is also 121 the
code point for the character lowercase Y
is 121 so okay so you got a character
set then you got code point now remember
this this important concept okay
character said code point which is
integer ID to identify the character now
also let me remember another thing each
character are not necessary
visible or you know like a graph you can
see for example a space character you
know space you need space writing in
programming of course you need space but
it's a character but yeah you know
usually you don't call it a character
because you cannot see it you know but
you see it's required it's needed so
space is also we can call it a character
so it has a quote point 32 and there are
also other invisible characters for
example tab key
let's see tab tab back horizontal tab
this one okay for example tab when you
when you press tab on the keyboard
that's you know like a character it's
invisible character so you have the code
point for tab is nine and in asking you
got bunch of others like no character
startup header line feed life it is in
using UNIX and Linux systems for like
newline so whenever you see a line feed
character it means a new line you know
again it's an invisible character so you
got this bunch of invisible characters
and some of them are control characters
like when in terminal you can press
control D to exit it for example let me
press control D you know it exit the
terminal control D is actually one of
these this end of transmission character
and it has a code point for okay so you
know you could you know that's called
control character so anyway so character
said you have the concept of character
set then you have a concept that code
code point which you know identify
integer correspond to each character set
okay now let's talk about encoding okay
what is encoding encoding is basically
you know you know computers you know CPU
chips they are just electronics they are
basically just one in zeros 1 0 1 1 1 0
you know pen pen range numbers why
because electronics they
actually just voltages you know when
it's high it's one when it's low it's
zero that's how you know CPU works so
you need you need to turn you know each
character into a sequence of one and
zeros so how do you do that well you can
say you know you know one way to do it
is one way to do it is that you take the
code point of a character for example
the character zero is 48 the code point
that's an integer then you just use that
integer as its binary representation you
know whatever 48 is in binary so that's
that's one way and that works for ASCII
so that's so ASCII you see there are
only 128 characters and each of its code
point can be turned into a binary
sequence so 127 is 127 would be 1 1 1 1
1 1 1 1 yeah that's all once so I'm good
with binary numbers so you see so so
what I what I'm saying here is that for
ASCII characters said you know they can
you know since they are only 128 of them
they can all be you know you can just
use a code point code point and convert
it to binary and that fits one byte you
know eight eight bits you know eight
binary digits that works for ASCII but
however if you have you know more
characters let's say if you have 200
characters let's say you know then you
cannot do that because you need more
bytes you know then you have the
question you know is one character just
one byte or is one character always two
bytes and things like that so the these
kind of all these things is is
yeah issue of encoding okay so I'm at am
i doing okay am i doing too slow and I
like you know talking about things you
already know okay alright so the
questions you know keep the comments
coming because I don't know you find
like talking dragging on us those are so
so so so so remembered character set
okay that's important code point that's
important
then encoding encoding is turning any
character into a sequence of ones and
zeros now that's what encoding is okay
now for ASCII the encoding of ASCII is
very simple you know you have a standard
ASCII so standard okay
ASCII defines the character set defines
a cool point it also defines encoding
for for you know 128 characters and it's
trivial because you simply turn the
character you know whatever the code
point into a binary digit that that is
its encoding but now if you have more
characters that's a problem so in
Unicode standard let's go back to
Unicode Unicode let's go back to Unicode
for programmers then the first page
Unicode for programmers then you go to
Unicode basics okay character said
what's character encoding then you have
so in Unicode Unicode is you know is a
Unicode consortium the standard body
started around 1990 so 1989 something
like that so they define first of all
they define your character set so what
is their character said their character
set is basically it contains basically
all all all writing you know it's
intended to to country include or
writing possible alphabets or writing
systems such as Chinese characters in
you
so it has like it has like I don't
remember how many characters anyway it's
it's it's the character said is defined
it is designed to four languages or
human languages Asian or today and today
each year they actually have a new
Unicode version so Unicode 3 is around 2
year 2000 Unicode 4 is around maybe year
2005 but anyway since about 2014 also
2015 they decided to have one new
Unicode version every year so you have a
version in 2017 you have Unicode so you
can see here Unicode 11 came out in what
in in 2018 you know so in 2019 you gonna
have Unicode 12 so in each Unicode
version they add more characters so you
can see here in Unicode 11 2018 they
added you know many more characters for
many different languages and also emoji
characters and so on so anyway so
Unicode has a character set each year it
adds more so it's a you know huge number
so yeah it has right now as of Unicode
11 2018 it has 137 something characters
okay so Unicode they define character
set okay and each year they add more
okay so character set and Unicode
defined code point for each character
you have a integer that that correspond
to that character identifies it okay and
Unicode defines I think around for
encoding systems to convert a character
into binary sequence so you have utf-8
that's one of them
you have utf-16 that's what another one
you have UTF third
- that's another one I think there's
another one oh and you know I don't
remember but anyway you know you can
read my articles or you can go to
Wikipedia you know you understand you
know when you read it so so Unicode
consortium defines three or more
encoding systems today the most popular
is utf-8 now why three encoding systems
how they differ you know why you you
know what you need feeding Kony systems
because ok let's talk about the simplest
one is utf-32 now the 32 the word 32
Signum have signifies 32 binary digits
32 bits you know which is 4 bytes you
know one byte is eight bits so eight
times four is thirty-two yeah so you
utf-32 is a encoding system such that
every character doesn't matter which
character it any character is encoded
into four bytes and no more and no less
you know every character is just four
bytes so the advantage of this utf-32
encoding system is that it's it's kind
of uniform every character has just
studied is just four bytes you know so
it's simpler to sort them you know it's
simple you know
but the flaw I mean the the the drawback
is that if we Christ required requires
more disk space for example if you are
all writing if you know if you are if
your text is mostly English or Latin
alphabets you know French or Spanish
each character now is four bytes you
know as compared to ASCII each character
is just one bite so now your file size
is like four times you know bigger so
that's you know that's a drawback so so
utf-32 is one of you
then you have utf-16 now so utf-16 is
called variable byte encoding meaning
that for most of the characters each
character takes two bytes 16 bits you
know 2 bytes but however for some
characters it takes 3 or 4 bytes so it's
variable I mean it depends depends on a
character character ok so it's kind of
changes you know like given a character
you know you have to look up you know
you you know it may may use one byte it
to a minimum of 2 or 2 to 4 you know 2
or 3 or 4 bytes
so that's utf-16 now utf-16 is kind of
it was popular it was used in Java you
know Java language standard you know the
source code is in is by the language
spec it's it's supposed to be utf-16
okay it's also using Windows file system
and also use the max file system so it
was popular back in 1990s because it was
thought that you know 16 bits is enough
you know you don't need you don't need
more characters than 16 bits so you know
so so it was thought because you know
you you must remember back then all we
have is ASCII you know we don't have
internet like today and in fact you
never see you know you never see
characters from Russia or you know from
China or Japan like you don't see it you
know like like in this not even much
internet you know so basically each
country you only see your own languages
this is asking you know for us Americans
you know that's you know yeah but that's
back then so but you know since the
internet you know you know the
international communication and so on
you start to see you know all different
languages and stuff and so it turns out
you need more than 16 bits so you
TF 16 is kind of less popular today's
the most popular is utf-8 encoding
system remember all these are encoding
systems which are kind of they are
standardized way to turn sequence of
characters into sequence of ones and
zeros now so what is utf-8 utf-16 coding
ok that's why it is popular especially
among Linux and UNIX people and also it
became the most popular on the web now
it's as seek asking compatible meaning
that if you look at ASCII so in utf-8
encoding if you have oops let's go back
if you have a character let's say
capital a which has code point 65 in
ASCII it also has you know the code
point in Unicode is also 65 but now you
want to encode it in binary you all you
do is turn 65 into you know binary
digits and in utf-8 it's the same thing
exact exact same thing it's also you
know 65 in binary digits so you TFA is
asking compatible in that sense and it
is also a variable encoding system that
means for some characters it takes one
bite for some other characters it may
take two or three or four so each
character takes one to four bytes so
that is utf-8 and that is the most
popular today it's used by like 92% of
the web today so let's go back to so I
think this okay there's one more thing I
want to talk about and that's about it
for introduction of Unicode to
programmers so
let's see so anyway utf-8 is most
popular today it's it's kind of a
standard for the web and it's used by
something like 94% of all web sites okay
one more thing about UTF about Unicode
then let's let's read the comments okay
so you know what's the character
encoding and you know what is a
character set and encoding systems
unicode character said encoding systems
unicode characters set code point okay
we know what is a quote point
that's a code point okay okay so code
point is ID for each character
now there's another concept called
character name now unicode also a sign
your name to each and every character so
and the name is so you can see i show a
simple bunch of characters and i show
you their name so this one capital a is
called the unicode name the character
name you know is called latin capital
letter a okay and this alpha you know
Greek alpha is called quick small letter
alpha and this Cyrillic character so
this with Sevilla character this one I
need to ask green deck so how do you
pronounce how do you finance this
character so this character is called
Cyrillic capital letter Z okay so it's
zip so you know each characters got the
name and the name is supposed to be
unique I mean in in a sense I given a
name that uniquely point uniquely points
to one character but however some
characters have has more than one name
because backed in UTF back in unicode
version two they changed some characters
names so for some characters you have
two names one is owed name
the other wise new name but but still
given a Unicode character name that
always uniquely points to one character
and one only that's that's by design
okay so you got Co point you got name so
okay you some folks for example Unicode
has a standard notation to to to denote
a character for example this a so you
got a unicorn name then you got this u
plus 41 now that is a standard notation
for this character
so what does u plus 41 means that means
the hexadecimal for this character is 41
and which is the hexadecimal for the
code point of this character so remember
each character has a KO point which is
integer now you rewrite that integer in
hexadecimal notation then you add u plus
to it that is the standard notation for
the unicode character so that that is it
yeah so that that is basically it about
unicode that's basically what you need
to know that's the essential basic
information about unicode you understand
character set you understand
encoding you know what does encoding
means and decoding is a reverse decoding
is taking a sequence of binary digits
turn it into characters so you have
character said you you know different
country have different character set but
Unicode defines one character set for
the Unicode you know so encoding systems
you have lots of encoding systems
Unicode defines three utf-8 utf-16 UTF
third utf-32 and there are several other
encoding systems you know there are ones
designed for Chinese one DS designed for
Japanese you know before único becomes
you know the standard you know so you
have encoding standard systems you have
code point and you have character name
so that's the basics about Unicode
okay so that's that's it you know like
when when you'd like Python to to Python
3 Python 3 was created because they want
to fix the Unicode in Python because you
know because before a string is you know
a string is just a bite you know which
is good for ASCII but now if you go
beyond ASCII characters each character
may have two or more bytes so that's why
python 3 wants to fix that so in Python
3 the string each string is a Unicode
character anyway so you know that's how
it ties to you know because encoding you
know the the coding systems encoding and
you know these concepts are actually
very critical is it's in fact
fundamental in computing doesn't matter
what you do programming languages
internet protocols
you know tcp/ip it all has to do with
encoding because when you have a writing
system you know English for example you
need to convert to to sequence of bits
so so it's you know it's so important
you know in a sub programmer you know if
you just started programming you may not
be very familiar but as you get more
experienced you are see more you know
encoding issues in fact it's a good
thing to actually understand the ASCII
well you know you have to you know take
a look you know read the article because
for example this oops let me go back
you know this Stack Overflow arrow page
you know they showed you this but now if
you read this page now you will
understand what they are talking about
you know this kind of like a joke but
you know each one of these correct a and
stuff they are actually control
characters you know if you have a C
programmer you might have seen these I'm
not a C programmer so I don't really see
this but but also you see these kind of
things in email
you know especially the character read
em so if you understand ASCII you know
you you read this you see different
notation then you get you know next time
you see it you understand it okay let's
read the comments so how many people are
watching let's see six people okay
that's good so web dawg
so Isaac says oh thank you okay
web dog says I spent like two weeks
trying okay Isaac says I just learned
home row for for a black so Isaac says I
had the problem of Chinese characters in
oak tables being too wide or something
and it messed up the oak table I'm not
sure how to fix that and I don't know if
that actually that something can be
fixed
yeah because you you should you see
English characters are you know Chinese
characters are so called to full width
okay this this concept okay if you go to
the Unicode page and if you go to
for with here using normally Chinese
characters is is is more or less you
know two characters with of English
alphabet so so you should so when you
have Chinese and English mixed together
they don't look good in the sense that
typically if you have Chinese every
character is aligned you know your page
becomes a great but as soon as you have
some English then it's not aligned
anymore
so for some people that's a issue you
know that's a I saw so they Unicode
created this you know in Asia you have
this concept of full width characters
which is English characters you know but
act but attract each character actually
takes twice as much space as the normal
English characters they are like
fixed-width but you know taking you know
twice as long it looks like this you
know so these are using full width
characters so so you know mod you could
use this but it's from it's probably not
a good solution because if you use this
then everything will be aligned but
however English becomes ugly because you
know usually you don't want to you know
read English like that but anyway
so web dog says started to explain what
I mean but I just wrote the emag miss me
instead so okay so maybe let's look at
that so anything else let's copy that so
go here open a new buffer paste it said
it took saw this mod and he did that and
okay you see here's an interesting thing
when you copy things from Twitter and
stuff you will get these invisible
characters you see where my cursor is
right there becomes a lie now look watch
I call describe cha okay describe cha it
tells me that I have I have a 0 with
space this happens on Twitter
okay on Twitter or other social network
on your YouTube you know Google pages
you know because when you copy something
actually they use you know things like 0
with space usually you don't want those
characters are very annoying and and
usually there are hidden you know so you
know what you don't see it so I have a
road
I have written a command that that takes
them out you know so look at the left
panel I'm going to call the command so
this is a command so that's sad we face
invisible cha and ok I press Enter oops
ok so let's do it again ok so it's
asking me do I want to replace or not I
say yes yes ok so those characters are
good you see so if you like that command
you can use it that command is this one
Kesava crazy invisible charts and you
can find it in this URL let's go look at
it
ok so if it tries to find all these
characters 0 with no breaks face 0 with
space
right to left mark you know things like
that those characters are very annoying
and you know they are part of Unicode
you know like we talked about they are
invisible characters so okay so let's
look at this in is code let's see what
it does it's kind of oh that's just one
function it's just a space and press tab
key press tab key so define the fund
copy next command Hartford copy kill the
output of a an Arri function given an
airy function okay a command for
function name okay keanu condition
command so kill so Keanu basically
delete attacks but put it in in a
clipboard
you know curing so Keanu condition so if
so if it's F is a command then then
execute so call the command okay so if
it's not command just call that okay
okay I guess I know what you're doing
yeah so you you want to call command and
for for its output you want to put it
into the key O ring so but I'm not sure
if this will I mean it's great
well it's great but I'm not sure it's
gonna work 100% because
both file name okay yeah I guess it
works and you have perfil file name in
clipboard
yeah I guess you what I mean yeah it's
great I mean yeah that's a good thing
about eMac you know and eMac this you
know when you have so many issues just
create a command you know that's what I
do you know then it solves your problem
it's a great thing so that's a great
thing too that's why you want to learn
eMac miss you know it's quite useful so
I think that's it for today let's see
seven people watching so anyone else
guys pop up and say something so I think
I think that that would be it
17 minutes talking Amy relax and have
have my drink
so what else what else guys so let's see
green tag so green tag Quinn Dex is
Quinn deck is it eight o'clock in
morning Isaak is in California I think
MOOC taken where you found the book much
how do you pronounce that and the web
dawg oh I forgot where you're from web
dawg
okay guys say something say something so
let's look at myself okay in closing
let's listen to let's close that let's
listen to this great song of kazahstan
hey once in just a second easy wen Shan
Winston what do you think about Julian
Assange Assange I think he's a great guy
oh my god this is a political topic this
topic is gonna get us banned thanks hey
Jane quest Christopher hey great to see
you so G so Julian Assange I think he's
a great guy you know he so if you guys
you know oh let's try that me yeah so
that's you know he actually he's a Emacs
user did you guys know let me show you
he wrote a Emacs package back in julian
assange oops that's not the one here
okay he's got several articles so
Richard Stallman went and met him back
in 2013 he is in the you know kind of
like in prison in the edge of quad or
embassy in United Kingdom since 2012 I
think Richard Stallman went and visited
him and they took a picture together and
Julian Assange is a Emacs user he wrote
he wrote a Emacs package for
manipulating windows you know frames
buffers back then back into 1998 or
before so you can see that people you
know special thanks to Julian Assange
for his change windows intuitively Dario
so he wrote that package
and another credit so you know another
evidence you can this is the same Julian
Assange as you know some people you know
question you know he said the same
Julian Assange yes it is so yeah it's a
sad story
you know so he to me okay
he you know shows you know disclose what
the government is doing nasty things
basically you know it discuss that to
the people and so back in you know in
2000 he was the enemy of us
conservatives you know because because
he exposed something about Iraq war
where you US military just kill people
basically but now he is hated by US
Democrats because you know because he
exposed hilari Clinton's you know evil
deeds you know so and and the thus
endeth so he went to a jerkwad or you
know to escape you know supposedly he
wait
you know he's under rape charges so what
are the charges actually I'm not gonna
talk about it here but you can you know
you can I have an article here I think
anyway if you if you such my article you
might see it I just tweeted it you know
in my Twitter recently so anyway so yeah
and he is seeing a bad shape now because
you know he haven't seen the Sun for
like seven years
that's serious you know you if you
cannot see the Sun I mean even in prison
you you have like every day you go out
and walk for you know 20 minutes or
something so yeah but but the thing is
the a jerkwater you know the president
has changed and there's a corruption you
know and you know if you are US
government or whatever you know you can
say hey we give you you know ten
billions or something you know you do
this as for us you know
and they are you know so it's seeing a
bad situation so thank you guys that's
it for today see you hopefully you see
you tomorrow and and you know and you
know if you like my walk yeah let me say
this if you like my work you know I got
patreon and Amazon and you know PayPal
you know you can put your money you know
for support thank you guys see you