foreign
welcome to another episode of sound talk
show so today I'm going to we are going
to call this stereographic projection in
wufam language so I'm going to explain
what it is and I'm going to show you how
to code it in Wolfram language
and those of you programmers I hope you
will do this either in Wolfram language
or in your favorite language in Haskell
in Julia in Python in skim lisp in Java
even or uh you know in or in JavaScript
with SVG or canvas whatever is your
favorite language I hope you'll do it
once you have uh you watch the video
you know learn something and instead of
just passively uh listening to
YouTube as an entertainment you know
actually start to
learn something code mathematics so this
is a
yeah so so Wolfram language uh if you
watch my video before you know that you
know you can have an entire tutorial on
Wolfram language uh you just go to
personally that info
and let's turn JavaScript
and you can see I've done many uh videos
on Wolfram language and there's also
lots of introduction so you go down and
you go down and you'll see this wufan
language so here's a whole tutorial and
where to download it for free it's you
know the Wolfram engine is free since
about three or four years ago so you can
download it and you can
or you can buy it you know buy the
Wolfram language if you buy the woofam
language then you get the notepad so
let's let me start the move from
language okay so start move from
language
[Music]
so this is going to be very fun you know
uh geometry and uh and by the way it's
it's easy it's it's not difficult at all
okay so
you know when you look at if you never
had uh geometry you know experience you
might think this is hard to do but
actually it's all it's pretty easy so I
hope you you know so you can download
rufan language and do it you know in Wu
fun language or you can do a JavaScript
in SVG so let me show you so I have a
SVG tutorial is very useful for
JavaScript for example you can learn
from the ground up SVG is very simple
it's just just
XML just like
um HTML files so for example if you
copy this and put in a text file and
open it in your browser it will show a
line so this is how you for example if
you want to draw a rectangle this is how
you do it basically just these three
lines you know and so on
and you and then you can write a uh you
know clock and that's just uh 50 lines
you know 59 so
so you can use SVG and the JavaScript to
do it if you already know JavaScript or
you can use canvas and so on so I hope
you guys do it so let me so let me show
you how you how do you code this it's
pretty easy okay so let me explain
so uh actually so let's let me write
down what what what we gonna do okay let
me uh so it's more organized Okay so
explain what is
stereographic
projection okay and
explain
how to code this the basic ideas okay
and okay showing browser so you can see
today's talk show explain what okay
explain how to code this the other basic
idea so you can code this in any
language it's pretty it's pretty easy
okay
uh let's see what else we want to cover
uh explain what is stereographic
projection and explain how to code it
and okay then maybe if we have time this
video is gonna be like 40 minutes or 50
minutes I hope no more than that
so then also explain
how to derive the function that the
projection function okay
how to derive the projection function
this so this is mathematics
okay so refresh okay that that's
basically what we want to do okay
um
explain what is a stereographic
projection explain how to code these the
basic ideas uh and explain how to
describe the projection function Okay so
you you know
um
it's pretty easy actually so all you
need let me let me explain so
stereographic projection I wrote this in
Mathematica in Wolfram language like
15 years ago in 2006 so you can see let
me explain what what this is okay
stereographic projection it's just a
projection so you given a plane you know
you have a grid you know given a grid or
any any point on the plane so you can
put a ball on top of the plane and from
the top of the ball the North Pole you
draw a line
to the point on the plane so this line
will cross the sphere at one point so
that is the projection so that is that
that gives you a for every point on the
plane you have a corresponding point on
the sphere
okay that's the key that's the essence
of stereographic projection
you know
given a plane
for any point on the plane you put a
ball first of all you put a ball on on
the plane in the center of the plane you
know you know the South Pole touches the
origin you know the center of the plane
then for any point on the plane you draw
a line from the North Pole to that point
this line will intersect the sphere at
one point so
so you have a correspondence so for
every point on the plan you have a
corresponding point on the sphere so
this correspondence is this
stereographic projection so this means
this means you can have any picture for
example a grid on the plane or even a
photograph or any drawing then you can
project it to the sphere and you you it
will appear in a different way okay so
that is the that is what stereographic
projection is so what what this is um
fundamental in mathematics truly useful
for example if you want to draw a map of
Earth Earth is round but you want to
draw a map on a paper so this is one of
the ways you know stereographic
projection is one of the way to draw a
map
so you can see and let me show you some
of the fun ones so you can start with
you know here we have a grid then on a
ball it appears like that
and here we start with this you know
decorative pattern this is uh you know
you can think of it as graph Theory or
networks not really graph Theory but
decorative you know so they project to
the sphere it becomes like that and you
can rotate it I'm gonna show you from
language okay
so if you start with this pattern you
get that beautiful and you can start to
get fancy if you start with this kind of
tiring random tiles then you got this
ball
and if you start with that you got this
Spore fat beautiful okay
so this is uh you know I I did a lot of
these for like 10 years
okay so uh any comments and questions
posted okay I love to see your question
hello immortality
uh and hello Dan
okay comments and questions about
related to these love to see it okay
uh okay so we explained stereographic
projection now how do you code this okay
now very easy actually easier than than
you think all you need first of all all
you need you need a graphical system
now in Wolfram language it's super easy
but in other languages for example in
JavaScript then you use SVG or canvas I
don't know about other languages but you
you probably know if you are a
programmer you can find out
so if so first of all you need a
graphical system to render to draw the
lines and curves and so you you know a
graphical library but the essence is
that
uh so you begin by drawing lines on you
know
this is what we are going to do you know
forget about the fancy ones you know
we're gonna start very simple just draw
this illustration a simple grid
on a plane
and project it to the sphere so
so first of all you draw the Grid on the
plane which is very easy you know for
example integer points those are the
coordinates then you have a function
that takes any point on the plane
as argument and returns a point on the
sphere you know Returns the coordinate
on a sphere so on the plane
you got you know normally you're playing
is just X and Y you know x axis Y axis
so you got a point X and Y now in this
case since we are doing this in 3D so
there's another component the Z
coordinate but in this case
they are just zero so imagine this is a
plane on the
Z equals to zero axis
okay so you got a plane
each point on the plane is three points
three you know coordinate of three
numbers x y and zero so then you have a
projection function that takes this
point x y and zero and return a
another three numbers that's the number
on a sphere okay so to draw to program
these so you have to do first of all
draw the grid then apply this project
projection function to every point you
want so you got a bunch of points on the
sphere so you end up have a you know you
end up with a bunch of points and all
you have to do then is just connect the
lines connect the lines on the you know
of the points on the sphere just as just
as the way you had you know you connect
the lines on the grid okay
so that is the essence of how do you
call this
in fact you can start to code it you
know in just about in your favorite
language you know if you are unsure
about how the formula you know it's very
simple all you need is the function that
Maps one point on the plane to the
sphere and this function you can easily
see the formula by just going to for
example
you know you can you can just go to
Wikipedia you know I'm going to cover it
today you know I'm going to talk as I
code but if you missed some information
or if you got confused you can
yeah who is my magnify key
okay so you can see here's the Wikipedia
on stereographic projection and then you
can see they explain
uh they give you formulas formulas so
you can just read it if you got confused
okay so now let's talk let's let's start
movement language actually let me show
you uh let's start to draw uh draw this
okay so
so I um so yeah so stereo so today's
talk show let's go to stereographic
projection page showing browser and
there is a Wolfram notebook I have wrote
this um
long ago okay let's open that so you are
looking at
this file sphere projection illustration
dot MB notebook so this is Wolfram
language or mathematica notebook
it looks like that you know you see this
is version seven this is like 15 years
ago so
you know this is how Wolfram language
looks like the source code and these
things are basically images these are
you know bitmap images uh
formatted in you know uffam notebook is
actually just text file so you can see
this is a bitmap image now those are
PostScript image here
but anyway so this is just a format of
the notebook let's open it okay let's
open it in Wolfram language there it is
stereographic projection let's magnify
okay and this is what we are going to
code continue with updated sliding yes
so you see 2006.
okay so you see this is so you first of
all you draw a grid then
then I I draw some you know colored
rectangle so to make this small apparent
how you know this illustration the
purpose of this image is to
visually illustrate visually demonstrate
what stereographic projection is you
know the power of visualization so when
people see this they already know but
what it is
okay so so I also draw some colored
rectangle so to make it apparent then
you
add add 0 to the z-axis Z coordinates so
they become three-dimensional so you can
see this is a bitmap image oh actually
it's a you know can you rotate no but we
we can later on okay then
then you just project it you know then
you become this
um
okay we don't I cannot rotate but but
let me show you okay so this is a final
image
okay and then
yeah then there's the other fancy ones
that's not here but um let's see are
they here somewhere and it's open
let's open this one let's see what it is
okay first of all make a backup
okay and open it
magnify 150 percent
so let's see what this one is
oh yeah so this is the um you know the
other ones uh fancy ones
let's see if we can make it
yeah this so this is pure bitmap let's
okay let's let's do it so first of all
you know I need
so this is written long ago and I used
one of my package transform 2D plot now
what so it's all building actually so
let me show you that package
so let's go to desktop
and the subwoof and packages
transform 2D plots and let's open it so
here is a package you can see
this is Wolfram language
code here is the in a
dark string for many of the functions
let's magnify
dark stream for many of the functions
then body then here starting here's a
code okay
here's a code you see
um
okay so it's all built in there but
let's just let's select all okay select
all
and evaluate it
okay evaluated shift enter evaluate this
okay
done
now this is one of my huge package I
spent half a year to draw this
um backing
2000s around so now you have once you
have this loaded
all you have to do is
um
see
stereographic will come
okay so now let's just evaluate the code
run it okay so here's a code graphics
and evaluate this part Bennett so I'm
drawing some colored rectangles
okay and when this fantastic
and
release okay starting now you can rotate
you have a
great
then this
and now you have the rectangles
I mean squares colored squares
run it
now you have
the color squares on the grid except
there's something changed so you know it
used to be color now it's black why
because
after 15 years there's some changing
Wolfram language that's why so you need
to remove this one lighting then
let's do it again there it is now you
have colored uh Square am I doing okay
check video check audio check yeah
okay
so comments okay so here you have the
colored square and Grid in 3D then let's
evaluate this part let's see oh yeah
then we started to draw the lines you
know the projection line is fantastic
you see in order to draw in order to do
these lines you see the endpoints of the
lines are the squares are the color
squares so and the beginning point of
the lines is the North Pole of the of
the sphere
so you can see here's a code array
graphics 3D
polygon line
patch graphics 3D
patch graphics 3D now what is patch
graphic oh these are patches okay yeah
so these colored rectangles I call them
patch graphics 3D
and the grid is called flow graphics 3D
then here
the patch graphic 3D
this means replace each polar gun
by
okay so this is kind of
well this is a very powerful Wolfram
language
um a pattern matching code so what
okay let me explain this one so what
what it is doing is that you take you
start with the patch graphics 3D so
patch graphics 3D uh
just these three rectangles you know
they
they are just uh
I can I can show you okay I can show you
patch graphics 3D so let's open a new
one let's put it here and let's magnify
[Music]
and let's evaluate it
and let's uh because it's a graphics so
that's why it shows like that
but you want to see the actual code so
what you can do is that you do that uh
you say length let's see how many items
are there one okay so they you
then you say first now slash slash slash
is the
so there it is slash slash is the post
fixed notation so you apply the first
function to this object first is just
return the first item
and essentially that just removes the
graphics head
um
if you don't understand it don't worry
about it so anyway so the basically it's
just a list of three polygons okay and
let me let me show you further so take
the first and take the first again
so you can see the first polygon and
and that green is actually a color you
see you see this little pop-up that's
actually the code is hue
um
is there a way to not show this but show
you the code well anyway let me let me
let's go further with this
yeah but it's it's not showing the code
I want to see I want to show you the
actual code
you see this green let me let me explain
this one the kind of the one of the
power of Wolfram language you see this
code let me show you okay let me just
type it
so this Hue function Hue function
reference represents a color just like
in CV in CSS cascading style sheet you
have RGB
right in
you know so let's see
let's see that
so if we go to the CSS you know the CSS
file and we
search for color let's go all the way
you can see
one of the way you specify color is by
by this way hsl parenthesis then
parameters values so let's how use one
of the way to specify color in CSS
so if you don't know you can you can go
to my tutorial okay I'm kind of
digressing but so you have many color
syntax but anyway here's how how you
represent colors in CSS okay by color
colon and the one of the value the value
can be your name color name or can be
kind of the hexadecimal
um format or it can be
you know it can be the RGB syntax or it
also can be hsl syntax so let me show
you so for example this is
this is a code you can see random color
you can see
you know so many many syntax in CSS to
represent a color
now in Wolfram language there is also
several ways to represent color one of
the ways by the Hue function okay so if
you say Hue 0.5
0.25 that's gonna be green so if you Q
goes from 0 to 1 so 0 is red okay so
when you evaluate it
it returns
you know it just returns itself you know
it's just a color Cube but however
the wolf Animal book renders it renders
it as a red square
just like
you know just like when you are in
you know CSS some of the editors renders
you know
colors put colors onto them so in the
same way we'll find language returns
that square
so for example if you want purple you
know it's a rainbow Hue is like the
rainbow color so purple is 0.9 around
there so if you do that okay 0.9
that's not purple enough let's say 0.8
okay so you can see you got the color
Hue so you can you can actually do a
range of colors we are digressing a lot
but let me finish this so Hue x x goes
from
a zero to one
in steps of 0.1 okay that will give you
a range of Hues basically the rainbow
color evaluated you can see
okay that's what Q is
uh actually we are digressing then the
polygon is just a bunch of is just um
so so the patch graphics 3D is these
squares
and uh
it's a list of three things each thing
is a list and in this list you start
with the color then you start with the
polygon function which represents the
polygon and inside you just
inside you see here just a bunch of
points okay
uh
yeah so
yeah
so why are we talking about this yeah
because I was trying to show you
how this works
uh
projection yeah so here you take the
bunch of colored polygon and you this
slash dot means pattern replacement okay
and the pattern you want to find is
anything polygon with anything anything
inside you know the inside polygon a
bunch of at least the points so you say
you want to find a pattern that begins
with the polygon square brackets and
anything inside and we give it a name
pts then we you want to replace it by
by a line
starting at 0 0 1 and ends
up at
okay you want it to be placed by this
expression this expression is mapping
this function to pts pts is bunch of
points in the polygon so
and what this means is a function that
Maps
this function to the points and this
function is basically a line starting at
0 0 1 and map it to that that particular
point so the result of this map
is a bunch of points I mean a bunch of
lines beginning at zero zero one to the
point so that's why
that's why you get this that's how you
get this
uh lines very very different programming
technique you see
you see by turning this thing
a bunch of squares into a bunch of lines
from one point to each of the squares
corner
just by this single line okay so anyways
then then
so okay so then let's evaluate this part
okay then this is a kind of the the
result of the sphere
um
then you also add
you add a grid to it to it
so let's remove the lighting
so now you get color yeah so there it is
okay
save it we are uh we've been running for
30 minutes we're kind of too slow we
want to start to get to the code okay
because I haven't
started coding
now the Java view you can ignore it this
this part is back then like 15 years ago
there is a Java applet that runs in
browser so that you can you can feed it
a Wolfram language code you know the
data points then you can see this thing
rotate in a browser
foreign
you know you can just rotate this in a
browser but Java applet is
dead in the browser it no longer works
so anyway so
so this is the package okay let's save
it now
what I want to do is start from scratch
okay now I can show you you know you can
see in this notebook everything is so
simple you don't see much you know lots
of code it seems so simple that the
reason I mean where is the projection
function like where is the function that
Maps one point on the plane to the
sphere you don't see it and where is the
where is the code to generate this grid
you see
to generate this squid that's the code
you know it's like it's like just one
line
but one of the reason is it's all in
this package okay so let's let's have a
look at the package for a little bit
okay transformation 2D plot so
so for example here is a usage for the
function rectangular grid
so all you have to do is just say
rectangular grid and let me let me do
this
all you have to do is just say
rectangular grid
and say x Min x max extend what I mean y
Max why step
that will return
the actual Graphics Primitives
so let me demonstrate so copy that
a new
notebook okay paste it there
okay run it so you see
a bunch of lines so that's what this
rectangular grid
a function do it just generate a bunch
of lines and how do you generate this
it's very easy you just like we did
before let me just say table
line for example line X
uh
so line you need
you need a list let's say X Y let's say
and this so line needs two points so x y
and x first one y plus one okay then you
say
x from 0 to 10 in steps of one okay then
you do the same thing for y
y 0 to 10 okay let's evaluate that you
see
that's how you get you know a bunch of
lines X and you know a bunch it's kind
of you have to
make sure this
you know is correct but that's
essentially what this
rectangular grid do you know it returns
a much bunch of lines but it has extra
it automatically you see added color to
each line
so this is fantastic
so you can see you can just run this and
get this um
let's say I want them thicker so
thickness okay
thickness let's see
0.2
okay it says 0.4
hmm
okay thickness
is not applying here for some reason
but anyway that's not important
um let's see increased graphics
resolution okay
so what what we want to do so that is
the function that is the function for
the rectangular grid okay
now that's how you generate this
rectangular grid
now what about
um
what about the actual
map into the sphere like where is the
code so that part is built I mean I it's
part of the package you see this
function
so let me let me make this easier to
read I hope let's see Ctrl shift n
okay it doesn't
see Ctrl shift T Ctrl shift n it doesn't
do much okay
so this code
so so this code
here is the important part this function
stereographic projection plot 3D
so you can let's look at the
documentation
you just type question mark and the
function name
then it tells you okay stereographic
projection plus 3D it takes three
arguments the first argument is playing
Graphics the second argument is R third
argument is C
shows a graphics 3D object that is the
input 2D Graphics stereographically
projected to a sphere of radius R and
above the orange and by C okay
so this is so
simple so let's just let's let's do
let's do it
okay so let's do it here
so let's let's see so you need we we
want to feed it
of flow Graphics okay
so that's the flow Graphics flow
Graphics is just bunch of lines like
this you know that's a great
okay then the second argument should be
a sphere radius
default to one and let's let's ignore
them
you see the second argument is R is the
radius of the sphere and above the
orange and by C so let's just run this
uh the T4 radius is half and the default
C is half okay it's the planet
okay not
uh yeah so
so it's not working why is it uh
let's see flow graphics 3D
now we have to see you see these parts
oh needs a 2d not 3D let's see so again
yeah so we feed it flow Graphics 2D not
3D so
do it fantastic you see how simple so we
didn't even have to code it you know
yeah but how does it work I mean the
problem with today you know actually we
wanted to actually code is not not using
a you know code already written so let
me show you okay stereographic
projection plus 3D okay
uh it's already 40 minutes uh
you know we can do this from scratch or
first of all let's look at the code okay
so the function is stereographics
projection plot 3D so the function is
here somewhere that here okay so here
is a code pretty simple let's see if I
can
copy the code
let's paste the code here and let's see
if I can predify it into a mathematical
rendering
yeah not much okay never mind
um DD did okay so
here is the code for the whole thing
okay and uh
let's see
so remember when we do this one of the
most important thing is the projection
function you know a function that takes
a point on the plane to the sphere okay
so we want to know where you know that
is the most important function that
function is here somewhere okay so let's
look at
there it is you see
stereographic project you see there is
that function so basically you can you
can kind of see you know the the code is
a bit complex but you can kind of see it
Maps this function to every point
you know from the points in the polygon
or points in the line so you start with
a
you know you start with a
whatever figure a plane figure that's
either polygons or lines
so each polygon or line
has
a bunch of you know line you know points
inside right
just just like this so for each point
you want to apply the function to that
point okay so that is what
this
uh this part is doing okay that
that is what they are
you see you use a pattern matching
you extract the polygon p is the points
in the polygon
and you once you got the point you apply
the function stereographic project
with that pointless argument and radius
of the sphere and the distance from the
plane see you know you apply this
function
at a specific level anyway the point is
that you just apply that function to a
bunch of points so now we want to look
up these functions stereographic project
so let's see
eventually it will just become
you know that function is basically just
this formula okay and Wikipedia so let's
look at that function okay
uh so what is this one okay let's
so
somewhere here
transformation Mobius transformation
okay uh
there is the function there it is
[Laughter]
fantastically
nicely rendered okay stereographic
project okay so given two points the
formula is
is that okay that
will agree
with wikipedias
um definition okay where's Wikipedia
so we keep PD essays that uh
anyway there's a lot of variations
depending on where you put the sphere
you know some
author put the sphere centered on the
plane some author put a sphere above the
plane like that so the formula will vary
but anyway so that's the code
okay that's it
um I think that you know basically we
cover it you know but
um
I'm thinking let's actually code it
walk through the package would be really
illustrative so we did you know we we
kind of did that uh I don't know if
that's helpful
okay so now any questions and comments
live people you guys say something so
now I'm thinking let's do it from
scratch I hope I can maybe I can finish
in 10 minutes if I really do it fast
like from scratch no need you know
from scratch let's do a really basic you
know this image okay let's let's do it
okay so let's do this so open unit we
need to do this really fast I want to
finish this okay so
so first of all let's let's
um it's not it's um the code seven
so
that's kind of the title that's not what
we want uh so
old age
this is a text this is a comment okay so
so Wolfram notebook is just like
um Oak mod if you use emacs you might be
familiar with Oak mod so you can have
title you have different headers you you
can have
um uh texts and so on
so what we I what I want now is to let's
see sales
of these format style sheet
um
styles
oh old seven is text so this part should
be old seven
all seven is
text okay so what I want to do now okay
let's do this
hopefully quickly hope you know
so what I want to do is geographic so
first of all
draw a grid okay
that's a bunch of lines then
Define the projection function
F okay then map the projection function
map
the map F2 or grid points
okay that's essentially what we want to
do so first of all draw the grid okay
so um
so we need to code this quickly now
let's go back to emacs because I can
type much faster in emacs okay so what
is this CSS index stereographic position
close so here is today's talk show and
go back and let's start a Wolfram
language here so I'm using wolf and mod
star wolf and mod if you just search for
it you will find it okay
uh let me show you so subwoofer mod you
just go to this URL so this mod allows
you to code Wolfram language in emacs
and it's on GitHub okay so you can get
it
okay so so let's code it so we want a
table
of lines
not tab
so we want uh so we want the bunch of
lines how do you
so we want the lines so let's see from 0
to let's say 10
X
x 0 to 10 okay
um so first of all so table needs two
arguments the first one is expression
line
okay line needs two point P1 and P2 okay
now the first point will be X
so X is starting from 0 so X
yeah X moves you know and Y is all zero
so here is X Y is all zero and what's
the end point uh the end point is going
to be
so this actually negative five to five
negative five to five
the end point the P2 is again two points
so
the end point is let's see
start there
so start at
X
so here should be negative five
and the end points is five okay X and uh
five okay so that is
uh grid points okay so that is uh grid
points I think
copy that
so now we need to yeah so
paste it run it okay you got a bunch of
lines so you can show it show
Graphics 2D
Graphics yeah that and add
grid points okay
fantastic that's all that's our vertical
lines okay now you want horizontal you
want horizontal lines
you know actually I know there's a
problem already because when you draw
lines like that you have endpoints you
know you have for each line you only
have two end points right then
then when you apply the transformation
you know the function map it to a sphere
you only got two points to work with
so you don't have you don't have all the
points in between the lines you know the
grid points
so that's not good so what will end up
is just the edges on the sphere
okay you see what I'm saying but
let's do that let's just do that okay
for now so that's a great point so
actually great points uh
vertical line itself so this is actually
vertical lines
okay this is aha
horizontal lines
okay horizontal lines is gonna be
uh lots of you have to think a lot
are you able to grab the code for
truncated isocahedron instead
of course how would that take things off
track
grab the code for what do you mean grab
you can do it in one minute truncated
isocahedron because that's so common
that's been done a thousand times you
just go to Wolfram website you just
search for wufan you just search for
Mathematica truncated isocahedron in the
library this
actually and and it's actually just
building there's a building but you know
that's a different topic it's not let's
let's focus on this one
so so now you want to you know uh
horizontal lines okay so horizontal
lines you want to
um we can combine these two actually so
I don't know so let's just try that I
don't know maybe this will probably work
okay
okay show
actually graphics
okay at
okay we got horizontal lines now you can
combine them
okay combine them
uh
okay let's let's define them
okay what is this uh
Microsoft
something
so there is your lines and now you just
combine them by
give them a list okay so
vertical lines and horizontal lines
there it is and then you can
show grid
grid lines automatic okay
uh actually we don't want grid lines we
want
um
we want frame
uh actually we
close to
we want yeah that's what we want we I
want the ticks so you can see easily see
we got we got our lines now we got the
lines now you we we now let's define the
projection
function okay let's define the
projection function we just copy the
code here
easy
yeah it's because that function this
function you can just get it from
Wikipedia okay
so yes Wikipedia you know you change you
can just copy it when Wikipedia and also
well we can actually derive this formula
okay this formula is actually easy easy
to derive if you know trigonometry okay
but let's not do it today we don't have
time
okay so projection function uh let's say
project F okay so actually
okay that's that's our function project
f
let's see uh yeah in C uh okay yeah so
okay
that's our projection function okay now
let's test
uh projection function and let's test
give it a point
let's say 0 0 it should be returned zero
zero because the ranger map sorry you
see it becomes a three-dimensional
engine okay so let's say
one one okay one one
Okay so
the point one one on the plane will be
the point that point on the sphere okay
that's a projection function now all you
have all we have to do is we have to map
okay
so we're gonna do
what we're gonna do is this okay
okay butterflies horizontal lines okay
make at least a list of them then you to
replace okay that means replace uh let
me show you in the more understandable
syntax
okay so replace all is the thing is the
function we want to do let's kind of pet
a matching let's show you the
documentation so
here's a documentation for replace all
uh you see it just takes uh it takes an
expression and a bunch of rules and
transform that expression let me show
you so so replace or takes two arguments
the first argument is the expression
which is a list of the vertical lines
and horizontal lines and the second
argument is how you want to transform it
and the way you do it is you say a rule
okay actually you say root delayed
okay rule delay takes two things one is
the pattern
a pattern matching a pattern you want to
match so in this case we want to
uh so um
and the second argument is what you want
to replace by Okay so
so the first argument is um
horizontal lines so for any so we want
to
[Music]
points so we want to say pts is a bunch
of points and the pattern will be line
okay so this is a pattern this means
anything
that's a line okay and uh
actually let's do it this way
Okay so
yeah so so this means this is a this is
this this means a pattern of a line and
inside it is anything and we name it X
points okay and we want to map it too
let's let's put it here
let's make them easier to see okay
so
okay the second argument for root
degrade is what you want to replace by
so in this case we want to replace by
line and inside will be using the
projection function okay projection
function to
map to
X points okay
that
do you see what I mean you know so so
this line is actually can be written
more easier to understand if I just
write it as
second
okay so we want to map the projection
function to
points okay so this
this line and this line are equivalent
just syntax differences so let's let's
use that
okay so let's try if it works
let's do
fantastic
one shot it works you see originally our
lines vertical lines and horizontal
lines are two dimensional lines you know
each point is just 2 I X and Y
coordinates now it's three because there
are now three dimensional and a sphere
so all you have to do is Show graphics
of these things so let's do it
you know we can just do it so here is
the
uh
graphics
g3d okay g3d wait
G
x g 3D okay let's just say that equals
to it's assign it to a
to a variable so we can refer to it xg3d
okay now let's just put graphics
3D
and give it an argument xg3d
wrong
oh wait is it
how is it
so
why is it wrong
uh let's see map project to the points
but um
so we got this bunch of lines Why is it
wrong I don't know
but uh I'm getting tired
he's here because uh formula is
incorrect
foreign
[Music]
let's try is it because our phone
formula is incorrect so if you have 100
what happens 100 100.
foreign
that's a point very far away
very far away
and so if you have a point very far away
you should
have
the resulting point should be very close
to the North Pole
so this number should be very close to
the North Pole that's right because you
see the Z coordinate here
is almost one
and this number here is almost zero X
and Y becomes
almost zero almost zero and the Z is
almost one so very close to the North
Pole so the formula projection function
is correct
but
um but why are we getting this this is
actually probably expected okay actually
that's probably even correct so let's
just do this again let's clean up the
code and let's do this again
okay so so let's clean up the code so
that's what we need
so let's put the semicolon
here
put put this in my colon here put the
semicolon here and
okay it's
okay that's that's a lot of code that's
all there it is so now
let's delete all that
okay and paste this code
do it
wait why is it
why is it not showing graphics
oh not graph graphics 3D not craft 3D
okay let's do it again
paste over do it
okay don't worry let's fix it now let's
say uh
in increment of zero point
five okay let's say increment
X increment equals to 0.2
okay
uh
uh there so here
here okay copy that
foreign
what is this
oh we got we got uh yeah we got a
syntax era or something
coordinate cell context
to your triple of numbers okay
what
okay there is something wrong
let's add some clear coat clear the
variables X ink
okay let's select all
paste just do it okay so there's
something wrong let's see let's figure
out
X and Y and uh oh yeah so we got extra
zero here idiotic so select all paste
run it fantastic okay now increment
0.1 okay
fantastic we got this patch now
now let's look carefully
actually that may be the correct result
yes that's the correct result because if
you look carefully when you have large
you know when you have points that's far
away from the center of the plane then
they become mapped to the like very
small patch at the near the North Pole
so our code is actually correct
so now we just need to modify the yeah
so let's do Max and mean
X found X
let's say bound okay X
boundary
um
let's just say x this okay
name is uh problem
s okay X length equals to one okay and
uh increment 0.2 okay so X length is
going to be let's say two okay
so this instead of five let's just
replace by X length okay
you place five by X length
okay copy the whole
select all paste open it
yeah I think that's closer
but still incorrect yeah remember the
reason
we don't got the sphere because we we
don't have many points to work with
so so now let's let's work on the
horizontal lines because we only have
the boundary of the points we don't have
the points inside
so now we it's just work on the boundary
I mean the let's draw the actual grid
so instead of so now instead of these
two code let's just simplify with one
code
we can do
um a lot with just one single table so
single table
needs
two arguments the first argument is a
expression the second argument is the
increment so actually we need two
increments
X and Y so
X
and the Y
X length y length Okay so and the
expression should be
instead of a line we got the list of
lines okay so list of lines so this will
be
so let's let's
okay so X
first
this will be
X starting from that to that
and the increment will be
X
here will be X
Plus
X increment okay
oh actually
here we'll be X and Y and here will be
X first increment
and Y plus increment okay
so
and
okay and
that's our new code okay so we don't
need that
so you say x lines
okay x squared
so this is a great
okay and now when you apply replace all
instead of the lines you can just say
grid okay it's hope it works one shot
blind coding
because
I know what I'm doing okay
Okay so
so something wrong okay so line X and Y
line requires at least the points so x y
X Plus increment y plus increment
so X and Y are variables
yeah so here you need
X increment okay
select or paste then
okay still no good because table
yeah that's okay oh syntax wrong extra
comma
idiotic oil paste again
hopefully this is looking fantastic
fantastic
fantastic okay but we are missing
we are missing the horizontal
yeah okay so uh wait this is what this
is actually
uh actually we got diagonal lines so we
actually need to draw so let me show you
actually our lines is diagonal that's
incorrect so I can show you by
okay
so select or paste run it
you see this is that's why it's
not correct that we got diagonal lines
but it's still pretty
so we got the reason we have diagonal
lines because of this here is incorrect
Okay so
so you you this is when you actually you
have to just think
um
yeah so actually so five more minutes we
should be able to finish it so
so the table x squared
one of the easy way to fix this is just
um
um let's say x squared y grid okay so
the x squared
X increment
[Music]
okay
so the Y grid
kind of like that okay and here
Graphics x squared and Y grid let's show
them both
okay and here you want to transform it
to that okay copy all
select or paste run it
okay
page down page down page down page down
big huge chunk of things fantastic
beautiful done
finally
huh fine finally holiday a Merry
Christmas
okay uh anyone still watching okay five
loyal watches so we we did it okay now
let's
um
we did it okay let's compact the file
the code
and wait no this is compact fighter code
compact by the code so you know here's a
kind of code
and uh and okay let's not show this uh
output
okay
now copy all select or paste okay and
let's make them
pretty you know rendered in math formula
okay so let's run it so there it is okay
um and then of course you want to draw
the lines but that
um we already know how to do it it's
just more tedious okay so Wolfram
language okay guys wufan language you
just how many lines of code five
how you can do this okay I hope
you know I hope you guys learned
something about how do you code
stereographic projection and so I again
I hope you guys you know go out and do
it you know with Haskell or Julia
whatever your favorite lens favorite
language go land just find a graphical
system of your library of your language
and
and show me the code okay you can show
it on my Twitter or on Discord because I
Discord you just search for xani Twitter
because I need Discord you'll find it
okay fantastic bye guys if you like my
you know don't you know if you like my
stuff donate okay just go to my website
saudi.info uh at the bottom patreon me
Amazon me okay pay for me
bye guys
so we shut down in one minute so now
let's put the code back in the browser
so here's today's talk show
you know and let's
syntax code go to the browser refresh so
here's the Wolfram language
code to do this from scratch you know
doesn't need any package then you you
know we can get fancy and then
so what is is do we still need yeah we
so that's a code so we can get fancy and
uh
and have a bunch of the other
things shown in the browser okay so yeah
let's shut down bye guys