streaming
hello welcome to another day of excel
talk show
so today we are going to do Advent of
code number five in emac bisp
so a defend of code number five okay so
we did Advent of code day five in wufam
language before so this is a page on
Windows code day five so the problem
is given this input those textual
Graphics indicates boxes so you have
boxes stacked on top of each other and
and your task is to follow some
procedure to move them you know so
that's a problem we're gonna but this
time we're gonna do it in emac lisp okay
emac this okay so let's begin so this is
a requested from requested from
um
from our friend Jacob L
so yeah so the band of code Xavi scored
if you have not already joined and uh
preferably use your real name and real
profile photo so because we want to talk
about real life stuff we don't want
memes Chan you know you know we don't
want cabbage so
if you join uh you know talk about real
life stuff your friends your work your
family real life not the typical website
rated I can use whatever you perhaps
talk about
personal okay so anyway so today coding
emac this we're gonna do this problem
secondary account hello uh yeah email
address so and uh so if you don't know
already you know I'm gonna tell you my
keyboard this one I'm promoting them
because they sent me one and I love this
keyboard you know really so you go to
sorry search for ergonomic keyboards
review Sardi and you'll find
um
expose okay
while I'm talking about this I recommend
you know Kinesis Advantage I've been
using for five years
but now I'm changing for a change you
know I switch back anytime uh and
Kinesis 360 is also excellent and this
glove 80 is also I recommend excellent
okay
not so much more Tron because you know
this thing is five five hundred dollars
you know you have to take the
cast into consideration so so and uh and
right now I'm using this exposed night
fantastic okay you go buy it not
expensive okay I recommend it I don't
get I don't get money if you buy it
because this one is not on Amazon but
you know they have semi prototypes since
like four years ago since they begin so
and I truly love this keyboard so you
know this I'm only saying the things
true opinions the things I love okay and
this one is also I discovered this one
about last month and this Alice layout
is also great because it turns out you
know they have less stagger so this is
Alice layout with less Wonderland
Alice without much Wonderland this is
Alice they are very interesting naming
of things because Alice you know the
reason this kind of layout is called
Alice is because it's like
it's like it doesn't make sense you know
you know first you know it's split
but then the left hand side uses you
know I mean the it has staggered you
know it still keeps the traditional so
it's kind of like weird
Alice like Alice in Wonderland
so anyway so this is uh my friend my
long time my old YouTube Watcher Zoom
well
Zumba Ben he's also he's he's a keyboard
collector so he has a lot interesting uh
keyboard and he sent me photos of it
you know let me put down my website so
so anyway Alice layout it's uh
so I discovered this one okay so
uh and you know so many so many to
choose from
let's go back to other keyboard so
this is great this is kinesis Advantage
great and this is 360 grade glove 80
great I recommend exposed great I
recommend Apple maker Alice layout I
recommend
Israel this this is also fantastic it's
but it's over 500 so you know
uh this no not good okay got several
problems and then the more common ones
okay
and then there's also some of these
anyway so that's about keyboard let's do
let's do the emac this coding of Advent
of code okay so let's begin doing that
that's the main topic About Today Show
in browser today's talk show fantastic
let's let's do the problem
hello Louise good morning
yeah you know we haven't done emac this
for a while
any advice on some of the best ways to
protect IPO especially for independent
events well that's
I don't know much about that okay you
won't protect your IP basically you
cannot
actually if you want if you want me to
give you one sentence summary about how
do you protect your IP you're talking
about IP address right basically the
answer is no you cannot any website you
visit
you it will be known by CIA by FBI by
Google by Apple any website you visit
doesn't matter you oh oh but I know I
know onion but I know uh you know the
the
the private Network you know that's all
okay
every website you visit
keep in mind that everybody knows
everybody those who wanted to know they
know okay there's no way around it
uh okay so
basically okay you you know gets into
complicated detail
okay let's get on the topic okay so
event Advantage of code Let's uh visit
the problem because I forgot we have to
go to the problem
Advent of code day five okay
oh I still have it logged in so day five
oh yeah so we last time we stuck on day
seven but anyway so let's do day five
day five
um
the problem okay so you got this input a
text each column indicates a stack of
boxes
the problem okay so what is the problem
there are three stacks okay stack one
okay so let's put here so you can see
stack one contains two crates okay then
you arrange you uh
so you have a crane that moves moves
these boxes but you can only move one at
a time
so and what is the problem
the Second Step uh okay so oh yeah so
you are given you know these Stacks but
you are also given this procedure
so sample input so let's actually
get it to emacs Okay so
[Music]
you know at the end of code it problems
are
kind of
um
so input
input is like that that okay so you have
the stack of boxes but you also have
this procedure you know move one
move uh
went from two to one so move one box
from column two to column one then move
three bugs
from column one two three so but each
time you can only one move one box
so this basically so when you see move
three that means repeat it three times
okay so you given this procedure then
you have to follow this procedure then
your output is your output
your the answer should be
which boxes you know what what order of
the boxes is in column one and column
two and column three and so on wait is
that true
now they the they just want to know
what's the top uh
the topmost Box in each column is that
right
so let's see
so the elves needs to know which crate
will end up on top of each stack okay
in this example so so the yeah so the
output should be
just a string of letters
the first character is the topmost Box
in column one the second character is
the topmost Box in column two so that's
that's the problem
okay so let's do this in e-max Okay so
so in emacs okay big let's begin with
the you know uh
with the sample input okay
so let's begin text okay so this is the
input this is today's ribbon so let's
code in e-max
so so first problem okay so let me let
me tell you what we're gonna how we're
gonna
do this okay
emac bisp
so
so first of all uh okay it's probably
easier just to do it than just then
talking about it
okay so let's begin the emac this code
okay so here is the input and
you can assume it's a string
oh uh e e magnis you have the different
you know the nested parenting syntax
okay hold on a second so let's move this
uh
okay so set input X input
to this string okay so that's the input
so first of all
first
split the input into two
Parts okay
input one
input two okay set input 1
okay so what we so we're gonna do a
split Okay so
split
okay there's three string
okay split stream
uh
so we want to split the string X input
by separators
which is two
new line character okay
do we want to Omit numbers no we don't
care about that okay so
uh
so this we're gonna create a variable
input
Parts okay
so set input Parts equals to that okay
then set input
so we get input
part one
okay equals to uh
input to uh
string split that returns a
a list
I think let's see what it returns
on it by match separators uh simulator
so
speed string two substrings bounded by
yeah but what is the structure
uh I think it's at least okay we can do
it okay just okay evaluate that part
okay and evaluate that part
yeah so we have a list of two strings
okay so the first part
um
uh you can say
um and stupid e-magnetism okay so X
input part
and zero okay
that's how you get each part
uh
one okay
now before we do this let's change the
variable names okay
um
input parts
[Music]
stack
boxes text okay
let's change the name to something
that's more intuitive
and uh
procedure
okay so we got these variables okay now
evaluate it evaluate that evaluate that
okay
now let's go to the messages buffer
uh
what is this yeah let's see let's
evaluate
um
let's see the variable yeah that's the
variable X boxes text okay and uh
describe variable procedure
that is correct okay so split them split
the input now what's the next step now
we want to basically this visual stack
we want to make each of them
you know the
each of the colon into a
into a list
so in lisp
lists is a suitable data structure for
stack
a stack is like a is a data structure
in computer science and what does stack
mean is just like a stack of books where
you can add new items to the top and you
can remove one item from the top and
that's the only two procedure you can do
to a stack so you know like a stack of
books so that's a computer science data
structure okay and to represent that
structure in this we want to use a list
okay so we want to turn basically this
text into
several lists each list represents a
column okay so any comments questions
say it okay
oh you are talking about intellectual
property best way to protect
intellectual property well never go open
source okay never
to open source again that's complicated
okay
um
there's a
you know you can patent it yes things
like that but uh because but the open
source has has corrupted the entire
industry so if you want to protect your
intellectual property
of code
well good luck basically it's very hard
to do you know the open source phonetics
they will steal your code
by by all means you know I mean it
doesn't matter if you are a commercial
company like the Hollywood they produce
movies you know the open source Fanatics
by day they say oh we are for the
prosperity like the richest well you
know they are for the prosperity of
society everything you must share by
night there's still Hollywood movies you
know the
the rip the that's a website you know
that's what they do
and by day they work for proprietary
corporations like Google Apple Facebook
you know they release some code that's
open source but actually their money
money cow is not none of it is open
source you know for example Chrome web
browser the open source buckets that we
will say oh Google Chrome is open source
open source not really you know like the
Microsoft vs code well yeah the core is
open source but good luck if you really
want to build it you know the actual
cream is not open source
so you have the you know they they the
corporations took over
uh you know using this open source and
the open source phonetics by day they
work for this Google they make a lot of
money Google Apple Twitter including
Facebook you know by Night they've seen
the zones of Open Source they put they
Chung out
open source stuff on GitHub
so what happened so so it rubs if you
don't if you are a good person you don't
work you know for this
one thousand lower your patent
corporations but you you have no way to
survive the only way is you you go off
for Google this open source it you
know putting their stuff on GitHub okay
that's what I say
in the cycle you know they they they lie
to themselves they think oh oh Twitter
is proprietary oh this code is
proprietary I'm going to use some you
know open source some some some some
some stealing you know Rob Rob the
protocol you know they create their open
source version using Discord but this
the score doesn't want you to do that
but anyway they do it anyway
because they think oh open source you
know what happens if this code went out
of business therefore blah blah blah
blah blah but in the end what really
they want to do is they want to steal
they want to reap the advantage whatever
good things you offer but they don't
want any pay they don't want to pay they
don't want to whatever
and then
discussed you know Discord is not open
source but lots of other things they
sold out you know they became they sold
out to a commercial entity you know like
like Java to Oracle and you know endless
history
then you know then these people they the
cycle you know repeats like the open
Office you know and then become star
office my SQL it's still open source
they've got you know endless stories but
uh they don't listen they you know it's
pretty bad situation
so what I support I want you know let's
go back to proprietary
companies who who never have any
controversy about stealing about you
know nasty things okay you trust people
you pay you pay for whatever they do pay
me okay pay me for you if you like my
YouTube pay me
that you pay for the services and as
soon as they did something nasty like
they they created hidden code that grabs
your information you know something like
that then you then that you know you you
you you get them have the
use law
get them to jail okay no there's no
leniency okay so if Apple for example
Apple they sell you know phones then
they when they whenever they have a new
phone they put code so that your phone
becomes slower
that's a crime okay when that happens
the head of CEO of Apple go to jail
it's not like oh Apple did something bad
therefore I'm gonna use Android no
you want the app or CEO to go to jail
okay not not penalty of 1 million two
million that's peanuts okay that's one
percent of what they do what they did
okay that's what that's what your
mentality should be
Trust
you know trust and integral the person
the CEO whatever and including yourself
integral if you truly believe in open
source open source or free software
Foundation fine but then you should
never steal Hollywood movies and when
you see those website you know Pirate
Bay report them okay if you that's
that's actually you truly and and you
should never work for proprietary
company
do that okay if you do that you are
great and I believe you're open source
you know I myself I I would say free
software Foundation reaches snowman
fanatic
uh 20 years ago
okay anyway let's go back to
emacs okay so uh so that so so we got
the we split now we want to turn this
into a um
uh uh at least each column needs to be
at least okay so first of all we we want
to pass each line okay
so but before we do that let's let's try
to get a um
more
complete
um input
so that we can see
you know this is a example of a bigger
input okay so each column
so first of all we need to
so right now we want to turn this text
into
so that each column becomes a list of
things okay but there's no way to
directly get the column so we so what we
do is that we take each line
and we pass it into a list then we want
to do a kind of like a matrix
transposition so column becomes rows
rows become columns okay uh that concept
is very firm is very well known in if
you do linear algebra uh so in Wolfram
language that's there's a building
function transpose okay but you cannot
do it in emac this you have to write it
so I don't think you know so that will
take some time so anyway so let's pause
this
so each line is like that so we each
line you can notice that each character
each box is four characters okay so we
want to split the line into
by every four characters okay split the
line by every four characters okay
so let's go back oh God I don't know how
long this will take
per line
into four charts
into a list of four charts something
like that okay so this is the boxes text
we want to process process this okay
so you want to split the string so first
of all
um yeah Max is okay
uh
[Music]
okay let's go let's use elaborate long
name so first of all so you want to
yeah so least so you want to first of
all
speed stream
Split That by
okay
so by new lines so now we got a list of
lines okay so this is a
this is a list of lines okay let's do it
do it okay let's describe variable
that's right that's right okay so you
have a list of lines okay
so now
for each
for each of the least elements
we want to
you know each each element is a line of
string we want to um we want to
split again
by every four characters okay
okay so you map
you map
this function to that list okay so what
is what is the function so the function
every four characters every four
characters okay every four characters
how do you do that I don't know so let's
look up let's look up
uh
all the stream functions in emac disp
okay so this Basics string functions
let's see if there's a building function
I don't think so
a speedy string
string two number speed string string
optional separators
hot any any comments questions
Okay so
let's focus okay so split
by four
so regular Expressions can we use
regular Expressions regular expressions
foreign
functions let's see mainstream so we
have a stream
for every car every four characters you
want to make it push it uh as a element
so
okay so this is this problem is actually
fairly complicated a lot to do
uh string call late less p
and whatever
string distance
associate string
so is Jacob Jacob are you here
Jacob
Jacob kind of requested this
Jacob asked me to do this okay so
contact a pen by two string down case
said case so all these are case so I
don't think there's a building function
let's see
a string
you want to split it
by every four characters
so there are a few ways to do it
let's think about it again so every four
characters
uh
don't case the paint string to char
a Google user hello I'm not here for
programming and work working on my own
project but I hope that everyone here is
having a good day hello
Google user so
let me think about it so we can use
regular expression though
okay so first of all first of all we
want to know
we want to know the number of columns
okay that's easy that's the last element
and the last number so let's let's set
number of columns
okay
set q and that would be
the
last okay
okay there is no so last
item of that
okay then you have to do car car which
is a idiotic disciples so basically this
will get you the last line
of these boxes okay then once you have
that you want to split string again
you want to split by y space okay
separators white space
one or more
uh and you don't want I mean oh I mean
more so split string
of that thing okay that's what you want
number of columns okay so if I evaluate
this you see
wait so wait
so you get the last item car then you
split it by yeah then you split by a
space then you want to get the last
again
yeah one two three four five now you
want to get the last so yeah so you
again you want to do car
last
okay essentially that's the code okay
let me
clear it this way it's easier to see
let's make it X Okay so
let's evaluate that okay done and now
let's describe variable
so I do is three correct okay
so we got number of columns now
okay now
so now we go back to the split each line
problem so
so given a line you want to split every
four characters how do you do that
every four characters
there's many ways to do that okay
every four characters must be an element
in a list okay if you know how to
uh use wire with substring okay so
that's a recommendation from Louise okay
yeah we can do that while with substring
yeah there are many ways okay so we can
also put it into a buffer you know for
example
you know suppose we have that
open a new buffer we can create a temp
buffer and let's say
um you know let's say this is a line so
we just move closer one two three four
then we grab you know but for substrate
no properties zero one two four
you delete that you grab that then you
DD region that then you got that
then you can push push to a um
thing okay so that's one way so okay so
let's do the while loop
uh you know we can which way is easier
so okay let's do wire Loop because while
loop is more traditional to programming
languages
instead of you know the buffer text
processing okay so while loop
so yeah so so while so let's say
so we have to give a example string
let's say that
okay let's uh temp
okay let's say let's work on that
you know just to test okay so suppose
this is a line
while
temp length okay
equals to
uh is not e not equals to zero okay
so well it's not equals to zero
uh
this will be slower because every time
you
process a string a string in emacs it's
slower than if you
actually have the texting a buffer you
know just move closer and deal with
buffer
uh yeah but let's push on okay
so uh
so where that temp is not that okay so
push
so you got
so you got to push so let's remove that
while
push
let's say exodused
and this is this part will be a
substring
substring okay
okay substring
uh substring let's say x temp so strings
X temp
from
from zero
yeah index start with zero to
four
but you also want to delete
okay so so you do that then you want to
say
modify
so this is not functional programming
because you are trying to modify this
thing
so set X temp equals to
this code
this time is from 4 to the end
let's save that okay
let's see if that's right
so you need to
so
okay so you also need that
okay we have lots of you know local
variables here
which is not good because they are
Global variables okay but suppose
so right now it's Neo so empty list is
near we start with Neo empty list
so here will be that okay
so let's double check well not equal
length
so when the length of 10 string is not
zero
you take the substring the first four
characters you push it into temp list
then you reset the temp string
by taking the last okay so if we do this
let's hope it's not infinite Loop okay
let's evaluate that to show the pink
window evaluate that the pink window
shows all my command course and the
keystrokes in command course okay then
now let's evaluate this let's hope the
Emax doesn't go into Infinite Loop okay
do it
okay that's done now let's move to
templist and describe variable let's see
what's the value
okay double check okay incorrect
okay we got something incorrect there
one two three four four characters so uh
why is it incorrect
so c t wait
what
substring
what so the first substring we got is
that
what is that
it's taken from the last so yeah it
seems this oh this is reversed okay this
is reversed we got reverse it yeah
idiotic
because we are using a push you know you
push to the front so
reverse
I believe there is a reverse
um
list okay which it reverses the order of
at least reverse sequence that's right
so
we want to imperative programming
imperative programming
lots of modifications of the
we don't want to do that we we you know
it could well but emac this is not
that much functional
anyway that's Fusion so we don't want to
end up three hours like the other other
days okay so now we reverse it uh avoid
variable reverse what oh
this part should be that okay evaluate
it
now it's correct let's see
no it's not correct uh
what is this
one two three four oh that's correct
okay one two three four then one two
three four okay
now wait which one are we working on we
are working on this one
one two three four one two three four
one two three four okay then one
then okay so the r part
Okay so
maybe off by one Arrow Maybe maybe so
and let's try again
so actually let's use a lead
okay so we move this to a lead group
because that's one unit that's one
semantic unit
so we have now temp variables okay
that's this is just for testing okay
it's
let's do it again
okay let's see
one two three four
no this is not right okay so this should
be four
uh this is four let's try that do it
again
debugger entered arcs out of range
let's simplify okay
let's just simplify okay so let's see
where did we debug the enter and why is
let's see substring uh documentation
okay
substring form two
now
they are inclusive right
like
if you say one
to two it includes the one index
character in Two index character okay
return new string whose contents are
substring of string the return string
consists of the characters between index
form inclusive and index 2 exclusive
I hate this kind of thing this is
zero based idiots
like like the python
okay exclusive
okay so the exclusive this uh it means
just uh you you do it five then yeah so
the first part is inclusive the second
part is exclusive you know people will
argue well but actually this way is more
easier mathematically something that's
that's that's idiotic
like the C C plus plus coders they will
say that
okay let's try again
okay we really need to think about this
okay so actually substring oh yeah this
is
so
this is four remember it begins
inclusive let's do it again
yeah
uh args are out of range what what is uh
oh okay so actually
one two three four one two three four
one two three four yeah so you need
actually so this is like a tricky
yeah tricky problem okay so
yeah so let's do it again
get out of that
oxide of range you want to
okay maybe our logic is wrong
helps use one always substream okay
uh
I don't want to get stuck you know
you're just gonna
watch me suck on this
okay we need to think instead of just um
let's just say
okay so wait and you need to think okay
it can just keep going
so
so you're gonna stream
so but our problem is right now with the
uh
one two three four so zero two five is
correct I believe
um but
so we do that one time then two wait how
does it one two three
four okay
so the next round start with one two
three four okay and then
one two three four then one two one two
three four okay then the last round we
should have still
four characters left
one two three four
yeah
so we should still have four characters
left so why is it out of range
uh wait uh set
substream from the fourth this part is
wrong I think so substring
of zero indexed what
zero
one
zero one two three what wait one two
three four
so basically you want to take you want
to remove four characters okay
um you want to remove four characters
yeah the easiest way is just to actually
do this
one two three four five okay so if you
do that you get five so that is the
correct code
here
is that right so let's try you know ABC
you know yeah that's the correct code
and what about this what about this part
let's let's let's
okay
this part is incorrect
oh yeah because zero based zero based
okay
yeah okay so that is correct now let's
do you should be should work fantastic
okay now the you look the answer so each
one got an extra character
so each one got extra character then uh
yeah before you push
before you push you want to trim stream
trim string
okay uh
okay so this part okay trims uh string
trim
uh
but where is the string trim function
you know stream stream
is not
you know it's added string trim Okay so
I think in Emax 28 it's poding you don't
have two
Falcons I think something wrong with my
it's describe function string trim yeah
it's building
but
I don't got the completion because my
emac this
mod error I think
okay I need to add that anyway string
trim
then you put that here okay
that okay let's try it again
fantastic Okay so so this is how you do
and this extra thing we need to do we
need to make sure these um
you know given a string
like that we we want to make sure we
want to pad
space at the end just in case the input
you know we just truncate it I mean
we want to make sure the string is in
multiples of four Okay so
so pad Jesus
the emac this because if you want
to pad string you have to
you have to require that okay
then
let's search for pad
what
stream people where is the string pad
string equal and string compare string
string substring no properties
plank string remove prefix remove suffix
stream trim right left
oh God
too bad uh don't tell me I have to write
a own phone function
maybe you have to use format very
annoying
emac disp
Ute let's
um
control U
describe function and control you
a purpose okay let's search for pad
right variable okay
common padding search for string
comma and Pad right common string pad
now
stream pad is in sub sub-rex
oh I don't have it on my page
I missed
okay so anyway so stream pan let's go
back so this is what we want okay
stream pad we want to let's say some
string
the length will be
uh
four times
number of columns okay and optional
padding string pad is it pad left or
right
pad stream to length using padding okay
if heading is near space character is
used okay string is longer than absolute
value
no padding is done studies new padding
is done to the end of the string okay
in the neopadies done to the start of
the string okay so we want to pad at the
end so
so Neo okay
so so optional so padding which is space
okay starting at the end okay
so that's that is the code and uh
we want it to be
we want to modify this temp okay
there
okay so let me show you what we're gonna
so that is the temp okay
and uh
Neo okay
so that is that
so and here is temp again
okay so let's try that
evaluate that
evaluate that number marker P3 run
type of argument
four times number of columns
what
I should be a number right
string pad
string length okay
stream pad stream
links
what do you mean number
so basically wrong type of argument
number or marker three oh okay so
our number of columns the value of that
is a string
okay we need to convert that into a
number that's why this multiplication
got okay so you need to convert
this
to a number so all you have to do is uh
string two number okay that then put the
whole thing there okay
okay
evaluate now move back here evaluate
fantastic you see the bottom
that's fantastic okay so but but this is
the sample code you see this is temp
so we want to actually so let's move
that remove that we want to actually put
this block of code into this Lambda
when complicated
so this block of code we need to put
this into this Lambda
basically
okay something like that now we just
want to make sure that X
so the x is basically becomes X temp
okay
so
yeah so we don't need this x temp that's
the
that's the input
okay so we don't need that
okay and uh now instead of X temp let's
name it XX
so the code becomes more clear oh my God
let's change this to X list okay
and now extemp
becomes XX
okay
somewhat somewhat easier to understand
so
now this x list is
temporary Okay so
so we need to
um
and he's coming that up let's put in the
bottom okay so with those uh things we
don't care
thanks I wanted to check again regarding
the Emax tutorial I bought you mentioned
you wanted to send it I I thought I send
so remember you know like there are one
people or two I don't know your email
address like if I don't know if you send
via Amazon or what sometimes I don't I
don't have the email address
so email me please okay email me and say
the date and say did you pay via Amazon
gift
card or via PayPal so give me a date
give me this give me a source of your
payment PayPal or Amazon gift card and
add your email put your email email me
okay you can find my email email me and
uh because I don't know where I cannot
send it I don't have the email address
and these names you know I don't know
who you guys are you know so
do that please
okay so now
so now let's get back to so yeah so now
we have
got this is already one hour
uh okay so
so code of conduct I mean code
event of code
um
code of conduct my ass uh
so now we where are we so we got a
number of columns
and we want to
we want to yeah let's let's refresh we
want to turn this
each line into a list okay so
list of lines okay so let's declare a
variable
Okay so
yeah these sub Rose okay so in the
beginning it's Neil
okay
that's going to be our Matrix
at least a nested list each element is a
list of the string of boxes
okay so for each row
Okay so
uh let's just say Matrix
box Matrix okay
at least at least each sublist is a row
of boxes Okay so this is the ultimate
representation for this thing and then
we're gonna do a transpose on this Xbox
Matrix okay
so but for now
Xbox lines then after you do this
then you want to push
this x list
into
into the box Matrix okay
I think so okay double check
wow so while that finished then you
reverse the list
then
you push
push the list into this Matrix okay so
at the end we're gonna have this
uh
Xbox Matrix so let's come and uh
okay
and here
Bo the Xbox Matrix okay it's evaluated
do it
run type argument character
character P but instead of you got a
string
who is who is and from
long run type of character
so oh let's evaluate that
evaluate again
okay toggle debugger I mean I mean
deeper down arrow
this about globally actually enable it
okay let's run it
what what what is what is the wrong type
of
set queue run type of argument
requires a character but you got a
stream
okay
so
so must be
here let's see set queue so
what
wrong type of argument requires a
character
but got a string yeah
wait why is that so
can we just then and Sprint
okay message
okay so we we know each step let's see
so okay okay so actually it
didn't even so let's close that
evaluate again show message solver
so it's just one
error it means before even it gets to
the loop
there's an error
what
so let's check
um
describe variable
is s0
X Plus lines list
yeah that's the input
so Y is the first one element zero
okay so we need to look into that
so number of columns value is three
that's correct and what is the described
variable
Xbox lines list
ah we got we got uh you see the first
line we don't want we don't want that
that's okay that's the input error so we
want that instead
yeah okay
so run it let's rerun everything okay
input parts
run it
run it run it
okay X Box is lying this planet
yeah one two three that's correct okay
so far so good then set number of
columns so net right three correct okay
then Xbox Matrix runet Neo now we got a
spelling Arrow let's fix it
m m a t r i x okay
now the we have lots of global variables
of garbage because we change the
variable names okay so anyway run it now
when this
we still got that any uh
foreign
type argument
requires a character
but got a stream of empty
got a string of one
space
now
set queue so the arrow came from set
queue okay
so but um
so the area came from set Q
stream pad
okay let's do something so here we are
modifying the parameter you know usually
I don't like that so let's change the
parameter just to X and let's create a
temp variable of XX so that we don't
actually modify
the input argument
we modify XX which is our own temp
argument I mean temp variable so this
way you know we don't modify variables
because that's not good for functional
programming
okay so let's run this let's see let's
still got the same error so so what is
XX do we have something beaked no
let's see
so what what what is this uh described
variable
okay
that's a bunch of a list of lines that's
right oh oh the last one
you see we want we need to drop the last
one because those the last line is just
a column number
we don't want that we will you know
Okay so
so we want to drop
the box is line list okay so
uh so we need to hear
then we need to modify again so we want
to drop the last
you know when you have a list
this this
you want to drop the last item which is
very slow
yeah but you're gonna
when you're gonna have to yeah
we we
okay now I
now I see that it will be much more
efficient
if we put this whole input into a buffer
you know
then we do text manipulation text
processing like you can eat like this
you can say move closer to the nth nth
line or nth column then just delete four
characters backward or forward that way
it's more efficient
and uh faster and uh
then then the way we are doing the
traditional way of programming this
thing
because right now we got X boxes line
Beast
but we but then we we need to drop this
last item
which is problematic we did you know DD
the last item in at least
which is problematic with the least data
structure
so but anyway let's do it okay so
yeah you know the very very extremely
inefficient way to do it is you do it
this way okay let me show you extremely
inefficient way
is you reverse it
then you call rest
okay
and I don't even have
you know rest is you know rest is a drop
drop the first item
yeah
you can just say cutter okay it's idiot
like this okay
okay so you reverse it
then you drop the first item
then you reverse it again you know
very inefficient
okay
this is how you drop the last item
which is the list of lines okay oh God
we cannot we
let's do it again okay and you cannot
you cannot do this before you get the
number of columns first so it's all
problematic or another way is we turn
this this into a vector first so we work
with a vector which is just like
Python's Topo but
it's mu each element can be changed so
but anyway let's push on so
do that
do that evaluate
do that okay now you see the bottom
there's no
you know there's no list of lines now
do that
now
do that yeah
one type of argument character p and
where does that come from
it came from said Q
wrong type of argument so it's expecting
a character
but it got the space
so let's push okay so let's do a message
okay
evaluates
so we got the D
so the first item is d
now where does set Q occur there
okay so actually so let's make this
could design
put here okay
let's run it
let's symbols function definition is
void
oh yeah so
okay
you're a net
let your own type of arguments
okay so it came from here
stream pad X
loan type of argument
oh so what the with the string pad
padding use padding if padding is new
the space character is used if not Neo
it should be a character
that's a problem you see because in emac
this a character is a different data
type than a stream so
you know if you want a space as a
character you have to say
this is how you represent it okay
uh 32 okay you just say 32. because a
character is the same as integer so if
you do that that will work brunette you
see no error
now describe cha
uh well now describe char
I mean describe variable box Matrix
you see we got it it's a you see one two
three now what's uh
oh yeah then you have to reverse it
yeah some of these got wrong okay some
of this is wrong
so you have to reverse box Matrix okay
now describe variable
yeah so but so it corresponds to that
but you got some issues what the is
this
uh
okay
comments no comments
well where is where is
you know Jacob yeah
because he's requesting this
this video
um
okay so we need to find out we still got
some errors
oh empty string what
so what is the value
the value is correct but if you say
describe variable
then you got that
I don't understand
but if you just eval buffer let me show
you okay
you Eva last sex
okay then go to the message before you
can see the value is correct you have
the empty strings
for the value X Box Matrix okay anyway
let's move on so now we want to now we
have a matrix that represents this
bunch of boxes now we want to do
transpose
and this is gonna be painful different
uh
okay so in Emax you don't do
so we're gonna write a function
transpose okay
transpose a
nested Beast okay
uh
that
transpose a matrix
okay so the
Matrix
is assumed to be 2 D okay
and assumed
to be
nested Vector okay
not least okay
ah
not so lots of code to do comments
questions okay
so we we're gonna write this F transpose
and it's let's say Excel transpose okay
so first of all turn you want to attend
these
um
convert this into
uh
Vector of
nested Vector okay so how do you do you
you want to convert a list into a vector
you have a nested list you want to
convert it to a nested vector vector of
vectors okay so how do you convert
um
go back to emac lisp
sequence types you want to convert a
list into vector
the difference is that
uh you know the list is is uh is a um
linked list
so it's not efficient if you want Random
Access
so if you want to represent a matrix
such as used in mathematics linear
algebra you want to constantly access
you know nth column nth element you know
then nested list of lisp is not
efficient you want to use the vector
data type which is basically nested
array okay
so right now we want to convert this box
Matrix
which is a nested list into a nested
Vector okay so let's see how do you do
that uh
you know I know because basically you
use map contact okay
wait convert this to string
there is a a hand joined is prepend okay
you want to convert the list to Vector
okay these two vectors so
how do you do that Vector okay
create Vector field Vector length get
element change element nested Vector
okay join vectors convert this to
vectors there V contact that's right
showing any sequence types in return a
vector okay
yeah okay this same Vector are both
sequence types Okay so
yeah so V contact okay
okay
so actually you want to
yeah you want to map Q
let me just show how it works okay so
let's say you have at least one two
three then you do that you got a vector
of one two three correct okay what if
you have a list of lists okay
one two
three okay which is a matrix okay
evaluate that you see one two uh let's
say three four okay so this part is a
nested list now when you do that you see
it doesn't dive in you only convert the
first level of elements
so if you have a nested Beast you need
to map
you need to map the conversion to each
element okay so you need
map
car okay
map car okay map car map function to a
sequence okay the sequence is going to
be that and what is the body the body is
gonna be basically something like that
okay
so
okay so the input
so you want to map each
X
yeah that returns a vector okay so
yeah map that function into this okay
and it returns a list okay
that's it
okay so let's do it again let's see
what's the value okay that's a nested
list now let's do this
fantastic now it's you see
that now it's a nest of vector
oh wait uh wait the you see the outer
bracket is your parents so that means
the whole thing is still at least right
now it's a list of vectors you want a
vector of vectors okay so you have to do
this again
one more time
and this time
is just that okay
okay and it
go to the bottom you see now the outer
bracket is a square bracket that
represents a vector in this emac this in
common this okay
so in fact let's just put it here so
that's
one line
formatting problem
okay so now
Xbox Matrix
is a
is a nested Vector of vectors okay
now
now we want to write the transpose
function that transpose it that's God
not it's already what 90 minutes
okay after we write the transpose then
then it's we are pretty close then
[Music]
then we transpose it then we got this we
got a columns
as our data but then we need to convert
it to a list again because for a stack
it's much easier to represent them it's
much much more efficient if you
to represent a stack data structure as a
list
data type
oh God this all this conversion back and
forth is very costly
but we are working with emac this you
know
so
I'm like I'm discouraged now I'm discoid
should we who is watching
should I go on three people eight people
oh eight
reasonable numerous
comments guys comment okay where where
are we going
so you see this problem
actually took took us you know three
three hours in Wolfram language too this
problem day five at the end of code day
five
is uh yeah it actually took us three
four hours to to
actually implement it so here is the
Mathematica code solution
you know 10 lines of code
um
you know and the problem too is just
change of a single function so basically
10 10 lines of code in Wolfram language
to do this day five and in emac this so
far we have like
we have about
30 lines we haven't write the transpose
yet so once we write the transpose we do
the transpose then we need to convert
Vector to least
okay yeah that's so I always miss that
suggestion you know just get it to work
then then talk about efficiency and
stuff okay okay let's do
okay
okay that's we we okay we need to write
the transpose function okay
thirsty
so transpose function
um so that means you know
so if you have ABC
the f
then after transpose it's going to be
like
um it's going to be like 80
b e
c f
okay that's what transposition means
okay so rule become columns column
become rows okay so you want basically
you want to go through each element in
swap
ah how do you do this God you know in
Wolfram language this building it's just
one line
there you know um but here
so okay so
let's see your purpose
let's see if there's uh
transports characters you know those are
not those just swap two positions so
these all these commands transpose rich
and transpose sentence they just swap to
position so that's not what we want
let's say let's see control u a propose
okay then
transpose let's see what we get
transfer charge transport line transport
sex yeah there's no building function
are we sure yeah I'm pretty sure unless
you unless you turn this list
Necessities into Old mod
uh table form then you can then there's
some function to transpose the text I
think okay so now let's go back to
yeah we want to make sure if there's
anybody in function that saves US 10 20
minutes
so building function for transpose list
or vectors so how do we find that
sequence type okay so sequence functions
you know this sequence of functions is
new about seven years ago so maybe they
they have a transpose now let's search
chance no I guess not
sequence into yeah
a filter yeah sequence take sequence
drop oh we can you we could have used
sequence drop to delete the last element
yeah
that's interesting but uh you know it's
inefficient let's let's see describe
function sequence drop let's see how
they implement it
thanks uh uh sequence drop remove the
first n elements of sequence and returns
oh yeah it doesn't make sense it remove
the first n
uh we want just we want to remove the
last item so yeah anyway let's forget
about this okay
okay transpose so how do you write this
so you of course you map
you you need to map for sure map car
uh so first of all the transpose you
have a
okay so let's see
you have a matrix okay and it's uh so
Matrix is your input
so you want to map to this Matrix okay
so how do you want to map it so well
here's the body
okay so how do you map the so so for
each one
you get the position
so you want to push
so first of all
let's get some variable let's get the
dimension Okay so
so
column count okay
okay column count
equals to
the length of
okay
no that that's row account okay but it's
close Okay so let's do this
so we have row count then we have column
count okay column count would be
uh column count will be
the first element of the Matrix okay
the first row of the Matrix then the
first row of the Matrix then you take
the length that would be the column okay
so you got the row account in column
count okay
then you
um
wait is there a partition so we can so
one one way to do this is that we just
Loop through every element you know map
car then we just create a flat list just
push to a result list so we have one
giant flat list then we use the
we use the um
your account wait which one
we yeah then we use the row account to
every row account is one Sub sub list so
but to do that we need
a partition function list partition
see if there is a
oh there it is fantastic partition
return list of the elements of sequence
grouped into subsequences of length n
that's what we want
fantastic now make things much easier
okay
so yeah so first of all we we do this
let's add that so we don't
so we're gonna use this later okay
partition so basically here will be row
count
okay
and something like that okay
something like that okay so
now we need to
we need to define a local variable flat
list somewhere here okay
okay
so so now we map we map and for each one
flat list is a empty list
so
empty list is Neil or you can write it
this way equivalent okay so we want to
for so each every encounter element we
just push it
to
uh
flat list okay push the X into it
fantastic
and we we don't care about the results
so we just use map C okay then then we
got the flat list then we just partition
into row accounts fantastic we done
laughs
okay I believe that it works okay so
so let's let's cling up I believe that's
that is a code
let's let's uh
this thing here
so
okay so now we evaluate this function
now we have it now let's do some testing
then
see this sound transpose
let's do transpose yeah and we're gonna
have a vector vector one two
three
and we're gonna have four five six okay
that's a nested Vector a matrix now
let's eval
wrong type of argument this p
you got Vector Okay so
somewhere here is wrong
oh here car you can use car for a vector
okay so so here you want um
uh a ref
okay
Matrix index zero so because the zero
indexed you yeah Zero indexed from
C buckets
okay so okay
evaluate the code evaluate this again
fantastic
wait it's incorrect
we should have one four two five three
six okay but close we got need something
to fix
uh let's see sequence partition is SEO
sequence in
sequence so raw count
so wait so the result will be
when you partition it
so you want the column count
column count so here should be column
count
okay eval Eva
it's still incorrect oh wait you need to
return
did we return the thing
return return
list of elements
return a list of elements of sequence
okay I don't know what's going on with
that let's try it okay
let's say
true
let's say one two
three four five six okay you should
return one two three four five six
yeah that's correct what if what if you
have seven does it drop
no it doesn't drop but you have that
okay so so this should work okay so now
let's try
a list instead
okay one two three four five six
okay
that's correct but the result is a list
now if you do this the result yeah the
result is still at least so you need to
convert the whole thing into a vector
okay so you can just see you can just
say
uh
V contacts
these two Vector okay so what's the
documentation for V contact concado
arguments and make the result a
vector
concatenate yeah okay so
the result is a vector sentiments okay
each element will be fixed okay we
concat that's what we want
so we just say
yeah that's that's right so B contact
okay
we can see
so that's the result but but why is uh
mission is not incorrect four five six
one two three no we got something wrong
uh let's see let's see again this map
so map
to The Matrix
now this map takes a list of vector
well it's a general sequence okay it can
take any sequence okay that's good
so map
we so we map to each row at a time
with some talk show
yeah so we map
here a row is the list of stacks
so NZ
so what is a
H let's let's show the result here so
it's easier to see
so here is the example so Xbox Matrix
okay
so we map uh Xbox Matrix
uh what wait let's see let's just say
that
it's incorrect
okay
hi sorry for off topic I'm trying to
recreate your floating window workflow
um
open box and I think you were right
thank you
yeah so that's about the tiling Windows
thing on the cup
okay so let's go back here
uh I don't know you know it's already uh
close to two hours and we have not done
yeah but we are close
I want to get up and walk for five
minutes
but now our transpose function is
incorrect
yes index from zero is bad in general
look up Sardi
should arrange you know search for sorry
array starts array index start from zero
or one you'll find my article
uh
okay so of course the C C plus plus rust
type of people they are disagree
vehemently you know they will say oh
blah blah but but array memory or
whatever you know but they they don't
you know
I don't think they
they know stuff
well that's not
fair but you know but uh but you know
just but but here is one reason okay
basically all math oriented programming
languages
they their index start with one
you know typically the programmers the
CC plus plus rust low level types they
will say
they will say zero is more appropriate
because zero is you know is for
mathematics when you have a zero base
sequence it's much more intuitive to you
know concoction
concatenate or whatever that's what they
think you know they somehow these
programmers adore math mathematicians
you know they are dog news you know they
think
0 is the proper index starting because
because of mathematical properties but
actually
or math oriented programming languages
they are indexed up with one such as
wufam language Mathematica Matlab Julia
APL
or any array languages you know
math oriented like mathematicians
their indexed up with one for example
Matrix they say First Column first row
they don't say zeroth column zeroth row
so the programmers are idiotic to the
extreme you know they have like some
some kind of
adoration admiration to mathematicians
but these themselves don't know anything
about math then they insist you know
array should start with zero things like
that
and for example these hackers Richard
Stoneman they will say you know four
principles of Freedom principle zip zero
something something you know start with
zero an idiot and gnuth too you know the
prototypical hacker mentality growth you
know like he has chapter zero in his
other program in chapter zero
you know but he's a mathematician that
that is for sure
but in in general math okay
mathematicians they start with one not
zero
anyway so that said
okay I don't know you know I should stop
or take a break you know it's two hours
now
okay let's finish let's say this finish
right uh finished writing the transpose
we got the error somewhere
so roll count row count is the length of
Matrix okay let's print raw count okay
just to be sure
okay uh
oh God
the Supreme column count okay
let's just print it okay now evaluate it
and evaluate that and let's go to the
message buffer so rural count is two
that's correct column count is three
that's correct and now we want to
partition it
uh we want to partition it to rural
count not columns so we got so this is
wrong
what
your account is two two rows column
count is three
so the new one
wait we should partition it to uh what
just try it
okay so we I think I think I know
something's wrong the
once we map okay after we map it
you see
after you map it you got a
so flat list push X
oh wait so what wait oh yeah I know so
you you need to do nested map that's
right
yeah that's right
yeah okay so you did you need to do
nested map okay
so you map because you you are mapping
to each row
and for each row you need to map into
each item in a row okay so nested map
map again
okay
okay and here is X
here should be uh
here should be X
and here is a new variable Y and what do
you do with the body you do this okay
you push y to it okay
that that's our error nested map
okay and the result should be row or
column count so
hey
you know I need to think about this okay
so happy New Years hello coffee house
yeah so
yeah end of the year so
a lot you know I have a lot of thoughts
let's digress a little bit so it's more
fun so you know I just uh 20 year 2022
is a good idea for me
and I think it's a great year for
America for you know in
in probably for the world you know so
many things happen I wonder you know
maybe I should do more uh
more talk show and talk about it you
know so many things okay yeah so you
know I hope you guys have a great
uh Christmas and holidays
okay so let's let's finish this
transpose and let's maybe that's that's
okay let's do it there it is six six
five okay something is wrong there
then oh yeah we need to reverse the
older oh God
Jesus this it is yeah
yes
wait so do we do we need to reverse like
twice
yeah we need to reverse for each row
then we need to reverse the whole as
well
and uh
for now let's just return okay first of
all let's just return the flat list okay
run it
okay so you can see the answer is
reverse so you need to yeah one two
three four five six okay so you need to
reverse it
uh you know because of the push you know
because we are using push which is
prepend
you know it would be nice if we just
change this push to append
but it won't work well it's very
inefficient because you have the least
because in this you stuck with this dist
data structure which you can only
efficiently
prepend or remove the first element
if you want to append that's very
expensive the this idiocy with
their cons you know every time I talk to
these people they don't
they don't agree they don't get it
so if I can just change this to a pen
then then we are done you know but
it's extremely efficient uh inefficient
to to to to to a pen this you know
there's not even Podium function to do
it so anyway so so now you reverse
um
okay so now you reverse runet
red okay
so you see that's the answer now you
partition okay
now you partition it
sequence partition and turn it into a
Vector but it's before we do that let's
just say
return that okay
when that
the net
see what's the result okay there it is
one two three four
five six you need to reverse again
wait when you partitioned it reverse the
order again what what the what the
Jesus
said Thank You partition return list of
elements of sequence group into
subsequence of length n
the last sequence may contain less than
element if n is negative okay your
relevant function document sequence you
know be but but it reverse the order
does it
wait it doesn't so
so what
try again
just make sure we are not run it
run it
six five four three two one okay
so we do want to reverse it okay reverse
oh I know what's going on okay brunette
renette one two three four five six
correct now we partition but you
remember you do have to reverse this
thing that's that's right we forgot
okay now we uh do it run it
run it one two three four five six
oh wait this is incorrect it should be
one four two five three six
oh that's right ah our algorithm is
entirely wrong and we wasted 10 minutes
on this
transposition
one two three four five six the result
should be 1 4
2 5 3 6.
came one four
two five three six
uh transposition
so how do you so can we
um
so so right now we are working on this
transpose function
so
so we have a nested Vector so let's swap
let's do the approach of swapping
Elements by their indexes then
so you basically again you do a nested
map
you know nested map C and the body
the body of the map c will be
not push but to
to
um
to swap two indexes we have two indexes
here one is X one is y
okay actually we don't even have index
okay so but if you want the index you
cannot use map C
or map car you have to use
two times
very
very extremely tedious
you have to do use two times if you do
want the indexes of the array so if you
do want if you want to swap the items
you have to use indexes to index
so that would be something like you know
um
array for example in Python
it would be something like array index I
index J
becomes array index j i okay you want to
swap the values and then you can you
know you cannot just do that you need a
temp
this imperative language
in Python okay
for example
yeah the fact I just started python I
don't want to start paid on nothing
cure it yes
God
python mod okay
so this is how you would do in Python so
array temp IJ get it to a temp then that
then basically
then 10 something like that okay
I J equals 2 then J I actually J
I yeah
I just got back up of lamio hey good
morning I I'm about done though today
uh
she's
so
okay I think maybe I should stop
because this is taking two hours okay I
should stop I I think so next day
you know I I wish I you know if you guys
gonna request me to do some video you
guys should be here Jacob you know Jacob
is a great guy though but maybe he's
he's
okay gonna watch later what the
uh
you know anyway so
we we have not written transposed we are
halfway you know debugging you know uh
but it can be done of course to write
this transpose function and in fact this
transpose function will be generally
useful in this
so I'm going to write this maybe in
another video
or maybe offline then it's gonna be on
my website the code transposition of a
nested list of a matrix very useful
um so you know I can continue in fact
you know it's almost like already
already there but who knows it might be
another 10
20 minutes usually that's the case
so you just want to use two times
uh you know two times so you get the
index you want to do a nested two times
okay so you're gonna do times again
okay
you know so you
so you're gonna do times then you're
gonna I and this is gonna be J you know
I J
um
come will be the length of the row
column then then at the body here you're
gonna be doing something like that but
in this
syntax
okay but okay so that's that uh you know
let's do that next time so thank you
guys for watching okay if you like my
stuff donate patreon me or PayPal
buy me a coffee you know you can find my
the links on my website you know
everything is on my website Saudi code
uh all the way at the bottom you'll see
it
okay so happy New Year and happy
holidays thank you guys for watching
bye
stop in one minute
what what is this privacy thing
hmm
no idea
okay so today's code
it's pretty good pretty good until the
we stuck we haven't finished writing the
transpose but and this weekend we don't
need any more
thank you because hey Luis thank you
Luis for coming by and ahm
bye bye bye guys
okay that's our code pop it back syntax
curved showing browser let's see what we
have at the end of code day five in emac
B is live coding yeah but failed
completion
and okay that needs to be fixed okay and
here's a code
almost then you know another
oh
another 20 minutes I would say we
yourself will be able to solve problem A
and B they are very similar okay bye