hello hello sorry no microphone before
welcome to another episode of s talk
show today we are going to do geometry
Calculus if you are learning calculus
you would be you would find it fun so
animations of mathematical curves and so
geometry okay let me show you some of
these uh animations so you see if you
have a
bar if you have a bar and you turn it so
that the end of the bar stick on the
two uh perpendicular axis you will Trace
out this curve so this this curve it
traces out is called asteroid so in
mathema itics we say the envelope of
this this movement is an asteroid now
asteroid curve is very interesting so
let me show you what is asteroid
curve so this is about mathematics
geometry and uh Graphics programming and
wolam
language if you have comments questions
post it okay if you are here uh post it
so let me pop out the
chat so let me show you what is the
asteroid curve asteroid curve is very
interesting in fact we can let me just
uh do it interactively so this is
asteroid so you see when you roll a
circle around a bigger
Circle then you
get this asteroid the point on the
rolling Circle creates a trace of
asteroid so let's let's create let's
stop this and make it more
um copy new file and uh let's not not
animate let's just generate a bunch of
graphics and uh shift enter do it okay
so you can see it generates a bunch of
asteroid curve so you see this is a
rolling a a circle
that is 1/4 the radius of the bigger
Circle row it inside the bigger Circle
so I want to uh create uh more number of
frames so number of
frames let's say 40
okay now do we get uh more tight 40 is
too small let's say 80
okay and let's do so we got now more
dots
fantastic now let's do list
animation okay shift enter to evaluate
it and there it is an animation
fantastic you can so this is wolam
language Mathematica you can export this
into a you know MP4 or any other movie
format am I doing good so let's see
double check voice check video check
yeah comments and questions hello ju
hello Soo so so this is animation so you
know so this is an this is this curve is
called asroy now you see what's
interesting there are so many
interesting properties about these plain
curves so you can see how this curve is
generated but now if we move a line you
know we move a bar so that the end
points are fixed on the uh vertical axis
then it Trace out it also Trace out
this uh this asteroid curve so let's
slow down what is is increase speed slow
speed stop play again
decrease speed now I believe that's
decrease yeah
slower oh okay now it's too
slow okay so that's you know like one of
the properties of asteroid and there's
more interesting things going on so let
me show you this one so if you have a
elisp
and if you draw all Elis el el Elis uh
you draw all of them so that they are
they share the same Center and also
their width and height the sum of their
width and height is the same is a
constant so you draw all such ellip
ellises and also of course they have to
be oriented right so the minor axis are
all the same and major axis
and then also you see the envelope is
also an asteroid so you can see this
asteroid curve we are seeing many
properties of it you can generate it by
this this spot by the way this bar this
movement is called tramal of
aredes TR r a m m a tra of Archimedes
okay so you you you are seeing this and
you are seeing the rolling Circle
and then you also see the relationship
to elisp now what what is elisp elisp
itself is very interesting so let me
show you so you see all these are uh so
this is a Elis so this is another
relation you see if you stop this slow
down let's do it again so you see you
use the traa of Archimedes all the same
but now you put a point on the bar and
you move the bar then that point will
Trace out an elisp okay so very
interesting so these are you know or
these are about special properties of PL
curves now what is an Elis Elis here is
another relation so you see Elis can be
generated also by Rolling a curve inside
a circle inside another circle like
this by the way there's a toy called
spiral graph
uh for Rolling circles around another
Circle very popular if you have not seen
it let me show
you sp r o graph this toy it was very
popular because when I was back in
Taiwan in the
1980s my granddad or my dad you know
bought me one of these so you can you
can actually you know draw all these
colorful curves by you know
this is a thing that has gears and
wheels and you put a pain inside it and
you'll Trace out all these curves so
this
toy they call this toy spiral graph SP r
o so they call it spirograph but the
technical name the mathematical name for
this curve is
called uh EP hypot troid and epot troid
so let me go back to show you so you can
see see uh there it is you see this this
is Apple
troid uh many interesting properties and
there is hypot troid now hypot troid
means when you roll a circle inside
another Circle so you draw a smaller
circle inside a bigger Circle you get
hyp troid but if you draw a circle
outside of a circle you get epot troid
you see very interest so that's a
technical name
for this toy spiral graph you know you
can buy this on Amazon this this toy
it's still there so this toy has Is Now
by now 40 or 50 years old very popular
okay so so you see you know elisp can
also be traced out traced out as a
spirograph or uh OC cycloid so that's
very
interesting and what about the
definition of Elise
oh by the way okay so here is another
interesting property you see they are
all related elisp can also be traced out
if you if you extend the bar you know of
the Rolling Circle so that also
generates a
elisp okay but what is the definition so
Elis can be defined in several ways you
can Define it in this mechanical way a
circle inside the bigger Circle uh of
certain size you know the circle needs
to be certain ratio so in this case the
smaller circle is half the radius of the
bigger Circle but in but but over
here uh yeah this is also yeah in this
in this case you have to extend the bar
yeah that also generally
Elis
so so but what is the so another
definition of elisp the classic
definition of elisp is this okay so you
you start with two fixed points and
you you draw all dots such that the
distance
from
from from one of the point to the dot to
the other point is the same you so you
create all dots of search property then
you get a elisp so this is the classic
definition of Elis
so you can see we already you know we
have so many we you know we have Elis
properties you can generate it this way
by the way you can also do this
mechanically so all you have to do is
you take out a piece of uh board you put
you you you stick in two uh TXS you know
Nails then you take take a string you
know sewing a thread you know then you
you know you tie get to the points then
you use a pen then you just tighten it
and it'll Trace out a
Elis so very interesting and and uh here
is another properties of elisp you can
also generate it this
way so this is slightly more complicated
than the other so you have to you know
form a uh triangle there
so so yeah so that that's some of the
properties of these um spatial plan
curves this is another Spiral graph
beautiful okay
so yeah so the all these are done with
wolam language Mathematica uh in fact I
wrote a package for this uh I wrote it
like 30 years ago so but I'm updating it
so I just updated it and I I will be
uploading to GitHub in few days in two
or three days by the time you watch this
video so if you are watching this video
offline feel free to uh skip
around can you draw a duck yes of course
you can uh but I'm going to you know
that's a digression
so for example you can uh that's a
digression but but basically you want to
that's an interesting question a lot
people ask including me when I was
learning calculus when I first learned
about plan geometry you have coordinate
X and Y you know so you can you can plot
a polom you can plot S curve you know
all sort of curve so the question is can
you do the reverse so given a cartoon
image can you have a equation whose plot
looks like that uh yes that's doable
but but technically actually if you go
really deep into mathematics technically
depend it really depends on precisely
how you define your what what exactly is
the drawing you want to have the
equation four because normally when you
uh well let me show you okay uh let's
see f i i i i have an article about it
so let's go to to if you search for Kar
math Blog then go
to uh my math pages then search
for parametric equation
parametric uh no search for
equation theories of equations the level
of math professors are not equal theory
of equations okay not there let's search
for graph stereographic projection
Graphics uh graphing
calculator uh okay
so many of you probably probably have
seen it so let's say duck equation okay
let's just go to
wolam language so your question is can
you plot a duck
okay so let's go toam Alpha it will
generate it right
away so let's see yeah so you can see
all these are some equate uh some
examples people has done Center like
curve so this is drawing a Canta Clause
okay Santa cross and the equation is
this you know so mathematically this is
not not interesting you know you can
basically you know for any drawing you
can create a mathematical equation for
it but the Deep mathem you know the the
issue is that because your drawing is
not well defined you see in mathematics
you see many of these curved we curves
we talked about you see may it be the
spiral graph or uh you see or the elisp
you know any of these curves we talked
about they are very very precise so you
know for example this Elis you know for
example this asteroid how do you
know let's go here so
uh you know so it Trace out an asteroid
but every dot there is very precisely
defined so it's pinpoint to down to
infinite number of
decimals so if that let's say the 100
place in a decimal is off by one bit
then that's not the asteroid okay that's
what that's the definition of these
curves so they are extremely well
defined you know very precise down to
infinite Precision that's right infinite
Precision so if you are at the millionth
point you know you are off by one bit
that's not that's technically not an
asteroid so back to your question you
know you you you kind of trolling
question mark Jefferson your question is
like can you draw a duck okay so we have
seen a Santa Closs here but the issue
here so and you know we do have a
equation but the issue here your Canta
Closs drawing is not well defined not
like you know the the math curves
so if your drawing is so well defined so
every point is has infinite number Pres
prisions
then then some of the curve cannot be
drawn by a equation okay that's a
interesting technical
detail okay so let's check out some fun
uh fun ones I I remember there's a
Batman and a bunch of others let's see
random DC Comics Cur so there's Batman
Superman so what is this this is Green
Lantern
uh let's see DC Comic
curve uh okay so let's do another
one oh this is what
Catwoman promethus okay let's see uh
Batman
curve Batman
curve there it is and where here is the
equation uh let's see uh there it is
Batman
curve s cosine s cosine infinite number
okay so let's let's look at the equation
okay so what exactly is
this this should be yeah I it's a
parametric equation okay so today you
have ai that just generate it's the
equation for you I believe this is a
parametric equation so
anyway jman Molina hi I'm doing good I'm
doing pretty good so now so we have
shown some of these you know animation
and some mathematics about it very
interesting so if you want to do this
you know there are two interesting
aspects so one is for example let's say
let's say let's say this one this one is
very easy to understand how do you do
this you know you can use JavaScript you
can use Python you can use your favorite
language
okay how do you generate an animation
like these so there are two aspects one
is the math math mathematics of it so in
order to generate this you have to
understand exactly you know where to
draw the bar in every frame you know
where to draw
it
so so that part is mostly about
trigonometry okay it's not it's really
just about Tri trigonometry so you have
to master trigonometry or analytic
geometry so once you know you can you
can draw this because for example if you
want to draw this what you have to know
is you know for every frame you have to
know where this where to draw this small
circle
and where do you put that bar so that is
mostly trigonometry you need to be a
master of trigonometry very
basic so that's one aspect the math
aspect of it the other aspect is the
technology the programming language for
example if you want to do this in
Mathematica wam language you have to
know wfam language so let me show you
the
code uh desktop so wolam language
packages so I wrote this like 30 years
ago and uh recently I just updated today
I mean I updated you know few weeks ago
so here is a code so first of all here
all these our documentation can you see
it yes so these are documentations then
let's go to the code so for example this
is a auxilary function and uh let and
this is this this is and this part is a
general function for doing any polar
equation so let me show you some some
more uh some more of it some more
advanced um so for example it all these
animations you have seen so far they are
specific you know for example this one
is for elisp and this one is also for
Elis but very specific but you can also
create an animation that do like a you
know you give give a equation parametric
equation you'll generate an animation
illustrating that so let me let me go to
one of them and so you can
[Music]
see yeah so let me show you another
specific one about sign curve okay this
one uh by the way this one is also
interesting this is this curve is the
red line the red dots is called
quadratics of heas
this curve is about 2 or 3,000 years old
okay you know 2,000 years old Asian
curve this red line and from this
animation you can see how is it
generated how is it defined you know you
have a bar moving from bottom to top in
a constant speed then you have another
bar that rotates in a constant speed so
when when so when these two bars move
they
intersect you know the other points of
their intersection is the quadrat
quadratics of heps okay and there's a
equation for it you can plot it but
anyway so the the purpose of this
animation is to visually visualization
of geometry to visually show you know
all these properties so you can look at
it and you understand how you know how
is it
defined uh so let me show you
some more specific interesting ones then
then we'll show a general purpose one so
here is how sign is defined you know s
cosine tangent cotangent all of them can
be defined by a single function sign and
how is sign defined you can Define sign
mechanically like this okay so you
basically you have a circle you roll I
mean you so you have a bar centered in
the circle you just roll it in a
constant speed that's important constant
speed then then you have another uh bar
that traces the height of that that
rotating bar that's how you get sign
that's basically how sign is defined so
that is why sometimes the sign function
is called circular function because
essentially it's defined based on a
circle and sign function is the most you
know it
you could say sign function is the most
important function in mathematics most
fundamental back to like 3,000 years so
trigonometry trigonometry is the most
important uh and all over physics so
sign function in other another way in
other words you can say s function
represents Pi okay represent the ratio
of a diameter of a circle to the
circumference basically sign is
pi okay that's sign function and here is
another interesting animation this curve
so you can see the envelope you know all
this line art formed a
curve this one Bell kind of bell shaped
that's called tractrix okay
tractrix and you can see this in real
life that is when you have a bicycle
let's say you ride a bicycle on slightly
mudy road so usually when you ride a
bicycle you go straight right
now when you turn a
wheel uh when you turn the wheel
then then you maintain that uh that
angle then your the the two points of
your bicycle SEL will Trace out this
curve so it's like dragging a line so
you can you can see we have a fixed bar
the red bar here we just drag it and it
will Trace out this curve so it will
also Trace out by your bicycle so this
curve is called
tractrix very interesting uh and then
okay so let's then let's go to the more
generalized advance so here here is a
function that does uh General
generalized polar equation so for
example we are given a equation T and
cosine T So xal to t y equal to cosine T
I mean theta equals to T which is the
angle and
uh and uh um the distance is cosine T so
you can see it's easier when you just
see it so you see it generate so it's
this is a polar equation you can give
any equation to it and it will generate
an
animation okay and here is another
example this this another polar uh
equation
example so that's uh mathematics and
here is another
example so
here what's interesting is that if you
want to write this program you can of
course write it in JavaScript in Python
in whatever language what you need to
know I mean this is is a generalized
animation generator so you can give any
polar equation parametric polar equation
and it will create this
animation so you have to know you know
trigonometry and anal analytic geometry
to so that for each frame you know what
to draw what you know which line and
which
dots uh and let me show you last one uh
is a very interesting and more advanced
for derivative you know D derivative you
know which is the fundamental part of
calculus the most
fundamental can also be generated by
mechanical means you see so far all the
things we've seen is almost all
mechanical that is you can create
linkages you know that's what's called
linkages let me show you so linkages is
very important field in
robotics okay so for example all these
are
linkages and especially in robotics
because in robotics you have arms that
needs to move in a certain
way you know it can you know it cannot
move freely you know but usually motor
just move around you know around and
around or you know back and forth so but
you want to make it so that for example
a robotic dog the legs movement it must
be in a certain way so all these are
done by what's called
linkages so so far all these animations
we've seen they are they are kind they
are linkages many of them are linkages
but basically they are all mechanical
means of doing things so for example you
have this thing that controls the um for
example the
camera shutter things like
that uh and here is a bicycle
linkage can you see
it okay so back to here so so I was
saying
uh the derivative actually can also be
generated mechanically so let me show it
here
there let's go slowly okay
slow stop
play
Slow okay and here is another derivative
this is a derivative a of a parabola X =
to X2 y = to X2 very simple so the
derivative of a parabola is a line and
here is how it works me
mechanically okay so is that
interesting uh maybe that's it for today
so let me talk about um
let me talk about how do you yeah the
code okay so for example let's
say let's say the first
one this tramal of Archimedes okay how
is this done so let's look at the code
for this
one uh so I have
called uh let's see search for asteroid
okay search for asteroid there it is
asteroid generator so the code is
here yeah actually it's not it's not too
big it's basically just uh
this these lines okay it's just
these
lines so what you what I'm doing is that
for each frame you want to draw the line
the red line the axis for so basically
for each frame you want to draw the red
line the bar the fixed bar and the the
line of the previous of its previous
position and you can
see and you can see this part
is a line you see line starting position
is cosine something zero and end
position is zero sign so you know so how
do you know s cosine well that's
trigonometry you have to figure it
out so basically the essence is just
simply this line so to so this animation
the essence of this animation is simply
just this these two points beginning
position of the bar and end position of
the bar cosine zero and zero
sign and the rest is just you know uh
wam language
graphics and you can do this in
JavaScript of course JavaScript is very
suitable for the web so what else I want
to let me let me go back to uh what so
maybe that's it for today uh what else
we want to uh let
me see so show the animations explain a
bit about each show wam Language
tutorial site yeah okay so if you search
for Wam Language tutorial on s. info so
I have uh all the tutorials for
programmers on wfam language you can
downloaded free you know over here and
then then there's a new I updated a new
section on programming
Graphics so all these are about
programming Graphics so you just let go
to uh go
down and uh Advanced symbol principles
Graphics programming
there so you know so you can learn about
that Graphics programming so what
else uh Dem oh demo the manipulate okay
so another you know one so here is about
one interesting feature of wolam
language let's
say plot okay let's say you want to plot
uh s x okay and uh let's say x from 0 to
six okay that's sign now what if you
what if you want to sign uh x *
2 okay what does it looks like so let's
do it
here
sign x * 2
inside okay so you can see it kind of
you know compress them
horizontally now what
about
three you see it's more compressed so
you can create an animation so what how
you do that is you uh just call
manipulate m a n puu l a t e okay then
just exact like
before uh no not
that yeah so sin x * 3 x 0 to 6 but here
instead of three we say
t Okay so T is a new variable then over
here we
say
uh T goes from let's say 1 2 3 okay do
it uh shift enter so now you got this
slider you can see as T increases how
how it changes the curve so can you show
the value there it is then also you can
do it by
animation and let's cycle
it you see that's a fantastic the most
you know Wonderful feature so this
feature allows you to see the effect of
parameters of functions or equations to
the functions graph so you can you can
easily visualize it now let's do some
fancy one okay let's say plot
3D
s uh sign
uh s x
time
y then x from 0 to
7 y from 0 to 7 okay what we get okay
now we want
to okay let's plot another one let's say
s
times cosine
Y what do we
get okay that's what I'm looking for now
what if you add a number here so and see
how it changes the graph so let's do
that uh not here
manipulate okay
something like before then here we say t
from 0 to three okay okay uh and uh
let's say let's just say t
okay do it okay we got the let's say
animation do
it oh it doesn't oh okay it kind of
shrinks the parameters so let's change
something
here plot range
let's
say 0
to 0 to
7 x for X 0 to
7 uh 7 for Y and Z let's say -3 2
three do it okay let's see see what
happens there it is
fantastic so you can see the effect of
the variable T here to
the but this one is not interesting the
more interesting let's you know let's
make the wave move so in order to do
that you want to put the T inside so
let's copy the previous input and put
the T inside here
T shift enter there it is
show let's see what how it changes okay
it's getting more
interesting and what about let's put a t
here too
wow that's more interesting okay now the
resolution is not so good so let's make
the resolution
sharp uh so what we want to do is we
plot
range we add option plot
points uh
50 shift enter
fantastic okay they are you know the
this not actually moving but it's
actually becoming smaller so but what we
want is moving you know like the wave so
what we have to do is instead of
multiply by T we say plus T
okay oh actually we can I think we can
put the T outside uh yeah I I think
that's
probably yeah there it is it's moving
but yeah you should actually just put
the T
outside
so so here plus t
oh no it's not
um yeah now now it's just move up down
yeah it should be inside but anyway so
this manipulate is a very useful
extremely useful uh function in wam
language okay I think that's it for
today um how to create animation we can
so we haven't get into programming uh
wolam language Graphics let's do that
another
day yeah so we just
introduced some
interesting uh mathematics
today I know a little about asymptot and
meta poost okay I don't know what's the
meta
post okay that's it for today thank you
guys for watching now for those of you
watching c talk show c talk show
is a variety ner shows you know I talk
about a bunch of uh very
interesting nerd topics you know
mathematics programming geometry
keyboards and
mouse and now I bought a new camera so
do they have a picture no they don't
have a good picture but this is uh this
camera is called Moose so this camera
will allow me to give you great closeup
of keyboard but right now I'm using
Logitech you know cheap Logitech webcam
so you don't see sh
pictures and also let me mention again
this is SW board s v a l b o a r d I
promised to use and demo and you know so
I have a review on my website but it's
very short 20 minutes also but I will be
using it you know until you know I I
will be learning it and show you guys so
I want to mention that until actually I
start to use
it okay that's it for today thank you
guys for watching if you like my stuff
you can just go to cali.
infoinfo
enter and and uh that's my website and
you go down you go down down down down
down down down the rabbit hole then you
can patreon me Amazon gift card me or
PayPal me okay pay me because if you
like my stuff that's how things gets
going thank you guys bye
guys shut down in one minute
you see I'm using this Mouse I mean this
track Bowl I reviewed uh about four days
ago on my YouTube fantastic