good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show uh how are you guys
and today we are going to do a bunch of
things miscellaneous emac list and
keyboard the Signum 3 keyboard and uh
emac and uh some programming issues user
interface uh uh web development [ __ ]
and and uh some math okay any of these
topics possibly and uh you know comments
in the comment box and I'll talk about
it and good morning Troy Fletcher so
Troy Fletcher is the creator of this
keyboard and by the way today is 20
21st February
17th uh Troy is a creator of this
keyboard the Signum 3 and I have uh I'm
going to show you okay that's the one of
the topic today I'm going to show you
this keyboard fantastic keyboard with
thumb
paddles uh do we have people okay uh we
don't have people here now let's I'm
think so I'm going to talk about uh emac
so let me show you the keyboard okay
I have quite a few keyboards to show
you
uh quite a few keyboards so first of all
so let me show you the Signum 3
keyboard
e e
up
okay so I I did a screw up I was my
sound is off no audio no audio is SC so
let me do it this again okay uh no audio
so I'm back so let let me let me uh so
hold on a second let me do this again
[ __ ]
ID [ __ ] idiotic technology I have to
finish that
okay so let me try to fix the
audio test
test do I have audio yes so do I have
audio okay so so again let me show you
this one more time this is tro Fletcher
creator of this keyboard this keyboard
is called s Signum 3 just search it
search for it and you'll find it
and one of the great feature is the
actually this let me do this instead
okay let me do
this uh let's see if
I
idiotic let's see if I can do this
yeah okay maybe like that okay so I have
to be careful so so th so this is uh
Signum three okay so this this is a
thumb paddle uh this is a normal key and
you have two more keys on the side you
can put a normal switch or you can use a
thumb paddle and it works uh really
great I have red switches so this is uh
really great so for example oops and I
just press the wrong I just press the
key on my uh ultimate hacking keyboard
so that that is my ultimate hacking
keyboard This is my is new
kesis so um so what do I want to say so
I have I don't have it set up yet uh and
also did I menion he sent it to me so
thank you Troy I don't have it set up
yet but but let me tell you okay let me
make a complaint the setting up is a pen
in the in the ass Troy I'm going to ask
you questions how to how to set this up
okay but but anyway the the major thing
is about the flip switch it's fantastic
you guys have questions about the uh
flip
switch okay I think I'm back now let me
just put this normal so I can
actually uh
talk okay so that's so I was going I was
thinking of doing this later but you
know so this is is the Signum 3 uh and
it's fantastic now there's a major
problem you know there's a major problem
with this do it yourself keyboards
because I'm excited about this keyboard
and I'm about to you know I want to set
it up to uh create a I want to create a
keyboard configuration key map for my
emac softly
keys but how do I do it that's a problem
you know you go to the Signum Signum 3's
website
so which is this website then you go to
uh here photos and he here is how uh he
explains about the flip switch and you
go to his website about
configuration it's one bunch of
incomprehensible
things I'm not a maker you know the
millennial Generations maker I'm not and
I'm not a keyboard you know Creator so I
I have little idea what these are so
from but from what I can tell I got a uh
you know Pro micro you know yesterday
actually I looked up you know what
what's Pro micro what the [ __ ] is pro
micro what what the [ __ ] is T
tiny so I looked up so I got promicro
and and so I have to supposed the first
of all I download this file okay then I
go to this
website then uh okay then I need to turn
on JavaScript
uh then I upload my file uh
oops I upload my file then it it pops up
a bunch of incomprehensible things let
me show you okay so for example let's
say that one oh uh wait so that one
looks nice leave page uh wait
uh so let's see
Yeah so basically when I upload my file
I got something like that then you have
pins like what what the [ __ ] what do I
have to do like what which one what do I
have to do which button to press then if
I made a mistake whoops my keyboard is
the firmware is [ __ ] you know so so
and where do I read instructions there's
not much you know on this side it says
promicro pin assignment okay you know
so that's a problem that's a problem
with all these uh most of these do it
yourself keyboards you know they don't
give the Creator a choice you know they
they are nerds and they just satisfy
themselves you know this and this is a
great Innovation but it everything stops
there there's no case so if if I drop
this it's dead you know if I drop it you
know it's broken $200
$300 and the USB connector is to break
uh you know that's a problem of do it
yourself keyboards and many of them uh
in fact more than half of them is like
that in
particular in particular you know I also
got this but I have no I I you know I
haven't done anything to it because I
don't have my keys you know I I the key
is not set up in order to do that I have
to spend few hours to read to to read
about how do you compile the qmk you
know software so that's one of the major
problem with this uh do it
yourself uh and and and also case is
important okay let me mention the case
is important need a case anyway so
anyway I I'm just going to use this for
myself and so uh so it'll work for
myself you know but you know you won't
have lots of bias that's one of the key
so you know if I make can make a
suggestion to you do it yourself people
setting keyboards out there you want to
create a package so that everything is
in one box okay case everything
assembled you know sell it for three
$300 or 350 if you have to you know make
then you get
sales okay so uh what what so let's see
what else hello zitron crazy haven't
seen you for a
while okay so that's about keyboard any
questions uh and Troy anything to say do
uh how's going so any any feedback you
have about the your
keyboard okay that's that's the
um that's the Signum keyboard I want to
show okay so the the most important
thing is the thumb padle is fantastic
I'm not doing so great so the thumb
paddle is fantastic
I'm not showing much here
anyway so that's about keyboard let's
see what's the next thing we want to
talk about any
um okay keyboard then what else okay so
let's go back to emac um what are we
going to do today
so I next we can talk about emac and
programming or
mathematics uh greetings bot so emac
programming and math now since bot is
here let's talk about some math because
uh bot is tired of emac so let's talk
some uh math first let me show you some
math
okay so we have so I have so let first
of all let me tell you about calculators
so I got this you know I'm a nerd so I'm
into calculators I got this calculator
for five for
$250 uh in 1991 so 20 years ago I bought
this one you know and this is the first
graphing calculator and uh that's before
I know anything about programming
languages I programmed eight Queens
puzzle
solution uh and also a program to play
music chords so so this is uh
hp28 but today I want to tell you is
that
um I also got this one CIO okay this is
this is a cheap uh
calculator
on so nothing nothing special about that
it's just a cheap
calculator then you know calculator is
amazing amazing thing imagine you
showing this C calculators handheld
calculators two mathematicians 200 years
ago you know greatest mathematicians SCS
Newton and see what they think you know
those people lebanes they are trying to
create calculators and then you show
this
uh uh which uh uh you know this this
thing is fantastic so anyway I want to
tell you so if if you are buying a
calculator you know the most popular is
TI n Inspire taxes instruments now
that's not so good uh the better one is
HP Prime okay so you know it's cheaper
and better and faster because there's
video reviews of it that's all I want to
show and also even if you buy a Casio
that's even better more powerful and
cheaper Casio so you can either buy that
one or I I guess this one this is all
model okay that's something about
calculators see comments no comments
okay so let's see let me talk about next
thing uh keep
watching test
okay calculators so I have so so so
there are some fantastic math software
here I'm going to show you a few you can
just uh search my website great software
for uh 2D visualization of geometry so
this one is plotting
complex uh
functions now it's called domain
coloring and there are several of them
there's a client
quartic okay and most of these uh these
are in JavaScript so it's
interactive so let me show some of that
let's open
let's
open okay let's open these are beautiful
you
know and and here is one uh for doing n
ukan
geometry let's open so let's show that
and's see I need to turn on JavaScript
there it is you
see let's see next
next and one
more so this one is for doing the ukian
geometry uh you can actually draw lines
or or Circle let's see how it
works oh you can draw Circle so you can
measure distance and so that nadian
geometry okay that's one of the big
branch of geometry hyperbolic geometry
and uh elliptic
geometry but this one they focus on
hyperbolic I think
yeah uh if you don't know what they are
you can just look up Wikipedia but it
will take you some time to learn because
you know usually it's taught in a course
uh for math Majors after after you had
calculus uh so that's that then there is
this one this one is showing oh yeah
there's more a lot more math application
a math programs okay so for example this
one me show
you uh Z squ can we do that there it is
how do
you uh there it is oops I don't want
that I don't want
that I don't want the Earth picture okay
that's better
divided by
z uh divided by Z + 1 okay let's see
what happens now how do
you how do you make this full
screen oh here
okay so that's uh that's the interesting
thing about this
application and
then then there is this one let's change
you can change
function uh
okay then this
one CLI
quartic what happened
H oh there there it
is okay so that's fun
that's fun mathematics this is also
hyperbolic geometry I haven't studied it
but you
can okay and what's this one so this
one oh yeah this this guy is amazing guy
this guy uh he's a programmer and
mathematician I think Rick R
russer he uh he wrote quite a few
JavaScript applications for example look
at this
one and uh it's you know it's all
interactive of of course
and this one is also interactive you can
oops uh yeah I screwed
up okay so you can see you can play with
it math that's fantastic math you see
okay so let's close that close close
close close
close and let me show you okay so
actually so we have a few so all these
applications are software for 2D
visualization of geometry now let me
show you 3D visualization of geometry
there are few fantastic applications so
open this one
and
uh open this one okay then let's see
this
one okay hey great break Loop and hey
Niko uh Niko says CIO
mp1 2 R is the best calculator for
common people you can calculate quotient
and REM remainder on it okay C your mp12
R so make a note of
it creepy smile is bot okay so let me
show you okay so let me finish showing
this then we're gonna uh I'm going to
read comments so this this one is a
great theory in Geometry by uh and and
this guy Rick uh rousa
made a visualization of
it okay this is a very famous problem
for like 20 years I don't really uh
understand it but but visually everyone
can understand it okay so let me show
you what what this is this is sphere
ersion
okay so basically mathematicians has a
theory that says a sphere can be
inverted inside out that is you can turn
the sphere
inside out
without without any any pinch or
tear
so so that's a theory in mathematics now
remember the key thing is that you
cannot have any pinch you know for
example if
you have
uh I I don't have anything to illustrate
with anyway if you go to this side here
you read it and he'll explain explain it
sphere ersion okay I think it's called
sphere ersion but anyway the the the
theory is that a sphere can be turned
turned inside out without any uh cringe
or Kink you know so in other words a
sphere can be smoothly turned inside
out and and it's allowed for uh things
to go through itself but what is not
allowed is any pinch or cringe you know
sharp points so that's a Theory but you
know it's difficult to uh visualize so
he is showing a version of it so you can
see start with a sphere then you turned
it this way and that way and that way
and so on then this way then this way
then it's inside
out so and he is I believe he's the
first one who actually made a
visualization that's easy to understand
you know if you watch it carefully you
can understand it then he also you know
he has explanations and he also
shows uh you know he shows you details
for example look at this
one so first of all you have a sphere
then you imagine you cut it up so he he
cut it up so that you can see exactly
how it is done so you can go on go on go
on go on and you have that and you do
this this this
this okay so here is a example where you
have a cringe you know that's not
allowed so if you do it this way it
won't
work but anyway so he's showing
different ways so so you can turn a
sphere inside out let's see right now
it's orange on the outside and blue on
the inside so let's go back
now it's blue on the outside so you can
do this slowly you know so you can see
the details let's see let me do it
slowly so
slowly slowly slowly slowly okay this is
no
goal
but but if
you okay don't do that then if
you TR it a little
bit
then
then do it that way that way okay anyway
I don't understand okay and he's got
other
versions
uh anyway that's the that's about sphere
ersion
okay uh big Theory Big theory in math so
you can look up differential geometry
okay you know all this visualization is
fun you know so I I I I've been you know
I read about this like uh almost 30
years ago but the thing is you know so I
failed in knowing a lot math because I
never actually UND you know Tred to
study it so what do you want to do so
you know you watch this it's fun but
what you really want to do is start to
uh take a course for example in
differential geometry and really you
know do the math not just
visualization okay and here here is
another one this one is doing uh are a
four-dimensional number system meaning
each individual qual this guy is
fantastic you know he's a he's a
mathematician and also a programmer and
he shows you quum here you probably have
seen his video so uh he consists of four
real number part here is a uh video plus
interactive application uh that explains
coronian okay that's that's it about
that so you can find all these on my
website so you just go to Kad math you
go to
um Kad math and uh math software so you
can find all these fantastic
software uh I showed some interesting
things um and Mathematica is the
greatest of them all okay uh in my last
video I talked about Mathematica how you
can get it free so you should uh go get
it uh and there's some interesting
things about puzzles um let
see okay I think that's that's it for uh
math let let me read the comments
I was on the phone so I didn't hear you
reply have you ever uh tried pink
switches uh no pink switches no I don't
even know which one are the pink
switches
fing so seat Addy says hi greetings
interesting uh keyboard the signal very
similar to the Atrius
uh now keyboard ID iio no okay I don't
like Atrius
uh I have some complaints to make about
keyboard iio keyboardio and and Atrius
you know keybo keyboardio keyboardio is
a very interesting
keyboard uh let me show you key keyboard
deal uh let's go
to
keyboards do it yourself
keyboards uh actually keyboardio is now
in history Oro history because they they
no longer makes
it so when key AIO uh began I was very
excited you know it's it's great design
it's and also it's got one of the
innovation of the palm key you see that
that that is a Innovation because you
have never seen it before you
know uh and uh but then you know
he the style of the keyboard went into
the elite Direction you know meaning
that it's a highest quality you know
it's made of wood uh you know some
expensive wood or something and
everything becomes kind of elaborate you
know I rather
prefer uh you know Common practical ones
but everything becomes
elaborate and now after the first vers
they don't I I guess I I guess they
don't you know they don't make this
anymore
so um you know I rather prefer it just
become part of a a model you can always
buy you know so they so you know they
they tends to be they it turns out they
geared to you know Elite you know kind
of become a elite thing then then it
turns out you know the next version they
did is the Atrius you know which is the
most idiotic uh among the choices in my
in my opinion the Atrius
keyboard which is where uh HRI is here
somewhere
uh flat one
piece Atrius yeah so Atrius is made by
this guy a great emac lisp coder and
also a closure coder and
also and also other things uh but it's
not so good okay first of all it's got
only 42 keys I hate that I hate those
only 42 keys that means it's impossible
if you are going to type lots of
mathematics or if you type Chinese
Russian Japanese this keyword is use you
know useless it becomes useless unless
you get the variation you know with 58
or 62 keys
uh okay so let me see some more comments
uh h HP Prime calculator because I
prefer having the physical keys of a
real
calculator okay let's break the
loop uh creepy smile is from
B uh
uh just P yes compared to yeah so break
the loop is talking about using the
phone using the phone as
calculator Ben eer the creator of the
educational bread bard video create a
computer from scratch creating a
computer from scratch and that quum
visualization that
showed Oh bener that's his
name I'm getting a new Ultimate hacking
keyboard version two plan to use
negative Tiding do you use any of the
modules on your ultimate hacking
keyboard no I don't have
um so the ultimate hacking
keyboard I don't have the extra module
you know the one I have is version one
now they have version two and uh you
know I you know I can ask them uh to ask
them to send me a module so I can review
and sell it for them maybe
okay so right so what next how long have
I been talking I I I been talking for 35
minutes so shall we do some emac
lisp uh I want to do some emac lisp I
guess so emac
LP okay so a lot has been happening with
emac
lisp let me do a rant first okay so
recently I run into this problem this uh
nasty web you know web programming web
de problem so basically I decided I want
you know when you click a link I wanted
to pop up a window you know because I
you know I realize for example click a
link you know you can go back uh
actually this stupid windows let me
maximize window instead not this
one maximize window so I decided to make
the link to open in a new tab instead so
like that I open it open a new tab so
the way you do that is to uh add a
blank add a Target blank to all your
links but it turns out there is a
problem with Target
blank because it turns out if you use
Target blank
[Music]
then then the other website that the
target goes to can use Java script to
reload your pH page reload your page to
some other page like a fake Bank page so
basically in summary whenever you add
Target blank you have to add you should
also add re uhel equals to no opener
because otherwise
hackers on the other side can you know
can hack you know can can create uh
fishing
site so that that's a problem that's a
giant pen from the web dev you know
these people these Tech geekers these
nerds that every day they tell you what
to do they tell you what is the best
edms and so on this Java typically from
you know you know these hacker types
people on Hacker News or from python
people py you know they tell you what to
do this so they created this
situation so that's a problem so that's
one of the complexity and TDM of
software engineering because for me to
do this I have 6, 47,000 links from my
website links to other site so you know
it takes me only 3 seconds to change the
all the all my links but however but
then a you know a friend who told me
there this problem then I started to
read about Pro the problem it which
takes another another half an hour then
I started started to fix it you know
it's not a simple find and replace
because then you run into other issues
you have to make lots of other decisions
on the
way so this is the story
about about one of the TDMs of uh
software TDMs and complexities of
software engineering
okay and I have a collection of it over
the past 20 years usually I try to write
it down whenever I run into uh lots of
problems you know I document you know
the software industry uh lots of
problems for example closure got lenan
crap Logan is like mpm you know mpm for
JavaScript is Lan for
closure uh you know you do one thing you
know one thing leads to another you know
so you have Java you know the Java the
inflexible Java programming language
then someone thought oh why don't we
write a you know a command line that
automate everything then you have you
know then you know then you have the mpm
or Lan then it becomes more complex then
you have init files configurations then
you you know that's a software industry
you know at on on each one of the step
it seems should be a Improvement you
know why not you know why not have a
command line Lun it just automate
everything but but then it Lan by itself
takes several hours and days to learn it
in the same way this happened to uh
GitHub you know Git You Know in the
beginning why don't we create you know
uh version in control that will improve
our lives you know code so you have a v
Version Control so you can yeah that's
better that's good then then eventually
after you know several Generations then
today we have git then it's one
complexity
[ __ ] git where is git yeah so I have a
tutorial that just shows you the basics
but uh git is one of the most complex
[ __ ] then then you have the commit
messages oh my
God so you know becomes a complexity by
itself can all this be avoided Yes
actually actually I think so you know
most of it most of the complexity you
know most of the complexity come come
from the C and Unix Fox okay they are
the they are the mother of almost
everything that's wrong in Computing
industry there's a reason you know why
things uh why things um happen that way
because for mostly social reasons but
anyway so what I want to say is can so
can all this problem be avoided I you
know yes in theory because if you stop
thinking from a
um uh how should I say explain
this if you design things and uh if
you basically if you stop hacking okay
you stop any Solution that's hacking
then almost all this problem will not be
created uh that's part of the reason the
other part of the reason for all this
complexities is due to uh the way
society and software are sold you know
social reasons you know tech companies
uh corruption in tech companies
competition
and lie and for example agil you know
agile you know that's one of the extreme
complexity that created
extreme [ __ ] [ __ ] lies in
software industry agile so why did they
why did why why did agile and all
extreme programming becomes more and
more I mean very
popular well that's because money you
know all these uh little companies they
create agile they they they tell you
that they can help your corporation save
money and so on money so they you know
they you have to pay them so you know
corrupt companies and corporations and
software industry and and uh and
including open source in fact lots of it
including open source because if you
know for example in Linux we have
extreme complexity Linux is the
worst uh desktop system okay the worst
desktop system system compared to
Windows or
Mac but why is it around and why it why
does it persist and why why does the
Linux [ __ ] persists you know like
Linux creates [ __ ] every day you know
gnome KD and you know it continues on
and on so why does it persist part of
the reason is not because you know the
open you know because the open source
fanatism again it's a social reason you
know the open source fanatism because
many of these people they believe they
are doing good for society you know they
they deeply believe they are doing moral
U you know they are morally Superior so
they they if you believe something
that's fine you do it yourself but the
thing with fism fanatic Fanatics is that
they want to other they you know they
push to have their op they force their
opinion on other people for example G
you know G or emx or you know Vim or SC
you you'll hear people so you should use
this you know this technology because
it's so great you really should that use
this technology because it's open source
you know for example when I was using
Mac or right now I'm on Windows lots of
my my viewers will say why why are you
using a Mac why are you using your
windows you know they all want you to
use Linux why because they have a open-
source fanatism you know they think they
are doing good but in fact
they they created a uh great wrong in
society this is how like some this is
you know uh this is getting into
politics this is what I think you know
why there are some great atrocities in
the world that happens in the world you
know million people dead why does it
happen because everyone you know wants
to be a good person right every nobody
wants to support the evil bad guys but
why does it happen it happens because
when you are the bad guy you don't know
it you think you are doing the good
thing and you want to spread it that's
why it happens of
often uh okay so that's about you know
so agile so complexities of software
industry so I I think maybe that's it
for today what
else what's wrong with agile in your
opinion well agile is just a bunch of
[ __ ] you know because so what's
wrong with agile
agile uh let me TR okay so you know so I
have a collection of articles about
agile okay uh voodo of software
engineering the first you know so what
is agile why I what's wrong with it it's
a code okay if you study codes you know
you can use you know for example even if
you go to Wikipedia you can find uh
certain characteristics of code or
different codes share you know there are
you know there's no exact definition of
code but usually they they share certain
uh characteristics for example usually
codes have one leader like one
dictatorship kind of leader and uh
usually all the members of the code
admire him you know you you you very
much admire one guy you know things like
that then code has a brainwashing
several brainwashing Tech techniques for
example controlling about food this
includes religion for example in
religion Christianity or Islam
they tell you what you can or cannot eat
and when you eat you have to pray so in
in in a sense they are controlling you
know when because food is the most
fundamental thing for survival food
eating you know you have to eat so coats
you know they always have something to
do with food because they associate with
food you know like you can some things
you cannot eat for example pigs or or uh
ox or you know depending on what uh uh
religion and then you have prayers
before food that means every time you
eat if you don't eat you're going to die
but every time you eat you have to by
the law of the Cod you have to think
about a Cod you know you have to thank
someone Cod you know whatever the code
says you have to you know do that so
controlling so anyway so back to codes
so there are some characteristics and uh
and many of these characteristics if you
look at agile they is somewhat similar
they share many of these uh things
okay
uh codes okay
for okay maybe I'm getting too far so
let me let me let me uh take it from
another perspective so why do I what
what what why do I think agile is very
bad if you look at agile you you see
what they say mostly uh
uh kind of this you know you know no non
science okay non science [ __ ]
basically you know agile they never tell
you for example those who push for agile
or extreme programming they never tell
you that okay if you want to write a
good software you need to study a lot
math you need to practice a lot coding
you need to understand things in detail
you need to uh you know be a better you
know a lot more about you know
programming understand the programming
language well you know all these are
qual uh qualities to write a great
software but aile is not like that aile
they tell you something else usually
it's about you know some mystical for
example if you want to lose weight there
are lots of you know uh crafts that
tells you about losing weight but the
most
fundamental uh way to lose weight you
know just stop eating okay stop eating
so much and stop eating junk food and go
exercise that's the Eternal that's very
basic Eternal way to lose
weight but people don't want to hear
that oh my God I have to know I I want
keep eating I want to keep eating junk
food I want to drink Pepsi every day I
want I want this that but I want to lose
weight without you
know uh and I don't want to exercise so
you know you have all this uh diet this
and that crap in the same way with the
uh extreme programming okay so you want
great software what does that mean you
know get great programmers programmers
you know study programming study
languages Master it Master everything
you know read documentation write good
documentation and so on so agile but you
know so agile doesn't talk about none of
that it doesn't talk about math how
program programmers should know math so
instead you have this kind of like uh
you know the
loose lose weight thing you know so uh
so you have you know look at look at
this you know can you tell me you don't
feel like this is some kind of cat
diagram some some new age so uh they
they you know a always have this kind of
thing you know this graph so PA
programming seconds code PA programming
and minutes unit test ours PIR
negotiation and stand up meeting and
accept test you know days then iteration
plan and you know all this
crap that's the nature of agile you know
so one of the characteristics you know
they have Jons they always have like
almost incomprehensible and how to
define joggin you know that agile's
concept okay so that's that and uh there
are some new terms from the millennial
generation you know one of them I
discovered few months ago is mechanical
sympathy mechanical sympathy a new Jon I
forgot what it is let's read about it in
programming Community a new fat is born
mechanical sympathy the term mechanical
sympathy was coined by racing by oh
there it is racing driver Jackie Stewart
and applied to software by Martin tomson
[ __ ] face a scum who who is this Jackie
St said you you don't have to be an
engineer to be a racing driver racing
driver but you have to have good
mechanical
sympathy he meant that understanding how
a Car Works makes you a better driver
okay this is just as true for writing
code you don't need to be a hardware
engineer but you do need to understand
how the hardware works and take that
into consideration when you design
software does that doesn't that sound
true that sounds so simple and true but
it's a
crap it's a complete garbage okay so he
is saying this so so this mechanical
mechanical sympathy is a jargon what
does it mean it it means that to be a
good you know good software programmer
you really need to understand some
aspect of Hardware yeah on a surface it
seems true but not when you put into you
know when you try to make a code out of
it when you have a shgon you know
mechanical sympathy for it why because
you know in fact I can statistically
speaking if you look at all the great
programmers okay I can tell you right
away a lot of them or even more majority
of the greatest programmers don't know a
[ __ ] about how Hardware works okay so
it's actually not necessary even to uh
to be a great
programmer you know and it's not
necessary to actually know
even a bit of
hardware and that is mathematically true
as well because why do I have to know
Hardware how how why why do I have to
know how CPU is designed why do I have
to know how memory designed suppose you
know depends on what programming you do
let's say you are a Java programmer Java
or let's say if you are JavaScript web
dev programmer you know if you want to
be a great web de programmer Master
JavaScript Master uh uh you know one of
the median uh Frameworks react you know
angular you can you know a lot of people
Master them Master CSS Master HTML you
know read their spec know them full well
you know CSS HTML
JavaScript you know you know this well
and you will be the great a great you
know one of the greatest javasript
programmer you don't even know what the
[ __ ] is a
CPU so apply that to this you know so so
this mechanical sympathy say oh to be a
great programmer you have to know CPU no
no you don't have to know Hardware what
the [ __ ] is this so this so this is a
example I I I suppose illustrates one of
the you know fake news you know fake
theories you know they they sell these
things to idiotic programmers you know
for for example if you are a beginner
you know you heard that programming can
make a lot of money program programming
is a future then you study programming
and you read you know then you read
Hacker News then you run into oh
mechanical sympathy oh my god oh I need
to understand
CPU yeah you need to understand but
that's that this is [ __ ]
okay yeah of course if you are a
programmer of course knowing Hardware
will help your career will help you know
it it it benefits you in general but it
doesn't make sense to single that out
because on the other hand knowing math
we also o benefit you a lot in fact
knowing mathematics in general benefit
you much more than knowing than this
mechanical sympathy
[ __ ] okay so in software industry we
have these kind of people you know so so
I I guess thank you for asking the
question you know about agile because
agile is the old thing you know we a lot
of people talk you know it's been talked
to death but this mechanical sympathy is
a new thing so I I hope I illustrate
what what's going on there you know so
in software industry software industry
is uh full of
um crap you know it's a social issues
and uh fake news and you know full of
um you know full of
uh fake false
things okay so that's it for today 56
seconds uh by the way I noticed when I
started this video Stefan wolam is live
so I was going you know I was watching
it you know I'm going to watch it you
know he was talking about you know I I
saw I saw for a few minutes so he was
talking about actually related to our
topic he's talking about you know uh
well oiled company and
Innovation I you know I didn't read I
didn't watch the whole thing I only saw
a few minutes but it seems like he's
talking about why or the situation about
Innovation you know how giant
corporations usually stop Innovation for
example Google when Google are smaller
in the first 10 years of Google Google
is one of the great innovator you know
Google created ethical ads they
basically
Google removed all the you know spammy
ads you know web from the web industry
that's the beginning of Google that's
why it become Google become very
successful you know and and lots of
Google Google did great Innovation to
the web you know that's well partly
because that's Google's business to to
make people use web instead of making
people using desktop applications like
you know Microsoft Windows so Google
want people to use web so Google have
put tremendous money and time to
innovate to to advance JavaScript to
advance web standards you know so so
compared to 10 years ago
oh you know web programming is much more
simpler because before every browser is
different you know then there's no
standard and you know you have to test
everything so Google did great a great
amount of innovation you know Gmail is
also Innovation because before before
web mail you know email application you
run on
desktop so and also Google Google
documentation Google Docs you know and
lots of things Google news but
but then Google today is so big you know
today's Google software you know most of
it is crap and it's not just crap it's
also uh unethical you know you know
Google become the worst evil empire in
the universe so I heard you know I think
uh Stephan wam is talking about some
something about Innovation and giant
corporations
how how they relate or how do you
prevent from being corporations and not
being Innovative you
know I think it's uh great to watch so
I'm so he Al I think he also talked
about his own
company uh it's very interesting because
you know Wan research you know it's been
over 30 years wolfan research and wolfan
research is a private company not public
you know he could have sold it like 20
years ago for millions of dollars and be
done with
but you know what happens when you
become public basically the just like
Google the product you know it becomes
crap it becomes political it becomes you
know it just become crap so he as far as
I know you know he you know he he he's a
guy with vision so he tightly control he
want you know his company to go in this
you know Direction tightly control it
he doesn't want to just you know like oh
sell it and become he's already rich
but possibly he can be much more you
know much more uh have a lot more money
if you if he uh you know open up the
company but he choose not to as far as I
know something like that so that's very
interesting
the process of writing good software
does not mean jamming every customer
feature in as soon as possible that is
true uh so so I think that's it for
today so thank you Troy for this
fantastic keyboard Signum 3 and Troy so
I want to ask you questions about how do
you actually program it because you know
so you're going to help me out so I I'm
going to make S fly Keys key map for
this and going to you know use this for
emac uh leaky abstractions okay uh but
on the core principle of agile sound no
the so Marx say but but on the core
principles of agile sound no like the
idea that getting feedback frequently is
a good
idea yeah that's the thing about these
Cy things so is you know for example if
you are you know if you do software so
is is getting a lot of feedback good
yeah of course it's good I mean you know
this you
know so so what so what so why do you
need agile yeah getting feedback
frequently is a good thing so what is a
saying so other people are not doing it
so instead you know AEL wants to create
a jargon and code you know they all
sounds nice that's a that's a problem
with these
codes uh so hello what other better
alternative to Agile do you think we
have you don't need you know you don't
need agile you don't need you you don't
need alternative like like what in the
in the first place what what do you want
to do you you know software engineering
you want to write a software just write
it
okay when you write the software if you
are not familiar with the programming
language learn more about the
programming language do more practice in
coding if you don't know about the area
for ex e-commerce for example or
chemistry if you are writing a software
for doing uh chemistry or doing math
then study more math okay if you are too
lazy you know you don't feel like
writing software then maybe you should
get out of the business you know or you
know try to be more disciplined you know
do more software
uh if so what is the problem you're
trying to
solve so at you know so if you have you
know uh if you have you know programmers
that doesn't do much and blame others
fire the guy okay fire the guy because
he's not doing work oh uh what you know
so if you want if you your software
becomes huge and complex then maybe you
got problem in communication in your
department
or something you know depending on what
software you're talking about how what's
a team size how complex are you are you
are you talking about software for
sending people to the moon or are you
talking about software like Facebook or
are you talking about you know one one
single person software or or you know so
if you got a problem solve it you know
why why do you need a special Cy you
know some some way something something
agile what is the problem
like so what so what I'm saying is that
you don't it's you don't need any of it
enti you know the the thing about this
code is
that they get you to think in their way
that so so every time you mention
including religion okay so when you talk
about religion you know for example the
first thing you know Western religion
I'm talking okay first Western religion
so you have the concept of God so first
of all you have to debate whether God
exist whether God exist or not you have
to debate it on and on you
know what the [ __ ] does it matter you
don't even have to think about that you
don't like before this you don't even
know there is such a thing you don't
think about it that's not the thing you
have to think about you got a problem in
life you solve it okay you're gonna die
yes you're gonna die
okay uh maybe in the future science you
know you can make you can live forever
maybe so that's the thing okay let Let's
uh let's thing about this a
thing agile is
systematized common sense no it's not
that at
all oh my God I I got I have to fight
agile you see how harmful it became you
know so so that's the thing about agile
you know it became deeply integrated
into each common people's
mind so so C is saying aile systemized
common sense so let me give you a
comparison to to to see that is not true
so Buddhism okay let's talk about
Buddhism because you probably don't know
much about Buddhism well maybe you do
came but
most western people don't know compared
to Asian people because we live it you
know it's in our daily life every day so
Buddhism so let me just say Buddhism is
a systemi systemized common sense do you
agree you are not likely to agree
because if you are Western you know
white people you live under Christianity
or is you know mostly Christianity you
wouldn't think what the hell Buddhism is
systemized common S no I have been
living all my life without you know
knowing a [ __ ] about Buddhism but I have
plenty of common sense so it doesn't
make sense to say Buddhism is like
system systematized common sense but to
our Asian especially those who believe
Buddhism that that seems true yeah yeah
of course Buddhism is a systemized
common sense it makes us to do a greater
good for the
humanity so you see so you see how that
sways your thinking so for someone who
have never heard of agile for example
before agile begin you know let's 20
years ago okay before this extreme
programming PA programming [ __ ] begin 20
years ago you know before a was Bor
nobody know what the [ __ ] is actually
you do have common sense among
programmers yeah of course and you can
does great software get created yes in
fact probably more so than today uh so
are you saying what so why do you need a
so so what so what does where does that
come
from okay that's it for today I think
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching
um I think that's it for today okay
so I want to show
uh signal keyboard I want to show okay
then well that's it for today thank you
guys for watching bye guys