Hello hello hello good morning good
morning everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show so today we're
going to code uh emac bisp we are going
to code multiple languages golan e emac
bisp that's today but this is in a
series of building a hash table also
known as map
or uh dictionary in golan
in EMAC lisp, in wam language and in
let's say powershell. So and maybe in
python. So we started yesterday. So
yesterday we uh we build a hasht uh not
just building a hash table but also
traverse a directory. The directory is
like 40,000 files. Okay. So um so you
know so traverse a directory of 40,000
files uh or more make them into a hash
table. So we're going to do that in
several languages and then we're going
to go through the hash table uh for each
key
check if it exist. This is for the
purpose of checking the file exist as a
replacement. And we're going to taste
test the speed of all these languages.
Okay. And you know language comparison
comparative language study. So we can
see you know for example the go code
yesterday. Uh let's see you know this
quite long. It's like 30 lines just to
go through a directory and build a hash
table. Also there's a condition uh go
through a directory but if the file
directory name is one of these given
then omit it so this is important part
because with this then then there's some
trick in depending on the languages you
know some languages make it so easy some
languages not so much so yesterday I
tried to do this in wuan language one
single line but failed um well partly
because I'm not too familiar with this
this uh this usage of wam language. So
anyway, so
so yeah, so let's build this. So so
let's um so let's build a hash table. Uh
I just discovered there's something
wrong here. Okay, so this is uh this
talk show and uh this is yesterday. Open
it. Uh go to the bottom.
This is placed in the wrong position.
this
nav panel. Okay. Where's the main? Oh
yeah. So
this topic box should be inside the
main. That is why you are seeing uh you
know so now you know formatted outside
of it. So refresh now it's good.
Okay. So let's start. So today is so
yesterday you know you can watch
yesterday we built Goland. Uh today
let's do emac bisp. Emac bbis I've done
it a thousand times so it should be
easy. So are we ready? Yes. Are you guys
ready? So if you are watching this
offline play at 1.5 speed. Okay. So
yeah. So we going to start to write emac
this code. Okay. So the the task is
specified here. Okay. Let's copy it.
Okay. So this is today. Yeah. So let's
start
uh emac this
uh
okay and uh start and paste it. So
that's the documentation.
Create a hash table. Each key is a full
file path of a dur including
subdirectory but excluding given list of
the names. Then test speed by go through
the hash table. Check each key exist.
Okay, then do this in Golan and stuff.
Okay. So,
so if you have comments, question said,
okay, do you prefer Windows Linux? That
question been asked one million times
and I've answered one million times.
Just search my YouTube. Uh, okay.
Uh, okay. So, build a hasht. So, so
there are two things involved. First of
all, you want to walk a directory, then
build a hash table. So, walk direct
directory. How do you do that? That's uh
here you can search for it emacs list
tutorial. Um so, we want all
subdirectories too. So, here is the
code. Here's the documentation. And
let's just copy the copy it.
Okay. So, we go through walk directory
then build hash table. Okay. Now, there
are some directories we don't want,
right? Let's so let's copy exactly what
is the directory should be excluded.
Okay. This is important part. So there
okay uh so first of all write
documentation first.
Okay. So exclude this.
So so this is scholan code. Uh so this
make it uh make it emac list. So this is
going to be a list. Okay. So wait.
So
remove the comma
because in list you don't you don't want
comma. Okay. So um
yeah you can do that or actually just
Uh okay. So let's do that and u
set a variable and uh
skip
the okay something like that.
Skip the equals to
that. Okay that's a eag this way. Now,
now traverse the directory. Now, first
of all, what's the input? So, so
input. So, you need the input for now.
Let's go to uh talk show page for
testing. So, so that it's not too long.
So, input is just talk show. Okay. Uh
yeah. So, now build a hash table. So, uh
Okay. So, so that is this function
directory files exclusively. We need to
go fast comments. Okay. So,
so yeah. So, um, so the ping window
shows all my command calls and
keystrokes. Okay. So, so directory files
recursively and here is the input path.
Okay. Now input let's name it
X input D because that makes it easier
to complete. So
so recursively go into this directory
then what is the file name extension? I
don't think we care. We want all files.
So go back to uh EMAC bisp. So what is
the documentation?
the regular expression the regular
expression uh return names that contains
the pattern. Okay.
Now you see the Emacs directory traverse
function is not very good. Okay. Because
I've used it you know tens of times like
for 20 years. Uh it's not very good.
It's not very flexible and it's ve it's
fairly slow. it's much slower than uh
other languages.
Uh for example, one of the example is
that suppose you want to list all
directories that are empty. So you have
lots of directories, you know, you you
want to you know list all directories
that's empty in a directory
that you know try to write that you you
think it's just one line but not that's
going to be fairly complicated. Okay. Um
I can show you the code. Okay, I can
like quickly show it show you it. Okay,
so uh kasan dd uh list empty. Okay, so
wait wait wait where is it? list empty
directory. Okay, so you go jump to the
source code. So this here is how you
write it. Okay, this this um
Okay, this code uh actually not so
trivial.
Okay, so let's go get back to uh what we
want to do. So, so input directory then
here is a regular expression. Now, uh
you can pass a dot that just match
anything. But I remember there is
something
special. Okay.
Um
you know this you can just say a dot
that matches anything. So but I remember
there's something special. Okay. Anyway
let's let's push on. So what's the next
argument? And also uh emac this does do
not you know you have a whole bunch of
um arguments ordered arguments. So it's
very confusing which one is which. So
anyway, directory regular expression
optional include include directories. Um
do we want to include directories?
Yes.
Okay. Yes. Then what's the next? Uh then
directory predicate.
Okay. So this part is the directory
predicate. Okay. So directory predicate
in this case um
filter.
Okay. Neo dive into all subdirectories.
Okay.
Yeah. So this part
right. So this part is um
actually if it's a directory ignore it.
Okay. We don't want to you know this
will return a list. So we don't want to
include directories. Okay. So the
regular expression include directories.
The regular expression include
directories neo. Okay.
Now the predicate which is a function
that filters. Okay. So
the function is passed a subdirectory
full path.
Okay. Uh if f returns true dive in into
that uh otherwise no. Okay. The function
is passed the subject. So what
what uh do we have not string match?
So this is uh this is skip skipping all
files.
Now in our case what we want to skip is
we want to skip this. So the function
will be
if
that
matches
any of that then skip. Okay. Yeah. Uh
I've written this somewhere before
mathematics teacher uh would be a cool
high school teacher.
Okay. So
I've written this before. So why don't
we just look at our code? So save save
us some time. So yeah. So why don't we
do that? So go to my a brief file just a
brief file that is all my personal in
it. So now just search search for that
you'll find I'll I'll kind of find it.
Okay. So
side external doc.
Okay.
Uh what is this? Is old code. I don't
want that one.
So what
finder ex okay so I have it there
describe variable.
So this is in package casind. Okay. So
search for that.
Okay. So this this is a function I wrote
find ignore the true root path. So
return true if one of the
uh
find the ignore rejects list.
Yeah. Okay. It's getting complicated.
Let's copy the file path here. Okay.
Let's paste that.
So find the ignore regular expression
this. So this is actually a list of
expression. Okay, the GX match case
sensitive. Okay, so uh and uh and the
function that actually does that is
this. Okay.
And what are the others?
And here this one is filter by path
regular expression.
Okay. So this you see
it becomes slightly complicated.
Uh
so this is EMAC this case. So what
so any anyway let's
okay let's let me just do this. Okay.
So,
so this is input.
Let's skip the
Okay. So, and uh what is our solution?
Now, these are exact directory names you
want to skip. Okay. Now if you want to
turn it you you know if you want to
implement them as a uh list of regular
expressions you can uh but the
specification by our problem is exact
biopath names.
Okay. So um
so we
so let's see we this will return a list
of the names and uh what this lambda
exactly pass a subdirect directory full
path
pass a subdirectory full path what it
doesn't make sense
okay this part I need to elaborate
because exactly what is a
subdirectory full path I suppose it
means
the full path of a direct directory but
minus the minus the root something like
that but we can test it here okay so
right now it's skipped in skipping dot
skipped in dot okay so we can just say
message printed
Um
let's just say x is
x. Okay, it's not that. Okay, so that is
that and uh this ignore it. Put it here
and uh here also
remove it. So here is our code.
Okay, here is our code.
Um, here's a code. We can run it. Okay,
so and we'll print a bunch. Then we we
will know exactly what is passed there.
Okay, run it.
Something is wrong. It's not running.
Uh,
why is that? What's going on? Oh, it did
print. Okay, it did print. So, you can
see Oh, okay. It's It's printing the
full path.
Okay, now that's good.
Okay, so now you need just to extract.
So given a full path, how do you get the
the base name? Okay, it um
let's run again. Show. Okay, here is a
example so you can see. Uh let's go to
talk show.
[Music]
Let's go to talk show. go to the
directory. So you can see
you see there's I and IPC
directories subd. So these are uh these
are a bunch of okay these are audio
files
and these are image files image files
and uh and whatnot.
That's one of the advant of code uh
problem.
So you you see we got this these subd
directories. Okay. Uh we got those
subdirectories and uh let's paste it
there and then we can document this this
my tutorial. Okay.
So this is confusing. Let's just name it
just you know uh
f is past
full path. Okay. And also
without the without the ending slash
uh because normally Emacs always prints
you know ending slash. Okay. Um
but without
the ending slash. So to the browser
refresh. So this is critical because
when you process directories you know I
do this in so many languages in the past
20 years
you know some use backslash some use
forward slash and also for a directory
you have to think about whether the
directory ends in a slash or not
because you need to know because then
when you want to join the file or or get
the parent directory uh you know you
know you want to join two path you make
We want to make sure there's only one
slash. So, so the detail about exactly
what it returns, you know, this function
takes is important. Okay. So, but now we
clarify it with the example. Okay. Good.
So, that is what the function get. Okay.
Now, back to our code. Uh,
back to our code. So this is a sample.
Um so now we know
now we know that we can simply get the
uh
uh file path. Okay. Uh
file path
file name directory. Um
yeah we can simply do that. So for
example
wait uh
okay so
that is the file path put it there and
uh remove that and uh
evaluate it. You see uh now that is
incorrect.
So, so you see even So, okay. So, what
you want is file name.
Yeah. You see it's misleading. So, what
you want is
that's what we want. Okay. File name
none directory. So,
so here x
now
you get the non directory which is the i
part then you want to see if it matches
any one of those. Okay. So,
so here you know here is another
problem. If it matches return true okay
in that case we can use emac lisp
let's go to our talk show
uh let's go to our talk show
okay hasht we
so let's go land that's goland that's uh
what we
file path functions okay delete the
goland stuff. Okay. Delete the Goland
stuff. Okay. So, file path functions and
what we want uh we want the
uh
yeah so we we want list functions. Okay.
So, so list basics go to list list
structure
uh sequences. Yes, there. So we want
some and every okay
sequence them and sequence every
yeah as soon as you found the item
return it you know don't continue
because
this would be efficient okay so copy
that code
uh but copy the file path here first
make
file path there so go there then copy
the code now go to our code
So now here is what we want. Okay. So
let's
let's be very careful here. Okay. So
lambda here is a sample x.
Okay. And uh this this is a string of
course. Okay. Then then then
this part we will use. Okay. Now file
name n directory. So we're going to do
sequence sum. That's right. Is that
right? Yeah. That's in. Okay. So now
we're going to do sequence sum. Okay.
Now sequence sum lambda again nested
lambda. Now this x will be y.
Let's just change it to y. Okay. And uh
then
sequence sum
uh
so let's use a let here. Okay. Let
the name. Okay. Let X the name just show
dot the name no um no nothing. Okay. So
that will be that.
Okay. That sets the directory name.
Okay. Uh uh this part we don't care.
Okay. We don't care. Then sequence some
move inside py. Fantastic. Okay.
So now the name is just a single i for
example. Now sequence them
lambda
y y.
Now if so the sequence is going to be
this sequence sap.
Okay, let's change it. Um
uh what?
Skip the list
the ignore list.
Okay, let's change change.
Uh because naming is very important. So
this is going to be extra
names ignore list. Okay, make it you
know so people read it. We'll know
exactly these are not you know because
in this kind of thing sometimes you want
you know sometimes you have a list of
regular expressions. Sometimes you have
you know a list of names but you mean
containing that part. So any directory
name contains that ignore it. But
sometimes you want exact directory name
match. If exactly match then ignore it.
For example, git. You know if a
directory name is exactly.getit,
you want to ignore it. But not if the
directory name is something
something.getit,
you know, you know, so uh this is kind
of
confusing. Okay. So anyway, so let's go
back here. So if
if the the current name So wait. So
okay. And we're going to use string
equal. Okay.
If string equal the name is one of this
you know y
then
then return true right sequence sum yeah
then return uh then return true that
means ignore it
okay so what what is the logic you know
sometimes They uh
what is the the um
work directory? Okay, there work
directory
predicate function
function. If function return true dive
into that directory. Okay. So,
so if it matches this ignore then new
otherwise true.
Okay. So let's see if if string equals
the current name
matches one of these ignore the name
then return neo otherwise return true
okay carefully
uh so this make can this can be one line
okay kind of okay so that is good so I'm
sure I'm sure um
purify the code. Okay. So, recursively
input the
dot means no filter. But there is a uh
more efficient way. So, this is a
complexity of the emac this directory
walk
uh walk directory walk um function.
Okay. So, let's see the documentation.
So you see regular expression um Yeah.
Yeah.
It's not here, but I remember maybe it's
in this.
Yeah, it's here. Directory files.
The return path may include the Unix dot
means the current. Okay. So that is the
directory files.
So to exclude them use match regular
expression that does not match dot.
Okay. Yeah. So there is this building
variable directory files no dot file
regular expression
uh there.
Okay. directory files no file you know
this is like um a hack so describe
variable that variable so you can see
it's a built in constant
whose value is this
um so this relates to
directory files function okay okay so
but does not relates to
directory files recursively.
So you see that's a confusing part. You
need to know these details. So that's so
I but in in our case we don't need to
worry about it. Okay. I think that's it.
That's that that's that. Um then this is
our code and this we don't care. This is
just um
okay let's run it. Right.
It doesn't do anything. Now you need to
print it. Okay. So now you need to um
Oh, did you actually build a hash that
way? Okay. So this return you need to uh
say
okay set file list then that that
okay then you can print file list okay
evaluate it then describe variable so
you can see
there it is okay So,
so you can see it's got like
2,000 files. Casar talk show. Okay,
2,000 files talk show including image
files. Now, there's a problem because
it, you know, it went into the image
directory which is named I, but we told
it not to go into image directory.
So our code is incorrect.
What the
And also if you want to match anything
just empty empty regular expression will
do also because we can try it uh
describe variable. Yes. Okay. But now is
the problem is with the uh it went to
you know it went to the image directory.
Did we have this correct?
Actually the name ignore list value is
yes.
Okay. So
sequence lambda.
Now if
string equal the name
y.
So let's rename ignored. Okay. So rename
y
ignore name.
So if string equal the name
file name then directory
Wait. So how do you know that? So is
this predicate does this predicate
always receive a directory or not?
Uh
okay. So you have to say include
directories.
What?
So the predicate. So it's a directory
predicate. So it's not just any file. So
this predicate is only for directory.
Okay. Filter on which subdirectory to
dive into
regular expression is applied first.
Okay. Uh before the predicate sees it.
Okay. So,
so match anything that's a regular
expression. Then neo means neo means we
don't care about directories.
Include directories. True means in a
result include path
that are directories. So false we don't
want a list of the directories.
But however we want to go into
subdirectories. So that is this the
predicate.
Have you ever seen Windows 11 before?
No.
Uh
what is this? So can we just evaluate
the whole thing again? describe bar.
Let's see it
sequence sum.
Okay, so in sequence sum returns true.
Okay, so you need to actually kind of
reverse this.
So,
so if
if string equal
return new
so we Don't need the whole if. Okay. Uh
just check that. Okay.
If it's equal then
So as soon as there is a true
exit.
Okay. Sequent as soon as there. So we
instead we want sequence every
Oh, okay. So, let's
path functions. So, talk show path
function sequence.
Okay, I think sequence every is what I
want. Yeah, that's right. Sequence
every. Okay. not
not the uh sum.
Okay. So, sequence every
sequence every
Okay, as soon as the value is false, the
loop stops. Okay, so
if so, you know, we got into a confusion
of boolean values,
you know, whether true is good or
false is good. There are two levels of
it. one level is within the sequence
every the other level is you know what
it's meaning in the subdirectory
so but here um
so if string equals to ignore
if that is true
so uh but overall this needs to return
so true means dive in
okay whether we want to dive into the
directory. So,
so that Neo, so that returns Neo
otherwise true.
Okay. Yeah, that's what we want. I'm
pretty sure.
Prefy the code.
I think that's good. Okay, we can run
the code. Run it
now. Describe variable that
check.
Fantastic. You don't see the I
directories anymore. You see? But now
you have the I IPC directory. We can
ignore it too if we want. If we just add
IPC for example.
IPC. Run it. Describe variable that.
and you don't see the IPC directories
anymore. So fantastic. So this is
fantastic coding and done.
Okay, very simple. Now we go into each
hash table and just check
Okay. So what we do now is we go through
the hash table.
Okay. How do you do that? So first of
all put the code back color syntax color
show in browser. So that is the fruit of
today. So now we go through the hash
table for each key we check if the key
exist. Um we do that because ultimately
we want to check the file exist.
But since we build a hasht wait did we
build a hash table yet? No not yet. Okay
let's build a hash table.
We haven't built a hash table yet. Okay
so let's
do it. Okay. So, but we got the file
list. So, let's create a hasht x table.
Okay. Then m uh okay create a hash
table. Uh then
uh then what to do? Um
so the default test is equal does equal
test string equality.
Uh let's check.
Yes. Good. It's kind of confusing
because in EMAC list you have equal, you
also have EQ
and you have string equal. You have
quite a few others or you and you also
have the equal sign.
Uh so anyway, so equal is good. Uh so
now we want to build hash table. So
first of all you need to go through this
um okay map C
uh map
map C
map a function to this file list and for
each one what to do we
hasht add
Uh,
put hash. That's right.
Mhm. Key
will be just the file path.
Value
will be we don't care one. Table will be
X table. Okay. Now
evaluate it. Fantastic. Now just print
the hash table. Okay. Now can we print a
hash table?
Clear map hash. Uh yeah. So you can map
hash. You can also pretty print hash
table. Okay. We got a code just let's
just use it. Why not?
So format hasht. Oh well. Okay. Format
then then uh print
print
format hasht x table.
Okay.
Format into a string. Then just print.
So we don't actually we don't even need
the format there. Okay. Evaluate it.
Show the messages buffer.
Fantastic.
There it is. Our hash table.
Okay. Done. Now,
now that's it. Okay. So
now we need to now the last thing to do
is some timing like we talked before we
need to check how long does the whole
thing take. Okay so put the code back
show in browser. Okay so we need to do
timing.
Um,
so for example, yesterday. Let's go to
yesterday. Okay. Backup. Close. Open.
Now clean up. What is this? Okay. So,
what is it? We don't need that. So, um,
so,
so what are we doing? Okay. Go to topics
box. Go to yesterday's talk show and go
to uh Golan.
Okay. This is yesterday's code. This is
Skolan. It's a different beast. So,
let's run it. See how long does it take.
So, this is Sally info. You see exactly
the same uh ignore uh
list of file names. Okay.
Run it.
First time is slow because it's going
through like 20,000 files or something.
Okay. Time spent in 1.2 seconds. Let's
run it again. Open it. Time spent in 0.1
seconds. So that including traverse the
directory you know go line is more
tedious. You know you this is how you
traverse the directory with this walk
walk the okay then then you build a hash
table here then you print the time. So
run it you know 0.1 seconds. Uh
so in the EMAC so let's uh let's print
how many items in the hash table we need
to know that okay so how do you print
how many items in the hash table so I
don't remember so let's go to goland
map
uh create map with make get value get
value add key delete key loop what is
the count
bad tutorial. I don't have the
information. I mean we I don't have the
easy to see information about how do you
get the length of the hash table. So
what so so that means I need to think
so Golan
switch mind uh to go language hasht.
So what uh I believe it's just count
right?
Do you guys know
interesting? I don't even have a count
length of hash table. What?
My tutorial is failing.
count. Okay.
Interesting. I don't have that
information. Uh, okay.
Let's see. Goland count map.
How to count items in go map
len. Okay. So,
obviously len
Okay. So, let's print len
um
then x table. So,
right.
So first of all it prints all of them.
Uh
let's see.
So there there are about 17,000
17,000 files in.info.
Okay. So go to the bottom the exactly
17,04.
Okay.
Um
now you see when you print it, it takes
a long time. So the time stamp needs to
go before it. Okay. We don't want the um
we don't want the time stamp there.
Okay. So there. Now run it.
Uh what?
Yeah. So it takes 0.1 second not
counting the time to print. Okay. So go
is pretty fast. So but
but there are 17 and four items. Okay.
So that's goland. Close.
Put it back. Syntax correct show in
browser. Fantastic.
Now back to Emac this code. Now we hope
Emac bisp code maybe better maybe not.
Okay so but first of all you need to
compute the time information guard. I
don't know how to do that. Okay. So, we
go to EMAC this basics.
Uh, search for time
print date time. Well, okay. So,
so you got can we get the Unix seconds?
Okay, there it is. Unix time.
Close that. So
set
start time.
Okay. Something like that. What
uh this annoying annoying syntax for the
comment. You know, you don't want a you
don't want comment syntax. that is
whites space sensitive. In the case of
Emacs, it is because it relies on the
end of line. So what does that mean is
that it stops your syntax
being capable of of of made into one
line, you know,
and and or reverse it, you know. So it's
basically stops auto formatting
capabilities.
So whenever you have a
syntax in your language that is whites
space dependent,
it stops your programming language from
being able to automatic format the code
in to some degree.
So typically in every language their
stream is always whites space sensitive
obviously because you know obviously
because when you want whites space in it
but
so almost all all languages has this
issue. So but however if we exclude
strings then we have the common issue.
So for most languages actually vast
majority of uh industrial programming
idiots C, C++, Python especially uh
Ruby, Bash, PowerShell they all
basically have a common syntax that is
dependent on the end of line which is a
white space. So that means
you cannot just like compact your code
like you can you cannot make it this in
into whole line. it won't you know
because it then it up you know the
whole thing becomes a comment undo
so but if you have a language that
doesn't you know there whose comment
does not depends on end of line such as
Pascal wra language P hascal
and others then you don't have this
problem you don't and html
because their common is is matched you
know in the case of wam it's penians
star and also for Pascal for Pascal it's
uh angle brackets with a dash inside
and for HTML it's angle bracket and two
dash something like that so but anyway
if you have matched comment that does
not depends on the line ending then then
your programming language maintains the
automatic formatting ability
so that that is an interesting issue.
Okay, about that. So anyway, let's go
back to this. So we got the time.
Let's evaluate it. Yeah, we got the time
in seconds. Then go to the bottom. So it
should be pretty simple. So before we
print, we want to say uh end time. Okay,
so end time.
Okay. Then you just say uh print
print uh start time
minus uh oh you cannot minus in elies.
So
uh
okay then time spent.
Okay, that should print it. So, let's
run it. Okay.
Uh yeah,
right.
Uh wrong argument number or marker.
Okay. So, oh this got time.
Okay. You need to true number. Okay. So
uh string true to numbering
string true number.
Okay. Run it.
Okay. So now we got the whole hash table
here. And uh do we have time? So is
there's too many of it is square off the
buffer. So,
so well then we have to create a buffer.
We have to print you know we cannot use
messages. We have to print into a
dedicated buffer.
So this is like entirely boring for you
guys I guess uh because too much
technical details now. Okay. So let's um
end time start time. So we need to
create okay. So let's go to buffer.
When your program is complicated and
especially when you are printing
thousands in this case like what what
was it uh
17,000 1 1700 uh lines.
You don't you do not want to print to
the messages buffer. You want to create
a dedicated buffer because you can see
the messages buffer just squirreled
off you know a maximum of 1,000 lines
you know it just scroll off. So you want
to So here is when we want to So let's
um
e this print daytime and we want to go
to
uh buffer. Okay. So that would be eac
this buffer in files.
Okay. So buffer functions. So we want to
create the buffer.
Yeah. Usually usually we want to use
this. Okay. I'm not going to explain
because it's
gets complicated. Okay. So but now
so now actually let's create a let.
Okay. So because now it's getting big.
Okay. So new buffer
new buff.
Okay. We declare a variable new buff.
And uh this buffer will be uh
x table output. Okay. Let's name that.
And by convention,
Emacs generated buffer has a name of
star before and end at the end. Okay. So
now we create a new buffer
and uh and and uh okay. So then then you
can move this inside and then you can
say with output to buffer
uh without to buffer.
Okay, wait there's a command with output
to buffer. Okay,
so now you need to go to print.
Okay. Go to print
print output. Okay. Print to buffer
print. Uh so we can use with output to
temp buffer.
With output to temp buffer.
What?
So I guess I don't have
uh a brief for it.
Okay. So buffer name will be
new birth. Then
then then buffer rest body. Okay. So
rest body. So what you want to do is we
uh we want to print that
okay and not messages. Okay. So we want
to print
okay and uh and also
okay this function.
Yeah. Well,
okay. So this function, okay, leave it
there. So, but
print predify it. Okay.
Redundant. Okay. So, kind of like that.
Uh then let's add
Okay, let's add lexical binding. Okay,
because that
I think makes it faster a bit.
Compare it. No error. Good. Okay, now
can we run it? Yes.
Oh, uh, how many items in hash table?
So, you need to print it. Okay, so I
want to know how many items in hash
table. So,
so print and uh
how do you find out how many items in
hash table? So, walk directory
file path functions every walk directory
print hash table. Uh yeah. So, go back
length. Oh, actually hasht count. Okay,
so
hasht count
x table. Okay, that returns uh whatever
put it here.
Okay,
so total items.
and uh then switch to buffer. Okay. Then
you just say switch to buffer.
Uh
new buff.
Okay.
Okay. Right.
Invalid function one.
What?
print invalid function. So some
Oh okay. So
so yeah you need format there
format
that
and
that is inside pretty.
Okay
evaluated. Fantastic time spent zero. So
it's even less than a fraction of a
second. Total items 164.
Oh, so it's different from the Goland.
The Golan is 17
and4. So Goland somehow got
uh 1,00 I mean 100 more files. Well,
I can see you see we got some uh some
Emacs backup files. So let's remove
those backup files. Okay. So anyway,
this is the result from EMAC. This
fantastic and beautiful
play code back showing browser. So this
is today's result. Fantastic. And
yesterday's beautiful code is this
goland.
But now let's go let's go to the
directory. Okay. So uh sorry info. So I
just press the key.
Press press press.
Do you want to delete all these backup
files? Yes.
Okay. So So not many. So what why is
there a difference? You know, so let's
run it again. Okay. So
Oh, because uh let's see.
because yeah so we don't want this I
here okay we want to make sure they are
the same get manual closure JJS not okay
run it so
total items weight now it's 20
wait why is it 200 now oh yeah because
yes 2000 two 2135. Okay. Now close that.
Put it back. Syntax clear. Go to
yesterday's talk show.
Now open the Golan file.
Now make sure the skip the is the same.
Prefy the code and uh
run.
Okay. So in the Goland case it's
23,000 files. So they are not exactly
the same.
I have to figure out why. Okay. the
result is
different. Uh I have to figure out why
is that exactly.
Okay, but that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching.
Yeah,
put a code back.
Uh syntax code showing browser.
Okay, bye guys. If you like my stuff,
pay me. Okay,
seven people watching. So, go to.info.
kxi.info
and uh at the bottom you can see my
Patreon gift card, Amazon gift card or
PayPal. So, if you work
in a corporation, just pay me a 100.
Thank you.
So, that's it. Okay, we shut down in one
minute.
So today is kind of like real life
coding because in real life coding you
got you know kind of lots of
complexities.
I mean compared to actual real life
today is actually pretty simple. You
know, all we want to do is actually
create, you know, walk walk into a
directory and uh ignore certain
directories and just create a hash table
very simple and print a hash table.
But then we have to look into we spend a
lot of time into you know look into the
technical details of this directory file
recursively
you know in a necessary necessarily way
because you know this predicate this
regular expression uh gets very
confusing and whether you know the
backslash or slash stuff.
So we then we looked into hasht uh then
we have to write a function to print
pretty print then file path functions um
and sequence sum and sequence every this
is functional way to do things and print
print. Okay bye guys.