good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
now this is called tv maybe
and today is 2019
may 2nd saturday
4 o'clock p.m california time
welcome all
and today we have topics of course we
have some topics
i don't know what i'm talking about but
we have topics
and the topics is going to be people ask
me questions on
discord star discord so i'm going to
answer them
and that's gonna be today's topic and i
have a few others
but i didn't well let's just talk about
the topics okay
so good morning alan morningbot and
morning
many others ronnie race
okay so let's talk let's talk about
topic okay let's go to discord
and let's go to up go up up up here
starting here
and alan says
can you make predictions for the future
of web technologies
specifically do you think web assembly
plus low-level stuff will take off
on the internet will javascript
dominance be
challenged okay i'm going to answer that
question
why do well so there's the why am
why do i cover one of my eyes because
i've got cross eye cause i problem
uh and i think i had it when i was young
usually you cannot see it
you can you will not notice it until i
look at you
from you know one of my eye you can see
i switch
switch switch so usually you cannot see
it
notice but it's getting bad it's getting
worse in the past two years because i've
been
looking at staring at the computer
screen non-stop
for up to 20 hours a day for 10 years
in the past since since about 19 2010
you know so it's critically important
you take breaks
you know actually i've been sitting in
front of computers all my life you know
that's
i'm a nerd i'm a superior nerd i'm an
extreme
schizoid nut which is a topic i talked
about many times
and so i sit in front of the computer
more than
anyone so it's gonna be a world record
something like that
in the past 10 years if you measure
statistically how long you sit in
you sit in front of a computer so on
average in the past
10 years i would be the top
let's say the the top 200 in your united
states
of all people so that's how long i sit
sit in front of computers and i
type all day and night so that's
the answer to one of the questions now
back to the javascript question
uh we have so many questions so i'm
gonna get them okay
why did my background change that's
interesting question because
my mom died okay my mom died in january
and there are changes in life so now you
are looking at
a big room behind me
i'm not ready to show it you know i'm
not gonna because there are some issues
so i'm
not gonna talk up much about that now
let's get back to
uh javascript do you think javascript
what do you think about the
web assembly and and those technologies
will they uh become the you know
extremely popular
actually i don't know you know i think
you know i don't have
specific opinion about that but in
general
as technology marches on
web assembly is you know it's kind of
it's it's been around for a few years
you know and uh
i think you know it's gonna be around
and it's going to stay
and it's probably will become bigger and
bigger
uh and right now not that many people
use it i mean
for average web developers you create
websites you just call javascript
or typescript or whatever you know
several javascript on top of javascript
languages wrappers and so on or you
compile to javascript and so on
we talked about this many times but but
there's web assembly which is you
which is kind of a a
subset of javascript that other
languages
can you know it's standardized so any
other language will compile to it
and in fact you can write encoding c or
c
plus for the same compiled web assembly
and you'll run
and by that means many there are many
demonstrations that you can see
they are running windows 95 you know
windows point you know 3.0 from 1995
on the web or some other old program
stars or whatever you can run them on
the web now
and they are using webassembly so they
are you know the c
plus plus or c code they are compared to
uh web assembly
uh so it's gonna it's a and it's a big
technology it's a great technology it's
going to stay
uh but we all it replaced javascript
how you know what will happen to it will
it becomes you know
like almost it's like every language
compiles to it
i don't know as you know i i don't have
a strong opinion on that
uh and that's low-level stuff you know
i'm i'm not into low-level
low-level languages and stuff so [ __ ]
them
okay so uh
but it's a good thing i think you'll
become more popular but i don't know to
what degree or
uh or will javascript become less and
less critical
javascript will not become less and less
critical
because it's it's part of the you know
it's the most
standard normal approachable
programming language when you want to do
web dev you know so it's not going to go
away anytime soon it's not going to
subside anytime soon but web assembly
will be
pretty important i think so
another question from alan aesthetic art
question
discussed here a while back what are
your thoughts on more modern remakes
such as notre dame cathedral new style
roof
okay now let me tell you about that
story
now keep the comments uh going okay uh
put the name to me so i can see it
now am i doing okay i see you are aware
of the portal
what do you think about it it's crap
okay this
someone asked me well the uh aratus
what's his name
he it's one of the questions that we'll
get into this guy okay it's a crackpot
crap geometric unity crap
we're gonna talk about that but let's go
back to
uh one one thing at a time okay so
what's the next question the okay so
let's go back to you
uh discord sorry discord fantastic
people variegated opinions so but
join discord okay so
aesthetic odd question so what do i
think of notre dame
cathedral now let me tell you the story
the notre dame cathedral
uh about a year ago last year three few
uh four four months ago or so they
burned
down well part of it burned down so it's
a big
giant disaster and everyone everyone is
oh my god
the history is gonna the the the [ __ ]
brainless [ __ ]
these normal people okay pop
the masses you know they don't think
they don't read history
they don't know nothing about history no
not that no nothing they don't they are
no nothing else
they just they they you know they they
talk on youtube on twitter
this the millennial gym they know
nothing noth nothing else
but then when something like this burned
down it happens oh and then
then if they are like oh my god oh oh
history
is burned down but but what do you know
what what the [ __ ] do you know about
history nothing
nothing okay so it burned down
and it became it's it's a political
issue because
uh because you know notre dame cathedral
is a cathedral right so it's
for christians catholics primarily i you
know i
so um and today in the politics you have
in usa america for example you have the
uh republic consent versus the demo
democrats oh [ __ ] so am i still doing
okay
cause depths are millennial gen okay so
i guess i'm still doing okay so anyway
so the notre dame cathedral it became
burning down it become it is it is a
political um
issue you know a giant political point
because
in usa for example you have the
republican party versus the social
justice [ __ ] party
the democratics okay and
the republicans are usually mostly they
are based on christianity you know they
are religious people
following tradition and other things in
general you know
christianity is a big thing in in
republic you know in the republic
uh the right wingers you might call it
meanwhile the social justice scan party
the the
the democratic party they are they are
pro-islamic
okay yeah so there's a big fight
and uh every day in the past few years
we hear oh bombing
islamic terrors the bomb here bomb there
burning down this uh
church church burn down you know here
and there
so it's a big issue now so now the
question is how did it happen
who burned it down is it the accident or
is it some
islamic people uh i'm not sure
actually um anyway there's conspiracy
theories okay i haven't looked into
exactly uh
what but we let's assume it's an
accident
i suppose i guess let's assume it's an
but anyway it became a political issue
then there then you know so this
this uh this cathedral is how how many
years old
let's see um this cathedral
is one thousand years old let's see
uh location uh demonet
demand demand
denomination catholic denomination
catholic
tradition roman right website no they
got a website
website oh modern status damaged by fire
style french gothic year built
19 uh 1163 to
1345 so it's
uh seven years 700 years old you know so
it's huge you know you have to imagine
700 years ago we don't have technology
that's before the
industrial uh evolution revolution
you know before we have steam engines
and all that
well we probably have is we probably had
sting
steam engines since the ancient greeks
but we don't have the giant steam engine
trend anyway so this is
um pretty old and they build religion is
the
uh in many ways region holds people
together he
holds uh human animals together so you
have a goal
instead of being goalless like me so you
have some sort of god religion
and and this is huge and giant it's a
great undertaking you know they
it took them 200 years to build it and
and religion is very much tied uh to
power and control and politics because
back then it is religion that priests
you know priests they uh how do you call
it um
ah metrocard matrix metrocracy or what
uh
anyway it's ruled by religious people
okay like
you know rude the word is ruled by ruled
by
po pope you know the white people word
and similar ins similarly in tibet
it is ruled by the um
the the the tibetan uh what what
whatever he sees name [ __ ] they
have a special term like the
pope okay anyway so
religion it's a big thing but anyway it
burned down and
it's terrible and they are trying to
rebuild it and the question
is how you gonna rebuild the um
spire you know the the thing that points
up you know that
you know the term is called the spire
a special terminology void so the
question is what's my opinion about it
you know the you know so the leftists
you know they want to
rebuild it with some kind of modern
style like just a totally new spire
spire
okay i mean while the traditional is you
know the right wing or
usually typically their uh
general opinion is that they want it to
be you know to rebuild it to be just the
way it
it is so what is my opinion actually i
don't have much opinion about that
so you know this could go either way now
politics is one thing but but
i mean as far as you know what style it
should be
it could be either way okay the reason
that the right right wingers choose to
pick
you know they want it to be the way it
is versus the
the left gun they want to you know to be
some kind of new
modern things that represent unity or
whatever [ __ ]
you know the leftist
you see these two opinions actually are
not really tied to
uh any concrete um
even they are not actually even based on
some concrete political
um ideology not really it's like they
have nothing to do with anything
you know you can build it in a modern
way if you want
and still be christians you know for
example
uh you know it it doesn't have to be
that way or this way
so but the reason
the left wingers you know the the
republicans wanted one way or
and the the you know the left wingers
one the other way is because
it's just because for some issues it's a
simple
decision to say you know which side you
are on
uh you know it's just like that like
that but
you really have nothing to do with what
okay so that's about that what do you
think alan
it does that is that answer satisfactory
do you have
additional questions good morning emily
so let's go on let's move on to the next
question okay now
actually let me go close the curtains
in uh you know to prevent prying eyes
you see my background you see my
background
it's emily colors you see it's a pink
purple
and i have here you see emacs we have in
the show we haven't shown emacs today
okay let me close the curtain
uh
okay i'm back so any anything
else thomas whoa
okay let me go answer some questions
okay so let's see
we got lots lots of questions but we
have the questions on discord first
and over here if you want to ask me a
question type my name okay so i can
read it did you change to vs code yet no
but
uh ronnie ray says i see you are aware
of the portal yeah okay so that
we're gonna uh get to it
why why did your background change i
answered that uh
every asian has a cross-eyed situation
do they
no i'm you know i have cross side so
actually i do see double sometimes
especially when i'm tired
uh can you see the future
go to considered harmful yes indeed
go to is harmful just in
scaffold hey justin you are unbanned
bam bam justin scarface says i got
banned from your discord
no you are unbanned you idiot
okay you can join you can come back now
okay so let's go back to discord
questions okay discord questions
click next question alan says
emacs aesthetic as um emacs aesthetics
question why did you choose your
signature
honeydew background in emacs do you ever
oscillate around and change game stuff
no theme are the idiotic thing okay
theme
you know do you know what's my most
famous page on my emacs
website let me show you let me show my
the power of my website so xrd website
you know ergo emacs is is the most
populous popular emacs tutorial
you'll find every answer about emacs and
emacs lists
uh you need and also things you don't
need to know
but i'm gonna tell you anyway that is
microsoft website
uh such as the idiocy of swapping
control key
uh with the caps lock key that's uh
extreme idiocy championed by all the
nerds all the emacs nerds they're
telling you oh you need to swap your
control
keywords and and and uh and the caps
lock key okay
and i'm gonna tell you why i'm going to
tell you why for example here
uh we i have 100 articles on that
tell you why that's no good with
reason itemized reason okay so alan's
question
so so do you know which uh one of my
pages
more popular on my emacs website there
are like 300 400 articles
that is let me show you go to emacs
tutorial
and you go down to theme okay
theme okay not here so you go to emacs
init
search for theme there it is set
color theme oh wonderful color themes
look
oh dark dark background oh this is great
now
now my eyes don't hurt anymore oh no
this oh this is
great this is a cool imax colors
color theme this is cool no okay
don't do the same thing my ass theme
nothing i don't want no theme nothing
okay
the best user interface the the most
ugly a user interface the best it is
okay
i don't care about themes nothing i want
functionality
pure functionality no themes no fluff no
no no no nothing no prettiness no
cuteness okay
this is this is my e max
appearance and but why do i have a um
my color background let me show you okay
call lcd
okay not lsd lcd lcd stands for
uh list color display which is a brief
i've said okay let me show you
let me show you my fantastic settings
okay so let's
let's call lcd here so you can see all
the colors
all the wonderful colors in emacs meta x
lcd but you don't have that command
because i have a brief now let's go to
my abbrev
no not a brief actually alias okay so
let me go to
let me go a brief okay let me just use
my super
fast open bookmark to open my
uh a brief now go to the directory just
two key press
go to the directory and you need to see
my keys my fantastic keys here okay
now notice the keys there's no control
nothing
that cg you see you see that says cg
control g there it's actually i'm
pressing one single key
but it because that key is mapped to uh
control g
so that's why it shows there so when i
use emacs there is no
uh control meta nothing i'm using stuff
like keys so now go back to
uh now go back to the directory let's go
to
um ads okay so
uh search for do i have ads file no so
it's in settings
so go to the settings file search for
alias and there it is let's magnify
okay magnify so you can see all my edius
is here
so instead of you know edius the yes
or no p command two y or n
p okay so instead of asking type yes or
no
just type y or n that's sufficient so
this is one way to do it
make it an alias so one of the areas
let's search for lcd
so you can see here lcd is aliased to
the command list colors display so you
can do meta x
this color display and you see all these
colors
and let's pick one okay so let's say
total is turquoise or whatever you call
it let's say
cn1 okay so cn1 split the window
now again look at my keystrokes and
commands on the right okay that's
efficiency so
uh copy the cn1 open a new buffer
and uh list mod xr
list mod
okay uh elise mod okay now
i want set background okay
not search backward okay so actually set
uh set background color okay wait let me
do it again
set background color
i don't have a brief for that uh set
background okay color there it is
what am i doing okay so anyway set back
color uh cn okay
so you see that code now i'm gonna run
it
run it now i gotta see on background so
that's how i set up my background but
alan's question is why do i
use honeydrew you see my color is
honeydrew
h-o-n-e-y do honeydew okay
janet so that's honeydew well not
uh there is no particular reason i
choose this color because
the the only reason is that i don't want
the white background because
white background is kind of um too harsh
for the eye
so i kind of just choose a
yeah that's white okay so
so let's go back to honeydew so you can
see the difference you see this is
honeydew
and this is white background and this
over here is pink or something emily's
color
okay so that's
tv uh okay so that's that question
answered let's go let's move on to the
next question
so yeah in summary i don't i don't care
about themes i don't want
i don't want any complexity i don't want
no themes nothing
the same simplest functional that's for
for me efficiency
and i was using a white background for
like 15 years but you know
then then the theme you know the theme
started to appear on the web you know
people talking about themes and i you
know when i saw that oh okay
so maybe i should change background to
something not so too bright so that's
why
i just picked um honeydew
so next question alan uh another okay so
please
flame digital hoppers
[Laughter]
so so alan is now into linux
and alan is using arc linux and alan is
also
uh getting into a freebsd
distro harpers you know the tech nerds
techno ski king
which one is the best which one is the
best windows
thailand manager they have to try them
all they spend hours
which i did the 10 uh
good morning a guy from china china
eric chen china china good morning guys
okay so next question let's see next
question
how long have i been streaming uh
how long how long where does it say okay
here
uh i've been streaming for
26 minutes okay
uh you are on top of chat you are on top
chat
you should switch to live chat what are
you talking about
you are on top chat chat
because you or an on top
chat what does that mean
so am i doing okay my live stream
okay let's go to the next question which
is
uh flame distro hoppers okay
uh you know that's a linux thing you
know if you use linux you probably
are a nerd a tech geeker you know that's
what you are
interested reaper hey reaper
so what do you mean drop down oh okay
uh
oh the the live chat thing the
censorship the google censorship
uh looks like they removed that feature
i don't know
i don't want to mess it with mess with
it
okay so um
okay next question let's see uh discord
we're gonna
get all the questions interesting
questions so reaper
ripper says i would like to know your
thoughts on closure and its community
and why the tech community should or
shouldn't
adopt closure more actually i talked
about that
one or more than one times closure
closure is the
uh the closure is the
the heaven for java coders the pen
pen okay so let's go to
let's go to let me let me tell you why
okay
white closure is dense
reaper why closure is dense
full detailed answer is here
i you know actually i talked about this
topic for one hour or so
and maybe probably more than one time at
least mentioned
you know at least one time i talked
about it in depth
anyway so closure is okay here's a
summary so i
so i have two articles that's uh good to
read okay so let me show you
first uh hold on second first answer is
this one
let's go to uh talk show okay let's
let's write down what we talked about
okay so
magnify magnify okay uh
closure is hard to learn okay white
closure is dense
so you go read it and there's another
article that's
uh good to read okay
here
closure's popularity a tango with
java
and and now i'm going to tell you uh my
opinion about closure in summary okay
basically don't use closure closure is
uh
idiocy well not not that it's
no closure is pretty good okay here's
the problem
now closure is a great language okay the
like the syntax
you know the language the design the
semantics of closure is great
however it's tainted it's
um infected with the java virus the java
[ __ ]
and the java virtual machine [ __ ]
and how you know it's it's not just that
because you know the
closure kind of needs java to survive
they suck on the blood of java
programmers
they need because you know why because
java is
is is the most popular programming
language
and they are loved by imperative idiots
that that is non-functional programming
but they are big time idiots
industry standard you know there are
millions billions of users of java
because they are
you know javascript systems the long big
history i've talked about
uh many times so java you know java is
very popular it's a
kind of normal-ish language
object-oriented language
very popular it's it's one of the most
the top five
most popular language and these people
typically
don't know nothing about functional
programming they are they are industrial
programmers they are enterprise
programmers
like they do database they they do
accounting they do trading you know
you know they are not interested of
fantastic graphics
technology gaming technology that they
are not interested
in ai they are not interested in that
they are in they are business people
java coders they are suits you know they
wear tie-in suits
to work and the closure inventor is one
of them this guy
rich hickey you know his background he's
a java expert his background is coding
java every day
you know enterprise coding the even the
most boring [ __ ]
that's what he do and he do that for
like 10 years 20 years 30 years
you know and he found problems he want
to improve it and he loved lisp
and so he created closure you know at
least but however there's a problem
what is the problem the problem
of closure is that it's intertwined with
java
intimacy you know intertwined like you
cannot separate them
it's intertwined when you talk about
closure you have to touch
java you cannot not touch you know you
have to touch intimately java
so they are intertwined like like that
okay
and you cannot even pull out why is that
because
and that i realized why i called it
closure for like two years
uh full time because thanks to this
david um uh
uh um what's his uh [ __ ]
david [ __ ] guy who who david [ __ ]
that guy who
i talked about this before he created he
is the creator of the
most popular web framework in scala
language okay i think the framework is
called spring
no not springs uh something but anyway
it's the most
famous web web
framework for the scholar language okay
david [ __ ]
[ __ ] created that and he is
uh he he he helped me five years ago so
anyway he
introduced me to uh closure because i'm
doing a project for him
so that's how i started to learn closure
back in so this is 2016
and i dived in close into closure fully
you know uh in depth
for more than a year and then
the so so the closure language the
syntax and semantics is great but
however
the the the intertwining with java is
[ __ ] it up completely completely
now normally when you if you are at
least fan you what you might think okay
oh closure is least right
it's one of the least and it's fantastic
and you know it's used by indus
industry so it's really it's great it is
but
except it's intertwined with java that
means every if you want to
know if you are like me okay when you
study your language you study in depth
like you want to understand everything
how it works it is
not how it works but at least you know
the functionality you know like the api
from the api point of view or math point
of view
you don't necessarily care about how it
actually works
underneath you know as most programmers
you don't need to care about that i
don't care about that
i don't care about low-level stuff i
just care about
how do i use this function what
functions are there how they work
together that's what i care
mathematical treatment of programming
language and you know
so i study closure a lot but every but
every time you want to understand you
know closure you have the concept of
sequences
and you have the concept of least you
know
every time you want to understand them
in depth okay
not just you know today's millennial
generation programmers they know nothing
they are idiots when they program they
don't
understand how what exactly it does
you know they don't understand how when
they call a function they don't know
how exactly what that function do it all
they know is that oh it works
these [ __ ] heads you know the today's
more you know today's generation
programmers are like that they don't
understand
what it means and i'm not talking about
the compiler you know how it works
underneath you know that
that's that's what i'm not that's not
what i'm talking about anyway
so closure um when you want to
understand
what it is you know how the functions
that you when you want to understand
language you you realize that you have
to
know java you start to learn java you
have to you know some people doesn't
agree because they don't
they don't they don't know you know they
actually there are some people online
twitter uh just few days ago he disagree
he read
my articles and he disagreed that you
have to know java
um and that's great because he actually
read my articles in detail but he
disagreed but i didn't have time to look
into exactly
to answer his question anyway my my
opinion my
my opinion is that every time you want
to know something
you know the detail of the language
you have to know java basically you have
to know the entirety of the [ __ ] java
with its object systems and interface
you know java
in java you know java not closure and
not lisp okay
you have to know that but besides that
if you want to understand how closure
you know to be a good programmer in
closure you have to understand the
entire [ __ ] java [ __ ] including you
know the inheritance
the its interface it's you know the
it's it's collection you know a
collection [ __ ] object
uh interface and so on you know so i
detail those
uh those in these two articles why
closure is dense
not just that you know not just you have
to understand besides understanding
the entirety of java you also have to
understand of course
functional programming lists list
symbols
and of course parenthesis and many
and also quite a few concepts about
closure itself closure
invented by itself not even haskell
programmers under
under understand it okay closure has
invented itself new technology
that doesn't exist in any other
languages
but but that's that's great okay because
that's
that's that's innovation but my
complaint my primary complaint is the
intertwining with
java [ __ ] i don't want to know java okay
i don't want jvm
i don't want interp i don't want to i
don't want to talk to java idiots
i just want lisbon closure but that's
not the case for closure closure are
intimately intertwined with java and why
is that
okay first of all is it really true now
you read
my article okay to judge for yourself is
it really true that closure is
intimately
intertwined with java that in order to
understand anything in closure you have
to
basically know the entirety of java
otherwise you i i would say you don't
understand closure
you know many programmers today they say
oh yeah i code closure for 10 years
you know for two years or something and
all javascript
but if i ask them a simple question they
don't know they don't know
i don't know i just know i type this and
it works this these idiots
okay that's that's closure so first of
all
try to you know you can decide for
yourself is closure really intertwined
with java
is it necessary to know you have to know
lots of java stuff to understand
you know the closure of the language as
a good as a good programmer okay
that's one thing now if you agree
it is intertwined with java this is the
question why
why is it that way can we i mean
wouldn't it be great if closure is you
know you have a new version
of closure that's entirely independent
of java
it's possible however they are not doing
that why because i realized the reason
closure is intimately tied with java
is because it's a marketing strategy you
know they can tell these
one billion java programmers hey hey
guys
java come to closure we are functional
programming oh by the way you don't have
to learn anything because everything you
know
also works here because we are java
compatible we are closure
we live in java we suck the blood of
java coders come over here
that is my story of closure okay reaper
so that answers your question
okay so i guess next question let's see
how long
how how um how am i doing okay so
i hope i'm still alive and talking oh
reaper gave me eight eight hundred
dollars thank you
reaper uh
okay am i doing good so how long have i
been talking
let's see 40 minutes okay that's pretty
long
so i guess we can do 10 minutes more or
20 minutes more
we have a lot more topics actually what
is the best way to learn a language in
depth
that's a good question you you just
study okay so
but anyway wait because i have other
questions coming in
uh emily says what are your thoughts on
ml
machine learning or meta language
i don't think i've heard you talk about
it okay
let me tell you emily my opinion on emil
okay i make an exception to answer that
first
uh right because i wanted to answer
other questions i looked at here i i
have
um so what is my uh
what what is my opinion on ml first of
all what does
ml stand for oh ml yeah i know what's
the ml ml stand for meta language do you
know what's a meta language
meta language is the father
of haskell now meta language is created
to start to
to to a proof system okay meta language
it's called meta language
then after that you have um standard
ml okay sml standard ml standard
meta language then you have then you
have um
object ml then you have oh camo
no no no meta language then you have
standard ml
of a variation you know a branch or
dialect then you have
um camo okay caml
cml camo they stand for category
something something okay meta language
then you have all camo or camera you
probably heard of or camo is the
most popular ml now so well
when i see people say ml the
abbreviation i already i think of uh
ocamo you know the meta language but i
realized that's not
that's not so you know today when they
say email that means
machine language popularized popularized
by google fox
you know google ai oh ai technology oh
robotics
oh machine learning oh this this order
or javascript or python python [ __ ]
okay so what what is my um
my opinion on machine learning uh it's
great okay i suppose it's great
it's it's a top it's a you know it's one
of the technology it's it's
it's it's been uh bloated up you know in
the past five years because of google
yeah primarily mostly because of google
uh brainwashing people so why am i
saying
so what's my opinion you know so my my
opinion on machine learning is
it's machine learning from a overall
humanity point of view not
not pop not fashion okay not fashion and
fat
and and millennials [ __ ] okay from
the overview of computer science the
history of computer
computer science the history of all of
the universe
the [ __ ] universe my ml machine
learning
is one of the human technology you know
it's a great technology technology but
it's not
uh thank you alan for for the money it's
a great technology but it's not
all important no is it all powerful okay
is it okay so i would
for example let me put the context so
machine learning is great but however
i would you know so what's the example
that's more important or
maybe more valuable for example proof
systems
okay proof theory that is what meta
language stand for
meta language is invented to do proofs
you know logics
so logic systems proof proof
systems proof theory that in my opinion
is very uh important in fact okay
machine learning machine learning is
part of the
ai okay artificial intelligence the
study
of artificial intelligence and there are
many approaches
there's machine learning there's uh
neurons you know the the
um
neural network there is uh
evolutionary uh programming you know
genetic programming
they act actually there are different
two different things you know so there
are several approaches to
artificial intelligence now machine
learning is
happens to be the most uh successful or
popular
in the past 10 years but on the other
hand let me tell you okay
there's the opposite approach which was
the most
popular in the 1980s now that is called
symbolic um what is it called symbolic
um symbolic ai
i guess the general term is symbolic ai
machine learning is kind of the
statistical ai
that is they rely on statistics to
predict
what will happen to understand things
okay kathy okay
good morning kathy now kathy is an
expert on machine learning that is her
uh expertise that's what she's studying
that's
she is doing kathy you are doing a phd
right
so anyway so machine learning is the
most popular today but it's just
actually it's just
one of the approach of ai okay
one of the great technology and i'm not
too interested personally in that
technology
i am more interested in the symbolic ai
which is the arrangement of lisp and
meta language
proof systems okay you don't for example
uh let's say language translation okay
or let's say
visual you know recognition recognition
of faces
of record speech recognition it so
happens that today
these are some these are solved more
successfully
by the approach of approaches of neural
networks and machine learning
they are kind of tied together it so
happens you know
they are successful but
uh but it's not necessarily true
that machine learning approach is the
ultimate
approach method towards these problems
not necessarily
on the other hand the other approach is
a symbolic
ai which which in general it means that
you
analyze the problem and you
you um you deconstruct
the problem into you turn it into a
logical problem in other words kind of
you turn the whole speech recognition
recognition for example
into logics linguistics okay allen is a
um
phd student of linguistics so alan is
an expert con you know so there's a
branch of science called computational
linguistics right
so so in that branch you use
you know you analyze languages you see
you know you you break down their verbs
or whatever
you know you you then you you um
create a system that maps through the
language then
you can use this system to understand
language so that's another approach
so so my basic uh point my opinion about
about machine learning in summary is
that it's just a technology one of the
technology
that happens to be very popular but i am
not personally interested in
it and also i am far more interested in
the symbolic approach
proof systems and others
uh i think emily was asking
uh i okay oh oh oh emily was asking
about me
language okay i went into a giant rant
on my own so okay so about meta language
i well i don't know
too much about it except i have learned
or camo
a little bit i you know he so yeah so
here's an interesting
story okay i think i like you know or
camo is
great language or camel you know [ __ ]
haskar
learn a camera in store instead okay or
camo so let's see
um okamo tutorial let's see
let's search for camel tutorial
let's see my website comes up
so there it is our camera tutorial on
the official camera website that one
sucks donkey ass i can't believe i
cannot believe these idiots
wrote that uh tutorial and i have 10 000
articles on that tells you the details
why this is no good okay so
this one is good or camo tutorial by
example
bike sally
so i so i studied your camera back in
uh i studied a few months so i did
actually i don't have much
materials here uh but it's you can kind
of spend one hour to read it
for you know if you are a beginner so
camera tutorial
i i o camo is a great language okay i
think it's
i would say it's better than haskell
okay haskell is very popular today
you know by the fashionable fat people
very popular every everyone is
more night every every day there are
more nights this thing or that
no good or camo is better more practical
faster and uh
it's just better in many ways so i would
support okama but however i actually
never
um again expertise in your camera
you know i studied for several months
and i
stopped um well because
back then i was planning to use the
camera to replace
python you know my the history of
the languages you know pearl mathematica
pearl python then i find pearl sucks now
i started to learn python python
python sucks so i wanted a camera to be
my
everyday language but i so what's the
reason i stopped learning your camera i
forgot but anyway
it i never um spend much time in okamo
then later on i learned golan instead uh
so there it is my uh my opinion about
meta language so okamo okay
along camel i think it's great
uh and by the way if you guys don't know
already
that emily is expert in erlang
okay so i think i talked for uh too long
now so 51 minutes
so okay nine more minutes then uh let's
go back to my youtube
here and let's see let's let's kind of
wrap up
let's see see who gave me money so uh
reaper gave me money thank you reaper
and and and thank you alan
okay so any questions here
uh aviation i
see you are aware of the portal oh yeah
so i haven't got too into that topic yet
okay so let's see so i haven't you know
so many comments here i did i don't have
time to read them all
but i'm going to cover i think one or
two more questions from the uh
from the um saudi discord
so again if you have question to me put
my name it so i can see it okay
so sorry you know what it means okay so
uh
if i was user side uh you are fine okay
good
uh the portal uh the point you know
actually i don't know how do i get
so i got 15 dollars i haven't looked how
do i get
the money out of youtube i have to look
these things
uh so does anyone know anyone of you
doing youtube's actually any one of you
doing youtube's you should say it you
know post your link
so i've learned uh i've never learned
java
and seems to be fine in the world of
work and programming
uh what is the best way to
learn a language okay that's uh that's
another let's talk about that
another day thoughts on
eric chan says thoughts on
anki spaced repetition what is
what does that mean
i think the term you are looking for is
go fi
good old-fashioned artificial
intelligence
uh i haven't heard of that phrase i
think no it's
i think it's called intel well good old
fashioned artificial intelligence that's
kind of a slant
but um the proper term is symbolic
artificial intelligence i think
symbolic ai yeah i think you'll find an
article on wikipedia about it there it
is
uh you know that this uh nobody
very few people is talking about it
because you know everyone is
talking about machine learning and
neural networks these days but you can
read it
they don't have much material you see
it's just one page
nothing here meanwhile if you go to the
neural networks or machine learning it's
[ __ ] 100 pages from google library
this or python [ __ ] that
fad you know fashion
uh and you know you can go to you know
the
camps you know what boot camp the
[ __ ] bootcamp jargon
oh you know you can from if you don't
know nothing about nothing
you can go to boot camp and then
tomorrow you are a machine learning
expert
that's a fashionable thing you know in
silicon valley here
and you spew out jargons every day or
machine learning or studies
statistics you know neural network
networks variants and
what what not uh
okay so
okay so let's go back to discord and we
are about to shut down
let me answer the questions on this
quote
oh reaper reaper's question big question
so uh wait did you see another one
before it
uh oh yeah yeah so reaper asked about
the closure so i gave the answer about
question closure and ripper also asked
none technical question if you have
anything interesting
anecdotal accounts on current chinese
economy
or society during kovite 19 it would be
interesting to hear
not looking for political stuff more
just
everyday accounts of people or for
instance if factories are going
okay yeah so if you i don't have
uh opinions like that well i have tons
of opinions but
any well my point is that
what i want to say is that if yeah
that's a good question if you want to
know
ask chinese chinese people ask
chinese people who lives in china such
as kathy
or kathy here she's expert when kovit
knighting happened she was in china
so she witnessed she witnessed
everything
you know you can ask her and actually
quite a few
other people in disco they they
they live in china some of them and also
on my twitter i have uh
quite a few followers some of them i
follow
they are from china so i i talked about
this many times before
if you want to know some other country
no
no none english speaking country you
know
you know don't don't read new york times
new new york [ __ ] times and ca and
[ __ ]
they are all fake news okay you want to
you want to uh mix in with local people
in another country in china in russia in
in islam you know whatever
iraq iraq iran you know what
whatever other countries spain or french
you know or brazil you or india you know
you you want to
and today it's very it's it's easy it's
it's actually very easy to do
you you you just dive in on twitter or
somewhere else you know there's lots of
forums
if you are winning the question is are
you willing or not
no pain no gain you you know if you
really want to understand let me just
use the china example
but it applies to other countries as
well no non-english speaking countries
if you really want to know what they
actually think the people of that
country
you mix in with the local people of that
country you talk to them
okay no not like you don't go
you don't just go in and ask them
political questions no not like that
you go in living in their community talk
to
them see what they say every day maybe
you you know if you don't speak their
language you can ask them questions you
know
that's the best thing is to understand
their language you learn their language
but usually you know for
americans or white people that's not
likely except adam
allen is a linguistic linguistist
allen speaks english of course and
chinese and
uh and and and and spanish french
russian and japanese and korean
right so anyway so so what i'm saying is
that if you want to understand what's
the actual thinking
of a country you go to you know today
it's very easy
you you know the question is are you
willing to spend time to do that
so you go to an online forum of that of
that local people's online forum okay
not okay yeah you go you go in and you
you mixing with them for a year you can
do that in many
many channels okay also in gamer gaming
communities for example second life
or whatever you play you know world of
warcraft
or you know whatever game you play i'm
pretty sure there's a community that's
just
koreans or chinese you know or japanese
or you know especially this is important
especially of countries that not
that that are not us alliance okay
so for example uh japan
you don't have to you know you don't
have to um
do this in particular because what you
hear on the news is
you know well so what i'm saying is
especially for
uh countries like china russia you know
the countries that u.s don't like you
know they don't speak english
you're going you you want really to know
what's going on what people think
you go into their forums and you mixing
with them
for a year then you all know what they
are thinking every day what's their
opinions about politics about
programming what programming language
they use
you know what's what they like what they
do not like you know what is the truth
you will find out not from the cnn
cnn [ __ ] and and fox news [ __ ] and new
york times
so that's what i'm saying so i i have
actually never been to china
so but i spent one year two years okay
uh talking to chinese programmers in
china
so i learned a lot of things and today
and right now kathy is actually teaching
me
quite a lot of things about china's
lands
now kathy is in um right
so anyways so that's my opinion about
that so let's get on to the next
question so
and you know reaper is you know ripper
is
a kind of academic type you know
he's usually often interested in from
um you know academic style of analysis
of understanding of what happens in the
world
but i am not really um
uh into that you know
that is a good approach but uh
i'm not much into that uh so anyway so
next question
so next question that's a big question
uh about
lisp why hasn't emaclis
turned into a more general purpose
language people use outside of emacs
well because emacs people are ideal
idiots
you i have a article on that so given
immaculate
success at creating full applications
using emacs as a framework yeah that's a
good question
you know i've been complaining about
that since like uh 15 years ago
i have article on that um
okay so let's let's show off my articles
uh
uh let's see emacs common list
maybe that'll find the article
it's uh old article i don't even
remember
there it is
thoughts on commonly skim disk based
emacs
okay so let's see if this is the article
i don't i'm not sure this is the article
uh yeah it is okay
yeah so here's my answer basically about
that question i mean the ques so the
question is why is emacs you know
emacs is so useful but why is it just
uh you know a niche language inside
emacs why has
why haven't the emacs people make
you know made emac these to become the
general purpose language
that is used that can be used outside of
emacs okay
well i think that's a question and that
i think that's something we could do
i mean it's possible however the reason
it hasn't happened is because
the emacs nerds you know these gnu
people free software foundation
[ __ ] they are idiots they don't see
you know the big picture of society just
like the linux people
for for 20 years 30 years now linux is
still
you know hard to use in a niche nobody
uses except
you know by the nerds you have to spend
10 years to study computer science
then you can use linux otherwise it's
useless
useless crap linux idiots and
and and they are citing oh oh but google
is using it
yeah google go work for google
and go go go yeah go work for the your
big brother
this is funking idiots so uh commonly so
emac means you know
so what okay let me
make one focus point about that okay so
you see em emac list is
insignificant okay from the from the
point of view of human society of
of the history of computing the whole
thing the unit
from the point of view of the universe
emacs
emac emacs list is one of the most
useless [ __ ] useless
insignificant [ __ ] in in the universe
okay
as compared to now that's not the case
for java
java python
java python php they are significant
okay
if one of this language dies tomorrow
like if god says
php go disappear tomorrow okay tomorrow
there's no
vh php the word the earth is going to go
into a disaster
you're gonna have people dead okay
that's a signific
that that's one of the ways you measure
the significance of a programming
language
is to see what will happen if it
disappears tomorrow
php c c plus plus java
python they are all extremely
significant okay if they disappear
tomorrow
you're gonna have problems you know
tomorrow tomorrow
people will die thousands ten thousands
medium
what about emac list nothing nothing
if email at least disappear tomorrow oh
we'll just use veeam
this is how how insect insignificant
emacs lead
lisp is but however the emacs the new
people these nerds
these linux people oh i love emacs i
love them
they are idiots they have no brain they
they don't they don't see this situation
they don't
until i mention it they don't see it you
know
you you ask them they'll say oh emac
this is so important
how can you say it's not important it's
very important it can again it can make
coffee
you know it can make you can brew coffee
it can make dildos
oh oh my god you can read emails you can
read browsers
these idiots okay email emac list has no
significance because okay in the world
generally speaking
so that's the situation but why
but but would it be great if it can we
can make it
significant yes we can but the problem
you see that's why i blame the e-max
fuel the problem is that
these nerds they don't see that their
view you know
you know the blinders you know the horse
you know or or bdsm community
you have girls you know with the
blinders so you cannot see
anything else you can only see here
that's that's the that's the nerds
that's these uh tech geekers nuts
they don't say nothing they only see
this oh emac this is great
emacs is great beam sucks okay that's
that's
that's the situation they are in so they
are forever going nowhere
okay that's my point that's the point i
want to make that okay i think that's it
for
uh today's sa tv
uh we talked about a lot of things thank
you guys for coming it's
it's quite it's been a while it's it's
the
hot
uh it can be a brew coffee it making uh
dealer
show you know the google censorship is
working here
i need to show all things that google
censored
if google senses it i'm gonna show it
okay yeah google censorship
um
show you know yeah that's what happened
with the open source you know you want
oh you love open source
i know i know you guys love open source
you know all the nerds linux linux is
the greatest thing
since sliced bread you know open source
that's what happens
censorship we need to help
thank you guys for watching uh 17 people
concurrent view so how long i've been
talking we've been talking for
one hour and a in eight minutes thank
you guys for coming by
and i think that'll be it for today and
we have a few more questions actually
uh yeah a few more questions but i don't
have to oh yeah so there's another
question
then from um
from wait
so is here so
so so is the conspiracy
conspiracy theory uh guy
okay so where is the other question
there's another question about this
um yeah they are uh
erin so he's asking about this guy okay
this guy and then this guy also also
happened to be
a reaper's hero
this guy this guy
i think he's a crackpot okay so he's got
a theory
of geometric unity so he's gonna tell us
about his
his theory of the universe geometric
unity okay
so what do i think of it i think it's
craft okay don't listen to him okay
if first of all check who is talking oh
it's
eric weinstein talking ah don't listen
don't watch don't waste your time
first of all if you want to understand
geometric unity
of his theory you should know
calculus group theory analysis complex
analysis
you should have a in general you have
you should have a equivalent knowledge
of a math major a math degree four years
in college
studying math okay not just engineering
you know you you you should understand
you know all these theories i talk about
you know math major
group you know modern algebra symbolic
algebra
group theory analysis
uh complex analysis topology if you
already understand that
then okay my opinion my opinion is that
yeah go ahead
go ahead watch what this guy uh eric
weinstein has to say about geometric
unity
his theory geometric unity your first
look yeah then then you do that
now if you don't know all these you know
basic topology
basics of group theory basics of complex
analysis
then don't read it okay what you are
doing is you are just
a fat and fashioned [ __ ] oh you know
you think you know you are listening to
a new theory of a universe this is no
okay thank you guys for watching
and hope to use uh see you next time
bye
you