the best feature let's see open a
document let's say JavaScript and I want
to print oh that's that's great let's
try that again
see ya cause a lot yes okay
hello would run file to say okay
JavaScript random name there it is
hello world let's see I want to let's
say I want to function
oh nice but I want constant error
function oh nice
let's say X X plus 1 so that's my
function and call it have let's say 3
and I'll remove here vennett there is my
answer for great so yeah so this is the
brief is the error function for loop
that's for loop and let's see if I have
wire huh that's window documents and
other things
ok so let's remove that let's try eMac
this okay save save the file xxx
yeah damp name so what do I want to do
let's print header word so different oh
so I press the space and different space
oh I have my template so have duck
stream blah blah blah I don't need that
no need that let's just say message yeah
it's nice let's say
vennett
how its run so now I just came X there
it is hello world so so they are so this
is you see this is different so I can do
let I can do
there's no V I can do insert and lots of
others basically 100 talk over the 100
most use functions I have a variation so
how do you how do you setup abbreviation
it's pretty easy how this you see these
other examples here for example I want
heart cos Unicode hot it is magnifier so
fine and you can you can just create
anything anything any abbreviation you
want so basically what you do is you
copy his file let's try that
copy and you want to go to actually I
already have my brutal bleep file so
let's keep that step so I just go to my
bookmark a brief and this is this is my
bleep file but basically it looks very
similar to to what I have online on my
website so you can find a website here
and the once so you you can add all
these a brief so let's try some of them
let's say so you can see new file so as
far as I know at the moment by the way I
can't do it difference between what's
the difference between you know that's
that's a hard one that's a lots of
typing so you can have abbreviation so
anyway let's go back to how you do it so
once you copy and paste and create a
file and save it let's save it it's for
that's for example you save us he max
LVL then you save it in the Emacs
directory 30 max 30 Lisp then my approve
da da then you're in a file
it's go to that he need fire
so you need file Vicki is a baseline he
just loads it then you have a brief now
a brief abbreviation can be much
dependent for example in this part
you'll see that is for : so for example
if i close this open new file and switch
to go mod now go language needs a
temporary sort of so I type g3 and they
bear it is I have it so it's planet
where to save xxx go
three you see there's the hope so you
can you can create a brief any anytime
you want so let's say I want any time
you want let's say I want on the brief
Haiti eww so what do I to expand to that
so what I do I go to my a big file and
just just copy it and you want anything
you want a W a why W and run the file
go back halite a V there it is so it's
extremely useful it's the one of the
biggest feature of Emacs so yeah so that
that's that's it for him except
deviation i in fact i pretty is a
package called why a snippet standing
for yet another snippet but i prefer
using a brief much better than that
because for example in javascript going
other languages when you type and say
hello function if you use my snippet
they they kind of force you to to move
your cursor in this field and and that
that that that field and whichever spots
it's set for you i think you can reset
it so that doesn't force you to but you
know but it's more work more much more
prefer free free form so once I have a
brief I just move using normal cruiser
commands to go anywhere I want
and you don't need to install another
package because usually when you install
a package there's lots of in it and
things you have to do that's specific to
that package you have to spend time to
learn it but with a pre bits with Emacs
everywhere now okay so that's the simple
way to use a brief by this by this
method this code now there is another
way to use Emacs a brief I talked about
here which basically Emacs has like 20
commands for a brief it that you can you
can add a brief at any time you can list
our briefs and stuff like that so so I
show you how to do it that way in this
tutorial but I've tried both ways you
know I've been using this way with a
elysée elysée é maclisp file and I've
also used the the Emacs the more
official way and I find that the the
Emacs Lisp way is much simpler and
easier but you know you might prefer the
other way so that's it for this tutorial
tutorial thank you for watching