Hello guys. Hello guys. Welcome to
another episode of sound talk show.
Hello guys. So this is happy hacking. Uh
this is no this is not happy hacking
keyboard. This is ultimate hacking
keyboard UHK80.
This is newia track ball over there.
Let's see. So over here and that's a
Logitech track ball. Okay. I got reviews
on my website. You can see you got uh
this tiny scroll scroll uh tiny scroll
track ball here and there's a trackpad
there. Okay, so we're going to code
JavaScript. Let's uh let's go to my
screen. So
we're going to code JavaScript. Okay, so
JavaScript
uh it's just me coding uh my JavaScript
website. The JavaScript in depth, the
most comprehensive JavaScript,
the most concise, the most clear,
the most indepth JavaScript tutorial on
earth in English language. JavaScript in
depth by yours truly. Search the web,
you'll find it. Okay.
fidgeting. Fidgeting I have some cough
it's going away uh and I'm quitting
smoking which is a good thing. So
JavaScript script in depth so you can
check it out. there's like uh a thousand
pages, you know. So, let's see. Uh yeah.
So, so in JavaScript, so there's uh 150
I mean 1,500 pages, but they includes
CSS and HTML. For JavaScript, there are
about maybe 600 700 pages. Okay,
JavaScript in in depth and of course and
the JavaScript object reference. the
complete JavaScript object object
reference. Actually, I'm missing quite a
few. I'm missing the typed array, big
int 64 array, you know, specialized
array of arrays of a single type flow 32
array, and I'm missing Yeah. And I also
missing I'm missing some modern features
like my for example international class.
Uh I'm not uh it's not, you know, well
done. It's a new kind of newish
international number format and that's a
big feature. Okay. And also proxy I'm
kind of bad there. Uh and promise why?
Because I want a like a mathematical
approach and uh that hasn't been has has
not been easy um mathematical treatment
of explanation of the uh proxy and the
promise. Okay. So iterator extremely
complex. So I have them fully detailed.
Okay. So there's some you know so I'm
talking about some parts of my
JavaScript in depth that's gnarly not
really in depth. For example weak set
and weak map I don't have and also there
is the big int. Okay that's a that's
another huge feature which I have not
started to dive into yet. That's like
very very complex because it has to
integrate with the whole JavaScript
system.
Okay. So what I'm going to do today is
just go random uh well not random but
I'm working on my JavaScript
uh inepth tutorial. Okay. So here are
the so those are the things I want I
need to work on.
Uh I'm talking about the weak parts but
the so so you got JavaScript in depth
you got the introduction section like
for beginners then you got uh indepth uh
like for example in depth string the
full detail about string for for example
about the code unit it's one of the most
complex thing for example if you type
the butterfly and try to get the length
you'll say two and this causes major
problem in JavaScript.
Okay, so that's uh you know so you got
in-depth explanation of the encoding
UTF8 uh 16 and so on. But anyway, I I
think last two days ago I explained that
for an hour about the JavaScript
and Unicode
UTF16 UTF8 encoding code unit issues
uh about two or three ago. Okay, watch
on my YouTube. So anyway, so this is my
JavaScript. So you got the beginner
sections. Then you got in-depth such as
array. You know, array is one of the
most
uh
bad badly designed part of JavaScript.
One of the major like the array in
JavaScript like destroyed JavaScript
language basically. So array you got the
array like object. Okay,
because you know why? Because this
language is just [ __ ] Okay, this is
like a major problem. Uh because it was
written and designed in 10 days
literally back in 1999.
I mean I mean 1995.
Okay. By Brandon Ike.
I mean he he he he he he he's a great
programmer but he has to rush it out in
10 days due to you know that history of
the Netscape but anyway so array is the
worst. So you got this array like object
that causes huge problems and lots of
fixes over the past 20 years like they
have to create a lot functions just to
fix this problem but it's still not
fixed is you still got this problem
array like object you know like what the
[ __ ] it's not a thing but it's a thing
you see that's a situation with
JavaScript you you have lots of things
that's not really a thing but it's just
there so you can't even try to explain
it. You know, it's just like so array
like object is one one of it and it's
not going away because the browsers, you
know, every time you uh you know,
document document.getelement by class
name, they they return array like
object. there's no way to fix it because
backward compatibility for the you know
for 30 years of internet you have to you
can't just remove that um
and you know the dome is another very
complex [ __ ] up [ __ ] okay so array
like object is one of the major [ __ ] up
in JavaScript but that's not all but
then you got sparse array
you see you might you might think oh
array is bad But but it's they are
different things. Okay. So you got array
like object that's one thing very bad
that's huge huge damage to JavaScript
the language but then a separate rather
totally separate thing you got this
sparse array thing. Okay
so it's very funny. So you know sparse
right that you know so that that's like
um you get the length is five but there
is no but there's no index for like for
for for for all the keys you got empty
items but if you ac items doesn't exist.
So when you say array prototype, you
know, if you call the map function, it
doesn't work on the empty items. It
doesn't feel it because it's not there.
So, so you got these empty items with
but however, if you access, you know, if
you say array, you know, you access, you
know, index of the empty index, you got
undefined
automatically no error. However,
however,
however, the you know the empty items
like doesn't exist is different from an
item that has a value of undefined.
Okay. So, they are diff they are
different. So, so this sparse array is
one of the another what like major
[ __ ] in JavaScript like major
then then over the past 10 20 years they
try they come up with lots of functions
to fix it. So in JavaScript you have the
situation you have like lots of um
functions they seems to be doing the
same thing but not really but for
example uh object dot has own versus
object.prototype prototype has own key.
Okay. And and quite a few others. I can
I can actually go through all of them.
Uh if you guys are interested, nobody
nobody is here. Am I am I like going
video check audio check? If you are
here,
say hi. Okay, nobody is watching. Uh but
if you are watching this offline, play
it twice as fast. Okay, since nobody is
here, I'm going to stop talking. So let
me well but let me quickly finish. Okay.
So, introduction, then you got array uh
JavaScript object references. Then you
got dome. This is the heart
where you want to program the web.
Okay. So, so now let me just go to my up
my tutorial. So, I've been working on
JavaScript a lot in the past week. So if
you can see in the past week uh so let's
see I in the past week I updated this
about 10 about 20 articles on regular
expression major update update so
beginning like four four days ago major
update on regular expression so all
these pages has been updated
and but of course that's not all I'm
meanwhile working on all these other
pages And uh let me show you one today
which is which is what I'm going to do
right now. Okay.
Video check uh audio check. So what I'm
going to do is that you know you have so
we mentioned object.prototype has own
property. That's one JavaScript method.
Another new method is object has own. So
let me let's go look at them. So this
bas basically this uh has own property
is a way to let you know if a object has
a key as its own property not inherited.
Okay so that's that's what this is but
however in 2022 3 years ago they created
a new function object has own which does
exactly the same thing. So why do they
create a new uh method? Well, because if
you use object property has own
property, it could run into a problem
because if um for example,
you know, so this is one of the major
problem JavaScript is also convoluted.
So let me try to explain this one. Okay,
if you know JavaScript a little bit, let
me try to explain this in in in a way
that you can understand. It's but it's
fairly complicated. Okay, hold on a
second.
Okay, let me try to explain this one.
close that.
Okay. So
when you have an object you want to know
if a particular key
exist that is that object has that key
as a property.
Okay a object in JavaScript is defined
as
uh a thing that can has a bunch of
properties. Each property is key and
value pair. So basically a kind of like
a variable that can hold a bunch of key
and value pairs. Okay, those are called
properties. Okay, when a variable
can do this then that thing is called
object in JavaScript. Okay, this is like
this is in JavaScript.
So you so you want to know if a key I
mean if a object has a particular
property property are identified by key.
Okay the keys are always unique they
cannot repeat. So you you you want to
know an object has a particular
property. So so that's why you call this
function dot has own property key. Okay,
I mean not dot but argument of the key.
Now the way you call this function
because this function is now this is the
complicated part. Okay, now has own
property.
This function
is a property of the object.prototype
which is a thing. Okay. And that thing
object.prototype prototype. This entity
is a property of the object entity. So
in other words, you got the thing called
object that's built in. Okay? Like
literally capital O BC
which belongs to the Windows object, the
global object.
So is it complic complicated enough yet?
Okay. So you got this object
Okay. So you can see the global object
is the windows in the browser. It's a
browser window object referenced by the
window word. Okay. Uh so that's the
global object. Then inside it you have
you have the so you you got windows do
object. Okay. So uh
okay then
then the then this object thing uh god
where we are we so then this object
thing has a property
uh whose property key is prototype it's
a string okay so you got this pop object
prototype okay where is it Um
where is this? Uh oh yeah already we are
already there. So back to object. So you
got object then object got a got all
these properties. Okay dotp prototype
dot create
you know dot is the access method. So
anyway, you got the properties
prototype, create, assign, group by, get
prototype of, set, prototype of, has
own, and few and a bunch of others.
Okay, all these are properties of the
object. Do you guys understand what I'm
saying? Or am I just like to get getting
too uh boring?
Like if you go JavaScript, you already
know this. Okay. So for example
uh
uh god
getting into uh getting this uh
so this this reflect on keys is a way to
get all the keys of a thing. Okay. So we
want to know all the keys in other words
all the properties of a thing. What is
the thing? That thing is object. Okay.
So, we can do that. So, uh paste that.
So, uh evaluate it. Return. So, there it
is. Here is the answer. Okay. Close it.
Now, let's uh do this. Press press.
Uh wait. Oh, yeah. Press press.
So, it will insert everything here. So
this is a way to know all
properties
of this object thing. Okay.
Now so so it tells you you got all these
properties. So you can see you know all
these methods we were talking about is
you know has own get own property
descriptor get prototype of and uh
prototype create assign they are all
here. You see assign prototype uh has
own is prevent extensions se create is
extensible keys entries you know form
entries value group by okay so all these
are properties.
So now one of the property is prototype.
Okay, prototype. You see one of the
properties prototype and you can access
it by
you can access you know the way to the
typical um syntax to access
uh property is just dot the property key
name and another syntax is is this way.
Okay. And there's a there's others
there's also uh reflect um there's other
another functional syntax but anyway the
most popular is this syntax or this
syntax okay so this syntax object
prototype means you got object variable
prototypes it means you are looking for
a string property key named prototype of
that object. Okay. So this thing so this
start prototype actually returns a new
thing. It's it's like a a variable or
function or whatever it's a it's a
thing. Okay.
So what is this object prototype thing?
So this thing is designed to be
for any object the parent will be this
thing. Okay. So so this is very critical
object.prototype prototype. In fact,
whenever you see something prototype
that those are all designed to be the
parent of that of some thing like array,
date, time, regular expression or
functions, you know, they all have
function.prototype, you know. Anyway, so
that's so so the prototype whenever you
see like in general
you have a properties named prototype
that means that thing
is designed to be the parent of what of
a bunch of things
parent okay so so that's why they say
JavaScript is proto prototype based
object
uh oriented programming system prototype
based not class. Okay.
So anyway, so object.prototype
so so it's designed to be parent of all
objects basically
and in this object.prototype
it has children of course.
Hello. Hello.
Something like that. J3Q.
So you got this um so you got
object.type
and they it you know object.prototype
this thing has lots of properties too.
It has
property has own property is property of
okay. So all these are properties of the
object prototype thing. Okay. Again we
can show it just like just like before.
So we can uh go here go down paste and
uh uh let's
write down okay let's write down what we
done.
This is ways two common ways to access a
property. Uh uh
okay those are that's those and uh this
is
way to list all
properties
of a thing. Okay that's that and two
common way to access a property. Okay.
Now a property
is
key and value
here. Okay.
Key can be string type or symbol type.
Okay. In this case these are string
keys. You can see those are all strings.
But but about 10 years ago 2015 you can
also have symbol type that's a new thing
okay but anyway those are should be
strings most most of the time very
complex okay so a property is key and
value pair okay and uh
okay I'm starting to
write a generic JavaScript tutorial
that's not good a lecture on JavaScript
script uh property is key and value
pair. And also one more thing important
to mention is that um
uh
object in JavaScript is defined to be a
collection
uh key value pairs which is
such is called a property. Okay, that's
what that's the meaning of object.
But in fact in JavaScript many object
have special
things besides just a collection of
key values
such as function
date rejects. Okay,
many object actually they are not they
are more than just key value pairs. For
example, a function is a function object
that is not just key value pairs because
it can compute
and date is a day time and regular
expression and so on.
So,
so we were talking about so we were now
talking about this this thing. Okay. So,
you want to know all the keys of this
object prototype.
Let's do it.
There it is. So you can see all the
properties of object.prototype. So now
you can see object.prototype my tutorial
reference. So you can see properties has
own property
and
where is it?
Check
is prototype of
uh check right here
property is in knowable innumerable
there check you see those are properties
th those are property keys which are
strings okay of this thing called
object.prototype prototype which is a
value. Okay.
So where are we? So where are we? So I
was saying so I was starting to explain
why do we have um so okay let's go up. I
was going to explain why do we have this
um
object has own instead of the um
versus you know this object has own is
new and the old is object.prototype
has own property okay so whenever you
want to know if object has a property
what you do you got this function okay
object.prototype prototype has has own
property. The way you call it is that xx
is your object. Okay. So xx let's say
that's the object you want to know
whether it has some
property of a particular key. Okay. So
the way you call this function has own
property is that xx dot has own
property. Why? Because dot has own
property is the way is a way of of
accessing the property. So when you say
xx dot has own property that means
it looks up the parent object.prototype
dot has own property. Why? Because the
parent of xx is object.prototype.
Remember
very complicated. Okay, let me show you.
So remember remember this this is
object, right? So let's say I want to
know the parent of this object. So how
how can you um
the
parent of this object? Okay, how do you
find it? reflect
parent of something. Uh reflect
uh
reflect prototype get proto. That's how
you do it. Okay. Reflect. So
you do that.
So can you see object then uh god this
this return value is hard to read.
Um
well I you know it should just be
actually it would be just this. Okay
object
second proto
I cannot format. I need to format
comment those out. Okay. And
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah. And then to
comment this out
so that I can format the code. Format.
There's still some Oh yeah, that part.
Format. Yeah, good. Okay. So, how to
find the parent of uh object?
The way you do is reflect.get get
prototype up. So this here is a object
and we can test if it equals to that and
it will return true. Okay, let me show
you
uh that you see true.
So when we have this xx is equals to
object
that xx that parent is this object
photoype. Okay. So, so when uxx dot has
own property,
JavaScript will look up the property by
the by the string name has own property
of the xx object. Does it exist? No.
Because xx has only one key here p. So
it doesn't exist. It will look up the
parent of xx. That is that is what
inheritance means. Okay. Like the
critical the essence of JavaScript
object system. That's what inheritance
means. When it tries to
when user when you know when it tries to
uh access a object I mean a property if
the object does not have that property
it will look up the parent. So the
parent of xx is object.prototype
prototype because we just you know it's
by design. Okay. So the object.prototype
does it have a property called has own
property? Yes.
So because object.prototype
you know that by definition by you know
it has that that has own property string
key.
Okay. So therefore,
so therefore this this xx
has own property
is accessing
is basically accessing becomes this
object prototype has own property. Okay.
And then
then you pass a uh
uh you you pass a a string p to check if
that has the key. Now how does it know
where does xxx
came from? That is via another mechanism
that's called this binding. Okay. Like
the javascript is like complete totally
[ __ ] up.
uh just to explain this well actually we
did pretty good job of explaining the
property things okay in in a in a short
um pinch
but the right now the question is like
if you have paid attention carefully
like be let's suppose you don't know
JavaScript at all but now you listen to
my lecture you paid attention carefully
you kind of understand you know that
this xx dot has some property
Why it just became this value
object.prototype
has own property. Okay, because of the
property and lookup inheritance you know
the parents of object mechanism but now
so now you are calling the function
object.prototype prototype has some
property. How does it know about X?
Because over here X is just a reference.
It that's how it knows this function.
But now this function, how does it know
you want to know a key of a specific
object like how does it know XX? Well,
that is because
that's another uh like very complicated
building function. It's called this
keyword. Okay. So if we go up like
JavaScript in depth then you uh you got
basics value types variable string then
you got properties starting to get
complex this part object and
inheritance. Okay.
Then you got object type. Uh then you
got prototype and inheritance prototype
chain. All the things we explained is
fully explained here even better because
it's written uh it's you know over 10
years. So, so the so then then you will
know so then you will come to a section
called um
okay uh
class that's kind of related it's
intermixed okay you you got to know
about then then the constructors and uh
this key binding okay so this
this This this binding is the mechanism
how
how that this
method
object.prototype has own property knows
about X.
Okay, because this this when when it's
called this way this X X is passed as a
value of the this key binding to this
function object.prototype
has own property. Okay, do you guys see
what I mean? Very complex. Okay, this so
this binding is a basically a implicit
way to pass arguments to functions. Like
normally when you call a function, you
always pass arguments like explicitly.
But in JavaScript, you got this this
binding. Okay, this all very complex.
Basically, it's a hidden way. You don't
even know it's there, but it passes some
argument to a function. Okay, so that's
what this this key binding is. Okay, and
uh basically the entire JavaScript OOP
system is heavily based on this and the
parent you know the things we explained
before.
Okay, so we got a common go J says
that's useful I guess uh X.prop prop not
equals to no. Uh if it's not present,
it's no.
Uh and uh if it's empty, it is no. So I
guess that fixes.
No, that's not. You see that? No, that
doesn't work because you say when you
say x.prop prop
and
you want to check if it's new. Okay,
that works. If it's not present, it's
no. That's not true because if it's not
present, JavaScript will look up at at
that object's parent to see if that
parent has that property. If not, it
will look that object's parent until
there's no more parent. So this is this
is called prototype inheritance system.
So what you are saying is that uh so not
person it's no and it's empty it's nor
so I guess that fixes okay I don't know
exactly what you are saying but um
any anyway
um so anyway so oh [ __ ] I wasted I think
I wasted an hour because
uh well I explained this thing
I kind of I kind I gave a lecture on
this.
Oh, we haven't explained yet why. So why
you know we haven't actually explained
the thing we wanted to explain.
Wait,
the way the the reason the the we
started to explain this because we want
to explain why JavaScript created a new
function that has own object
has own in three years ago 2022
and as a way to replace the
object.prototype has own property. So
the reason is that so now you know this
how this works okay but what if your
object has a property called has own
property then what won't work no uh it
won't work okay so let me demonstrate
um
so we want to know uh so if we run this
uh it's going to be true true okay right
so this property uh that that that
that's true of course and uh that is uh
true of course.
So so why does uh so what's the problem
with this? Uh the problem is let's say
uh okay let me demonstrate. So,
okay. Object create. Let's see. Um,
uh, okay.
Let me just do something. Okay. Xad
X. Okay. Um, okay. D.
Okay. Just some random property names.
Okay. Thad. Wait. and uh uh reflect
settle.
Okay.
Uh promise. No, I don't want to promise.
I don't want promise nothing.
Okay. So, we want to set prototype
um sun
the that is the dad of the sun. Okay. So
we created two object there and we set
the prototype. So now that is the sad is
that that sun is sun. Okay.
So now we can
Okay. Now we can uh send
that wheel equals to um let's remove
that. Okay, let's remove that. Okay,
that equals to
that. Of course,
that will return true, will it? Error.
Okay. What's the problem?
And code promise sun is not defined. Oh,
spelling error. Okay. So, x. Okay. Run
it again. So, true. Okay. So, you got
true.
Okay. So, now we set up dad and son two
objects. Okay. Now,
now this the dad,
let's add a property to the dad. And uh
let's let the dad have the property, his
own property.
No, that doesn't work. Wait. Uh yeah.
Wait. So Okay.
Aha. Okay. Now the dad has a property
named has own property. Okay.
It still works. Okay. Dadson
relationship still hold. But now you
want to know
you want to know this. Okay. Now you
the sun.
Does the sun
have the property of
let's say toy. Okay. So the sun got a
toy
bear something. Uh let's say train. Um
you know boys like trains. Okay. The sun
got a property toy and value is train.
Now we want to know if the sun has own
property of the toy toy run it
but
what it's not a function. You see you
got a problem says it's not a function.
Why is it not function? But we got, you
know, this has some property is supposed
to work that way, but it won't work
here. It [ __ ]
You see?
So, so now it's [ __ ] It says it's not
a function. Let's change it to a
function. Okay. Let's like [ __ ]
change it to a function. So, function
uh Siri JavaScript uh
console log. Uh let's not even console
log. Let's just say haha. Okay. Return.
Return. Okay.
So, so, so, so, so, so, so, so so so,
so, so, so so so, so. Clarify. Okay.
Okay. So, sun and dad. Okay. Son and dad
that has a that has a property. Haha.
Okay. And now we want to know is the um
you know we want to know if the sun has
own property. So run it.
So you got haha. So you see this
function has own property is supposed to
return true or false right? But now it's
like haha. So you got [ __ ] the
JavaScript programming language when you
want to check you know whether something
has a uh own property you got.
So that is why
three years ago just three years ago
they started to create object has own.
Okay. So because this way object has own
does not rely on the on the on the
prototype
chain the parent sun lineage does not
rely on this blood line. Okay? Because
if you want to call so let let's
demonstrate that. Okay. So
so this return uh so wait hold on a
second.
So right now this return haha you [ __ ]
run it. Okay. So that's what we got.
Okay. But now the proper way to know
is uh is that you know the proper way to
know is not that
But this way object has own. So that is
a function okay based on object that's
building. So it doesn't depends on user
whatever sun or dad you know user
object. So this object has on building.
So you want to check the object sun has
the property toy. So run it.
It says true.
Okay. So this is the reason
in 2025 they created song. Okay, I think
that's concludes today's talk
because uh hold on a second Simpson
because you know I was going to work on
uh I'm going to work on lots of code
actually let me work on my code anyway.
So, so this is the
we took 1 hour has it been 1 hour we
took 45 minutes to explain why they
changed you know why they created a new
function object has so okay so hope you
guys those who don't know JavaScript you
learned something
if you know JavaScript
maybe you learned something too okay uh
very so so by the way JavaSc is this not
use this function. JavaScript has lots
of you see you see each of these thumb
down they got a replacement you know
after 10 years they Jesus Jesus this is
sucks so bad we got to do something
about it so they new JavaScript spec
they say you know we oh so this delete
operator you should never use okay you
should never use if you want to use it
you know usually it's used in array you
shouldn't okay if you want to use um SPL
applies for array or simply you know uh
and or or use delete reflect delete
property. Okay, much better. Similarly
for you know this uh in operators key in
object like like JavaScript is filled
with like idiotic things. Each one of
these I might take 10 or an hour 10
minutes or an hour to explain each one
of these lots of problems. lots of
JavaScript. Uh, pretty sad. Yeah, pretty
sad. You know, I really wanted to like
JavaScript, but it's just
bad. Okay,
great. So, go. So I'm glad somebody
understand what I'm talking about you
know because so Simpson says simple
postman says a long time no see hope you
are doing fine I am thank you very much
why such a deep dive into JavaScript
for my experience vanina JavaScript is
one messed up language which should be
avoided what do you think about web
assembly okay
why deep dive because while JavaScript
is one of the most popular programming
language.
So just like C and C++ first you know
it's so and also PHP and Python. So in
fact all these languages C C++
PHP and Python and we might include um C
C++
JavaScript PHP Python. Okay, this this
this these are basically the top five
the most universal language the top five
used by 99%
of all software in the world anywhere
okay 99% of 99% of them are written in
one of these language C++
JavaScript Python and uh
and PHP okay basically all your phone
well I I mean all websites is
JavaScript. Okay. And and anyway so so
these five most popular languages
are we could actually fairly correct to
say they are also the worst [ __ ]
possible.
Okay that's another you know so we are
getting into the huge topic of language
popularity.
So I have a I have tens of articles on
that. Why HC, why I love Golang, why I
love PowerShell, PowerShell complexity,
why bash sucks, which to learn, which
the nature of a programming language
written in 2000 year 2000. What
languages to hate and the latest 2025,
which programming language is best for
text processing? Okay, so what is
expressiveness in programming languages
2005 and 2025? We have programming
languages expressive expressiveness
comparison via line count. Okay. So we
got you know this the topic I'm very
much into and a section on popularity.
So anyway
the top five most popular languages most
popular languages are basically they are
the worst reasonably. Okay that's a
reasonable statement. They are the worst
[ __ ]
Now so
so the wow the you were asking why is
why why go dive uh why deep dive on
JavaScript well that's because you have
to wait you know because people needs to
know you know uh but for me personally I
I deep dive to JavaScript because I
because I writing website is my job it
so happens creating you know like myinfo
is over10 10,000
essays and tutorials on programming and
mathematics. Okay. So, and JavaScript is
the the programming language for the
web. Actually, you cannot avoid it. So,
you have to use it. So, that's why I got
deep into JavaScript.
And so let me mention again I have this
JavaScript in depth is the best
tutorial of Jav JavaScript the most
concise in a way written that you
understand and most in-depth and the
most correct accurate based on
JavaScript specification. I read several
versions like 1,00 10,000 pages you know
the incomprehensible JavaScript spec
ECMAS script
ECMAS script script so this this is the
best JavaScript in-depth tutorial in
English language
on the web and in printed printed form.
So what I'm saying is that you will not
find one single JavaScript tutorial
or reference in depth better than mine
doesn't on the web or in printed in in
print except you know but I have to make
one uh a couple exceptions
that is
so I can tell you a couple of exceptions
So you need to JavaScript books review.
So let me tell you a few exceptions okay
that could be better than mine or
comparable I would say. So JavaScript
the definitive guide by David Flanagan.
Now David Fla Flanagan is the best
programming language tutorial writers.
In fact, I my JavaScript tutorial I
started by reading his book, okay, cover
to cover his book in 2011.
Okay, so that's I that's when I really
started to learn JavaScript. I learned
it before, but it was like I thought
it's just like oh so simple. This chunk
script is different from Pearl, Python,
Ruby, Java, C++ because of the prototype
actually is fairly uh different all than
all the others because the prototype and
functional programming but it turn it
sucks okay in the end. So anyway, so
this this book is this David Flanagan.
So I his book
um how should I put it, you know? So
he's probably better than mine. you know
he's like
uh you have you can you know he's you
know he's a professional of course he's
a computer scientist like me but he's
certified okay he's well respected
so that you know so so that uh and this
of course uh Quarkford most famous
JavaScript guy highly respect you know
he's a language deep language dive
person okay I read I read and watched
lots of his stuff. Highly respect that
guy too. Quack. Okay. Crockot and this
David Flanagan.
These two person greatest
um you know of course I do not agree
with everything they say. But anyway so
the David Flanagan he doesn't talk much.
I mean he's mostly just known for write
for having written this JavaScript uh
guide. Okay. I highly recommend it. I
haven't read the latest. Okay. Nor have
I read his the Douglas Ko.
Okay. Now those two these two books I
highly recommend and I can say their
books might be better than mine
depending on your preference of style.
Okay. These two not the Mozilla. Okay.
Like most of you guys will say oh
Mozilla oh the thing you don't know
about JavaScript. No those are [ __ ]
Okay, whatever you know about
JavaScript, whatever you if you are
average, you know, let's say you work at
Google for two years on JavaScript, you
don't know [ __ ] Okay, that's what I'm
telling you guys. Okay, so check out my
tutorial JavaScript in depth.
Uh,
okay. So, so but we haven't finished
answering the question yet. Okay, so we
were talking about other possibly better
than mine. So there are these two guys,
David Flanagan and
Douglas Quarkford,
which I haven't read his latest book.
This one came out five years ago. Oh.
Oh, wow. By now, seven years ago. Java,
how JavaScript works. I haven't read it.
Okay. This new edition, I haven't read.
Okay. Now, another guy, this guy is also
extremely deep. Okay. I learned a lot
from this guy, Dr.
Axel lo
okay that's his kind of his name this
guy is very deep okay very two to two
reality to reality he's known by that
name uh I think today blogging kind of
died so but anyway this guy is very kind
I think kind of well known among uh the
JavaScript like elite JavaScript coders
okay
so his stuff on JavaScript. I have read
quite a lot. Okay. Because I I also do
my own research when I write my
JavaScript in depth. I read you know
like I have
like like the the the specification
sometimes I have trouble understanding
so I check other sources and so and
today there's AI of course but anyway so
this guy
Dr. Rash may you know exploring you know
exploring JavaScript he wrote several
books he he's a very deep his JavaScript
uh tutorial and guide of you know is is
the best I would say among among these
other like you know I would say you know
among the David Flanagan JavaScript the
definitive guide and or the Douglas
Crockboard okay or the exploring uh or
him so these
I respect I highly respect. So I would
admit if somebody say their JavaScript
book are better than these JavaScript in
depth, I would accept. Okay.
But but not from the Google or whatever.
Oh, I work for Google. Oh, I'm an author
of of notjs. Okay. Well, not not JS Ryan
D. I highly respect. Okay. But not not
some other. Oh, I'm author of jQuery.
Okay, those are [ __ ] in my opinion.
The Zuma, whatever the popular framework
by the Zumas. Uh, also I take it back
that jQuery
author.
I I don't like him, okay? Because I
think he's one of the like he's pushing
for social justice warriors, okay?
Anyway,
I I don't respect many, let's put it
this way. I don't respect many of the
Zuma like popular JavaScript like
framework creators.
So, okay, let's just say that the way
they I mean, so I mean obviously for
example, let's say uh
like many of them they they they they
are great coders. Let's say for example
like like like the JavaScript framework
creators okay those are very deep
non-trivial coders
but what I'm saying is that many of them
they
let's not go there okay that's something
else but anyway these are the books I
highly respect okay
and there is this book which I doesn't
really know. I just put it here for
comparison because this sik is a very
famous book for functional programming
for scheme lisp and there's a javascript
version. So it's you know worth
mentioning so I don't know how good it
is but basically they it's about more
about like the book's uh structure and
interpretation of computer programs.
Okay. So this book then there's this
elegant JavaScript eloquent JavaScript.
It's uh by a great coder but this is
[ __ ] Okay, this is one of the [ __ ] book
for beginners. JavaScript for beginners.
And then you got the MDM which is
Mozilla. Their tutorial are the worst
misleading crap. Okay, whatever. If you
don't know JavaScript, you try to learn
it from MSM or Zilla, you get you get
misled into all sort of like bad
thinking like the C or C++ or whatever.
Okay, that's that's a Mozilla. That's
the that's the JavaScript things you
guys most people know the most. Okay.
However, Mozilla is one got critical
thing is that if you want to know the
latest like browser support or whatever
latest from the JavaScript spec they are
actually the best because there's no
other source because all the browser
those implement JavaScript they they
they contribute to Mozilla in fact
there's a like corporate sponsor you
know for example Microsoft
closed down their entire JavaScript
tutorial video about 10 years ago and
they push for Mozilla. Okay, there's
some kind of background like behind the
scenes agreement. I don't know what's
going on. Okay, so Mozilla is very big.
Okay, it's like it it's it's
for somehow it there is some reason it
became like the JavaScript reference
as a you know like for the whole world.
So it's very powerful but their tutorial
you know the reference part is almost
essential because you cannot get that
info anywhere else not in any of this
book because once you write a book after
two years it's like outdated okay
including like after two years it's
after three or you know basically it's
outdated okay including all these books
so But so Mozilla is like the absolute
essential reference. It's it's updated
every week, every day
so-called open source, but there's
actually like deep deep state behind it
for reasons. Okay. But the but but their
tutorial is like sucks. Okay. Then
there's this we W3 school. Let's craft
and the and and then okay then then
there's another anyway.
Uh so anyway I I I was just promoting my
JavaScript tutorial. Okay. So uh you
guys give it a whirl.
So what do I think about web assembly?
Web assembly is you know the low-level
assembly I haven't looked into. I don't
know much about. though
uh but why introduce parent child to
illustrate the point why not I mean what
else the parent child is the most
natural in fact that's what inheritance
means parent child relationship ACP
go J says much better sometimes I wonder
what is uglier JS or C++ definitely C++
I think C++ is a magnitude more
Then JavaScript. Okay. Uh J3 Q says, "Do
you support purchase in Ali Pay or
WeChat?" No, those are uh uh Chinese
stuff. So
I hope to but you know it's too much
trouble. So I don't have
uh so just you know you well I guess you
are in China just uh just browse my
website. It's free anyway. So you can
like you can buy it. Of course you can
you can buy it. I send you a zip file of
the whole thing. How much is it now? 35
cheap. I should increase it to 100
because it's more like a donation. Okay.
Like nobody pays. Nobody you know what?
Why should you pay? Like everyone you
know everything is here on the web. You
can go anywhere on iPhone whatever. Why
should you pay? When you pay, you get a
zip file and which you have to like put
on your
uh Mac OS desktop. You can read it on
the phone, iPhone or Android.
So I can read it online. Why should I
pay? Well, because you are beautiful.
Okay, that is why and that's you know
I spend the time to write it. That is
why
and that is why
people do things. Okay, we do things
because you get paid. You you you get
paid to eat, to work, to whatever,
you survive.
You need food. That's how things work.
Everything that like like just like
everything you see in the world. Why is
it that way? because somebody is getting
paid to do whatever you do.
So, if you like my stuff, pay me. Okay,
that's a good thing.
Uh,
thanks for answering about JavaScript.
Uh, yeah, Rust language was spread by
Mozilla. Yes, that's true. This fact
alone should tell you enough. Yeah.
Yeah. Mozilla
Mozilla is a very deep state org just
like Google. Okay. Anyway, that's that's
getting pol into politics. Mozilla is
like all these like giant open source
they are called NOS's like non nong
government organization but actually
they are like a lot government in it. So
they so in the past 10 years things
become very bad. So Mozilla is no
exception. Then um I mean pushing for
rust is not really you know that bad but
they they but they they lots of very
nasty things. Let's not go there. Okay.
So I mean couldn't you show the issue
with his own property with just accent
alone? Oh.
Uh, what? Well, I guess you could
because
uh
Oh. Uh, yeah. So, if you have if the sun
has that property, that's right. You
could. Yeah. I know. Yeah. So, okay,
that's it for today. Let's put this back
and let's uh What is this page here? So,
I didn't do Okay. Okay, that's it. Bye,
guys. Hope you guys enjoyed it.
So, how how many people I'm going to
shut down in in one minute. Okay, bye
bye.
So we're going to put this code in
today's talk show. Yeah. Some
explanation. So we explained about the
prototype inheritance system today.
Part of rent part of lecture mixed
and spontaneously exemple without
preparation. That's what I do.
So where is S talk show today? Yeah. So
we're going to put that section there.
And I was going to actually work on lots
of coding. This is been being been
coding a lot JavaScript like like my
tutorials. All these need has a update.
You know all these update the all these
are updated today. All these sections
and then those are from yesterday and
still more to needs to be done. That's
why you still see this to-do. I mean
they are already written. I mean they
are written like this one for example
since 2017 almost 10 years ago or this
one since 200 uh okay
this is another new thing from
JavaScript 2022 three years ago they are
trying to uh kind of fix the ad because
the you see when you want to get a index
of an array you can you cannot use
negative index that's another major
problem in all Other languages you can
but you cannot in JavaScript. So they
created a new function a new method
string at oh yeah to extract the string
you know negative index.
Okay so this this you know so that's
another new thing added two years ago.
Uh and uh uh so let me just demonstrate.
So you can see for example you can see
all the JavaScript changes. So for
example, this this one is in um
ECMAScript 2015. This is 10 years ago.
Now go to the bottom. Let's go to the
bottom. So we have I have full
documentation of all the changes. Now
ECMAS script 2016,
you got these changes, you know. So I
document them. Then 17 2017, you know,
blah blah blah. Then the last let's go
to 2025. You got all these new functions
which I wrote about last year. So fully
documented. So this this is you are
looking at some of these JavaScript in
depth. Okay. So you can check out my
tutorial. So I was going to I was saying
that I was working on my website. Yeah.
So much you know coding uh update.
Okay. Bye.