good morning everyone
this is our talk show today is September
15th Sunday San Francisco time 1 o clock
p.m. yes I am Alive
let's pop out the chat and let's see
what we're gonna talk about so yesterday
I did a video on CSS my experience with
CSS and web design so that's one hour
night that's 18 minutes talking about
CSS and web design stuff it's
interesting but in the beginning six
minutes or seven minutes of the video
I played Bach it's music and that's a
mistake because then Google told me they
have automatic algorithms they told me
that you know they are I am infringing
the right you know of some company you
know it's all automatic
they have algorithms so I have a option
you know if you don't do anything then
Google you know according to the what
Google says they will introduce ads you
know the ad money goes to them even
though I don't have ads you know I don't
have ads turned on so that's one option
according to the Google page or I can
remove those audio those infringing part
of the music and they have a button you
know you just click they automatically
remove it so I clicked and however there
seems to be some software glitch so it
appears that one part is removed but the
other part is still there so I have to
do it again yesterday I have to do it
later on today and also for some reason
that is known to me the
you know the chat box is not available
it's in the beginning it shows but then
they do I it's it says it's now
available I do not know what is the
reason for that it may be related to
this music copyright thing I don't know
and possibly could it be because some
one male cat there if you are there you
know don't mention sensitive words
swimming is okay but yesterday you know
it's different you know don't swear like
you know it does pad to my video because
Google you know there's nothing I can do
so so avoid swearing just try to replace
them with some other words okay
Oh AB Fewster Kate it okay a few
stockade swearing words and but
yesterday someone mentioned there's a
political topic we didn't we didn't talk
about politics but however this summer I
mentioned some words so possibly that's
a reason it's a big time thing you know
one of the political guys is mentioned
so am I good morning am I good morning
battles number ten
oh okay good morning Cathy great to see
you Cathy Cathy speaks Chinese that's
fantastic Sagar how should I call you
Cathy do you have a Chinese name so many
people know me as in Chinese as that
that really means me pretty much means
products ah you know because in Chinese
you you know in Chinese culture or Asia
in general you have you know you respect
elders elders or your parents or your
grandparents or your or your ancestry is
kind of important you know the its
building into the whole culture its
building into the language so when you
so you have different terms to address
you know people who are elder there's
also always different terms
you know distinguishing older and
younger you know between brothers and
sisters you have a word for older
brother you have a word for younger
brother or older sister younger sister
and so on you know so in in Chinese
culture typically that's god damn don't
mention that word don't mention that
word I got you know the the the comments
got removed yesterday okay so I'm gonna
delete this comment okay you know yeah
let's you know let's not mention that
what good morning dear
and thank you Deon so much for that for
your patreon because I looked the
yesterday on my patreon account so some
people over the past half a year or a
year you know have contributed few
hundred dollars so thank you Deon for
that and in many others and you know
look that guy that guy you know that guy
that guy who got you know let's let's
not talk about that that guy who yeah
let's not talk about that so you know
YouTube chat now this this is a
different okay you know I noticed
there's something changed with this live
stream chat apparently it the chat you
know like before the video begins you
can chat right you can chat to me and I
can be pry but however it it looks like
the chat wheel oh when the video begin
whatever is before the chat will be
raised
same thing when a video ends so so when
when for example today that when the
video ends you guys can usually say
goodbye you know but usually that that
doesn't show because the moment I click
in the video that
God removed so is that rot13 so Michael
Michael has this rot13
let's see rot13 region
can you read route 13 without conversion
no I cannot I need to any conversion but
I never thought of that first you can
learn that's interesting so for those of
you don't know rot13 is the most ancient
encryption system that is you for
example let me show you this is called
Caesars encryption see how they call it
okay so let's begin talking we have two
topics actually number 10 and number
five or six five okay so hold on second
do it since so let's go through first of
all let's go to our talk show page
showing browser page down page down page
down and today's this this one is today
there is something I want to say and
rot13
now let's talk about in encryption a
little bit okay now I have a tutorial of
course I have tutorial on everything I
have a tutorial on crypt analysis basic
introduction where do you find that you
go to tech review tcp/ip let's see if
it's there there it is okay public key
cryptography for beginner now this is
this article is nothing technical it's
actually is just the introduction of the
concepts of the terminology of how it
works in general public key cryptography
now ciphers print X ciphertext okay a
method of encryption you know there are
many method
of encryption you have in general you
have symmetric key category of
encryption then you have public key
cryptography which is very popular in
the past 30 40 years and so you so you
have categories of in so all these are
encryption methods you know ways to
scramble text so so encryption method
they are called ciphers okay technically
they are called ciphers so safe cipher a
cipher means encryption method you know
so we have many ciphers now plain text
is the text you you want to encrypt you
know before you want to make it into a
secret and ciphertext is after
encryption you know you you take the
plaintext you apply a cipher to it you
got a encrypted text that's called
ciphertext now ciphers you know one of
the most basic encryption method
ciphered is called substitution cipher
so how does that work that is like this
okay let me show you let me show you
okay so for example if you have this if
you change a to n p 2 o c 2 p actually
that that's whipped what's going on okay
so a a to be for example b 2 c c 2p + z
to a okay this this kind of encryption
is called substitution so you just
replace every letter by some other
letter now this method encryption is
called there's a name is this is called
Caesar cipher okay I don't know if I
didn't show here but the gender modern
name is substitution cipher okay you
know you substitute words or letters but
one of the most simple one is Co
Caesar cipher I believe there it is
Caesar sir you see the picture a 2n okay
this is what 13 so a 2n Caesar cipher so
four and one of them is called rods 13
that means to rotate 13 places a
replaced by n P is replaced by oh where
does n came from n is basically the 13th
letter so B is a second letter then P
becomes o o is the 15th letter you know
you use of you know you substitute
substitute like that and in Emacs there
is a built-in command called what 13 for
example I can I can select this I call
the command wrote 13 region enter you
see M becomes a oh we go becomes P they
actually become reversed because you see
English got 26 letters so if you go by
13 that means they doesn't doesn't
matter which way you encrypt or decrypt
they are still they are kind of the same
pair a to n n to a but if you do rot 14
then this is going to be different so
rot13 is kind of a popular way to for
example if you are posting a puzzle
puzzle you know a math puzzle and you
want to show the answer you can rot13 it
then people you know so people don't
accidentally read read the answer and
you know rot13 is simple because you
know it's reversible I mean it's it's
all substitution ciphers are reversible
but what rot13 has the properties
properties such that the way to encrypt
and the way to decrypt is the same you
just rotate 13 faces so that's about 130
and that's about Emacs okay so
so let's see so let's read the comments
okay so many comments anyway use Y
snippet I talked about that I don't use
it I used for the first five years but
then I just use brief I talked about
that in some video a grave is more
powerful okay let me check let me read
the comments okay that and let's see
let's see what is topic ten topic ten
[Music]
okay I need to stop these and wasting my
CPU okay topic five is explained
javascript object and javascript opie in
depth about two days ago we did that one
we did that why in depth and I think
it's a very good one
so if you are one if you want to
understand JavaScript opie in detail
check out that video about two days ago
two or three days ago
javascript object and opie in depth and
so we so javascript is a huge topic so
that we talked about that for ninety
minutes but but we can continue so
maximum use is you know topic number
five so we can continue on that and
bathroom uses personal explanation of
cars in Python yeah we can do that yes
so bathroom you did you watch that video
I suppose did you maybe you did we can
do that and what's number ten number ten
colon write a script that validate
matching brackets okay this is also a
great topics to talk about but we I'm
not sure you know I'm thinking maybe
next time and so which topic between
these two so anyone have more opinions
like say which one you prefer so we can
do that for : I'm thinking maybe we
should do a dedicated one
because Scholl and for Golan that topic
you know right a Golan script that
validate matching brackets you know all
type of matching brackets square
brackets round bracket curly braces and
the many Chinese brackets and I also
have a Emacs script that does that you
know that's gonna be live coding so
maybe we should do that another day what
is what sweetest dream in timing as
today's fattest well it changes so it
changes often you know I was sticking to
it changes so you know because my swim
is sleeping schedules you know changes
all the time and also I was thinking you
know because if I have some other time
then people in other places in China for
example they could watch it when live so
let me check read the comments okay so
is there a new feature that lets you cut
off stuff out of the video after
uploading isn't there a new feature I
don't know if it's new or not but
YouTube provides a simplified editor
video editor but I don't know how to use
it you know I've never edited video
before you know you have to kind of
learn how to edit video Michael says I
mean still would love to know how
compiler works because really have no
idea and kind of want to get to higher
level understanding okay yeah so compare
how compiler works that's another topic
okay so we got three topics we already
we kind of already started random let's
see what you know we talked about 17
minutes
okay so I mean I I'm not sure so if you
have opinions say it okay good morning
Xetra ski OS Key says topic suggestion
what are your thoughts on patch or shell
scripting okay those are no good shell
scripting those bash shell scripting
those are dead long dead technology
nobody
well people actually still use that
especially for installations but you
shouldn't use it you know Perl totally
replaced it 20 years ago at least 20
years ago Perl totally replaced bash or
shell scripting 20 years ago
why because Perl is already building you
know it's out of box in Linux you know
pose kind of the UNIX philosophy school
of thought you know they are kind of the
same community so Perl 20 years ago is
in every Linux box by default you know
out of the box and Perl is more powerful
than shell or bash more concise and it's
actually a general-purpose language and
you know you have data structures you
have least you have hash just just Perl
is the same class like Python Ruby okay
so Perl is far more powerful flexible
and easy easy to use and the the the pro
is very the syntax is hated by many
people but see oh it's better than
impassioned in shell okay so Perl and
it's no slow it's in fact faster then
past Rochelle so you actually should
just use pearl you know passion shell
scripting they should be long dead you
just use pearl
but however UNIX people they you know in
my opinion they are idiotic in my
opinion UNIX should be replaced you know
Perl should we play smash scripting long
ago 20 years ago but people don't do
that they still do bash you know
especially the Ruby you know Ruby has
this anyway you know back in ten years
ago you have this anyway so the UNIX
people
they didn't they didn't think of that
way so they still write you know bashing
shell scripts for installation squids
so today bash is still around you know
bath should be used only for interactive
you know interactive shell that's the
only purpose anyway so yeah though is
there's no good reason to still use bash
so skills s key skill skill ASCII says
I'm currently writing a really simple
script to handle my mouse key vines for
that only nuts you me on Linux right you
know except so bad you know I have
article about that so okay so I think
today we're gonna just talk a random
then so no more opinions about that
so bathroom amuse questions but is Perl
is easy ass bash yes well yes actually
you know it depends on what you mean of
course patch is smaller language so of
course the badger is simpler but
actually not really pro is far more
powerful family in Peru is basically
just a bash / you know Perl syntax is
basically just shell scripting the same
kind of thought the same kind of you
know pretty much all the same including
you know the the variable thing and you
know the you know if so okay so let me
show you
so micro says every language you already
know is the easiest no not really
you know thank you learning a language
is actually not that easy but you know I
but you know to be to me you know to be
fair I think it's fair to say pearl is
not more difficult than bash me because
they are almost like the same thing okay
I mean Trudy because I know Perl
very well how is the language I know and
you know at least 20 years ago 20 years
ago I haven't been
in peril for more than 15 years pearl
but you know but once you know it's
something so well you know I know I
coded you know you know I I coded pearl
you know company for four years writing
ecommerce software you know servers so I
have a pro tutorial so this page is one
page overview I mean this one page
teaches you basically all the pearl
I mean Python and Ruby is still easier
to learn but anyway if you do shouts
within you know there's no reason to do
bash but today the story is again
different I wouldn't I would not
recommend you know o learn Perl and
don't do tournament Badgett I do not
recommend that 20 years ago I recommend
that today know why because there's more
reasons you know things change in
society social reasons why so why do I
not recommend pearl anymore because
pearl today is dead okay it's dead you
if you are going to learn pearl you are
learning a dead language there are still
jobs you know one or two you know that
pearl is dead so that so so we we are
back to the situation you have bash bash
for installing script for you know some
can fix things you know you are back to
that state you know situation but okay
but still writes all right so nobody
used bash today well people still do but
I still recommend don't use space don't
don't don't do bash okay don't do you
know people what people do you do you
want you can use Ruby or you can use
Python okay don't you know there's no
good reason to use bash okay there is no
good reason to use spash today use Ruby
Python okay
Oh pearl Oh pearl but pearl is dead
okay so so Ruby Python they are far more
powerful and simpler than bash but
however the industry I mean if you
working in an industry it's still the
kind of use using bash for installing
script is still common for example the
most you know there are so many
installation scripts that's written in
bash that's one of them that's the most
idiotic okay let me show you Ruby so
Ruby and these ten years ago I think
she'll still so today you have this you
have this what's it called
okay I think I'd remove that Joan so
ruby gem break you know Ruby has its own
jargons IRB IRB is the interactive Ruby
command line interface interactive Ruby
so IRB so for example in shell you can
type I are be okay
now we are in Ruby can you guys see it
yes okay so for example one first three
you got four okay now exit and Ruby has
you know IRB jump jump so ruby gem is
toward for installing managing Ruby
packages gem is written in Ruby you know
so Jim is like you know uh rpm of
JavaScript you know and in other
languages so Jeong Ruby jump so rake
rake is like make in UNIX you know like
make make file you know Rick is
returning Ruby juvies version of break
and make is in anyway anyway so ruby has
rake you ruby has this bunch of jargon
bundle bundle then your ruby has artic a
vm okay our VM yeah our VM is the one I
want to talk about so let's go to Ruby
copy the path paste it here link off' i
then go to the file go to the directory
such for our VM because I have a article
on that okay our VM he's one of the most
idiotic I don't like them you know I
hated them in fact in 2012 I was
learning Ruby for like two months I I
did learn Ruby for two months but I
never actually caught anything much I'm
in Ruby back then I was thinking Ruby is
going to be my main language you know
switching from Python and before I was
switching from pearl but that never
happened so so right now if I want to do
general scripting of industrial
languages I use : so anyway Ruby Ruby
you have this a VM a VM is kind of a
tool that gives gives you a independent
managed independent Ruby environment
like like that you know you know anyway
independent Ruby environment so you have
differently Ruby versions installations
and different said you know each one has
its own libraries you know whatever
libraries you install so you can you
know for different projects and you'll
be a VM you know when you go when you
want to install Ruby a VM this is
fashionable like ten years ago they tell
you they tell you to just run a you know
copy and paste this line of code and run
in shell you know it's extremely idiotic
it's a security problem where do I find
it did they change that okay chair Ruby
is better chair Ruby is a alternative so
anyway back then you know you be when
you go to our DM website okay here I
think you know what they tell you is any
okay somewhere somewhere was anyway back
to end on their website what did
how you is they tell you okay to install
a VM you just copy this line of code and
paste in your shell and run it okay
that's wait is that right apt-get
install be essential no not that one
this one this line this line that's what
they tell you to use you know curl - L
and URL and bash piped to bash this is a
[ __ ] idiotic practice you know and
this this has been popular around 2012
2010 2008 - mm I don't know if they
still do that so a lot projects you know
when you want to install they just tell
you to copy your shells quick line or a
single line and just run it so what
these two is that this will do is that
it will fetch the bash script it will
fetch it and you'll just run it so
basically if if they have a bash script
that that says TV the whole directory
delete your TV do entire life then you
just oh you know you know you just run
it that you know that's that's bad and
that's what this idiot millennial
generation of coders are doing I think
this kind of thing are popular in Ruby
community and JavaScript because you
know a programming language and its
community are often associated with the
kind of they do have some kind of a age
group generation so for example Ruby
Python they are kind of the millennial
generation coders and the thinking the
ideas you know the style you know are
different for example from Perl
programmers from see from Emacs users
typically okay this is general okay of
course many of you are not annual young
people you don't think it that way but
anyway so Ruby Python you know I mean
you be and not Python Ruby mostly Ruby
JavaScript they most of their people are
kind of this new millennial generation
and they tends to be these kind of
people they don't really know
details about algorithms they don't they
don't care they don't they are not
interested in those kind of things they
are not you know they tend to be just
library users and you know follow follow
following instruction kind of people
you'll be I realized you know once I get
that into the Ruby community so Ruby you
know they have this shell script you
know that's no good okay so let me copy
that this page is pretty good oh this is
from 2012 this kind of things change all
the time
so so I wouldn't say this page is still
good but you know that gives you the it
becomes history so this becomes a
historical document like ten years later
then you'll see oh this is how they do
things back then 2012 installing Ruby
Ruby a VM and Ruby a VM is is is stinks
in every way you know I try to use it
stinks in every way and it's by you know
millennial generation you know but the
people are good though because you know
here's what they do like okay so if I
have a Ruby IBM question like I try to
install it and I run into some error up
for example I go to treat her right
Twitter is the you know social network
popular hymn with Millennials so I post
the question hey does anyone know you
know usually talking to my followers
does anyone know this arrow in Ruby a
via then you know what they do is that
the Ruby IBM guy you know they they have
two guys and they they are they are
sitting on Twitter they watch everything
they you know they have a search for RVM
all the time automatic or otherwise so
whenever they see your question they go
answer it that's what they do and this
is the way actually this is a SEO you
know search engine optimization this is
one of the way one of the technique to
grow your audience to make you know
whatever you do popular so they they got
this guy is
you cannot say it's bad it's a nice guy
okay you know he's just sitting on
Twitter or Facebook or you know the
social networks and whenever he see your
question he answered and you know kind
of me very well so he did that you know
every time I come friend you know every
time I find this this this this our RV a
VM [ __ ] you know I don't like the design
they do you know I don't you know it's
I've in my opinion it's you know bad in
many ways so everybody every time you
post a question this nice guy answers
you know politely that's that's a issue
okay that's a problem you know so I
usually it's helpful okay so that solves
your problem especially when you are
working for a company you know we are
you know you need to get things done
then you saw the answer it's extremely
helpful so I'm grateful for that but
meanwhile that also stifles any
criticism you might have but because now
now he answered my question now I cannot
you know [ __ ] you know frame the [ __ ]
of a VM anymore because you got this
nice guy answer your question what are
you gonna do so this is a social issue
okay this is this is it's it's it's just
the way things are it's not not a
problem it's not exactly a problem you
can solve you know but then you have to
kindly maybe possibly kindly if you want
to criticize then you have to possibly
kindly criticize anyway it turns out is
I learned a lot of people don't like a
VM either
so anyway obvi and back then like in
2012 at least it was like the number one
solution it's like the most popular tour
for for you know managing in independent
Ruby installations so that's about our
VM we we were talking about that because
we were talking about we were talking
about shell scripts so we got so many
questions so I'm gonna get into that but
I there's are the things I want to
mention okay so so that's about Ruby
then crochet
it's a same thing okay they got a shell
script which I despise closure enclosure
you got okay okay this topic Israel you
would be interested because I know you
are doing kosher stuff you're into
crochet anyway we were talking about
shells good so let me mention this
crucial in argon which is a pain in my
ass okay
kosher closure
you've got the Linlin again script so
what is it it's an installation script
frog crochet it's not just installation
it's for installing closure well mostly
it's a closure library manager okay so
for example on Linux you use apt-get you
know AB AB get AB search you know you
have apt in other packages that's for
managing Linux PAC packages you know
libraries whatever you use that all the
time in JavaScript you have RPM right in
closure you have this one to Lin again
lannigan is written by this hacker this
well known hacker also he is a great
hacker though he's a great programmer
he's he his name is he goes by techno
man see anyone knows his name type it ok
I forgot that moment so Ruby so Hannes
again so let me write down what we were
doing so closure techno Mansi and I know
him I know what he does a lot he so he
created the he did many things okay so
he's a hacker techno Mansi is a great
hacker okay he's a hacker I you know I
normally I would say a quick programmer
but he's not he's a great programmer but
however he's the he's one of those guys
who are into the UNIX philosophy thing
okay he's that type of people so you
call him hacker so he's a he's a L
emac this expert crucial expert he's
also a closer expert he is also a Lua
Lua expert he is also a keyboard field
building expert okay he be on the
keyboard so let me show you what's the
name don't let linen you cannot when
you've to closure you cannot avoid not
using then then then okay closure is
this extreme Conville intertwine with
java you know I would loved closure
except it is in I talked about this many
times in my past videos I would love
closure except it is intentionally
intertwined
you know ingratiating with Java
intertwined like cake you cannot
separate them it intentionally
intertwine with the [ __ ] Java in
every way so that you so you know so and
and then that is why you do tracks in
you know the Leningrad we haven't
stopped to talk about that yet but let
me finish the we're talking about this
guy this guy techno man see okay he is a
keyboard expert he created this keyboard
anyone remember the name type it okay I
like that if you know the trio's okay he
created this Atria's
keyboard okay so he's also so he also
Leonard gun is written by him okay you
know that's a story so this is a story
related to Emacs community so he's also
of course a Emacs coder
I mean Emacs user so anyway he created
reinigen so what is Lanigan Lanigan is
this huge bash shell script okay it does
many things I mean it's well done I
would say okay but
because for I did closure intensively
for one year because I was working for
this David Pollock he's a great guy okay
you know so he paid me for it
he paid he paid me you know industrial
industrial compass composition like like
eighty dollars to code closure and emag
bees so I did that for him that's how I
did closure that that's how I you know
wrote this whole closure thing closure
tutorial let me paste that here okay I
already did
so lane against Olynyk on is is is this
manage you know package management tool
you can search libraries you can install
it you can you know manage dependencies
just like JavaScript rpm you know it
install manages dependencies and all
that so it's a shell script you know
it's a bash shell script okay I have a
tutorial here you can see all the
commands it's it does a lot of things
you know these all these commands you
know warm start of Java but the thing is
with Java you know then you just Java is
Java is complete country pain yes Lynne
again so why are we mention and again
because we are talking about bash you
know so so this is an example of where
in industry patch we still used it's a
it's a mainstream it's an its kind of
necessary you don't you know but in my
opinion in my opinion there's no reason
to use bash you know you use call and
you use Ruby use Python or even Perl you
know you should not use smash so we got
a lot comments so let's so so that
concludes my topic about whether we
should use passionate like my opinion
about bash and Shou you know don't like
my opinions don't use it
unless okay another topic you know you
were saying who is who said that who
asked that ask his skill I think so I
think he was saying that he was creating
bash script to modify keyboard key
bindings okay I guess in that case you
use bash because this is only two lines
you know you don't it doesn't make sense
to use Perl Python and also in that case
in fact you know it's yeah you would use
bash I guess yeah so so what I want to
say about Linux yeah about that okay so
I do have a there's something I want to
say about that
let's go to keyboard software let's
search for Linux okay so actually let's
go through keybinding search for Linux
there it is this article Linux versus
Mac versus windows which is best for key
bindings okay let me talk let's talk
about that okay this is a epic story the
tale of Linux the tale of key binding in
Linux okay now as you know I'm a
keyboard phonetic you know I you know
sing back in 1994 1994 I created use I
created a for a clay out on the Mac
using the tool best edit on the Mac
that's the most popular tool back then
you know because back then on Mac you
don't have Borak Windows has were like
building since 19 since Windows 3.1 I
think 1994 or so but Mac doesn't have it
until 1998 were actually out so back so
I started to use for rack since 1994 by
creating a variety out myself
so you know I you know then you know I I
also use you know in past 30 years I
used Linux Mac Windows as my main
desktop machine so I'm familiar you know
every time I you say you know I I
familiar with all the software tools
related to key binding on each operating
system so by now I know which one is
more you know which operating system
with me with with respect to key binding
like customization of keys which rappers
are in system is the best which one is
more powerful which one is easier to use
with with respect to you know how to how
do you create your own keys and so on
and my conclusion is linic is the worst
the sucks donkey ass Linux [ __ ] Linux
[ __ ] open-source [ __ ] free software
foundation okay they that's all related
okay that's all this can this conclusion
about the next key binding it's it has
to do with all all that I mention
open-source fanatism
and free software that's that's the end
result okay I'm telling you just you
know believe it or not that's up to you
okay I'm telling you my experiences
because you know before I you know I I
use Linux as my desktop system from
nineteen from 2000 about 2011 to 2000
for like four years okay maybe 2010 2010
to 2004 I you know I used Linux as my
desktop everyday you know for four years
by the way before I was Solaris at the
main for four years back in year 2000
okay like year 1998 starting there so
don't say oh you don't know Linux okay
shut up those guys okay the my first
Linux installation is MK Linux on Apple
Apple created MK Linux back in 1997 look
it up MK Linux okay that's my first
Linux installation but anyway so I use
the Linux as my desktop obviously
for four years you know around 2010 so I
thought you know the the the foremost in
me I thought obviously in Linux would
provide the most power and the most
flexibility when it comes to change your
key bindings because you know obviously
Linux you have shell you have everything
shell okay everything is a file
you know the UNIX philosophy everything
is a file shell script you have X 11 you
have configurations for X 11 you have
you know X X X mod map okay so I have
actually a complete tutorial on Linux
key bindings so you know for example
this is oh my for example you go to sake
Bob guide you go to key bindings no you
go to software section and you go to the
Linux section so you got 20 yards of the
articles 30 articles on pre binding on
Linux you know how do when you get into
key binding there are many details okay
then you started to discover many they
are different different levels of a
power how do how do you define key
bunnies for example some tool can swap
keys but they cannot if you want for
example f12 to do ctrl C you cannot okay
in many tools you cannot then that
requires a different tool different
level of power okay
you have many of these kind of issues or
to example another example suppose you
want from from this day on you want
every time you want to when you press
ctrl T for example you want it to become
ctrl F now that's another power okay
many gaming software cannot do that okay
actually most gaming software cannot do
that that's another kind of different
level of key binding okay so anyway I
have 20 articles about key binding you
can so this is a good tutorial you can
learn it I mean may impose it here so so
after today's video on YouTube then you
YouTube I'll have these index or you can
see all of you can see them by going
into my website saw talk show so I have
an index of my past videos and typically
for example yesterday I have a list of
topics you can you know so anyway back
to the back to linux key bindings so
what we were talking about we are
talking about these articles so linux
key binding versus mac and windows so I
thought you know you would Salinas would
be the most powerful and easy to program
especially when you already know bash or
pearl you know you already know UNIX
well it turns out that's not the case it
turns out Linux is the worst it's the
worst [ __ ] [ __ ] it's not just the
worst okay compared compared to the Mac
or Windows it's a [ __ ] [ __ ] you know
it's ten times worse okay
even you know assume you already know
bash scripting you know x11 you know
this technical details it's still ten
times worse the [ __ ] no [ __ ] the Linux
people you know all that we here we have
other you know my friends or you guys
every day saying Oh Linux is better Oh
Microsoft sucks
Oh Linux is better this way that way
[ __ ] it's a patent you know your brain
is is fried by the unique Linux idiocies
ideologies so much that you don't see
what's you don't understand you don't
see the word we award anymore okay now
I'm pretty sure you guys disagree okay
if you disagree post post your reasons
okay let other people Church you know
I'm not going to buy anything okay
I'm not like the Linux [ __ ] and the
the Emacs [ __ ] they pen every time
you say something disagreeable like you
if you criticize Richard Stallman on
reddit they pan you okay same thing with
a Linux [ __ ] they ban you right
away
I don't ban okay use use if you disagree
with my opinion posted okay let other
people Church so it is my opinion that
Linux sucks donkey ass and I
that this I learned this the hard way
okay so I'm a I'm a keybinding phonetic
so I look for answers like I want to you
know I want to do weird things I want to
make you know control F becomes F - okay
I do this you know we are things so
every step you know every step of the
way I learn it you know I spent hours
going to stack overflow
you don't you don't get much answers on
Stack Overflow you go to the our clinics
that's the best face our clinics they
have a wiki okay you know you they they
did they focus on Linux tech details
anyway I hope you know so I spent hours
hours every day here four four four four
four years this or that everyday [ __ ]
[ __ ] Linux then eventually I learned
you know if you want to do that this is
how you do if you want to do that this
is how you do it if you want to you know
do this you have to install this to or
that you know so all these are detailed
here in this you know my tutorial about
Linux key binding and so you know here's
my result that's my conclusion okay so
on the Mac on Windows for example on
Windows what is a solution aren't we on
Windows let me tell you so you go to
software on Windows Windows you know
they have their own ways you know I'm
not into Windows okay I don't like
Windows why I don't like I don't like
big corporations I like the the none
none you know I like the I like the
grassroots I like the people I would
like the freedom people like you guys
like the Linux phonetics and open-source
phonetics freedom people I like that's
me that's you know I'm the product
that's why I'm in this community
I don't like Microsoft I don't know okay
and I I use Microsoft as my desktop for
like three years before Linux I guess
that's how you know I used for four
years I switched to Linux as my desktop
so back so my lead on Windows is my main
operating system from about 2009 or 2008
to 2011
something like that okay Windows is my
main desktop I use it every day you know
do everything so on Windows they have
their community you know they award I
never got into you know I thought when I
switch to Windows I thought you know
okay I'm going to become you know I'm
gonna learn all the windows details you
know the registry that never actually
happened you know I don't I just I don't
it doesn't happen didn't happen with me
okay but anyway for keybinding stuff I
learned basically there are many tools
but basically you just use this one tool
autohotkey okay all right so I have I
have a complete tutorial
you know autohotkey so okay let me post
it here so so order so on Windows you
just use autohotkey that that basically
solves all your key mining needs
basically oh okay
I suppose supposed to Linux
you have to oh this tool this tool that
tool x11 config you know for example x11
whatever you doing x11 that's only for
x11 that doesn't work for example if you
want to switch to varrock but that only
works for x11
once but if you are you know in you know
on Linux you have then you know the
Buddha the Buddha of scream you you have
you know you have the single user mod
then that's not ball rack okay so if you
want work on that then it's some other
thing is some other [ __ ] config it's
very it's very complicated and that
convict you cannot just you know is for
example let me show you one of the
complexity of Linux okay so so if you
want go out everywhere not just in x11
you have to do system keyboard layout
okay
you have to sudo dpkg we configure
keyboard configuration you have to
install that [ __ ] you have to install
that [ __ ] and the technique of mechanism
is in act default keyboard
okay so that's another config file you
have to dig into and don't make mistakes
if you make a mistake in that in that in
those value [ __ ] up you put up then
you don't know what where your keys go
you [ __ ] up okay
then what are you gonna solve that I
don't know it's gonna be you know the
grub boot you know you go to into coops
and whatever you know I don't know how
to solve that there's gonna be another
five hours five hours scan for that
don't make me say okay so that's about
that's about how you change for act
layout on Linux okay and but and by the
way also different district different
this Linux distribution they may or may
not be different depending on what you
want to do for this one I suppose
I'm guessing it's universal but you can
never be sure because every distro they
do their own things they [ __ ] [ __ ] the
Linux share phonetics the open-source
[ __ ] you know what I mentioned this many
times why they do that because they all
want their own power you know on the
surface they are all sharing you know we
are or one you know one word for better
humanity but actually no that's not the
reason that's not the case okay so
that's about Linux and what about Mac on
the it turns out okay let me go back to
the article Linux versus Mac versus
windows which is best for key binding it
turns out Mac is the easiest by far by
far by far but you know by biped by a
Mac Mac magnitude okay on the Mac like
right now I'm using if you want to
change key binding doesn't matter how I
so tarik one you know there are many
tools on the Mac okay so I have you know
I have also a complete tutorial about
mat key binding so you go to software
you go to you know I have 10 pages 10
pages about all everything you want to
know about key binding on the Mac and
the first article shows several tools
for the Mac you know over the past 30
they they come and go you know for four
five years these two is the best then
some other tools come up you know anyway
on a Mac today you just go install
carabiner okay you just install that it
does everything you need you know and
it's GUI and also it you know anyway
they how they do it changes because
carabiner also went you know they have
different versions you know Mac changes
you know Mac always change versions they
and also they anyway on a Mac it's the
most easy okay you just you just use
install carabiner basically you get all
you need all the things you need okay
that's that's my grand about you know
Linux and about Mac versus windows
versus Linux how with respect to key
binding so today's topic we talked about
these things we talked about in you know
we talk about encryption cryptography
ciphers rot13 ciphers we talked about
learn Perl WETA Bob talked about learn
Ruby we talked about Ruby IBM how it
sucks because of the you know and what
we talked about shell scripts and we
talked about Lena Gong and closure and
taking take no messy guy he created a
triage keyboard then so that's that's I
think that's basically today's that's
one hour so maybe we talked about ten or
twenty minutes more so if you have
questions put my name into it so I'm
gonna read the comments and address all
the questions and I need a drink
today's drink cranberry cranberry with
raspberry may gotten cranberry first
raspberry okay if you have questions
address to me okay make it orange
colored so I can see it like typing
sorry you know my my name okay let's let
me add read the comments answer
questions so let me read my name first
so we're gonna do our pee-wee let's
continue doing ope tomorrow okay if you
are here bathroom meal yeah next time
you are if you are you know in my video
say it you know then we do that so next
time yeah next time we do that so Kathy
where you from if you don't mind tell us
like are you in China or are you
somewhere else so bad so yes for that
power is easier a special battle says
they are plans consideration to rebrand
power6 as a new different language in
profile power7 and profile as per 7 so
that there is no misconception i
provides old or not develop any more
proof 7 I haven't heard a power 7 you
know I think Pro is dead
forget about Pro 6 I mean they are so
there are always people there are fans
of some language ok phonetics like you
know every time you know no and then I
mentioned pro in social media like on
Twitter or Master Dan because I coded
you know I was a pearl expert you know
then people then will there will be
pearl people you know they don't exist
anymore anyway anyway they don't exist I
mean there but they have you like my
people but every time they're just you
know they they all say on social media
then they think you might think oh there
are a lot pearl people but they don't
exist anymore poor people the poor is
dead ok but anyway they had you know
these fanatics they say they'll say oh
you need to learn / 6 / 6 is so great
and they are you know doing this or that
same thing you know this happens in
every language has cow Julia you know
has sky is gonna tell you all you need
to learn Haskell category theory it's a
future it's a future guys Haskell is the
future guys you know every program in
the future every software
is gonna be hundred two hundred percent
proved you know math system that's
returning Haskell is the future then
Julia and the rust come my god Rose
people versus you know what you know
what I don't like rust okay Rose must
belong to the community of see see see
okay see hackers UNIX philosophy those
type people they like worst and they
it's a big thing just you know they all
tell you oh you gotta what do you think
of rows you need to write used Ross okay
I don't like it I don't like it because
it's not my type it's not my style
because Ross rust they focus on
low-level stuff like memory a memory
stuff written memory references int
float [ __ ] I don't like I don't like
those they focus on compiler stuff you
know the the same kind of thing the UNIX
people the C code asleep that they like
okay I don't like those all right I like
functional programming I like high-level
I like cruise proof systems in your
since I like Haskell okay but but a scow
is kind of popped so I kind of in anyway
so sorry that's my not my thing but is
it good I guess Rossi's good you know
you know it's a new language in general
that new newer languages are better goes
by ten years every decade you know if if
to language to language they differ by
by ten years in general the later ones
are better so you know so if you you
know if you are was fans that's good
then people tell you learn julia then
you know things like that people always
tell you to do you know that's language
fanatism of course so that is not a
drink okay so but for me to drink and
also first added the cheap energy drink
sugar-free question how do you split
screen vertical witchcraft sorry keys
vertical that's easy what do you mean
okay so you pressed and not the key
you know you press one key to switch
windows so for me I'm onboard keyboard I
by the way I also have my own
customization so the key you see here
may not be what you type I've you know
anyway so I pressed one key to split top
and bottom and and if I want vertical I
I press space for okay
that's what do you mean right space for
okay one key ok space for know most okay
no more split then vertical
no more split a vertical no more space
this is the ear X let's see vertical
speed way in vertical okay so there it
is Emacs and let's run calc so I got a
calculator wait what okay let's run
crack here so 3 3 + 3 + 4 enter first
now that's how you do 3 plus 4 it's a
post polish notation ok now I can tell
you about the history of that notation
and the gin in general the history of
notations that's another topic first
polish notation ah
you abbreviate it as rpm a reverse
polish notation that's what you call it
reverse polish notation then this show
calendar here calendar ok
oh so we got calendar we have calculator
and let's see let's show hexa mod hex
hex Ahmad and Hank smart format discard
and do yes yes oh [ __ ]
it turns everything into X mod ok so now
I need to switch buffers so
now I go here switch to a buffer now
let's show all my buffers here and over
here let's - yow yow
great yow let's do a shower then over
here
let's go through diet and over here
let's go to diet and go to a image
directory and let's show a image okay
then we need to God I need to I need to
shrink the image size okay image
decrease size okay so how do you
decrease the image sizes let's show
another picture then okay so they there
it is the the fantastic Oracle Emacs the
power of Emacs okay back to comments
what we what were we talking about yeah
that's how you split windows vertical so
I think it's faithful ya pro is where do
you use agree screen why do you use that
ugly screen what ugly green oh you think
this screen is ugly now this color is
called honey true okay by the way this
color for example it's this back to
Emacs oh we got a what let's see
okay so we got a new window by the way
this this article is about those
computer scientists they John Hennessy
and David Hedison they they wrote a day
oh they designed risk chip I think they
designed a risk CPU so anyway I wanted
to show oh yeah so new buffer so
actually go through my Emacs in it
that's not not it let's go to keybinding
my Emacs keybinding customization so
this file is my Emacs keybinding
customization go to diet that's a file
and every file in this directory is my
Emacs in it
now I let's delete those backups I don't
want it
d-damn yes then go to settings ok now
this file is the most fundamental
settings meaning that you don't need any
packages excuse me thankee like every
setting in this file can run from a you
know from a fresh Emacs without you know
installing packages so these are the
most basic setup such as background
color for example you see this so you
see this block of code and you see this
lamp called background color honey Dru
okay that's how you that's this color
that's that's not ugly green my friend
Israel you know people have asked me how
do you know like what what color theme
you do you use I don't use any color
theme I don't like color themes you know
I don't like those all those color
themes the fact that color themes I want
my user interface to be the most ugly
possible because I'm a functional
person you know I'm 100% functionality
person
I don't want curly stuff I want I don't
want pity [ __ ] you see and you see many
Emacs fanatics they think they are
functional your for example you go to
Emacs you know reddit forum you know you
go to Emacs many little phone a lot of
these Emacs people they will you know
they are like going extreme they say
they tell you oh you should use Emacs in
shell like let me show you know window
like for example let's let's let's -
let's start Emacs
Emacs - Q and - end of you that means no
no no window in system so this is the
this is Emacs in shell you know so you
go to the Emacs forum they gonna tell
you oh you should use Emacs this way
because we saw that and they say and
they say oh you should we move you see
the score bar right here
many Emacs people they tell you - oh you
should remove scuba because this or that
because they are idiots okay I'm telling
you they are they are inefficient idiots
they are doing they are they are
inefficient in efficient you know do you
want talker you know you want talk about
efficiency I'm the master you know I'm
not a great programmer I am NOT great
eMac this coder there are a lot people
know you might be spitter than me you
know i'm not you know i'm i you know if
you asked my own opinion of myself I'm
not a great program I'm not even a good
mathematician because you know I don't
know yeah that a best at best I'm a I
had a I have equivalent to a in the
undergraduate degree of math that's the
most you can say about what I know of
math okay but they have a few things I
could say I'm a master and they are not
very much now not many in a word okay
one is efficiency about keybinding
about yeah keyboard key binding
efficiency issues okay I would be the
master you you you will not find many
you know in a world and and I'm also the
master who has been sitting in front of
a computer like right now in the inning
in one chair over 20 years span of time
if you take statistical average I would
be the top within top 1000 in the world
probably okay it's City you know you
measure the hours sitting in front of a
chair I am a master of that okay back to
the Emacs stuff okay so so many of these
Emacs nerds okay they think they are
efficient you know big that's not true
okay they think they are actually what
they are is they they are just into they
are into whatever is more difficult
whatever is more seems more nerdy more
men you know whatever is more difficult
they like and they think that's more
efficient that's you know that's what
that's what they are and also a lot of
them they are they are telling you okay
don't ever use the mouse that's idiotic
okay use the mouse I use a mouse in
Emacs and the only purpose the only the
only the the only time the only function
I use mouse in Emacs is for school is
for scrolling buffer like right now okay
why why do I use the mouse for that
because that turns out for my you know
years of study research this is the most
efficient and this is the most
appropriate application of a mouse when
it comes to Emacs use use the master
squirrel okay now I'm not that that's
another topic because I can go into
details you I can talk about math
Scorpio acceleration in Emacs or outside
of Emacs in Mac Linux windows how they
you know do they have acceleration
that's another topic I can talk about
one hour about that I have I have
articles
my well said on that just such folks
sorry mass axillary acceleration or
Sally Emax Mouse okay you find the
articles anyway so I'm telling you those
Emacs phonetics okay they they think you
know that they are kind of the
mainstream in emacs community you know
they tell you to remove the score bar
they tell you to remove the patterns
that I agree okay the the you know you
have the bunch of buttons like copy
pasted at half then they also tell you
to remove Emacs menus okay that's all
idiotic okay they think that you know
they are if you ask them why they think
they're gonna tell you oh because this
is this is more efficient no it's not
okay
and also they tell you to never use the
mouse that's also wrong yeah use the
mouse casarse is use the mouse what do
you use the mouse for for school not for
like selecting or you know right click
you know not not that okay that's what
they think that's what they think when
they say don't use a mouse they think
you are going to you know use the mouse
to select you know like maybe turn off
the orders click okay they are thinking
they are turn
you know when they think you know don't
use the mouse they are thinking oh you
you know don't use you know they are
used yeah are they I think you use the
mouse to strike things like that like
that don't do that okay I use the mouse
and basically the only situation is
score the score the window and also
sometimes switch window because okay
that's that's detail okay I have Auto I
have Auto quick like right now I don't I
show this before I don't click like you
see my hand and my mouse my keyboard I
don't click like I move the cursor here
you know I switched window already so I
don't I don't quick okay I don't I don't
know I have auto click and if sometimes
in some situations you don't want Auto
quick
for example when you are in Google map
or Google Earth okay in that case I move
the mouse to the right right left corner
right bottom corner then the auto click
is now off now I have to click now I
have to click to switch you see quick so
Auto click is fantastic I have a lock on
that okay you know you can go read it
anyway so I was saying you know those
people they don't think they are not
think they don't think okay because just
like that just like people watch TV you
you stop thinking you don't know what
things mean anymore why are they like
that why are they suggesting don't use
the mouse and turn off the score bar or
turn off menu because that's the
mainstream you know that's mainstream in
the Emax community for banking thirty
years ago like every every nerd is
saying it you know they and they see it
every day on reddit on Hacker News
noticed they see it every day and they
just follow it they never you know they
never actually spent one hour to
actually research like you know from
scratch you know when should you use a
mouse what's them you know didn't it
never to anything of that they are
idiotic okay so every time I have
opinions like I post my opinions they
pen they panned me you know this being
happening since 20 years ago they're
gonna ban you that's and this is also
why they are forever in this coat you
know it's a coat you only see what you
know you only see these kind of opinions
it's forever you know ten years ago 20
years ago or 30 years ago
you live in this Emacs bubble every
other opinion is spanned you know they
shut it down this open source Linux
[ __ ] that's why this my I I hate
them that you know let's say I don't
hate the people you know this this
remember that not the people this is
just the their opinion the way they you
know the opinion okay not the people
because some of these people you know
some of some some of them there are some
bad guys okay
they don't like me because I criticize
you know I criticize Neelix Emax vicious
Tolman then they don't they know then
then it's like politics you do war you
know they then they every time they see
my name they say bad things they say oh
sorry never coded you know one line of
emag B's there are people like that on
Hacker News the this [ __ ] called
least his handle is list M okay which
stands for this machine on Hacker News
you can look up every time he sees my
name mention he'll say bad things now
it's kind of you know in the you know
past few years it's getting better
because because the social justice rise
so hacker news you cannot you know
criticize people because then people
will pan you you know it's so thick and
also because I started to do videos I
become more you know people see see my
actual face you know my I explain myself
you know so there's more understanding
but but he used to yeah like every time
he see my name he'll say you know he
said you know for example five six years
ago he said cuz hardly never coded one
line of Elise oh oh he does his
copy-paste other's code and he said that
you know and back then I was you know
seven years ago in 2012 2012 around
there there you know I was going to die
I don't have money I don't have money to
eat
you know hunger I suffer hunger I mean
not not just like literal hunger for
like you know I mean war for a year okay
I want to I'm hungry
I need to eat buy a banana a banana is
25 cents I don't have 25 cents and and
I'm hungry you know nothing it's not
like oh if you don't eat banana why
don't you go eat beef and at that time
so I you know that's a crisis and you
know I don't you know I'm kind of a nerd
so I sometimes you feel strange you look
at yourself you know you you know
apparently you know how did you get into
that situation I don't know okay some
sometimes these things happen that's
another topic but anyway back then so he
posted you know he posed you know he
just he tells people you know don't
don't don't donate you know it's good
that's aa you know he's gonna die that's
good thing that's something like they
are like a couple of people who says
that two or three they are you know
socket us so anyway so that's we talked
about lots of things so I think maybe
that's it for today so I you know I was
talking about the Emacs phonetics I'm
flaming their technical you know they
are code they're you know they're
they're mantras you know they they have
these things they want you anyway so how
long I have I been talking so let's see
okay soft like keys actually there's a
question here that's too late for today
I was going to talk about that so one
hour and 23 minutes okay two more
minutes I guess in the past few days
it's I'm doing like 90 minutes talk
so battle says I see you are using no
mouse aren't you in to track boss yes I
have Logitech MX MX ago and I like it
very much yes I tried that well my
friend has that right now I'm not on on
a trackball I used to like I used to
have to like one is trackball but
ideally I would like you know first of
all I need to buy it you know I don't
have much money so I'm much better now
but I don't know
I can't just such I cannot just go buy a
travel I would like like to so tribo is
pretty good but if I can only choose one
Maseo trackball i think that would be
Mouse because anyway that's that's
another topic the second I can talk for
a while now about that so let's talk
about that next time
those are people and that's not really
relate to you there's always a few
people criticize anything
okay so face face is subject in pretty
must be on YouTube huh what are you
saying Israel so by the way Israel also
runs a YouTube Israel runs a Emax
tutorial and sometimes live coding on
YouTube so check it out Israel Israel
has been one day a few months ago Israel
has been chatting with me on one of my
videos okay so I think that's it hey
John Lewis John Lewis haven't seen you
for a while great to see you
you don't read my funny comments where
Zach Fermi comments because you know
usually when I'm talking on video and
there's a lot of comments I
not you know I cannot focus on which is
which who said what and you know usually
I get confused you know so Israel says
you should plug my channel ok now I see
it new video on Python ok and using nice
theme ok
so let's check out what's israel's
ladies doing youtube now his channel has
a name it's called Emacs something ok
but I forgot what's or something so it's
just such for YouTube why I as a e-l
though ok
Israel doe of YouTube there it is oh I
need my auto click back ok so you see
auto click is it saves you click you
know it's actually much good but you but
the thing with auto quickly is that you
have to get get used to it because if
you just try it now you'll get
frustrated you have to actually spend
like a week to get used to it so here is
Israel's channel and Emacs is great ok
that's a name episode 43 PHP now I know
now Israel is a open source freeze of
all office of a plantation phonetic ok
we just we disagree on that so anyway
there it is Israel's YouTube channel so
so you know even you know even i don't
you know i don't agree with many of the
free software and open source but but
but but still mostly i'm open source and
free software guy because almost every
every software almost ok every software
I use is open source and I when I look
for a software I always look for open
source well partly because there's
nothing you can do right now because
right now you know Google and in
Microsoft they
or doing you know open sources becomes
the mainstream it's like you cannot
escape it like whenever you deviate from
mainstream doesn't matter what subject
what topic me max config or or even
which even if you are using Emacs or not
or go to mainstream such as Adam or I'm
you know any anything you know or even a
lifestyle like what how you gonna be
every time you deviate from mainstream
you are going to run into little can be
inconveniences here and there you know
that's just the the thing you know
there's nothing you can do every time
you deviate from mainstream for example
if you use class Emacs well if in your
company everyone is using using
Microsoft Visual Studio or whatever
Microsoft code Oh Adam you know those
are become popular you know then you are
the one man out you run into problems
you know to you Emacs is great yeah yeah
but then in you know if for example in
in in whatever you could you the the
agile you know the two guys coding
together it becomes a problem because
he's using he don't know Emacs you know
do you have little these problems then
you have to explain things or then
there's pressure for you to not use
Emacs because everyone else is using
Microsoft Visual Studio or you know it's
lime or whatever sublime now so I supply
slime is the Emacs this package anyway
so yeah and if you have a different
lifestyle like me don't watch TV you
don't have a TV for 20 years you're
gonna be hard you're gonna be a bit art
because oh that guy who is you know you
yeah so that so so in the same way now
open source you know this skype me is
kind of like the open source by the way
let me mention open source is the
mainstream no it's not like this freedom
niche group no open source is the
mainstream he sees it's once
by Microsoft love it you know the huge
you think you love Microsoft sponsored
by Google sponsored by Apple Apple you
know Apple computers Apple the these
these companies each has 1,000 patent
lawyers yeah open-source uh and what are
you gonna do what you gonna do you know
so anyway anyway so that's it for today
and what else let's see
and purl that is not a drink okay so I
think I answered or comments okay so I
think that's it for today it's 90
minutes I think yeah so that's it for
today thank you guys for coming
yeah bye guys
Farzin says Kathy Thank You Kathy for
coming by
great to see you Israel battles guys
fever
Jean Louis Pano's fuzzy
John Lewis use fever yeah oh yeah one
thing I want to mention is that Israel
introduced me many great open source
software for example if you want to do
video chat with your friend Israel
showed me several you know like one or
two great posit okay Israel posted like
you have you have 10 seconds to post the
link you know the the like you know
follow Israel okay oh as as Israel so he
showed me several great open-source
software that does you know video chat
or or or text chat I forgot the name
actually you know I want to use them but
I got so about I got many other things
so I you know side that's why I didn't
so anyway my guys