good morning guys
welcome to another episode of Santa's
show today's 2019 December 10th known 20
minutes afternoon and today is Tuesday
and this is San Francisco time so hi
guys hi Alan
so today we're going to talk about
Japanese input systems Japanese language
Japanese writing system Japanese input
system and Japanese keyboard layouts
they are quite a variety of Japanese
input systems in in keyboard layout
because for example in English language
we have loraq
we have Commack we have gorac all these
different keyboard layouts and for
Japanese language it is similar in fact
that because Japanese language is more
complex so you actually have more input
different input methods systems in the
arm
konnichiwa we've stream good morning
Island so let's drink to ban the ban
energy drink so we have okay three
people watching you know not many people
today so let's four people okay so let's
shall we begin talking about well Adhan
already know Japanese system because
Alan is using you know Jai Helen has
learned Japanese so he so type some
Japanese force Alan theis types and
Japanese in the chat so ok so anyway so
I'm thinking let's talk about I guess I
I should just go and start on the
tutorial about Japanese systems yeah ok
so let me just do a monologue on the
Japanese system for a while and
Aaron has some suggestions of topics
number on keyboards and number of pads
okay
well they are several okay some some of
them I don't know much like those some
of them are general questions like I
don't know where to begin like I need to
I can s you have a question or something
like well you what we were talking with
Nabi right and an SV he said something
specific so anyway so I studied Japanese
input systems I don't I don't know
Japanese I have not learned Japanese but
I have studied their writing systems and
also remember writing systems in the
speech the language is entirely totally
almost like hundred percent separate
things
so writing system is one thing the
language the speech is on another thing
entirely different because if you look
at around the world the writing systems
you know there are a few major writing
systems for example you have Latin
alphabet and or European variations like
Spanish French Italian then you have
Russian alphabet
it's basically still the same thing but
they changed the shape of the Russian
alphabets so actually let's go into okay
so let's just start to talk about random
stuff I mean on the you know on the
Japanese input system so let's go to I'm
going to say I was talking about layout
so layout you can see different
languages you have English then you have
German French Russian okay and
Portuguese or Spanish so German pretty
much the same Latin alphabet in first
you have several a few special
characters such as those omelettes you
or a so there you have the Russian
keyboard and so on
and in French similar okay and in
Russian okay so for Russian is still
basically just the same alphabets yeah
you know a bunch of letters man but you
have different shape and here is Russian
layout heat map basically all the words
layout are very inefficient and so you
know so the food so this is what this is
Portuguese okay so this one is this one
is a empty knob Nativa layout
it is a efficient layout designed for
Portuguese you know just like Warrick
for English so anyway so these languages
they have above they have the writing
system basically Latin alphabet based
and then you have Chinese characters so
let's close close close okay let's go to
Chinese let's see where I can find it
okay so Japanese Japanese and Chinese
okay so Chinese you know you have of
course you have the Chinese characters
and you you have so here on this Alka we
are talking about Chinese input system
anyway it's Chinese simple system that's
another complicated thing so what I'm
trying to say right now I'm trying to
focus is that different languages the
writing system and the speech are
entirely different it's it's almost like
a 100% separate thing so what I'm trying
to say is that in many languages you
know a writing system usually a specific
writing system is used in many languages
for example the Latin alphabet is used
in French German English Italian Spanish
Portuguese and so on the Chinese writing
system is used in Chinese Korean
Japanese and used to be used in
Vietnamese as well even though you see
even though this language is Chinese
Riaan Japanese and the Vietnamese they
share almost nothing they are entirely
different languages however you know
they all borrowed the Chinese characters
as part of the writing system and in
Arabic Arabic countries you know the
Arabic alphabet so the Arabic alphabet
let me show you okay the Arabic alphabet
so you go to my Unicode you know you
search for Saudi Unicode you can see I
have so you have Latin so let's go to
actually let's go to Unicode sorry
Unicode okay so here we are here we are
talking about writing systems of the
world so first of all let's look at
Latin okay then then we gonna start to
talk about the Japanese info system okay
we already digressed so much because on
this topic alone it's gonna be happen
anyway so here is the Latin alphabet
writing system so you have have all
these characters then you have Greek
okay yeah Greek now the Latin alphabet
came from Greek okay so here you have
Greek different characters different
shape then you have Cyrillic which is
basically Russian and Eastern European
see we like alphabet okay you know
Cyrillic alphabet is a whole bunch and
just like Latin so but for Russian they
have you know they have a subset of them
so this is Russian alphabet
this is Belarusian alphabet but a ruse
see enough Abed then Ukrainian you know
they have a subset of you know all the
critic alphabet just like Latin
just like Latin and variations you have
all these things but in
I only have you know the you only have
these 26 of them so so you can see we
have all these different alphabets net
then we are talking about Chinese now
Chinese you have tens of thousands
characters literally and they they are
not alphabets so each character means
something and basically for a in
practice you need to know about 3,000
characters you have to learn them by
rote basically there's no other way so
every Chinese you learn in school in
Middle School in high school you learn
these characters you and you learn how
to read them how to write them and you
need to know about 3,000 of them to
parity okay barely understand newspapers
you need 4000 or 5 - yeah actually I
would say college-educated
Chinese people in China or Taiwan they
will they would know five five or six
thousand characters so here is a snippet
of you know example of Chinese writing
system well the characters Chinese
writing system is basically just these
characters then you have okay so Chinese
writing system then we have Japanese
writing system now Japanese writing
system is one of the most complicated so
anyway my point here so let me talk a
little bit that's I'm gonna talk about
the Japanese writing system in a little
bit okay later then we are going to
because we need to know this before we
can talk about the Japanese keyboard
input system and layout you need to know
the you know Japanese writing system
first but we're gonna talk about that a
bit later so you have Japanese then you
have Korean Korean is very interesting
Korean is you see these square squarish
characters they are actually alphabets
they are alphabets invented about 300
years ago was a 300 or 400 years ago
it's pretty new so but this alphabet
differs from the English one where you
just have characters you place them to
the right of it
instead you have these shapes and you
compose them to form a character so
these are actually alphabet but act
I don't know Korean okay I only studied
a little bit about the writing system so
I don't know Korean but anyway so Korean
system the Korean writing system is
actually pretty elegant that's you know
that's what people say that's what I
when you study these kind of things you
you will hear that it's pretty let's say
scientific and Korean used to also use
Chinese characters okay not so much
today but let's say a hundred years ago
Korean writing just like Japanese like
half of them will be Chinese characters
they don't do that much these days so
and so so we have Korean alphabet so
let's go to Arabic yeah so so back to my
point so here is a Rebeck alphabet a
riebeck alphabet is used in several
languages very different languages in a
Middle East region so it's using posts
Persian it's used in Arabic languages
they are - there are different languages
okay but I don't know how much they
relate to each other but anyway they use
the same writing system which is the
Arabic alphabet like that so when you if
you don't know the language you look at
them youth you know they look the same
yeah so that's aerobic and you have some
others so you have Indian stuff Indian
has lots of languages you know India has
like almost like a thousand languages
local regional languages but they are
like ten five or ten major ones
anyway I don't know Indian Indian stuff
much so so this alphabet is called
Devanagari and this is used in by the
language Hindi Hindi and few others okay
so if you read Wikipedia it will tell
you several details so it's used in it's
using several languages like Hindi so
among the language using is using it is
Hindi Sanskrit pati a what he but Jo for
e you know civil like ten other things
other languages use this Indian Devan
agari
script so my point here you see my point
here back to the point is that the human
languages and the writing system are
almost totally separate things so and in
fact many writing systems are used in
diverse many different totally different
languages that that is the point I want
to mention and also a practical tip okay
if you guys are learning if you if you
guys are learning a foreign language
like let's say Russian or Japanese or
Korean or Spanish okay you want to make
you want to make sure there is the
writing and reading skill and also the
speaking and listening skill they are
entirely different
okay I talked about this in previous
videos before like maybe half a year ago
so because the writing system are almost
totally different from the natural
language so so the reading and writing
skills are entirely different from the
listening and speaking skills now most
of us are nerds okay like most of us so
when we study a new language we tend to
tend to read you know the grammar the
vocabulary so we can read well but we
can't we cannot speak well and we cannot
we don't listen we don't understand well
on the other hand there are some other
people who are not nerds you know who
are extroverts you know they go out they
socialize they talk to people when they
learn a new language they almost you
know they they ignore the raging grandma
you know that's too complicated or
linguistic so complicated for them
rather they just talk to people so so so
my point here is that you know the
reading and writing skill is entirely
different from the listening and
speaking skill and in fact in general
the listening skill and in listening and
speaking skills more practical and more
important so you can just go to Spain
and speak to Spanish to people you go to
Mexico or you go to Russia you can just
talk everyone talks but the but the
writing when it comes writing and
reading that's kind of becomes more
complicated then you get into
linguistics literature grammar then you
got grammar nazis you know you know then
you got pedants you know they tell you
oh you spelled it wrong
programa should be to em that's inerts
okay so remember practical tip if you
are learning a foreign language
remember that reading and writing is
totally different from listening and
speaking skills so depends on where
actually you want to go so if you want
to be able to talk to people you want to
focus on the listening and speaking
skills okay as to as as far as how to do
that well I am I I don't I'm not gonna
talk about that but basically you just
listen like one of the easy way to learn
a language you just watch movies for
example you want to learn Chinese you
watch Chinese movies okay and don't
don't never ever show the subtitle okay
never ever show the subtitle title in
English like typically for example when
I was learning English you know I was
born in Taiwan I speak Chinese I don't
speak English until I started to learn
English at the aah
age of 14 okay so when I was learning
English or when I watch English movies I
want the subtitle subtitles you know in
English so I can you know I actually
literally go through every word look up
dictionary I don't understand
you know then read it down I do that all
the time every day I literally open
dictionary literally like two hundred
three hundred times a day for like over
ten years that that's when I was 14 -
you know - my 30s so I do that so it's
because I'm not you know IIIi I think
I'm going to learn English well but I
did not know it at the time this is like
almost 30 years ago at the time I did
not know that that writing and reading
skill are entirely different from
listening and speaking
so my skill in underneath understanding
people understanding TV or movies is is
pretty bad okay it's really bad I know
people speak I don't understand okay
and I am I speak they don't understand
because I have heavy accent you know at
this now I'm doing much better but it is
you know 30 years ago 40 years ago so so
remember they are totally different
because I was I was a nerd you know so I
focus on you know I thought I'm gonna
learn all the words in English so I did
pretty well out there and I can read
wearing and I can write I can I can I
know what's you know back then I know
what's a normal English native speaker
would not know because you know but but
however I am able to you know the
listening and the speaking skill is
pretty bad so that is a thing I want to
mention you know so when you learn a
language be sure there are two separate
things you can focus on one or the other
they are almost it's almost like they
are not related you know because because
you look back at the world's languages
and they're writing systems in many
many languages they don't have a rating
system that is many you know that they
are more there I think thousands at
least a thousand languages they don't
have a rating system they cannot you
cannot read it down they don't they just
never developed because the heat you
know if we look back at history we human
animals we just gesture and make sounds
just like dogs and woof
you know dogs lions you know they make
sound birds you don't you don't write
things down until much later okay so so
remember that okay so so so okay so now
I think I'm gonna read some comments and
let's look at the then we're gonna talk
about [ __ ] Japanese Japanese writing
system and the Japanese input methods
and Japanese keyboard layouts so I've
been talking for 20 minutes that's good
okay so Alan says it's Oh Alan good
morning Kathy so I have a 6-figure today
what they come on in
Daniel Anglo is what day is today no not
Tuesday Tuesday should have a lot of
people you know Tuesday in general is
the busiest day well not not the pcs but
but Tuesday Wednesday Thursday tends to
be the busiest on the web so Alan says
wait let me check gee you didn't learn
English until you moved to Canada yeah
more or less well and here I so when I
was 14 I left I won and that is that is
1982 I moved to Brazil
- not Brazil but put but para Y okay
let's go to Google Maps so I stayed in
Paraguay Paraguay for one year then we
went to Central America so I learned
Spanish you know I was also studios you
know studious about Spanish but me why
I'm also learning English so I started
to learn English when I was
14 and also learning Spanish so let's
look at the map so another day of map
talking map coke cocking so here is wait
okay I need to turn off the auto click
so here is South America so here is para
Y and we stayed in astringent here okay
so that city that is the capital I think
also so I stayed there for one year then
we went to Central America Guatemala
Guatemala and in the Venezuela El
Salvador here we stayed we stayed in
mostly in Guatemala for half a year then
I went to Canada so I by 1985 I'm in
Canada so I was like 15 also 16 and so
so that's that that's running in the
hardest way yeah so let's see what other
questions so maybe we should just give
up talking on people face to face always
use smartphones to communicate with
people's around us
keep up on talking to people face to
face one counterpoint to the separation
between writing and speech here are lots
of idioms words act that are motivated
by writing oh really
what are some examples like from novels
oh yeah that well that makes sense
yes yes I can see that for example I can
I can you know for example goody
two-shoes okay there's an English idiom
goody two-shoes or good deed to shoes
now many years ago I was you know I was
reading you know then I came across this
word goody two-shoes I don't know what
it means so I look up and the definition
of course I learned the definition is
says by the way I never used
merriam-webster dictionary okay
merriam-webster the online version and
also the the dictionary they sell the
abridged version they are - they are
shipped ok because I I am an expert of
dictionaries actually I need to show you
my articles now like five or six
articles about details of different
dictionaries but anyway they're good
goody-two-shoes okay if you search for
Kasauli dictionary review you'll find my
articles it's written like fifteen years
ago
anyway goody-two-shoes so it means it
means a detective
okay user as a modifier before now so
what it is mean okay of or having
prudish self-righteous and all rigid
rigidly moral standards goody two-shoes
oh that's not what I thought it means he
says an exceedingly and or haughty
prudish self-righteous or rigidly moral
person someone who conforms inflexibly
to the rules of the law oh that's not
what I thought it was okay I was wrong
then okay because I thought it means
someone who always tries to be helpful
you know like always try to be kind and
helpful to I to the extreme but okay I
remember that wrong but anyway I so
there's a idiom so then eventually a few
years ago I looked up on Wikipedia so
apparently that word goody two-shoes is
a character in a novel in children's
story
this one the history of little goody
two-shoes is a children's story
published by John Newbery Newbury in
London in 1765 ok the story popular
popularized the phrase goody two-shoes
as a descriptor for an excessively
virtuous person or to good good yeah
that's what I thought he means but
however the the definition here which i
think is from Americans Heritage
Dictionary ok so it's from what
dictionary so anyway the dictionary
given here is contrary to the it's a
slightly different from the the arrangin
the history of little goody two-shoes
because in the in a novel it's about a
person who is excessively what virtuous
person or too good but the definition
given here is about someone is ha T ha T
V prudish and self-righteous and rigidly
moral so anyways as that's interesting
so have you guys know heard of this face
anyway so I think that's an example
where ideas came from writing so
actually I uh there's a lot comments I
kind of we've been going over attention
for alone so let me see that comments
she was Japanese police Japanese is
police sweep symbolic like European
languages ok opinions on top-down
language planning should return language
be controlled standardized top-down
language funny oh yeah so that so Alan
is saying about you know some languages
they try to the government try to try to
force or try to have a strict standard
as far as I know French is example
of such a language the government or the
other people they don't want the
language to change in uncontrollable
ways so for example French as far as I
know French is an example so they are
pretty strict they want people you know
they have strict grammar the way how it
should be said how it should be written
how you know things like that on the
other hand English I think is the
opposite extreme where anything goes you
know there is no standard body to
tightly control tell you what it should
be well yeah yeah they are pedantic
forensics people in crime areas but in
general English language just it's like
free-flowing you know you borrow words
from Japan for example we have we bought
we boat today we have lots of Japanese
dragons we bow and you borrow phrases
from French from you know just let it go
and I think most languages is like that
they just you know whatever happens
happens so you know I remember one day I
was reading the etymology of okay so
that's an interesting story okay so okay
it turns out I don't remember the
details but okay I think it came from I
mean it you see like why what what does
okay mean I mean this it's not a
abbreviation to some foods you know
you're just okay okay K is ka Y so one
day I was looking you know what Y where
they came from so it turns out I don't
remember now but I think people I mean
we don't know for sure but we have
several theories I think okay so here
for example they say proposed
etymologies so he says many explanations
for the origin of the expression have
been suggested but few have been
discussed seriously by linguists the
following proposals have found
mainstream
recognition so you know it means we
don't actually know where okay came from
the world okay okay not the hand symbol
the hand symbol is a different thing but
I don't know how that came to be neither
so so they have several theories about
we're okay came from so you know so you
can you can go read it so it's
interesting so so so I'm saying English
is an example of a language it just go
wherever it wants to go so do I have a
pinyin about whether it should be
controlled tightly controlled or free
flow mmm I don't know I don't have a
strong opinion on either I guess it
depends on what if you have a goal or
not for example if you for example we
have the logical language low swung okay
so we have okay so I should Emily good
morning Emily great to see you
so we have the okay Inc Emily's expert
of Lois Wong
well actually I know Emily is learning
it I'm not sure she's expert yet anyway
Lorsch mom is a artificial language it's
a constructed language it's designed
based on logic so it's supposed to be
extremely precise and logical now when I
studied art was wrong you know a long
time ago
2003 so because it's logical I thought
this is gonna be great but then one day
I realized I realized something critical
okay
so Lois bong loss bong once you learn
the language
once you become extremely familiar with
it you know fluent then suppose you have
a group or you know community let's say
1000 people speaks let's say more than
you know $100,000 or some small town who
speaks low strong all the your children
speaks rose one when they were
okay so it's suppose that so meaning
that lotion became popular then I think
something will happen okay this is what
will happen when this this is a very
precise logical language but however
when you become very popular you know
human animals we are not we are not like
machines
we are not CPUs we are not logical
machines so we will make arbitrary
nonsensical expression out of the blue
anytime all the time in fact all the
time we will just make you know like
like there is a word inside joke inside
inside joke like we we share many inside
jokes with between us nobody else
understand you just come up happen you
know because so so when we when we
humans when you when you are using los
bomb okay it is my guess okay that the
lowest one the logical structure and
grammar they all kind of they will they
will they will rot rot okay they will
rot away because the force of
spontaneous expression that is illogical
is so strong I mean in spite of humanity
we just we will just say something and
make funny and and people will accept
you know you just spread so so
eventually let's say one after one
hundred years after a few generations I
think you know large one if you don't
tightly control it then it's gonna be
become it's going to lose its property
of being you know the original property
of being logical and precise and
supposedly help you think okay so that
so I thought about that and and I I have
written an article somewhere I don't
know if it's online on my website or not
but this is like 10-15 years ago I think
I post it to the lowest amount group and
they of course they don't like me you
know because in my usual manner of not
being conformity conformity come from
come not being a conformist so anyway so
so there so you have this issue when
when you let the language just freely
flow it it will change its nature the
pronunciation will change over the over
generations the spelling will change
over the you know it's just going to
change so about whether you should we
should control the language or not I
don't know I guess it depends so for
language like Louis well I think you you
know if you wanted to maintain its
precision properties you have to you
have to control it and controlling it is
a problem actually so you see you know
these are not computer languages you
know these are languages used by human
or supposedly those fungi you can't like
even even French you can't really like
control it you know because people just
want to say things the way didn't OD
nobody sticks to Grandma all the time in
fact most of the time people don't stick
to gamma so about the controlling the
language that's that's almost a natural
and almost an impossible thing to do so
I don't know what what's the situation
with French so anyway that's about this
that's my thought about that so let's
see what for example we talked about
ABCs of such-and-such so let's see
comments so many my [ __ ] my I have a
neighbor who who has a motorcycle and he
likes to make noises all the time it's
very loud Frankie calves ship early to
find the true touch typists ok so what
you guys talking about so what should we
do now should we go back to the Japanese
input system so let's see Alan kuchiki's
so let's see ok let me read the comments
quickly ok ok actually I need to close
my window the lunar cycle is too loud
yeah the guy is [ __ ] annoying I don't
want to close it because he is there you
know I don't want to make a rude gesture
this guy you know guy mail you know they
like to ride motorcycles and make the
the motorcycles make huge noise so
actually so let me read the comments
quickly okay let's see let's go back to
here so Alan says and says Fugees so if
you rue the word if you route the word
or some corner of it what would do to
standardized language measurement okay
okay he's gone the [ __ ] Hamdi okay
Fuji keys argh ricado japanese i'll
ricardo maybe okay i don't know what
that means
alan say it's never thought of that so
what does that mean you are from Brazil
Portugal okay oh nice Latin has accents
okay English is 60%
orthography under sized keyboard without
enough buttons okay
so Allen says simplified charts biggest
orthographic waste of time oh okay so
the issue about simplified characters
versus traditional characters Chinese
characters that's another big topic and
of course I have articles on that I have
actually more than one quite a few
articles on that but should we go there
because we already have quite a lot of
things quite a lot of topics to go over
okay let's show let's showcase my
my looking into my obsession towards
these kind of things sorry
simplified charts okay I'm just gonna go
over them quickly
okay do these odd oh these are okay so
these are programming related that's not
what we want
Great Firewall Chinese net censorship
whatever so you need to go to the
simplified chance versus traditional
okay these B's okay there it is okay
there is my one of my articles so this
this page is a complete list of
simplified characters and alongside
their traditional version so on the left
with the black background
those are simplified characters on the
right is traditional characters okay so
on this issue there's a lot to say about
it so I you know starting to talk about
this I'm gonna talk about one hour then
I have other several other language
articles related to that then related to
pinging the Chinese normalization
systems or Chinese phonetics systems
they are several of them and I looked
into so let me just give you give the
people generally on over the overview
what what it is okay because most people
probably don't know so Chinese we write
Chinese in these characters right so but
around 1919 forty 1930 the Chinese
government actually the government from
Taiwan you know you guys almost more
most people don't know even Chinese
people don't know these okay I know I
know the details okay let me try to
explain the first
so anyways so first of all I mean tried
the general what what it is okay for
English people so Chinese characters
you know we write these characters but
in 1930s okay the Chinese government you
know originally it was the Taiwan
government you know the government now
who who are in on Taiwan where I grew up
but later on around 1950 it's pushed by
the China the Chinese Chinese Communist
okay anyway so so they want they want a
to start a movement to simplify the
characters because back then remember
this is 1920's 1930's you know we the
technology started started to grow we
start to have World War World War two is
coming and there's a lot of technology
going up and the you know you begin to
have airplanes you know travel travel
around world travel to Japan to Europe
you know this international
communication you started to realize you
know then well anyway Chinese people at
a time you know the the academia the
they think they we need to simplify the
characters because if you don't you're
gonna die okay because the characters
they they take tremendous time to learn
so in fact at the time they want to
entirely eliminate Chinese characters
they are they are planning to move into
a alphabetic system using English you
know the Latin of it so anyway so so
there's this movement you know it's it's
huge movement Allah among that there's
also simplification of the writing style
like using a modern style of writing
reform you know you call that reform so
anyway one of the reform is the
character simplification so they the
China you know after the war that the
Taiwan government escaped to Taiwan but
the Chinese government they started to
push this simplification because the
thought is that you need
it's kind of necessary because if you
don't your people you know the the
citizens they're gonna it takes
tremendous time to learn all these
characters too many strokes you cannot
write remember back then you don't have
computers yet so you write a Chinese
character each some of these has like 20
strokes 30 strokes so that's it that is
why you want to simplify them okay so
you so that is a movement that's the
reason why you they they sit together
you know some some people you know some
of these academics they design you know
they try to create a simplified version
of the other characters then so that's
the whole engine okay that's our engine
of the simplified characters and it is
espoused by Chinese government pretty
much you know since 1950s the reason
they push for it relates to lots of
other things
they also push nuclear bomb okay so
China since 1960 or something people are
very poor but but they have nuclear
power they they have nuclear bomb okay
so so that is why there is a significant
reason China is still you know big over
there because otherwise you're gonna
have you're gonna have us a coming over
to palm you out because you violate you
know you are a threat to the world enter
USA is gonna a nuclear bomb you
so anyway China among many different
reasons
China pushed for the simplification of
the characters meanwhile Taiwan the
Tehran government is packed by USA
basically it's it's a puppy okay kind of
put because the the the weapons the all
the things came you know much of it okay
not all but much of it is basically USA
and also Taiwan culture to this day
today is is is a follower of USA
whatever USA have they have in in Taiwan
right away like today for example in USA
politics we have trans we have you know
feminism we have you know gay gay rights
you know gay right marriage is it's all
entire
right now it's you know Taiwan follow
closely with USA USA puts money and and
all that because why because USA don't
want China to become powerful just like
the Russia Cold War USA don't want
Russia to be powerful so USA need
stations and troops you know to form
into you know to around China and Russia
so USA befriend befriended Japan and
South Korea and Taiwan so you know
that's that's good for us
USA Americans so yeah anyway that's a
big history a political history but
China they they you know they push for
simplification but Taiwan for phone for
four reasons okay for reasons they they
they do not they want to keep the
so-called traditional characters for no
good reasons okay what what is the
primary you know when this is a very
controversial issue you know in
especially in Taiwan you know very
controversial
you all have debates you have debate on
TV you have debate among professors you
know academics there debate endless okay
but the but if you ask me I can tell you
why okay I can tell you what is the
reason that Taiwan government kind of do
not want simplified the basically the
only reason is that's China you know
that that's our enemy they are doing
that we don't want we don't we don't
want whatever they are doing that is the
most important reason Taiwan sticks with
the traditional characters okay then we
can go on to talk about the or ancient
like how are these characters designed
you know what you know for example some
of these simplified characters they are
ancient they are used you know one
thousand two thousand years ago some of
them so anyway the the technique of
debate about which is better or not is
it's it's you know yeah that's a big big
question and okay so I
I guess I kind of went off on this too
long how long have I been talking okay
I'm still all night people watching so
no no comments okay so I guess I'm
getting boring
so okay anyway that's about Chinese
simplified characters what else okay so
this some of the these are some of the
the most frequently used Chinese
characters okay so these 500 are the
most used frequently used Chinese
characters so anyway let me go back to
the okay so this one I need to mention
this you know I studied the issue about
character simplification and so if you
ask me whether it's good or bad I don't
have a you know one one easy answer okay
it's not like oh yeah you should
simplify oh no it should be traditional
I don't this but if you ask my opinion
which ripe which I support I would
support the simplification okay I
support a simplification simplification
not much because it is actually in some
sense technique of superior that's not
why but rather I support it because it's
already there
okay you you can't just reverse history
it's already there and widely used you
know it you cannot just revert let's go
back and reverse history you know so and
also I don't like the Taiwan government
you know they the you know they are not
for for that or this or that for any
technical reasons they are you know the
argument mostly came from political
reasons like you you are communist I am
NOT communist therefore we fight we
fight over which one is better but all
the reasons are garbage okay so anyway
so I don't have a very strong opinion
about which one is technically superior
but however I do have a pinion on which
one I support
I support the simplified characters and
I also use simplified characters okay so
but anyway when studying this right you
know the the characters you have a
chemical you know many of these
characters I have my own notes so this
page is my own notes
I tell you which character they are
simple of a simplification is good and
which one is very bad so anyway I
started to write this there are only
like 20 of them but you know this
article is just beginning of it I didn't
continue because there's because when
you study this if you actually start to
study this it's gonna suck your ears
years out of your life you know you're
gonna end end it's gonna be endless
because when you talk about Chinese
characters Chinese writing system this
is like two thousand three thousand
history is you know it's a deep black
hole to dive into more so than English
history you more so when you let's say
you go in to study Old English and so on
it's a deep it's a deep black hole to
dive into and also because when you
study these kind of things it's like in
practical it's gonna be useless so I can
study this for the four five years and I
will you know it's gonna be useless
basically unless I become a professor
focusing on that and even so you the
chances of you being hired is slim you
know because this history you know when
you study history art or the linguistics
history of linguistics is kind of dead
impractical thing to do so anyway here
on this page is some kind of a history
of Chinese Chinese characters okay so so
we have this ten thousand pc oracle
bones so this is three thousand years
ago this is a arrangin of chinese
characters and then you have this
cauldron this is you know metal brown's
vessel it's in
782 BC so it's 2700 years ago and very
very interesting very interesting be I
can still read it that's one of
incredible thing about actually I cannot
read it and not this one but anyway you
have this one okay so this one this one
is from what howard is this one this one
is 209 BC so it's two thousand and two
hundred years ago and you can I can kind
of read it so anyway yeah no no I cannot
read it okay most people cannot read
this but however the point I want to say
okay here this one this one is from 616
PC so also 2000 years ago and I can read
it completely like every character I
know every character and I know what
they means I can read the whole thing
this is 2000 years old you know I wanted
to show some of the old like Browns
carved into this stone kind of thing but
anyway my point here is that I find it
amazing because many because when you
study Chinese language you can read you
know that's like like literally books
written 2000 years ago basically every
Chinese can read it can see you know you
can you can actually see what people are
saying what they are talking about 2,000
years ago I nobody in English you cannot
you know you know well because you know
I know English but I I opened you know
oh the English that's you know 500 500
years old I cannot understand it so I
think I find that quite interesting okay
I think I talked random for too long so
maybe I don't know what where am I going
with this so I talked about Chinese too
much
[Laughter]
so any questions so Aaron says my grass
is prescription got stronger after I
learned how to read a few thousand carry
Chinese horses also you have so you
learned a few thousand Chinese
characters Alan let's see one of the
goody two-shoes complaining about noise
pollution and okay so what are the
comments addressed to me so any comments
questions I don't think we're gonna get
into Japanese input systems because it's
already one hour so let's see one
counterpoint to the separation between
writing okay so for example abc's of
such as such terms of abbreviations we
use all the time
PC personal computer / HD / EG quick
correct yes not speech makes more
references to writing things okay
so Erin says we should give up talking
to people face to face and always use
smartphones to communicate with the
people around us subtitle through the
video I just try to add subtitles to the
video what video but we can do live
English English has lots of accents just
in England okay
in America we speak American so Kathy
says gee you didn't know English yes so
Alan says people still have funny
accents English people still have funny
accents but I don't want to understand
people only anime okay hey hey na b h HK
japan was different than h HK english
what h HK happy happy hacking keyboard
okay European dictionaries have synonyms
in antonyms unlike American well
American also have it I mean it depends
on what you which dictionary so for
example let's go to my dictionary okay
sorry dictionary review so I just want
to show you my my rent on the various
dictionaries I'm very obsessed about
dictionaries because I read them I thumb
through them few hundred times a day
literally you know one time two times
you know three hundred times a day for
every day for like over ten years twenty
years so and I have used several
dictionaries you know I actually
memorized I memorized the way they
define words especially merriam-webster
you know like I you give a word I can I
can again I can tell you how the
dictionary says is a definition in the
same style as merriam-webster anyway the
thing about merriam-webster dictionary
is that you know Merriam Webster Webster
for some reason they they market a lot
so every wherever you go when you are in
college use the merriam-webster
dictionary when you are young online the
memory and Webster dictionary will will
show up on top okay for some reason they
do marketing a lot they are successful
on the other hand my favorite dictionary
American huge heritage dictionary you
almost don't see it okay you don't see
it you have to go to a bookstore to
specifically look for it but anyway but
and by anyway the the problem the the
the merriam-webster dictionary is
actually pretty good it except except
the ones you encounter such as online
the merriam-webster website and the ones
you buy in call
stores you know they have you know the
hard copy they are actually collegiate
version so caliche at virtual meaning or
breached
so in these versions it's crap okay it's
it's it's worse it's one of the worst
you you can pay the same same amount of
money and get a different dictionary
that's that's not a pretty [ __ ] okay so
the my problem with the merriam-webster
dictionary is not because the
merriam-webster you know they have like
they have full versions but you don't
you you rarely see it you have to go to
library like then then you see you know
very big thick that's a real real
merriam-webster dictionary okay but what
you see often it's a preached collegiate
version if you carefully to read the
full title of the dictionary they will
they will say collegiate or a breached
okay and and these this I'm referring to
this are very bad very bad
okay so in a sense in a sense that if
you are learning I mean if you are
beginner you know you're gonna be a poet
for it or you're gonna be a writer you
don't want you don't you you want a good
dictionary okay you want a solid thick
heavy one you don't want those
collegiate so-called collegiate meaning
for college college students so Emily
says what's your favorite word that you
won't come across what [ __ ] no that's no
what's my favorite word that's
interesting I have to think about that I
can't I don't I don't have like cannot
come across like you you have a favorite
word Emily so Danielle say streaming
Carla decided to abandon official
diplomatic relations with Taipei in
order to recognize Beijing yes indeed
that's because because China Beijing
they they they detonated a nuclear bomb
you know ten years ago before that
so us saw that of course you know it's
it's broadcasted you know so USC started
to make friends with China and today
it's like China everything every day on
the news
Trump China China China China and is
this that that that splendiferous
splendor for us now that's not that's
not actually a word right now be let's
see splendor for us
Oh
splinter for us so what do you say let's
see spend differ us okay so you see is
you see this one is from American
Heritage Dictionary that's my that's my
favorite dictionary so you see
merriam-webster comes up on top they are
[ __ ] you know let's do an example let me
show you why they are [ __ ] okay so let's
open merriam-webster a breach and let's
open the this dictionary calm and also
this free dictionary
they are typically like ten years ago
they they were American heritage so you
know look at this [ __ ] this
merriam-webster it says extraordin
extraordinary or show really impressive
okay okay okay not Navi okay so he says
spend spend differs okay so if it means
extraordinarily or show IDI impressive
okay I learned a new word so now let's
look at the I think this is American
heritage okay splendid Magnus of a
magnificent and fine okay and let's look
at the the free dictionary okay just say
splendid informal okay so okay I don't
have a rant on this one
okay so this this one where it came from
according to English English dictionary
okay then it says facetious grand
facetious grand splendid it's magnified
okay I like that definition so splendid
and splendid is fine but okay so this in
this case the merriam-webster in my
opinion is doing good okay
faux faux okay I forgot what that means
cuff oval so I think maybe that's it for
today so we've been talking for one hour
right you know one of five minutes
that's it so any final say-so let's see
what are we looking for kerfuffle to do
offers this orderly outburst or two mode
okay kerfuffle yeah kvitko Feifei let's
see let's see if the dictionaries show
that word now I think possibly Oxford
Dictionary will show that okay so yeah
so the merriam-webster they this this
word is only one years old we all have
to see you know maybe you will not I
don't my guess is that is that you will
not show up in Oxford Dictionary because
unless because it's not popular enough
oh look at Wikipedia look at look at
this come Wikipedia they are going to
they are going to have an entry and look
donate don't do not donate okay I talked
about this in my last video or two days
ago do not donate to Wikipedia okay let
them die in fact the time today is that
you've Wikipedia dies possibly we are we
will have
information because the the time has
changed you know technology is changing
all the time so Wikipedia came at the
right time during 2003 by this Jimbo
Wales not not a very good person and now
all this money millions just goes to his
pocket in my opinion okay I don't know
for sure but this is my opinion so do
not donate to Wikipedia and if we keep
Vidya shut down today possibly we will
have an alternative you know a switch
even possibly better tomorrow it will
spring up right away that is what I
believe
so anyway Wikipedia has a lolicon
khofifah okay so whatever ok that's it
for today thank you guys for watching I
Freddie Freeman I'm hey good morning
Freddie
we I'm just I'm shutting down so Emily
Emily show us one of you ok
everyone of you show type type your
favorite word okay just type a word type
your favorite word so Daniel asks what
do Taiwanese think of simplified Chinese
they don't like it in general the yeah
so you know it's a political issue
contrary H Lord Sonics to say for China
things to tick off the neoliberal
technocrat
the only good reason to have Wikipedia
is to get some info on population of
various cities some info on population
of various cities what do you mean
good morning part what you are you are
so late
English has lots of great phrases mental
masturbation ok that's your message is
helpful review ok I'm good bye bye guys
have a good day