good morning welcome to another episode
of sod talk show you seen whenever the
it's around five o'clock in my abode
well in my apartment this this window on
this light shines on my face like a lie
sometimes I don't even notice so let me
start today we're gonna talk about
JavaScript and I'm going to explain
javascript object system with the most
clarity you'll ever hear you are here a
representation of describing the
JavaScript system the computer language
in general computer language in a way
that's what I would call a mathematical
style and you rarely see them anywhere
okay so let's put the date so while I
wait for people to come in and let's see
what so this is Mike's a talk show page
and you can see it's a talk show 17 I
mean April copy-pasted and others ok
javascript object system and others let
me put the title here copy/paste so we
got one guy watching hi hi say hi in the
chat window and so we're gonna talk
about JavaScript object system but
before we do that let's do some
excursion excursion into lemme start
start start command lot man you see this
is a this will show my Emacs command
however you see when I call this command
I want to remove the this panel so
there's one more step that's not in my
command so let's fix that I'm going to
show you this email
command saw start command log mod hoping
that so here's the code and we're just
going to add a command called delete
window okay add it here tap and that's
good
evaluated okay so you see this is a code
you know just copy it copy it it will it
will basically start command log mod so
let me start again
Emacs miscellaneous here say okay let's
go to my terminal and start Emacs that's
how I start Emacs
great my Emacs is here now let's go back
to Emacs and let's see switch here now
I'm going to call the command you cannot
see hold on a second let me oh just a
window this way okay then we call the
command mxr start command log mod you
see now it's good you see I don't have
to do the extra step of removing that
panel okay okay let's go back to castle
talk show talk show
that's the Emacs command then let's do a
JavaScript JavaScript object system and
how are we here yet
how are we here yet one guy watching
okay and and let me wait for a while let
me do this keyboard page okay there is
this interesting keyboard let's go to
Twitter twitter.com and I'm going to
show you the keyboard let's turn on the
JavaScript you kind of need JavaScript
to log into Twitter
okay let's go to notifications and there
is this keyboard I want to add too now
I'm going to show you this this thing
and that is also Emacs demo so if you
are in max user this would be great for
you so you see she posted these photos
and let me show you open it yeah okay
one two three three photos we're gonna
right click open image okay right click
open image right click of an image
now switch tab save it save this file as
a JPEG okay anything starting with EE
okay in my download folder save it close
save key to save close save key III in
downloads folder close now back to Emacs
now go to my keyboard block open showing
browser now this is my keyboard block
now if you go down to fun keyboards and
you will see this funky keyboard Oh
actually not not fun keyboard funky what
is over here let's see if I am showing a
window one second
okay I'm still here and I'm showing the
window okay so in this window needs to
be go like that okay anyway front
keyboards so these are a bunch of very
interesting keyboards and you go down
here and you will see this Chinese
character drum keyboard let's magnify
okay so this Chinese character drum you
see you got this keyboard and it's full
of keys like a drum kit but actually so
this is actually April Fool's from
Google Japan so so some nerds created
this actually Bo this keyboard they are
like you know dummy keyboards there's no
electronics it just for the looks so and
they put all these characters on the
keyboard but if you actually read
Chinese they don't make sense because
many of these characters are not used
you know barely you know you you don't
you hardly see them once in a year so
I'm going to add so apparently so this
is back in 2010 so it's almost it's nine
years old
April Fool's and apparently she is a
Japanese eventually she went to some
kind of Museum in Japan and saw this
keyboard so she took some photos so we
got new photos and I'm going to add it
to my keyboard log so I mean if you were
watching two people say something
here's they say something here guys
say hello hallo H not Hollow but hello
okay let's back to the keyboard so I'm
going to so I already save the keyboard
so let's copy the URL copy it switch to
Emacs open the file then I'm going to go
down update
block date and let's just add it here
for now
actually it's go down here let's look at
where I want to add them I want to add
them below these okay Chinese input
methods
let's see such Chinese input method okay
it's right here so I'm going to add here
so I just call the command that some
movie image file and where do I want to
save it to
ok the directory I and let's just say
yes
ok now view in browser go down we're
gonna gonna you see we got it here let's
do another one
hi e to okay hi he okay that's all added
here so back to browser refresh you can
see I have added them here this is very
super convenient command actually I
talked about yesterday cuz I move image
file it will it will automatically move
the image any file starting with the
name ie from a certain directories such
as download directory desktop you know
and move it to you know where you want
it to be and create a image tag for it
like that like that but now let me show
you another command which is you see
this e file name is no good I want to
rename it
I could have renamed it you know when it
asked me to name a file file but I'm
going to show you another command so I
want to rename this file you can you see
I can tell I can return and open the
file you can see that file I want to
rename it so I want to rename it like
that okay copy that
so call the command search team I'll
rename sauce file path ok and I want to
rename it to let's say drum keyboard ok
Chinese from keyboard okay do the same
thing for this one Chinese from keyboard
and add a random string okay you see
it's here and this one as well rename
add a random string okay save it go to
browser reload you see it looks the same
now the mission so that command is
renamed is this one size TLD name source
file path you know that someone is
so my neighbor has a motorcycle I hate
those guys
you know they in America you have
sometimes you know these motorcyclists
they like it they like it loud you know
okay back to three people watching okay
so let me rename it we're gonna get into
JavaScript after this you know right
after these few more minutes okay so we
got we have renamed them but there's one
more thing I want to do I want to let me
just show you then switch show the panel
so you can see all my commands on the
left so I'm going to extract the URL
that's done okay now move the cursor
here paste the URL you see so that
command is Sai HTML extract URL for
example I can select these two and I
press a key and you know then they are
got the URL extracted you can do it for
the whole site you know the
motorcycles is really annoying okay so
for example let's copy the whole file
I mean selected extract URL and those
are all the URI just extracted and in
gets fully put into the ki-rin so I open
a new buffer and you can see so this is
very convenient if you work in HTML
let's go back to the yeah so I I just
extracted that and paste it here and
I'll do the same thing I'll copy this to
extract extract the URL TD the block and
paste it here then I'm gonna call
another command look this command is
called this oops actually the file name
is wrong but anyway this one works so
I'm gonna call the command this command
is called
cuz I any HTML in any lingo Phi so
basically you see that it automatically
put the text figure caption text here
based on the image name based on you
know this image name and it also
automatically creates the odd thing now
let's look at this fire okay yeah so
this file is identical to the the
previous one so we don't need this block
anymore and this too it's actually image
file but when we renamed it we forgot to
put JPEG so well so what do you do so
you open the file go to tired tired jump
and you see this is the file and this is
the other one let's rename them so I
call the command tired toggle read-only
and dot jpg and dot jpg okay and save it
okay so they'll be named so I know I
mocked him then I call this command so
copy file path so this to file path is
copied close it close it we don't need
this anymore
taste you see we got the correct file
path and with you know with a JPEG
correct name so now I linked link again
showing browser go back down and that's
good you know that's the there we have
it that's what I wanted to add to my
blog you know a new addition
so I copy now last step last step is
copy the file path of this buffer close
it go through my keyboard blog and go to
the top here add a new section paste it
blink of eye and say add it more photos
okay make it a paragraph shrink blank
dice then go back to the URL put the
cursor in the URL then I call this
command which is make atom entry so
basically what it does is it added these
few blocks into my RSS XML file that's
good close it save go to Esau saw a
brief saw interactive a brief you know
it's a abbreviation and let me choose
which one I want I want the first one or
sink
yes enter okay then it's uploaded to my
website you see we got you know several
updates of different files that that is
it you see some my blog shows the link
and people can go to you know so that is
about that so so shall we get on to the
JavaScript then for people watching
break the loop yeah great to see you
again
that is cool seeing how you update your
web page very proficient process thank
you
so I think let's talk about JavaScript
let's go to an talk show because today I
was you know I was I made an
announcement that we're gonna do
JavaScript and we're gonna show you I'm
gonna show you
the JavaScript object system I'm gonna
like kind of a tutorial and I i'm going
to explain javascript object system or
you know as explained the computer
language in a way in a style i think
you're you rarely see you almost never
see and this is a kind of a mathematical
style what that means is that i tell you
exactly what you know what's what a
function or a sequence of you know
sequence of alphabets do we exactly we
found you know without getting into oh
this is a pattern or that's a method or
you know this you know this you know
without order like computer programming
methodology kind of way okay this is
like you'll see it's it's like it's like
mathematics everything is based on
purely on logic okay so let's go in not
close that so let's go through yet
javascript yeah so if you have any
questions or comments or any other
topics just type in the comment box and
we'll talk about that after maybe 30
minutes yep so let's go to javascript
you know let's see where are we gonna be
heading into because when we talk about
javascript there could be a lot of
topics that just come up about
javascript so this is my true javascript
in depth and yeah let's talk about that
then ok so javascript object okay I have
a article here now if if you are a you
know if you are someone who prefer to
read you don't want waste time watching
videos then you can just go directly to
JavaScript in-depth and go to
Travis this this page object overview
and you know it's a it's kind of a
condensed version of you know all the
food details you can read but let me
talk about it so javascript is is so
javascript has an object system you know
object a scene object oriented
programming however the Java Script
object system is entirely different from
from Java Python Ruby Oh simple as first
okay those languages their object system
is called class-based object system you
create a class then you create an
instance of that class you know the
class can serve as kind of a model you
know kind of a mode you know of what
your objects is going to be and class
can inherit inherit from other classes
so you have a kind of a class tree you
know then you create a object of you
know of any class you want so that that
is Java and C prospers and pythons their
object system but JavaScript actually do
not have that at all I mean it has
object system but it's call so it so
called prototype based object system
okay it's entirely different it's
nothing it's nothing similar to the
Chavez job away okay so if you are
learning JavaScript and if you really
want to get into it it's good thing to
totally forget what you know about
objects system in from Java so
JavaScript object system it's entirely
different but however of course however
you can you know even completely
different languages you can kind of
emulate so they they always have some
kind of similar ideas but just remember
JavaScript object is fundamentally
different okay so it's is you don't want
to think of it as a object of seeing you
know Python or Java
so it's called prototype based system
and let me also mention in you know
JavaScript now they have a new version
every year so in 2005 2015 they added
let's see JavaScript 2015
it's called Ahmed script that's the
official name so they added they
actually added a keyword called class
let's see crass you see so so these days
you know in browser when you code
JavaScript there is actually a keyword
class let that lets you define class the
way similar to Java and Python okay they
added the the keyword class constructor
static extents and super so on the
surface they look which they appear just
like the Java system but actually still
it's entirely different okay you really
don't want to think of JavaScript as a
you know the object as a jumble weight
you know if you really want to
understand JavaScript you know a lot of
people don't really understand it you
know you you could still walk in company
you know for two years but when you know
deep problems occur when some bugs occur
you get into problems you're gonna spend
hours saying figure out what why did it
doesn't work you know because you
thought this is the class and that is
the object and but it's just doesn't
work you know so don't don't think of it
like a Java or Python the class keyword
and this bunch of keywords added in 2015
they are they are kind of a wrapper okay
they are kind of a convenience what's
what's so called sugar syntax so
basically these what these keyword does
is that they they are kind of equivalent
to you know several like when you use a
class to example have a tutorial here
javascript class now this page
teaches you about the JavaScript the
class keyword used using the class
keyword to define your crest but however
it's really just a syntactic wrapper you
know you know the class keyword is kind
of equivalent equivalent to like ten
lines of JavaScript that people do
before before there was a class keyboard
keyboard so anyway yeah so so there's
this new you know class features but
again don't it's entirely different from
Java or Python so let me talk about
JavaScript object once I explain this
you're you're kind of see they are you
know totally different so object
overview so a JavaScript object is
actually don't don't read don't read
that article now because yeah you get
distracted so the JavaScript object is
JavaScript object okay first of all let
me perhaps any comments so break the
loop says that's confusing and stupid no
JavaScript cause it's object if they are
different from C first first Java Python
objects yeah you know so yeah so I yeah
that's an interesting topic you know
because I actually one time spend time
to dive into what does the word object
mean in different languages
he actually they they mean quite
different things in this they also have
a word object you know using that in
these manuals but the this object
actually just mean let's see so sorry
object
what is object
so what does wait that's a meaning of
object in computer languages so that's
the that's the article you can read so
Chavez got a concept of class in object
and pythons cressid an object is is
quite different from Java as well then
this got the you know the word object
the object game this pretty mean in this
pretty much just means a binary blob
okay and javascript object is another
thing not yet JS object is yeah it's so
totally another thing it's just a
namespace in c language is also has its
own object so anyway so you see the
words you know in computer in
programming they got a views you know
each each programmer if you only program
in certain languages you think object is
that but another other programmers see
it you know that totally entirely
different way so anyway so let's get
back to JavaScript so let's see so let's
go back to the javascript object so
javascript object is three things okay
before we talk about javascript object
let me talk about javascript type types
in javascript first yeah okay let me
quickly cover that now I'm going to try
to be succinct you know hopefully I
succeed in covering this topic about
JavaScript object okay first first of
all javascript has value java javascript
is not a typed strongly typed language
and it is not statically typed it's
dynamically dynamically typed basically
meaning that when you have a variable
you do not have to declare what type it
is
however values has types and JavaScript
types are these six types
so undefined no pulling string number
symbol an object okay one two three four
five six seven seven types now the
symbol type is new in in since 2015 and
it's kind of it's a bit exotic but well
anyway let's cover each a little bit
each type so undefined undefined is just
a it's a CD type is the only value that
belongs to the undefined type is the
keyword undefined
you know just the full keyboard
undefined and what's the purpose of
undefined so undefined is basically
anything that's that doesn't have a
value you know just like undefined you
know so and nor you know javascript is a
language full of watts you know full of
extremely extreme complexity and
mistakes know is a new is another type
and whose the only value of that type is
the newer keyboard so this these two
things are kind of funny so you have the
newer type but the only value is the
only possible possible value for the new
type is the newer keyboard
similar to the undefined so so what does
no mean no no is kind of a mistake in
JavaScript it basically just means it's
kind of like undefined but it's like
undefined but it's not it's even hard to
explain but because no is actually a
mistake okay just you can just think of
it as as as you can think of it as a
intentionally something that is
intentionally undefined now as opposed
to undefined the keyword undefined the
value which is just anything that's not
defined you get undefined now Noah is
more like intentional
define okay then you have Pauline type
boolean type is just two possible values
for boolean type true the keyword true
and the keyword force okay then you have
string now you are familiar with strings
you know that you can create strings
lots of strings now you have number type
now in JavaScript unlike you know unlike
C or Python
you have flowed into long turbo and so
on in JavaScript number is just the
number there is no int there's no float
there is no distinction actually okay
and that's actually a mistake as well
but you know anyway so the number type
is just a number like 34 or 3.1 however
the number type also includes two other
special keywords nan na n which stands
for not a number and infinity which
which is the result you get if you
divide one by zero okay so the nan and
infinity they are like keywords I mean
they are just they are values in
JavaScript like like you can type I'm
not going to show you but but you know
so they are they are just like you know
undefined no true force they are just
keywords that stand for a value and so
nan and infinity is also belongs belongs
to the type number okay so that's a
number type symbol type we're gonna
we're not gonna talk about it now the
now it comes to the object type which is
the you know the the the the other type
we haven't covered yet
now the object type is the or important
type in JavaScript it's kind of the most
important and the most used used and the
most critical to program programmers
okay the object type so now remember
these are the JavaScript types okay so
if you have some value in JavaScript any
value if it's not undefined if it's not
normal not puling not string not number
and not symbol
they ain't object you know it's it's
like by definition you know it's it's
just object now what what does object
mean now okay so let me explain
javascript object well first of all let
me tell you what I give you a flavor
what what what are objects in JavaScript
for example you have functions in other
languages right you have functions you
have arrays you have you have you know
functions where you have you know in
other language function array lists you
know hash table or dictionary code
dictionary in Python so all these things
in JavaScript is called
object you know the the technical all
these you know least you know ArrayList
hash table they are actually just the
object type okay now as a programmer you
of course you think a function is
different from array obviously you know
function is a function arrays array
erase the data type function is not a
data type function is actually you know
how you run a program but however in
JavaScript both function and array and a
bunch of other things you know map you
know a bit anything else listen you know
you know any anything else is technique
technically they are not they they are
the object type okay object yeah so
array function is object arrays object
you know
okay let's quickly look at some of the
object array object
each Robo each Robo is also object okay
yeah so they are just objects okay
object now let's go back to JavaScript
object overview so so you know they are
like the as far as the language is
concerned they you know function in a
way their type is just object there's no
a different type that's called function
there is no a different type called
array okay they are just object now now
so so what is the technical definition
of an object in JavaScript okay let's
talk about that now javis the technical
definition of anything object is is
first of all it's a key value pairs you
know you've got a bunch of keys each
keys got a value so this is similar to
hash table in Ruby in Perl it's similar
to dictionary in in Python it's called
dictionary and in Java
it's called hash table I think so
so yeah so when you have a key value
pair first of all object is a just key
value pairs so so this is actually the
defining characteristics of JavaScript
object okay when you have something
that's key value pairs when you you know
that's let's say object
you know technique for your object in
JavaScript now you might say you might
question you okay okay you said function
in JavaScript is an object however
function is not a key value pair so what
do you mean function is the object okay
you are wrong a function in JavaScript
is a object meaning that it is actually
a key value pairs so let me show you
example them so let's open a new buffer
let's go to such JavaScript mod ok and
let's oh god I haven't called a
JavaScript for a while let fix so yeah
what we're gonna do we're gonna
demonstrate a function okay we're gonna
demonstrate a phone
that is object function okay so function
name it F let's say we turn three okay
this is just a simple function that just
returned three ok console.log let's call
F F and that's go ahead and print it and
it I need to name the file so let's name
it XJS okay it returns three you know we
are calling a function now but if you
console.log type now type type of type
of is operator that returns what the
type is of something some value so if
you say typeof f use oh okay it says
function now that's that's actually a
mistake as well because in JavaScript
you do not have a type code function but
however you know this is this is part of
the reason javascript is extremely
complex when you use type typeof
operator on a function it returns
actually a function string for example
you can see I do here
I run a code you see type of F equals
two function returns true it returns a
string function so why does this a
function it's kind of it's just for
convenience because if if function an
array for example they are or objects
but but sometimes when you want to need
the type of something you need to
distinguish function and array they are
obviously you know very different you
know for as far as programmer is
concerned that is why type of the type
of our function returns the name
function but actually there's no there's
no type code function in JavaScript so
this is one of the problem of JavaScript
is extremely calm
but however I said you know a function
is a key and value pairs right you don't
believe me let me show you an example so
let's say function so we defined a
function let's name it
FF oops let's name it FF instead of F
okay so that we don't so we don't
confuse it with something so let's run
it it still runs okay so now if F is a
function object now let's say that x
equals to 3 now we assume FF is a object
and we add a property named X and we we
we set the value of 3 to it
then we print console.log FF okay we
just print it so let's see what happens
there it is you see now it actually
prints this print this you can see now
that's an object notation that's an
object but so you know it's an object
but however it includes this function
thing we'll get into that why you have
that but you can see here it actually
shows the key and value X you know X is
a key value is 3 in fact you can add
lots of more you can add y equals to 4
and let's run it and you see now you got
2 keys and value X 3 y 4 and actually
you can see keys you can print all keys
of the the FF reflect keys ok so ok I
haven't coded JavaScript for a while but
let's find out there is a function that
returns all keys or keys of a object
these properties here so object go get
on property keys okay let's do this
reflect on keys that's the word reflect
on keys ok ok that's what we want
FF okay and let's console.log print it
up run it you see now it trains all keys
of the object FF you know the function
FF so we got length we got name we got
arguments we got color
we got prototype and we got x and y XY
is x and y is what we just defined the
others are kind of building so anyway so
here that the purpose of this is just
show you that function is actually just
technically a object in JavaScript and
same thing with a race you know same
thing with JavaScript arrays for example
we can 3 4 5 3 4 5 that's alright you
know same thing with a race for example
let's do this so we just defined our
array 3 4 5 and we we try to okay let's
do this type of ok let's run it so type
of array is you see nowadays object and
when we when we want to show all the
keys of array we got hey you see we got
0 1 2 and length you see array we
normally don't think of the index as
keys right array has indexes but array
is not a dictionary it's not a hash
table so normally we don't consider the
indexes keys but however in JavaScript
you know being being so being so screwed
up array is technically a object
and it has keys so the keys is you know
we got the index is actually the keys 0
1 2 and you also have the length as key
why do you have why is length that as a
key again it's just due to the
complexity of JavaScript is extremely
it's very bad language okay now let's go
back to javascript object so we we have
covered the javascript types ok value
has types we covered all the types then
we explained the object type the object
is kind of the heart of javascript the
object type so what is the object now we
let's talk about javascript object
overview so so object is first of all
object is a key value pairs okay that's
no key value pairs that's the most
important characteristics of object
every object is key and value pairs now
if it's if it's an object such that you
cannot you know it doesn't have key
value pairs then it is not an object
basically because the equipment appears
this is the heart of a javascript object
so again here contrast you know this is
different from job Java or Python okay
in Python or Java you you don't think of
object goes like key value pairs like
what the hell what the hell you know key
value pairs let's hash table that's
dictionary that's not object so that is
why javascript object is totally
different okay javascript object is key
value pairs just like pythons dictionary
okay but it's got other things we will
talk about that so it's key value pairs
that's the that's the definition of
javascript object but
but javascript object they have several
special objects now many special objects
they have kind of special things
attached to it like just you know just
one of special you know special behavior
such as function in array you know you
got all these bunch of special behaviors
you know so let's see let's see what
we're going so so so far so good
so break the loop to you new code
JavaScript let's see how many of you are
watching for people how me go for people
so JavaScript types JavaScript object
yeah so let's go back to JavaScript
object so object is a key value pairs
but however many object in JavaScript
has kind of a special internal thing for
example a function is a JavaScript
object but however it can be called you
know it can be called and if you are
evaluated so it kind of got the special
thing you know as a function then
JavaScript also has other object for
example array array say object and array
also got some kind of special thing
because array you got the length
property building kind of a special and
and also in JavaScript 2015 they added a
bunch of things they added let's see
JavaScript stranger escape character
iterables okay javascript in JavaScript
2015 they added a set object a set is
like a mathematical set it's like a it's
it's actually a ordered list
you know it's like an ordered array
except that you cannot have repetitions
so JavaScript 2015 they created they
added this set object now set object
again first of all technically it's an
object meaning that you got key value
pairs you know any any javascript
objects got key value pairs but however
the set objects object is got kind of a
special internal you know data data that
actually you know work as a set like you
can add elements to it you know it works
as a mathematical set separate from
being a key value pair so for example
like even for example let me show you
this code so let's open a new save it xx
JavaScript let's save it xx to
JavaScript okay now let's see so we here
we we create a set new set and we add a
few elements to it six five six then we
trained it you can see it prints out six
and five because a set object do not
allow duplicate so that that is a set
object in JavaScript 2015 now however
remember a set any object is your object
meaning that it's actually your key
value pairs so so reflect so let's print
out all the keys
so let's print the keys SS yes okay
let's print all the keys of the set you
see it's empty it doesn't have any keys
right now but we can add it just like
before so s dot s x equals to 3 let's
add some X star y equals to 4 let's
evaluate it
it's okay let's print cheese again you
see now it got keys X&Y is you see and
you see now and if if we you see because
we actually added the key so now
remember set set is a object so it means
that it's got three value pairs
indeed we just added it you know we just
added kin and and and we can actually
print it out let's see print out of four
key and value you see it prints here so
we got key three and we got key key X is
three key Y is four you know but however
a set is again you know it's kind of
like special it's got internal data
structures just like function you know
so it's got this internal data structure
that actually contains the set you know
the purpose of this object but however
it's still key value pairs so that kind
of explains so so remember a set is a
object in JavaScript is key value pairs
but for many object it got kind of a
special properties or special internal
things for example a function is a
function a set actually contains the set
data that's separate from the key value
pairs and in the same similar way
JavaScript 2015 also added a map object
it's this is this is another example
where it shows how javascript is really
convoluted now what's a map object the
map object in JavaScript from 2015 is
actually the proper hash table or
dictionary so map object is just like
pythons dictionary or rubies hash table
it's the proper data type for key value
pairs now you may be wondering so wait
I'm check this is already key value
pairs but how come you now have like
this map object that's also key value
that's the proper key value pairs well
the reason is because the Java well it's
just it just shows that how javascript
is you know a very bad language that
evolves over time so in the beginning
javascript is you know it's just you
know you got the object everything is
almost everything is the object you know
object is key value pairs but however
it's you know it it serves as a you know
hash table or dictionary you know Python
dictionary but however it's it really
it's got lots of issues you know that
that is why javascript finally in 2015
they finally added a proper key value
pairs called the map object so it's
really confusing because object is
already a key value pairs but now you
have a map object which is also you know
intended to be the proper key value
pairs so the map object in JavaScript
just like a normal object you can add
you know keys and values you know you
can add key value key keys but also it's
got an internal data structure that
function was you know proper hash table
or dictionary so that's what's going on
so why do they create this because for
example for example the so they why do
they app add the map object because with
the map object the cheese can be any
type okay but however the JavaScript
object
you know the key can only be string or
symbol so that's kind of you know the
problem so that that's why they are
created the map object so if you want
your keys to be numbers for you for
example integers you cannot do that with
you know the JavaScript object because
the object all the key
is actually Austrian so symbols stranger
symbols but with the map object type you
can actually have integers as as keys
the and they are several other reasons
okay the other reason is yeah the other
reasons is about you know inheritance
we're gonna talk about because
javascript object has inheritance you
know but however we are using a hash
table or dictionary often you don't
really want inheritance like if you want
to check a key exists you don't want it
you don't want it to automatically
automatically lookup parents you know to
see if the key exists in parents or
parent of parents and so on so you know
if you really want a data type that's
hash table you only want concern about
whether the key exists in this hash
table so in the in the JavaScript you
know map object which is a hash table
you know you don't you don't have to
worry about looking up parent objects so
that that's some of the reasons they
created the map object and you know that
illustrates why javascript is very very
very complex language now let's go back
to javascript object okay we are about
done so javascript object is key value
pairs and javascript object some objects
has special special internal structure
or special behavior such as function or
such as you know the set object array
object map object and so on and others
now okay now javascript object has a
each object usually have a parent it may
or may not have a parent what does that
mean
meaning that given a javascript object
it
it may be linked to another object that
is considered its parent okay so so so
any object may have one parent one only
one not two okay not not two or more
only one it's not it's not possible to
have two parents so each object may have
one may have a link to another object as
its parent and of course that object may
also have another parent so so you have
this chain of parents and this is called
a prototype chain okay technically the
parent is called a prototype so if you
have an object you know Java Script
object and if you if another object is
its parent it's called its prototype
object okay you don't call you know you
don't technically you don't call it
parent object but you call it prototype
object of the object okay so so what
what's the deal with prototype I mean
why do you need parent now parent is the
technical definition of this parent the
significance of this parent is is that
when you actually look up a property in
JavaScript such as for example when we
type when we want to print okay when we
print s S dot X okay when we when we
print s dot X we are trying to look up
property with a key X we are trying to
see what the value it is when you do
this javascript will first check if X is
in the object is a key in the object
okay now if it exists then it prints the
value for example let's run it it exists
it prints three here you see it rains
three
however if it does not exist it will
actually look up the parent to see if
the parent contains that key now this
mechanism is called inheritance this is
the technical meaning of inheritance and
it means nothing else except this this
is the only thing the only meaning of an
inherent inheritance okay it is when
JavaScript tries to look up of a key it
will try to check up the parent you know
it will check up at the parent if that
parent does I have the key it will check
up the the parent of that parent and so
on until it reaches it which is a object
that has no parent okay so let's try
let's try it
for example let's try this by the way on
let's try this okay okay
okay what we are doing is that we are
trying to look up a chi that is named to
stream of the object egg s okay we're
gonna run it
they actually return this function to
stream but why is that because we have
previously we just printed reflect on
keys we have we have printed out all
keys of the object and there's no key
named to stream but however here we it
shows actually you know it prints
function to stream so where does that
came from so it the two string actually
is a key in one of the parents of this
object object s okay so that is why so
this happens because of inheritance
you know the key doesn't exist there's
no key name to string of the object s
but however it's parent it's parents or
parents of parents does have you know
that key that's why we get this and this
is called inheritance so this is how
JavaScript works inheritance
okay so that is about all it is about
object in JavaScript so javascript
object is a key value pair and some
object has special behavior poverty and
you have the concept you know and each
object may have another object that's
linked to it considered as its parent
and and that's it about object the
significance of this parent thing is
inheritance which is you know how
JavaScript when JavaScript tries to look
up keys you got you know it may look up
the parents keys and there's another
thing about extensible property but you
know we skip that for now but that's
that's that's it for JavaScript the
technical definition of JavaScript
object now from from so this is called
prototype object system now that's all
about it that's all nothing else now at
this point you you might you know ask
the question so you don't see you know
you don't see the concept of a class you
don't see the concept of instantiate you
know a object
you know like creating object from class
why is that that's a good question
because there is no class you know this
this that's that's it about JavaScript
object there's no there's nothing to do
with the Java class or Python class or
or in here or you know or extend
extending or class nothing like that
toad it's entirely different so this is
this is critical to remember when you I
don't know if you maybe you have worked
in JavaScript for a few years you want
to it's a good idea to to try to change
your point of view entirely you know try
to reshape your entire concept of
JavaScript object
these from this technical definition
point of view because once you do this
you we are actually obtained clarity you
know you know yeah so I think that's
that's kind of covers it one hour so let
me read the comments with the loop
even though JavaScript's object go
differently behind the scenes as key
value pairs in practice are they used in
a similar manner as java objects kind
yes and no okay let me talk about that
yes I know so no I do not program
JavaScript mostly Python Java in bash
okay I plan to learn JavaScript
okay so there's no instantiation or
extension yes there's no instantiation
yeah there's no such concept at all but
it's fairly complex because for a
typical JavaScript programmer you
actually you will be led to think that
javascript is like Java and Python and
in some way you can get away thinking
like that but actually if you actually
think like that you run into lots of
problems when you basically you will not
advance your JavaScript skill we are not
of advanced you know I have to have
after you know some level you you know
because then you are start to get into
all sort of weird behaviors that you
cannot fathom you cannot figure because
because you are thinking of JavaScript
object you know like the Java or Python
system you know javascript actually
tries too hard tries very hard to
emulate the Java system in fact that's
the goal of JavaScript you know
javascript began in 1995 and you know
it's it's the base of JavaScript it's
it's
intended to emulate I mean the design is
intended to emulate the scheme Lisp
language and also copy the object system
from the programming language code self
so the prototype object system came from
the self from a programming language
it's called prototype system which is
entirely different from Java okay but
however because of you know commercial
reasons back in 1995 Java is very hot
Java just be you know became Java was
just invented and some Microsystems put
huge millions of dollars to advi--
advertise java and so everyone you know
knows about java but nobody knows about
javascript you know javascript is in the
browser you know I mean they trying to
pitch it they trying to somehow make
JavaScript popular they trying to find a
way you know nobody knows it yet they
want to announce it so and Microsoft
some Microsoft systems you know who
created java made a kind of a major
collaboration with netscape you know who
creates an init netscape browser so they
so java so javascript tries to use the
sun microsystems you know java
advertisement you know try to use that
as you know as the part of their to to
make javascript popular so they
advertise javascript kind of like a java
system but the internet the language is
entire different eyerly different but
however they they made the JavaScript
syntax to be like Java syntax so they
created keywords like they you know
instance of they created keywords like
you'll see you know they do everything
they can to make it you know look like
Java Java you know they look to make it
look like Java even though the language
is is there's no way to be like Java
because the the system is entirely
entirely different there's no way no
possible way
it's like Java it's like two entirely
different things
and also Java Script is based on scheme
this language so it's like functional
programming it's a functional you can
consider JavaScript is functional
programming that's why you know you have
the the guy who created JavaScript the
good part you know the famous guy
what's-his-name who created Jason
so anyway so let me wrap up about that
then let me read the comments so so so
this is why so this is why javascript is
very convoluted very complex and it on a
surface it seems to you know the
keywords and so I appears to the to be
like Java or Python system but actually
is entirely different because it's based
on scheme and self language called
prototype object system yeah so that's
why it's very commonly come loaded you
know if you begin to learn learn Java
Java JavaScript you know it may appear
to be like Java and you can get away
with it but you won't get far if you you
know stick with that model of mod of
thinking you really want to you know
learn the JavaScript way object key
value pairs object an object has special
special behaviors and object has parents
that's it there is no class
there's no instantiation there's nothing
like that there is no constructors again
even though javascript has many of such
keywords I mean there's a keyword called
constructor but it's like entirely wrong
I mean it's just like like it's like
garbage you know maybe I should explain
a bit a bit so let me look okay here so
yeah so once you understand covered you
know that that's it about JavaScript
object there's nothing more to it it's a
key value pairs
special behaviors and each object may
link to a parent object called parent
and that's it and so anything you see in
JavaScript that seems to behave like the
Java or Python scrath they are actually
using this
object and parent trying to emulate it
that's that's kind of what you are
seeing and it does not work so well it's
actually does not work very well and if
you study JavaScript you you know you
you are start to find all kind of
problems that's why you do not want to
think of JavaScript okay you know the
prototype system as you know the
class-based object system you can read
you know if you already know JavaScript
a bit then you can read I show you what
function what section to read read the
JavaScript object inheritance section
now this section tells you properly what
is a Java what is a object in all its
manifestations in JavaScript the
language you know it's like a
mathematical description of it you know
what does you know object to in
JavaScript so that that's this section
JavaScript object and inheritance now
after that then you can read this
section this section is about JavaScript
constructors in class now this section
all these things are actually they are
they are manifestations of JavaScript
trying to pretend to be Java okay
that's why then you have you know you
have these key binding you have
constructor you have the property called
prototype you have the operator new like
new something you have the operator
instance of then you have a properties
key code constructor then you have the
keyword called class you have a keyword
called extents they are added in 2015 so
you got these things they on the surface
you know they look like the Java
thing but the other not
and when you read this section you will
find extreme complexities because it's
it's really impossible to emulate
emulate it well so you will find you
know some keyword it seems to do one
thing but only in this special in case
and not in others it's very confusing
okay let me read the comments and maybe
that yeah I because I piece I covered
the essence of JavaScript JavaScript
object and how they how and why they
differ from the you know the Java Java
in titles were world so was it confusing
for you to understand JavaScript object
system when you first encountered it
no it was not confusing for me when I
first encountered it because when I
began I knew there's I knew there's
something kind of I kind of already read
somewhere the JavaScript object system
is very different from the Java object
system so I knew the I I heard about
prototype object system I try to read
Wikipedia I don't really understand it
but I began my JavaScript journey in
depth beginning around 2000 2012
I began by I by reading this great book
the so-called Rhino book so I actually
wrote a similar book reviews of all
JavaScript books out there you can
actually see so I have two oligos you
can go to the URL and read offline so
this page is JavaScript JavaScript books
review I basically cover all
JavaScript's printed books and all
JavaScript's literature's online all of
them yes all of them I give you my
opinion which one is good or in I you
know I think Oh in English language
anything you know if you are a
JavaScript expert I will cover your book
you know you will find it here you are
seeing my opinion about it if if some
online resource is not mentioned here
it's not worth reading okay that's my
that's that's what I say that's my
confidence level okay you can check this
out now I started to learn JavaScript
from this book JavaScript this thick
book called
this is superb excellent JavaScript book
today it's not worth it though because
JavaScript has you know it's JavaScript
has changed you know since 2015 it has
turned inside out so this book is only
covering JavaScript back in you know
year 2000 so you know if you are coding
JavaScript today this book it's not that
useful because you are missing is that
you are missing you know like more than
50% of it but I began learning
JavaScript with Facebook back in 2011
when mm you know JavaScript 2015 is not
out yet you know it's four years yet so
and and so for that version of
JavaScript that this is an excellent
book and part of the reason is that the
style the the style of the writing style
the the the philosophy of covering
computer language this guy and earned my
respect this guy is what's his name
David Flanagan I think he works for
Mozilla right now I'm not sure but
anyway so he covers the language in a
style
I prefer which is also the style of my
languages which I call kind of like kind
of like mathematical style I mean but
you don't usually want to use that
phrase because when you say something
mathematical is it scares people away oh
my god this is math no I don't want to
read this style you know but but but
basically it is a mathematical style you
know don't worry about the jargons you
know you know I'm a you know I don't
want to pretend ok oh it's not
mathematical but actually the nature of
this style is kind of mathematical you
could mathematical style what does it
mean it just means that you approach the
subject
in the most logical and and you know in
a logic system cycle like you approach
you know logic system you remove
everything that's not relevant okay you
just cover exactly what exactly
something do exactly how it behaves you
describe it exactly in terms of you know
how it relates to other object so
variables you know in that sense you
know you don't give a story like some
other books Styles you know tutorial
styles they they start to give you a
story
oh I learned you know I learned C++ then
one day I was done in JavaScript you
know they give you a story then they
take a Chavez script you know it's you
know the system is then you know they
talk about patterns so this is
JavaScript patterns like you have
factory patterns you know they talk
about computer engineering methodologies
you know like that then then some books
they talk about kind of like compiler
oriented style they talk about int Oh
JavaScript number is an int or float you
know like what the is float then
you know so if you program in C you know
like you are into system programming
type of guy there may be those kind of
style fit your way of thinking because
they talk about CPU how references works
you know but that's not but that's you
know implementation anyway so it's like
that's about writing styles so this book
I learned from this book I learned from
a lot from it in the beginning it's a
good book is its mathematical style so
similar to the way I like so so I didn't
get confused because I was reading from
a good book this book and in industry in
practice are there
are they you know use in a similar
manner in JavaScript objects so in in
industry so as we said JavaScript object
is prototype based system it's very
different from Java but in an industry
like do people get confused to people
pretend the JavaScript object is to the
people use JavaScript object just like
Java so that's a question what's the
answer the answer is you know it's kind
of fairly complex because on one hand
they are really entirely different okay
indeed and if you really try to think of
JavaScript object as Java you really run
into a lot problems okay that's that's a
fact okay that's the technical effect on
the other hand javascript language as we
mentioned the history of JavaScript
language is that you know it's based on
you know scheme Lisp and you know the
self the language called self object
prototype object system which is
entirely different from Java however
however they try as much as possible
they really try hard to to make the
language appear you know just like Java
you know they hide everything you know
the object the photo type system they
try it you know very hard to make it
like Java the syntax you know the the
keyword names you know they try to make
it like that so what so you know when
you when you are learning Java you know
you kind of you get pushed into that you
know you so can so the real question is
can can you really pretend JavaScript
language like a Java or P system it's
hard to say it's kind of yes and no you
know if you really I mean let's say if
you are C if you are really programming
advanced things let's say if you are
running compiler you know if you are
really you
you know working on heavy projects no
the answer is no you cannot pretend
javascript object like Java no you
really have to understand Java Script
prototype system prototype based object
system Oh in other words if you have 10
years working in JavaScript or if you
are gonna going to write a JavaScript
book that's going to be appreciated by
experts no you can you cannot pretend it
like goes JavaScript however if you are
just you're working a company even for
two years you can kind of still get away
you know with not knowing much about
JavaScript details but you won't get far
now if you work in you know company for
five years
you're you're know you have your own
node you know or the difference is then
so that's the situation so that's why
you know JavaScript is fairly you know
complicated
okay thank you break the loop and Norman
says you can extend by modeling a
prototype object to make its children do
something different yes exactly
so again JavaScript again you know like
we mentioned it's just key value pairs
it's just object it's just key value
pairs and each object has a parent it
you can have an object that doesn't have
a parent okay it's possible you read my
tutorials I give you details but but
usually basically I'll be owning objects
has a parent okay and only one parent
and that parents usually have another a
parent of its own until you have a an
object that doesn't have a parent that's
called root object so you kind of have a
tree and also so that's it so so object
at anytime on object you can you can
change the parent like you can say oh I
don't want this to be my parent anymore
you just relink you can change the
parent to some other object that's
that's it you know you cannot do this
with Java you know with JavaScript
that's that is it's that's that's their
design of visit of this prototype based
system you don't have classes you just
have objects each object have a parent
and anytime you can change the parent to
anything else you know it's change
change it but here let me mention and
how do you change for example you can
see all the details so you can see how
how to create object with parent X get
set for o-type prevent adding property
determine type object clone object you
know you can see add methods to
prototype
yeah so I basically there's a page that
covers how do you change parent
I must mention somewhere here anyway so
uh anyway that I think that's it yeah
okay what I want to mention is that
however in practice actually Google all
the you know Google basically in
practice it's not recommended you change
objects parents why and here's another
very complex situation JavaScript
because because implementation you know
Google and all the web browsers will go
Microsoft five arts they implement
JavaScript they put a lot programmers
you know they want to make it extremely
fast so there's a huge amount of hack
you know incredible that means it's
almost impossible to for a person to
write a JavaScript compiler I mean you
can do that but your result will not be
comparable to to the JavaScript compiler
in Google browser or in Microsoft
browser or in in Firefox because they
are compiler is hack after hack after
hack you know extreme hack you know
ninety percent of it is actually the
poke of it is actually hack to make it
extremely fast so because of that you
have a situation where when because of
these compilers you have a situation
that whenever change you change you
actually change object as parent there's
a penalty penalty it makes it slower
it makes things slower now this is of
course this is not in JavaScript SPECT
you know you will not find this warning
in any JavaScript suspect you know
JavaScript is designed that you you
can't change the objects parents anytime
you want
but however because of this
implementation because they want speed
it so happens that you don't want to do
that because when you do that it makes
things slow you know you you're learning
about this
things when you get deep you know like
when you have few use us experience in
JavaScript then you'll hear people say
that anyway that's it for today okay my
god this is a loan talk 90 minutes so
thank you guys for watching thank you
with a big loop and thank you know man
I hope you liked it if you liked it I
have a patron on my website and PayPal
and stuff and you can contribute and
helping you know support the channel
thank you guys see you next time bye