hello welcome to another episode of
sound talk show today we are going to
code emac lisp We are continuing emac
lisp
coding of a writing a python mod from
scratch part three so the previous two
days two videos we covered part one part
two so this is part three it's probably
going to be on hour and we're gonna come
this is probably going to be the last
part so we are going to write a four
uh python mod starting very simple and
you know so watch those videos you'll
learn uh how to write a full featured
complete programming language mod in
emac Beast
okay and the the first two minutes let
me show you this keyboard I talked about
a little bit uh two days ago the glove
80 so I got this
it's fantastic okay fantastic so I'm
going to update you know search for
glove 80 keyboard on
sardi.info you'll see my reviews so I'm
going to continuously update this page
in the coming
weeks and months and uh then I'll be
using it uh live coding so it's
fantastic if you want
um my opinion you know I would say it's
just fantastic you know I can recommend
that you buy it
no questions asked you know like I'm
certain I love it so
um so I mean if you you know it's a bit
expensive 370 dollars and right now they
are in second batch I mean if you buy it
it'll come out you'll get it in a month
or two so anyway so I like recommend it
okay so watch my videos You'll see uh
more reviews and coming up
if you like the bow shaped if you like
thumb keys and if you like Wireless this
is
you know uh this is the one to buy I I
would say so because the or the other
choice would be kinesis
360.
now that one is uh 500 something so you
know this one I also
have some experience I tried it you know
uh so it's this is also pretty good but
at 500 dollars anyway so that's my
review I recommend it okay
uh okay so that's that's about the
um
the web 80 keyboard let's start to code
emac this if you have comments and
questions post it okay I'd love to see
see your comments okay on the on the
Ping window you can see all my command
course and keystrokes
uh you know again select it delete it
undo and you can see all the command
names and keystrokes I press I'm using a
varac keyboard and my current keyboard
is also fantastic and not very expensive
is expose
okay
so um
so yeah so let's continue let's first of
all let's get the code uh let's go to
the code so we're gonna show you uh go
to the directory search for python there
it is the python mod copy it
make a backup and uh okay copy the link
close close
and let's put the link here so we can
jump to it easily okay so here's a code
uh let me review okay so hold on a
second so go to talk show
today's talk show go to emac lisp uh you
know every the how to write the major
mod you can find my tutorial on my
website this is you know the last video
part one and part two and today today's
video will go there and here is uh
another one we did last year a year ago
uh on how to write a go Landmark from
scratch
okay so so you so you go to my website
you can find all the tutorials so let's
let's start to
um
yeah writing a major mod so copy the
link
go back and paste the link here okay so
now we got
uh let's start to code it okay so let's
go to the file
um and uh let me
should I do a summary of what we did
last time just okay briefly for two
minutes
so we got
um
so the first important thing is syntax
coloring which is basically just these
three lines keywords you know the python
keywords or function names then you just
create a regular expression the essence
is that you want to create this variable
which is a list of particular structure
essentially a list of regular expression
the regular expression is generated by
that function rejects opt
and so you got this this is the regular
expression called sub python highlight
then all you have to do
is you know this is the part where you
define the mod all you have to do is you
call you set that value to font about
defaults
so if unlock defaults is a built-in
variable from the front lock mod front
lock mod is a library for syntax
coloring so this is this line is
essentially all you have to do to create
synthetically
so that's the first thing we did
yesterday I mean the part one then we
did um then we created a
so hold on a second so let me show you
the code
uh okay
yeah I was thinking I was thinking to
show you the
entire code but they won't fit in one
screen uh okay so forget about it so
anyway syntax killing these three lines
then we create a syntax table which is a
emacs concept that classify every
character into certain groups such as
such as
Woods or punctuation group or
or the comment and common you know the
the programming language common starting
character and end character in The
Python case starting character is a palm
sign or number sign and end character is
a return
in a line break so this is setting up
creating a syntax table uh
by coding mixing tax table and modify
some entries so we create a syntax table
in particular this code just says that
it just says that the pound sign is the
starting of the common character
okay so once you have these then you
you just add that line
you know you just call it set syntax
table to that to your syntax table that
once you do that then you will have
syntax coloring of
strings in common okay
so that's the
so let's go to the beginning so let's
see so so we got syntax coloring then we
got syntax table for coloring string and
comment of the programming language okay
then we create a um then let me show you
what's what's the next thing we did okay
then we create a
uh a brief table abbreviation which is
uh emac system so you can type
for example I Type M and her m space
becomes message space again it becomes
the whole complete Syntax for the
function message for emac bisp I'm using
SAR emac this mod
so in the python case delete that so in
the python case we just did you know
this these five lines 10 lines that
creates a brief
a brief table so you can type filter and
you'll become the full function so
so let's evaluate the buffer okay now
let's let's go to some python uh code so
we can see how how our mod works so
let's go to a python code okay so let's
go to I have a kind of the Python script
here
so okay here let's see this one python
find and replace regularly by regular
expression this is a short script
okay it's an example python code 98
lines of code and right now you can look
at the mod line at the bottom it says
summation python so that means this is
right now you are looking at sub python
mod we just created you know in two
hours very simple okay so let's copy the
copy the file
so I don't want to mess with my script
so let's create a
new buffer paste it here save it as
XX dot p y okay
that we that you know we're gonna test
over here so you can see comments are
colored
uh strings are colored
now
single code stream is not colored let's
fix that okay let's fix this comments
and questions if you guys are watching
say hi okay love to see your comments
okay so single quote string is not
colored okay to fix that all we have to
do go back to our mod to fix that all we
have to do is the syntax table we need
to tell emacs that the apostrophe
character is
is part of the string Okay so
it's somewhere here okay so uh wait
so we need to set syntax table so you go
to the tutorial
syntax coloring so there is a section on
syntax table let's look
actually we can just do this and let's
just copy let me show you how to do it
so so you have to say is modify syntax
entry
of the scene table scene table is the
one you created by calling make syntax
table
okay
and then
okay then so we here the first argument
is a character now a character in emac
this is equivalent to a integer so in
e-max there's no dedicated dedicated
character type so a character is simply
your integer
of the character's Unicode code Point
okay now if you don't know what is the
Unicode code point
uh yeah let me let me plug in my um
sorry Unicode just search for Saudi
Unicode you can see this page Unicode
search and you go down scroll down
then you'll see Unicode for programmers
Okay click on that now here it will
teach you everything you want to know as
a programmer what is a Unicode you know
so start with Unicode Basics what's a
character set
you know what what he's uh encoding what
does it involve what is a utf-8 what is
code Point okay so a code point in short
is basically a ID
for a character so every character is
given an ID which is an integer so
that's what code Point means just think
about of it as an ID okay ID for each
and every character there's a ID so you
know so check out my Unicode
um tutorial
thank you in the
okay let's go to talk show and post the
post the link there so you guys uh
people can read it later
okay close that close that now
so back to syntax table you know we are
creating so here so in emac this a
character is just a integer so
so what is the integer for the
apostrophe so you can find out by
calling describe chart so you put the
cursor on the apostrophe and and code
describe charts so you can see in the
Ping window you see a code describe
chart so it pops up this window expanded
so you can see character apostrophe
displayed as apostrophe code Point 39 so
that is the ID 39 in hexadecimal is 27
okay so anyway 39 is the code point and
you can also find the name
apostrophe of the character okay so 39
so so all you can do or you can do here
the first argument is 39 that stands for
apostrophe okay and then the second
argument is what class of the syntax
table it is so in this case we want it
to be a string delimiter okay so go back
to the syntax table uh in the major mod
tutorial there is a syntax table
so uh character type yeah so here is a
detail about character data type in emac
this
essentially just like what we said
there's no dedicated character type but
any but characters are just integers
so
so okay character type then you go to
syntax table so now we want to look at
what is the
the code that stand for
um
string delimiter Okay so
like I mentioned before the character
the syntax table Concept in emac this is
a little bit complicated and difficult
to work with but anyway so we gonna just
skip around and uh
and string delimiter okay it's string
delimiter is represented by the code
double quote okay so you just say
uh you need the backslash
double quote okay
so that
okay so so here let's add a comment
make a
apostrophe us
stream
delimiter okay that's that's what this
line does okay now evaluate it now let's
go to our python code
let's copy it close it let's uh yeah so
we can open open it again
now let's type some single chord string
let's see if it works something
you see now it's colored just like the
double quote fantastic
okay so that that is
that is uh where is our code syntax
table that this line does it
okay so any comments questions or flamio
good morning
so we got the so what about triple let's
see let's try triple
okay triple also works you know the way
it works because it works because you
know triple is just like you know these
parties
quote you know anyway so we got
syntax coloring for the single quote too
fantastic
uh let's say okay let's say test equals
to
uh test a single quote okay let's just
add it something okay
X single quote
why single quote uh oh yeah you need a
single quote
and here let's do triple
single quote fantastic okay close it
okay now but let me show you another you
know
like before we said 39 is the ID for the
apostrophe
so in emac beasts
a integer is also stand for
uh a character
but it's confusing because integers are
integers but now it also stands for
characters so when is it represent an
integer when does it represent a
character
you know that's kind of a flaw of emac
beasts but anyway emac this provide a
alternative syntax to represent
characters so what you do is you say
question mark apostrophe so these two
lines are equivalent the question mark
followed by a character means
you know you want so so this part
evaluate to 39 actually
uh yes I have 381 uh tabs open in
Firefox yeah that's my habit the
workflow so almost all of these uh each
one of these uh my website I need to
somehow walk on steel uh yeah
so
uh you know I love I I must have
vertical tabs welcome tabs yeah so
anyway so let's go back so yeah so this
will also work evaluate it now let's
open last closed you see the single
crochet Works close it
open last closed you see
so you see so let me comment that out
you see these two lines are equivalent
okay
that's about
that part is about
the
syntax table and character type you know
if you read it you explain it yeah okay
we got this single quote coloring work
now next
now let's again review last time so we
did the so so
this part is syntax coloring
this part is syntax table
in particular they they color
strings and the common okay that's also
done then we created a brief table a
brief table is here so let's show how it
works so it's for example filter
it's open python file again
let's type filter
space Oh fantastic now I can just
you know
so you can so you see fantastic
let's go back close so you can you can
see this is a brief table and you can
add you know a hundred more you know all
the things you
use the most often so for example we
added if so let's open python code if
space fantastic
okay so that part so that's the abreve
table and all you have to do is just
Define a brief table here then
then in this part define derived mod you
just say
you know add a brief table okay
so we got a brief table now what what
else so we got this part is a brief
table okay
syntax table a brief table for
uh
for um
for templates okay then you got key
binding because in each mod you have
your own key
that's specific to the mod only so we
did add one key so we so you all you
have to do is to create a key map you
know python saw python mod map makes a
sparse key map that creates a key map
then in this key map
you just Define tab to call this command
python complete symbol okay so that is a
function we defined in the beginning so
here
so this function does completion keyword
completion you know very simple we
explained previously
so let's try
so for example in e in Python you have
con you have the keyword continue
finally
class method let's try some of them okay
open less closed okay let's see
c-o-n-t tab you see it pops up at the
bottom okay one one completion Choice
enter continue fantastic let's let's try
class tab okay now we got
three choices plus each subclass class
method let's Type M to make it unique
enter
enter class method fantastic okay
fantastic close close and do close so we
got
completion which is just 10 lines of
code that does confusion okay
and so you see so this is uh the
function sub python complete symbol then
then you add a key binding to it Tab Key
okay then in your Define mod all you
have to say is um
you know use local map that means key
map
okay
so we got we got a lot of things done
now
so what what is what else to do for a
python mod you know actually we are
pretty complete so open python file
again so I you know
all right there's one more thing I know
we need to do that is the indentation
you know in Python code
the indentation is kind of a headache
um
let's try if statement okay so sometimes
you need to indent more sometimes less
so but right now we got a problem
because our Tab Key when you press it it
does completion
you see it doesn't so there is actually
right now there's a problem there's no
way to indent unless you do Ctrl Q tab
you know Ctrl Q is a shortcut for
let's try describe key
control Q it calls quote okay Ctrl Q
course quote insert
so in emacs anywhere you can type Ctrl Q
then whatever you type the next
character will be inserted literally
okay this is useful as a general tip for
emacs using emacs
why is it useful because sometimes you
want to press enter you know especially
in mini buffer
you know sometimes you want to press
enter or tab you want to insert an enter
or tab character but in the mini buffer
when you press enter
it means you finished so you just exit
so that doesn't work so that's why this
code insert is uh very useful in emacs
to know
quote insert command which has the key
control Q okay so whenever you want to
insert some character literally
you just call quote insert first Ctrl Q
then you press whatever key so this is
very useful especially for you know
return or tab for example let's do Ctrl
Q return
oh that doesn't work because read you
know it actually insert a literal
literal line return the ASCII character
so but that's not what you want in emacs
line return is represented by Line Feed
as key
so so let's control Q
and the Line Feed is represented by
control
M no control uh
wait uh
Ctrl l no
uh Line Feed is represented by let's try
again Ctrl Q
control
M no not m
let's try again Ctrl Q control F no not
f
what
from the you know you know this is this
is a bit confusing and complex
let's go to ASCII characters so if you
are a programmer you know this
this is actually a very important thing
to know eventually if you are a
programmer for you know in your first
two three years you may not know as he
character as well but if you keep
programming you have to know this well
okay so if you don't know yet read up on
this page just search for
sardi.info as key characters
so ASCII characters uh
127 characters okay that you know from
40 50 years ago that is essential okay
so you need to know you need to
understand what's the NC characters
especially these
unprintable ASCII characters no you know
so for example like uh so for example
uh
horizontal tab that's the Tab Key you
know it's a bit confusing because you
have the Tab Key you also have the tab
character so anyway
you know this character horizontal tab
ASCII number nine represents a tab
character and for line return it's more
complex you have Line Feed you have form
feed then you have carriage return so
when you see those M we showed before
hold on a second so let's paste this
link to talk show
okay so okay close it and close it okay
close it
you see when you see that correct M that
is actually the carriage return so if we
want a uh line v j oh how can I possibly
forget okay so if you actually want the
line return in emacs you call okay let
me show you
Ctrl Q for code insert now
Ctrl J is a line return e Max
buffers use to represent the new line
now in different operating systems you
know you may be different so
anyway that's a digression
Xin Yang Hao Nihao young Putin hey
Justin genius
fantastic great to see you
uh so okay so we so we are talking about
the
the general quote
insert okay yeah so we are talking about
the indentation in Python so right now
we have no way to indent because
whenever we press tab it becomes
completion
how
you know because we said the key to have
to do that so how do you fix that okay
here is what here you know different
major mod have a different approach you
know different major mod depending on
the language and depending on who coded
usually they have a variety of approach
you know
so for me
the way I want to solve this problem is
that if the cruiser let's open the
python file if the cruiser is before a
word okay then you should do completion
you then you should do indentation okay
if the cursor is after
some word then when you press tab it
should be completion okay that's that's
how I
solve the problem okay so if the cruiser
is before
any character I mean before if anything
before the cruiser is empty then we when
you press tab it should do indentation
okay so let's do that
so what we need to do is we write a new
command new command here
and that command will be called uh
python
um
indent or complete okay so let's copy
and paste it here let's name it
some python
indent
or complete okay
okay that's a new function so let's
remove all these
so
to
indentation or completion
uh Okay so
if Cruiser
is after a word
call
down complete symbol
okay
else
to indent okay something like that
okay version today's date
so first thing we need to so we're gonna
write this command Okay so first thing
we need to do is to check whether there
is something before closer
okay if the character before Cruiser is
a space or a tab
or
or a new line a like the return
character then you want to do
indentation okay so check the character
okay
so how do you check the character so you
want to find the character before it so
you can there's a command before char
no
chart before
let's see I forgot what's her name
Char before yeah they are Char before so
before is a building emac lisp
function
uh
so it Returns the character before the
cruiser okay Crazy Frog I mean I've lost
a lot of passion for a lot of things
these days
you have to drink more tea or power
drink go
okay beef Char before Returns the
character so so describe function you
can read the documentation return the
character in current buffer preceding
position
purse okay position is the integer that
represents the current cursor position
diff it defaults to the current per se
Cruiser position here so you don't need
any
so actually so let's create a variable
let
uh
Ken cha okay so
the value of kancha will be
Char before
okay
okay we don't need the option okay
there
so now
check if the current charge is any of
the space okay if
Concha
equal
let's see if equal Works uh
it's test equal three equals EQ you know
in E Max there's a lot equality
functions test functions to test
equality some works are integer some
works on string you know so that's why
we have to test it so a character
remember is an integer so equal will
work EQ
equals to uh now what space Oh God
now you need to know what's the integer
for space so
go to a space move closer to a space and
call describe char
so let's show the Ping window so you can
see we call it describe chart
so space is 32 I remember I memorized by
I memorized by heart so if
or
if that character is 32 which means
space or
or that character is a tab so what is uh
what is uh ID for tab I forgot
Ctrl Q
tab okay now we got the tab describe
chart so a tab is nine that's right I
forgot how can I
so if it's a space or it's a tab or it's
a new line so what's a new line move the
cursor to a new line character describe
char
a new line is 10 okay
so let's add another 10.
okay so if it's you know if if the
character before closer is a space or a
tab or a line return then
then do indent okay then do indent
else
just
call AD function
so how do you call a function apply
function apply
okay what is the Syntax for apply
apply function rest arguments Okay so
apply
function name
and no argument be quiet okay so now
that's our function now predify the code
fantastic okay now we need to do the
indent part so how do you do indent
let's just say insert the tab character
okay
insert tab character is stream slash T
backslash t
okay so that is
pretty much it so python indent or
complete
okay so if the character before Cruiser
is a space tab or line return then just
insert a tab otherwise do completion
fantastic
now
now let's go to the key binding part of
our code key binding here
now we want to reassign the tab
character to
uh hold on a second let's
let's copy that and paste it here we
want to reassign it to this function
okay
not that okay
predify the code fantastic okay
now we already either the buffer let's
see if it works if other buffer
okay
and now go to the python page okay open
last closed okay
now let's try
press Tab Key you see now our Cruiser is
not our word so when we press tab it
should insert the tab first of all let's
show y space so
okay so you can see
uh you know turn on white space smart
you can see the white space characters
okay now press tab do it fantastic do it
fantastic do it fantastic
do it fantastic now let's put the
put a closer after a word now press tab
long type arguments list P sub python
complete symbol okay so when you try to
complete
uh you got an error so
why is that
so let's go back to the code
so he's trying to complete okay apply
apply a function now
why is it
campaigning
so
why is it let's look up documentation
Define function apply core function with
remaining arcs okay rest arguments
foreign
so let's look at the error messages
again so go to the messages buffer
your own type argument so it wants a
list
but it got a sub python complete symbol
so the apply
the program or the program
the program part okay so
this part
why is it wrong I don't understand
uh you don't need to you don't you know
I don't understand but I know how to do
it you can just all you have to do is
just
say that okay you don't need to co-apply
Common out
but
I rarely use Supply I don't I don't see
why it shouldn't work but anyway this
will work okay
eval the function
go to the python page okay now press tab
do it fantastic
so let's say I want class method okay
classmate enter fantastic
okay
I think actually we have completed
is there anything else to do of course
there are but however those are just
more details more uh let's close close
close
go back yeah so I think
at this point our package uh major mod
is
fairly complete
so let's review a little bit okay so we
got keyword completion okay so this
section two functions keyword completion
and indent
so we don't actually have any extra
commands
now this section commands is supposed to
be you know your mod may have
you know may have a lot of other
features so if you're gonna add them you
know you can add it here
so go to the beginning Okay so
so yeah so at today's date this is a new
update
so keyword completion and the indent
okay then we got syntax coloring for the
keywords in function names this part
needs improvements because you need to
gather
all the Python's function names possibly
including all the building Library names
building libraries function names that's
that would be super helpful but that but
this part that takes a lot of time you
know you have to dive into each package
find out their function names
but anyway the skeleton the structure is
like this okay so all you have to do is
you know just add more
variables okay so keyword complaint
completion indentation then syntax
coloring
then syntax table
mostly for stream
delimiter characters
and for common characters okay that's a
syntax table then a brief table this
allows
allowed us to have template
functionality okay and then key binding
yeah key binding for the major mod right
now we basically only have one
custom key Tab Key okay it does either
completion or indent okay and finally
here is the
defining the mod define derived mod so
simple
and these two lines set local common
start common end is for
uh
is for creating your own common command
you know on this page so for example
let's go to python so you can press the
key to comment out or uncommon you know
that's all you have to do these two
lines and there is synags table there is
fun lock defaults for syntax coloring
there is use local map that's a key map
and set up the brief table you know
fantastic
okay
we oh we have six people watching so
anything else anything else you guys
like to so I think that's it so today is
55 minutes fantastic and we shutting
down
in three minutes okay
if you like my stuff pay me okay
you know I've been doing open source for
15 or 20 years
you know you don't get much pay so if
you like my stuff
it would be good if you pay donate
you know a bug
a cup of coffee or dinner or something
anything else that's it okay now
okay you can also buy my emacs tutorial
of course you know you can you know
I have a pretty popular emacs tutorial
okay so now yeah is there anything else
python mod fantastic you know I looked I
I'm writing this mod for myself too
because you know I've been coding emac
this for now for 15 years so it it is
actually easier for me to create a
hormone from scratch then to look at and
modify the existing code for example
let's look at look up the default python
mod so describe function python Dash mod
okay here is the documentation for the
building emacs Max python mod okay press
tab to enter to jump into the source
code you know 5
000 lines of code
five thousand and seven hundred lines of
code
this one is written by Fabian e Galina
fantastic okay and he's got a GitHub
let's go to it
you know it's great but
um you know since I have experience I
can you know I can I can now create my
own mod easier
pretty easy for me and uh suitable for
my own code
uh of course then you can also use
default
you know deforma they they have a lot of
features I don't use you know I don't
you know or I don't like their behavior
and so on so anyway so emacs you know
has a lot of for example you drop to
diet you can see you have prog mod you
have PS mod this is for post script I
think
let's see uh for the post script
language then you have python mod you
have Ruby mod you know you have scheme
this mod you have shell script mod you
have similar
simula mod for similar language very
interesting
adopted by ESR oh hence Eric Erickson I
think I know this guy
uh so so so you know you have similar 87
you know a programming language very
interesting so all these smart b.oding
you can you know it's it's very useful
you can look up you know their code that
will help you learn emac this when you
are stuck for example
when writing your own mods this SQL mod
is TCL model let's see TCR Tommy John
trummy is also a a kind of popular old
emac baseball
hacker okay don't you know
I know many I'm familiar with many of
these people because you know I've been
in the emacs community for 20 years you
know getting old Tony is uh old
uh lisp hacker okay by old mean meaning
they have a lot of experience you know
so um you know for 20 or more years Tom
told me ESR for 30 30 years or 40 even
so scheme mod is written by Bill Rosas
okay I don't know who he is
and adopted by Dave love okay I think
I've I heard of Dave love
anyway so yeah it's interesting you can
look at you know the
uh default you know emacs mods to learn
stuff how they do things
Okay so
that's it no comments okay uh no
comments
okay thank you guys for watching bye
for you Chinese out there happy New Year
New Year so this is I think it's a
fantastic New Year
and uh
lots of happening in the world right now
you know
in particular
some highlights in
2023 the artificial intelligence
technology is really getting I would say
starting this year it's getting
really really incredible
uh Hey rasu so artificial intelligence
is truly getting incredible and also
there's a lot of inherent you know you
don't know you don't know we don't know
what will happen
unpredictable AI okay so that's one
thing the other thing is you know global
politics USA versus China
and the current Ukraine war and we don't
know what what is going to happen you
know it's not very good
so um yeah we don't know so
bye guys