hello guys sorry I'm late this is a talk
show today is March 24th 2019 and today
we're going to talk about keyboards I'm
five minutes late so we're gonna talk
about keyboards keyboards and mouse and
related topics so today's topic is going
to be let's go through my list of topics
so talk show in browser so these are the
topics I'm going to talk about and okay
first of all I need to clean the
messages here hi guys
type in the message messages chat to let
me know so today is 24th and the topic
is going to be let's copy the topic copy
switch back to Google Google hi Guys hi
Guys hi guys
type in the chat top chat any comment
question I'll talk about it question
comment question or your opinion okay so
and there's one more thing to do
then we'll begin I'm doing a little
buffer for those coming into the show so
here's the topics you will see it in the
video info box below there it is
and the today is 24th right
okay so you got three guys here good
evening
okay so let's start let me just begin
then let's go to break browser I'm going
to show I'm going to begin by going
through my keyboard blog sorry
keyboard and I'm going to give you a
introduction of the website so there are
lots of things I love keyboards I've
been studying keyboards for like 15
years various topics related to keyboard
keyboard keybinding keyboard design key
switch mechanisms some of the
electronics how they work the operating
system software to remap keys how they
work and efficiency of layouts for
example quality versus work versus Co
mag and so on yeah quite a few and
typing habits yeah so let's begin with
the let me just give you a walkthrough
then now again keep the comment type
something okay hi guys
you know tell me something so I know you
know where I'm going you know if I am
going into the direction you like if you
want me to cover some other things just
say something in the Box any you can say
anything you know that's it like this is
a chat this is a chat show okay so this
is my website you know sake Bo blog I
blog about keyboard like every day
almost every day keyboards and mouse
loops how so that date well that that
that one is the gooseneck these days
they have the gooseneck for you know
holding iPad iPhone and stuff let's turn
JavaScript
super-slow a little bit slow anyway this
device is good gooseneck Hey great to
see you again no man break the Louvre
how's your Sunday so he said since you
dislike latech have you ever had I need
to write mathematics using your computer
yes of course I need to do that all the
time so if so how do you like to write
math on a computer if you do not use
latech that's a hard question actually I
don't have the answer I mean I've been
seeking for the answer for you know the
past 20 years there is no good answer so
normal say speaking of keyboards I order
the Kinesis - recently great Kinesis
advantage - that's what I use
so yeah about the math let me talk about
that a little bit yeah so that's a huge
topic so I can talk about that for an
hour but essentially yeah that's gonna
be a big topic why don't we let me talk
about keyboard first then you know maybe
after 30 minutes then we switch to that
subject so you know remind me okay break
break the loop you know if it's you know
discover you know some keyboard first
because I was you know I told people
that we're gonna talk about keyboard so
anyway so this is my keyboard side so
you have economic keyboards you I
suffered from typing problems since 2006
2006 yes that's why I was using a laptop
everyday
exclusively for 2 years that's my first
RS I repaired it repetitive strain
injury that's when I switched to a
Microsoft natural keyboard which is not
this one but the one the the
but actually I have this one okay so
that's not a history of using keyboard
but anyway so in 2006 I was typing a lap
on a laptop every day for two years and
I got hand problems they I switched it
to this one I don't like the Oh gonna
make keyboards I mean I've been typing
for 15 years before since 1990 so I
didn't like the I've seen this I didn't
like it because the you know it's funny
they put the P here and they put a six
on the left hand side the six should be
on the right hand side but anyway I
didn't like it because I was using Emacs
and I always use the right hand to press
this key this key is P but on Barclay oh
it's X so it was my habit to use my left
hand to hold the control key down and
use my right hand to press the X on a
normal keyboard so I didn't like this
anyways so yes but but because I had
hand problems since 2006 I forced myself
to you know use this keyboard and once I
got used to it you know after to a month
or two I now you know I must have you
know ergonomic keyboard is a must have
when you type on a straight keyboard
again like we think within a minute you
feel pain and you know in this keyboard
I also bought I used this one so so this
one I used for three years
the other one I used for something like
four years this one so okay so I can
actually go into a history of keep what
keyboards I've used you know but let's
get back to on the you know on my on my
keyboard blog site okay so keyboard
okay yeah let's talk about maths maybe
later on because you know maybe so III
have an Norman says I an older version
of MAS natural keyboard not mechanical
mushy yeah exactly mushy robot on
switches
yeah so okay so let me just quickly then
quickly go over the what I have here so
keep your guide
ergonomic keyboard so this section is
all the ergonomic keyboard I reviewed
now I don't have all of them I actually
only have like four or five keyboards so
I have this one I have this one and I
have this one and I have this one so
that's one two three four and I had this
one I threw it away because the
Microsoft natural keyboard this this
particular one four thousand the
spacebar it's got a very bad problem of
the Steve spacebar the spacebar is very
heavy very stiff and that's causing me
problems after three years so after
three years I switched back to to the
older that the previous model this one
is better I mean so keyboard is funny
you know with repetitive strain injuries
you cannot exactly tell for example so
so they have this model first you know
the natural multimedia keyboard then
they have this model which has actually
more curves you know so it's like
technically it's more improved because
they have more curves and but actually
it is on this keyboard I developed two
issues two problems that that cost me
hand pen you know I don't it's not
exactly pen but I mean so RSI is very
complicated issue repetitive strain
injury first first symptom is some kind
of discomfort like right now I have
discomfort over here that's the first
thing symptom then you feel numbness
sometimes it's I mean for different
people it's different things sometimes
it's up for some people it's this finger
or suppose some people it's a knuckles
here I mean there are stories on the web
I can like point you out like yes I mean
like you know but I I want you know like
there's so many things I can point to
but anyway let me get for you know so I
want to you know keep on track instead
of going over the face so so for many
people it's different symptoms
but anyway so in different places
sometimes it's a wrist over here
so for some people it's a finger some
people is a knuckle some people it's a
thumb and so and and for me currently
right now it's over here
I mean it's again this is a issue is
hard to describe it's like when you go
to a doctor the doctor says so okay
what's your what's wrong and it's it's
hard to describe exactly the pinpoint
you know so that's why you know and
technically is I is not completely
understood by you know by the sciences I
mean there's no we don't we don't
understand exactly what caused it
hundred percent I mean for sure you know
you type too much or you play tennis
every day or you play piano you know you
get problems guitar you you get RSI you
know problems but but we don't really
know exactly what's going on 100 percent
say and often also the other thing is
that when you visit doctors I mean many
people would have you know many
programmers you know I have stories from
programmers all the time and also you
can see them on reddit or hacker news
almost every month you search for Emacs
pinky or you search for keyboard RSI you
know you keep watching it it'll happen
every month then people will talk about
it what they did you know and then then
there's a link to other websites and you
know you'll see them also stack over
news you know you're just such
you know looking for keywords like Emacs
pinky keyboard hand pain you know you'll
see them almost every month so and some
of the stories are horrible stories I
mean you are programmer you are living
live Lee who depends on typing a lot and
if you're if you have hand pain you
cannot type anymore and you know it's
very bad for your career but this stays
of course you have voice dictation which
is very good today actually it helps
actually we can do a voice voice
dictation demo on the Mac that's I did
that in few months ago in a video it's
very fun I mean but anyway so so yeah so
many issues but let me yeah let me
quickly get over the the topics like
what I have here hi Matthews so here is
a list of ergonomic keyboards my
recommendations typically I go like I've
I have heavy interest in these things
keyboards you know in the beginning it's
like I want to buy a keyboard
maybe because hanpan or because you know
I need a new keyboard
you know my keyboard is old then you
should you window shop you know online
you'll look at Amazon you read the
reviews you know but it's undecided so
tomorrow you you read more reviews and
the still undecided this undecided after
month you keep reading you know so after
I have to fight after year I still
didn't have the you know I did invite
the keyboard you know but I've read
ordered all the articles like out there
so that's how that's kind of that's kind
of also part of the reason how I began
to write all these keyboards you know
because part of the reason is like I'm
the personality I like to gather
information I don't make decisions
easily that's kind of like a flaw
actually so you know III gather
information
you know just exactly which is better
okay they they differ by ten dollars
only ten dollars but but you know so you
geek you know so I'm not still decided
you know so look at every aspect so so
anyway so here's a bunch of ergonomic
keyboard and here is I have a list of PC
keyboards PC keyboards you know which is
the most popular you know okay and here
we have fun keyboards these are kind of
exotic keyboards or or novelty keyboards
for example this one it lights up a very
expensive though it's like few hundred
dollars each one is actually a liquid
crystal display or some kind of you know
it's it can do animations it can show it
can actually show a small movie like you
know so each one you know they take they
you know in the beginning like around
2001 this is the first one they come up
you know it's you know it's on slash dot
which is a new news for nerds website
it's like hacker news back in 2001 it's
a first website of that kind and this
one was you know the the first one that
says we're gonna make these you know
each each key is actually a little TV
and when it come it it didn't come out
after like five years or something but
when when faint finally come out the
price is like $2,000 $2,600 okay there's
a video let's just see if I can watch
the video
but but anyway this is like back then
today you have other technologies to
have display on each key and and is
cheaper like ePaper let's show it again
yeah so here's a video you can see the
first version of the but anyway so a
bunch of fun keyboards hey web dawg
good morning hey Matthews I ordered an O
go ducks easy that's great so you also
have wooden keyboards you know what's
interesting is like in China all the
keyboards or any electronic devices it's
like six times cheaper you know in China
it's quite amazing not even six times
the yeah but in general I give
everything you buy is like six six times
cheaper and they are not wood wooden
keyboards they sell in China too so
anyway this page is just collection of
funky things like there are people this
guy he's got a 1000 function keys a
power station battle station you know so
for this guy whatever you want to do is
just one press one key you know you
press one key and something is done and
so they are quite several of these
figures so for example this guy he's got
now this this keyboard is made by matron
the company who also makes me the matron
keyboard it's the design is originally
for those disabled like you know they
don't like they only have one hand or
they have you know difficulties
with their fingers and so on anyway this
guy you know put two got two of them
together hit another one in the middle
so this is supposed to be a single
handed keyboard so just on on the right
side it you have enough keys to for all
the letters that's the intended
operational use yeah but this guy is
funny he's on Twitter by the way he's
he's this guy he I'm you know his friend
David Cole and he's so much into
keyboards too you know so he got all
these this oh these are his photos I
think yeah I think all of them yeah and
this one-handed keyboard the motor on
keyboards they are not cheap like I
don't know how much is this one but I
suppose it's at least probably 400 or
more you know at least 300 I would say
you know motor for some reason their
keyboard this this this is motor oh yeah
I'm going to show you some videos as
well but but you can see you know I have
a Kinesis let's see if I can do this
so I have a connects Kinesis keyboard
here which is like yeah you can see it
which is like you know this one that's
what I have
Clarence's keyboard I put my hand here
actually you know if you want to I did a
video of Kinesis keyboard and and a
couple of my other keyboards it's on
YouTube so you can just go to my YouTube
channel and you see it so funky boards
keypads
keypads these are you know programmable
key pads now programmable cube heads are
critical because because you know not
normally you have to use ctrl C to copy
so V to paste and so on but with a
programmable keyboard you just press one
key like that's what I'm doing now for
example let me see what I want to do so
so web dog says those one hand the
keyboard another level whoa hi wall wall
says motrin is my dream keyboard yeah I
think more trans great but motrin is
very expensive analysis is god-tier but
looks pretty bad Canisius looks pretty
bad why because of the because it's
heart-shaped so you see here we have
mantra and Kinesis the motrin looks
bigger but actually they are the same
size I mean the the motor on just look
you know exactly the same size as
Kinesis but you can for example you can
compare the pictures here this is
someone someone's picture so this key
both of these are my my keyboards so
this is a Kinesis keyboard this is a
normal keyboard on on top of it so you
can see they have actually about the
same width but however you know with a
standard keyboard you put your hands you
know on the letters side when you want
to reach the mouse you have to jump over
the arrow keys and number number pad but
with Kinesis it's like you know it's
right behind my hand you know like you
know I you know it's right here I don't
have to jump so you know because a lot
of people buying Kinesis you you know a
lot of people didn't like doesn't like
the you know the the number pad you know
that that's a huge gap between your
keyboard and mouse yeah actually I did
actually it let's get back to let me
quickly go over this topic because then
we can actually focus on something some
specific thing we can talk about so
anyway fun keyboard is just a bunch of
funky once this program I'll keep had
it's actually with display and this is
very good this is cheap this is I think
120 or 150 something like that you go to
Amazon you check it out and each key is
a little TV and this is so this is a
program of programmable keypad so you
can you know you can set it to Firefox
Google Chrome Emacs or terminal
you know Photoshop or whatever just
press a single key that's what I'm doing
that that's what I do right now because
you know you see I I don't have a
programmable key keypad like right now
but I have let me show you you see the
you see that number pad this this is
actually just a normal number pad
however however I'm using a software you
know Mac OS software code called this
name let's go to here
yeah carabiner so I'm using carabiner to
program the number pad key so that some
lab for example I I you know so what I
have copy cut paste let's see let me
show you
okay so here so this is coffee copy hey
copy cut paste no no way
select all select your copy paste pack
browser forward browser previous page
next page previous tab next tab this is
increased font size decrease font size
this is close window this is close
window one of them is reopen last closed
by mistake you know if I close by
mistake I can just press a key reopen as
close so for example I can do it right
now you know oh I just closed
window I didn't want to cause that's was
the oh yeah that was the photo booth so
anyway so if I go here now you can see
okay close window reopen yeah we opened
is this one and refresh is this one
refresh for example I go down refresh
anyway so everything is one key one
single single key operation so that way
is good for your hand health you don't
have to hold down ctrl keys and stuff
but some people will say oh but it's
much slower well it's it technically
it's slower but long turn if you really
type a lot you know like I sit in front
of computer almost like 10 hours a day
for past 10 years and every day and you
know if you type a lot then that's
something you want to consider you don't
want you you you want single key
operations never hold down ctrl alt you
know
to do that okay so so the fun keyboard
and keypads and this this section is to
itself keyboards now they are like
thousands of do itself keyboards these
keyboards are like you go to a website
you buy the components for example this
one you you buy the components and you
have to assemble it yourself you know
you know the electronics the keys you
have to use a soldiering so you have to
spend like half a get half a day to
assemble it so here's a video you can
see typing on that keyboard and you know
so on so each one of these so this this
one is like Kinesis is actually I tried
this in a keyboard Meetup so they have a
keyboard meetup in bay area over here
and like every year they also have that
in other cities I know this one I think
in New York I mean major cities usually
you have it know if you are interested
if you are interested you go to reddit
are mechanical keyboard and you can see
all the groups you know the fans
keyboard fans and people they talk about
that and also they announce meetups over
there oh you can ask people you know
people will tell you and they have in
other countries as well I know they are
in Japan I know they are in Australia
you know so break loops at the say it
says the customer number pad is good
idea like that yeah and so if you like
that I have like tutorials showing you
how to do that how to do how to program
that so for example if you go to keypads
so I mean the best solution if you want
you know single function keys the best
solution is actually just buy a
programmable keypad so I here on this
page at least all the
options you can buy all these are good
ones
all these are good ones so these are
program programmable keypads you know
they they are they vary from like cheap
like thirty dollars to two you know over
a hundred dollars you know like this one
this one is also you know with the TV
screens each one is a little TV screen
and they they've feature different they
are programmable programmability differ
a little bit
for example anyway I might talk about
that later but so all these programmable
keyboards so that's the best one you
want to get that why because when you
have a programmable keyboard you program
the keys one shot one time okay and it's
it's burned into the memory so it's part
of the hardware and also when you press
a key for example if you set one of the
keys to control see you first it you
know just send out control C by hardware
you know it the electronic store to the
USB but if you are using your operating
system to program the keys for example I
say the key to to control C that's not
direct that goes through the OS 9 OS the
key translation then it sends to your
app that always have glitches like it
doesn't matter it's on Linux on Windows
or Mac they always have problems like
sometimes it doesn't work or in some
applications it doesn't work things like
that but the firmware you know these
programmable keypads with a memory in
you know on them it always works you
know you know 100% because the keyboard
is actually sending the correct signal
so that is why you want you want the
actual program about keypads
you know keyboards with the memory on
them also it's important you want to
make sure they have the memory on them
like some gaming keyboards you know they
are programmable keyboards for such as
those made by razor razor they
they require to install their cloud
software you know you if you don't you
know have a counter you don't have
connection to Internet all your
programmable keys doesn't work it
doesn't work anymore
so with programmable keypads and with
memory on them you can you know plug it
in go to your office and forgetting and
walk right away as you programmed it so
that's why programmable keypads are the
best the best choice now of course they
are more expensive but if you don't want
to spend them for example this one made
by razor razor so it it looks great
right you know you got you know this
open re but it's it's it's crap you know
they the razor company in some cases
they intentionally remove the memory
remove that from where they want to you
they want you to install their app like
razor they have the you know fancy world
synapse in the register account so you
are always connected to their cloud you
know they and they also of course they
can monitor what you do so don't never
buys anything made by razor that's my
recommendation never buy anything made
by razor ok so if you don't want to
spend that much okay here's a big one if
you don't want to spend that much money
on a programmable keypad then you buy a
numeric keypad now if you have a normal
standard keyboard you know usually
there's an American keypad now for many
people you don't use that but actually
that's a very good thing because you can
program those keys on your you know
normal standard keyboard and and use
that as a you know single press key for
copy paste you know switch to Emacs or
whatever just present one-time no switch
windows switch windows switch tabs
switch any application you can program
it so so so on Windows and Mac they're
going to show you so so if you go to
he key how to this tab click it open it
this page is about how to program your
keyboard using the operating system
software so you have one for Microsoft
Windows basically the best one is
autohotkey just install that you know I
have a tutorial here you can look into
so all the hard keys lets you it has
lots of features
Aloha key language is pretty lousy but
you know you know buddy it's very useful
so here are all the tips about key
shortcuts keyboards key binding on
Windows then I have a bunch of articles
on Linux you know Linux is more
complicated but anyway I have tutorials
on how to we might remap keys and so on
and there's a bunch of our Mac now
basically on the Mac the one you want to
use is carabiner so I have a list of
tools here of course you know on a Mac
Mac OS you have building feature to let
you swap caps lock or control option
command keys that's building then
carabiner is basically the most popular
and very powerful software today then
they are a bunch of others app launcher
is another one there's a bunch of others
you know I've been using a Mac since
1991 and I've been monitoring you know
for for much of the past 20 years side
or 30 years I know almost every key
application on the Mac you know in the
very beginning in the 1990s the best one
is called I don't know if I still have
that listed here anymore but quick key
yeah that one is called quick key qu IC
ke y
and that was the earliest one and the
best one they still sell that I think
anyway here's a bunch of tools you can
you know I heard good things about them
because otherwise I wouldn't put it here
so bunch of tools for automation you
know key bindings launching apps
typing today's state you know typing
abbreviations you can all program it so
that's the key how-to section then
there's about Emacs you know for Emacs
then I you know it's a it's a another
word by itself you know I have all these
tutorials you can learn how to reset
keys on Emacs and some mouse mouse in
tips and also they are software for
logging your keystrokes you might want
to try to install that especially if you
are heavy keyboard users because once
you know what you know you got the
actual data about what Keys you press
the most you know what should could you
press the most you can actually learn
you know if you have hand pain for
example you can start to design okay you
know I want you know you can see maybe
you can you might see okay this is a
shortcut I press it most of the time all
the time and it's very hard to press so
you want to eliminate that you know for
example you're signing a single key to
do that shortcut so here's a bunch of
keylogging software so back to the the
number pad so get the program about key
first of all get a programmable keyboard
okay now when you get a programmable
keyboard there's economic ones or you
can get non-economic ones now which to
choose that's up to you of course but I
would recommend basically if you type a
lot or you have hanpan or if you use
Emacs then I highly recommend you get an
ergonomic one
okay but in any case you want to get a
programmable keyboard okay you want to
get a programmable keyboard with onboard
memory you know I gave the rig reason
why before because you know it's direct
and it's on the memory you can plug it
in at home at office your walk as the
way you program the keys for example all
these here's the list of programmable
keyboards with onboard memory over them
and and you know so any of these
keyboard you can you know you can say
the key to press ctrl C if you want
which is good because in this case for
example for example on my Kinesis right
now let me show you now Kinesis also has
the on-the-fly
programmable feature that means I don't
have to actually you know launch some
software application to program the keys
if I want to reprogram the keys I can
just press one of the these keys and and
start to set a key but I want I want to
show you this let me see if I can do
this
you see I'm going to press this key
single key what that key will do is
switch me to the last application okay I
guess I need a white hand go camera but
then he said okay watch I'm not sure you
can see that do you see that kind of
basically it switched that he switched
me to the last window and it works
because because the keyboard is a
programmable keyboard so I have that key
set to it's actually doing when I press
like he is actually doing command tab so
you see in my various videos you never
you have never seen me press this have
you ever seen me please come up you
never see it because I never use it
why do I never use it because
because these switch application
shortcut is very inefficient first of
all it's a key combination you have to
hold down control or command you know
then you press the tab then you have to
look like which is the one I want you
know that takes some brain cycle you
know that takes some brain cycle when
you do that you know it's it's not good
in general because it drains your brain
energy then you have to you know press
the tab and decide which one you know so
that's not good then you have to release
it then you know the instant you rather
want you know a single key like right
now like monkey monkey monkey monkey
if I if I want to switch to Emacs I also
press one key I don't have the key right
now for that key because well for
reasons well because I the function keys
is too tiny and all my keypad keys are
used up so I do not have one single key
to go to Emacs I used to have like one
single key just get me to Emacs one
single key get me to a specific browser
like Chrome another key came into
Firefox and so on but I'm out of keys so
I need more yeah I need to get more I
need to get a real programmable keypad
you know right now I just only have this
number keypad so let's let's check some
of the comments requiring a cloud
service to use a keyboard is laughable
yeah razor is doing that very very bad
because razor market to cameras you know
and came on you know a lot of them for
you know young people they don't know
much they are going after the cool stuff
whatever is cool what is whatever is
popular
what is whatever is used by celebrities
you know like the gaming champions you
know they pay the gaming champions to
show to take photos with your keyboard
of course you know so yeah so that's the
razor
the Apple Magic Trackpad is very popular
in Silicon Valley companies but I prefer
a mouse myself yeah yeah yeah big the
roof yeah quick keys it get back to 80s
well
oh well no man I didn't know that I
started to use it in 1991 basically 1981
yeah maybe it's well I can't say for
sure so yeah but anyway I started to use
in 1991 that was superb you know it's
like well anyway Mac in general you know
Mac design is really good you know even
back in the 1990's especially in the
1990s Mac design because back then most
windows are you know half of the wind
you know they are still using toss and
command command line you know you don't
have graphics actually you know it is
the Mac that introduced that to the you
know white population then you have
Windows 3 windows 95 you started to have
graphics then stuffed so okay so do
itself keyboards there are so many
varieties now because you know I almost
like basically I stopped obtaining this
page its magnify because you know
because they are in this I mean
basically all the major key design
shapes are already out there and you
know different people can still create
minor variations but it's almost the
same you know like if you look at this
one this one this one this one you know
it's like they all like almost the same
but you know but those but but this is
important okay
even though if two of them look the same
for example this one in this one ergo -
versus fortitude for example
when turkey went to keyboards they
looked like almost the same but actually
a tiny difference in placement keys
actually affect whether possibly you
might develop you know hand pen actually
that happened to me you know with an
example of Microsoft natural keyboard
you know the two versions versus the
Microsoft natural 4000 you know I never
had a problem on the natural keyboard
but the the natural demand the Microsoft
4000 came out and it looks you know in
every way it's improved you know more
curves and more shapes so I switched
that then I know then I one day you know
I got pain you know I got pain that was
the this pin and you know when and I
didn't know what what happened you know
when you have pain like that it's it's a
very horrifying like one day you know I
remember like one day I woke up in
morning ok I had you know I had hand
hand discomfort you know in that during
that those weeks but one day I just wake
up without getting into the keyboard yet
I felt you know a tingling it was my
left hand I think you know it's just
like tingling like a sensation that just
goes over you know when I just woke up
and that was very scary I mean it's not
like funny tingling you know you know it
was and I know something is wrong you
know something is wrong because you know
I'm feeling a lot discomfort you know
because you know if you can type anymore
that's the end you know so I was you
know during that time this this is this
is like around 2009 you know since 2006
when I started first have discomfort
then every like every two years it
happened again you know on something
else you know it just like almost
unpredictable every two years you know
two or three years old you know
there's something else happening you
know doing a period you know because
when when I finish it you know you know
and I discovered what's the problem and
I thought oh I just changed the keyboard
now it's all good yeah it's good it's
good for a year and to paint sudden he
says something else take like magical
appearing from nowhere something
happened
so anyway every like two or three three
maybe three years I had some issues like
right now I have the issue of my left
arm just over here now each time this
currents you know this episode you know
about happens you don't know exactly
what's causing it for me for my personal
case again it's very different for each
person you know it depends on your
health depends on your you know maybe
body weight it depends on you know what
your inheritance your you know so
everyone is different but for me like
every three years the problem appears to
be different I mean it's not something
we relapse you know happen again it's
not like it's not that and because you
know I'm also I've been studying
keyboards you know since I've been
reading keyboard since 1991 a lot you
know I read I went to the library when
there's no internet I went to the
library I read about the wall rack
layout you know the history you know
stuff and I switched to varrock since
1994 purely for the reason of you know
my pursuit of efficiency you know I have
a obsession towards efficiency because
they're so since I learned about Warrick
I cannot stand quoting anymore but I
switched not because I had some hand
problems no I never had any problems
until 2005 2006 that that's when I was
typing on a Apple laptop all day you
know for like several hours a day for
two years exclusively because that's why
I was living in my car
in those years so that's when I had a
hand pain
but I didn't have hand problems the 15
years prior before that you know I'm
typing every day you know I didn't have
problems so anyway so since 2006 I had
problems recurring problems you know the
hand issues discomfort every two or
three years but each time it seems to me
the the reason that causes cost cost it
is different and each time when this
happens like when I have discomfort you
try to find out what exactly is a cause
again you know like there's no one cause
like each person is different and for me
each occurrence of the hand discomfort
is also different you know each
occurrence is different and also in
general stress we we are worse on it if
you have stress whatever stress wherever
stress come from maybe at work at home
my family or whatever stress also will
make it worse
like when if I have a hand pain and if
I'm having a situation that's stressful
you'll become you know more painful it's
so it's it's it's like the psychology
you know the your mind has a lot to do
with it too I mean although we don't as
you know the science don't know exactly
you know like some people I mean there
is definitely a connection of body and
mind the way you think oh you know it
can affect your physical wellness for
example the placebo effect you know
there is we so far you know we don't
understand exactly why it works but it
does works sometimes for you know in in
our cases but we don't know why we don't
exactly know why and also another thing
I want to mention like when you have
when you read if you have hand
discomfort and when you read online
there are some there are some websites
that suggest you know kind of like
you know kind of like meditation kind of
thing okay you don't want to trust that
you want to be careful because a coding
some sim site I mean there's a popular
website who the guy you know who is a
program you know he started a company or
something but anyway he's a programmer
and one day he had you know RSI and you
know he's suffering you know hand pain
and he see doctors is basically the
doctors are cannot solve the problem
that is also true in general when you
have hand pain you go to see your doctor
even after surgery many often okay often
it does nothing to you you still have
pain this this is true from a lot
accounts from people I know you know
this is true so so you basically you
want to avoid are a side you want to you
know just don't get it anyway so this
this guy who says then he finally
discover the solution the solution is
that it's kind of a new age a cohesive
stuff like like the solution is
basically just like Medicaid meditate or
think about you know like thinking some
kind of thinking training like he's you
know what he says is that you know look
at my friends over there you know they
they sit you know they don't have the
right pole posture and they are typing
all day more than me however they never
have any problems that's true you know
you look at some people they are like
that you know they see it weird and it
seems they don't have any problems but
so he create you know he says that you
have to his solution is that you have to
buy a book I think you know but you know
then you know basically some kind of
thinking thing training and you know
don't trust that that's not science you
know that's that's basically that's not
science you know that's that's something
out there and there are also some
programmers they tried out alternative
you know so-called alternative
you know medication like acupuncture
chiropractic s-- again you know they
don't really they are kind of like
cracky you know I I wouldn't trust it
anyway so back to the hand pin so each
time is different so whenever that
happens I I try to trace you know
exactly what's wrong and that's usually
hard you know I cannot it's very hard to
pimp on exactly what did I do wrong I
mean is it a particular habit or is a
particular way I press some keys but
each time I have most of the time okay
it happens every three years but you
know I actually I have a documentation
here so if you go to typing now in this
section it's all about typing typing
habits repetitive strain injury so I
discuss you know how to touch type
typing games website for timing games
and measure your typing speed and some
bad advice for from programmers about
typing you know when you want when you
want typing a device you know or
shortcut advice don't listen to
programmers they know nothing about it
you want to ask those people who do data
entry like the data entry crooks types
ten times more then programmers you want
to listen to those people's opinion for
example that for act that for example
this motor on keyboard you see this
video this video this guy is a
professional transcript stenography
transcript so heated you know you want
to get his opinion so he hasn't blog
about you know about his keyboard so you
know and that's why I also mentioned you
want to the keyboard tools let's see
here earlier history key how-to that's
why I mentioned about the key log list
of key rock software because
when you don't have statistics the key
lot the key log will give you the actual
data just exactly how much you type
that's important because programmers
let's say you type this much now the
data entry croaks types a hundred times
more than you although you think you
know I'm a programmer I sit in computer
all day you know I type a lot actually
if you you know type everything you need
to type in a day continuously it might
be just five minutes literally so that's
why the key log is important when you
when you have hanpan or when you want to
you know when you want efficient key
binding or whatever you know Emacs pinky
or whatever I mean if you are interested
interested in this topic you want to
start to record your keys key log once
you have the key lock then you know
exactly how much you type what you type
which key you press the most often you
know you solid data that's that's the
point
sorry data so when you listen to
programmers opinions they have a bunch
of garbage like you know freaks okay
here's an example how many keystrokes
programmers type a day I have measured
mine since like since about five years
ago now this one in particular is this
one is from Emacs it's a two years worth
of keys in Emacs I when I'm typing I'm
always almost always in you max so
here's my key dog so I know exactly how
many keys I pressed a day you know it's
like you know 13k keys per day here so
if we assume 50 50 words per minute they
assume typing every day
no weekend no holiday then my typing
load is equivalent to continuously
typing for 60 minutes a day so one
holiday so that's one of my that's my my
key lock you know you want you want to
do that if you are if you have any
concerns about keys on keyboard ins I
mean the concern comp comes in many ways
for example if you have hand pen then
you want key dog if you using Emacs you
have hand discomfort you want Keira if
you want to design you know if you are
designing a keyboard layout for example
if you go here layout so this section is
all about layout layout is a arrangement
of the alphabets on the keyboard so you
have lots of layouts so that here is a
quality the most normal Corey there's
here's of Iraq they have a oh you you
know so these are layouts you know there
are quite a few there are tens over ten
more than ten of them so if you are
designing your layout then you want a
key dog so you know basically if you are
serious about certain aspect of keyboard
you want to you know start to have your
key key logger okay Norman says smart
my eyesight comes in cycles also
changing keyboards seems to relieve it
no idea what exactly the cause yeah
that's I agree you know sometimes you
just want to like change the keyboard
sometimes that helps I that agree so you
know so each time like every three years
I have it looks like to me I have
different problems you know so but one
of the problem you know I I have a
account and see typing go to typings
so here is a habit and injury okay
why undo shortcut keys are bad okay
mechanical keyboard and repetitive
strain injury okay you want to get
mechanical keyboard mechanical keys
that's that's really good for you then I
have like okay here's my record saw
keyboarding RSI experience 1992 to 2000
13 2017 know basically each time my RSI
happen
you know I tried to write it down I have
a record of it so here's my summary but
anyway I'm just gonna talk about one of
them as an example here so this is the
one so in 2010 is my second brush which
with RSI okay the first one is like 2005
2005 because I was typing on a laptop
for for two years so 2010 is my second
instance it happened back thing I was
using the Microsoft 4000 remember that
keyboard I mentioned that Microsoft 4000
which is still this yourself today it is
this keyboard so so before this keyboard
I was using this I was using this but
the 4000 came came out so I you know I
bought it you know I thought its upgrade
you know I got a new keyboard new toy
you know it's got the zoom buttons in
Scott you know so I change it but on
this keyboard I got the problem so 2010
second brush with is I do too bad habbit
of pressing keys 1 & 2 though the the
key 1 & 2 on the left hand induced by
the Microsoft 4000 keyboard keyboard ok
and I have full detail here
so in this occurrence you know when it
happens it's really horrible I mean it's
not fun I mean you know it's not it it's
no joke because back then I know I
remember it you know back there at the
time it happens you know you are
thinking you know oh my god I cannot
type anymore that's it you know that's
you
that's it for your program in Korea it's
really bad you know I was very scared
but after a month you know I can't find
out why is you know I forgot yeah I
think it was here I cannot find out why
it it hurts you know I don't know
because I was thinking you know I'm
typing on Borak
I'm using an ergonomic keyboard I am
fairly healthy you know what possibly
could go wrong you know why do I have
this you know it just you know it's like
say my pen but I know it's going to get
worse if it continues you know all I
sighs like that at first you have maybe
numbness or tingling if you if you if
you you know delay you know oh you know
I'll check it out you know maybe you'll
go away your kid was and eventually pain
will come that that's you know when you
have numbness numbness or tingling
that's the sign you you you want to be
you you want to go all out you know
finally find the solution wait
find out what's wrong you know you want
to maybe see a doctor you know
but anyway so it happens so I don't know
what's wrong but after one month I
finally discovered I was pressing a key
so on that keyboard on that keyboard
okay not the others not any other just
on that keyboard I developed a habit
whenever I want to press the one or two
I twist my wrist like this and use my
index finger to press the two or one
I just develop that habit on that
specific keyboard this habit does not
form where I'm using you know the other
one so that's the one of the important
point I want to mention because you know
because all these keyboards you know for
example all these PC keyboard organ ami
keyboard they look you know they look
like the same but actually the even tiny
differences in their shape in their hate
you know just for one one of the keys
you can create this kind of problem so
it's different so I got that so finally
I discovered that problem you know then
I tried to move my hand you know then I
try to like I move my hand like that
then immediately I can feel pain you
know that's when I realized that that is
the cause you know at that time for that
so you know so I stopped you know
stopped you know stopped pressing the
key by you know moving on hand that way
you know just use you know maybe
should you know just lift my hand and
press that key so that's one one of the
example of the eyesight for me
occurrence and let's go back to the
let's see so let's go back so yeah
that's so that's 2010 then 2012 is
another one so what's this one pressing
X key too much exactly okay
that's another interesting story this is
another interesting story because well
you can you can read the you know my
article but but that this is another
instance where I had pen then finally
you know eventually I discovered what is
the cause you know I I pinpointed it I
found out the exact cause of that so
that that's this article then what's the
next instant incidence so 2016 so yeah
okay so every four or five years 2016
feeling discomfort with for nation
problem okay yeah I remember that
you know whisper nation is that like if
you have a keyboard you know this flat
keyboard you you you when you put your
hands on the keyboard it's it's it's
it's it's that but if you are using
organ ami keyboards like that so this
way it's more comfortable but this way
is not this is a normal keyboard I have
this problem this is like risk for
nation problem why because I was using
let me show you this keyboard I was
using if you go to keyboard history so
here's a bunch of historical keyboards
keyboard history then you go to economic
keyboard history over here now here's a
bunch of
Manami keyboards the history of
ergonomic human then you go to this one
truly AG anomaly keyboard mm this one
came out in 2013 I was using this
keyboard at that time for like you know
again taken more than 10 hours a day 10
hours a day for like two or three years
this is flat as you can see it's like
it's flat
oh I have a YouTube video showing that
keyboard review I'm doing a review of
that keyboard but anyway you can see
it's flat so it's not tented you know
usually when you when keyboard can like
in two pieces or not not necessarily two
pieces some some monkeys keyboard they
also obtained like like my Kinesis so
when you have it's called tenting you
know it's like a tent that's what they
call it
thinking so when you ever attend it so
so I didn't have tent but I was putting
on my hand you know on this keyboard all
day you know the ten hours a day I got
problems you know you know to to average
people you may think you know how could
anyone get problems you know because
look at this way they are tortured you
know in you know back media were times
where they put person you know in a cage
like you cannot move you know if you
don't move like for five hours you get
pain extreme pain because I I have I
have done you know because I when I was
younger I was sitting on chair you know
well in also in the past few years
because I'm sitting in front of a
computer all the time not moving I
discovered its it does have up to your
body you start with a backpack pin and
also the you know so too or no more
people you cannot imagine how is it
possible to just you know put your hand
like that how is it possible you're
gonna have pin you I it happened to me
you put your hand flat on a table you
know just leave it there - nothing King
hours out Stuart do a few days
you're gonna have pain the restauration
is important you want to and you want
you want to do that this is another
thing owner deviation which is solved by
this keyboard so anyway so okay so how
long have I been going oh wow 70 minutes
okay I think maybe we can we should wrap
it up I got so many things to cover we
yeah many things we didn't cover but so
I'm so web dog says I'm going to make
the thumb keys my modifier keys honored
over dogs
okay thumbs are too strong thumbs are
too strong of fingers to be wasted on
just the spacebar okay this one thing I
want to say about thumb using the thumb
there's one thing you want to be careful
because the let's go let's go to yoga
Docs
so do it yourself hi Kirk great to see
you Kirk Kirk says I have X about expose
it's okay cherry red cost me to make way
too many typos oh okay so I guess you
are big you have bigger body frame than
me yeah did you get used to it or is it
I mean he said okay now you still rather
have like cherry brown so let's go let's
look at Google Docs
so Google Docs so one thing you know
oviducts
this flaw you know we can say it's a
flaw that a lot of people complain is
that the thumb keys are actually too far
too far away from you know too far
outside so you have to extend you know
stretch your thumb to press press you
know maybe the middle the second thumb
key so some a lot of people you know
this is one of the common campaign
and in fact there is one guy this guy
you know he wrote an article you can
read his article here I I quoted here
but the original website is here geek
hack so basically he's a big fan but
it's let's kick hack but basically that
guy who was his name
tie red tie-red something like that so
he's a big fan of a gonna of Google Docs
keyboard so he got like a couple and
he's using all the time in one day he
noticed pain eventually the pain is
traced back to hitting the the thumb key
the thumb key caused the pain because
he's doing you know extending his thumb
in some way you know something that guy
it's a thumb key so you want to be
careful of that especially if your hand
is not very big you know if your hand is
big you just rest on the thumb that's
fine but if somehow maybe your hand is
too small you know or you know the
direction isn't IO something you want to
be careful so once he had a pen he his
solution is he he threw away oh he's a
Google Docs keywords he switched back to
the normal keyboard you know normal
mechanical you know flat PC keyboard
that's that's what he did but it was a
big story because you can t you can see
he's you know he spent like over a
thousand dollars on keyboard he became a
keyboard fan and he became a Botox fan
you know oh it's all gone I'm again in
keybinding key bindings and women stuff
I think he's a wimp user maybe Emacs I
forgot which but then eventually he got
this pain you know then he flew away
toggled oxy switch back to so that's one
thing you want to look out this also
happens on the Kinesis so on Kinesis you
know you got these thumb keys I've been
careful to you know my hand let me show
you
you know my hand is not big it's a
typical AC on hand so normally if I put
my hand there it's like this is probably
natural you know if I push it a bit it's
on this key then if I press this key out
I certainly need to stretch so I don't
stretch don't do that
instead - like that move your whole hand
that's what I do
so you I don't do that don't do that do
this yes this is good this is good you
know this is good
you know like move your whole hand don't
you know anytime you notice yourself
doing you know the kind of like
stretchered stop that you want to avoid
that I mean it's up to I mean of course
it depends on how much you type you know
if you look at your mom or your dad or
your granddad you know they don't have
much maybe do they just use a computer
for five minutes a day that's all right
maybe if you are a programmer but
depends on how much you actually type
for most programmers they don't actually
type that much you know so most so for
most programmers they don't see the
point of you know Kinesis I'm not going
to you know spend $300 on this weird
thing you know on my desk you know they
are you know perfectly happy with you
know one of these normal you know nice
normal PC keyboard you know they cannot
see you know why do you have so many
weird opinions about keyboard they don't
see it you know this is you know works
fine for them which is you know true
because you know maybe the actually they
don't type that much you know average
programmers you don't because you have
to go to meetings you know luncheon
whatever you actually only code maybe
two hours a day and a month you know
doing the two hours the actual time you
are typing is maybe just 10 minutes it's
literally you know so that's why I say
you know the keylogger is important you
know get the keylogger
then you have the actual data just how
much you type how much you type exactly
you know
that's a point so so let's read some
comments so I'm going to so if you have
a question asked
let's ask ask it and you know I'm going
over like I probably I went over like 18
minutes now so you know let's wrap it
wrap it up I'm probably I did I probably
talked too much repetitions you know I'm
I'm getting better you know I'm getting
better actually I'm getting better with
my videos now I can actually kind of you
know you know grab one topic and express
what I wanted to say in a more or less
coherent manner and not you know not
afraid like before you know I'm not sure
oh maybe this is something I shouldn't
say you know oh people you think you
know that's no good you know so I'm
getting better you know having done a
lot videos now but I think something I
still a lot of thin parts I need to
improve like sometimes I'm repetitive
you know like some things I repeat you
know over you know several times or
something and also the articulation I'm
getting better but the expressiveness
you know the grasp of the correct
English word you know the proper term to
describe some feelings of expressions
that like Jordan Pederson you know he's
the perfect guy he has he's the best at
that you know when he has when you want
to describe some complex ideas he always
came up with one sentence each word is
the perfect you know what for that
situation you know but usually my
diction might the words I use are
usually like very basic like this it's
almost like basic English you know by
the way basic English is a thing you
know it's a it's a it's a language it's
kind of a simplified language but anyway
part of the reason I use speech you know
basic I don't use much of jargons that's
also intentional that's not that's
another topic because I want to
I want to avoid any loaded words any
complex words you know anything like
that I don't want to academic words I
want to use words that average people
you know even including the native
English speakers you know for example
Chinese my Chinese friends so people in
Morocco hey in you know other countries
they can understand so that's one thing
anyway so let's go back to the topic so
yeah we've be careful with the thumb key
you know and I use sparkling spring
Unicom for years oh I see right
several months later then I'm okay with
expose red I see okay cool so um I think
that's it today so actually maybe yeah
let me show you this one second so I did
all these talking without showing you
some of the keyboard I actually like I
actually took it out and put it here I
want to yeah but my camera you know I
have a lousy camera so my camera's right
now it doesn't it cannot focus and you
know I have two cameras the other one is
this one the that one is Logitech okay
hold on a second
that is really bad the logitech 920 it's
really bad
it cannot focus you cannot focus on
anything close and the one I'm using
right now is like 20 15 years old
webcam logitech okay so anyway so but
anyway I did a video on this one you can
see you are YouTube this one I never did
a video of let's see but you know I'm
going to I need to get a camera that can
do that so thank you
web dog trackpad Norman says trackpad in
Mouse living for this away wires
wires
you know I don't like you know there's
of course lot most people use wireless
today but there's one thing I don't
really like about why is Wireless is
that I'm paranoid about the security
thing I don't want you know people to be
hackers to be able to especially
keyboard for miles it's less important
but actually not really because you know
for example if you go to
typing's key bindings key how to itse
key key binding design okay I forgot
where but if you go to the key
okay Sophia yeah key how to key hard to
software then you go to
okay keylogging and security you see
there are hackers that creates these
many instances of it okay for example
this one there are hackers that creates
sniffers you know it looks like a
charger but it actually can detect it
can record any any Microsoft keyboard
wireless keyboard in in the vicinity it
just looks like a normal charger you
know whatever device you know so you go
to your office you know you put it there
then you can monitor you know within 10
10 meters or any person who are using a
Microsoft keyboard actually you lock
their keystrokes and Incans and send to
your web server this is real I mean this
is but this is few years ago
this is spiking it's few years ago so it
seems so since that you know so new a
Microsoft keyboard they you know they
have methods to prevent Prien that okay
so key wireless keyboard is a security
issue but also wireless mouse is also a
security issue because it turns out you
know the the firmware they use for the
wireless reception reception and you
know communication they actually it
appears to me you know I am NOT expert
you know I didn't look into you know I
don't program hardware so it but
according to the web you know I've read
you know so they they apparently some
many of them they use the same software
you know the same firmware you know and
this firmware is actually keyboard and
mouse combined you know into one so when
you are if you have a mouse using that
software okay it's receiving my signal
I mean it's sending out signals and okay
but it also it can also send keyboard
signals because the mouse and key
receiver you know transfer
you know the the software is written
together as one package
so when hacker is able to hack into you
know wirelessly hack into your mouse he
can also you know send commands so your
so your mouse computers start to type
keys you know type type whatever switch
browser launches look at your photos and
stuff and you know send it to their
server so so that's why I don't trust
you know I don't really trust wireless
mouse neither you know like normally the
thinking is you know Mouse just move
around
it doesn't really it's okay if people
know where you click because actually
you know at the FBI level they have
software that actually even track you
know which window you know with like
exactly what you click they have that
you know it's getting you know anyway so
trackball versus Mouse versus touchpad
okay so touchpad track well you know I'm
so I have a I'm a trackball nerd okay I
have always been fascinated by trackball
so I got this Logitech this is this
thing is like very old like 20 years old
not this one though but I mean the model
and I have a review on my website to
like if you go to champ or if you want
to buy trackball so if you want big
trackball these are the best ones if you
want small trackball these are the best
ones
the Logitech is no good you don't want
to buy nobody these are all these are no
good but okay so I think I have a
fascination with trackball since like in
the 1990s but I never used one until
until maybe five years ago I I have I
have this one and this one I only have
these two so I don't actually have the
others but I mean I already reviews most
my reviews it's like I spent hours you
know the I have the obsession like for
example this but I spent you know two
hours a day read about it some website
next month I spent three three hours you
know they so each page you know I I read
you know I read all Amazon's reviews
like maybe there's a few hundred I read
them all I read them all all on kick
hacks you know whoever mentioned that
you know all reviews all people say
about you know what happens you know
with this industry and also YouTube
videos you know i scout all the YouTube
videos about you know the keyboard or
trackball stuff so anyway so so yeah the
trackball you know trample is so I
bought out about here trackball versus
Mouse where I type into the question you
know which is better which is actually
more intuitive you know the trackball
users usually say attract bow is more
intuitive you know I'm a trackball fan
for like 20 years before I actually use
one but the idea but I'd but I'm still
just obsessed about the question you
know so you know like theoretically you
know which which should be better you
know because human computer in the
interaction and so on but anyway I've
been using trackball for five years now
in general today if you ask me to choose
only one I would take Mouse not check
bow because Travis Scott you know so it
is it is actually more intuitive you
know if you have a person who never used
both I think track bow is more get is
easier get to use to anyway I have a
this article that talks about in detail
some of these issues so who you know who
uses trackball usually and stuff you
know many issues but today I if I if you
ask me to choose only one I would choose
Mouse because trackball you have the
cleaning problem
I mean today's so it's very easy to
clean you just okay did you just take it
out you know there's a hole here you
just pop it out and you just take tissue
here let's do that
so you know I you know the camera is bad
but anyway there are three points you
just wipe it wipe it wipe it so you can
see you know but anyway you right wipe
it then you just pop it back and and and
it becomes smooth
okay so anyway anyway so but the problem
is you still have to do that every week
or two you know basically you don't want
to do that I'd like I don't want to you
know even it just takes you know ten
seconds that's a problem I mean that's
the problem for everyone like usually
that's what not what people want to do
with Mouse also with Mouse it's actually
more accurate I mean it's more of if if
you are playing fighting games you know
what I call first-person shooter games
actually Mouse is I think you know in my
opinion is scientifically more efficient
meaning or more accurate meaning that if
you survey like let's say 1,000 people
using a mouse for the first time and
1000 people using trackball for the
first time you you let them play
you know first-person shooter games you
train them every day you know for let's
say a month
I think the mouse users on average will
beat the trackball for sure you know
absolutely like we wipe out the
trackball players doesn't matter how
good is your trackball which model
doesn't matter so so that's you know so
there are these issues several opinions
but however I think trackball is more
healthy I track oh yeah yeah I remember
you ever I track about touch pad a touch
pad that I never really liked using
touch pad okay I was going maybe I was
going to show you this yeah but oh
another day I've been talking like for
half an hour how many people are
watching no great yeah so originally I
had several issues I actually I'm not
sure I've even covered well yeah I mean
a lot
well I guess that's it for today then so
you know we talked about 90 minutes
thank you guys for coming see you next
time