hello welcome to another episode of sop
show today we are going to code emac
disp just coding emac disp okay uh so
let's begin this today is just coding
emac
disp okay here is today's talk show and
what we are going to do is we are going
to modify this command Exar HTML lines
to
list okay let's let's start to do that
so let me show you what does what does
it do so you have uh this is s HTML mod
so you have something you know like you
have uh several lines of text and uh you
press a key they become lines so you can
see the command is called ctml lines to
text uh lines to list and the keystroke
I use is a left side I'm using a v
keyboard and the sfly keys the most
efficient emac key
binding uh more efficient than Vim Neo
Vim showing browser so you can see it
makes a several lines to a
list uh but what what
if each line is long uh short par graph
okay
and
something else so you want to make them
into a list but not just by line but
rather by paragraph by the text block
each text block should be a line so in
that case you make a selection you call
the same command just like
before uh tab C so there it
is showing browser refresh so you can
see each of the block of text becomes a
list
item okay so the difference is that one
of them a b c let's say one of them is
um when you don't have a selection lines
becomes a list item but if you do have a
selection uh let's let's do it let's do
it here if you do have a selection then
you do the command then each text block
becomes a list item okay so this is
superb so but what do I need to do what
I want to do is that you see there's
something about the user
interface uh I want to redesign it so
this is about user interface design
currently they make a dis distinction
whether to use each line or use each
text block as a list item depends on on
whether you have
selection but I want to change that so
so the difference is more explicit I
want to change it so that the command
will always just make lines to list
however if you want to make text
paragraph to these to these items you
have to
call the universal command which is the
standard way for emx
to to to to have a command to have
different Behavior okay so uh let me
write it out so it's more clear
so for those uh who came here late okay
if you are here say hi if you are not
here skip around play at speed 1.5 or
something uh and don't forget to donate
me okay hello I don't know are figure
and figure caption standard HTML tags or
are they system stuff they are standard
okay they are standard since the HTML 5
around 2008 by the what the [ __ ] group
created by Google Opera because they are
they want to promote they want to create
you know especially Google Opera kind of
died you know Opera was was 20 years ago
was one of the greatest standard
conforming
browser what's what standard
w3c standard that's a standard for web
technology HTML CSS
Stone okay so
but but around
2008 Google started by Opera you know
Opera is led by this uh northern
European guy who is a Microsoft hater
he's a scun okay his name is what
whatever Swiss name but anyway remember
the the Opera founder okay he started
then pretty soon joined by Google and
apple why do they want to do that why
why is Google Apple want to create a new
HTML
because well the fundamental the gist of
the reason is that they they are
commercial corporations they want to
control the HTML especially Google so
that they can have you know for example
Apple they want canvas you know the
canvas
tag okay so let me show you you know
canvas tag for for like replacement of
flash why do why does Apple want canvas
tag because they sell iPhone they don't
want flash but Javas script is not good
enough so they want they created the
their own canvas which is painting you
know and SVG they don't want to use SVG
because SVG is for vector graphics line
drawings they want bit map so so you can
create games you know big money Apple
want canvas which is lousy
technology so Apple want Camas on their
phone to make money and Google Google is
like everything for you know they want
to control the web you know they you
know so Google Apple join Opera to
create this what the [ __ ] group HTML 5
so what is the what [ __ ] group that is a
separate organization like a rebel okay
they say you know w3c group you should
die you know we we are take over
basically so that's a long history about
web history so you can go to let me show
you my
pages uh so showing browser let me show
you okay so remove the camera so you go
toar talk show you go to. info then just
search you can search or uh or just go
to web
history okay that's a giant that's a
huge chapter of web history of course
eventually the
w3c standard organization lost so you
know the W um the what the [ __ ] group
took over so uh web history so let's say
search for history there it is history
of web Tech so during for about five
years you actually have two web
standards one is from the uh what the
[ __ ] group what's the proper name W you
know so one of them is w3c okay
w3c they are you can recognize them by
this badge this badge was
popular in in 1990s and 2000s you know
it says you know your web page is valid
and every programmer especially the Unix
Elite idiots they love this they they
they they Champion it you know they say
you must you know your tag is inal you
know anyway and that became history and
today the Zoomers don't know because
well anyway that's another long story
but let me just talk about the uh HTML
standard and uh this okay w h a t
WG which stand for uh web uh something
working group okay what you know I just
call it what the [ __ ] group versus is
w3c w3c is a HTML standard started in
around 1990 okay
so
so uh you know the what working group
versus w3c split so for about five years
you have two version of HTML standard
the
w3c organization which is also corrupt
they became you know all the these
standard
organizations after 10 years they become
corrupt same thing happen to unic code
Unicode Consortium okay that's why you
have pregnant man emoji you know a
literal Emoji one single character of
pregnant
men corrupt organizations so anyway w3c
is a standard HTML uh standard you know
n XML and uh web and Dome for JavaScript
scripting and SVG for for graph you know
line graphics on web anyway and versus
that so for about five years or so they
you have two different standard you know
w3c claims their standard is the
standard while the Apple and
Google group what the [ __ ] group they
they you know they say we are the
standard eventually w3c lost okay so you
know so what's the difference well you
know you can read there's a difference
because I dive into this you know
technical
standards uh so what is the example of a
difference did do I have it somewhere
here somewhere okay I have like article
somewhere but anyway here is their from
their website how they claim you know
w3c defense how they are the standard
while the W you know you know the what
working group says that they are the
standard you know for example you can
see the what the [ __ ] group
FAQ what are the various versions of the
HTML spec you know so you
know so um so for example this section
what the f group and the w3c HTML WG are
there plans to merge the groups no blah
blah blah
and then which group has Authority in
the event of a dispute then you know the
FAQ says the group from the you know the
what working group they say the two
groups have different specs so each has
authority over its spec the specs can
and have diverged on some topics
unfortunately these differences are not
documented
anywhere except I have some document
some part of it okay their difference uh
one one of the difference is the tag uh
some tags related to HTML table table
group or something I forgot I probably
have it in another
blog and here is uh the
w3c groups what they say about the issue
Force dich dichotomy you know they so
each one claim their HTML is the
standard but eventually they merged okay
So eventually around what year so do I
have it there I also have it documented
so this is a documentation of History
okay not as kissing
anybody many of the white people's
documentate documentation of history is
like partially fake news for example
especially around open group I mean the
open source history you know like moo
reads that
MO is like oh this is this is the god
book this is the real
history
uh and okay so anyway I'm digressing a
lot So eventually they merge so your
question about figure tag so let's go to
HTML index okay figure tag and figure
caption tag they are standards by now
for 15 years now so it's supported by
all browsers so you can just search for
figure there it is
okay so they started you know 2008 or so
but they became usable in many browsers
around 2011 figure and figure tag okay
so that's what I use so that answers
that
question today's drink is apple juice
okay let's go back to uh HTML
uh go back to code so uh so I need to do
this put this here go back here go back
here so
this web history okay big giant chapter
in you know history of web
Tech um okay so we are doing this so we
want to write out the difference okay
so so this is what we are
doing this
command if no
selection it turns each line into a list
item if there is a selection it turns
each
paragraph into a list item okay that's
the difference showing bow
there it
is now let's colorify
this now it's colored
okay we want to modify it so
that to
turn each paragraph
into list you
call Universal argument first
okay this is more emac
convention there it is so this is what
we want to
do uh okay so let's begin okay so so
let's jump to my source
code describe key press the key and here
it is HTML allines to list tab to go to
the source code here's a command copy it
new buffer paste it and uh save it as a
new file so a temp file so we're going
to work on this temp file so this is uh
36 lines of
code
okay not very big
um I don't know say it's very
interesting I never knew about this you
should have a talk show about it
actually I do I did I did talk about
history but you know but I've done like
you know today's episode episode is 500
79 so I already have 600
um live stream videos all almost all of
them are live stream so the issue with
my you know because I like to do live
stream I like to do lives so it's real
genuine not prepared you know and edit
modifi edit so you just you just see the
beautiful Parts like five minutes and a
lot money you know so you get a lot more
views because Google YouTube they don't
promote live stream like live stream
after three days is dead also because my
my style when I do live stream I talk
over things so today iMac this then web
history you know I talk over so there's
no like like there's no kind of
searchable you know of all the topics
I've talked about so I I so i' I've
talked about like whole hour about web
history about the what the [ __ ] group
versus
w3c more than more than one time okay so
but let
me talk about all uh so let me show you
guys I promote you know I have a you if
you go to S Talk Show index page there's
a talk show Clip Clips index so I try to
gather the best of my videos and the
subtopics here so if you want to see the
best keyboard videos you go to S Talk
Show keyboards you know this is a
collection of the kind of kind of my
best more focused uh talk shows video on
keyboards okay and or if you are into
emac or emac this here here is a
collection on emac or efficiency
workflow or this one for example this
one is very popular very good one hour
talking about work Emax workflow and
efficiency and then emac this from the
ground up you know a tutorial and
writing a major mod from the ground up
so the best collections of my
emac uh and emac list videos then you
have several random kind of things you
know how to change your behavior you
know I talked about what is a schizoid
you know it's these are more
like uh popular topics because when you
talk about technology
programming you have 1,000 times less
people you know but if you talk about
General Life issues like diet which diet
what what what diet and you know the
meat diet or no meat diet or you must be
a
vegan or is red meat good or you want to
go with the dinosaur diet that Americans
Obsession apple juice juice is good okay
just don't you know don't eat any
man-made sugar you know that white sugar
or or brown even Brown okay but 100%
juice if if the box says 100% juice it's
good although you can go deeper then
then then you'll see lots of tons of
YouTube videos saying oh juice is
actually just sugar it's bad for you
because this or that or because
chemistry but they don't know actually
nothing about actual biological cell
uh mitochondria you know what you know
biology they cellular biology okay you
if you want to talk about you know those
things you got to go study cellular
biology because I'm a hardcore guy I
don't talk about the fluff you know you
don't know things but you talk about
that you know so anyway so this
collection of you know what is schizoid
that's you know very popular among the
forchan types they want to know uh El
musk um how to judge a person and the
parents ask for girlfriend what can you
do and parents parents ask you do you
have a girlfriend yet do you have a
girlfriend yet they they want they want
Grand
grandchildren uh so anyway and then lots
of my rants on the Unix hackers you know
so then then about programming and
programming language related issues okay
uh then uh wolam so wolam is my one of
my main topics so there's a lot
um okay actually wolam you you you just
go to Sali wolam language there's a
dedicated page of collections of my
wolam uh video tutorials and there's
math and geometry okay and some you know
so anyway that that that is c talk show
clipse index you know just search it
you'll find
it
uh CU our hot dog Saucy s okay so you
know gu you know we talking about you
are talking about the hot girl you know
Chinese goinging girl because you know
when you put a girl on your YouTube
thumbnail your view viewership increases
10 times something like that but not
like not so much live stream because
Google doesn't promote live stream for
example I I I know it because if I you
know after live stream if I if I you
know re reshare it I mean to the on on
YouTube I I we shared as a just a video
exactly the same content then that video
gets a lot more view so that's the
situation Google doesn't like you know
Google doesn't Google is nasty you know
there's lots of nasty things Google try
tries to do so back to the code problem
okay let's let's quickly uh we already
talked for 24 minutes let's finish this
one uh so we got a code so here's a code
okay 36 lines of code let Let's uh shall
we go over it let's see how we want to
do
this uh let me just quickly modify to to
what I want to want it to do okay first
of all version number change okay so uh
make each line into HTML list item of
current uh selction uh of uh okay so
okay just say that then if the region uh
so let's modify the documentation so to
what we want it to
be okay remove that okay wait so if
Universal command is
called oh God okay so we are already
using Universal argument for something
Jesus because when you have that then it
creates all the list of lines now
so it's now this is a
problem yeah I haven't you know I
haven't thought about this we are
already using the universal
argument if you call that then it makes
makes a older list of lines so
H now that's a that's a issue I'm not
sure
what's yeah given the situation I'm not
sure what you want to do do
now so I have to think Focus okay so
make a
lines make lines into a list but
sometimes you don't want each line to be
a list item you want each paragraph to
be a Leist item is that needed yeah
sometimes it does this happens when your
each your your line is multiple line
but you still need to make a list uh
that happens
in that isn't not a common style the
common style for HTML is that usually
each line is just a short you know no no
more than let's say 100 characters then
you use a
list but but for my
style
sometimes when I describe certain
properties about a keyboard you know
keyboard review for example this support
Bluetooth this can also be used uh
Wireless as a with USB dongle it also
can be used USB the how long does the
battery last and how does the key feel
you know like a bunch of uh features of
a keyboard I group them into a list okay
so typically each item is short but
sometimes it's a bit longer um more than
one line so that's why some sometimes I
want each list item to be a
paragraph okay that's just something I
do uh less common out there but do I
should I continue that practice yes I
think so because there actually often uh
let's let's show some examples okay so
go to keyboard block lots of
update so search for
uh let's let's say search for Ur okay uh
it's going to turn up 1,000
Pages let's say Okay so let's say search
for
Uli I want to find a example to show you
guys where each list item is long
okay uh so let's
see okay not
not here let's search again but this
time uh so they are like few
thousand results like okay this is not
good yeah because it's searching the
text the navigation box like that so
there's like
few thousand results it's not not we
it's not what we want
it's let's try this
again anyway we are are we wasting time
so I do want that so what you can
do
uh so let's focus this emac this
oh
God yeah the first issue is how you want
the how do you want the program to
behave
okay so right now it behaves like that
okay how but
um so if you call Universal argument
first then you could have like ask user
to have you know whether you want list
or ordered list on ordered or
unordered and then whether you
want you know each line as a Leist item
or each paragraph
yeah but I don't want to do that because
then every time you call this
command with a universal argument it's
going to ask you you know a few things
then you have to
answer um so I'm
thinking yeah I'm thinking currently
let's not do this okay save it go back
I'm thinking let's just not do this
let's go back here okay let's skip that
okay okay let's skip that now um okay
let me show you guys if you want that
command let's see if it's available yes
okay so you go here here's a URL for
that command you can grab it and you can
use
it okay HTML Lin to list it's part ofar
HTML mod and uh and then you can
um you can you know uh you can also buy
you know just buy my tutorial okay so
here's a link list let's put it here
let's merge this two uh first of all
yeah put okay put uh put there showing
browser figure tag
what the [ __ ] group versus
w3c lines to list okay and that's a code
you can use and uh this we skipped now
let's do the next one okay so modify s
HTML convert to
jpeg okay let me show you what this do
uh for example you have a PNG image for
example this one beautiful China girl
okay now usually you want to sometimes
you want to convert to PNG because I
mean to jpeg because jpeg is smaller in
file size so let's see if I can yeah
it's annoying so you can see this file
is right now PNG and it's
286 kilobytes so I have a
command I
can uh actually let's make a copy okay
make a copy rename XX let's just rename
this uh to a simple name there okay test
you know we going to test on this image
xx. PNG
so copy the file path close close close
okay let's go back here let's go to um
let's go to the
bottom uh and add a that okay there it
is the file path make a image
uh figure and go to the bottom so you
can see this is our test file now this
is a PNG I want to make it jpeg so I can
just boom boom boom press three keys No
Control no meta so you can see it cause
image magic to convert it to
jpeg okay now you open the file and you
go to the directory di jump you can see
now it's half the size okay so this
command convert to jpeg it will only do
that when the when the new JPEG file is
smaller than original
PNG okay now so why don't you always
convert to jpeg that's not good because
jpeg is lossy that means each time you
save a JPEG file the
quality uh you lose some quality a
little bit usually
imperceivable but however you save that
file again you also then you lose
another tiny bit of quality so that's
why on the web you see lots of these
memes or you know these meme pictures
they are very bad quality because
they've been copied and saved and copied
and saved and you know for example
someone saw this picture they like it
but they don't they just want the face
you know so they you know they they
screenshot
or in Photoshop they save it you know qu
every time you do that and save to jpeg
it loses a bit quality then another guy
they just want another part you know
they so that's why all the images are
lousy but if it's a PNG PNG is not ly
format so you always have doesn't matter
you quop or whatever how many times
always uh the original image quality
okay that's the difference between JPEG
and PNG so that creates a problem
because sometimes you want PNG sometimes
want you want jpeg because jpeg actually
saves significantly file size for
example half half right
now so what I want to do is that you
know this command um you know uh HTML
convert to jpeg let's see if it's on the
web I don't think so so
press the key for example go there uh
yeah so here is a command but it's not
on my website you have to pay you know
buy my HTML
mod uh you'll have it
so yeah so this command will convert
only I mean only if the new JPEG file is
smaller but what I want to
do okay so I want to modify it so it
will keep the new jpeg only if it's
20% smaller okay yeah because it's
almost the same just you know few bites
smaller sometimes that happens I don't
want to convert to jpeg because it's
very lossy so it's only only if it's 20%
okay let's do
that so go to the source code so here's
a source code new buffer save it go to
the Top Copy the name save it as XX date
the command name. eel okay so we're
going to modify this um command Okay so
new
date if the new image is bigger nothing
stand uh else replace okay let's modify
uh let's the new Behavior should be
if the new image
is
20% smaller in file
size okay is
um if the new image saves less than 20%
file
size then do
nothing there nothing in done okay this
should be the new
Behavior okay this is the old
Behavior Uh you know old Behavior
new Behavior
okay old Behavior so something like that
so okay so we need to do this let's push
in um to do this
okay so what does this command have to
do basically it first of all it needs to
find the url so let's make let me show
you um go to HTML so when the it needs
to find the file path around your
cursor uh and uh that
is uh that
is search backward for image tag then
get you know grab the points okay
so yeah so then you get the X path is
the image file path then you create a
new
name uh so if the new name exist report
Arrow file already exist okay then you
call image magic to convert
it uh then
you uh you how do you call image magic
you just call a shell command shell Dash
command then you check the file size so
yeah so let's see so the original file
size is
um yeah so this is how you get file size
uh by file attributes
okay uh
then the new file size okay then you
compare okay so actually all we have to
modify is this part okay so compare size
if the original is greater than
new then you you do the change basically
you rename you rename
[Music]
the you rename the
file
um yeah the X path is original file path
so you rename it into a
backup and then you modify the current
buffer so
that so that we it will change this part
to the new file
name right so first of all you generate
the file you compare the size if you
want to make a change you change the
file name on on the
disk of the original file to a backup so
it's possible for you to revert you know
if you for some reason you don't like it
then you also modify the current the
curser position to point into the new
file okay so that is uh what's this
doing here if the file size is greater
otherwise otherwise just delete delete
the new generated file okay then tell
the user about it so all we have to do
is modify this part okay so let's try
let's
see so if the original image image size
we want to like be 20% or so thing if
the orinal
size times okay
so times
08 let's say 0.7 so shrink the original
size let's see what this how this work
so if the original size
I think that's
it times
0.7 is greater than
new that means the original
size is
is um you know this logic let's let's
try to create a new logic so
this is like about buing
logic so if the original size is greater
than the new size times
1.2 or
1.3 orinal is greater than the new
size uh well another way maybe you know
kind of confusing let's do this this way
okay so if the new size divided by the
original size so divide so let's
say if the new size divided by the
original size is is is less than okay
not greater than so less than
okay if the new size
divided by the original size is less
[Music]
than
um
0.8 okay this is more intuitive then we
do the change otherwise don't okay so
let's try
that so remove that remove that okay so
let's see new size divided by original
size
is less than 1 Point uh
0.8 okay yeah let's do this so actually
it's should be pretty simple we don't
even there there okay now evaluate the
perer let's try
it okay so actually
now uh
actually let's change it
to 0 five you know that means the new
size
is let's let's make it severe so we can
actually test it so if the new size is
actually just less than 1/3 of the
original that's what this means evaluate
it so we can can actually test it so go
here go to diet rename this so we have
this back okay then delete the PNG open
it delete it and make a few backup of
the PNG so we
can back up back
up okay so this PNG is
286 okay the new jpeg is 100
uh 17 so it's not 1/3 so when we do this
let's say JP uh PNG okay let's cut let's
do it again new delete that so open it
so this
PNG is
280k the jpeg would be 117 it is not 1/3
of the original okay not enough so when
we call the command now it will not
replace the PNG let's try it do it oh it
did
uh
well yeah it did so
one3 okay let's let's do it let's delete
let's do it again
okay okay let's now go back to our
Command so what
uh what do this new size divided
by now now do we have to be concerned
about int and Float stuff let's say two
three
Eva the
[ __ ] you need to convert to float that's
why this is annoying
part because two divided by three gets
you zero okay let's look at the
documentation
uh okay I don't so well I mean so you
have to into float okay in to float can
you do
that something float
okay is there some I forgot what's going
on with emag Lis
about uh so let's go to emag L
tutorial lisp Basics number okay
so binary hexadecimal octo input uh by
by arbitrary number base input okay so
let's see
arithmetics oh we have convert number
string okay so you got to convert to
float yeah you have to this is one of
the Annoying
Thing okay so
actually float
now that's correct answer you can see
0.666 okay so we just need to put the
float there so let's do
it there okay now let's grab that and go
to S Talk Show and uh paste it so
because it's a interest same point
point there and uh copy the file path
put it here okay that's an interesting
point now let's let's do this again back
to the code close that back to the code
evaluate the buffer go back here now if
we do it again it will not
convert do it there it is
is now the message is the wording of the
message is bit wrong because you know
it's not larger but it's um so let's fix
the wording okay new image size
is
is is let's see uh 0.3 let's say
six so you new image size is not
0.6 of original size nothing inst done
so that makes more
sense uh we might have to trick this
number
because yeah
anyway uh let's say seven it's not to be
too yeah seven okay so now this is this
code is done and it's valid so let's
copy that to the talk
show uh or behavior let's let's just say
that new Behavior okay then
we cut that
code back to
HTML
HTML paste the new code now the old code
cut it and put it to this temp file okay
save it close showing browser
uh let's go toite CH so this one we
ignore close close
close eval the
buffer HTML mod now let's see the
difference okay this command VC Das
diff What no change oh not not here so
close that uh h HTML commands Evol
of VC diff there it is that's a
difference we changed
today basic basically just over here
fantastic okay so fantastic HTML
commands so now close that showing
browser we are done basically so
let's
um let's see should I put the code so
you guys can use it answer
answer uh let's go let's
see now if the command uses some other
command then yeah it does it you know
this get thing at Point that's
free uh but then you have Co image magic
yeah
so yeah I'm not going
to I'm not not going to publish this
code because then you need you know you
need to also image magic which you can
do by the way you can easily do by Cod
or shell
command yeah but I suppose for most
people it you know it takes some
experience to code anyway I think that's
it for today close that close that
showing browser I think that's it any
anything else so let me read the
comments and uh that's it for today
uh what do you think of do s
HTM ml server side include I never used
it and and that was
technology of late ' 90s to early 2000s
okay nobody uses that anymore server s
include I forgot even exactly I
mean um shtml nobody use that today
okay but you are probably interested
because you are you are like not trying
to like you know trying to go you know
use the Asian
technology
uh computer good hope that's all pit
site I suppose F you know all these are
scums these are you know all
these well except Apache You Know M MCA
the scum deep State controlled virus
program antivirus
program you know this file.org that's by
some scammers you know Tech geekers you
know they they trying to make money so
they try to or file name extensions like
things like that you know then copycat
so you have lots of them file format you
know uh then another one file
info uh you know I just want Wikipedia
okay Wikipedia of course is also very
corrupt
now because it's corrupted by Deep state
so on Wikipedia let me say this again if
you search anything technical
information math physics chemistry
programming no
problem if you search for esoteric
history like China history 1,000 years
ago uh America history 1,000 years ago
Europe history 1,000 years ago no
problem but if you search anything on
the news let's say whatever War
currently going on or Middle East or
Ukraine or whatever China something
about China and Taiwan or about
American uh
election everything you read is complete
fake
news okay that's how you judge you know
Wikipedia uh by the way I have a one
hour live stream on how to judge
Wikipedia information
correctness uh trustworthiness
sometimes ago half a year ago or
something in fact I more than one live
stream about that so anyway server side
includes is a simple in inter
interpreted interpreted serers side
scripting language used almost
exclusively for the world web it is most
useful for including the content one or
more files into web page that's [ __ ]
okay that's just like include from the
C idiots the SE scums first created is
like you know you just include the whole
file you know no Library no module no
name space you know you just say include
this file and every it it it behaves as
if the whole file is in this file that's
basically [ __ ]
anyway bye
guys anything else bye guys
1 hour
exactly stop I don't know stop talking
about that thing okay stop you know if
we uh yeah don't you know
don't mention it for no
reason I mean that um you know that's a
deep State thing
but um but some
people there are some people good people
okay so you know don't just randomly
throw that word
out okay bye guys