hello guys welcome to another episode of
excel talk show today we are going to do
this uh we are going to write a
JavaScript application to do these
interesting things for example inverted
text
same thing you see that's very
interesting so we are going to write
this in scratch okay I'm gonna show you
I'm gonna teach you how to write that
JavaScript with a Dom and there is also
this thing interesting for example
some things so you can have like this
fan Fantastic mathematical font you can
have double stroke you can have math
board let's try double stroke okay and
uh
you can paste it to uh to Twitter
you know and they will show up as double
stroke or both I don't have I'm not
logged into Twitter so not gonna do it
but you can do it in for example uh
let's try and Discord
you see something
and the double stroke okay math bold
and let's paste it again
okay it's a very interesting and there
is also run you know this you can think
you can you know this is very fun this
one is fun let's see
uh Delete and let's say
something magical
so you can then copy that
showing the window go to Discord or
Facebook or Twitter and you can paste
that something magical
run so this is a Asian alphabet used in
1500s also
and then you can convert it back to
Latin for example if I copy that copy
that and say to that and and I post then
post that then that becomes that
you know
so that's what we are going to do okay
let's begin okay uh yeah run then there
is another one Braille very interesting
you can do
same
here okay and so you can when you have a
puzzle uh you know you want to share
with your friends and but you don't you
want to hide the answer
you can use one of these Braille or run
uh
which adds a little uh
Mr season to your post okay so let's
let's write it okay
so I'm gonna show you how to write from
scratch okay so let's go to uh
okay that's that's right from scratch
okay so actually so let's create a new
HTML and by the way so I'm using emacs
I'm using soft light keys
okay search for it you'll find it and
I'm using
exposed keyboard
search exposed study you'll find it
for example
there it is exposed keyboard
uh my review so you know I recommend it
because of my keys I'm using volarag
layout and on the Ping window you can
see all my commands course you see
you see all my command commands course
and the keystroke okay so now let's
start HTML so let's start to write this
from scratch HTML that's HTML mod so
save it as
xxhtml temporary name okay
and show this in browser right now it
looks like that so now we want to title
test
convert
text to upside down
okay so that changed the title and the
header
see change two places now so we're gonna
write a um so
first of all you need a JavaScript Okay
so make a backup drop to directory
rename this
JS okay
so we got a JS file open it
DD them okay nothing copy the file path
close it close it paste the file path
linkify so now this
now this HTML file will call that
JavaScript code okay now before so you
know
and if you are here hello rat rat hello
rad good morning good afternoon good
evening good evening to UK
okay this font
I don't like the iPhone that is the
default Siri font so let's create
um
let's make a backup rename it
CSS okay open the CSS DD though and then
say paragraph let's say body
magnify
uh 18 okay let's say body magnify font
family okay Farm family area okay that's
what we want close it close it show in
browser again oh you forgot to link
reopen copy the file path show the Ping
window copy the file path close
paste the file path here link it to CSS
now
to refresh fantastic sense serif
programmers font
okay now we are going to remember we are
going to write these Unicode things so
we need some interface let's see which
one do we start uh let's let's do this
mathematical font one okay let's do this
one
so we want uh let's say let's say bold
okay now how does this work you see the
JavaScript will simply take this input
whatever you type there or paste it
there he'll take the input hello or
flamio you take the input and they
basically do string replace
each replace each character by the
corresponding character you see these
characters are Unicode characters you
can see as I move the mouse overhead you
can see the Unicode okay if you don't
know Unicode you can
go to my website I have a for example
Emoji they are all Unicode or
for example
math symbols you know it's made possible
by unicode
and uh you know and as well as many
Stars you know or uh
many cultural symbols cross uh Greek
cross Latin cross various kind of costs
um you know so these are characters
these are in this Chinese Trigon
background very interesting
hexagram
okay so that's uh so so so what the the
application will do is simply let's go
back let's go back go back it simply
take the input string replace each
character by the corresponding one
you can see you can see so and this
corresponding character the character
you want to replace are just uh they are
much like Emoji okay
so that's what we want to do so first of
all we need to create an interface like
that okay so so let's see uh so you need
a output
element where the output will show and
you need the input element where a user
can type things then you need some bunch
of these are called radio buttons
you know why are they called radio
buttons so first of all radio button is
such that only one of them can be
selected if you select one the other one
will be canceled so that's multiple
choice basically
so why are they called radio buttons you
guys may not know and I I barely you
know am old enough to know because back
in the days let me show you
back in the days on the car
okay you need JavaScript
uh on a car
you see oh God this this is modern they
are not radio buttons
okay let me show you all uh here is the
old radio buttons okay
yeah yeah exactly so this is a radio
button because when you push one button
down it pops up the other one when you
push it down it'll be it will stay you
know in a lower position but when you
press another button it'll pop all the
others out
so and this is used in a radio you know
in old cars you you twist the knob to
tune it's not digital so yeah like that
for example this one is more uh
pronounced
for example there's also radio buttons
uh yeah so and classic radio buttons you
press one down the other ones pop out so
one choice at a time
so that is why this interface
uh where is it
that that is why this UI interface is
called radio buttons okay
now we need to implement these radio
buttons input text and display uh
user interface so let's let's make the
display first
so what we do is we just create a dive
tag
type with a ID and class okay
so let's say uh I'll put let's just name
the
this element as output okay
that's where the JavaScript will find it
using this ID and display output in this
type okay then we need the text input so
that would be
input tag okay input tag looks like that
now I don't remember what are the
options so let's look up
so you can go to Sally JavaScript search
for it JavaScript in depth then you go
to Dom here is all the fundamental
things you need to understand to the web
dev okay then there is a HTML input
and here we need a text area Okay so
text area looks like that
you can see as you type
the output are shown there
the output you see so this is how you do
it and here is the HTML code you need
and here's the JavaScript code okay
let's just copy them copy and copy paste
time copy paste Advanced programming
technique
okay
so so here's the element that correspond
to this text input
sorry the element is called text area so
we don't need that input anymore so here
okay let's say Let's uh
let's let's call it
input box okay
input box some number okay real column
okay type text here
okay so that is that okay now
now
um
now let's this is a JavaScript we don't
need now showing browser
okay
we
got a text input area fantastic next
we need the radio button
yeah where is it
okay I don't know where did it go it's
go to a talk show again and
comments and questions okay
so let's go back to
upside down my thumb okay
so so now you have a text area and you
have the display area let's not do the
radio button yet let's start to do the
JavaScript so we can have results as we
code okay so now open the Javascript
file so those interface are sufficient
now open Javascript file
so first of all you need to get this
item X output okay so that will be
document
uh get element by ID okay get element by
ID
okay let's see do we have it
okay
and this needs to be document okay
so first of all we need a constant okay
a constant
let's say output okay equals to
get that element and the element ID is
that okay fantastic
so whenever we have a output we just
insert it to this element we'll get to
that okay first of all we need to get it
so the second thing is the
text area input Okay so
so select element by ID because this is
an ID okay
and X input okay I just name I name them
starting with x so it's easier to search
hello then pureec
what switches do you have on that
keyboard I have
red switches this is gate gate around
red and its lightest I I prefer light I
must have light because even if you you
know that's very interesting point
Cherry MX you know you have Cherry MX
red in the beginning then you have a
bunch of Chinese
manufacturers you know they also because
the of the Cherry MX switch mechanism
they the paint the patent is expired
about about 10 years ago
so you have a lot of Chinese makers they
make you know Cherry MX compatible key
switch
um and uh
it turns out they are they are they are
very good okay the Chinese ones the
different ones and they also make new
ones you know Improvement but anyway so
all of them you know by different makers
they all call they name they try to be
compatible so they have this they use
the same naming scheme so linear
light switches they all call it red I
mean color code you know there's lineage
so
linear light switches so from Cherry the
corporation in Germany Cherry they they
have Cherry MX red
and another corporate company in China
Gate wrong they also have
red linear switch red okay so and uh
however here's the thing however all
this red switches from different makers
they they are sensitivity their
resistance to Keepers is actually
slightly different noticeably
so
cherry red
Cherry MX red I like very much good one
red I like it very much but not Kyle
thread Kyle thread is like 5g's uh
heavier so I cannot it actually matters
a lot to me
uh so have you so we are getting off
topic okay I don't want to actually I
want to go back to um
to today's uh
stuff okay and JR says do you know how
to program a TI calculator no
so we're getting off topic for if you
but if you want to know all about
mechanical keyboards you can go to
design and you have design flaws of the
keyboard and you have key switches here
is an introduction to All Keys keyboard
key switch mechanisms you know the most
popular is the rubber Dome you know this
is on your laptop and on cheap keyboards
very cheap to make but bad then of
course you have the topper which is
actually also robotom but it is
uh it has a capacitance
electromechanical switch
electronic switch mechanism so even
though it's rubber dome but it it's not
the same
feel and quality
than the cheap robotom so you know so
that's super switch so anyway so you go
to this page and you'll see then you
have the classic Cherry MX which
this is what it looks like and this is
how it looks like when you you know you
can just plug it the keycaps out in your
seat you know before before I got into
keyboards so this is like this article
is written in
um
uh the article is written in 2011.
so about 10 years ago before I really
get got into keyboards you know the
first time I see this I was thinking why
do these people you know when they take
a photo of keyboard they always always
like pick up one of the key that's ugly
and idiotic I mean why do you have to
then you know then of course I realized
that's because
you want to show the key switch because
in a sense key switch of a keyboard is
the most important
part of the keyboard as far as your uh
the quality of the key and keyboard and
how you feel that's critical so
so anyway here's how the key switches
looks like like and here's a classic you
know blueprint the design of the Cherry
MX
red and brown brown is creaky they call
it tactile then blue is really clicky
and makes a click noise when you press
down click crack then you have Optical
so anyway
so what I'm trying what I'm saying is
that so there are you know quite a few
uh switches especially today but what I
want to say of the Cherry MX
you know even if I expect
but I expect there or say they are 45
grams of force to activate the key but
however they are different okay so I
know so I've used skaterang
I like red you see it says 45. okay but
however you have chaos Kyle switch
you see it looks the same but you see
the red one
uh box red okay not okay so anyway this
red one they also say 45 but actually
it's it's heavy it's much heavier
um I know because on the ultimate
hacking keyboard there that one you see
this you know this one and on the side
you know the the keyboard above like you
cannot see it but
I see you need to get a camera so this
is the ultimate hacking keyboard
okay that one
so on this keyboard it's using Kyle red
and that's just too strong for me I
cannot type you know if I'm gonna type
thousands words I don't want to use this
because then I'm gonna have uh
hand strain like right now actually here
okay that's digression I'm gonna let's
go back to JavaScript okay you guys code
uh
let's go back to JavaScript
okay close the keyboard yeah let's so we
got the input and uh okay so now
let's JavaScript
close it
okay
so now we got the input okay now
now let's do
let's let's make whatever we typed
to show up in the output area okay
so what you have to do is you have to
write
um
show output okay function
say
constant Arrow function so we're gonna
Define a function show output
okay show output and what does it do it
takes no argument and but what it's does
it do you take the X input
dot value
I guess
so yeah okay so here is what you have to
do X output value
equals to X
[Music]
um
something like that I think
okay so here's a function you know the
the X output refers to
refers to this box okay and its value
will be
equals to X input value which is the
input box
here okay then then we have to right now
this doesn't work
because
okay you have to call the function
okay call the function let's see if it
works refresh it doesn't work we
probably have some syntax error here so
let's see how it is done
let's go back to the
yeah where is my so go to kasabi.info
info
then
yeah that's my website go down then you
go to
JavaScript in depth
okay then Dom
then you go scroll down HTML input
text area there so let's see how do you
get the
oh text content yeah okay so text
content is unknown is what we want so X
output text content equals to that then
here we call the function okay now
format clean up the code now
Shilling browser there it is you see
you see that
okay now we need to add some space
between these boxes okay now you want to
add a space okay now so you modify the
CSS
you want to say
X output ID
you want to put the margin
okay now go back here
you fish
fantastic
okay
now and and you can
close that now you say let's move it
down
and let's add a break and let's say
output
make it H2 show in browser so there it
is
but when you type more it doesn't show
because it's not updating it you see
only when you refresh then it's there so
we need a way we need to tell the
browser to update it whenever user types
whenever this text area change okay so
let's go to JavaScript again JavaScript
event that's called event okay whenever
the event of user type something
happened then call this function okay so
event
uh how do you assign a sign event I
don't remember uh yeah add event
listener so the way you do it in
JavaScript you know with the
Doms op model is that you say
X input
Dot
X input is the element is object so it
has a method add event listener okay
then then
then the first argument is what type of
event let's just say input that
basically means whenever the input
changes okay then the second argument is
a function
so whenever this event occur you want
this function will be called so in our
case it's F show output okay
then the third argument is kind of Asian
and obsolete let's just leave it you
know
you know you can look up you know you
can look up add event listener if you
want to see the documentation okay let's
try
you see the Mozilla you know event is a
very complicated Dom okay so if you
don't know web dev if you want to learn
Dom your uh try my tutorial okay
try my
um
just search for Sally JavaScript in
depth you'll find it very
I you know you
teaches you the fundamentals of it
critical parts and you don't need any
framework or Library
okay sounds good fantastic now let's
so we have that
now let's
okay that should work and double check
okay
okay so X input and even this now okay
let's close it show in browser
oh it worked
well it worked fantastic
okay now next
next we are going to add the radio box
you see we want you know the
the radio box okay
okay so that gets a bit more complex
let's go back to the
to the Dome reference let's see the
radio box how do you
uh button okay radio button
cat dog bird
okay so the HTML is like that copy it
here okay so basically a dive okay then
a label okay label is uh
well
it's a bit complex okay so let's just do
it
so you use the input and then you have
to say type radio
hello My Chosen
I just want to say hi I don't remember
who you are though long time ago must be
yeah hello guys great to see you guys
concurrent the viewers too Jesus
oh God
okay so so let's get back to these radio
buttons okay so what we want to do the
radio button so type you have to say
type radio then name
uh
fun to use okay
let's say x font okay
then value
okay so what what kind of font do we
want so
double stroke bold okay
okay
copy that paste it here
then you don't need that okay
and here let's just say bold
and let's just say that okay
okay so we have two choices okay here is
a boat
here's double stroke
showing browser so we have two radio
buttons now do you want one of them to
be default yes
so in that case you have to do
uh
default and C
checked okay so if you want the one of
them to be default checked you have to
say checked now this this HTML is very
inconsistent you know this this input
tag are Asian they are from 1990s so
notice that they don't have a closing
tag you see let me let me show you okay
so it's very ugly so you see this input
there's no closing input and also
this board you know it's just a text uh
display you see
very healthy is Asian so okay now you
have two radio buttons let's add one
okay so we need to actually we need to
go faster uh already 30 minutes okay so
let's say script okay
front let's say Factor okay
uh
so copy that
so
Frank tour whatever that means Frankton
okay
okay so we have just three choices okay
show in browser fantastic now they do
nothing they just show the interface now
we need to
um
do them add them to the JavaScript okay
so where is the JavaScript here
okay so we need to go faster so how do
you get the code so radio box is a bit
involved actually
uh
oh God we need to do this you know it's
much easier if I just copy my code the
existing code
okay so anyway so here is a code
let's put them inside like that
it's uh in radio pets equals true Okay
so
we want to select the radio buttons
yeah
Okay so
so the name is X font okay
and how do we select we use document
query select all
we want to
pick out what's the current radio box
that's what we are doing
it's radio buttons
yeah we want to you know
we want to know what did user pick what
is the current Okay so
so actually so but here is actually get
all this radio box elements
so it returns a list of elements
okay so shoebox
so this will be X fund Okay so
yep
so and uh and how do you
how do you know what is a current
current radio box radio buttons item the
way you do it is here okay so
you do document.queryselector
and select that radio this is the syntax
that selects all input elements who who
whose attribute name is xfont so it will
select all those basically all these
radiobox elements
then you have also this checked that
means those elements that has a value
that it that is checked okay so for
example let's go back here
uh you see here you see that one is
checked
so in this case we'll select this one
but it will select this element okay
and then dot value the value will be
exposed okay
so
selected value equals to expose now
Showbox
okay so now
let's say x output
text content okay equals to that
okay and then
let me show you what else okay so let's
update
so cut that
here is all the radio
button elements
that is assigned to X font
okay then
this update function
TD that TD that needs to be
should output so instead of show output
let's rename this function to be update
okay
that means update the page
so instead of updating the
the text here
I mean instead of just displaying the
input text here let's display the
currently selected radio box here okay
so here's how you
do it
you
this lines select the current radio box
button
then
you say x output text content equals to
selected value okay that's that's how
you do it
okay
I think that's it okay so and what is
this let's see ignore it for now okay
so let's refresh
there it is Frank Franklin now let's
click bold oh didn't work
well didn't work because
you didn't call the command I mean you
need to
set a event listener so that when the
event for the radio box changed
happened it will call the update command
Okay so
because right now if you refresh you'll
show double double stroke because that's
currently selected let's do it you see
but it doesn't change dynamically so we
need that's what this line is for
uh let's
reformat the code so it's easier to read
okay so this means array from
array from okay so here is X fund array
from this
radio
box radio button element and for each
one of them
X
and event listener input call update so
that means every time every time any of
this is clicked
it will update it will call the F update
okay so now refresh refresh Okay click
fantastic
click fantastic click fantastic okay so
we have the fundamental structure
of this app
now
now the next thing is the main thing
that is we want to text take this input
text
and actually replace them to these
to these fonts okay
okay so let's try it and let's just copy
that okay so
so that's what these this of of f update
will do okay
hold on a second so that's the
so this selected value let's change the
name
let's change it to unicode
uh
you know it's incorrect it's incorrect
to call call this font because they are
not font they are actually Unicode
characters
so
um
so this name X fund is actually wrong
so let's use yeah let's use the proper
name so instead of calling them font
because it's not found is different
typeface these are these are actual uh
Unicode characters
so okay so let's do it uh
so how do you call it so instead of font
you call it
foreign
yeah let's just call it font okay
because there's no proper way
to
[Music]
you know each one of these is just a set
of characters so the proper
the the proper name to describe this set
of characters is Unicode mathematical
Factor
characters
okay and the proper name to describe
this set of characters is Unicode
mathematical double struct characters
so and uh
similar for others so what about a
proper name to describe all each one of
these different sets that will be
uh unicode
math character Style
so Unicode math character style
something Unicode math
uh yeah so it the name is quite hard
so okay let's just say fun because fun
conveys the idea somewhat
okay current font and it's just say
selected value is just let's name it
current found
okay so now we know our font we need to
replace each and every character by one
of these okay
so yeah so let's just do it so
so given the text we want to replace
each letter by one of these okay
God this is not tedious then then I
thought
so let's define a function
Arrow function and let's call them
okay
so replace text so given a string
by the Unicode
cha
by
the corresponding Unicode chart okay
something like that
and so
so now the problem is how do you do find
and replace in JavaScript okay
uh uh I don't remember because
JavaScript is very complex there are
quite a few functions to do that you
don't know which one is the most
appropriate appropriate therefore you go
to JavaScript reference
and uh
string object so here you can see all
the
objects let's see replace oh okay
probably this one yeah
okay JavaScript
stream replace also X is a string then
you wanna say replace all
okay then the first thing is what you
want to replace by oh God we have a list
of them
so basically you want to replace a by
here's what you want to do
see
and but you want to do this for each and
every one of them yeah God so we
so you need the array
so you need um let's see
[Music]
let's see characters
let's see I breathe
you know this is taking too long
and I'm thinking let's cheat
let's cheat by
instead instead of just code coding this
from scratch
let's just
copy and paste my existing code
because this will take a long time to do
so anyway so here is a string
above a bit and here is a string of the
things you need to replace
so replace Space by nothing okay
okay so you need to go through
so
so we can do four each
for each a function
then you grab this inside
yeah this is this is a bit complex
I hope you can understand
I don't expect you to
because JavaScript is very complex so
okay
now replace or what does the function
take
the function takes
for each
yeah so now we need to look up for each
okay so the area is replace so
and let's go to
array
then array
for each
so the function I want to know what
arguments are passed through the
function current element current index
okay
so the current elements
index
so current elements
current index
okay
so that's the current element
and
the current index okay
um
so constant
okay
copy that Define that here
the actually
let me show you don't worry about too
much
okay
like that so we got letters
okay so here is just letters letters
start for each
for each then we have a function okay
and the function takes two arguments
so x e is alphabet
okay
so that way it's easier to understand if
we name it that way and the second thing
is index
okay
so
and uh
X Frank
okay now I hope that's let's clean clean
up the code maybe that you know be clear
okay so
here
okay so let's clean up one more time so
now I think this is right okay so we
have a replace text function
no it's uh I want to name it
function names start with f my own
convention okay
so
Okay so
underscore
so this function takes a string
and uh
then for each letter A B C D E F G
for each letter for each one of them
you
apply this function
this Arrow function
okay and this error function takes two
arguments the the letter
okay so actually let's rename it a
little bit so this should be called
alphabet
okay
and this should be
something like that okay so
for each letter in alphabet call this
function
and letter index and here's the input
string
replaceable by
replace the letter by
the Frank uh character
uh
with the corresponding index okay
so this function is fantastic okay so
now let's call that function
in the update body in the function core
of date party so let's just say let's
just put here so
current font it's not too good one it's
just equals to
Collide function
okay and
X input value okay that part we don't
even care
so this update function will just
take the input
which is this
which is a text
and replace text
to this francophone
okay actually let's copy it move it down
that way it's easier
it's more intuitive so replace each
letter by the corresponding Factor
character
okay and set it to the output okay
refresh
and we should have
hit
ah
nothing happens
[Music]
okay this is when
this is when you need to press Ctrl
shift I
to show the
debug console the JavaScript Java
JavaScript browser account so
so here's his uncle type area alphabet
for each is not a function okay
something something it's
pop this in how do I pop this thing in
back to the right okay dot to the right
okay
uh
alphabet for each is not a function
[Music]
technology is not a function
oh yeah
obviously it's a string string alphabet
is a string character string data type
and it does not have
the method for each because the method
for each belongs to array object
okay that's uh
JavaScript technicality
so you can turn a string to a array by
by
string two array okay so that's pretty
easy you just do
uh string through arrays basically you
need the
I think this this this is how you do it
okay let me show you
this is the dot dot dot operator I
believe
so in fact we can just do it here
okay let's just try
back to here
refresh
XX alphabet Oh yeah so yeah I believe so
but
but we are still wrong
refresh what is going on no output
what
and let's see JavaScript console
refresh what not even error
we should at least say there's an error
what no error what is going on close
that close that close that close that
show in browser
Ctrl shift I
console
not even
what let's print something okay when
that happens all you have to do
open the JavaScript and it just say
console log
something okay and here refresh there it
is so at least our code is running
but no output what why is it no output
oh yeah that's because your function
didn't return nothing
wait
yeah the the replace needs to return
yeah yeah of course we are doing for
each so
you need to actually return it so
instead for each let's just say map
okay so wait so he said right
yeah so map is the thing we want
so wait what
so each letter and each index replace or
wait
okay so let's define a result okay
let's just say x output equals to empty
string okay let's say empty array
and yeah
so
for each time you replace it you
yeah okay okay so this should be a
string so X output equals to
it's an empty string
okay then you do this each time you
set the output to oh yeah so
um
actually so you actually just change the
string
okay
yep
it's
refresh
yeah nothing
wait we change the string oh yeah we and
then we need to return it
right he needs to return
don't forget to return
okay
refresh there it is
there it is except we got this
Bond problem
what a that's okay a b c d e f
G
oh okay
you see that's a bit strange now let's
do it again carefully okay so a
space you know a b c d
you see it uh
somehow it takes two characters to
become one character and the reason for
that is because
the JavaScript idiocy okay the
JavaScript has a lot of idioces
uh for example I can show you
okay for example you have this emoji
okay so and let's say
that's a stream and let's say length
okay
yeah copy that
so if we run this paste it you can see
it says two even though you just want
you got one single character and the the
reason because for that is because
JavaScript string
is not just a sequence of characters
it's actually a sequence of
utf-16 bytes
okay now if you want to know the it's
very very complex okay not many not that
many JavaScript professional JavaScript
programmers even understand it so but if
you want to understand what does it
really mean
you go to
JavaScript in depth
okay then you go to string
string overview
okay then you can see there is a section
string is a 16 bits unit sequence okay
so you can open that
then you'll know the detail
it's very fairly complex okay
so anyway
so our purpose for our purposes
what are we doing so how do we fix this
hmm
so we already did one hour
uh
for so we want so yeah so the problem
right now is it takes two key strokes to
return one thing why is that
so you replaced all
I think I know because the yeah
JavaScript is really painful
because wait
prototype replacer
uh
so
it replaces all currencies that's right
and
so for each letter
and we are doing this very efficiently
him are we
oh not necessarily
so for each letter we
yeah that's right we do that we do more
we replace all and set it to that
that's right
uh and uh
is that correct let's look
okay
Go to JavaScript in depth
then you want to go to those uh itrobos
so in about five years ago seven years
ago 2015
JavaScript
introduced the iterable concept
so that the string is now iterable okay
in the technique technical detail is
fairly complex
uh so so string is iterable and how do
you convert a string to array so you can
look here spread operator
spread the value of each one into an
array okay so that
yes so that converts a
so for example we can show
okay for example that uh yeah so
so we can say let's say that okay
and we can say print
dot dot dot okay
copy that
new tab
Ctrl shift I paste
you see we got the array fantastic
fantastic
so that part is correct
oh I know what I know why it's uh wrong
because this second part is incorrect
because here the factor is not array so
you know this is a zeroth index
but this is not the first index the
first index is actually
okay so let me explain
in this string the Unicode you know
you know normally you might think the a
is index 0 B is index one C is index
three actually that's not true
you know we can test it let me show you
okay so for example
let's say that let's say the index one
let's say
let's say the index one it will not be
any of these okay so let me show you
okay let's save it
comment those out okay let's run it
print okay
so what is the result the result is
going to be
the second half
utf-16 by encoding for that a character
so it's gonna come out gibberish okay
run it
you can see
that's output you see
so that's a problem this is a problem of
JavaScript again if you want to
understand it you know go read
um
did I already close it again
yeah now here
you know JavaScript code unit you have
to understand
JavaScript stream okay
so how do you fix that well you can so
if you want the index to correspond to
the letters what you can do is uh you
first of all
turn this francophone thing
using the dot dot dot operator to turn
them into an array
and that will
put each of the character into a element
as a element in Array
then you say one that would be the first
one a okay so let's try it
oh B yeah B is because zero index you
see
fantastic so that's what you want okay
okay so now let's go back so here
so actually so
just copy that dot dot dot that okay
that should do it
let's go back to our app here
refresh
fantastic
a b c d e f g
something morning
[Music]
okay
I think that's it for today we've been
coding this for an hour over hour now I
think you guys get an idea how it is
done
uh and that'll be it for today
I hope you learned some JavaScript some
web dev real web dev
you know we have written a entire
application
in browser
of flamio says why is Javascript so fast
if it does all of this crazy stuff
yeah well
JavaScript is very fast I mean not not
not that fast I mean but it's very com
the JavaScript compiler
by all these by these giant corporations
by Google
you know Chrome browser by Microsoft
is also using Chrome and also in um
you know in in Firefox they have their
own JavaScript compiler so they are
highly very competitive
that is why
they are fast because they have you know
each of the JavaScript
compiler developer in the browser they
get paid you know twenty thousand
dollars a month something
uh
yeah
so
um or more I would say uh so they so
JavaScript is you know browsers is very
competitive so
okay that's it for today so so if you
like my stuff okay buy my you can buy my
JavaScript tutorial
you go to it then you can click on
JavaScript in depth and uh you know I
can read it online why should I pay
um because you are beautiful
okay so and uh go to my home page
gossadi.info and all the way down you
can see how to support me
okay that's it for today
bye guys
okay shut shutting down okay let me just
copy the stuff we talked about and put
into
put into our talk show page
spread operator
Java stream immutability in the code
unit
extreme complexity
seedingly
and JavaScript prototype replace all
that is actually new added about three
years ago you see
new in 220 JavaScript 2021 this is added
a year ago actually
before that if you want to replace or
string a substring or string you want to
do all of them it's more complex
um
event listener yeah that's right we
don't care okay bye guys