good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Excel talk show today is 2019
November 7th 12 o clock 14 minutes
San Francisco time good morning Bart
good morning beautiful people
good morning crew for school so what is
CMS content management systems content
management systems ok so but what what
about that so that on that topic content
management systems I'm gonna talk about
my Emacs setup this basically yeah you
know unless you have something specific
in mind
so tell a spot and discord let's go to
this code okay so so Santosh so today
we're gonna start let me show you this
window okay so let me show you this
fantastic start cuz our log mod okay so
MX start command log mod in this window
you will see all my Emacs commands for
you
Emacs users
good morning Liam good morning Alan so
alive yesterday someone said you should
talk about content management systems
versus self self-made someone did but I
don't remember what is the question
though I mean like okay I can I can tell
you something about it but but German
but German Stoffel this guy this guy is
a voodoo ax this is straws but mahjong
mahjong straws drop the see first first
inventor budva a reasonable budva see
first first the worst language on earth
the virus let's go see him so if no
topic I'm gonna just talk about random I
have lots of things on my blog I can
talk about I'm going to talk about so
this is this this guy is a voodoo is
he's actually quite reasonable when I
see him talk you know and like for
example as far as personality goes
personality goes Amanda programming
language creators I think he's more
reasonable then for example then the
Larry war who created Pearl and guide or
van Rossum who created Python you know
those like empty is nothing Python guy
yovan Rossum his opinions his opinions
is nothing nothingness guy yovan was up
and the Perot guy Larry was a crackpot
defacto crackpot and but John straws
stove he's a reasonable would world you
know he's reasonable but he is a you
know I can tell you the reasons I have
to give you my reasons because because
you know because if I cram this
you know this this Idol you know this
this this guy is a programmers Idol you
know people idolize him oh he's a genius
he's the greatest genius genius genius
my ass
this guy tsipras first the worst
language on earth okay so let's see
beautiful people had all beautiful
people agree with their I agree with
this of you okay so yesterday someone
said you should talk about CMS was
herself self-made okay CMS versus
self-made okay let's let's prepare saw
talk show
okay magnify today state and the Casal
new page create a new HTML page link if
I cut paste it here three that then go
to the page showing browser this is easy
so this is new magnify but before we do
anything let's go to yesterday so
yesterday someone said CMS so let's
search for CMS okay here Pano's a said
CMS wordpress joomla drupal the jungle
CMS guava versus hand crack handcrafted
handcrafted website okay panels are you
here panels panel is not here okay so
that topic okay what am I gonna say
about that topic that topic you know it
like usually a topic a blank topic like
you know see what press Joomla Dhruv oh
the jungle you know I've never used any
of them well I do have a wordpress
account I just used it for 10 minutes I
don't think I'm not sure I still
remember the account I yeah the long
time ago 15 years ago or something I
might have one account but you know
WordPress blogger
Joomla what
what what is Joomla let's see so such
wait ok search I don't have a thing
about these topics but well I can tell
you my opinions about this topic but so
Joomla is a free and open-source content
management system for publishing web
content developed by open source it is
beyond a Model Model View controller my
ass framework that can be used
independently of the CMS ok went
whatever so what is it it's just a
blogger right you just go to a website
you vlog it's a free resource content
management system yeah so you know that
word has many means so it's just a
website you go to end postings right
oh is it a you know so the content
management system the the meaning has
kind of diluted I think so do they mean
just a block website or do they mean
like WordPress you know what press is
just it's just a website you go their
creator account you you can write blocks
now on the other hand there's content
management system for basically for
creators for website creators for
example sorry dot info so I can use a
content management system so I generate
HTML pages like that but so what does he
mean panels a Drupal so let's look at
Drupal I don't use any of these are you
brothers both of you cement so named W
Allen W greetings Liam
Allen is from a Allen is from Sacramento
we had wait yeah right I think so and
Liam is from the armies from Europe
somewhere very firm medium
so I started watching the Bashan video
before this stream oh you did okay so uh
huh you know so he's you know he when he
talks his personality I think he's
reasonable so lamb the Army's from
London okay come on in London so now
your since the joke in the scream okay
see CBS was a self-made I was young
straws drop so strop that's whatever his
name presentation it was really boring I
feel I left early okay haha he doesn't
seem like entertainment so how would you
define CMS exactly that's the question
only in Troy Fletcher what qualifies
that and what doesn't yeah good question
now Troy Fletcher I must introduce Troy
to you guys
he is a to it yourself keyboard creator
right Troy so Troy he created this
keyboard let me show you do it yourself
and and he's got newer versions but I
haven't up keep my website updated
Signum so this is Troy's fetchers
creation Signum keyboard and and right
Troy
say something thank you respond okay so
so this keyboard
Troy's creation and there are several
versions covers keyboard yes that's you
so this is this is Signum to then this
is kavas keyboard and i think you do
have new new versions right
feeling a little cold out
okay so Troy Fletcher dotnet so let's go
to yeah why don't we just it's not
talking about things you know random
topic so his website on a second so he's
he's got a video here if you go to if
you have JavaScript on then you can see
it and you can buy you can buy his
keyboard from his website the kit I
think so let's go opening brave hold on
second open link in brave and I let's
turn on JavaScript I don't know if in
case you are using javascript
okay so Twitter keyboard sales YouTube
reddit writings okay let's say let's see
let's look at keyboard sales that's
what's let's see what is new Signum 3 ok
Signum 3 you know what one one of the
thing I find interesting is that is this
the big corner key troy put their big
corner key so so you can buy on a second
so I have let's talk JavaScript and
refresh stupid video ok so there it is
so you have video and you can buy a kit
here one thing I find interesting is a
big calf big corner key so that you can
use your palm to press it easy does he
have a picture like that oh there's a
lot on this page ok so there is also
board 40 what is this Fletcher five one
zero one this is standard PC keyboard
and sigh code from an old and dying
keyboard okay what is that about
sort out meticulously cleaned rebuilt
and painted okay anyway so rebrand an
ode 8101
okay so there is a picture god [ __ ] I
don't I should have a picture here
because there is a picture okay so I
know where to find it
so that's his keyboard okay so check it
out and funn keyboards okay I mean let
me show you this this one corner key one
big-ass corner key fantastic you put
control on that key so you can just you
know use your palm it's very natural for
that okay so that's that's a good idea
so anyway so let's go back to CMS you
know so I don't know what you know so
CMS there are two things about CMS one
is just like WordPress you go to a
website you create a blog you know like
blogger and then the other is for
example the content creation system the
content management system I think that's
what you guys mean so Drupal is
according to Wikipedia is a free and
open-source content management framework
really in PHP and distributed and the
good news something something license
crap Dhruva provides back-end framework
for these 23 of all website worldwide
yeah because it's PHP is not because
Drupal ok its PHP pretty homepage the
most popular programming language that
the elite hacker types despise PHP and
JavaScript
the reason they become popular is
precisely because this elite hacker node
types idiots they don't know how to do
things they don't understand society
so therefore the programming languages
that this elite hacker types loves such
as Haskell list closure they go nowhere
scheme scheme this there are forever
forever tail recursion on Mars you know
somewhere at some corner Univ universe
Nannette they go nowhere
meanwhile the language is despised by
these elite hacker types such as PHP and
JavaScript they are they became the
first you know the the most popular
language
so anyway Drupal ranging from many from
personal blogs okay so this is marketing
talk ranging from personal blogs to
cooperate for the Korean government shut
the [ __ ] up so systems also use Drupal
for knowledge manager FAQ so what is
Drupal reserved as of 2019
the trooper community comprised more -
it the standard release of Drupal so
what what the [ __ ] is this originally
written by this guy dress by turd dry
spiders dries dries by a pop-tart by
Todd as a message board Drupal became
open-source project okay so so can
anyone answer the question so is it just
the website you go to post blogs or is
it just is actually a for programmers
these idiots okay
anyway I think Drupal is a yeah it's
easy it's for programmers you create
website for it content management
framework that's right so you have
Drupal and you have the jungle the
jungle is something from Java what a
offensive name the jungle what what what
the [ __ ] that is the jungle and guava I
don't know what is squad let's look also
for your sweet I think okay oh we had
one of those not very popular rebrand
non programmers and people can add
content blogs so so nonprofit oh okay so
none programmers and people can add
content blocks okay so it's like a
Wikipedia right I mean the Wikimedia
software
which fuels Wikipedia right okay so
content management system well I mean so
what is my comment yeah the jungle is in
Python indeed I know so content
management system so that you have this
graph which apparently is not very
popular okay so there is a Wikipedia
page let's see Wikipedia guava okay
this new logo nice logo well the concept
of the logo is very good but the
implementation is not so good because
this astronaut looks like a baby you
know is it looks like a baby in diapers
so guava is a free software self hosted
content management system written in PHP
again and based on this on the symphony
web framework frame application
framework it uses a flat file database
Oh flat file database that's a revival
of the classics for for both packing a
infinite
bob is designed to have a shallow
learning curve and so be easy to set up
and so on okay so yeah this content
management system in our context it
means like you know a software a
programmers or Cecil being install then
you have a website where people can
create web pages you know things like
that so it's you know like Wikipedia so
what is my opinion I don't have much
your opinion yeah I mean it's it's a
tool it's useful it's a tool it's useful
I don't use it I don't use it for my
website because well because I you know
my website is just personal website you
know it's not it's not for you know a
lot of people for a team to create
content so I don't use it you know when
it comes to creating website there are
so many aspects you know for for my
website I also have kind of a system you
know custom system for creating websites
you know Emacs for example
something okay let's see content
management system you know I type
something I want to create a web web
page of that name so I just cooks a new
page or custom commands' okay oh nothing
it's all right cool
Poisson new page okay now it's done
now I can press ENTER to open that page
he's there he's everything is there you
know templates stuff whatever showing
browser you know it is yeah and okay I
don't want it anymore
switch back to Emacs I want to delete
this page press three keys it's good
okay then press one key that is also
good okay so that's you go back here we
open last opened it says file not found
because I delete it so that's that's the
content management system too so yeah I
don't use it
content management system it's a good
tool but I can I can tell you the
history of the content management system
so the earliest you know let's go back
so if you trace back to the earliest you
know one one earliest we can think of is
Wikimedia Wikimedia is a software that
runs Wikipedia okay now when people when
we hip here began in 2002 also 2003
you know they it's written in PHP back
then in through through our 2,000th
every website is written in PHP okay
ninety percent ninety percent of all web
sites or including all the most popular
web sites including Facebook actually
later later it's all written in PHP
pretty homepage and they and so one of
the early so you have Wikipedia in 2002
now in 2002
you know it's written in PHP they don't
have a Wikimedia software yet you know
basically because whenever is every
software began you just have kind of you
know you don't have you may not even
have a name you just have a software you
know
you passion you do whatever then after a
few years it becomes more robust
consistent then you it becomes a
software independent software you know
Wikimedia you know then you have lots of
wait it's not called Wikimedia it's
called is your website or static pages
yes my website is all static pages do
you have any server-side code no not
zero base yeah 0 basically astronaut
might look like baby in diapers but
where are you gonna pee and you know I
heard apparently for some time they pee
in their pants
astronauts it's true if you look in fact
there's a there's a video YouTube video
from astronauts from you know from you
know NASA or something you know they
they talk about apparently for a period
of time they just pee actually I mean
they okay so so there's an invention
basically you have a pee back in your
pants
so you pee into it but however before
that is even invented there are some
cases where the astronaut really needs
to go pee and they you know they they
call hey Houston I need to pee I really
need to pee I can't do the Houston says
so I mean the astronaut says Houston so
so would it be okay if I pee in my suit
would that be a problem then after a
while or the scientists busy as he at
the station you know work things out
calculus and it's a and after a while
they go back a you know you yeah you
can't go ahead pee in the suits and he
just pee in a suit that actually
happened so anyway
okay so I can't okay so let's go back to
talk about the history of content
management system so Wikimedia let's
search for Wikimedia okay I um I don't
Wikimedia okay let's see
Wikimedia movement Wikimedia movement or
simply wiki media is a global community
brahbrah
what's a software had created wiki I
mean the Emacs I mean the week Wikipedia
wiki okay so wiki again let me talk
about wiki because that's the history of
the content management system so you
have Wikimedia wait wait let's get the
Wikimedia the word correct you know so I
don't keep using the wrong word
what's the software for so let's look at
four so anyway so let's look for let's
open media wiki okay wait a fact these
confusing names media wiki okay yeah so
it's called media wiki media wiki is a
free software open source software wiki
engine okay so so you have several wiki
engines so so wiki engine you can
consider it consider it as you know
content management system so here's the
wiki Amith media wiki which is a
software that runs Wikipedia then you
have list of wiki software now if we
look at them I can tell you - they have
a list of names I just want a list of
names I don't want your philosophy okay
ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba ba public
enterprise wiki ba ba ba what whatever
he or history of wiki [ __ ] its robbing
my job
okay yeah it's okay it's it's it's it's
talking about what I'm going to talk
about more or less somewhat so I can
tell you so you know I'm gonna tell you
my own opinion you know so look look at
look here in 1998
proponents of extreme programming voodoo
extreme if you have a if you don't know
extreme programming is what became agile
you called agile you don't go extreme
programming anymore but in 1998 extreme
programming is extremely popular you
know it's from there you have the
concept of pair programming and also the
Voodoo is garbage why do you why do you
have wait how did extreme programming
begin I mean what why did it became
popular because it is a mechanism it
says it's a way it's a propaganda it's a
mechanism for non programming managers
non-technical managers managers who
don't know nothing about coding okay for
them to manage technical you know
programmers because if you have a
programming manager you know I have you
know we have a project I asked you to do
but you say you tell me oh it cannot be
done at this you know within a week
because this or that or it cannot be
done how do I know like I don't know
right
so non-programming manager how do I you
know it's a it's kind of I have to trust
you it's kind of a issue so they created
extreme programming so it's a it's a
front-end it's a propaganda it's a
method to so that they have you know
they have many concepts for example
stand up meeting you know like this
weird you know non-conventional
thing and filled with tons of jargons
for example pair programming so what's
pair programming so as a manager I don't
know how to code I don't know nothing
you know if there's a bug I don't know
if it's a it's a mistake on your part or
it is really significant you
even great programmers we have that
problem you know you as a programmer you
do things I don't know what do you do I
have no idea I just manage you I'm your
boss so when you say you know I cannot
Church your work that is I don't I can
and I you know in many often I'm unable
to see to church whether you are a lazy
programmer
you are [ __ ] off fooling around all
the time or you are really good I don't
know you know some project it might take
one week but you tell me it takes two
weeks so how do I know okay my my
neighbor is removed
mowing the lawn very noisy [ __ ]
annoying let me close the window
[Music]
so it's a Thursday oh god it's knowing
it's really annoying
Thursday you know that's what you know
this is when you wish you have lots of
money you can move to expensive gated
community apartments you know or you buy
a house then you go ahead you don't have
these problems okay so today's kind of
random random things am i doing good
should we focus on some technical topic
or something so yeah hello beautiful
people I think you guys don't hear it
much because the microphone it you know
it only captures my mouth so you don't
hear it but to me it's very loud it's
like in my ears and even with the window
closed so history of wiki so history of
the founder management sister let me let
me finish talking about that so we were
talking about what what was I saying
what was the I forgot what is the thing
I'm I was saying I was like talking a
lot about okay so the noise is okay
don't worry about it so what what's the
thing I was like starting to have a rant
like okay so I don't you remember
so anyway content management systems
wiki so you have this software and what
is the thing I'm going to say is
so anyway me media wiki is one of the
earliest okay now before we key before
then you have the term wiki you know so
media wiki came after the turn wiki wiki
just means a super chat Thank You Alan
ching-ching
[Laughter]
so you were searching for the four oh
yeah extreme programming yeah that that
is a tension on the extreme programming
so you are a manager non-program a
manager you manage your programmers but
you don't know what they do you know the
parameters can lie you know you can you
are unable to judge so what do you do is
you create okay here so yeah so so you
create you create this extreme
programming thing is that so that's how
you create this extreme programming I
don't remember where I read it somewhere
here so basically you create this
extreme programming and I anyway so you
create the extreme programming so you
create a concept of pair programming so
you get some programmers you know use
usually they work by yourself so you get
two programmers working on the same
project essentially you get them to
watch each other you know they are
programmers they know each other so so
it's it's like the communism in China
the red you know the red cards or the
Russia you know you get people to report
on each other that's the tactic you know
so you encourage of course when you say
extreme programming or agile you don't
actually say that you you say the
positive aspect you know like oh we
should collaborate program English with
well we should help each other you know
player programming allows you to learn
learn from you know each other's
mistakes you know and so that's the
extreme programming you encourage so you
read of you read of the qualities of you
know a great programmer learning stuff
you you you ignore that you emphasize on
collaboration help each other you know
bring out human potential things like
that so you so you encourage extreme
programming you also encourage like if
there if there's a bug like no you
discourage
responsibility rather you encourage like
one of the things stream programming or
agile say is that you want to you want
to let me show you the article okay sub
programming page programming extreme
programming you go to you go to hacker
code
okay so hacker code you will see agile
extreme voodoo diagram you see you see
whenever you see a code they always have
like a whole bunch of joggins almost
it's like you can recognize it like for
example in UNIX philosophy you have a
bunch of joggers you know then you you
know kiss keep it simple stupid small is
beautiful dry you know dry programmers
you know dribbling from their mouth dry
like like do not repeat yourself all
these Chagas when you see you you you
you can kind of always tell when there's
a code for formation of code lots of
jargons UNIX philosophy is one of the
example the UNIX people so look at this
extreme agile programming you know so
you have pair programming seconds unit
test yeah that's the important by the
way you know some of these are good you
know like of course the part of it them
are based on you know good things you
know that's all code is like that you
know you somewhere there are some truth
to it so anyway you see pair pair
negotiation then stand-up meeting
acceptance test iteration fat release
plan you know this [ __ ] you know they
they create these codes like you know
they dislike code always have their own
philosophy so this is at your diagram
and you can see some of the famous
people on on this on the topic agile and
extreme programming and this is not the
only this is not the only route diagram
there are others let me show you look at
this one okay okay
this is another one so you a jido t
agility is you know you got bunch of
circles like in young you know like
Taoism and you have visibility
accelerate accelerate delivery you know
a chili cheese strategy release
iteration daily continuous then come out
working software then you have
visibility and values adaptability
transparency simplicity unity you know
then your vision goes charter you know
this [ __ ] this this this is what you
know agile agile agile is the you know
the the the next generation it's evolved
from extreme programming pair
programming so they all came from
extreme programming okay that's a route
for some reason I don't know why for
some reason extreme programming the term
kind of went away then it became agile
probably because agile is more like code
like you know because agile came you
know usually code like jargons they can
mean many things like they can mean many
things you know each person we can take
it differently so you have agile
meanwhile extreme programming is kind of
you know maybe the term is not very
suitable because you know it's like
extreme sports you know it's like you
just do coding go crazy you know so
maybe that doesn't it's not suitable for
marketing so so the agile agile is most
suitable for marketing so maybe that's
why they become agile software so I have
collected a bunch of people who
criticize you know the extreme
programming you know it's officially
this guy programming [ __ ] okay
so he's got he's got you probably you
guys have seen this side right this is
very famous
'we did he I used to have punch you know
you used to have these graphics did he
remove that let's go to a manifesto
oh he removed that what this is
this zet show guy he's a great
programmer but he's also he's a pretty
weird but I like him
okay so maybe it's this site or bio
t-shirt [ __ ] he removed wait wait why
is this owner loading because of
JavaScript let's turn on javascript in
script blocked no okay refresh his
website instead but you know because the
firm part is that you see this black guy
with a gun from the movie this very
mature content yes you idiot [ __ ] [ __ ]
the social justice this way
okay so let's its turn on JavaScript
maybe so that's about extreme
programming there's a lot to say you
know I can talk about that for 10 it's
good yeah he's a website you know you
don't see what's going on oh there it is
okay
that that looks familiar programming
[ __ ]
do you speak it now he changed now you
see you see this shirt by the way this
is not original or the original one is
from the pope fiction
okay so let's look at let's let me show
you the pope fiction thing so you need
to turn on JavaScript then you need to
copy the world then you need to close it
open a new one search it again because
of the idiocy of toc-toc oh then now you
can click on images there it is also
originally it's his caddy sky who is
about to pop the guy this black guy you
know it's it became it has became a meme
okay so you know I I'm I'm trying to
find a picture where he pointing a gun
it's like that so in general it's it's
like picture like that so apparently I
was I suppose for copyright reasons he
changed so it's you know he so it looks
similar but it's not that picture
anymore but this but now his website you
don't even see the picture anymore for
some reason I don't know why maybe
because yeah and and you have these
spoken images I don't know what's going
on with him
he's got by the way he's on Twitter so
this guy is a great programmer this Z
show that show he's you know he's sway a
lot and he has written very popular web
server in Ruby community or was it
Python
yeah
Allen says the hacker code philosophies
is married with pop psychology we have
overlapping how they talk about people
society systems with wudu terms in dogma
as income and long b-beautiful hours so
I see his children and long beautiful
hours but what you mean
so hello beautiful people I am your boss
I do not know what you are doing I just
managed you yes so that's the extreme
program so in my opinion ok I so I mean
it's hard to say exactly because the
social issues there's no you know like
the answer it's not a math question so
input in my opinion that's the that's
the whole thing about extreme
programming and agile that's why they
become popular it's basically it's it's
it's a you know it's a social movement
so that the managers and also
corporations we could not you know like
Google Facebook corporations they get
control so they have control over the
programmers you know so so you
programmers becomes a it becomes a
school you know you know they can
unscrew you anytime kick you out we face
you you know it's like you become
nothing that that's that's what extreme
programming and agile is doing you know
they they focus on you know they rap you
know collaboration basically they get
you to watch each other's work and also
they remove responsibilities so like
before well if you are a programmer if
I'm lucema is responsible for this
project I created if it sells it's great
I should get a raise so you know I I you
know I will be greatly you know because
the the money made by company came for
me basically I'm the guy who created
created this software and if there's a
problem then I'm also responsible
because you know because there's a bug
major bug or something I'm responsible
for it that's normally think how things
are and how things should be you know
responsibilities and if you are good you
get rewarded for it you know if you are
no good you don't get reward you know if
you create lousy software that's it's
you know you don't you you get kicked
out or or you know you don't get reward
you don't get the raise things like that
but that's but the the but but the this
a Chow and and the extreme programming
they are trying to change that they
don't want that because because they
cannot control instead they want they
they want to create this concept which
is a lot of today's social justice
people are doing you know they thanks to
agile in the extreme programming they
want to create a system such that
individuality the person is no longer
important you know you as a person is
not not important today the corporation
the system is important you know so so
you you become just a cocking of wheel
you know you get you are we they want to
make you to be they want to make
programmers to be replaceable so they
focus on this you know social
collaboration kind of schema of all
things and they for example what happens
if there's a bug okay so before when
there's a bug who who created the bug
which [ __ ] which lazy programmer
which you know idiot created this bug he
will be responsible he will be fired
that is normal okay that's
responsibility but the odd job doesn't
do that they did you know they want to
fire whenever they want you know they
don't like you they want to create so so
when when there's a bug in the agile
community when we in agile way of
thinking is that okay anyone should fix
it right away
like like they have you know they have
one of the atacama like do not like when
there's a bug you should go fix it right
away do not you know focus on who you
know who created the problem you know
it's just so it's like you should you
know they don't focus on the person you
know we
who you know who did wrong who did good
they don't care they want to have like
everyone is the same everywhere everyone
is same when there is a bug the team
when you know fix just you should just
fix it that's you know that's the agile
in the extreme programming [ __ ] and
and and they become big they become like
why do they become big you know so
partly because the management the
cooperation you know it's good for the
corporation's you know because that way
they can sub program has become
something they can easily be placed you
know that important they want to create
this you know thinking to thread this
thinking so so to even to so when it
become successful so it becomes such
that even for average programmers they
will believe in you know this agile
extreme programming kind of thinking
just like open source open source you
know when when you see someone who is
not Pro open source you [ __ ] you [ __ ]
right you you you do all you can to you
know to to [ __ ] that's what that's
you guys open source in the same way
that's an extreme programming it you
create this massive you know basically
brainwashing propaganda social
engineering okay which is similar in my
opinion similar to the concept of
democracy of USA okay you know that
nobody even know what it means anymore
you just say democracy and you can
attack any country you don't like so
that's so that's my opinion about
extreme for women so and back to content
management back to the history of wiki
okay so the history of wiki so you have
week week MediaWiki then before that you
have you have what's called FAQ
automatic okay let me show you I don't
know if they still have entry in
Wikipedia
I think if I I don't remember for sure
but I think they had entry in Wikipedia
at the scene in the early days
it's called FAQ automatic okay let me
copy it and paste it here so where are
we so what's this page so back to close
that so go to consult today's San talk
show and paste week Wikipedia o matic
okay that's the thing and let's let's
paste for my blog close go back to here
what is this it's not important for
programmers okay yeah it's about the
extreme programming
so let's paste that that's the things we
talked about and yeah the history of
wiki so so before wiki wait like where
does the wiki concept came from it came
from FAQ automatic okay let me show you
what that that is so FAQ automatic so
this is the history of I'm trying to
find a Wikipedia page of it let's see if
we can still find that this is very old
you know this is like 2002 I I think I
remember there was a Wikipedia page
maybe if you read their wiki history
then you might find it let's see history
of wiki its search for FAQ wiki FAQ they
don't have it now so this is bad history
incomplete wiki you know FAQ automatic
is the not now we are talking about the
history of wiki software okay not the
wiki concept but the wiki software
wikiwikiweb okay so wiki wiki whatever
okay so I'm pretty sure you'll find the
world FAQ automatic in in Wikipedia
somewhere okay so let's say FAQ man you
have a queue so it's not here so anyway
there is this thing called FAQ o matic
which is you know is it's just a
cruise-o-matic what oh and FAQ o matic
so let's see so this is spec in year
2000 okay year 1991 2000 FAQ o matic
dotnet now that's something else yeah I
think is something else but anyway let
me tell you what it is
FAQ o matic basically it's a software
it's like one file single file pearl
yeah basically one file maybe 4,000
lines of pearl something like that so
you you put it on web server website it
uses the I mean it equates FAQ basically
creates a page of FAQ frequently asked
questions where each person everyone
anyone can contribute can edit part of
it you know that's that's what it is you
know so that's the idea so where does
FAQ o matic came from well before have
AQ o matic you have the concept of FAQ
which i talked about last week or two
weeks ago in my video you search for
sardine etiquette okay search for
network word dog sorry TRO on youtube so
i talked about that you know net
netiquette anthropology so castle talk
show netiquette anthropology so it's
this one south Axio 2019 October
eighteenth
netiquette anthropology at Ross
confection dead links and stoned okay so
that I thought that I show you this page
okay this this page is a lot of early
history of the internet so anyway so FAQ
so FAQ is
the is the most popular concept in 1990s
online its its faq is similar to today's
Wikipedia okay so you have tons of FAQ
FAQ some piano playing if any FAQ on
Saturn masochism you know the sex play
FAQ on Seavers first on see differential
on computational geometry functional
programming you have all these FAQ and
it's like today's Wikipedia it's full of
information
great information solid so you have FAQ
and FAQ is manually written by people
you know by editor so-called editor you
collect you know great content from your
forum page basically over the years and
it's very tedious if you are a blog
writer you know how tedious you know how
time consuming it is actually to create
to maintain you know a blog or website
it's a lot of work you have to edit lots
of edit you have to restyle wording you
have to you you know it doesn't work if
you just for example if you are
interested in C++ you know it doesn't
work if you just collect snippet you saw
every day it doesn't work because then
you have a page you have a book where
every pack paragraph is in entirely
different context and style by itself it
has solid information but it doesn't it
doesn't work so so to write FAQ or you
know it takes tremendous amount of work
you have to rewrite with style or
organize and you have to keep doing it
like every day you know because it get
us updated faster especially when you
when the document becomes law
so FAQ is very hard to maintain you know
typically you have usually it's one
single person but often on a forum for
example this complan Lisp or Emacs you
have like two or three people you know
regulars in that forum who collaborate
you know manage the FAQ so but it's
still tedious so daddy
how someone created this FAQ o matic you
know page a software pearl in power I
think it's really important one one file
per so that so now you have like
everyone of you can just go to the
website then edit you know on the fly
you know edit collaborative you know
interactive in real time so instead of
emailing to each other you know suppose
we have three person ABC we let's say we
manage keyboard FAQ you know mechanical
keyboard FAQ you know you have that on
reddit too you know hacker you know read
it r / r mechanical keyboard you know
you have a fake use like what's the best
mechanical keyboard how do you where do
you buy keycaps how do you buy artistic
here cabs you know where by where to buy
those you know the the tools and stuff
you know chips you know things like that
so so before in the 1990s when you have
faq it's tedious
you have three person you maybe you
email each other every day it's tedious
but now someone just created FAQ o matic
you know page you know you just go to
the website and edit you know in real
time so that is you know that is
fantastic that so that's a kind of
that's a big you know milestone in the
wiki in in a history of content
management system that's a that's a
first that's a first I would say yeah fa
fa q o matic I would I will consider
that's the first the very first content
management system I wish you know I wish
we can actually find who who created
that because it's a guy FAQ o matic ok
so maybe your sauce Forge maybe this
maybe this I don't know
okay that looks familiar
I think okay I think maybe this is the
one I don't know if I cannot be sure
it's original
I think that's a one okay bye FAQ o
matic was principally authored by
jang-ho well okay so so this side
documents the FAQ o matic the FAQ
America is a CGI's CGI based system yes
this is back in 1999 CGI based system
that automates the process of
maintaining a very q yes this is one so
from 1998 yeah so this is the one this
is the father of all content management
systems okay I'm glad I found it history
I haven't looked at this for 20 years
this is the one FAQ automatic you know
so it's just one page you know you can
all go it there edit so that's well
that's my story okay that that's what I
want to say so you have FAQ automatic
then you know once it's out there then
other programmers see it you know they
can create variations you know different
versions they they focus then they
create then it becomes wiki the the you
know FAQ o matic maybe it's true one
mouthful they you know the then the wiki
you know it's easier to pronounce they
become wiki for some reason I don't know
how exactly but anyway that's a this is
the father wiki so you have wiki then
you have you know then you have wiki
media you know media wiki you know and
so on
then you have the content management
systems okay so after so at at during
the time of wiki you started to have
blogs so the first you know the first
one is at the time it's a lived your
live journal live journal whole lives
you know how you however you pronounce a
live journal that's the first one and
then you have WordPress then you have
another one
I forgot then after a few years you have
blogger then Google part blogger you
have you know there's there's a lot
history of that
so that's about content management
system Oh another thing I should mention
is that as far as content okay so when
you talk about content management system
which I would include FAQ automatic ok
this is a first first one then there's a
kind of related concept about static
website generating system okay I think
that's they are kind of that they are
rather different okay so content
management system focus on creating a
website where people can go and edit
things
meanwhile the static website generator
system a focus is on you know creating
websites you know static website not
necessarily for you know people to
comment or edit basic Belize's but it's
a system for creating information you
know you've you know so you have several
of them okay anyone give me examples for
example there's you know many people use
oak mud plus they have hack check or
something like hide and jackals
something Oh act octopus something
what's the name guys and this is a kind
of you and vector or Victor Hugo yeah
Hugo is one of them you know static
website generation system so what's some
of the names guys static site generation
Chekov yes Chico Chico is one of them
yes and Hugo and cap CJ is I haven't
heard of that anyway so yeah that's one
of that's some of them so that's content
santak website generation system so
that's one thing so my my Emacs you know
system is kind of food like that static
website generation system you know for
creating a website so you create for
example you create your website you read
your blog in oak mud or mock down you
know which
is very easy then you can press a button
it generates the entire structure like
footers headers you know images things
like that link they link you know think
you know then you put it to a web
website
so so that's static website generation
system then do you have the content
management system okay so one more thing
I want to mention is that back in 1999
1997 1998 around that you have another I
would say the the earliest content
creation system which is called frontier
does anyone know that frontier on the
Mac if you know say it okay so check out
stone kid you can easily deploy static
sites stone kid okay so I don't know
what he said so I think maybe that's it
something that's anything else
how long I have I been talking let's see
if there's any I've been talking for one
hour okay so maybe that's that's that's
about today so we talked about FAQ of
automatic content management system okay
then there is static website generate
teen system that's not a proper term we
will find the proper term in a minute so
we have Hugo and Jake IO
for example that's examples so and
content management systems that's put it
here so content management systems then
agile an extreme programming and sigmund
keyboard
then we have adjoining extreme
programming then we talked about fe f AQ
o matic
history of content management system
okay then we have static website
generating system then we have the
father the grandfather of the
grandfather of content management system
is frontier
okay so frontier does anyone remember
okay I this this is frontier on a Mac
now let me let me find it okay so it's
by this guy Dave Winer okay so this dave
winer in my opinion he's a crackpot dave
winer there it is the story of frontier
jesus userland indeed that's a you know
we are talking about history of the
internet so frontier so what i'm going
to say is that frontier this is a
website frontier is the father in my i
would say it's a father of static
website generating system I actually am
expert of it because I use it yeah I
actually use it for like one year or two
years I know it very well I you know I
calling it this is before I started to
dive into Perl and UNIX frontier okay so
here are frontier frontier the father
the dad of static website generating
system
by Dave one whiner okay I know like the
guy I think he is a crackpot okay he's a
crackpot dave winer he is also the guy
who created RSS he invented RSS the the
notion okay so we're talking about
frontier okay the father which way okay
so what is frontier it's a it's on the
Mac it's originally saw its Mac only but
later on they put it they ported to
Windows but okay so you can I guess you
can read the history here yes you know
so you know he is trying to get he is
trying to sell it to Apple you know he's
trying to sell the frontier so it
replaces apples Apple script but it
didn't work out Apple didn't want it
eventually frontier frontier kind of
died but anyway he created RSS and
things moved on from there you know so
RSS picked up so he saw Dave Dave you
know dave winer he's you know I don't
like the guy I think he's a crackpot
he's one of the whoa
voodoo purveyor you know he's like Larry
whoa he gives you know he he tells
programmers a bunch of you know crap
like UNIX philosophy is a code code
formation kind of people kind of god
he's a garbage [ __ ] this guy
[ __ ] dave winer now by the way I
don't I don't think you know I by no
means disclaimer ok disclaimer I don't
think he's a criminal anything like that
this is just my opinion I don't like him
I think he's a [ __ ] disclaimer so
anyway so Dave Winer that's a guy you
know this is a crackpot and story of the
front here anyway so
can we actually see a picture of
frontier somewhere and what maybe it's
somewhere here
yeah so be beheaded back then so anyway
so this is 19
you know 1997 also and I would say
frontier is the father of content static
website generating creation system ok so
that's about that so sorry of frontier
did I have it here yeah so ok so let's
close that so what it does what it do is
that you you know just like you know
today if you are a Mac user you use oak
mod you know you can have a directory of
oak ma files you know you you know you
don't have to learn complicated markup
like you know like this you know
incomprehensible you know you simply
writing a you know simple markup things
like that special you know for example
in oak mod for example if you want to
create a header you just say something
you know then that's a header if you
want a you know subtitle subsection you
just do that then you can say hello
every one
today's weather is good
sunny and stuff and I went to shopping
ok
so you have a directory full of that
then you press a button it becomes HTML
and with with links images you know the
generates for you so frontier is kind of
like that but you know right now I'm
doing this in Emacs but frontier is kind
it has its own it's application you know
you today you call it an application you
know you anyway so frontier I don't know
if it still exists in some form or not I
don't know but but that's a fun T ok so
so I think that's it for today Dave Dave
Winer FAQ o matic netiquette history of
that
talk-show faq o matic is math important
for programmers okay extreme programming
any comments say it now okay I think
we're gonna close in five minutes so
Alan says can you contrast Wikipedia
style of knowledge document document
document II versus the Stanford
encyclopedia of philosophy style for
example crowdsourcing versus having
single author extra sauce sauce pages
okay so yeah so that's a that's a big
topic like where to begin with that well
I mean I think you need both okay like
we have to specify like what what
exactly what perspective perspective are
we taking in general you need both
I mean Wikipedia I mean we keep Vidya
the reason it thrives is because anyone
like you have seven billions of people
human animals on earth anyone take
anyone you know they can they can start
to edit comment you know so that's you
know they you co it you know there's a
jargon these days you call it like since
10 years ago you call it mob wisdom mob
you know how they call it mob yeah
there's a term like mob wisdom or
something on or something you know
basically which which does have some
basis because you have a lot of people
you know you want to you know one thing
difficult about writing is that it's
like where to begin that's the that's
the difficulty about writing like like
for example you guys many of you maybe
you are expert at you know some language
you are expert at something right you I
mean each but it's difficult to write a
book because like where to begin
like like if you are just chatting to me
immediately you can you know I asked you
a question like how do you like for
example I can ask you any question then
you can answer right away
oh that one do you just do it this way
you know and other people can ask you
questions you can answer right away but
it's difficult for you to write a book
because immediately you have this this
war like where to begin then you have to
think about what what topic you want to
cover you know that there's a problem so
on the other hand if you have a wiki the
thing is you don't have to think
anything you just start like you know
like if I start a wiki you know the
first page you know for example suppose
I'm going to say I'm going to have a
list article about list history I can
just say I can start to create an agro
history of list oh and and and the
entire article is just one sentence
dismiss created by this guy in 96 1960s
or something by this Chong something
that's it this is created by this Chong
something guy in 1960s that's it you see
that's a beauty of wiki wiki because you
don't have to be perfect you know you
you you break the war there's no war you
just begin any any minor thing like even
a correction of one word of spelling
mistake or a typo anything is a little
increment advance you know then someone
saw so that oh then they can you know
you save Jang they can find that what's
his name John you know what's his name
the guy who created this you know you
take text time like each little detail
takes you know five minutes time to
think about but if you are doing it
yourself you don't have it's like a
burden you know like the whole thing you
have to deal with but so people start to
correct miss pairings perfect the
grammar you know correct typos then you
know then create the precise state the
young guy who thought about least then
somebody else added you know maybe your
another descendants then you grow that
that's how that's that's the power
that's that's the heart that's why we
keep Vidya is successful because you
have billions and people each one you
you don't have war anymore anyone can
contribute a little thing that's the
power that's a beauty
now of course it has flaws the flaws is
that you it's not it's not managed by
expert that means often you first of all
you have vandalizes right you have
people who have strange opinions like me
you know i go to i go to wikipedia ok I
go to Wikipedia
I see UNIX philosophy page ok then they
have a grand history how great UNIX
philosophy is oh it's you know it's
created by this guy that guy you know
UNIX philosophy small it's beautiful how
this is the foundation of modern modern
computing FLAC you know these [ __ ] it's
so I go there I say oh I cross this out
I say no this is wrong I started to put
my own opinions you know so so that is a
flaw of Wikipedia you know you you
especially today you have you know
social justice scan and you have us you
know you have government the power
powerful entities they can have
thousands thousands of people who try to
do edit war you know to try to create to
make certain articles you know fake news
you know to be favorable to them anyway
so so the problem we with Wikipedia is
there's no authority I mean no certified
you know we're a recognized expert to to
to put a stamp on it that's that's
that's kind of the flaw
so on the other hand you have something
like in Stanford encyclopedia of
philosophy
or you know traditionally you have the
encyclopedia
Britannica where you have it's written
by you know hundreds of top experts in
respective fields so you have
mathematicians you know focusing
focusing on various various categories
of math you know topology analysis
geometry algebra you know in history of
math you have experts writing each you
know overseeing or being an editor for
each you know hundreds of articles on
those then you have historians economics
you know and so on
and so so you really truly get experts
you know quality information truly
expert you know so so one of the problem
with Wikipedia like even today even
though in many ways it's the information
and quality is far superior than any
encyclopedia you know the quality or the
quantity Wikipedia today is in fact
better than Encyclopedia Britannica the
entire Encyclopedia Britannica I would
say okay both quality and quantity all
things considered I would claim I would
say it's better than Encyclopedia
Britannica for example if I can only
have one of them so suppose I have
digital access to Encyclopedia
Britannica entirety of it all the
Wikipedia I can only have one I would
today I would pick Wikipedia okay even
despite all its flaws oh it's fake news
oh it's you know as I will still pick
Wikipedia because I consider it's the
quality and quantity is better than the
professional management you know the you
know Britannica today so but anyways so
the problem we with Wikipedia even today
is the concept for many articles the
content tends to be like incoherent
potshots
you know like you gotta be especially
for topics you are not familiar with you
know I'm going to assume for example I'm
going to assume you don't know math you
know let's say complex analysis okay
so complex analysis which is a branch of
math okay all right let's let's assume
you didn't you know what nothing about
it but you want to learn you know you
want to learn about it so you go to
Wikipedia you started to see like kind
of this and it's factually correct okay
everything is factually it's good
content you know quality but however you
don't get the coherent picture of what
is it about like what the [ __ ] is it
what and you know you want to know what
the [ __ ] is complex analysis in math but
you go to Wikipedia you have this you
know turns up you know 10 pages long
article with hundreds of links you don't
get the picture like what what like what
are you trying to you know you don't get
the picture like it talks about you know
you know some part of it is history some
part of it is research level things
about the topic you know some part of it
is you know curiosity information it's
still good you know you still solid
information but is that's a problem with
Wikipedia you know you don't you don't
get you know you don't get you don't get
a coherent picture so you know so in
this case so so in this case it would
help if you have some professional
mathematician you know who oversee you
know who is kind of taking
responsibility as the editor of that
page then then things fall into you know
more coherent you know esoteric you know
so you get forth first of all you have a
coherent introduction on what is complex
analysis then you can have you know
links to more in-depth you know for
example complex analysis for
differential geometry point of view you
know from geometry point of view from
algebra point of view the history of it
or you know notable theorems you know
then you you have a coherent picture so
but so as to how do we fix it I don't
know how to fix it you know it's kind of
open question maybe there is no no
answer you know how like how do you fix
Wikipedia so that you you know you you
can you can maybe you can you know so
you can have some kind of actual
authority you know some expert you know
opinions to make it more coherent I
don't know how to I'm not sure there's a
answer to that so that's so that's my
answer to that question that's my
opinion
so I think that's it for today let me
read the comments and that that's it one
hour and 22 minutes
okay so comments so my website is just a
static website and it's just created in
Emacs and created in sapphire keys and
saw HTML mod and also with the help of
several script in Python in perl in :
and in Magnus they help for example I
have a for example I for example I have
a script and right now it's in : it's
also it was in Perl then I have a golden
version you know I write this in several
languages over the years over the past
20 years for example let's go to local
so this script now it's in : so this is
the : script 220 lines what it does is
that it will select run in so it will
check all
in this website so they are like 3030
30,000 files about 10,000 rht ml files
the others are images and CSS and
JavaScript and so on so you know some
30,000 files in this directory and let's
check all HTML or XML files let's run it
so if I have a bad link like local link
that's linked to non-existent file you
know tell me so I'm running it you'll be
turning night in one minute you know in
30 seconds so I have several this script
to help me out
so my website is basic it's basically
static or static and there's some
JavaScript some on some website let me
show you sorry
let's go to Unicode arrow search for
único arrows this is my most popular
page on my website of all my websites
único arrows [ __ ] now these people is
checking over me so you go to unicode
arrows it should my should be the first
he was the first it was the first on
Google search I think Google com
let's try it
unicode arrows ok please make my birth
page first yay actually you know because
I'm laughing so Google tells me what
what is this search performance for this
query [ __ ] google creeks 766 impressions
1.71 k this is the past 7 days average
position so my website is still number
one
yay you know this then these other
people just they just copy you know they
just copy your website then they you
know that's what people can do on the
web so anyway and they anyway so so my
website so for example único so actually
so my website is static but you have
interactive for example if you want to
find or emoji that contains the word
water you just type W a T in real time
so this is all Unicode characters that
contains the word W 80 in their name
so let's find something more interesting
let's say + okay I want to find all
words that contains what o Unicode that
contains the word + PL us okay so so
apparently you have lots of
incomprehensible so Cooney foam wait it
should show up I don't know why is it
not showing the font this is [ __ ] let's
go to Safari anyway you should see it on
your browser I think I hope so so my
website is static website but there is
some interactivity but that's JavaScript
that's funny so that's it for today
thank you for guys for coming by
Sacramento yes yeah maybe I should move
to Sacramento yeah that would be yes
extreme programming Thank You Allen for
the super chat
my guys
mob programming no I have not heard of
that
by