Hello guys, welcome to another episode
of Exile Talk Show. We are going to talk
random. So if you've been following me,
you might like it. If you do not know
who I am, then you probably going to get
confused. So this is for my fans.
So-called by the way fans it seems that
the ethmology of fans came from
phonetics. Uh so we are going to do
random. Okay. So I wanted to show you
some of the things
uh I did you know I've been what I've
been working on. Hold on a second.
So, that was my alarm clock. Tells me to
get up, get my fat ass up every 30
minutes and walk. because I've been
typing so much my hand is I'm going to
become a
So fan ethmology of fan let's
look up
uh look up ethmology of
fan device to make air. Okay. Then uh
then fan two devote. Oh, that's a good
alternative word. Devote
1889. American English originally of
baseball enthusiasts. Oh, probably a
shortening of phonetic, but it may be
influenced by the fancy collective term
for followers of a certain hobby or
sport. Let's magnify.
uh especially boxing. Okay. Fan
phonetics see fancy but not necessarily
you see you see the ethmology of fan the
history of the word the origin probably
it says a shortening of phonetic. Okay.
There is an isolated use from 1682 but
the modern word likely is late 19th
century that means 1800s formation. Fan
mail attested from
1920 in Hollywood context. Fan club
attested in
1930. Okay. So this fan my fans you guys
are some kind um are like from
uh from late 1800s 19 early 1990s. Okay.
And it
may be came from phonetic but not
necessarily. Devotey might be a good
word but well actually no because you
know if I say you guys are my fans it
would be incorrect to say you guys are
my devotees but because devotees
actually carries uh somewhat more
serious meaning kind of like religion.
So hello I don't know fantastic new talk
show emac hi
Louis which Louis are you I think you
are the Louis that that liked my Twitter
often right you are the Louis uh let me
show let me show by the way I want to
mention Scott is a great guy Scott just
bought a new keyboard this one fantastic
this key K2 Edg G H wireless magnetic
switch. Okay, it's using whole effect
switch. So whole effect is a you know
magnetic switch and it's very good. So
and uh Scott is a
professional bit diddler. Okay. Scott is
a like he been coding for like 20 30
years and he's a great American I would
say great American Christian and he he
does um you know professional coding and
he codes um he doesn't he doesn't post
random stuff but anyway he he he design
like GPU and CPU so it's like deep
professional
level that's what you Scott. So Scott is
being bought a new keyboard.
Fantastic. Uh oh yeah, Louis. So let's
go back to see if I can see Louis.
Uh Louis like which one are you? Luis
Mike Benz. Fantastic guy. This
guy transparent
transparency. By the way, if you are
watching my uh stream offline, play at
1.5 speed because I ramble. So 1.5 speed
is perfect. So let's let's one thing at
a time. So let's not forget um Luis uh
which which
Luis because the Luis I remember you you
are on Kasar
Discord and uh you know so I have some
memory of you know who you are and but
then there's another Louis so that's
confusing
uh this you know this Fox Cosby post
always
posting
Um anyway, you see the one thing about
online this, you know, like we started
to have this online situation about 15
or 20 years ago is that all these people
I learned eventually, you know, look at
my past, you know, 10 years or more
interaction with people like most most
of the time like you can't have anything
to do with them. I mean like you guys
like I mean what I mean is that the the
the you know because of the technology
we got into a situation that any person
can have like a million followers you
know literally many of these you know
so-called influencers or grifters they
have a million or several million
followers and for small people like me I
have like 5,000 followers right and you
guys know me but so My experience is
like you know so looking back like you
don't like so I'm talking about you as
well so when you go to go online you
know you see a bunch of people some of
them you might have you know start to
talk and know a little
bit but but what but what I want I want
to say what I think is that um this kind
of online relationship they like they
don't actually mean anything. They in
fact they doesn't do any do you any good
in real life. They kind of just waste
your time.
So So I'm thinking what? So Louis,
where's Louis? So So I'm thinking what
I'm saying is that um Oh, Luis, are you
the Louis Mayor? This guy the new Emacs
for
success.
Uh are you are you this Luis? So anyway,
so I'm thinking you know online you when
you go online social networks you you
know you see like literally thousands of
people and some of them let's say a 100
or 50 of them you might started to have
chat and and know somewhat
um and what I'm thinking is that they
kind of I mean this online activity they
are really just wasting your time
looking back from my experience in the
past you know 10 or 30 years I started
to use online chat back in like
1991 okay
1991 there's different medias uh you
know so looking back these online
interactions with like diverse people
you don't know like very diverse like
like each of us like you have no idea
what they are uh where they came from
their background their cultural
background religious background, their
racial background and also they are all
different. I mean can be very different
like you cannot possibly imagine your
attitude is not the same as they they
see different things you know like they
grew up in like people you don't know
like like in entire different
environments and also um if you are into
programming I suppose most of you okay
you are that Louis I I guess yeah
because you interacted with me a lot
thank you so what I'm saying is that
when you know these online
people. So for us I talk about coding
right? So I know you know many of you
uh but I mean so in
general the people I mean even if you
have the same interest in coding let's
say Python
but but coding itself has become so
diverse you know like you know there are
lot a lot professional programmers but
you really code different things and
your interest in let's say even in the
same language language Python you code
different things like some are you know
really really very different and the
degree of coding is also very
different so what I'm saying is that
this online people you you know you go
online you know you know they it doesn't
do you really do you any good and also
you don't really learn anything from
from online
crowd like you for example Let's say
Python, you know, I'm too old to follow,
you know, this the pop stars, you know,
so but they are like Python, you know,
influencers or JavaScript influencers or
influencers or Golang or whatever. So
they get reasonably amount of followers.
Let's say
uh let's say you know 10,000 or 50,000
like coding stuff, you don't get that
many followers. So anyway you listen
like like or if you go to hacker news
you know some of the programming
group you think that you are learning
new stuff but not really it's just
wasting time okay like if you really
want to learn Python or whatever like
you just read a book or tutorial just
focus on that so what you need to do
instead
is I you know some somewhat not not
fully that that I think that just ignore
more ignore all these social media
especially things like Twitter you know
like you you you don't know who they are
uh you know
like I I don't mean you guys okay I
enjoy you guys company but I mean
seriously most of you guys um I don't
know really who you are and uh yeah
anyway so that's kind of what I'm
thinking
you know looking at back looking back
you know past 20 30 years what did I you
know get from online really it's more
like a chat the you know the human need
to
chat so yeah anyway so it's so it's kind
of like the kind of the activity we do
every day so if you don't to go online
if you don't go online. I mean if you
suppose that going online talking to
these people, you know, different people
is a waste of time. So if you stop doing
that, then what you do? You're going to
waste time anyway because you started to
to to play some games, you know, like
which is not bad, but you started to do
random things, you know, that's like
kind of a human need, I think.
Okay. So that's uh some random chat. So
we talked about the ethmology of
fan. Very interesting. So I wanted to
show you some of my uh what I've done.
So my JavaScript tutorial I have added
um wait the font is not big enough. So
let me increase the
font. Am I going am I going? Is
everything good? So, I'm going to answer
the questions, okay? In a bit. Let's say
133. Okay. Mega
big. So, my JavaScript tutorial I added
a table of contents. So, this is
JavaScript in depth. This is one of my
like best professional
tutorial and uh uh so now there's table
of contents. So basically a list of like
all articles
uh and yesterday or two days ago I did
one talk show about the JavaScript
object system. So that's a very
condensed one and uh so far I think 300
people watched pretty
good. So anyway so I you know so table
of contents so check it out. Okay
JavaScript in depth then I also have so
I did add that I also added Python
tutorial uh table of
contents. So I started Python tutorial
back in
2005. Same thing with my JavaScript
tutorial
2005. Uh so check it out. Okay.
So so what else? So, and Wuam language
of course my favorite language my first
language for the first 10 years
beginning in 2000 uh beginning in 1992 I
started
coding learning Wufam language and I
coded up to
1997 including a summer intern at Wuam
research
so that's literally kind of my first
language But actually my first language
is HP28 calculator calculator language
called
um reverse polish notation
lisp. So that's a that's a good
one but anyway I just coded you know uh
like for a couple of years to you know
just little programs but the real
language my first language is wufam
language. That is why my perspective on
programming is a bit different. It's
quite different from the average
industrial coders because I came from a
math
background. So, Wuam language in depth I
added table of contents. So, you can see
there's like you know maybe a hundred
articles everything you need to know.
This is like Wuam language in
depth. Yeah. Well, kind of in depth
because I teach you the how this
language works which is very different.
It's a symbolic term rewriting system.
So it's a term rewriting system that's a
computer science jargon that what what
what does that mean? term reing system.
It just means that every
syntax every time you call a function
when you do computation you basically
just replace your source code by some
other source code. You define some
rules. You know like every time you
write a function is basically defining
rules
for syntactical replacement just like
find and replace of text or regular
expression but instead of doing just on
strings you do with the whole source
code. So you write syntactical
replacement rules that's how you define
a function. So every time you call a
function that just means the woofam
language tries
to you know replace the what whatever
the argument expression by some rules
you have defined and replace it again
and again until the result no longer
changes. So this is called term
rewriting system and is the foundation
of in fact the foundation of functional
programming like lambda calculus and
combinator. Okay, lambda calculus and
combinator they are theor theoretical
foundations and what they do term
rewriting like when you see lambda this
you just and body you just replace that
by that then you came out a new
expression you keep doing this term
rewriting so-called or just find and
replace so that's a and and lambda
calculus
uh and and combinator is basically the
same thing I term rewriting. So, wuam
language is an actual language that does
term writing and
symbolic symbolic one which is different
from non symbolic such as you know I
started to learn the ling proof system
fantastic I'm doing it slowly I mean I'm
a slow learn learn learner kind of well
I'm well anyway so I I I I've been you
know reading lean fantastic So I
recommend
it. So most of you guys are young people
so you got a lot of time. So am I still
doing well coding? Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Say
hi
guys. So I'm going to read the comments.
Okay. So uh I don't know says I have a
question. So GNU Emacs is in
Uganda. Yeah. Uh yeah. So I don't know
says I have a question. You often hint
at the fact that you
think that Pearl is badly designed both
on your YouTube and your blog. That is
correct. But you never elaborate on what
makes it badly designed. Okay, I'll talk
about
that. There's no question about that.
It's so simple because you know because
for that my opinion is almost similar to
everyone because you just look at
everyone's opinion on pearl general in
general it's just like you know the the
syntax is
unreadable basically making it so-called
right only you know you you write it one
time by next month you came back you
forgot what it's exactly it's doing
because it has got all these cryptic and
short syntax
That's Pearl and Pearl people you know
the Larry war pearl was the most popular
language for like 15 years like the most
popular like today's Python you know for
15 years from about
1995 to I would say 2010 the most
popular language and most the websites
in that era is written in pearl okay
then it got replaced by PHP then Python
took over Pearl for scripting and
stuff. Shell scripting. Um, yeah. So,
Pearl today kind of died. Okay. So, why
is it bad? It just extremely lousy, you
know. So, okay. So, let me let me go
back to the talk show. So pearl
tutorial there is a camel cookie ugly
loathome unly hacking it supports team
toy it sports and transports steam wits
fancy you know so you might be wondering
what is this team toy and what is this
DWIM those are jarens from the pearl
community because they they love this
like cryptic like nonsensical juvenile
jarens. So Tim to what does it mean? It
means do what I mean. Okay. So like um
team to
um what does it stand for the full
um oh dream stand for do what I mean?
Okay team to stand for there is more
than one way to do it. Okay, that's that
you so both of these uh pearls slogan
there is more than one way to do it. Tim
told okay and dream stand for do what I
mean. So so these two phrases together
kind of describe
pearl the philosophy if you will. So it
you know so it has like tons of
variation of syntax and usually very
short
cryptic and according to the pearl
fanatics they think that you know so
this you know there is more than one way
to do it. So they kind of they they they
refuse they attack they
um they deny they uh dismiss the
computer
science oriented concept
of of orthogonal design. that is when
you write when you have an algorithm you
want to implement
it usually
it's you know it's kind of believed to
be a good thing there's only one way to
do it
so you know so you don't you you know
you don't have like several ways to do
exactly the same thing which python
people which kind of like uh promote you
know the glossen you know just one way
you know we try to have it only one way
but actually that's not possible anyway
but that's like the general feel it is
technically not possible to just have
one way to do things when that thing
becomes a little bit more complex you
know like if you want to do one +
one I mean even that you have multiple
ways in in C in pearl in in in Java in
Python you know you can plus+ one or one
plus you
like 1 plus one or one + one, you know.
So you you have multiple ways to do it.
But in general, when a task gets when
the algorithm or the or the
implementation gets a bit complex, this
is like usually more than one way to do
it. But however, you can still try to
stick with the principle of a language
design such that in general when you
want to do something, there's just one
way. Okay? for example, get the get the
first element of a least, you know, but
even that you have several ways. But
anyway, so Pearl language they thrive,
they thrill, they, you know, they they
are like against computer science like
they are like they are outside of the
box, you know, they they they they pride
they pride themselves that way like the
Unix you know, the Unix
proponents, the Unix, you know, the the
Unix philosophy
idiots. They so pearl you know there
like part of the pearl slogan there's
more than one way to do
it and then then then they do what I
mean you know so it means like you just
type this and it'll do like exactly what
you mean like you don't have
to what they mean is that by is for
example the contrast is Java very
verbose you know the Java
language okay so for example Example the
Java
language Java uh let's say print string
you know like public class then public
static void
main you have to like spell it out then
string capital string then then bracket
means it's array argument then system
outprint ln line you know very like very
specific and
verbose Java like Java is like the
opposite of pearl. You can say that like
in Java there is only one way to do
something that's kind of true. Okay. So
but very verbose and then people say you
know you get a situation where you have
template coding like if you are if you
just want to print something then you
have you need this entire template
public class print me public static void
main you know and system out so Java you
know very verbose and very everything is
explicit and almost one way to code it
but pearl is the opposite it you know do
what I mean it means you know cryptic
syntax you have so many varieties you
can do it this way or that way and then
they say do what I mean that means you
just type this and it will act you know
even you it doesn't say like print
system you know outprint line but it
actually does what you want it that's
what they say you know that's what they
claim they design it's a hack it's not
even design language you So, so print.
So, for example,
print. So, the so anyway, so what uh do
I have a print even? I should have. No.
Yeah, my my pearl tutorial is like
quickly wrote up. Uh anyway, so pearl is
one of my first language after wufam
language. I started to code pearl
professionally from
1997 to to about 2003.
like in a in a corporation, you know, we
we wrote the first e-commerce system
like the one you would be using at
Amazon.
So anyway, pearl that's so that's why so
it's like full of you know so let me let
me show you so example of like these
pearls um way okay so let's go let's
search one liner
okay so you got this um what you know so
uh let's go
back what is one line what is one liner
uh code
golf obuscation contest you know code
golf is very popular back then you know
for 20 years I don't know today you
zoomer here that much but code golf
means
that you know it's like a competition
you want to create the shortest code
possible to do something you know that's
code golf you know like analogous to
golf the game then pro you know So P pro
pearl is the pearl community they are
very fond of this oneliner like in other
languages Java Java to to open a file do
find replace you need like 10 20 lines
in Python you need five lines in pearl
one line you know like so pearl people
are very proud of that but then it's
like cryptic okay so uh so let me show
you so yeah so let me show you some code
this is like my rant about you know this
is this article is back then
uh what 2022 I think it's much earlier
uh it must be much earlier where I
um I kind of summarized anyway but look
at this one okay you this this article
from year 2000 so online you know I was
online back in year 2000 news groups. Uh
so they there's this guy you know they
are posting this all the time like in
year 2000 pearl is the most popular
programming language among C C++ and
pearl okay so these three are the most
popular language for like 15 20 years
Pearl so you know these people like
today you know you can you know you guys
can imagine today what is the most
popular everyone is talking about that's
the situation for 20 years for pearl. So
one guy posted you know this you
know you know the pearl version is
oneliner you know someone is posting a
question and this guy is just hey look
look pearl it's just this
line that's that's you know and then
Eric Nagam a famous guy you know he
retort pearl is pearl looks the you know
let me so let me read it so because this
will tell you
how me and other people you know those
who don't like Pearl
uh Pearl's problems crit criticism okay
so Eric Nangum says Pearl looks the way
it does
because 110 board
teletypes were once upon the time the
best people had on Unix and with lousy
typers who had to correct their mistakes
all the time it made sense to abbreviate
everything down to one or two
characters. Lisp has a different
heritage to put it
mildly. Better typers, better user brain
power than to remember thousands of
certainly similar
abbreviations and better
terminals. So we so we are not as
interested in oneliners with compact
syntax. But for people who still live
their lives as if all they can hope for
is a 300 board teletype, the value of
oneliners cannot be underestimated.
Okay, that's Eric Nagam's rent against
Pearl. So he he
associated this cryptic lousy crap short
compact syntax as because because back
then the people you know like you have
to imagine you know back in 1980s you
know your whole screen is is like 80
characters by 40 lines or even 25 lines
only. So anyway, he associated to the
the you know old slow terminals and and
things but but I don't but my view is
not like that. Okay. I think pearl I
think oneliners is fantastic. Why?
Because in wufam language everything is
one single line. Okay. If you write a
program that is let's say
1,00 you know uh lines of code. Okay.
But in fact you can make it one line. In
fact it's one single line because the
way woof language is functional
programming is basically a sequence of
functions. Sequence pipe pipe a function
pipe to function you know like a
function call a value
um input to function then output then
input to function. This is like one
single line. Entire woofam language is
kind of like that. And in fact you can
any woofam language program actual code
you can actually make it one single line
like one one like lisp okay kind of like
exactly like lisp okay one single line
and functional programming okay so I
actually think that the oneliner is a
good thing okay but not m but not the
short characters so wuam language every
name every function name is very long
very descriptive so in that sense it's
like Java okay so for
example function names you see these are
all string functions boolean string by
array to string date string display
string DMS string end of string export
string front end resource string string
pad left string start string partition
you know
so all you have to know do of what
something does. Just read the function's
name and there is no other syntax.
There's no operators. Well, there is,
but anyway, but but in principle,
everything in full wam language is
function call. There's no class or
method. Everything is just function. So,
all you have to do to know what a
program does is just read off the
function names. That's it.
In fact, lisp is like that. Okay. Wuan
language is like a branch of
lisp. So, so opposite to pearl. So,
pearl. So, let's go back to the this,
you know, this pearl one line one liner.
Okay. So, you see that's what it is. You
know, pearl one line liner. So in my
opinion the one on one liner is a great
thing. Okay. And this is the same thing.
This is Wuam language doing exactly the
same thing this pearl code is doing.
Okay. See
that and you can turn you can change the
syntax into the fully nested form. So
this code here is exactly equivalent to
that because before wam language runs it
will convert any of these operator
shorthand syntax to this fully nested.
So this code wam language is equivalent
exactly like that to the compiler
because before it does anything it
converts this to this. So you can but
you can write in both ways you know
nobody actually write you know in like
that this is like more like the full
lisp syntax
okay so in pearl if I want to do this in
pearl here is my translation okay like
the full more powerful version of
whatever this guy is posting that's my
opinion you know because you know back
then I was the I was a Pearl
expert, you know, I read I read like 10
books, all the books possible published
at the time of Pearl
um you know, so Pearl Books. So I talked
about this a few times, Pearl Books
survey 2002 and I got the guy Larry Ward
to sign one of my
book. So you can see you know this pearl
books this pearl programmer's companion
this is around year 2000 okay uh
learning pearl
from Mac pearl um power and ease this is
before Mac became
macosx unix based mac os so you have
classic mac and you don't have you have
a port of pearl to
mac which is different from the normal
pearl on Unix. So then then you got this
advanced pearl programming. That's my
favorite book of of all pearl books.
Then you have effective pearl. You know
some of these people they they
disappeared because I've looked. Then
this very popular pearl p cookbook very
thick about this
thick. Uh and this this is like the
fundamental classic by Larry Wall
himself. Pearl programming pearl or
righty and then then there's you got
algorithm with pearl and regular
expression very popular
book so these books are very popular
again this is around year 2000s okay I
read them all okay like some of them few
times so I was a master of
pearl so when I see this oneliner um so
where is the one one liner so let's
the yeah this pearl one liner you know I
think it's idiotic
but it's because
pearl cannot do um anyway it's you know
cryptic and and
stuff so anyway that's the I hope that
answers your question you know pearl the
nature of pearl and this is actually
this is the reason Pearl died you know
Pearl So you know they say oh we have
cryptic syntax we have shortage syntax
and we are like do what you mean we have
more than one way to do it they are
proud of it but
ultimately this killed pearl because in
real life coding or in real computer
science you can't you you can't really
have this you know like do you know
what do what I mean you know cryptic
unreadable
Okay, I think maybe that's it for
today. I think that's it for today. How
am I doing?
human interact with human. So it depends
to be honest. I think at the beginning
you learn a lot but then you reach a
level where you don't get much from
online blogs. Yeah, that's true. Uh that
is many uh that is in many communities
that the most favorite tool become the
best. Mhm.
So I talked for 41 minutes. Let me do
one more thing. You see this my power
tutorial. There's no table of contents.
Let's add one. Okay. So now this is more
like Emacs. How do I work on my website?
Emacs workflow demo. Okay. So first of
all open that show in browser pro
tutorial. So I want to add table of
contents just like my
um you know just like my woof language
full of table of contents or my Python
programming tutorial full of table of
contents. So let's do that for pearl.
Okay. Okay. So uh so this is the page.
So uh first of all update the date. Do
that. Press a key show the pink window
shows my command calls and keystrokes on
the left. I'm using kasfly
keys kafly keys and I'm using a vora
keyboard layout. So here is kasfly keys.
Okay, you can that's the most efficient
key binding in EMAC. Okay, so pro
tutorial table of contents. So uh add a
section table of contents. Okay.
Capitalize first word. Delete. Delete.
Delete that. And uh copy the entire
panel. Paste there. Then select the
whole section. Narrow to region. So I
only see this
section. Okay. Then I want to add uh I
want to find replace add a new line to
the beginning of ul. Then do that again.
Add a new line to the be to the end of
ul. Okay. Okay. So that's good. Then
this navigation bar. Delete it. Delete
that. Uh and uh let's see. Okay. Now
expand all. So I can see the full buffer
content. Now show in browser. You kind
of got the table contents. Basically
it's done. But now I want to rename this
you know now this is a matter of kind of
style I want to rename to the files full
title name. Okay. So let's go up
here. Uh so actually so for example you
see the first section per version string
version history help system file name
extension. So I want to rename because
if you open the version
stream this is how you can uh
print the pro uh the version pearl is
running. Okay, version is kind of the
most important thing when you learn a
new language because when you learn a
new language let's say
F there are so many version like you
don't know what is the current version
what what the version you know is the
current or you know and you know what
version you have on your system maybe
for example in the case of pearl on
Linux mini Linux came with pearl you
want to know what version and also you
want to know like uh version history,
you know. So, I have this version. What
date is that? Like, you don't know. So,
usually you that's that's what you need.
You need how to print version, version
history, and how to get help. That's one
of the first thing you learn anyway. So,
go back here. You click version string.
The full title is actually print version
string from script. Oh, yeah. That's
what you want because on the command
line so for example on the comm command
line magnify you can always type um you
can always get a version
right you know so that will tell you
pearl
version you know pearl d- version
similar for ruby python you know but
this but when you run a pearl code it
actually may not be running whatever
that is. So you want to know what that
is in in in Windows, you do
GCM GCM pearl. Okay, that will tell you
I'm running when you type pearl
something that's actually in this
directory you might have several others.
Okay, so but when you run a script, it
could run some other things than this.
So what you want to know is in a script
you want to be able
to print the version number that is
actually running. So for example uh I
can open that this file. So search for
pre. So you see this part. Okay. Now I
pop it out and run it. So you see it
tells me I'm running this uh
5.321. Put it back. syntax color syntax
color showing all. Okay, so
that's why it's important to be to know
how to print version from within a
script. Okay, but so now remember the
full title is that go back to the
tutorial. Uh wait, go back to the
tutorial. I want the full title in all
these links. Okay,
so close. Okay. So now you see there now
I do press press you got the full title
showing browser you see full title now.
So, it's a matter of style. You
know, I used to be, you know, remove
this redundant pearl, pearl, pearl,
pearl. Like, of course, this page is
about
pearl. But actually, I prefer this
because this way allows you to
systematically change names for your
entire website. And also, sometimes you
have some
other, you know, on this pearl page, we
are talking about pearl. Yes. But
sometimes you do have some other issues
like pearl compared to Python you know
uh so the title will be so that
indicates tell you oh this article is
actually not specifically just about
pearl but also about something else so I
want a full title okay so let's
do do that do that okay so you can see
the command is s html re relink that's
just my personal command do Do that.
That's Emacs. Okay. Do that. Do that. Do
that. Do that. And modules. Do that. And
advance. Do that. Okay. And last one. Do
that. Okay. And showing browser. Now you
can see all of them become full title.
But there's more to do. Okay. So for
example, list and array. Pearl list and
array.
There's quite a lot other things about
list and array. So I need to so for each
so I need to put these links back to you
know here if then else let's see okay
there's nothing more uh true for boolean
okay there's yeah anyway so that's it
for today so that's you know kind of
kind of how I work on my
tutorials anything else
um sound talk show
today ling fantastic okay go learn ling
well I mean not necessarily because ling
is for kind of for mathematicians and
prove systems so but if you are a
programmer in the area
of let's say correctness you know
critical systems nuclear websites
nuclear launch website you know so you
might pick
up bye
This by we shut down in a
minute. So I'm just going to do some
clean up. So can talk show uh what is
this todo? Close close close.
back to this pro index. Okay. Copy. Uh,
okay. I need to work on that. Talk show.
Pro index.