Hello guys. Good morning, guys. Welcome
to another day of Xah Talk Show.
Another day of Xah Talk Show. How are
you guys?
Stop this. Okay.
Check video. Check am I alive? Yes, I
think I am.
Not dead yet.
Okay. So,
you are looking at the keyboard, the Xah
keyboard. That's a video thumbnail.
That's the best keyboard design. This is
called X No Code keyboard. This is a
keyboard I designed about
uh 14 years ago, 2011. Okay. X No Code
keyboard.
The plan was to make it for someone else
to build it cuz I can't. Uh so, I have
these drawings, but it
but
I didn't do it. Of course, I didn't make
it.
Uh
but George, our George, thanks to George
on our Discord, George our friend,
he used AI one of the day. You know, we
have AI today. AI created this image.
Amazing AI, okay. So, you just, you
know, tell it to generate an image based
on this page, Xah
No Code keyboard, and it generates an
image of the box and
the keyboard itself. Amazing AI, okay.
AI is incredible. AI is taking over.
The future is uncertain.
Here's some coffee
to soothe your brain. Well, coffee
doesn't soothe your brain, but wine
does.
Okay, now I'm having some
Pete's Cold Brew coffee.
Now, the cold brew thing is supposed to
be elite, you know, it's a
white man elite thing.
Well.
I'm not sure I like it though.
So cold brew.
If you are watching, say hi, okay?
Love to see your comments and stuff.
And today we going to code Emacs
advanced computer science.
So anyway, so this is
XCode keyboard, okay?
Fantastic AI image and let me tell you
should I? Yeah, let me tell you some
basic principles why this is the best
keyboard. This is called no code
keyboard so so that there's no key
codes. Key code is a worst [ __ ]
possible.
You know, like press control, hold it
down, then press C, then release C, then
release control, otherwise it won't
work. If you want copy, you know, copy,
paste, new window, you know, close
window. It's like hold this modifier
key, then press that key, then release
that key, then release that modifier
key. [ __ ] idiocy.
That's what we have.
Why do we have that? That's because the
shift key
back to 100 years ago, the mechanical
typewriters shift keyboard.
Okay, I explained this quite a few
times, but shall we do it again? Let's
let's just
do it. Typewriters, okay?
You got the shift key.
Now back back on this keyboard, this
this what year is this?
This keyboard is um
1890, so 120 years ago, 100
almost 150 years ago.
So does this key even have this does
this mechanical
typewriter even has
even have a shift key.
I don't think so. So, back then you see
this is too old. This doesn't even have
shift key. So, if you want to press
capital letters, there's separate keys
for capital
letters. See, there's no shift key.
Okay? Now, let's look at this one. Okay,
so this one does this one have shift
key?
No. Okay, so you got, you know, you
capital letters key by itself then then
the lower case. Okay, so not that one.
So, what about this one? Caligraph
number three typewriter.
What year is this? 1891.
130 years ago, 140 years ago. Do they
have a shift key? No.
Oh, Jesus. How far When did shift key
key begin?
Let's see this one.
Uh
This one, do they have a shift keys? Is
that the shift? Uh could be. Not sure,
okay.
Let's see.
Okay, let's go to a more recent. Okay,
so let's see this one.
What? You need a big image.
There it is. I believe that's a shift
key. Okay, that's in German. I don't
understand, but I believe that's a shift
key. So, when did these modifier keys
begin? Well, that's because the shift
key. You see, you have to hold it down.
It shifts the gears like moving it
a bit to the left or right. Then you
press the key,
then it's it's it strikes a different
hammer. So, these hammers come up. You
see.
So, that's a origin of all these
modifier keys like shift, control,
super, alt, Windows key idiocy.
Because when computer keyboard were
invented, people have it stuck.
You know, like
computer keyboard, you don't need you
know, you don't need to like there's no
gears underneath. It's not mechanical
typewriters, right? So, it's it's much
more advanced. There's no gears
underneath. Not heavy like this heavy
metal [ __ ]
Computer keyboards.
But people's habit
takes priority. They say Oh Jesus, this
key this keyboard doesn't have a shift
key. I need to shift. I need I need to
shift. I need to shift. So, therefore
we got this modifier and shift key [ __ ]
Like you have to hold it down then press
another key and release that key first
then release the shift key. That's
idiocy, okay?
To this day it's stuck.
So, what I'm saying is that if you care,
if you are you know, a thinking person
you know, either shift key, the modifier
key they should be banned because they
are idiotic.
Okay, they they are like idia- idiotic
idiocy.
You don't want that.
Do you want idiocy?
Well, probably don't. You don't, okay?
So, you don't want that.
So, therefore
Hello people Hello SCP. Hello J Juggles,
okay? Uh
I'm going to answer your question pretty
soon, but let me quickly finish this.
I'm talking about the
mechanical keyboards, okay? I'm talking
about the origin of the shift key idiocy
and all the modifier keys, okay?
So, let's go back. Uh let's just go
back. Go back. Go back. Go back. Go
back. Uh yeah, we were talking about
that. So, this keyboard is designed to
be no chord keyboard. [ __ ] the shift
key. [ __ ] the control. [ __ ] the alt.
You never like hold down this then press
another key.
Or like sometimes like for example you
have uh
For example,
press control shift escape, okay? Press
control shift escape to launch the uh
Wait. Control shift escape to launch the
uh task manager.
So, hold down control, hold down shift,
hold.
Uh yeah, hold control and shift then
press escape, release escape, then
release
both of the shift and control. [ __ ]
Okay, so complicated. You don't want
that. So, instead you just want to if
you want the key code, just press
control and release it, okay? Then press
the other key.
Simple, okay? So, and you can turn that
on today.
In operating system, just turn on uh
uh what's called sticky key, okay? So,
for example, you go to Windows settings.
Sticky. Search for sticky keys. Then you
can turn it on, which I do have it on.
Okay, that's why you hear the beep.
You see?
Yeah, now it's off.
So, you don't have to hold and
something, okay? And and also this
holding and press another key. It's a
major cause of hand pain, repetitive
strain injury. Major, okay? So, that's
that that is why I designed this
keyboard. It's a no chord keyboard.
Okay? I modified several times, so this
is like version nine. So, anyway, AI
created the image, okay? So, so so the
the keyboard the design is that you
don't press any uh
modifier. But I mean you do have
modifiers, but you don't you're not
supposed to hold it. You just press and
release. And also, for example,
one of the design of that principle is
that you see the number keys are all in
the center. So, you don't So, it's much
easier if you have a all the numbers in
a square, okay? Much easier than if they
are on a row, okay? So, number key. And
you see all the symbol keys, such as the
dollar sign right here, dollar sign, or
the percentage sign, or the bracket, the
parenthesis, round brackets, the curly
brace, the braces, curly brackets, and
the square brackets,
they are single key press.
You don't have to hold shift and deal
with it, okay? And also, the ampersand
and the correct
Well, some of them you have to hold
shift because otherwise, you you don't
have enough keys, anyway. But, anyway,
so you get rid of most of the shift
keys, okay?
So, that's a premises. Then, you got
other things like thumb keys are very
critical important. That's most useful.
Like, we have another another idiocy is
the long space bar, okay?
Now, I talked about on my keyboard um
Brock about why do we have the long
[ __ ] ass space bar, like
Do you
Like, do you ever like go all over the
place? No, you only press one spot
because you can see Look at your
keyboard, you'll see a shiny spot.
That's the place where you place you
press the
space key, okay? So, you don't need a
long
ass
idiot idiotic space bar, okay? That's a
You see, in life, we have full of
idiocies.
And half of the time, it's caused by
idiots.
Okay, let's let's slow down and let's
look at them. History? No, that's not
where we want to go. We wanted to go to
Okay. First of all, let's keep our
history. No, we wanted to go to but
first of all, let's go to mechanical
keyboards because I want to log
what we talked about, so
go to
uh
cuz uh today's talk show, so we want to
So, there it is. Ksar No-Code Keyboard.
Let's paste that here and
move that here.
So, here is the things we talked about.
Uh let's Yeah, so
let's put it here.
Okay, then we talked about typewriters
and now let me show you about the space
bar key and the shift key, so you go to
Ksar Keyboard
blog, okay? Then you go to um let's see.
Do-it-yourself normal laptop key office
history key switch guide design, so
design design flaws. So, you see design
flaws. We got lots of design flaws.
And uh
uh most of the idiocy came from
typewriters, mechanical typewriters,
okay?
So
Okay, so anyway, so there it is.
The space bar.
Spaced out.
History of space key. Why long space
bar? There it is. History because back
in 19 back back in 1871.
You know, somebody said somebody said uh
let's have a space key, something like
that, okay?
The typist suggested that two space keys
be installed, one on at each side of the
keyboard, okay? So, that's when they
don't have space bars. They don't have
space keys, so so they want to add like
two space keys.
One for each end. Then another guy says,
"Oh, that's a good idea. Let's do it."
Then they told another guy, "Okay,
they're going to make it." So, but at
the end the one guy says, "Oh,
you see we got two space keys. Why don't
we just make it one, like one single
long one that looks beautiful?"
That's the history of the idiocy of the
space bar.
And you see, it's interesting about the
habit because these days, to this day,
if you talk to people,
like when you have keyboard with two
space bars space keys, split space keys,
and some most a lot people will say,
"Jesus, I don't want that. What What
kind of idiot make the space bars that
tiny?" You know, they want the big huge
ass space bar, the idiots.
Why is that? Because habit, okay? Now
you have to remember, habit is the most
important governing
thing
of
you know, of lots of things, of your
opinions, of your perceptions, like
habit.
Basically because uh
habit, convention, because of the
impetus, you know, it has much weight.
It's like weighty trend, you know, it's
a like momentum, you know, you have a
heavy train going, you can't stop it.
That's your habit, okay?
So,
a lot people hold on to idiotic
thoughts, like in programming, you know,
there's you we we got the C
programmers and C++ idiots.
They like to talk about uh the uh
reference memory, you
habit, you know, they cannot change,
they cannot help.
Because they were born like that.
But the younger generation, like today,
we we got the zoomers with rust.
They don't think it that way, you know,
so that's when change happens. You wait
until the generation to die off.
Okay, we digressed a lot and and um
I was going to say, yeah, so that's a
space key
history of the space key, okay?
So, let's put it here, link it, and go
back and
and and and space out space bar, okay?
And and we are not done yet.
Okay, now, do we need a long space bar?
No, you don't, okay? So, you can read
the details.
Uh so, you go to my page, you know, and
the history of the
length of space bar on different
keyboards, okay?
Then we got uh oh, yeah, tiny space bar,
that happened on the Mac Japanese
keyboard. Lots of interesting stuff,
okay? But let's go to and we got this
fun thing, big ass space bar. This
[laughter]
this this keyboard uh this SteelSeries,
you know, not just long, but it's big,
big ass, like American. We need it big.
Okay.
So, big ass space bar, SteelSeries Apex
keyboard.
Is this Is this So, it began in 2015. Is
it still available?
Okay, it's dead.
Finally, it's dead.
Okay, so that's that. Now, we Now, let's
go back. We wanted to We need to talk
about um
So, copy that. Paste, linkify, make a
list, merge the list, show in browser.
Fantastic key keyboard collections.
And Firefox says it has an update. The
Firefox is updating every week. [ __ ]
Firefox. [ __ ] Firefox deep state [ __ ]
Okay, so let's go
go back. What I wanted to say is about
We talked about the history of the shift
key, which is the granddaddy of all the
modifier keys, okay? So let's go to the
keyboard shift keys shift section.
Is it here?
So space fat enter key, control key, and
caps lock key position. That's another
sensitive topic to the all the
programming idiots, like the Unix
[ __ ] and the the
Yeah, the Unix [ __ ] and Linux
[ __ ] They talk about control, they
want a control key on the left of A.
>> [laughter]
>> And they and they
spew fake news. They say, "All the
keyboard before you have the control on
the left of A." You know, that's a
[ __ ] Unix [ __ ]
Okay, so we want to we want to check out
article about the shift key. It's not
here, so okay.
So that would be in design because I do
have a article about that.
Uh
Yeah, here, okay.
Uh let's use pinky for important keys.
That's right. You see this area, you got
like six keys for your right pinky.
>> [laughter]
>> You see this area, you see you got six
extra keys for your right pinky.
Let's use pinky for important keys,
okay?
And let's see what else. Let's button
right pinky. Let's slow down typist,
right? That's right. That's a QWERTY
idiocy. QWERTY,
okay? Next next hand angle problems,
space bar.
Uh where did we talk about shift key? Um
Oh, and that's another thing.
It's the idiocy of the most tradition
habit again, you know, most people like
they like to tilt their keyboard like
the back the back legs up.
Uh but you see, so so but eventually it
takes several decades for things to
change. So, this is example of change.
You want the front
to be tilted up, okay? To be higher.
That's better for your hand.
Okay, so but we uh
I wanted to show the article about uh
shift keys. So, where is it? I
It's um
Okay, so it's in the modifier key
section. Okay, something like that.
Special keys somewhere here. History of
the meta key.
Somewhere, okay?
Wait, I can I I'm pretty sure I can find
it, but let's not do it. It's wasting
time. So, let me read the comments.
Okay, so we uh let's see. Hello Jade.
If you are mentioned this elsewhere, but
what is the reason that you use a
separate
planning device, a trackball and a
mouse? Oh.
Oh, that's because
Oh, yeah. So, sorry. Took a long time to
answer that.
So, well,
I always wanted to,
you know, I I
before like in short, two mouse is good
for your hand. Uh, less repetitive
strain injury because you don't have to
use one hand at all the time. So,
whenever you can also use your left
hand. So, if you have hand pain using
the mouse, you can try to switch the
hand. Or better, use two of them. So,
you can use whenever uh, like switch
hands whenever it's convenient for you.
And also, uh, it's good idea to have,
you know, use a pen. Pen's actually the
best, but even I mean, if you use the
pen, if you are a for example, painter,
you know, they also have problems if you
use the pen all the time. So, it's it's
good if you use trackball mouse, you
know, switch around, you know. So, I
have like the pen tablet right here and
the trackball on the right-hand side and
mouse on left.
So, I used to have two mouse, you know,
so
So, that's that's a that's a that's a
reason. And also, the other reason is
because I always have some kind of
obsession about being
ambidextrous. So, I don't I want to be
able to use my left hand as well as as
good as my right hand, not just
right-handed because that seems
a sym- asymmetric, you know, that's not
just the you know, I want I want my left
hand to be flexible, uh, very fluent as
well.
So, actually, I'm right-hand
uh, I'm right-handed. But, so actually,
So, why is there Why are people
right-handed or left-handed? What I
mean, why does um
most people
uh
better at one
side? That's an interesting question. We
can ask AI for it. Let's do.
Why are people better at right hand or
left hand? Why does nature favor one
hand?
>> About 90% of people are right-handed,
and that's been pretty consistent across
human cultures and even back to
Neanderthals. Nature doesn't really
favor one hand for everyone. It's more
that our brains are wired
asymmetrically. The left side of the
brain usually handles language and fine
motor skills, and it controls the right
side of the body. So, most folks end up
right-handed. This split lets the brain
multitask better. One side for routine
precise work, the other for spotting
threats. Evolutionarily, it probably
kicked in stronger when our ancestors
started walking on two legs and making
complex tools, which needed specialized
hand use. A recent Oxford study ties it
directly to bipedalism and our big
brains. Lefties stick around at about
10% because they have an edge in fights
or sports. Opponents aren't used to
them, so it throws people off. It's like
a rare strategy advantage that keeps the
trait from disappearing.
>> Fascinating. Great answer. This is
actually in-depth answer.
So, and I haven't read about it before.
So, it's saying that
uh it's because the brain is asymmetric.
Um then it gave more um
evolutionary biology reasons.
Okay, very interesting. Okay.
So, let's see
AI, you know, amazing AI.
Yeah, so that that's that's that. Uh
your keyboard
Oh, Y O, sorry. So, you mean the
keyboard that you see the keyboard this
is the
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard 2, okay. So,
it has a trackpad and also have actually
you have a track point
as variation or a trackball or tiny
trackball on the right-hand side module.
This is
Uh so, if you watch my YouTube, I have a
review of this
um
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard. I have
several reviews.
Version 1 and version 2. So, the
left-hand side also
there's a actually a tiny track
trackball there, you see.
So, this um
So, you see
but
you know, they they they they are useful
if you are in a pinch, you need to use
them, but they are usually
uh not good for long-term use. So,
wait.
Okay, so you see I can use the trackpad,
you see right here.
I but it's not so convenient, you know,
you don't want to use it long-term.
So, actually I don't like I don't use
them.
Okay, that that that answer your
question. So, Sal loves typing
technology. That's true.
Uh double-sided pointing device, not
planning device. Okay, I I don't get
your hate for Rust. Rust is just C with
algebra data types, basically Haskell in
C-like syntax. That's Well, you are kind
of right and I don't know Rust
much, you know, I don't know Rust.
But, like you said, Rust is kind of Rust
the history of Rust is OCaml.
Okay, you got this young guy who want
who are into all different languages,
like he believes
all different languages, very diverse,
you know, functional or C or others, you
know, that like he believes each one has
some utility, you know, each So, it's
So, he is trying to take the best of
them all and put them together. But,
most of it Rust is based on OCaml, which
is a functional programming language,
which Haskell kind of followed, okay?
OCaml, the lineage of OCaml's dad is
Caml. Caml's dad is ML. So, they are all
ML. ML stand for metalanguage. They were
originally designed to do math proofs,
okay? Mathematics.
So, they are functional programming
languages. So, Rust
Rust is
OCaml, okay?
That That is great. Um but, Rust wanted
to be They wanted to be not just
functional and not pure functional. They
wanted to like replace C.
Kind of or C++. They want to be like
system programming language, okay? So,
they and so, they need to deal with
memory. The C and C++
bit diddling [ __ ] their obsession.
Memory, you know, they need memory. Oh,
memory, garbage collection. Oh, we love
that word, but we hate it.
These
[ __ ]
Garbage collection, they're obsessed
about that. Garbage collection, but they
hate it. You know, the the the jargon.
If you say automatic memory
uh management, oh, that's boring. They
don't give a [ __ ] They don't care. But,
you If you say garbage collection, oh,
these [ __ ] will get excited. Huh,
you know, what's the the algorithm?
Garbage collection. What how do you do
it, you know, these [ __ ]
C and C++.
Okay. So, they So, anyway, Rust is meant
to
you know, be a system programming
language. So, they need to deal, you
know, if you have automatic memory
manage- management, some it's not
suitable
for system languages because sometimes
you need real-time reaction. You you you
want predic- predictable
uh time. So, so, anyway,
so, Rust
um
So, that's kind of the history, a little
bit, you know, I know a little bit
history of the Rust.
But, um
But, you see, Rust somehow I don't I
don't know Rust, okay, and I don't
really know the Rust community. Rust
somehow Rust become a cult.
A big a big one, okay.
>> [laughter]
>> Rust, you know, Rust become a big cult,
just like the C [ __ ] and the C++
[ __ ]
Rust become a cult by itself, too.
And they they and and it it so happens
that the Rust and the C versus the C++,
they trying to kill each other.
Okay, Rust want to wipe out the C and
C++ [ __ ] While the C
[ __ ] hates the C++ [ __ ] because
the C think the C++ are like complex bad
design. While the C++ [ __ ] think the
C [ __ ] as simple-minded idiot that
impractical.
Okay, so so, they are like in a war.
But but
So, actually,
so, Rust for some reason they they uh
become a cult and is somehow uh
associated with, you know, the new
generation and the trans. Like, you can
Like, like when you talk about Rust,
then you get you you you're going to
have to talk about trans with their
programming socks.
>> [laughter]
>> For some reason, okay?
But, uh
And And also, the other thing is Rust is
seems fairly complicated, okay? Rust is
fairly
uh complicated.
Anyway, I don't know what Rust but my
opinion is that I would be very happy
to see Rust
kill C++ and C.
Okay? C programming language and C++, if
they are dead
killed by Rust
I'm happy.
That's my take.
Uh Hyper 7 keyboard I talked about that,
you know, people asked me that a few
times. Hyper 7 keyboard, that's a great
keyboard, but it's not
it's it's actually very bad. It's not
practical because Hyper 7 is based on
Space Cadet, okay?
So, let's magnify that. Opens This is
Space Cadet keyboard.
A classic old from 1978,
okay? Used on this machine, Space Cadet,
very famous. And
and you got the And here's another
version of this uh
Space Cadet keyboard, but made by you
know, a different company. They are in a
war in war at the time. You know, um
Uh so, anyway, so then you got Space
Cadet keycaps. So, Nuts creates them.
They love it. Uh I love it, too, you
know, so it's Space Cadet. You got this
Roman numeral.
>> [laughter]
>> And And the pointing fingers, you know,
the pointing fingers.
You know, and some up and some down on
the
uh Space Cadet. So, you can see
see the thumb up and thumb down and
pointing fingers there. Okay, then you
got So, these are these machine
keyboards and So, one of the thing
people made is the Hyper 7. So, there is
So, Hyper 7 is inspired by the Space
Space Cadet, you know, so many keys. So,
they made this
You can buy. I'm not sure, you know,
like you can buy, you know, people make
it.
But, it's pretty bad, actually, because
Space Cadet itself is pretty bad. I
mean, it's fun to look at, you know,
history. Oh, you know, thumb key, you
know, like thumb up keys, like funky.
You know, but
if you But, this as a keyboard is very
bad design.
Not ergonomic.
Okay, like kind of idiotic. Idiotic.
But, if you are not a touch typer, if
you are hunt hunt hunt and peck,
like half of the programmers are the C
and C++ idiot.
Hunt and peck peck peck they hunt peck
very fast. You know, two-finger system
or three-finger system, each in their
own way, and they insist that's very
good because you don't get hand injury,
you know, these idiots.
Lots of idiots, you know, like the
mythos and the fake news they believe in
human society.
So, anyway, so this So, people um
you know, they see this keyboard, you
know, they think it's great. So, they
thought, you know, the So, So, they
created the Hyper 7.
Well, it's like you know, it's a
how you say, a novelty.
As a novelty, yeah, fun, but in
practice, no. Because, for example,
you know, this Look at the the uh
special function keys.
Or on top, you know, you got two rows of
three, right?
You want them to be separated You you
want them to have gaps. Okay, that's one
of the important design of function
keys, so that you don't have to look.
Like, for example,
F6 and F7. Okay, for example,
F6, F7. On a typical keyboard, the F1 to
12, they are separate into three groups.
So, you don't have to look at them. You
can feel it where they are. You can, you
know, press F6 or F7.
Easier is F7 and F8 because they are on
the edge.
But, if you have all your function keys,
some keyboard, they have all their
function keys in a row, like like like
this like this Hyper 7 without gaps.
You know, if you want to press one of
the middle keys, like F6 or F7, it is
impossible. You have to look because
otherwise you easily press the wrong
key.
You have to look at, you know, like the
position. That's That's what happens.
That's what happened with the Hyper 7
idiocy.
You know, but but if you are hunt and
peck,
you always look at your keyboard, then
it doesn't matter, you know, you know.
Okay.
Okay, so I think I talked for 1 hour
without beginning
to talk about what I wanted to do today,
which is this Emacs Lisp coding.
Uh okay.
So, that will be next day, then.
Yeah, because I was going to code this
uh I can show you, but
Okay.
>> The keyboard component that yeah, it's
it's I mean it works, you know.
This
this touch pad it works, but you know,
it's just tiny. So,
if you have real mouse or real trackball
or large trackpad, it's much better than
this small one.
Okay, I think that's it. If you design a
high-performance system language, how
would you do it? Okay.
That's a long question.
Uh
I mean that's a
Yeah, that takes an hour to
explain. Okay, I think that's it for
today.
Uh
Python Python is most idiotic
programming language, okay? By the Guido
van Rossum.
A very
kind of um
not good person, okay? Guido van Rossum.
Okay, I think that's it, right?
Anything else you guys have?
Uh so because we talked for an hour and
today we talked about keyboards, okay?
Rambling about keyboards for the nth
time.
Because by now I have done
700 800 videos.
One third of them is about keyboard. So,
all the things I talked about today,
I've talked about before, like more than
once. About the shift key, about this
long ass space bar, about, you know,
So, uh
and Hyper 7, I talked a few times and uh
and these machine keyboards, I talked
about many times.
So, anyway, we talked about keyboard and
now it's
uh oh, it's actually 40 minutes, right?
Oh, actually it's 40 minutes. Actually,
we can
40 minutes. Let's Okay, let's do the
coding tomorrow.
Today, let it be keyboard. So, anything
else about keyboard you guys want me to
talk about?
So,
would you mind doing a stream sometimes
to talk about politics? Yeah.
I
I'm so willing to do it and able, but if
I do it on YouTube, YouTube is going to
ban me.
You know, if I talk a little bit,
you know, then it doesn't
you know, then it just like what's the
point? If you if I talk
uh full,
you know, I if I go into it
the way I want it to about politics,
then YouTube is going to ban me.
Oh, Jesus. You know, your email account
is canceled. Your credit card is
canceled.
That's what happens.
So, if I really want to talk about
politics, I need to go to um
like one of those alternative uh
video um
uh such as such as such as
actually I don't even Odyssey. I haven't
used it for like 2 years.
But you see,
even Odyssey, you can't you know, you
got to be very careful because USA is
very [ __ ] up.
You you know,
you talk about politics, if nobody
watches like like you guys, you know, if
I got
oh, 10 people watching my talk,
100 people,
then I'm fine. Okay, I can talk all I
want.
Now, if I started to get like 1,000, few
thousand people watching my politics
talk and they are interested, if I got
10,000 people, ho ho, then
you got to be careful. Your bank is
going to get closed, you know, things
like that. So,
that is the state of USA, okay? It's we
are being we have been collapsing for
about 10 years, I would say. You know,
so like we can say 2015,
we can say maybe that that is a year
that's a
start of the collapse of USA.
You know, it's it's not like
it's not a sudden thing like earthquake
or flood or
you know, a huge flood or something.
It's like, you know, the collapse of USA
is like a gradual thing.
We can have a self-hosted peer YouTube.
Yeah,
you know, that that doesn't work.
You know, like the nerds always have the
idea, you know, they're going to have
their, you know, they're going to try to
fight the tech with tech, so it prevents
censorship, you know, you cannot censor
it. But actually that
doesn't work. If you want change
in society, you need to deal with
humans, okay?
You know, it's not going to do any good
if you try to like you know, new
technology, this or that or Bitcoin.
Like like Bitcoin or crypt, you know,
the blockchain is a good example.
You know, you're trying to fix something
by tech.
It Then you end up you get [ __ ] Now
you have 1,000 cryptocurrencies. Like
you know, you can't know which one is
like fake. You don't know.
So, if you want to change, you know, if
you want to change, you have to deal
with human animals, okay? You have to
stop being a noun, show your face,
say what you mean,
stop [ __ ] around, stop meme posting,
stop your [ __ ] posting [ __ ] stop your
Pepe.
And stop all that. Stop [ __ ] around.
Stop like doing the you know, [ __ ]
posting and oh, you're going to get
likes or you know, stop you got to stop
all that.
Say what you mean.
You know, use your real name. Stand up.
Um
then
maybe
then things will will change, you know,
if a lot people do that, okay? Then you
don't need to worry about oh, which
browser I'm going to use. I need to like
spend the next hour to find the browser
that doesn't
uh you know, spy on what what color
panties I'm wearing today.
You know, like the like you guys like
tech geeking. Oh, I use that browser
because you know, the because of the
technology this that that [ __ ]
You know, that been going on for 20 30
years.
And we end up with, you know, every
social media like tracks you and you
like like nothing you can do.
And you can but you can be happy about
oh, by the way, I'm using this browser.
It keeps the it keeps my secret, you
know. I'm so proud of it.
Okay, bye guys.
Oh, 19 viewers.
Oh.
Very nice. Bye.
Uh if you like my stuff, you can put
money to my uh PayPal, okay? You can go
to my
my website. Just go to my website,
ksodi.info. Then you'll see PayPal and
stuff.