hello guys hello guys welcome to another
episode of sound talk show today we are
going to do some unic code stuff very
interesting unic code and this thumbnail
you are seeing they are generated by
Machine artificial intelligence by Gro
on x.com El musk of el musk okay so if
you are falling for the clickbait that's
what it is now I'm a ugly guy I'm
talking about I'm just to talk about
talk show which is about coding okay so
today's talk show we are going to
do we are going to do uh emac this
coding and unicode very uh sunry
interesting things about Unicode and
HTML and CSS okay so let's
begin so if you are here say hi if you
are not here you can skip around play at
speed 1.2 or something because I talk
slowly and and
randomish okay so let's uh are we ready
yes video check audio check let's begin
uh coding what we need to do so today's
talk show uh we are going to so let me
show you my unic code page so this is uh
Unicode you can find anything you need
to know about Unicode IM Emoji hands
food can you see it yes food love
clothing
and uh then you have some esoteric ones
culture and uh including this symbol
okay and that's a Chinese character from
Buddhism and uh common and punctuations
all the weird punctuations you will find
this circle is China and Japan's version
of check mark basically check mark or
correct or perfect or good
so you know different culture so Chinese
usually you know usually when I use a
circle people don't know what I'm doing
but whenever you see that Circle for
example the PlayStation from Japan you
have that Circle means check mark or yes
or okay or uh
correct so many interesting things about
Unicode including sexual symbols uh
White means Obsession particularly in
the past 20 years uh and then you have
stars cross cross is also his you know
the you know it's interesting Unicode
embodies the entire human
history's written symbols so in so in a
sense Unicode captures the history of
humanity and on this page you can see
all the crosses which in a sense
captures the western civilization ation
history of you know all the varieties so
these are written
symbols uh and then but you also have
interesting ones uh such as all the
keyboard symbols you need you you know
if you want keyboard you want to label
them if you are a keyboard maker or if
you want to create your custom keyboard
uh labels so introducing to Unicode so
I'm just introducing my website so you
got a bunch of circle numbers and and
squared characters and most of these are
used in Japan Japan love this squared
character
thing uh for Japanese culture and you
have Asian symbols AR uh Alchemy you
know archical symbols so you can see the
the symbol names on the right lower
corner um hello Dan so we are going to
so let me finish introduction to the UN
codes you know so arrows you have like
100 arrows or two all sort of
arrows uh ever used in
human uh written system writing
system uh then so you have arrows then
another interesting counterpart to Arrow
is all the types of brackets and quotes
this is these are extremely useful in
programming because bracket the bracket
character is a unique character that
comes in pairs in matching pairs so when
you use a bracket character such as in
programming for example you know these
braces or for example a list uh you
know third index of Leist you know
square brackets and curly brackets the
that's a
European term for the brackets this is
called cly brackets
and this is called um square brackets
and parenthesis is called round brackets
that's a United Kingdom style of wording
now in United States of America we call
this is this is brazes this
is this is um brackets and and this is
parentheses okay so different wording
style so you also have different
varieties of characters you have white
variant white variant or small variant
very interesting then you have Asian
ones uh used in China and Japan mostly
and uh maybe Korea I don't
remember and uh and Chinese and Japanese
while Chinese for sure that used to be
written vertically so you have vertical
versions of these brackets you know for
the past 3 4,000 years in Chinese it's
vertical okay but now this these days
mostly in China at least they switch to
horizontal from left to right why
because that way it's easier to inter
intermix with Western languages so for
example if you are you know for example
math textbooks or chemistry textbooks
you know or or translate or or Russian
about you know a Chinese book about
Russian history or or American history
you know you have you you need to make
in math formulas or western names so but
if your text is vertical it makes it
hard so today in China at least mostly
it's you know the written uh flow is
Switched switched to the Western Way of
from left to right not Arabic from right
to left okay that's you know variety of
interesting
things is it is it interesting um so so
you have brackets and a bunch of weird
ones you've never seen before uh okay
brackets very interesting then we get
into uh so then you have math symbols of
course you know the Unicode math symbols
and then you have math font this these
are special characters that's
specifically designed intended to use in
mathematics at least part of at least
that's a partial purpose because most of
these uh characters they are mostly
rendering of English alphabet okay but
they but they became a character in unic
code because this style of characters
are mostly used in
mathematics so you got bold you got
mathematical double stroke then you got
this franor style which what which came
from around 19 uh around 1500s it was
the St of you know text uh but today
it's mostly just used in mathematics you
know like for example this I is for
complex
number
uh uh and uh let's see if there's
another one I can that's commonly
commonly used
uh well yeah I for complex number and
and for engineers sometimes they use J
instead of I because I is already used
uh so i j m anyway
so yeah mostly I think it's just I
sometimes the H yeah but sometimes they
use it in esoteric mathematics in group
Theory and uh abstract algebra and you
know some of these character while this
is common for example uh the Double stru
they have a meaning they have a uh
standard meaning in mathematics
for example double stroke Z stand for
integers double stroke p stand for Prime
double stroke Q is for rational and so
on double stroke R Is For Real so you
know so these are these each one of
these are Unicode characters okay they
are not found style okay they are not
found style each one is a unique
character for
example for example let's copy one of
them and you can see
uh let's
say let's say this ABC so just copy it
and uh paste it here new buffer I mean
magnify so you can see so you see ABC
there's no you know it I didn't say
style italic or whatever so if you in
IMX if you do describe character
describe character expand window then
you can see the name here so the name of
the this character is mathematical B
franor capital c okay so that's some
interesting things about UN code then we
have APL symbols APL is a programming
language that is called um array
programming language so let me explain
that one you
know uh sound talk show is a variety
show a variety show meaning a variety of
topics but usually Center around nerd
interest so that would be programming
mathematics engineering physics heart
Sciences infot technology the world uh
sometimes occasionally politics and
history uh but for example we are
talking about writing systems all these
unic code characters so that's a variety
show so APL so APL symbols in Unicode
they are these are characters used in
the APL programming language Okay so for
example let's show you so this is the
keyboard original APL programming
language keyboard it's actually a
printing code printing terminal IBM
2741 okay so you can see AP characters
now the API programming language is
mostly unique and interesting in the
aspect
that you know all the programming code
is just these symbols okay so let let
let me show you um do I have uh APR
symbols okay so let's go here so that's
a
symbols do I have I have a page about AP
source code programming language source
code you know just as example
but uh it's somewhere you know let's not
spend time to search it but anyway so
these are APL characters APL is a
programming language it stand for a
programming language you know it's just
a programming language and it
um so one of the unique characteristics
is that the syntax is all just this
bunch of symbols so if you are if you
have not learned it it's unreadable you
know you have to first learn what each
of these usually they are functions the
each one of these
functions so that's a uniqueness about a
language from the syntactical aspect
that's the first thing you see okay now
the second thing unique uh I think it's
a
first with with with started by APL is
that it's a array programming language
so what does that mean array programming
language means for example in Python you
have the map function you map a function
to a list of things right map in
JavaScript you also have map
so so let me digress and show okay um
python Okay so Python tutorial uh one of
the best go read it
okay Python tutorial and the JavaScript
tutorial JavaScript in depth okay I'm
going to show you uh I'm going to talk
about um map
okay so in Python for example you have a
map function so let me just quickly show
it uh so you have a list right so you
have a list which is a list of items
items and you want to apply a function
to the list to change every item in the
list so normally normally you just do a
loop okay for Loop while loop that's
that's from the C and C++ and Unix
imperative idiots okay but in functional
programming you don't do you don't
manually create a local variable and
loop for p to you know length something
you use map this is the most common
edum for doing a loop in functional
programming not all Loops can can be
done with this map function but but
however this is the most common okay so
you simply say a function you call the
map is a function then you give two
arguments map a function and the list
then it returns you know uh for example
if you map a function the function does
plus one and you give a list 1 2 3 4
then you get two three four five a new
list okay so map is very common so it's
also in JavaScript so if you go to
JavaScript in depth you go to array so
this is object reference you go to
array then you'll see also a function or
so-called method that map basically does
the same thing so you have this map
function uh in almost all languages
today you have that in uh in Goan I
think um I forgot but we have to check
um so I have to show my goand goand
tutorial okay s Cod this is my website
let's see let's go to goand tutorial
let's see if they uh in power sha you
also have a map similar but let's let
mean let's not digress all so go
land go language one one of the best
programming language okay so you have um
uh okay in Goan you don't have map uh
yeah yeah Goan don't have the map
function uh goine is from the C in
Heritage you know you don't have that so
anyway MTH function is very commonly
used but in AP programming language you
don't have this map function because
every time you call function on
something the function automatically map
into the list okay automatically so you
don't even have the map concept because
everything because effectively every
value almost every value in the AP
programming language is a list or Matrix
or nested you know there of so every
time you call a function on the argument
the argument is almost always not not
always but almost always a list or
nested list or Matrix so the function
automatic ially map into so which is a
similar situation in wolam language
because wolam language is based on lisp
and
APL so the important thing to remember
is that APL language is a array
programming language so just remember
that array programming language it just
means every function automat
automatically map into a list okay so
let me uh show quickly uh a wolam
language demo okay
uh new new buffer okay I mean uh new
notebook let's say
three shift enter to evaluate and
magnify so let's
say okay let me show you map so for
example
list okay so we have a list one two 3 4
and let's say
plus uh
plus one yeah I typed something wrong
okay
plus one
okay shift enter you see it becomes 2 3
4 5 so this plus function automatically
maps to one so you know another another
way we can do this is uh more clarity is
uh uh
so anyway so that's the anyway that's a
demo
okay so let's go back to uh because
today actually I want to do unic code I
started to digress all over so let's go
back to unic code um uh where is it APL
symbols okay AP very interesting then
you have the asky characters the most
traditional so basically asky characters
are the characters that you see on your
keyboard
okay okay and uh if you are a programmer
it's very critical to understand the
asky what does it mean so in the first
10 years of programming you not you may
not care as much but let's say after 5
years of programming eventually you will
know all every character in detail you
know the new line their official name
form feed you know and they encoding and
so on okay s key
characters so then you have interesting
inverted inverted characters you know
all these are came from Unicode because
uh these symbols were used in human
written in in in in books you know
hundred or thousands years ago or EDG in
stone in human artifact you see all
these symbols they occur therefore they
are in Unicode and Coca-Cola or
commercial American
capitalism company Coca-Cola basically
Coca-Cola is a symbol that represents
USA okay United States or idiomatically
we just say America make America great
again not make North America great again
and not make United States of America
great again we simply say make America
great again which stand for make United
States of America great again not make
Canada great again or
Mexico even though they are also North
America well Mexico is C Center Center
America but anyway so Coca-Cola you know
they are doing marketing which is all
important in America so
they they they borrowed they use this
trick to have upside down text to have
this you know it's a ad for from
Coca-Cola
okay so anyway so and uh so you have
upside down text and uh and you can
Dynam dynamically
interactively create your own there it
is upside down text
okay uh so yeah it's interesting so
let's make a screenshot of
it okay upside down text that's another
thing interesting from unic code and
actually they came from Latin I'll show
in a minute and unic code you have Ipa
symbols IPA stand for international
phone
gentic uh alphabet okay they came from
French the Nemesis of United
Kingdom the foreign French because the
French and the
UK
people uh they has you know they are the
Nemesis they have always in war so
anyway so the International fonetic
System they utilize this unic code to
Mark pronunciation while the American we
don't do that you know American just use
ad hoc symbols so each dictionary for
example American Heritage dictionary
which is my favorite dictionary of them
all because I dived into for 10 20 years
American Heritage dictionary have its
own phonetics system symbols and the
maram Webster
dictionary has its own so they disagree
so you see these two this dot part hot
pop Bob body you know they use different
symbols but IPA is more International
standard so if you are Chinese Russian
or uh or or from Saudi
Arabia or typically you use you know the
learning material is all use IPA because
it's more standardized so anyway in back
to unic code interesting symbols and
characters that's their use okay then
you have the interesting thing about a
full Unicode
English alphabet letters so what are
they exactly they are just English
alphabets and characters and
punctuations but however they are full
width so for example this text is full
width meaning that each character is
basically the same width as a Chinese
character so where does this full width
alphabet came from so let me show you
okay so for example we paste it here so
you can see this is uh how it looks like
you know there by the way notice
carefully pay attention there is no
space between
characters but however you see they are
rendered why because that's what the
these characters are they are called
Full width characters so why does this
came out because in Chinese every
character is the same width so when you
have a Chinese text let's go to Chinese
for
example uh you know when when you have a
Chinese text let's
magnify so you see the the cus
align but in modern times you do need
some times English or math formulas and
so on right or English names Russian
Russian names or Spanish names once you
add that then then the alignment all got
[ __ ] up that's when you introduced
this full width
English uh characters I think originally
it's just a font I forgot anyway that's
that's where this came from okay it's
also used in Japanese I think maybe or
it was created by Japan I don't
remember uh no I don't think no I don't
think Japan because Japan now this is
interesting thing about Japanese
language their writing system is very
complex their writing system consist of
consists of uh by the way there's also
Japanese language page which we are
getting into because we are introducing
all the interesting things about Unicode
so here's a introduction to the japanes
Japanese writing system now in Japanese
writing
system it consists of about 3,000
Chinese characters okay Chinese 3,000
Chinese characters then you have this
Japanese phonetic
symbols which is made of which you call
uh Kaa okay and this phonetic system
called Kaa has two parts hogana and uh
Katakana that's what they looks like so
anyway they are they are phonetic
symbols for
Japanese okay so 3,000 Chinese
characters plus about uh about about 70
this Japanese fonetic symbols then plus
the English alphabet but okay so here is
the hogana and Katakana
okay plus English alphabet so the
English alphabet which they call a Roman
alphabet okay basically means the same
thing or Latin alphabet so they are part
of Japanese writing system so in other
words Japanese writing system this AB
bcde e FG are part of the Japanese
writing system okay so it's like
integrated is part of the Japanese
writing system so that's interesting
thing about the Japanese writing system
you know the English alphabet is part of
it so so that's why in in Japanese they
don't they don't necessarily align um
anyway that I don't know about the
history of that much but anyway that's
that's the story about these uh full
width characters
okay then you have other interesting
things you have uh you have Unico
uh unit symbols like
millimeter
micrometer
nanometer cimeter kilometer inch
millimeter squar cenim squar and volume
you know and so on uh each one of these
is a single character you see km is a
single character that's in Unicode so
where does this came from why don't you
know you know how come you don't just
write k
why do why do you create this complexity
why do you need to create you know a
character by itself in
just well this came from Japan
because for some reason I don't actually
know the history but Japanese they they
love to have this kind of
thing so this this were used mostly used
uh in Japan I I'm not sure now but any
anyway so you got this unit unit symbols
okay then you got bra another
interesting things for you guys NES or
mathematicians because brail you know
bra is for the blind you
know they they they are interesting to
mathematicians because they are just
combin combinations of position of dots
okay so you get into the combinatorial
problem like counting like how many
possibilities are there what are the
different uh arrangements and how do you
sort them so I spend quite a few time
trying to S them you know you can s them
by Unicode name or you can s them by the
position of dots you know like like like
how do you determine the you know you
can s them by position of dots which you
have to
design the criteria then you can also s
them by number of dots okay so once you
have number of dots for
example uh three dots you know so here
is three dots then you also have three
dots in different position
somewhere uh or four dots you know for
example here is also another three
dots so if you sort them by number of
dots then you
have then it's not total sorting total
order so you still need to devise a way
to sort these three dots versus these
three dots so it's a you know kind of
interesting issue about sorting the real
characters okay or you can sort them by
what they mean by you know by what this
dots stand for for example if this dots
stand for a b c d you know a then you
just sort it by a you know things like
that then you have a variation you have
a kind of new thing a DOT sprad
which is not often used so you got now
eight dots okay so very interesting
thing okay then we get into languages
you have all the Latin all the possible
Latin alphabets now so this uh
characters letters each one is a unic
code I mean it which uh each one is a
decorated
Latin letter okay or in other way to say
it is accent accented character uh but
well some of them are not access
accented
character some of them are simply a
character by itself for example
um for example let's you know let me go
through the same way and we'll see so
this is uh this is grave a this acute a
this is um uh what does it say
circumflex a this
is T A so for example this t
n this character you know use in Spanish
such as Nino and ninia
for for boys and girls you know with the
te that is not a accented character that
is actually just an alphabet
and some of the others uh to for example
this uh for example um for example uh
let's say the
[Music]
D for example that I think that from
northern European language there's a
character like that or was or was it
something else but anyway so in general
you can call all these decorated
characters de decorated Latin letters
okay so you got all these you got
hundreds of
varieties you know most of these are
never used
almost but Unicode has to to cover the
entire history of writing WR written
symbols and then you have you know you
have ligatures and diagraph which is
which is kind of combining them uh then
you have small letter small Capital
version uh oh then this character is
what I was talking about this F uh they
came from I believe Old
English which is like 1300 year 1300 or
uh
something uh then you know so you have
all these interesting
varieties uh then you have upside down
you know it's like some of some of them
like to understand what are they and
where they came from is like is
basically a few years of studying
historical Linguistics you know actually
the entire Unicode you know the to to
know all this for
example you know cross is is you know
the Christian history of
Christianity you know you have to study
where where does who first which book
which eding which uh which Stone first
use the symbol who created it you know
things like that so to just understand
all these course history of these cres
take you a
year you know then we are talking about
all these you know
decorated Latin letters that takes you a
year a few years to to know we you know
for example what the [ __ ] this one Latin
capital letter Q with diagonal stroke
you know what what is that who where was
it used so you know it takes uh you know
a long time to know to find out about
all of these okay that's interesting
then then you have also these specials
yeah I have no idea where they came
from okay today I was going to
do I was actually going to uh code in on
my website about
about about changing the markup of
Unicode you know but I end up talking
now by now 40 minutes basically an
introduction to
Unicode uh soy says s you got to stop
the Hony bait with the
thumbnails uh no I think that's
interesting because girls are the center
of humanity
okay uh
so Unicode let's continue talking about
Unicode okay so
Unicode then you got
um okay so where are we about
Unicode Chinese uh Latin alphabet okay
so so then you have uh you know then you
have Greek uh you know uh wait not
that so now we getting the writing
systems of human languages Greek very
common okay Greek and Greek it so
happens for some reason they are usually
often used in mathematics physics and
Engineering too so for example Pi the
most popular is this Pi symbol which
stand for the ratio of a circle's
diameter to the circumference
okay and Theta used for angle very often
Delta used for change you know like the
difference uh usually in capital letter
or small
letter and Fe you know so Greek now I
don't know the history so the question
is why does math and Engineering uses
squeak where does it when did this
practice originate I don't know so
that's another interesting thing to look
into and let's ask for chatbot okay
so let's ask for
chatbot let's say when or how did math
and Engineering use Greek
letters okay so magnify magnify magnify
gr okay copy copy P
ask very interesting I want to know the
answer so but for now let's paste it uh
it's too big let's paste it here so
actually let's clear up
that so we have a record of what we
talked
about showing browser that's what we
talked about okay so back to the
so it says SC the AI says the use of
Greek letters in mathematics and
Engineering has a rich history that
spans back to Asian times but it became
more standardized during the development
of modern mathematics and science here's
how and why Greek letters became
prevalent historical context Asian
Greece math as we know it today has
roots in Asian Greek civilization okay
Medi evil and the Renaissance periods
during this time Scholars often referred
back to classical texts Greek letters
were used in translations and
interpretations of Asian Works which
were founded foundational in mathematics
okay that makes sense uh you know Asian
Greece you know uh so Greek Greece Greek
culture is kind of
a foundation and basis of Western
Civilization what white man's culture
okay so you got Zeos you got Europa you
know Europe is you know you got Europe
is named of this beautiful girl which
the God of all gods Z zos changed
himself into a white bull and
seduced this girl and she became Europe
you know she the personal
personification of Europe Europa that's
where the name Europe came from came
from her name
Europa so zeros in other words they say
you know seduced or rape okay that's the
Greek mythology I I love the Greek
mythology okay let okay let's digress so
we go
to
uh love of Greek mythology
uh actually let's just go to
Arts uh art okay so let me quickly show
you a few
um articles okay so here is Greek
mythology okay you got Europa and the
Bulls you got Le and the Swang okay
these are all classic you got aamus the
greatest [ __ ] of all times since about
two or three thousand years ago you got
Hades or I don't know how to properly
pronounce it Hades and pone you know the
god of the
hell okay uh and look at these beautiful
sculptures that relates to your
sentiment and question you know you says
you say soy says so you got to stop the
Hy bait with the thumbnails no this is
the
traditional white man's culture okay
this these sculptures are priced you
know priced historical artifact you know
if you not they they are not for sale
but if you sell it cost hundred millions
hundreds Millions okay this beautiful
and and look you know so you think oh
but that's just a normal sculpture
actually no look at look at the way they
depict this completely naked girl okay
not just naked but completely naked and
feet you see right there feet fetish you
know this today's white men they don't
know things you know they they don't
know and also this when talking about
these subjects it relates to
Christianity because Christianity has
certain taboos that is so that is
antithesis that's the enemy of Greek
mythology for example Greek mythology to
Christians they are considered um heresy
okay so on one hand the white Western
culture are the the Greek culture and
mythology are fundamental to the white
men's culture for example you know today
the elus rocket you have we have a new
project named aamus okay named otus what
does it do it's going to the I think
it's going to the moon for the second
time
otus it's named after Greek in fact you
look at corporations like tons of it is
named after Greek gods or goddesses from
Greek mythology okay so on one hand the
Western culture is
heavily have have the Greek basis Greek
cultural basis okay but on the other
hand the other part is um Christianity
okay then they don't like you know they
don't like this whenever you talk about
girls they they get they get sensitive
you know it's like this is taboo you're
not supposed to talk about it you know
and which is the which is the name of my
pen okay when you know when I talk
to no offense to you Christians out
there but that's a
fact uh and of course and you look at
USA
cour houses for example you look at
White House the in Washington DC the
Supreme Court building you know you look
at the you know that's all Greek
architecture then at top you see this
you see these sculptures
naked women with their tits showing
right in front giant sculptures in front
of USA Supreme Court
okay that's so that's you know that's
Greek mythology you know so that's what
I mean so but meanwhile the American
culture they they they kind
of so that's you know so you got this
kind of issue the white man's issue that
you know on one hand it's you know the
culture is
um kind of has uh Greek culture as basis
but meanwhile the christiany is kind of
incompatible so so for example this
leader and Swang what what is this about
this is again Zeus the God of all gods
made himself into a swan to seduce a
girl to [ __ ] the girl okay so all the
greatest you know artist in Western
Society Michael Angelo or whatever they
all have a painting
of this
story which what is
this Z today in in in today's zumas who
who don't know nothing zilia you know
[ __ ] dogs and whatnot gay trans you
know this is called
bestiality which in Bible is mentioned
and forbidden forbidden but meanwhile
all the greatest western western
greatest names they all covered this
story okay this this
Zeos you know changed himself into a
swan and [ __ ] a girl so for example this
this one this one is Asian this one is
2000 or three you know some of them two
2,000 years old you have 2,000 years old
to mod okay so what's some uh you know
for example
modern this one is painted in the you
know last 10 years this one in the last
1996 in
Germany I think you know this one neon
sign what they doing they [ __ ] a swan
[ __ ] a girl okay and uh you know look
at this sculpture this became more
explicit by this one by eagle Z love
1959 I don't know who that guy is okay
so and and and modern you zumas you
forchan people you you you know into
this W Jack W ja what whatnot here's
here's a modern example from year 2020
four years
ago okay
so Le and Swang okay that's uh one big
story of uh you
know white men's artwork history of
white men's artwork and and and Europa
in The Bu you can look up that's where
that's how Europe got its
name from Europa and from this for
example this this this this vase
decoration that's from 370
BC 20 2,000 years old and there's a poem
from Greek uh from you know uh from
metamorphosis poem by over
2,000 years ago describing how
zos you
know changed himself into a beautiful
white bull and basically took the girl
away
um very interesting story because
because you know it's not just taking
the girl away like swiping off of her
feet but also zus gave her several gifts
one of them is
automata which is today's Bots robot
which you know this automata protect her
Island it goes around you know it's
giant robot so this is story from 2,000
years ago and zo also gave her several
other gifts a javelin that will never
miss and some other things okay and this
painting is also 2,000 years old 1
Century
ad okay so that's some of the
you know uh stories of quck Mythology
and another you know like very
interesting let me show you a few okay
so for example
another so this you know hates that's
the that's the underworld King of the
ruler of the underworld I don't know I I
don't know exactly what's the story but
you know
but then another very famous all over
you see this Medusa all over in America
okay that's another huge story from
Greek mythology by the way it wasn't
mythology it was religion this you know
this Greek mythology they were religion
back
then not not so much today but they were
religion just like Christianity okay so
Medusa the story I love I love Greek
mythology because they their stories
often reflect reality if reflect the
human the human needs and flaws and
characters for example we talked about
you know all these all these girls and
ass and raping why because that's what
we do men you know are you know you are
you in looking are you looking at the
girls the girls walking on down the
street yeah you look at them because you
want to [ __ ] them that's the fundamental
fundamental nature of
males and what and what the females do
they want to be pretty and they want to
show their tits and ass look at today's
social networks Instagram you know the
and chatterbate you know they they they
have these stresses you know they they
show their body why because they want to
attract the powerful rich guy that I can
protect them and have baby
with fund fundamental Greek mythology in
my eyes captures the fundamental
characteristics of
humanity okay so this this you know this
atmus the greatest SP of all the time he
she she and her
brother played the game with their bow
arrows and bow and kill
the 12 childrens's
of of
another a
mother okay that's what she does she is
the greatest speech like like today you
know some of the you know hard girls
influences
they
anyway so and the zos of course the God
you know the God of all gods why what
why why do you have that because that's
what we all all males want to be you you
know you know you you want to be
powerful like like today's speden you
know you know you you want more power to
do
things and uh anyway so so that's lots
of the stories and uh you know
so so the
um and for example this Story the minor
and Labyrinth and actually this story is
part of that this story is uh uh dadelus
and his son I carus okay very very
interesting story so manator is a is is
half man half
bull where he came from because he came
from a beautiful white boy [ __ ] a
women [ __ ] [ __ ] a woman
so their children is this white boy
minor to you know you see that often
like you guys scammers right you you
play World of Warcraft you see that
minor half man half horse
everywhere okay so that's man Manor and
then there's a so anyway Manor got
captured because he he needs to
eat men okay he needs to eat people so
he got captured so in in a labyrinth so
the manor cannot run away okay
so uh then there's a story about that
and another thing then but then there's
this story so they the dadelus is the
greatest engineer this guy okay so this
guy personal F the greatest engineer so
for example if you today you Gamers you
buy the latest Mouse fantastic Logitech
you know this this is a mouse named
named after dadelus I think you know
let's
see
um uh some somewhere okay so
actually let's see the mouse you know so
mouse weight comparison uh I think I
believe Logitech mouse you know there it
is this mouse Logitech
dius Prime gaming mouse
okay so what what does the Dias D me
that's this
guy that's this guy this old man in this
story he invented wings he represent the
greatest engineer he also
forged
um he forged some s and you know like
the the Greek mythology is huge you know
you you take a year to read them or
years so anyway he he got the wing and
he you know he and his son is going to
fly away from laby Labyrinth I forgot
why they are there but they they're
going to escape you know instead of you
know Labyrinth you cannot get out so
they he this guy the invented winds you
know so they're going to flew out then
his
son is is too idiotic like today's zumas
like today's white American Gamers like
the uh hot dog guy you know they they
think they know
everything so he's just you know the dad
says don't fly too high because if you
fly too high the Sun is going to melt
your wings because the wings is made of
wax okay but the sun don't listen he
think he can just s and fly and then the
sun melted his wings and he fell
to his his
death okay so what I'm saying is that so
I love Greek mythology because they
reflect the human characters Humanity
okay then you got this Oedipus andh and
the Sphinx so for example in Psychology
we have a word called oropus
complex uh he killed his father okay so
anyway so the the Sphinx story is is
also well
known because like you have to answer qu
three questions or or was it just one
question if you got the answer correct
you pass if you if you got it wrong
death you know so that's some of the
uh stories of Greek mythology so that's
a huge giant digression let's go back to
UNI unic code okay
uh Unicode so we were talking about why
are we talking about Greek mythology
because we were yeah so we were like
onto
um we were talking about uh close back
close
show blog okay blog close Okay so we
were talking
about
um where are we so Unicode block oh
that's actually that's the wrong page so
hold on a
second yeah so actually let's go to c
talk
show so we were talking about unic code
because we were talking
about Greek language how they oh yeah we
were asking how did um
how did mathematics and engineering and
Sciences started to use Greek letters
for you know in Sciences okay that's we
got the answer answer because it's from
you know because Greek mathematics
because Greek mathematics is also the
foundation of w of Western mathematics
up to up to
until up to like 1,600 it's all
basically most vast maj majority of
Western mathematics is is centered
around Greek mathematics
okay
so so that's about that so then we talk
about so Greek so we were talking about
yeah the Greek language then you got
also the world the world's languages you
know the writing system of it critic
used in Russia basically mostly
you got ccs and how are they invented
because you know someone just invented
it you because someone thought that you
know we must have a unique uh alphabet
so they I think it's invented 15 1500
wait um 1,500 or
something okay you can look up Wikipedia
then you got Chinese of course the most
ancient since like 4,000 years
ago uh Chinese and then um then you got
okay then then you got Japanese we
talked about then you got Korean Korean
is also interesting because this
Korean uh they are actually an alphabet
system so this although they don't look
like Western alphabet but they are
actually alphabet you put them together
you you put three or four of these
together into a square it forms word
okay so but it's like alphabet it's an
alphabet
system uh so Korean then you got you
know you got some of the weird ones
ethiopic so I don't know anything about
it so I learned you know where they are
I don't even know where they are
ethiopic you know but one thing we know
ethiopic that's where
the Omar you know if you follow the the
drama of USA politics one of the
congressman I believe congressman is
Omar is from there Ethiopia or some or
or or neighboring countries
okay so this is
Ethiopia then you have you know this is
one of the mainstream of alphabet Arabic
they are not exactly alphabet they are
like because they don't
write
uh vows so the all these are constants
you know I don't know much about it but
and they are also written from right to
left okay
so Arabic we when it comes to Arabic
it's intertwined with the Arabic The the
Middle East religion the Islam okay so
it's kind of intertwined
so because for example you can see they
have characters for God for their God
Allah and they have you know in the name
of God that's one single I mean that's
that's one character unic code okay for
example copy that go here
paste you know when you have a okay so
emac doesn't show because uh because
emac cannot find the Fone that's why
anyway that's one single character in
Unicode for that okay then you also have
several other kind of religious religion
Islamic religion related characters okay
so that's
Arabic then uh okay the words languages
you know so then you have the Indie you
know Indie is very complex you know
India you have so many you know like you
have like several languages in India
literally hundreds but the main ones
is you know you might think okay several
hundreds but actually the main one is
just two or three or five actually no
because there's so many so India that's
one issue of India so you have demon
deari so anyway so you know it looks
like that uh then you also have bangali
it looks like that they kind of similar
though if you compare so if we let's go
back uh for example let's open a
new so you see that's
one this is
stari and this is Spar they are like
similar uh then you have tamamo which is
another language around India or you
know in all in uh southeast Asia and now
I don't know exactly what's their
relation but anyway so you got this very
very interesting uh writing
systems and uh then you have the Tibetan
thing this is actually so this is for
political reasons it became very well
known because in USA in past 50 years
like they want to talk about tiet for
political
reasons uh anyway so you got tetan okay
that's Tibetan characters and by the way
you also have Mongolia but Mongolian
language but I'm not sure I have that
um on my website so let's
see yeah and then you got a few okay
let's just go through so that's it for
today today is like kind of introduction
to the fascinating topic of Unicode or
in other words the history of written
written symbols of humanity okay so you
got the Egyptian hieroglyph okay very
interesting uh and whenever we talked
about this we mention to we need to
mention this look at this breasts tits
okay childbirth you know the white men
the Western culture of today is kind of
you know they they they they feel uneasy
when you have these
things uh then tits then you also got
penis right there and of course
Microsoft censored it because Microsoft
do not provide the phone for it but you
can see a picture of it here because
I've
captured that looks like that okay penis
and piece I guess I guess and that's
what I don't know what that is penis
with a tower so it's your homework to
find out what does this character mean
exactly so you see Egyptian High Ro life
is like 3,000 years old something like
that okay so basically in the older
times you don't you know you say things
as they are usually so you got
tits critical importance in
communication because that's fundamental
okay the Ts for feeding children you
know women's organ and penis of
course too and child birth you know
that's like the the fundamental thing
about human animals
us uh and you know some of them are
funny like you don't know what is this
one for you
see oh God
do you like do you guys enjoy the show
is it
good so there's a question
conscience so conscience is
computational or not question that's an
interesting topic about AI okay we I
talked about it before uh but you can if
you search
forar artificial intelligence podcast
you will find my discussion about it
about the meaning of intelligence
sentient
soul you know related things which is
very much
philosophical and also partially very
deep in science and in Neuroscience
that's what we are trying to discover
and we are learning more and more every
day like every
year so Consciousness I mean the first
question I mean you are asking
Consciousness is it
computational so I see so you are taking
a particular perspective already you
know instead of instead of asking what
is consciousness that is a question but
you are already taking a particular
perspective you are saying it's you know
maybe it's computational we don't know
nobody knows okay uh so anyway so then
another question the word will forever
be indepted to the Greeks for both their
art and Mathematics
yes well I mean I mean
part of the world to be more precise
because you know one thing interesting
is that whenever we talk in English like
us we automatically assume usually
usually without awareness without
explicit explicit awareness but we
automatically assume we are talking
about the Western World okay but the
Earth is not just the Western World the
Earth you know if you go go by
population some
70% are Asians Chinese and Indian in
particular people 70% are like Chinese
and Indian okay and uh if you go by land
I don't know what 60% you know majority
is not white men's World it's China
Russia India and also Middle East you
know they are not white man's culture
they are not Western mathematics they
don't follow Greeks in fact they don't
know what the [ __ ] is zos what the [ __ ]
is all these Greek mythology you know if
you go to Japan if you go to China Hong
Kong Malaysia Singapore you ask them
what's you know some of the story we
told the Greek mythology the god and
goddesses and the nymphs they have no
idea what the [ __ ] is Medusa but instead
they have Buddha they have Buddha and
The Monkey King and you know they have
the Asian stuff so so we so the
interesting thing we need to remember is
that when whenever we talk in English we
we kind of automatically assume without
being
aware but we assume that we are talking
in the context of white man's world and
history and
Society so the Greek mathematics is not
has no influence almost whatsoever in
China for
example uh and for India I don't know
much about uh India okay so anyway so so
here is another beautiful mural in San
Francisco right here 40 minutes Drive in
San Francisco about of Medusa one of the
principal
characters that is known to Americans
you know the Medusa the story of Medusa
now let me tell let me tell her story
okay why is she interesting why is she
Al ugly because
she she was once the most beautiful girl
okay but one day the the god of the sea
posidon grabbed her and raped her or rap
you know grab her and raped her in a
temple of the Athena okay Athena is
another is a goddess is a very high
powerered goddess okay so back then it's
Greek religion okay it's not just
stories and mythology it's religion they
have temples for worship okay so you
have the Temple of Athena okay Athena so
one day the sea you know the the Sea of
the the god of the sea
posidon grabbed a girl this beautiful
girl Medusa and raped her or or sidu you
know that like in Greek mythology rape
and sidu is kind of mixed Okay so don't
know exactly it's not like today's like
the today's American idiots or the
social justice oh rape oh dead rape they
don't they don't know what they're
talking about so anyway posidon grabbed
her and [ __ ] her in the temple of
Athena Athena saw it got angry and
punished the girl and you you're going
to be the most ugly girl possible and
which whoever sees you eye to eye
they'll be so shocked that they become a
stone
they become petrified you know like when
you go out when you go to a street you
know let's say in a party or in a bar
you know you see this girl uh you you
didn't see her face but you want to go
check it out then she turned around and
turns out she's very ugly and you kind
of oh I you know you pretend you are
doing something else you know that
that's what that's the significance of
this story okay she becomes so ugly that
anyone look at her with eye contact
become becomes
petrified that is my sense my you know
you might say interpretation of the
story okay
so so now the story focus on few
things first of all [ __ ] okay because
the god want [ __ ] you know men want to
[ __ ] women any almost you know we we are
willing we are willing at able you know
if you are if you want to F let's go
that's a characteristics of males all
men in the world okay all men are like
that so you got this posidon which which
is
powerful okay who gets to [ __ ] the
powerful men gets to [ __ ] so called
today in this Zuma idiots alha male okay
you don't get to [ __ ] if you are the
weak you know you you you don't know
nothing you don't have power you don't
have muscles okay the god you if you
powerful males get to [ __ ] all the girls
so you got this posidon the god of the
sea grabbed this girl the most beautiful
girl and [ __ ] her why grab because the
women now this is another very sensitive
political topic women they they
they they love you know in other words
you have like rape fantasy why is it
fantasy it's in well you know it's
partially true because it's it exists
okay because they basically you know the
female they they want to have children
they want to have a children of a
powerful man who can protect them who
can basically ensure that their son and
their daughters get to
survive okay that's basically that's a
bottom line their son they want their
son and daughters to survive
if you [ __ ] with random men or not so
powerful weak men you have children but
they may not survive because this man
cannot protect you when there's a tiger
or wolf C by you
know so and and if you prefer you know
if you prefer the poets you know you
don't like the powerful man if you are
I'm a girl I prefer the gentle kind you
know the nerd kind of guy
I will die out because my children you
know this nerd this poor s poor no money
like me he cannot protect a girl you
know you know when when when B done come
by you know I'm just going to
disappear the bad guy sped and so on
right so so if I'm a girl who prefer
this you know this weak man or whatever
I will die out you know so the only
human that will remain are girls who
prefer the powerful ones because they
children
survive that's why women are like that
and that's for the same reason men wants
to [ __ ]
around okay so this capture the this
story capture the P you know the the man
wants to [ __ ] capture the powerful man
capture the bu and and capture the the
rape you know the rape or
seduction and captures
the beautiful why why why is the story
say she she was the most beautiful
because that's what girls want Beauty
captures the the attract the eyes of men
okay Beauty not ugly not old women we
must res like the American liberal you
know culture or we must must respect old
old women's you know things like that
like like like P pure purely
[ __ ] of course you respect old women
but I mean that but we you need to
understand how things work okay it is
the girls that attract men okay that
become powerful when when women when
females are young that that's when they
are the most valuable to society and
that's when they have the most power so
this story captured that because she was
the most beautiful it the story didn't
say she was a old woman or she was like
something you know the the uh ugly woman
no she is was she was the most
beautiful and why she became and and
then the story mention Athena which is
another woman jealous
jealousy he sees a you know a girl
[ __ ] with another guy in my temple
you know in her Temple so she punished
her jealousy and punishment and made her
to become the most ugly okay with the
snakes on her head things like that so
that's why I say the Greek mythologies
they to me at least they often captures
the fundamental Essence qualities of
human animals
okay I think that's it for today today I
kind of rambled a lot on Unicode did we
finish unic code yet let's see did we
when when is the last um oh yeah we
haven't covered there's so many
interesting so let's just so we already
talked for 80 minutes let's continue a
few so we got
Egyptian hoges okay very interesting
then we got
COI form this is the most earliest this
is even earlier than Egyptian so COI I'm
I don't know if I pronounced it
correctly Kuni form okay okay it was uh
in year
3,20 I mean 3,200 BC so it's 5,000 years
old okay you got this you know very
interesting characters characters look
at that very interesting you know and
complex characters you know I look at
today I think of it as a space space
ship you know you got
this space
ships okay very interesting then we got
and and here you have a Kuni form edged
in stone you know I found it on
Wikipedia of course um yeah so this is
from what year
uh I don't know what year from Wikipedia
okay so from
Wikipedia and oh this is trilingual okay
so
anyway in written in Old Persian and
aradian and elamite okay uh some dead
languages but all all using this uh uh
quen form
okay then we got Linear B now Linear B
for some reason this is small Asian this
is from uh wait um oh not well actually
it's just 3,000 to 4,000 years so linear
be very popular among white
people so on Microsoft Windows you don't
have the font but on the Mac it has the
font by default so it shows and but if
you don't have the F you can download
the F you know here
uh just search for SAR Unicode you'll
find it okay then you got fici which is
this is the root of the Latin alphabet
okay the Latin alphabet the Greek
alphabet they all came from the
phenician alphabet okay so it was like 3
3,000 years
old
1,200 BC okay for uh fici and very
interesting they got this X-Men symbol
you know today's you know
X-Men uh finition okay so then you got
run this is also this is this is
obsessed by a lot white people I
noticed you know before before I wrote
this page I don't understand because
sometimes I often see here about run
characters by the way I don't know how
to pronounce it run or running I I think
it's just run okay so you you hear it
for example in one of of the most
popular books uh the toan trilogy you
know the two towers the you know
that are obsessed by a lot nerds I
didn't I didn't find it interesting at
all but for example that book that
author has used run characters
um yeah actually you know actually one
of these is uh named after him token
token uh version of run okay so I didn't
understand why what are what what you
know what the [ __ ] are these until I
looked up so I spent you know few days
few weeks to look up so it turns out so
it's a this is a writing system used in
Europe northern Europe in particular for
uh up to up to 13,000 okay so from year
150 to
to
1500 runs no used in northern Europe so
in other words this is the this is the
Asian version of English alphabet okay
kind of yeah you know so so that's why
so that's so in other words it's a root
of the American American is mostly from
UK and Germany okay UK is mostly from
Germany so you know that's my
understanding I might be wrong but but
basically okay
so the
most and the majority of white men in
USA United State of America their ancest
ancest
ancestory is from Germany okay German
not it it Italy not French not Greece
not Russia okay the majority of the
white men in USA or white skin colored
people are from Germany okay they are
ancest ancestry and and also not from
UK but anyway the UK United Kingdom the
Eng England they they are uh as far as I
understand they also are came from or
inally from Germany German and Vikings
okay I don't know exactly the history
but anyway so you got this WR characters
I you know I noticed why are all these
people you know showing this for example
is a keyboard with key CS in run you
know you know so you can see that so
what is this thing so I that's how I
learned about the Run
characters uh okay and then then we have
made up languages you know the Deseret
alphabet this is for
moments now this relates to cality
because moments is kind of a deviant
depending on your your point of view it
was for most Christians is it the
moments is considered a deviant
Christianity you know they don't accept
moments as
Christians you know but anyway so so
this you know the desate alphabet is a
artificial I mean invented
alphabet uh just um and it's phonetic
the design principle is such that
such that each letter corresponds to a
phonetic so when you see a word you
always know how it's pronounced when you
know a a word pronunciation you always
know how it's spelled so it you know so
it's called I believe this is called
alphabet principle alphabetic principle
okay which Spanish has that property so
anyway the desert alphabet invented by
moments in 1847 okay it it died out
never caught up but then we have another
uh try shavian alphabet uh created in
1960s okay so let's see Deseret is
1847 now shavian alphabet is 1960 so
about 100 years later now this is
another alphabet that's created from
scratch the design principle is that
it's this is for English to represent
English phonetically so you got about 36
characters I think you know design such
that you have a system
systematic way of pronouncing it and
writing it okay also never caught up I
mean also kind of died okay that I think
that's about it for Unico today okay so
I was originally going to you know I
need to make some changes on my Unico
page but but we we didn't do that at all
and you don't even know what I'm going
to do so let that be next day or
tomorrow or
um okay I think that's it for today
let's
see how many people are watching
concurrent viewers
six that's it for today thank you guys
for watching bye
uh so like the bright air black so I
don't know who is that guy so let's look
up and's see what is uh interesting
about
that hello guys bye H then
so um bright air
you see by the way so are we seeing a
unic code
here let's see
what
uh
invisible you see we found something
interesting let me tell you guys okay
you see I just copied I just copied the
YouTube
comments but you see I mve the cruiser
the first character is you got a
invisible character there can you guys
see you see let's magnify you see so
here's my cluer you know move to the
left move to the right right right right
right right right there it is it becom
you know it becomes a thin slice
then I I move right again again th slice
invisible I move again then you got to
the eye so you see they you got two
secret characters hidden there that is
from YouTube YouTube is doing that and
and that uh the reason for that is that
it actually so if you move here then you
call describe fun uh describe character
you can see
you got a zero width space there okay
now let's move again and
call so you got two zero width space
okay
so that's tricky because when you have
this invisible characters it kind of
screw up your text processing because
you know because your character count is
off and so on so I I have a command to
replace and find replace system for
example the command is called s replace
invisible character do it so it says
found zero with space okay replace yes
okay found again replace yes okay then
it replaces all replaced all invisible
characters okay now let's look up this
uh bright air Black by David Van okay
let's see what is
that a novel okay
Bri air Black by David Van is a
retaining of the myth of medus media
wife of Jason of golden F man f it
begins as media Jason and AR feeling the
uh oh
interesting bye guys uh this is a no
okay so
uh G 80 over Advantage okay that
question has been answered to death okay
glove 80 versus Advantage 360 now if you
just search SAR keyboard glove 0 versus
Advantage physics you'll find part of
you you'll find my entire uh written
answer to that bye guys