good morning guys welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh today is November
15th Friday 10 o clock in the morning
San Francisco time now YouTube says
warning please check the video
resolution the current resolution is
1920 x 1080 which is not optimal what
not optimal very annoying not optimal
well so good morning good morning people
Emily Alan Fitch BOTS Nebo and scene 2
so today we are going to do JavaScript
the Wonderland of JavaScript and
mathematics fantastic mathematics
morning Cathy and have a look at the
math now this is math in second life and
that is what we're going to do polyhedra
platonic solids wait do I look good
check ok I look good I look good and
beautiful so today math platonic solids
regular polyhedron now this is called
equal angular spiral or logarithmic
spiral and that I don't know what the I
forgot what is that but and and this is
a bundle this is hopped bundle very
advanced topic in differential geometry
and yeah differential geometry hops hops
bundle and you have this Japanese girl
in kimono and you have this fantastic
fantastic thing and you have this try
for you or not and mobius strip and you
have this japanese girl you recurse Evan
so you guys do you know do you guys know
what character this this is this is
Second Life snow so it's fantastic
this is almost 10 years ago 2008 also
and this is the most this is the one of
the most wonderful experience in singer
life like you know as I mentioned before
in second life everything is built by
yourself by by the players so you go
there you build these things
so this dome this is called it's you
know this this dome is called geodesic
dome which is a idiotic name okay but
people call it that because of the book
Buckminster crackpot you know there is
this guy say my mathematician whose name
is Buckminster how do you say his name
math yes JavaScript so there's this guy
bug mister you know guy okay let's look
up them Buckminster so / keepo / keepo i
remember i i know how to find his name
by just searching perking ball / keepo
okay this guy in my opinion is one of
the crackpot so we are going to do some
free loot then we are going to get on
into javascript we are going to code
live three dimensional rotation of a
cube in real time and we gonna
disconnect to be less than one hour and
not know libraries no framework no
nothing pure javascript and it's going
to be within 100 lines yes Buckminster
buckminster fuller that guy you know
he's a crackpot
he's one of the crackpot crackpot to me
ok so what's his name so let's go you
know well there it is his name is there
so this etymology okay yeah this is this
guy no that's not the thing
so preparation and occurrence etymology
let's go find his name this guy so how
do you say it
fuller yeah yeah Wikipedia doesn't link
to his name
amazing so he you seek am i okay this
crackpot crackpot oh okay
it's quite interesting his name is not
mentioned in the articles content wait
let's see let's try it again
well anyway so let's just go back here
we found this guy thinking out loud this
guy okay this is a crackpot now anyway
he he did you know quite a few things
he's kind of like the coat leader kind
of thin coat in in technology and
sciences coat kind of guy so he created
well he pushed for you know he you know
this coat kind of people they have a
bunch of joggins dragons always come
with coat okay so he did he has this
space spaceship earth time axion this
ephemeralization synergy 10 security all
these are crap [ __ ] this [ __ ] head so he
created you know lots of these things so
one of the things he created is called
geodesic dome okay sorry
geodesic dome
Mincy by the way by the way guys I'm a
member of Mensa okay it is true I'm a
member of Mensa
in 1993 also you see it requires
membership you know it requires payment
to be a member so every you know in 1993
it's like $40 or $50 a year so I was a
member
geodesic domes okay let me show you this
fascinating poor Odo's he had his own
words - I don't yeah I don't like the
poor audio sky but poor poor others he's
he's a mathematician you know call it a
qualified mathematician so I don't like
Perl auto poor autos and in physics
these this this there is this sky
finiman like every programmers every
minute every hour every day is I've been
phenomenal ease phenomen thinks phenomen
is like that idiot I don't like these
people okay fin finiman poor dough but
these two person you know they are solid
okay I just don't like them their
personality their style I don't like
them but but however this guy but mean
Buckminster Fuller I think he's a
crackpot okay so anyway so but let's not
pay membership maybe maybe fifteen years
ago
Oh nappy young fifteen years ago
wait aren't you the game you you working
again Kim company right
but anyway so here we got I have a
collection of the most beautiful things
geo geo tea sick Tom now okay so the
reason we mentioned this because we were
looking at you know geodesic domes and
you know and I was saying this is a
stupid name okay it's a idiotic name it
doesn't it's where I'm not
to talk about the history of that word
or the anyway it's a stupid name the
proper name for this kind of thing will
should be regular polyhedron dome okay
oh you oh you just call it polyhedron
dome okay I'll see your spherical dome
okay not geodesic it because it's
nothing about you this is idiotic okay
that by that book full full full minster
guy crackpot
and by the way Emily good morning Emily
Emily have you been to this place this
is a beautiful place the the atom
project you know the other day you went
south you know it so I was going to ask
you about whether you've been to this
place this this face you know it's in UK
United Kingdom Conwell come war come war
send Austell convoy UK okay so so there
it is you have geodesic domes and you
have this dome in Montreal I was there
like 30 years ago in 1987 also you have
nothing there
okay so it might be a you know place to
visit and then then you have the Disney
space earth and stuff like that so we
are talking about domes and all these
are you know beautiful you know modern
architectures so codes you know Tom's
and Tom's and Tom's and Tom's and domes
and domes and domes and you have igloo
hotel this this is a primitive dome
technically I don't think well they are
this kind of architecture they are all
called domes okay but this is not this
one is not
apparently it's nice very spiritual
okay so and this one is a tone atomium
now this one is at one of you people
space Belgium okay so you guys can visit
this atone atonium it's modeled it's
modeled on the the molecule structure of
ion I think okay I don't
I forgot the details but you know it's
you got this thing okay so we gonna do
JavaScript yes I guess yeah okay no
problem no problemo
see there's a forum for this stream yes
okay so so we're talking about your
geodesic domes so now let's get back to
you know so I was talking about second
life so you know this mathematician
henri stageman he introduced me to a
second life and there it is tetrahedron
no this is octahedron so you have this
octahedron a stack of octahedrons and
then i want to show you this this is
built by my girlfriend okay
Lorenz attractor the I had the most
wonderful time in second life when we
are doing this so you know what happens
you know so ii i've it's like a 3d game
right so you this this character in the
middle like floating in the sky that's
me so you see this this this stars they
are like they are they are called
sprites they are actually called
particles they are so this shape is
generated by particles basically just
like images you know so anyway you these
are generated in real time and you can
look around and you can follow it it's
quite amazing it's quite amazing to
experience this thing in real life and
we have quite a few things you know
we're gonna talk for hours if we're
gonna talk about this let's see let's
open some of the pages and let's just
see what they are
so this Lorenz attractor that's amazing
let's see okay and then you have then
you have Eric Alexander's home the
sphere this thing now this thing is
nesting forever you see this this wing
has a little ring at the end and that
little ring has a little ring it in the
end and and go on forever they interlock
so this is a monster in topology this
thing this shape is created this concept
this object is is a monstrosity in
topology and then you have this Spanish
keys
chango's and that is me okay I'm a
trance okay back then you don't have the
trance word not really but I was dressed
as a girl in second life and this this
this woman this lady but past
shada don't she is a mathematician she
is a great artist mathematician artist
now you might have have heard of her or
seeing her things if you are into math
just search for her name past
fed ba don't anyway it's amazing ok
second life so you have iterated
function systems you have then you have
this inversion kind of turning or
tourist inside out ok so we got lots of
things ok then this is the most
beautiful thing in second life you know
then we hit there we have a isoka he'd
run in this storm and these are
beautiful
mystic Japanese comics and there's this
nico which is my companion in second
life and this this cat is me and there
it is
there we are and you know it's truly
amazing in second life and you have
other things so second life you know
that was then
I haven't been to second I for like
seven years also so we're gonna do
JavaScript yes let's see what some
common sky in real life
you are a girl equals two guy in real
life that's you know that's not true
actually you know today there's you know
even ten years ago okay that's another
topic anyways it's because I can talk
about that topic about girl game players
female presence online you know I can
talk about that for 20 minutes but let's
do that next time
Bathsheba is from the Bible she's a
women she's a woman King David cheated
with oh I didn't know okay that's
interesting the interesting story so so
we cannot start JavaScript okay don't
worry about that and and since we are
talking about polyhedron guys this is I
have a collection of great software for
doing for fun software for polyhedra I
highly recommend this one by Jeff weeks
you just go there and download okay go
to my website you go to Solly actually
just just such folks re polyhedron
you'll find it okay and okay let me know
I don't I just paste the link cut and go
to it has evolved significantly you mean
the Second Life okay that's interesting
so what are other comments let me see
so you go to this page okay
this you know this the first one is
fantastic download it it's free on
Windows Mac or oh I phone or even iPhone
so it's very fun and you can learn
something about polyhedra the math of
polyhedra then you have other software
for doing polyhedra and the magic
polyhedrons are one of my favorite math
puzzles this is my piano by the way back
in year 2000 when I had money when I had
okay so so anyway polyhedron and let's
do JavaScript in so let's see what the
comments okay okay it's not frozen for
me
comments okay comments keep the comments
going like a river the spice must flow
okay so spin subs miski sub sub Pinsky
okay that's how you pronounce it I
suppose devolved Sartre talk email okay
that's parts forum replace of and let's
go with that art okay so let's do the
JavaScript so we're gonna do it from
scratch and first of all of course I
need to show you what it looks like very
simple okay now you don't need to know a
lot math you know act you don't need to
know any math okay I'm just gonna show
you how to do it from scratch so here it
is we're gonna write this you can rotate
it rotate it in real time you can change
to octahedron rotate in real time and
that's what we're gonna do okay let's
begin so begin at the beginning we're
gonna create a HTML file okay save this
as HTML okay let's say X X poly pol Y
dot HTML okay magnify and let me start
command log mod so for you Emacs users
you can see all my Emacs commands on the
left window okay so HTML start a kind of
HTML skeleton rotate cube that's what we
cannot write I'm just going to show the
most basics once you know you know I'm
going to show you the core techniques
then you can create any other polyhedra
okay save it create a new file name it
JavaScript so we're gonna paste it link
Oh Fayed
okay so this is a JavaScript file open
it and wait open it
yes okay here's the file comment today
state and now close that save showing
browser
there is nothing we're gonna show this
in chrome okay so let's go to Chrome
actually so this is our file okay so let
me let's put a header h1 rotate cube
there it is okay now go back to here I
need to copy these two mics on talk show
so we have a memory of what we talked
about so okay this crackpot okay cause I
don't want to close that okay let's go
to chat okay so so let's do so now we
got the template now first of all we
need to create a dive because that's
where are we gonna insert our graphics
okay now Polly anchor okay usually they
call this anchor so I think do we have
JavaScript coder here raise your hand
please do it do you have anyone who
called JavaScript here and I know al
Allen does so in general how do you call
just regice regice stood for the forum
okay so so Poli
so Poli
so what we gonna do so we're gonna do
let's say Poli box okay
this draw area yeah and you know comfort
I'm confused about every time there's a
naming you get I get confused because
you have to go back and forth about what
is a better name okay so anyway so we
had we have a dive draw draw area and we
need that because then we gonna insert
graphics there so here is our JavaScript
code let's let's constant okay constant
draw area equals to document get element
by ID okay draw area so that that gets
the element okay now now what we need to
do next okay I need to I need to make my
font larger okay settings okay hold on a
sec night hold on a second so settings
farm size ok default font let me make my
Emacs font larger so menlo 15 okay
mineral 15
okay let's see okay so that we are back
here so so what is it we want to do now
we want to Emax settings close okay so
we got that the the next thing so we're
going to begin by drawing one surface of
a cube okay here's what we're going to
do write a app that does rotate a cube
in real time so first of all are we
going to start to do is just have one
face of a cube and trying to rotate it
okay so so let's define face constant
okay face we need four coordinates so
face is coordinates okay so four points
in three space in 3d so the points the
coordinate will be let's say it will be
[Music]
one one one okay one one one
okay let's copy that then let's go back
here then one negative one one
okay then go down you can figure this
coordinate out so then go down it'll be
1 negative 1 negative 1 then go back
there it will be 1 1 negative 1 1 1
negative 1 check is that correct I think
that's correct so we got a face of a
let's say face 1 about you now we got a
face we have to now create a that's a
coordinate of a face now we need a
projection
now what projection does is that it will
take a 3d point and put it into a 2d
plane so project so we're gonna write
this function okay parallel project
constant arrow function parallel project
it takes a 3d point X Y Z and it returns
a 2d point in this case we simply drop
the Z coordinate okay so that's a
projection because you know your screen
is flat it's 2d so you want to any 3d
point you you drop the Z and then you
can draw it on your canvas
okay then we're going to create a SVG
okay
okay so I'm going to show you my SVG
tutorial so you can go to and you can
read about the SVG things let's go here
so SVG tutorial this is important
because without this you cannot do it
let's get back to the talk show and put
it here okay so back to close that back
to okay so we're gonna so what we gonna
do we gonna first of all create we are
going to create a SVG element like that
okay so to do this in JavaScript so we
are using javascript to create these
these elements so how do you how do you
do that you go to SVG you you you call
this function okay so let's just do it
SVG element okay SVG element you say
document create element okay ng because
that's what you need let's see let's
let's double check so you go through SVG
you go down there is a
scripting SVG and here is the function
you need create element NS not ng yes
stand for namespace doesn't matter if
you don't know what it means because
that's complexity created in XML so
anyway so you call this function create
element in s then that will return a SVG
element it will basically return a
return something like that so now you
want to add
okay so add the width and hate okay okay
so add attribute and attribute set
attribute set attribute okay that's what
you want so set attribute which let's
say 500 okay then hate okay then we have
that okay and then we want to attach our
SVG element to the draw areas to the
dive okay to the development on the HTML
page so what you do is speech permitted
what do you mean so what do you do is we
want to append child okay that's that's
what you want to do so SVG element dot
append child okay and append the draw
area so you go back to our page okay
then you press command option I to turn
on the JavaScript console now on windows
is ctrl shift I I think Oh control I
think it's ctrl shift I but you can find
out oh press f12
so then you go to elements then you can
see here we have created oh we have not
created did we create so let's see we
have the SVG oh we we got this wrong so
this should actually this should be draw
areas attach SVG to it okay this is the
right way so go back to the browser
refresh wait what oh it's not there
because we got it wrong it's not class
it should be ID so let's go back to our
HTML page so instead of a class it
should be ID okay now refresh in browser
why why don't we see SVG tag here
because the code is wrong so why why
don't we so draw area so area is the is
the dive okay and
so area okay bunks one okay let's just
name box one so I keep renaming this
thing annoying box one okay box one is
the place we want to draw so so box 1
then we box one appendchild
SVG why is it not working then so let's
refresh oh because I have JavaScript off
what what ideate in brave okay you
cannot turn okay so let's go back to
Chrome then let's do it here okay how
long I've been talking 33 minutes we
gotta go faster we gotta go faster we
cannot finish this so there we have it
you can see we have added you know a SVG
tag there that's how you do it now we
got we are going to create this face
this face in SVG so we gonna just like
before we copy this line paste it here
we're gonna SVG face 1 okay so here's
the SVG and the tag we want to use is
polygon P Oly gon okay and what are the
attribute the attribute are so let's go
back to SVG and our SVG reference
polygon there it is so here is the
syntax so let's let's copy it so we want
to create something like that okay this
polygon so points points is the thing so
points and this the point should be like
that so we need to generate that okay so
how do you generate so we need now so
you see now what we need to do so we got
four points in space in 3d space we want
to make we want to project them to the
plane drop the last element
so we got a bunch of two-dimensional
points then we got four of them for
two-dimensional points then we can we're
gonna change the array into that into
this stream format so how do you do that
easy okay so let's do that so face one
dot map okay we apply a function
parallel project so that will return a
list of two-dimensional points each
element is just X NY okay now once we
got that we just say to stream okay then
it will become like that a sequence of
numbers stream and the okay so so this
is actually what we want so we put it
there it's let's shrink this thing this
shrink okay so that's this is so we are
creating trying to create that so let's
do that so another thing we need is this
okay we need to add a style otherwise it
won't have any color and stuff sometimes
because in SVG sometimes the default
style is blank or not
so it's stroke blue fill yellow okay
let's try that so once we have way this
is this is this should be called SVG
face so this this face will be something
looks like that actually will be a
square okay so once we got the face we
need to attach it to the SVG element
basically nested inside the SVG element
so let's just copy the code let's do it
so basically like that
okay so SVG element appendchild up in
the face then you append SPG to the box
okay let's go through the browser
refresh let's see what we got no we
failed we have failed so box ID equals
to box one then why don't how come we
don't see SVG inside so so box one
what's going on refresh and is there any
error messages let's go to console
console syntax error missing parentheses
what line 21
okay I'm missing a parenthesis it says
yeah indeed
because extra call Mark because extra
semicolon semicolon is a pain yes in
JavaScript refresh who what's going on
so so so points
oh then here again okay yeah so back to
browser refresh now it's good now let's
look at our elements correct correct
you see we got this poly polygon element
you see it's all good
now why is it not showing possibly
because oh I know why because right now
you see our polygon our length is is our
square has a width of 2 basically but
our our canvas is 500 so we don't see it
it's tiny that it that is why so in
order to solve that we can add something
called user coordinate so
to that view box now view box takes
phone numbers x and y and width and hate
okay
XY is the ancient on the upper left
corner now let me go back to the HTML
and let me show you something okay let
me let's add a style here so you can see
a border of the SVG so style box one
folder okay solid thing way okay now
back to the browser show okay that is
our canvas so we know our image should
fall inside it so now we got a border we
go back to javascript and let's see what
did we I close the window by mistake so
many mistakes so any questions so far so
so far so good guys let me know okay so
questions
okay so so we're going back to
JavaScript and we are doing we are okay
we got a so far so good great Thank You
Alan so so we back to JavaScript refresh
again so right now our cube is too small
so we are trying to solve that with we
trying to solve that by adding a user
coordinate coordinate so here we tell we
tell JavaScript that I mean we tell the
browser that from here to here from the
left to the right instead of you know
it's it's 500 pixels however we want to
tell the browser to consider it to be
let's say 4 instead of 500 and you know
so because because our square is only
with weeks two and the XY is the upper
left corner we are trying to tell the
browser what what's the coordinate of
that point so we wanted to be a negative
negative negative two and negative two
okay so in this case the Orangemen
should be the inner center so let's
refresh there it is we got some kind of
thing we can detect a face you know
actually that actually that's not a face
that's that's the stroke so what have we
done this is actually not good because
because okay so the SVG let me explain
this so we got this SVG canvas okay the
SVG by default from left to right is the
axis and the vertical is the y-axis and
by default the top left corner is zero
zero so X goes from left to right and Y
goes from top to down and you see what
so so so what we are doing you know why
is it shows like that because our face
happens to be we are actually just
seeing a line because we are looking at
the face edge on that is y so let's
change to some other face let's redefine
it let's change it to some other face so
let's change it to let's figure out so 0
0 so so that let me figure out ok so
negative 1 1 1 ok
so from here negative 1 1 1 okay
then negative 1 negative 1 1 ok then
negative 1 negative 1 1 okay
so the Z is or just 1 okay so let's try
that in browser let's refresh ok we got
something else now this is incorrect we
got we still got something wrong now
let's say stroke width okay now because
stroke width stroke width 0.2 okay then
back to the browser show okay it's
better but oh it should not be a
triangle something is wrong here so 1 1
so 1 1 1 1 1 negative 1 1 negative 1
negative 1
oh the last one so it should be 1
negative 1 that's why there it is we got
a face of a cube ok now we are going to
rotate this thing my friends we are
going to rotate this thing in real time
ok now you see we I'm just I'm going to
show you the fundamentals how to apply
this you see we got one face later on
you can add you know phase 2 phase 3
when we have time we'll do that but now
with it let's do this but but for now
let's try to rotate this thing so in
order to rotate okay hold on a second
let me let me let me get this yeah
perhaps I take a break and mitts
see what's going on with the comments so
far has just manual dom manipulation
stuff nothing math graphics specific
[Laughter]
though we got we got we got graphics
well nothing math graphics we got we got
math and we got graphics actually
actually this projection this projection
is called parallel projection it's
actually math you know it may seem
simple because the way we do it because
we are just you know it like if you
don't explain it looks like oh you just
drop see you know it's like CD but it's
not silly at all this is this is you
know technically it's a projection with
a projection point at infinity okay
that's why that's what it is all a
projection and anyway we okay okay get
interesting when we do when we want to
do the rotation because that will
require matrix multiplication okay so
actually so so let me take a break so so
at this point they are quite a few ways
to go depends on so let me ask you guys
a question I was I'm wondering whether
I'm getting hot or not I guess not so
much so let me ask you guys a question
so we have three ways to go one I'm
going to explain projection not not
parallel projection I'm just going to
explain a little bit about projection
because that's really interesting
because when you want the application to
be at the in the end you don't want
parallel projection you because your
eyes in real life it's not parallel
projection you want perspective 'ti
because something closer is bigger okay
things far away is not you know it's
smaller that that is projection
so we so I'm gonna explain that okay
explain projection so let me know which
one you want okay
extreme projection a bit okay Oh to
explain rotation you know we we are
going to do a rotation that that is
basically matrix multiplication okay but
I'm going to explain how do you derive
that now okay explain rotation explain
how to derive the rotation matrix or
what does matrix multiplication means
because if you haven't studied this
before you know when you say matrix
multiplication it seems magical or
something just come out right you know
what you know so I can explain that or
forego those just get on with the code
as far as we can so which one like which
one interests you that's that's the key
you know which one you are interested
the most okay whoever's are still here
so explain projection or to explain how
to derive the rotation matrix or
continuing with a code so you can
actually see more JavaScript and stuff
so guys let me know okay pick pick pick
a choice so but are you see watching
Mart you know give give me a choice
let's see how long I've been talking
livestream video
Sophie Fitch says three okay we got
seventeen people not too bad
one vote for rotation okay so we got the
tie
one more okay three wait so Allen says
one explained projection now Fitch says
three continuing with the code okay push
out the JavaScript code and one vote for
M so Emily says rotation okay so we got
a tie one each one got one vote okay
I'll just do all then they did that you
know let's do quickly we can do that
so projection it's easy to do okay well
you know we we are not going to do it
today but let me just show you the
basics steel graphic projection
projective illusion no that's not what
we want we want
okay so linear algebra
so in this article I describe the
differences between technical drawing
and descriptive geometry and projective
geometry and linear algebra you can read
it offline but basically this this is
what projection is about this is
projection is what allows you to have
real realistic drawings you know in
before 1800 before 1700 when people draw
like in churches it's like flat you know
God you know all the people are flat you
don't have realism but however this
drawing by this guy
Albert Albert duro he's a master okay
not this page now this guy is a master
of illustration you know he's you
probably have seen his work is fantastic
is one of the best artists okay so so
you see when you look at these drawings
they have the ilysm why it came from
projection okay projection is a key now
when you look at this window okay this
window actually also illustrate
projection when you have shadow weight
yeah shadow is the best example of
projection you know if you have a
flashlight or candle you know when you
have a sphere or something you can see
the shadow that's projection so
basically you have one point it shoot
out straight lines over then the
straight lines will touch whatever
object you know whatever object like a
bow or whatever object then it will heat
the ground so the point on the object
and the point on the ground that that is
that is the point on the ground is a
projection of the point on the on the
object so in the case of a window you
know the patterns on a window get
projected into the wall so that you know
that's projection that's in principle
okay that so this you know they
any type of projections but but the one
we are talking about is called how do
you call that anyway it's just called
projection it's the most important
projection it is from projection that
gives you real lism enjoying so is it
may seem trivial to to us today but back
in back in 1500 you know so there it is
14:17 171 you know most people people do
not understand it you know when they
draw they do they draw a flat like
children's drawing you know flat
everything is flat they don't understand
it
so it take us something like you know
1500 years to understand projection and
this guy illustrates projection you know
so you can see basically from one point
to to the wall to the canvas so here so
though the point here this this point is
a fixed point that's kind of the light
source
you call that light source then you have
this is the object you want to draw so
for every point on the object you draw a
straight line to the light source then
you have a plan crossing that straight
line so so the intersection between the
line and that plane is the is the point
you want then you get realistic joint
okay so that's about projection okay and
today we have CAD software we are
blender we have AutoCAD they are all
based on projections okay so that's all
projection is it except it's automat
automated you know it's done by how is
it done it's done by matrix
multiplication but that's another thing
okay so let's copy that so let's close
that that's about projection and that's
about that projection so we we got we
got we're gonna finish this
okay so projection then we're gonna talk
about let's see the other thing we
cannot talk about so okay wait hold on a
second about projection so you have seen
that you have seen that you know this is
projection from one point okay now
actually hold on a second I have another
illustration somewhere I need to show
that because perspective drawing okay so
so here here is another example of
projection and this is exactly what we
are doing so you see a cube that's what
we are going to draw and this plan is
our canvas and this this point here
that's a projection point or the
position of the eye so you can think of
that point as a position of your eye so
just like before you for every point on
the object you you draw a line to your
eye or the projection point then the
intersection between that line and the
plane is should be the point on you know
the canvas so this pain is called canvas
so that's how you get realistic drawing
now we are going to do a little bit
variation now suppose this I point is
moving further further further and
further away then apparently the what
you will see on a canvas will be
different slightly different okay mostly
the same but slightly different if the
point if the projection point moves to
infinity like very far away then that
projection is called parallel projection
and that is what we are doing here
so you see this function parallel
projection you see when you do
projection you have a point on
three-dimensional space
the output of the function is a point on
on 2d so you essentially lose one
coordinate but when you do parallel
projection then the computation is very
easy all you do is drop you know you
just dropped chop you just drop one of
the coordinate that's it that's called
that's parallel projection but if you
want to do you know the no mode you know
the how do you call this what's the name
you know you can look at let's look at
Wikipedia then we will find the proper
name easily so parallel projection so
there it is Wikipedia so parallel
projection is a projection of an object
in 3d onto a fixed plane Nomos
projection plane Rob Rob about
orthographic yeah it's also known as
orthographic projection but I'm central
projection okay so the one we are
talking about the projection from a
point is called central projection but
when this point moves too far away it's
called parallel projection because all
the projection projection lines becomes
parallel so parallel projection is most
easy to compute so that that's what we
did there now let's do the deviation of
rotation matrix but first of all let's
just do the rotation matrix so we can
actually show the show show this up
let's show the stuff and we're gonna
show the nice things that's interesting
another interesting thing okay I don't
know the formula offhand but let's just
copy okay get because I've written this
before get okay let's go through
let's go through let's go to talk show
let's go to talk show and projection
polytopes polyhedra rotate okay here is
the code here is a code I've written
before okay
I'm gonna just show you okay you're
gonna see it here close that close that
okay we're gonna put a code here we you
know let's just draw this first then
we're gonna talk about so so this rotate
X okay so let's talk about this rotate X
first
so rotate rotate X is a function that
that we all rotate a bunch of a point
around the x axis by by this many
degrees okay it rotates counterclockwise
so this here is a formula basically it's
just sine and cosine sine and cosine
then we need to fix the code here
because it's incompatible with the way
we are doing so vertices so vertices is
actually just is our face one okay so
vertices is our face one
yeah face one
okay
okay so let's look at this code so so
first of all we define two constants
cosine something something sign
something something then we remember
face one is a bunch of points we just
want to we want to rotate them so this
is the original position you know very
nice coordinate one or negative one now
we want to rotate them by by certain
degrees and it should so so what we are
doing is we map them so face one is a
array we map it you know we map it by
this function so here is a function so
this is actually the rotation formula
okay
so it's easy to understand I mean this
JavaScript it's easy to understand right
so far so so let's to make sure it works
let's just console print console.log
let's just print it and see what happens
console.log so we're gonna rotate rotate
X by let's say ten degrees okay we're
gonna call that then we print our face 1
see what happens let's go back to
browser let's go to the cube let's go to
the console and let's refresh please
make it work no type error assigned to
constant variable Oh what idiocy face
one should be not constant because we
want to change it now back to browser
refresh yay fantastic let's look let's
see now we are talking what is this yes
indeed so again it's a list of points
and now all the points changed you see
it's no longer just one and negative one
because we rotated let's try to rotate
some more so instead of 10 we say 20
and show it okay let's see what's the
value so the x-axis remain 1 and
negative 1 obviously because you know we
are rotating around the x-axis but the
others were changed but the let's that's
so why is it not like the you see we are
seeing a face it should be you know we
should see something like that you know
rotate so ok so let's continue with this
so oh yeah because we haven't actually
changed the SVG yeah so let's do it next
let's let's do it now okay so so rotate
formula is working now we need to change
the face okay so SVG face we actually
want to so we so what we do is let's
copy it create it we will get back to
the deviation in a bit let's continue
with a code for now so constant phase
one we start with face one actually we
won't rotate it first so we rotate by 20
degrees let's say by 30 degrees let's
say by 45 degrees okay oops
45 degrees okay then then we now it's
rotated now we generate the SVG face so
face one now we projected and now we
generate the code that's right so we
comment out our previous comment out our
previous face and let's go to the
browser refresh okay what is not defined
what doesn't what the hell back to the
browser refresh what the hell
reference error rot X before
initialization
okay we need to put functions up copy
copy okay put the functions at the top
okay let's say here back to the browser
refresh now it's working because you see
you are seeing a face of a square and we
are trying to rotate it around x axis so
now it's rotated 40 degrees so you don't
you know no longer see your square so
now that's done let's continue okay
let's push on let's see how long I've
been talking one hour in seven minutes
oh god me I got so projection projective
rotation so okay so linear algebra is
when I give up on math how linear
algebra is is one of the have you done
calculus linear linear algebra is
actually more fun than calculus well it
depends on the people you know but
linear algebra is not hard so you might
give it another shot it's easier than
calculus it's not isometric projection
well no well isometric projection that's
like gameís you know that's the other
thing
well II math is just since central
projection and the parallel projection
he met you don't code you know isometric
projection is rather it's it's schema so
engineers you know they they need to
draw stuff you know
so anyway perspective versus orthogonal
view so again you know you you have lots
of jargons right but you need to
organize those Chagas because you know
like you know what's a what's the
difference between a car and the vehicle
you know a child would not know but you
would know because they are the same
thing you know Viggo is just a more
academic generalized name for
ha so it seemingly met so
so let's you know so so in math you have
st. central projection which is like how
shadow works
now if the is if the light ray is far
away like the Sun or moon then it
becomes parallel projection that's what
you need to know that's important that
says how shadow works shadow the shadow
from the Sun or the shadow from the moon
those are those are parallel projection
ok this is important but the shadow from
a candle or from from a spotlight those
are central projection you know because
the projection point is close you know
it's not infinitely far that's all you
need to know that's the essence of math
now you know the orthogonal view or
perspective or isometry projection those
those are you know derived jargons from
from bees ok so central projection we
are doing parallel projection which is
like the shadow of a Sun or moon and now
we are going to so we we successfully
rotated now let's use JavaScript let's
create a real-time rotation ok so we are
going to add a event so we are going to
say if so if user presses up and down
arrow keys we want the browser to detect
it so each time user press the arrow you
will rotate so it use a hose down the
arrow you continue rotate so let's do
that
so so what do you have to do so ok so
let's get the okay so the box actually
needs to the top okay so the box is our
dive element so box 1 let's say box 1
add event listener okay add an event in
JavaScript this is how you do in
JavaScript then the event will be key
press ok then so when when user press
okey we need to do something so what we
want to do we want to so what we want to
do here is rotate it render it okay
so okay let's let's do it rotate and
render okay so write a function arrow
function Harrow function takes no
arguments and we're just going to say
rotate around x axis by five degrees
okay then we need to write a function to
render it okay so basically that that's
the code now we don't have render yet
actually we already have but it's not a
function so let's make it a function so
we need to create a render function
somewhere here so let's say constant
error function benda now the the render
will be delete that cut that we have
already written or this okay that's our
render function so render function will
create a face
it will create a face then it will
append it to the SVG okay so let's let's
do that so that's what happens so render
will create the SVG face then append it
let's go back to browser let's just try
it
No okay I know it does own work because
we've got problems so why is it not
working so console no error amazing so
we still we got a SVG stuff we got a we
don't have you see we don't have the
polygons that's why it shows nothing why
is there's no polygons oh because we
wait so here is the SVG
[Music]
so this is actually that's what it
trying to create so render create a
polygon so we have created a SVG there
then when render is called it creates a
polygon and then attach to the SVG thing
appendchild
SVG face 1 to the SVG element then the
SVG element is attached to box 1 so why
is it not working
sure oh my god it's not working debug
time linear algebra perspective okay so
why is it now again check this code for
perspective projection picture okay
let's let's check it out discord
where is it be your life
and though I don't see projection
perspective projection picture check
discord programming
oh yeah well that no that's that's
that's not well you know that that's
that's that's abusing projection to
create illusion that's what that picture
is it's a famous painting I mean it's a
famous drawing to use to wait that's
actually accurate yeah never mind I was
I think no I remember if I recall
correctly this is this is this is this
is this picture is trying to abuse
projection to create absurdities if I
recall correctly I'd climb it I may be
wrong but let's go back to what we are
doing so so there's a problem wide why
does it not why does it not show so we
got SVG element here and we render did
anyone call render yes render is called
oh that's why because render render is
not being called because you have to
press a key to render and we didn't
press a key you know for example if we
press a key they in your walk so let's
go back to browser let's press up arrow
up arrow wait the CUSO must be here
let's press up arrow wait okay so box
one key press
like why is it the key press rotate eggs
so rotate X rotates the face FeO face
you see the rotate should be below the
face we got everything so wrong there
okay now back to browser now the code is
a mess but you know that's what
prototype is now let's press okey let's
see the code is a mess it's not working
but let's just say it's let's just say
put render here
okay refresh refresh
okay so we have so whenever keypress
happens we want to rotate by five
degrees and render but we want to know
if it actually detected keypress okay so
let's put that go back here refresh go
to the console press some key press some
key so key press is not being detected
so I think the capital P let's go back
to browser refresh press a key press
okey no so what is the okay let's cheat
let's look at my code let's see what
what is the
she down okay it's not keypress it's
Kido
very annoying JavaScript
okay so we got it closed that key down
okay back to browser refresh key down
press press refresh press a key press a
key it's not printing anything it should
be console.log now key down is key down
capital or what capital letter so what
no our document.body okay let's do
document body not box one okay
document body
okay back to the browser refresh press a
key now it's no it's okay so now we are
actually seeing rotation success at
least he's projecting fear check
absurdity to 2d picture yeah so you know
that that that illustration is AK you
know it's it's it's famous you know it's
popular like when you take drawing
classes they show you this you know we
need when they teach you about
projection so anyway so let's so so so
far successful now there is something
wrong here though when you press a key
you know why why is the blue part does
not move with it that's because every
time we draw the last frame is still
there so it's actually drawing multiple
you know multiple face of the cube so we
need to remove it we need to remove what
we've drawn so let's do it here now what
I'm doing here is very inefficient
because you when you when when you want
to rotate a cube you don't want to
redraw everything every frame but you
know let's just get it to walk you know
you know the basics know the principles
then you can think of ways to improve so
what we want to do is to remove the you
see let me show you what what we are
doing so you see this this sparks
element then we have the SVG element
then we have you see these polygon
elements you see these polygon elements
you see we have so many polygon elements
because we did not remove the old one we
just read draw lots of them
so each but each time we draw a new one
we want to remove the old one so how we
do that we do that by
just remove children okay so that you
can do by tart innerhtml equals through
nothing okay that's one way to do it
refresh now press a key press a key now
it works now let's add another we are
almost done okay tamam needs
let's hope then maybe we do the
derivation of the this matrix
multiplication you are actually not
actually seeing a matrix here because
it's already multiplied hub but you know
like you it would be interesting to
explained the matrix thing so anyway but
let's continue to push the code so we
actually have something to show so
rotate why we let's let's rotate another
let's create another rotation around z
axis okay so so when so let's make it so
that when up/down arrow is pressed it
rotate around X when left right arrow is
pressed it rotates around the z axis so
we got different rotations now okay so
let's do that we don't need that anymore
okay so rotate X rotate Z
if okay I don't remember the key but
this this is a bit complex so actually
we need to look at key code okay
close close so basically we need to
detect the arrow key so this is how you
do it
so let's let's copy that up arrow so to
key press ok so instead so let's do this
it's just copy and paste code
okay that's what we're gonna do Dukey
press wait what's going on
Dukey press okay that's right and here
is the Dukey press so if it's okay so if
it's up/down arrow we rotate around
x-axis if it's right or left arrow we
rotate around z axis then we went okay
that should work
let's go back to browser refresh now
let's press up arrow please it doesn't
work coding so Dukey press why is that
[Music]
why is keepers not working
don't tell me that I have to use the
other key code thing yeah very annoying
so two key press let's let's do a
console log to see if we actually
receive the code actually run refresh go
to console key press okay cannot read
property key code of undefined okay so
oh you need to pass right you need to
pass an event okay so that's it's okay
it's time for key there it is
so we don't need two of them you just
one of them back to browser refresh up
arrow up arrow there it is down arrow
there it is right arrow there it is
up arrow again there it is fantastic now
this is now we are at I think we can
consider this stunt now all you have to
do now is add the other phases right so
let's take a break so let me ask you
guys so should we continue to make it
full cube or should we try to explain
about the matrix multiplication how do
you get the rotation matrix one hour and
thirty minutes so that's you know that's
90 minutes for today so what do you guys
what you would like to see like what you
would you know for yourself what would
which you do you prefer should we finish
to make it a complete cube and then we
can add transparency so it looks nice or
we take ten minutes
complete a cube Emily MTR what what does
empty army matrix oh my god again
disagreement which one we need one more
vote
okay guys we got 18 people someone else
put another vote that's that's I don't
know if maybe we can do both I don't
know so let's let's try to add another
face quickly so okay so let's see what
happens now I'm getting more into the
math of it so more math okay okay more
people want to matrix okay so matrix
motor protein so here the question the
problem is the the problem is rotation
in 3d space okay so you have a point in
space you want to rotate it around x
axis or Y axis or z axis any one of
these axes now if you want to rotate it
around like a of like AK axis then it
gets a bit more complicated but however
any rotation in free space can be can be
done by any sequence of just rotating
around two axis okay so we don't have to
worry about complicated rotation around
a black axis so for example let me show
you what what is okay this is getting
complex I need I need tours you see so
this is this is XYZ axis okay so you can
rotate around one of these or you can
rotate around I'm out of pins oh you can
rotate around you know some some of like
axis but anyway the thing that you know
there's a theory basically any rotation
around anywhere can be done by a
sequence of rotation around these three
axis so that's what we're gonna focus on
now so since you know they are symmetric
so it doesn't matter which one we do
it's basically the same so we can hope
we can now just focus on rotating around
one single
okay so so basically we want a function
so given a point in free space you know
XYZ coordinate you you want to get a new
coordinate that's this point we rotate
it around you know x axis by alpha
degrees right so so a function the input
is a 3d coordinate the output is another
3d coordinate the question now is how do
you compute it how do you find it okay
so and we already talked about general
rotations it can be reduced to rotation
around a single axis let's say x axis
because they are all the same so let's
just focus on x axis so so so now we can
actually reduce it further because
because we are rotating things all
around this axis so it doesn't matter
where we are you know the the doesn't
matter where the point is on the x axis
it just it's like the rotation is like a
cylinder you know it's like a cylinder
so so instead of three dimension we can
actually not reduce it like collapse the
whole thing into a plane so it becomes
plane rotation so we just have to think
about the plane because the Z act you
know the the hate of the thing that it
doesn't change you know we are only
changing you know so if we are rotating
a three-dimensional point around the the
x axis you see the the the x axis the x
coordinate never changes because they
stay the same it's only the points you
know the the the the y and z coordinate
changes you see so therefore we can
reduce the rotation further by just
thinking about a plane so let's
you know start over by just thinking
about XY you know the standard XY plane
so now the our problem is to rotate a
two-dimensional point around our engine
by a certain degrees okay we want to
derive that how do you compute like for
example I say I have a point at 2 1 2 is
x axis 1 is the y axis I want to rotate
it by 40 40 degrees what what is the new
coordinate that is a problem
ok now you see we have reduced
three-dimensional rotation to just the
planar one like do you it does that make
sense you know it may be you know if the
if this is new to you it may be
overwhelming but you actually you think
about it it's you know we watch you we
watch my videos it's very simple
so now we are talking about
two-dimensional plane we want to figure
out how do you rotate the point to
another another point what's the formula
ok and that you know that involves
two-dimensional matrix so before we have
3d makes a matrix now we have 2d matrix
we will get to what what matrix means
later but now let's forget about matrix
so so we want to find a formula so what
is a formula ok this so makes sense ok
so great so we want to write a function
basically you know normally when you
program you write basically you you want
to write a function rotation ok 2d let's
say to deed so for example this is has
nothing to do with our code but let's
just okay
so let's create a new buffer let's write
it here so we write a function such that
you know normally in any language
so we XY salt so it's like that ok
so 8xy Hoffa okay and it needs to equal
to something something okay that that's
what we want to do okay
so how do you do it how do you how do
you do it's very simple if you now what
you need is trigonometry basic
trigonometry then you all know how to do
it because you start simple so if you
you know and I assume most of you have
forgotten trigonometry because most
programmers you don't need it you know
so I'm explaining the basic trigonometry
here once you know trigonometry the
whole thing is like trivial it's become
so easy so let me see if I can I have
articles written about it already let me
see if I can pull it up so let's go here
let's go to coordinate transformation
typically they call you know
mathematician cause it coordinate
transformation but but you have not
taken trigonometry have you or have not
I you know so what's her name is she
here today but Z Tron crazy these from
crazy is not here today she is taking
trigonometry or yes has she already so
well you you know if you want to do math
you should take trick trigonometry so
it's basic 3d kernel to add in trick to
forming projects okay so so how do you
do that so
rotation of a point okay so let's
explain so let's go here translating a
vector rotate the vector so how do you
explain this
so you have to actually you need to draw
I need to draw you know again I don't
think again because you need to start
Kemp to draw this is so powerful this
tablet I don't I don't think I have it
set up and but you need to draw
triangles because in order to actually
talk about this otherwise you know if we
didn't do this we let's see that that
would just be yet if we'd if we don't
finish this in you know five minutes or
something we then there'll be it that's
it for today yeah this too much problem
okay now let's try so we need to go to
[ __ ] we need to go to a new new one and
we need to go pick a big canvas and say
okay so let's see if I can okay we can
kind of draw so for so we need x-axis so
here is the y-axis this is too big
okay so why
X
kind of books it's amazing like actually
get this to work so so we have why there
we have X here we let's say this is this
is our point okay this is a okay now we
want to let's say how do you do this
okay so actually let me show you this is
how we do it
this is a circle okay this is a funky
circle okay funky circle and this is our
point a we want to let's say P okay this
is our destination and this is alpha
angles we want to rotate a point a by
alpha angles we want to find the
coordinates of B you know what is the
actual coordinate so so the coordinate
of B will be here this one b1 and
basically be - you know so the question
is that's not should be - the question
is how do you get p1 and p2 so
trigonometry you know God technology you
you need to you need to find ya so you
need to find so we have so this is our
this is the this is the hypotenuse so
anyway we start with the point a we want
to rotate by alpha angles that's all we
know we don't know anything else so we
should end up at some point B you know
we want to find a code and how do you do
it now if you assume let's assume alpha
is small let's say 30 degrees 40 degrees
something like that so it looks like
that so you know you know lets you use
this graph for example to do do the
derivation
then we can extend it later so so this R
is the radius of the circle because
that's basically the length of a so a
has the coordinate of of r0 basically
and and we know alpha alpha is 40
degrees okay half R equals to 40 degrees
let's say okay so we know this length
and we know the angle and what else we
need to derive a formula for rotation a
rotated by that IIIi don't know so we
know actually I actually I need to
explain a lot you know the sine cosine
formulas so sine sine x equals 2
y over r cosine cosine alpha it's a
mango okay equals two x over R cosine
start with one so when it's zero yeah
okay so that's sine cosine well you know
I see I need to explain that but other
but so anyway let me try to figure this
out so yeah there you have it actually
we already know the answer so you see
now I'm not going to explain this Y sine
alpha equals 2y over you need to study
trigonometry but anyway we have this
formula so as alpha is known alpha is
known here okay so sine alpha we know
that value and R is no I is the length
of our point you know given a point you
can find the length by again
trigonometry yo gates so so I is known
science no so so Y becomes R times sine
alpha so you know now you can know the
there so so the y equals to R times sine
alpha and X similarly we also know the X
here so here is X okay similarly it's a
real bad actually that's not X that's
why this is this length is X okay so we
know why and we also know xx equals to R
cosine alpha okay we know this
so the new point the new point the the
beta okay so this is b1 b2 actually this
is b2 this is P Y P X that's a
coordinate okay that's actually so we
actually in fact derived the formula to
compute a rotation of that kind of there
you know this is a very lousy job but
maybe gives you some ideas you so does
that make sense at all but I think
that's it for today okay so yeah okay so
thank you guys for coming and that's it
so you can simply simplify to make it
easier so I think you know I should stop
now so what 150 minutes yeah that's
that's it for today thank you for guys
for coming and that's it bye guys the
trick the trick I don't know if I
explained well actually it's not hard to
explain you know the sine of Phi equals
this this is basically the definition of
sine
but anyway so look up guys this is a
great opportunity you know I you know I
you know what I'm what I'm doing here is
equal to is like equals weeks cause it's
like a half semester in college okay hey
is this from crazy okay because the
professor will you know go into details
but this is the gist and so I hope you
get some ideas so then you know you go
to look Wikipedia like how rotation
matrix you know then you get you start
to get it now we haven't started to talk
about matrix yet like so far it's like
what what where does it came from like
what
but right now we do have a formula for
rotation matrix is is basically a format
you know you turn this formula into a
format so things looks neat
that's all basically the formula is the
key you know that's a heart of the thing
bye guys so we I'm gonna shut down we
I'm closing down and see you next time
let's see my code so our code is still
working and our code is fantastic it
actually works where's our code yeah so
we can rotate it by by both axes you see
we can now we can do this