Good evening everyone. Good evening
everyone. Welcome to another episode of
talk show. We are going to code wufam
language on advanc of code 2025 day six
problem one. Let me introduce my
keyboards. Ultimate hacking keyboard 80
UHK 80. Search for YouTube you will find
my reviews and unboxing.
Uh let's switch to my uh desktop screen.
So this is what we're going to do.
Advent of code
2025 day six. Okay. So on wam language.
So this is advent of code 2025 website.
Let's go to that's day five. Now let's
do day six.
By the way, I asked I asked Guac AI
about how long does it take to do a vin
of code. So usually uh on the early days
easier problem it's about one or two
hours
but in the mid med medium difficulty
problems two to four hours two to four
hours and uh for the last few days it's
more than four hours or several days. So
it it is not a trivial
puzzle programming puzzle at the end of
code. So this is the guac AI answer.
Now that's for average programmers,
experienced average programmers. But
there are speed coding uh programmers
they you know some of them solve in 10
minutes like in in some in instance
solve it in one minute. That means it
takes just one minute even just to type
the solution. So that's like almost
impossible.
Some of them are questionable uh like
cheating or uh using libraries designed
for the v of code. So those kind of
things. So anyway, but they are very uh
talented speed coders which is very
different from actual uh real world
coders but because they are kind of
different
so speed coders you know. So anyway, so
that's I guess that's why they removed
the leaderboard for the advent of code
global leaderboard. They said they said
they removed it because there's abuse
and so on. I don't really know the
details. Okay. Top competitors
historical record global leadership
under five minutes. You know those are
crazy. So anyway, so let's do the venue
code. Okay. Close close open that start
talk show. So we're going to write it in
Wufam language the most advanced
programming language
and uh if you don't know Wufam language
about last week we did a one hour
introduction.
Okay so Wuam language you go to S talk
show episode
there. So we spent 1 hour introduction
on woofam language but today you can
just you know so if you don't know about
wuam language go to my website
kasadi.info info search for just search
for my name kasardi wuam language for
programmers you'll find complete
tutorial from the ground up for
programmers
and a download link at
wufam.com/developer
so you can download the whole thing
that's like 45 gigabytes for free okay
and if you are watching this offline
play at 1.5 speed or twice as fast if
you are watching in this
live. If you are here, say hi. Love to
see your comments. Okay. Start Wan
language and magnify 250. Okay. So,
that's going to be our
code.
Okay, we just going to go relaxed, you
know. I'm just going to play with the uh
this advant of code. So, uh again, play
it at twice as fast.
Okay.
So, let's see.
So, it's day six. So, it might be a bit
difficult. I don't know if I can finish
it in 1 hour. Plus, I need to talk and
explain things.
So, day six. So what uh so basics yeah
so first of all the advanced code is the
web design is fixed layout extremely
lousy and also dark background which is
basically unreadable
and you can as an evidence of that you
can see that when you are watching
YouTube wi and with some website with
dark theme white text black background
uh became unreadable. So let's try it in
um in Firefox. And so you can turn CSS
off actually. So let me actually delete
my history
browsing histories. So okay, so you go
to uh view page style, no style. Okay,
it seems better. Okay.
Okay, let's let's start to work on this.
Okay. Hello, surface. So late day 607.
Day six.
Uh I haven't done day six. So day six.
Okay. Is that right? Did I get confused?
Yeah, last time. Yeah, last time is day
five. Today is day six. Okay,
so let's see.
Uh, day six, trash compactor. After
helping the elves in the kitchen, you
were uh taking a break and helping them
reenact a movie scene when you
overenthusiastically jump into the
garbage shoot. A brief fall later, you
find yourself in a garbage smasher.
Unfortunately, the doors been
magnetically sealed. As you try to find
out a way out, you are approached by a
family of
the fow parts. You are pretty sure they
can get the door open, but it will take
some time. While you wait, they are
curious if you can help the youngest
Salaflo
Sallallow part with her math homework.
Okay. Some interesting back background.
What what what is safod?
Safalopod.
What is this? Oh, some kind of squid.
Salafopod
is any member of a molluskan class.
Okay. Squid, octopus, cottofish,
nautilus. Okay. So you got this laugh
part. They can help you
and you need to help with their
homework. So let's see. You see they
linked to math homework. So what exactly
is it? Let's see.
Advent of code 2021.
Okay. Go back. Salafopod.
Safalopod.
Excuse me, some lingering cough. SL pot
math doesn't look like that different
from
Okay, sorry we are wasting time here.
Safal part math doesn't look that
different from normal math. the math
worksheet. Your puzzle input consists of
a list of problems.
A list of problems. Each problem has a
group of numbers that needs to be either
added or multiply together. So, a bunch
of numbers. Each line is a bunch of
numbers. You either need to add them or
multiply.
However, the problems are arranged a
little strangely. They seem to be
presented next to each other in a very
long horizontal list. For example, okay,
each problem's numbers are arranged
vertically.
At the bottom of the problem is a symbol
for the operations that needs to be
performed. Okay. So instead of
horizontal columns by column or line by
line, you have like vertical. In that
case you just do a matrix trans
transpose that will
reorient it.
Okay. The problem the bottom of the
problem is the symbol for the operation
that needs to be performed. Problems are
separated by a full column of only
spaces. Okay. The left right alignment
of numbers with in each problem can be
ignored.
Okay.
So that means you trim white space when
you get a number which is string there
are white space around it you trim you
remove them
uh you know like the typical programming
solution that's what you do you call
trim or chop function
so this worksheet contains four problems
1 2 3 * 45 * 6 there it is the first
column then the second column
Okay. Then the third column something
something plus or multiply. Then the
fourth column is plus sum of three
numbers. To check their work
safo part students are given the grand
total of adding together all of the
answers to the individual problems in
this worksheet. The grand total is 33210
plus 490
plus big number plus something then
equals to that. Okay. Of course the
actual worksheet is much wider. Okay. So
you got lots of columns. You'll need to
make sure to enroll it completely so
that you can read the problems clearly.
That means the long line formatting.
Okay. to play. Please identify yourself.
Okay. Solve the problem on the math
worksheet. What is the grand total found
by adding together all the answers to
the individual problems? Okay. This is a
very trivial problem. So all you have to
do is turn the input
text
into a matrix. Then you just do a matrix
transposition.
that will invert it. I mean that will
transpose so-called transpose or you can
kind of think of it as invert but
actually no because invert in matrix
means something else. So transpose just
means you swap the columns with the
rows. So columns becomes rows, rows
become columns. Okay, that's called
transposition in matrix if you have
studied linear algebra. So in most in
all basically every programming language
well not every but mo in most
programming language that has that
function you just need to load linear
algebra
in wam language it's built in of course
okay so where is my woofam so let's uh
let's make this go here and let's put
that here so you know
so that's trivial that's very trivial
problem so let's copy the input. Okay,
but first of all, let's get the user
input. What is my custom input? Get your
puzzle input. So, select all copy. Close
that. Back to Emacs. Search for txt. So,
adventure code. I already prepared this
file. This file uh paste it. Uh
uh did I not copy it? Select or select
or copy.
Okay. Cut. You cannot cut. So you have
to Okay. What?
So that's one line.
That's one line. That's right. The
operations are all at the bottom. And uh
notice that they have extra white space
in the last line. Interesting. But
anyway, save it. Close it. Okay. So,
close that. So, and let's copy the uh
the toy sample input.
So, let's start code on it. Start
coding.
So far so good. Say hi guys. Okay. So,
let's say
start a wam language. Paste the input.
And here say solution
markup. Okay. pop out and x input as
usual we make this whole thing into a
string that I mean supposedly
okay so that's a string so all you have
to first of all you turn this into a
matrix you know we can we done that
multiple times in adv of code because
advent of the code they liked this kind
of
like uh maze input you know a bunch of
numbers like
like they they treat a list of lines of
numbers as some kind of matrix or a
maze. So you have to actually navigate.
So that's very common um phenomenon.
That's a very common situation in Venom
code. So in day five we turned it into a
matrix. So we need to turn a bunch of
numbers into a matrix by
excuse me uh by where is this code? So
yeah so basically some code like that
you know we can do it on the fly. So
okay let's do it on the fly. Okay let me
just start to code it.
Say hi. Okay say hi if you are here. So,
first turn it into a matrix.
Turn the
X block into a matrix
of numbers. Okay? Because we deal with
numbers except the last row
remain string. Okay?
Okay. So
let's do it.
String split by default they split on
any white space. So we need to say we
don't want any white space. We want just
the
line ending. Okay. So you split that. So
here is your input.
You split that. So that becomes list of
lines. Then you map.
You map each line.
You map in each line by split again. So
you map. Okay. Map takes a function
something. We'll write it here. Okay. A
function something something that will
involve that. Okay. Then the second
argument is this input. We already
already split that's a list of lines.
Okay. Now what is the function? The
function will do it takes each line.
This is a line. Let's make it clear.
Line is the parameter. Okay. So it takes
a line. Then what you do with the line
you split by
you split by white space which is a
default. Okay.
Okay. Then you um
then you have the question about this
last line. Okay. So for example so for
so so okay. Okay. So you split into two
lines. Then then what you have to do is
that you have to turn it
to turn it into expression. So
so function lines then um
two expression. Okay. At that will turn
everything into expression. In fact, we
can run it. Okay. Now, when you do this,
the interesting thing is to observe what
will happen to the last line because all
the other lines are just numbers. When
you do two expression to uh to a list of
numbers, they turn the string into
numbers. So, those are strings. But what
happens when you do two expression to to
these kind of symbols? Let's see. Uh we
can try it out. Okay. So two expression
that's that's the way uh similar in
other languages of string to number.
Okay. So we can try what happens with
this. Okay. We can run it here. Run and
show the output.
Now, let's have some
red wine and apple juice.
Okay, you can you can see
invalid.
So when you are given a list of these
operators, Wuam language will say
invalid. They cannot turn that into
expression. In other words, they cannot
interpret it. it doesn't know what to do
with this you know what you know so you
you so when you do two expression you
cannot do it here you have to omit
um
you cannot apply to the last one okay so
let me just do this okay so let's do
this quickly um
x input list okay so that will turn into
a list. Okay, so just run it. You'll
see.
So that's what we got. Each one of these
are actually strings. Okay, wait.
Uh,
no, you got
it. It should be a it should be a nested
list, not one single. So did we?
Yeah. Annoying. Okay. So let me just do
this again. Okay. So what happens to
what you get? Oh, this is not slash. It
should be backslash.
So my coding arrow. Okay. Slash
slash and backslash. So this is uh
backslash that key. Okay. Now do it.
There it is. And beautiful. Now you need
to turn this.
Now turn them from string to number
except the last line. Okay.
Okay. So what what do you do? So um so
let's do so hello. Well only uh
used to be more a few years ago. Well
only three viewers used to be more.
Yeah.
Well, yeah, that's a situation. Well,
anyway, so
so you guys you can introduce yourself,
you know, where you from like are you a
student coders or are you a professional
or mathematicians or whatever. So you
can like help the channel, you know, the
busier the chat the better.
Uh, I don't do advertising. I don't do
memes. I don't do like oh new discovery
whatever that drama Okay. So
anyway, we we now we turn them from
string to number. Okay. Except the last
line. Okay. Easy. Okay.
Uh
so we can do uh so uh
okay let's take the last expression of
that and uh uh and uh drop
means remove element. Okay,
that will return everything except the
last line and you just say to
expression. Okay,
then the last input list. Um,
okay. So before we do this,
before we do this, let's transpose it.
Okay, that's a heart of the solution.
Okay, that is just like that. We'll just
do it. That basically solve the problem.
Uh yeah, we we haven't uh okay, we need
to select or paste shift enter. So you
got a matrix of strings. Each element is
a string and all you have to do is
transpose
transpose input list
shift enter. Can you see that? That's
beautiful.
After this point it's trivial. Okay.
Then you can do is uh then you now
uh
now you need to uh well before you uh
before you transpose actually
we want to remove okay so let's remove
the operations. So let's let's do this.
Okay.
Opterator list equals to
uh there.
So operator list equals to the the last
uh
row. Okay, we didn't do transport yet.
Okay, we did not do transpose yet. So
this is the last row. So operator list
is the last row. Then
numbers list. Okay. So let's say number
uh list in uh let's say number matrix
equals to
that. Okay. Superb.
Then then you uh then you want to
transpose the numbers. Okay. So actually
so uh number matrix equals two.
Drop the last row. Then you do a
transpose. Then you do two expression.
Okay. So this is beautiful. Copy all.
Copy all back to wam notebook. Select or
paste. Shift enter. Ah, back. We got
some error somewhere. Uh, what? Well,
drop
uh
Oh, yeah. So, this this need to be input
list not easy because
this is the input and the input list is
a matrix.
So let's change the name input based uh
x input
string matrix just just make it like
obvious.
Okay, close it. Reopen,
highlight that. Highlight that so you
can see all the variables. Copy it to
language. Select all. Paste. Shift
enter.
So now you can query X operation list.
Shift enter. Fantastic. Each one is a
string. Now X number matrix. Shift
enter. Fantastic.
Did we already transpose it? Yes. Yes.
Okay. So you just for each for so for
the first row you just apply
multiplication. For the second row, you
just apply the operate, you know,
corresponding to the operators.
Trivial. Okay. So, let me just do it.
Map thread.
Okay. There's a function map thread
takes two arguments. A function there
and the second argument is a list
one.
list
two. It will map F to the first element
of the first list and first element of
the second list then map to the second
element of the of their list you know
and so on.
So what we do is map a function we write
a function here. Okay then list one is
uh X number matrix. Okay, list two is x
operation list. Fantastic.
Okay, and what is the expression? It
needs two arguments. So
uh
so the first argument is a row of
numbers. The second argument is ops
operator. Okay. So let's so exactly what
does does it do? That's this part
expression. Okay. So uh so what is the
expression? So what you want to do is
you want to apply
uh depending on what this this uh so
okay so it depends on what that that
string is. So if
x ops
equals to
Plus
actually we can simplify this because in
wam language this this multiplication
and plus are represented by a function.
Why don't we do that? Yeah. Okay. Let's
let's not jump around. Let's just keep
doing this. Okay. So if the operation is
the plus sign
then
then you just total
total is a function you apply total to
the num row. Okay. So what you can do is
yeah that will work.
Num row. Okay. So let me let's try that
out. So
3 4 run it
seven. Fantastic and beautiful. Okay. So
that works. Now if it's not plus it's
either plus or multiply. So if it's not
plus then you you just do times. Okay.
Time is a function times add num row.
Okay. Now let's test times.
three four run it
okay so that won't work why because well
instead you have to do this okay I can I
show you okay at add
that will work okay
now you see 12 now what does this mean
exactly well what that that that add at
is a shortcut syntax. So what that add
at at actually means is this
apply times
it actually means that okay so yeah so
if we run this you'll get se uh 12 okay
run
So that's some examples. Let's uh um
let's comment it out. So I mean let's
comment it so people know what we're
doing.
Shortcut syntax for that. Okay. So let's
cut that cut go back to talk show and uh
let's put a example here so that people
know what we you know what what's that
cryptic at add at
okay not back here so here we just say
add add at
okay so if if it's plus sign then do the
total else do the times okay so Let's
should we just Yeah. Okay. Let's use the
more
universal syntax so people understand
better. Not the shortcut syntax. Okay.
Apply times to num row. Okay.
And in fact this total you can actually
do
uh
total you can actually do. Let me let me
show you. Okay,
total three four
you can actually write it as
first
that. Okay. So for example, run it
seven and you apply plus to that you get
seven too. So that's another
convenience.
So cut it. Go back to the talk show.
Let's put it into example so people know
what you're doing. Okay. So now go back
to our code. And in fact, let's be more
consistent. Let's just use apply plus
apply times. Okay. So if the if it's
plus sign, then do plus otherwise just
do times. Okay. Then the ops. Yeah. So
that that's it. Uh that's the function.
Let's see. That's a function. You map
thread to uh to that. Then you just
total them all together.
Okay, I believe that's a whole solution.
Let's double check one more time. That's
a complete solution.
Uh let's look at map thread
documentation. Okay.
Yep, that's what we want. Uh okay. So
actually uh you need them to be in one
list. Yeah. So okay. So error here. So
these two things needs to be in one
single list.
Are you sure? Yes. Can we run it? Yes.
Run the whole thing.
There is the number 4276679.
I think that is correct.
Did we 4277556?
What?
Okay, that is not correct.
Jesus.
What?
That is not correct.
Okay, we need to be careful here. So, we
got a wrong solution. So let's run this
in wra language. So you can see
which is not correct because the correct
answer is 427
4277556.
Now what the
What could be wrong? I don't know. Any
comments?
Comments, guys. Okay.
So, what the is wrong here? So,
let's see.
So, that is supposed correct solution.
Did we get everything anything wrong?
1 2 3 3 28. Oh, we didn't.
What
did we do? Transposition.
Yes, we did.
Transpose.
Uh,
what?
Uh let's see what does what is the drop
syntax? Give a list with its last n
element dropped. So that is correct.
So instead of drop you can say most
you can actually say most because most
will just drop the last element you see.
So make it simpler.
Okay. And most is added to wraim
language when 2003. Okay. That's good. I
don't want use functions that are too
new.
Okay, so
this um Okay, let's double check
what is punk is going on.
Copy all go to wra select all paste.
Run it
and uh set tag plus is protected. We are
Did we have a syntax error somewhere?
Uh
what?
Okay. I don't know. So
there is something wrong here.
Now what is my
x operator list?
Okay.
And uh
what is my x
number matrix? Shift enter. 1 2 3 4 5 6.
1 2 3 4 5 6. That's correct. Okay. You
need to make sure. So,
you know, check
one uh 1 2 3 4 5 6. Okay. Then
then you got 328 6498
328 6498.
Correct.
Then you got 51 387215.
51 387215.
That's correct.
I think I know what's going on. Then you
got 6423
314. 64 23 314. That's correct.
So what is going on is that our you know
we forgot to trim.
Did we forget to trim this
uh this operation? So did we forget uh
string split? Uh
wait.
So this is this we didn't I don't think
we forgot anything. So this each one of
these is a string. Okay.
So for example,
burst
at
operation list
use slash slash
string Q slash slash is a postfix
notation. So we apply string q means is
it a script string true.
Okay.
And uh we can you know so so let's just
do this. Okay.
String Q
uh map
X uh X operation list.
It's all string. And uh and then you can
do length. I think they are all one.
Okay.
Paste shift enter.
What?
Oh, you need string length. Okay.
Stream length. Okay. God, stupid.
Shift enter one one. So we made sure
that this actually each one is a string.
So So what is going on? So
So you
What is going on?
Oh, this this part stupid. I said plus
three four obvious.
Oh god. Okay, so that fixed it. Okay, so
let's
copy the whole thing. Go to wra
language. Select or paste it. Shift
enter. 4 277556.
4 277556
that is correct. Okay, we solved it.
So let's remove this Remove remove
run the whole thing
using saw mode. Okay, so there is a
solution. Correct solution. Okay,
so let's put it back. So let's uh make
sure our comment is still correct. First
turn the text block into a matrix of
numbers except the last row remain
string. Okay. Uh so
uh let's make it better. Okay.
Matrix of strings. Okay. We turn it into
a matrix of strings. Then then
extract
the
last row as operator
strings
list of okay extract the last last row
as list of operated operator strings.
Okay. Now turn
the top rows from string to number.
Turn the top rows.
First of all, transpose
the top rows. Then turn them from string
to number.
That's what this does. Okay, this line.
Okay. Then then you you just uh then
that's it.
Okay. Perfect.
Now put it back.
Cut it. Wait. Okay. Cut it. Paste and
paste one more time. Syntax. Cut the
whole page. Show in browser. So, we
finished today's talk show, but we need
to do our personal input.
But before we do personal input, well,
actually, let's just do personal input.
Okay. Uh, so search for txt
there. There. Open it. Copy it. Close
it. Okay. Then, uh, then go to here.
Then select or may actually select uh
select inside the string. Paste it. So
we got now a gigant.
Let's remove the last blank blank line.
Okay. A gigant text. Okay.
So go to the bottom. We just do like
before. Run it. Just run the whole
thing.
Okay, that's our solution.
Cut.
Uh, are you sure? Yes.
Paste it. Enter.
That is the right answer.
Congratulations.
Congratulate me, guys.
Solution obtained.
Okay, now we can do some clean up.
Why? Because um so that it looks better.
You know, the whole thing can be just
one single line.
Yeah. So, you know, so
let's make it one single line. Okay.
Uh it's let me just do it. Okay. Uh,
remove all the comments. Remove all the
comments. Remove all the comments. So, I
know what I'm doing. So, I don't need
all these comments.
Um, so that's the input.
So, let's turn them into the shortest
code possible.
Okay.
Okay. So,
one single line. We removed one
uh variable and we're going to remove
these two variables too.
Yep. Just delete it.
Delete it. Okay. And uh and what is
this? Yeah. So
So this input is just
here. Okay.
Okay. So we can run it
at error.
Uh, okay. So, we got
So, hold on a second. We can fix this.
No worries.
So that is correct. So this is correct.
And
the
why is the whole thing not correct? I
don't understand.
Why are you returning that
Ah
Okay. So,
you got the order re you got the orders
wrong. Okay. So this this part
this part needs to go here. That's why
simple error.
Okay. So simple arrow
it
is. Okay. So
remove remove. Okay. We simplified the
whole problem into this.
Now it can be further simplified. Okay,
let's shall we do it? Yeah, let's why
not? So, first we'll put it back. Cut.
Make a copy.
Syntax color the whole buffer. Pop the
copy out. And let's improve on this.
Uh,
okay. Let's replace string replace.
Yeah. So the in fact the whole thing can
be done.
God,
so trivioly.
Uh
Okay, that's going to replace the
operators by warm languages function for
plus and times
and
okay so
actually you know the input is annoying.
It It would be better if you move it
out.
You know, it doesn't dis
distract the elegance of the program if
you move the input up.
So, okay. So,
So you get you rotate
rotate
right. Okay. So you
right.
Okay, let me just do this. Okay. Copy.
So,
so you got that. So, you you have that
you rotate, right?
Okay, let me try something
two expression
first.
Three.
Does it work?
No,
but we can make it work. Okay. So,
not difficult.
Okay, fantastic.
Now, let's try this.
Fantastic. Okay. So we
so all we have to do is
two expression and that whole thing.
Okay. Then we don't even need to deal
with this taking taking them apart
and the two expression the whole thing.
Then we just
map
Okay, we don't even map thread.
Okay, map something to that. And what is
the function here? It is
Apply
the first element
to
rest.
Okay, I think that's it. So, let's
So, let's comment this out.
And I think this is our new code. Much
shorter.
Just this. Okay.
Uh yes. So hold on a second. Let's
delete that.
Delete that. Okay. So actually just that
input then that. Okay. Let's try this in
wam language notebook. Paste it. Shift
enter.
Invalid syntax. Okay, I up
somewhere. Back to the drawing board.
Okay.
Oh, yeah. First X obviously.
Copy.
Paste. Shift. Enter.
What's going on? Okay. So, we need to
try this uh
so what why are we getting errors true
expression invalid syntax in OB4 four.
Now, two expression.
What's wrong with the two expression?
Let's try. Let's see. What's this?
You see, that's what we get.
And uh Oh, you forgot to replace. Oh,
you forgot to replace. That's why.
Yeah, you forgot to replace uh you know
uh wait
string
replace. Okay. Oh we deleted our
code, didn't we?
Refresh.
Did we delete our string replace? Let's
type it again.
So something
uh first sign replaced by
first symbol and multiply sign replaced
by time symbol. Okay. And what do you
want to replace this on?
You can do this in the string. Yep.
So you can even do it this before
and not there. Okay. So
there. Okay. So let's copy it again.
Copy
back to Wuam Notepad notebook. Paste.
Shift enter. Yeah.
Okay. Hold on a second. Hold on a
second. I I gotta go, guys.
I gotta go, guys. My wife is back. Okay.
Let me quickly finish this.
Uh
Anyone
here? Nobody here. So, okay. So, let me
quickly finish this. Okay. So,
um
so input
replace that by times then
fit. Then what you do then you uh
Yeah, that's that should get you what
you want.
So, shift enter. Yeah.
What are we doing? God. Okay.
Oh, this is wrong.
Why is it wrong?
Oh, you can't when it's string you
cannot replace it by uh
yeah it's it's a string you you cannot
replace part of the string into a symbol
that is why so yeah okay so you you just
need to put them into
uh string.
Okay. So now paste it. Shift enter.
That's much better. Now copy the whole
thing. Actually just copy that and paste
it. Shift enter.
Okay. So something is wrong.
Um
okay. So two expressions. So
copy that. Copy.
Paste. What do we get? Yes.
And uh
and those uh
so that
see
first
is times
It's a simple belief.
Uh, no.
What?
So, it's not a string.
It's not the symbols either. What the
is that?
Time is Yes.
A little
Yeah, bro.
No. What? What exactly is that
thing?
Oh, simple Q.
What?
No. What is symbol Q?
Uh we it's it's undefined function.
We got a typo that's why.
Now, is there a isn't that simple queue
that supposed to check if uh
Okay, I'm almost done. Okay, we already
solved the problem, but we are trying to
shorten it significantly.
So, symbol
symbol operation isn't uh
Is there a function called symbol Q?
No, I assume it's just correct.
Okay. So why can't you just map it?
So the problem is here. Okay.
Seven.
Correct.
Oh, except the first one.
Yeah, stupid. Because Yeah, I know. Why?
Eight.
So, why can't we just do it here?
Did we transpose? We forgot to
transpose. idiotic.
We forgot to transpose. That's why Jesus
uh
Double check to make sure. That's right.
So, here is our solution.
Paste it. Shift enter. That's right. And
just do a total on it.
Okay. So, delete that.
So now
run it.
Here is the solution. Is that correct?
Yes.
Fantastic and beautiful. So our whole
code shortened to this one. Okay.
Fantastic and beautiful.
Copy paste. Now let's use the uh custom
input just to be sure that our code can
still work on the
custom input.
Yeah. Here. Backup. Do it.
Select that. Do it.
run it.
Okay, so here is the answer. Now delete
that. Put the code back
and
search for that number.
There it is. Okay, so that is correct.
Syntax color the whole page showing
browser. So this is today's fruit.
Hope you guys learned something. Uh
three watching but it's at the top
but it would elite.
Thank you. So fantastic. Okay. Advent of
code 2025 day A6 problem one. We coded
we explained some syntax shortcuts and
here is our complete solution.
uh we break it down by example
into parts. Then we solved our personal
input this huge
uh number of numbers. Okay. But now so
we solved it. So 663 something. Okay.
But now we we compact the code. We
actually changed our algorithm
to use um Wra's supreme solution.
Actually this part is repeated. Okay, we
we we we use this one. So this part is
repeated. Let me remove it.
Uh okay. So
yeah, I I think that part is remove
repeated. So refresh. Yeah, remove that.
So we compact the code into this this
like oneline solution. Fantastic and
beautiful. You see first first of all do
a string replacement a plus sign two
plus and multiplication sign two times
okay that's string replace then we split
them we turn it into a matrix function
split string okay by the y space then so
we got the list of we got a matrix of
strings okay then we rotate right so
that means the symbols The bottom row of
symbols now goes through the top. Okay.
Then we do two expression that converts
the entire string of the matrix of
strings to matrix of numbers. Okay. Then
we do a transpose
so that now the top row was a row of of
operators. Now we do a transpose so that
the
the row of operators becomes the the the
first column. Then we got you know each
row start with a operator then a bunch
of numbers. Then you just apply the
function to each row. So apply the first
element is operator
uh apply it to the rest of the elements.
In fact this part this can be uh
shortened and anyway then we just total
it. Okay. So it's like fantastic oneline
solution.
I will say this is the shortest possible
in any programming language. Okay. You
know if you are into advanced code try
to find the language Julia Python ascal
advanced programming language like uh
and uh common this scheme this name rust
whatever. Okay
I believe now including APL. Yeah, you
can include APL actually. I believe this
is the shortest code possible in all
programming languages
by the token count. You you don't want
to count, you know, the function names
because obviously if you you know that
doesn't really matter. You want to count
the tokens. So I believe this is the
shortest code of all programming
languages.
Okay, bye guys. Thank you guys for
watching. If you like my stuff, go to my
talk show.info.
Go to my.info homepage. Uh, go all the
way down. PayPal me, Patreon me, Amazon
gift card me. Okay, thank you guys. Bye.
We shut down in one minute.
So, we got uh three watching elite. We
got the elitist mathematicians, coders
watching.
Fantastic.
Okay, we solved it. Fantastic. So,
anything else? Let's see. Uh,
yeah. Did we Did we not include that?
Uh,
do we have that? Make sure we don't we
we don't want to delete it by mistake.
Oh, actually, we want it back because
that's a compact version. Okay.
The compact version of our first
solution. Okay. Showing browser. Okay.
So, bye.
Close. Stop streaming.