foreign
talk show so today's topic is random I'm
sorry I'm so late uh today's topic is
random okay so if you have any questions
for me ask now okay
today's topic is random so I'm gonna
just go relaxed for you watching offline
this is not worth your while okay go
somewhere else go somewhere where they
are doing you know nice camera and fine
and fine video and and focus and
whatever hello Jr hi so any questions
ask me okay
ask me questions
this is the time because in the past
year also I've been very fairly focused
on programming emac this or wolfam
language and so on so hello hello hello
George uh honest School
where you guys from
so questions questions okay questions
you want me to talk about keyboard or
programming or languages or whatever
whatever questions you may have for me
and uh you know and you know just ask
and I'll see okay ask me and I'll see
what to answer okay so questions and
questions and you are looking at glove
80 keyboard okay fantastic glove 80 okay
it's one of the keyboard I recommend
okay they just came out uh you have to
buy and you'll get it in a month or so
concurrent viewers one what the [ __ ]
you know that YouTube got some problems
I'm from Romania oh hi
we have a friend from Romania from you
know on Discord
uh Finland oh fantastic the world has
won in the ratsu that's Sue is from
UK okay can I say that I guess it's um
you guys are Anonymous anyway have you
gained weight recently are you eating
better yes I'm eating better I used for
the past for 10 years for the past 10
years 2010 to 2020. I've been living
I've been living in extreme poverty okay
those of you in America you can't
imagine you don't understand you don't
understand what that means you know in
America you have poverty levels you know
government legal legal poverty below
poverty I'm in the category of the
poverty below poverty level
where you don't have I don't have food
to eat okay that was that was wind that
was the time now those of you who have
watched me for a while no you know the
first thing you'll find is Oak size
dying on the online you know typically
people will search for your name and
you'll see a video of me
you know kind of that that is the day
when I was about to kill myself
okay so I'm doing better thank you guys
uh and I'm getting gaining weight you
know maybe five kilograms since 2020.
so Finland and Romania and China
you know what Johanna uh
uh uh defense
[Laughter]
China Bank currently in Peru oh
interesting so I I was you know I was
you know my life story when I was 14 I
was born in Taiwan
you know in 1968 okay in Taiwan so I'm
now 55 so
uh um you know I did uh yo you got uh
uh
so I I wanted to do a you know Chinese
video but you know I don't have a plan
that's my personality I never really
quite followed the plan watched your
view video in BD video did someone
uploaded that
let me check it's very welcome okay
let's see B the PV okay so that website
you know bdb for you guys don't know
that's like China's YouTube
you know China has several okay so not
okay Billy Billy oh did they change
their interface looks like they did
so let's see if someone put my video on
Billy Billy China's YouTube kind of
China has a lot quite a lot okay so
search
uh you need cookies or something let's
see
PDP reloading such wait date
wait is this the real Beauty video is
this like a clone or something
bdb
dot TV am I correct
the goal is to never kill yourself so
hello did I miss someone Jr
uh Jr and uh
so any questions you guys have or just
like let me talk random then
uh let's search for song okay now I
think Billy Billy changed their
interface
what the [ __ ] is this condolence you
know because I used to be a unique name
but since about 2010 you have more and
more uh
xah
wait I don't think I don't think this is
real bdb [ __ ] [ __ ] this is a bdb
clone
I have been deceived you know there's a
lot of scams in spams maybe this is a
billy Billy's new uh website oh wait you
guys cannot see my screen oh [ __ ] hold
on a second
you guys cannot see my screen okay hold
on a second let me show my screen
so that you can see it
so uh yeah so go to today's talk show
okay so yeah share screen first okay
let's share screen Hold On Second
check check talk so again today's random
topic if you have a question this is a
time to ask me okay
don't wait until I'm doing a Wolfram
language coding or emac this coding and
then you're gonna ask me random
questions
okay so share screen let's see let's
just switch Yeah switch share screen
okay so Billy Billy so you know Billy
Billy is basically kind of like YouTube
you know one of the biggest video
website in China so I don't know if
that's a real one
ah
okay so let's check so bdbd.tv
bdb.com okay yeah so bdb.tv they have a
global edition no that's that's new I'm
pretty I think this so this is original
for Chinese Speedy Billy so let's see if
someone put my name there
uh I mean let's see if someone uploaded
my video there
turn on JavaScript of course
and search for SAR
okay so since what is this no that's not
me
okay so excited strike Sardi and let's
try my Chinese
you know this is just like Chinese
YouTube you got a lot you got lots of
memes in any whatever random
random [ __ ]
okay not here now wait let's try Chinese
we have to type Chinese now
uh windows windows
space to switch to Chinese input system
and okay uh
oh God now I got a problem
you see
I have set up and this is gonna be
complex to explain [ __ ] I have set my I
have set up my windows
uh let me show you okay so you can see I
have the different
um you know us keyboard layout or a
keyboard layout and Chinese ping
keyboard input system okay so I'm using
that one however I have modified it
so that
um
oh wait
okay no I I did not modify it so the
Chinese input System is using quality
so you are using quality layout you know
that's a default on the Chinese input
system however I'm used to use the vorac
layout for the Chinese pinging input so
now I cannot type okay actually I can
type core T now let's see my quality
skills
so it's complicated I have to type Corti
and I have to type ping in to enter
Chinese
and I haven't you know I don't type
Chinese every day so
let's see how do you sa okay then
okay the
okay if anything doesn't work just
follow the labels labels on the keys
okay
okay it's a
but he says what is this
okay so I think need
s-a okay s a
yeah this is
okay yes h a yeah there okay finally
scroll down I saw your video oh you did
okay so where is it
scroll down
no it's not here oh here okay there it
is fantastic
someone named okay let's open that one
control click right
control click okay
yeah so someone uploaded my video the
most efficient emacs workflow more
efficient than veeam now what they
okay this is a few months ago I think
that's the one
Lisa fantastic thank you guys
uh and uh so let's go back to bdb
so let's I want to search for let's see
Lisa what deal come up
nothing I guess just that one video then
this one
okay so anyway that's uh anything else
so you are currently located outside of
the USA no I'm in USA I mean United
Kingdom no nothing I mean United in
United Empire
okay
which is known as America American North
America okay so you have these Russian
star I guess whatever
uh anything else I guess you guys don't
have any questions okay
Okay so
I did I want your video previously in
Chinese okay you did great
okay so so what's now so let's go bit
back okay so nothing
oh okay fantastic you know Thomas ran
Thomas ran this guy is a keyboard key
switch expert you know he I watched a
lot of his videos so he is a key switch
expert can you guys see my keyboard yes
so key switch expert okay Thomas ran
this guy and he and I asked him a
question today about
Rock hat Titan switch what is it
and apparently he says that he haven't
covered it yet
uh you know
he asked him it for once he asked them
but they didn't reply okay so looks like
it's a Cherry MX like switch okay
am I into machine learning yes
artificial intelligence however I never
actually got into it much you know
especially because the latest craze I
never got into
so let me have coffee
so anything else okay you guys don't
have a question so let me just let me
randomly go over okay I wanna I don't
know uh let's see so I so you're looking
at my website I've been working a lot on
my website
foreign
what's interesting so you guys buy my
emacs tutorial so emacs blog a huge
amount of work so you know the latest
you know what I've done in the past few
days is one of the you know this I did
this review
so the question is you are excellent in
math so why not get to in get into it
machine learning well well there's a lot
you know machine learning is part of the
methodology
approach of artificial intelligence okay
artificial intelligence began
in the 1980s about you know uh evolving
around lisp the programming language
which you see me code all the time
you know so artificial intelligence
there are many methodologies Okay so
what am I doing oh switch now I have to
switch back to volrack
and do yeah so
so artificial intelligence there are
many approaches so for example let's
look up
okay so let's uh
search there are many approaches through
artificial intelligence okay not sorry
org I want to go to search
info
Okay so
AI let's see what Graphics programming
paints Unix Pro now let's see artificial
intelligence okay so I have several
articles on that artificial neural
network is nasty okay and I did some
talk about it you know in my past videos
artificial intelligence and quite a few
things okay so one of the Articles
artificial neural network is is nasty
okay so let me show you a few
uh anyway so AI you know which the the
goal of AI is to ultimately to have
human intelligence you know so in the
past 40 Years also and you you have many
approaches including uh neural networks
you know new neural networks that's one
approach uh also you have expert systems
you have genetic programming you have
[Music]
um
you know you have uh you know a handful
of approaches and one of them that
becomes the most popular and uh dramatic
is neural networks and it became the
most successful okay the most successful
uh because you know
in you know you know
um neural network is one of the things
and you also have in uh image record
recognition face recognition recognize
the Human animals you know you can
pinpoint you know you just just like
human animals we can recognize
your friends your parents or whoever by
their face
so anyway the the the neural network
approach is the most
um successful spectacularly
spectacularly successful successful in
the past 10 10 years since about 2010.
uh but um
and the neural network approach is
rather the most nasty you know basically
again
like I said I haven't really studied
artificial intelligence I haven't
studied machine learning you know but I
have his basic ideas I'd be interested
in them
but I don't actually haven't coded or
anything about new uh machine learning
so anyway it's the most successful and
basically it's a statistics statistics
based approach what you do is you just
gather billions upon billions billions
to the powers of Mega billions of data
you know you just let the machine
read them
and the Machine will kind of learn learn
them so whenever you ask a question the
machine will just
reflect whatever is in the you know
piles the pump piles of data that's how
it works
um and by by what's called neural
networks which is
kind of you know you have
it's you know I met you know it's
basically prediction okay it's based
statistical
prediction kind of like that however
there's a major problem because if you
do this approach you know first for
today
you know the artificial intelligence can
play chess can play go and can you know
but they
you have no way you have no idea how it
works like it doesn't explain anything
like it's it's almost like a black box
although it's algorithmic meaning that
every step is known you know it's new
you know because it's a program right
every step you know exactly how it works
but when it gives you but the way it
gives you an answer the way it works is
that there's no way you you cannot see
you get no Insight of why it is this way
for example in chess you know it may
pick up a particular move or in goal or
in you know AI drawing or whatever
whatever it does
you cannot ask him how do you how how
you know you can you cannot get any
insight you know why is that this is the
right answer why is this the best move
why do you draw it this way you cannot
ask it and you don't know because
there's no in uh you know you know
neural network program there's no way
you know this
it just does this Statistics okay that's
that's and you know thousands of
parameters you know there's no way to
get any insight from it
uh
what is the so what's the there's the
question what's behind the search engine
in your website so my search engine
you know I did a video actually writing
this search engine from scratch okay so
I did a video about you know half a year
ago so if you search for YouTube sorry
search engine how to write a search
engine you'll find it so we we called it
live so basically it's just this one
thing that but this one JavaScript okay
so the so the first part
you know 6 000 lines they are just
uh
Pages page title and the file path okay
so first of all you have this
information page title and file path of
six six thousand Pages that's on sorry
dot info okay
then
then you just write a you know you know
about
100 lines of JavaScript you just search
you know you just search this
title words keywords you know search
search the title words that's it
JavaScript simple and so
this search engine can be improved a lot
you know it's super fast for example
let's see
Mouse so if you search Mouse there are
136 results if you search for Ergo
ergonomic you know Ergo emacs logo
that's the Emax package I did
around 2008 for five years ago Emax is
like soft light Keys okay so you have
the ergonomic Mouse then you have
ergonomic keyboard Ergo plus keyboard
Microsoft Surface ergonomic keyboard and
so on lots of keyboards ergonomic
keyboards
uh yeah so then sound talk show so
that's it you know you just a JavaScript
that reads 6 000 lines of a
file title and file path in Json format
then you just uh you just basically do
stream search you know go through you
know a research through array
okay so why Windows not gonna Linux
something like guix maybe well that's
the old question that's a good question
I same answer for 30 years so
so if you just search for Windows Mac
uh so okay search there it is I mean I
have tons of uh articles about them okay
so there is one relevant
Linux versus MAC versus Windows which is
best for key binding okay that's that's
one of them
uh you know there is particular one I
want to show you
uh switch
to Windows okay so there's the article
why I am switching from Mac to Windows
okay and uh
and uh let me also show you another
article Windows suck okay Windows sucks
major donkey ass okay
window sucks in lots of ways
so here's the article I am switching for
Mac to Windows this is written in 2009
so um give you a history of my computer
use
um
you know from
1990 to 2020 okay so I've been basically
most of the 19 you know I've been using
a Mac from 1990 to
2008 okay
uh 2009 okay so Mac I'm a Mac person for
20 years 1992 2009.
and uh that's when I wrote this article
2009 I got tired of Mac I switched
Windows there's lots of reasons you can
read it you know one of the reasons like
this you know you buy a Mac it's
beautiful and elegant four thousand
dollars smack
but for a PC you know 1000 something it
look looks ugly like that you know lots
of wires and ugly [ __ ] crap like right
now Windows window is you know why
Windows sucks you know there are 10
articles you can write read the detail
every just about every aspect the window
UI this is a fantastic unimaginable
how is it possible it sucks the [ __ ]
brainless facts at Microsoft
by the way Microsoft have have lots of
very smart people but why is it that way
because because they have they are
saturated you know they don't they it
doesn't do them any good to improve the
UI in fact they can let the UI to be the
worthless [ __ ] they don't care because
it's gonna be the same number of people
who will buy Windows you know in fact
because they made a contract so that you
know it's it's part of the Computing uh
Habit already because most people are
used to Windows for the past 30 years so
when you buy a computer obviously you
get Windows if you use Linux what the
[ __ ] you know if you get Mac most people
are not familiar you know they don't
want to change just like quality or
vorac or the the C and C plus plus in
JavaScript idiots you know you know they
are used to the C syntax when they see
something else like Wolfram language or
this they think what the [ __ ] is that oh
word god this is no good you know habit
habit is the is the one of the biggest
reason for a lot of things okay
so Windows why does do they suck
they don't always suck okay for example
in in 2000s Windows NT that's that's one
of the best you can control everything
by keyboard and in the most efficient
way
year 2000 year 1999 and at the time mag
crashes every day okay my gos okay now
you guys are young as I assume most of
you guys are young so you don't know he
wasn't but you were you weren't born in
1999. so anyway
windows
today
the UI sucks the one of the worst okay
this is purely brandless but why is it
that way why
because Microsoft Windows they have a
lot of money they have lots of
developers they make ten thousand
dollars a month okay you know so
they are smart you know but the wise is
why does it suck because they don't care
you know the management you know they
they don't have the code to improve it
you know they don't they don't want they
they don't do that why because it
doesn't do them any good most people use
Windows anyway you are not going to
switch maybe you are but most people are
not okay
so it just remains stuck you know it
just become you get conditioned that's
just the way it is like the Linux and
Unix idiots okay now let me talk about
Linux because most of you guys a lot of
you will say oh yeah Linux is great
Linux is worse hey Linux is the the you
know the the
okay so I'm gonna starting or rant on
Linux so here's my Linux tutorial
everything you wanted to know about
Linux by command okay bioshell
uh bioshell okay so so let's clear so
let's
clear
history and clear screen so I'm using
Powershell
so you can see
so anyway so powershello by the way
Linux Fanatics Powershell is 10 times
better than bash okay
you don't know [ __ ]
you [ __ ] Linux and Unix and see
[ __ ]
okay bash is good okay I have a tutorial
on not bash the tutorial on Powershell
okay okay I gotta control myself not get
into a rant
um you know not not starting to do a
rant on on the Unix thing okay so anyway
here is a my Linux tutorial everything
you can learn by command okay the most
practical tutorial okay then you click
on
Linux miscellaneous tutorial so actually
I rambled a lot over I haven't finished
explaining uh why I switched from Mac to
Windows but anyway that's a odd question
so let me answer that question Windows
Mac and uh
Windows Mac and Linux which one to use
this one simple answer okay that's been
the same way in the past 30 years since
1990 as far as I personally have
experienced I'm a nerd okay I I dig into
I know all key bindings on Windows
or on on Linux every one of them I
memorized okay you don't know [ __ ] okay
I've been memorizing them since you know
and every every command every key
shortcut
possibly there are for the Mac as well
and I have articles about them I read I
you know I have lots of
documentation I wrote them down Okay so
Linux was a smack versus Windows
basically for the past 30 years the
condition Remains the Same didn't change
because every you know every few years I
switched or I looked into you know all
my experience using them it's pretty
much the same Mac okay if you want the
most you you want things to work you
don't want to spend time to Dido to
config to learn about the esoteric
memory jumpers your switch this kind of
thing you don't have time for that you
just want to do your work Mac is the
best okay no
no doubt no doubt about Mac McIntosh
even today I mean over the past 30 years
they are you know they go up and down a
bit but overall today Mac is the best
design best UI even for for programmers
too okay if you are a programmer if you
are a Linux [ __ ] you know about
kind of Maggie is a better Mac is better
okay Mac you just pay the money but but
the disadvantage is that everything mag
is two times more expensive just like
this picture you know elegant but
but everything is two times more
expensive so you you gotta be a elite
you know [ __ ] Elite [ __ ] you
know with your MacBook
so here is the MacBook
you see I'm a elite [ __ ] you know
the elegant the [ __ ] thing and when
you open it
no do they do they actually shine over
the light they don't anymore I don't
know so you see
you see it's a Mac Mac M1 by the way M1
is M1 chip is fantastic it's the it's
the best okay my game one you should buy
it
so let me go back to finish this so Mac
the UI and everything the design just
perfect okay they spend tremendous time
you can tell you can tell okay
you know mag is the best UI okay for
programmers too for programmers you know
you python coders JavaScript script
coders
maybe not Java Java on the Mac is not so
good but everything else okay but anyway
Mac is the best but twice as expensive
and apple apple the corporation they
suck your blood okay this they suck your
blood in everywhere every way possibly
they can okay when Steve Jobs is around
he's the best guy you know it's not so
bad but now with the social app Apple is
showing the social justice scan
so not only everything is expensive they
make your phone slower when there's a
new version came out so they're being
corrupted and then then they they they
Soldier the memory chips the the the the
the
you know the
the the flash drive whatever Soldier is
so you cannot change it okay you you
want a better mag your Mac is too old
you have to buy a new one
it's a [ __ ] apple is doing but you
know but still Apple still
the design as far as user interface and
everything the design is the best okay
Apple
now Windows window is just like Windows
you know you yeah it's cheaper but it
sucks donkey ass and in every step of
the way window will try to get into your
pants they will know what you do they
want to know you know they don't care
they don't have privacy on the other
hand Apple very good privacy okay very
good although you you they they get your
information but but apple is not like
Google Apple don't sell at ads don't
make their money you know your personal
info Apple is very good in that way okay
windows on the other hand they don't
they do whatever they you know
and the user interface sucks you know it
sucks lunky ass okay I talked about this
several times you know you can read each
of this article sucks in every way just
pure brainless pure brainless window
doesn't matter it's Windows 10 oh Metro
design the [ __ ] you know boys talking
about Metro oh demo we're gonna we
haven't made a [ __ ] windows and window
is 11 okay windows are idiots the worst
in every way but but it's free basically
when you when you buy a laptop it come
with it it's free okay windows and you
and then if you want to play games if
you wanna you know most of you are
Gamers game boys you know game boys
machine gun you know oh okay helicopter
you know you know whatever
defend America you know like that
Windows okay that's basically your only
choice and get your GPU you know fancy
fans lights you know that like that like
Linux
tech review you know that Linux
chipmunk okay
you know that that chipmunk
Lena's tech review you know Gamers you
know with your keyboard idiotic like
lights on it you know that that's Linux
okay cameras okay so if you are a gamer
Windows is basically your only choice
okay
you can spend one thousand dollars by
you know buy a Windows gaming machine
one thousand dollars which is very good
if you want to do that on the Mac three
thousand dollars okay
now the Linux people the Unix and Linux
people these are the most idiotic facts
okay the the Linux UI in everything is
ten times worse than Windows okay Mac is
the best UI window sucks in every way
as far as using it you know or or Dev
you know or if you are a programmer you
know
Linux is 10 times worse in every way
but it's free plus it's Freedom okay so
you if you wanna Linux yeah sure Linux
it's free you can spend
hours stays a month to to to dig into
kernel what to do you know yeah it's
it's there it's great you have so many
choices Linux
free and freedom and no privacy concern
but you have to spend your life you know
you have to drop in blood to to to to to
to to
let it run okay that's Linux
so you know you want no Linux and Linux
you know many of the Linux open source
phonetics they all say oh Linux is you
know a [ __ ] you know they are just
like big corporations when they are big
like you know like the Ubuntu you know
they introduce Zeitgeist which is a
process running in the background
it wants to know everything you do what
program do you launch when did you
launch it he wants to gather information
Zeitgeist part of Linux
you know the most robust used in
industry operating system Zeitgeist
Ubuntu [ __ ]
kids and [ __ ] you open source phonetics
okay
and lots of things Linux okay post audio
post audio [ __ ] okay you know I've been
using Linux I've been using my first
Linux is 1990 okay 1999.
MK Linux viewed by Apple okay that was
my first Linux
but then I haven't then you know I'm a
Unix admin I use Solaris
okay I use Solaris and other unix's you
know I'm a Unix Unix admin in a job for
three years or four in around 2000s then
sucks okay then I use Linux as my
desktop from you can see here in this
article I use Linux as my desktop from
2011 to 2017. okay so I use Linux for
six years that's when most of these
articles are written okay so you know
the the Linux Linux [ __ ] idiocy you
know they they they try to be hip like
apple you know they think they can
innovate you know whenever Apple did
some Innovation like change of UI like
oh this is brand new this is you know
not the same as old it actually works
you know you don't have to worry about
it you just use it you don't have to
learn anything it just works and works
better most of the time whenever Apple
did some UI change okay Linux the
[ __ ] idiots the Linux idiots you know
they try to have these score bar so that
the scroll bar doesn't show but it shows
only when you move to it the [ __ ]
idiots okay and it and then then it's
annoying every other way like every time
Linux do something it's annoying every
other way and then you have spent three
hours one hour two hours three hours to
look up the stack Overflow usually it's
10 years old article to find out how to
how to fix it how to get it to the way
you want [ __ ] little
who went through [ __ ] and and and
you guys the windows you know the
windows managers
shut the [ __ ]
okay it uh worse okay worst Linux is the
worst in every way why because it's free
you don't have to pay that's that's what
you get free okay
uh
okay that's about Linux okay that's so
that's that's your choices if you have
money
go with apple okay if you are a gamma or
the middle you just buy Windows you know
it comes within every computer you buy
free okay if you and uh if you are the
freedom conscious you know if you think
you are the idiot Freedom Fighters you
know if you are fighting for your ass
get get on to Linux okay it's free
Okay so
you know this so that's uh that's you
know you know and and the Linux you know
they change and change you know some of
these article gets old
so you know um
okay so that's some of the Linux rents
okay you know I was surprised when
around
um let me show you this article so
around 2016 you know I was thinking
because I'm a keyboard Fanatics right so
I do a lot of key remapping I look into
all the possible ways how you can remap
Keys such as many of you want the caps
lock to be control you know things like
that
so I thought Linux would be the best
because I know I am a programmer and
I've been Unix system mean you know for
10 years so oh Linux so I'm on Linux now
so I can finally you know write code or
script so I can have the most efficient
possible kiwi map okay on Linux it turns
out in Linux is the worst [ __ ] possible
doesn't matter you are a programmer or
not okay so you compare on the Mac
you know if if you want to remap your
keys
and if you do not have a programmable
keyboard like the gravity so you want to
remap your keys so what you do you you
go via the operating systems way to
remap the keys so
on a Mac it's actually turns you know on
the Mac it turns out it's the best okay
you don't even have to be a programmer
on the Mac there's application free and
with the source code open source you can
be you know you can just remap two key
the most powerful okay I'm not going to
into the detail because there's a lot of
details about remapping keys for example
simply swapping keys or if you want the
key to be to send some other key when
you are in this particular application
but when you are in other application
this key should be do something else so
there's a lot of issues okay so on the
Mac it's the most easy the most easy and
also it turns out it's free too and open
source okay you just install it in in
five minutes in 10 minutes you can have
whatever key map you want okay on
Windows
this is sucky you go to you go to then
you know then you go to auto hat hotkey
so let me show you okay key binding and
so software so here is all you want to
know
about how to remap keys on Windows I
mean on Linux okay all you want to know
all these all these articles 20 articles
how to
remap keys or set keys to to copy you
know so for example you want F2 to be
copy for example so you don't have to
you don't have to control alt whatever
[ __ ]
so dinos okay so and on Windows here's
all your options today you have the
Microsoft power toys you should install
it's fantastic okay but other otherwise
you you can use autoheart key this is
the most popular and very complex okay
we'll take you a week or two to just
learn it learn the esoteric idiotic
programming like idiotic script okay
but however just like Windows it does it
it does the job it sucks but you can get
you can do kind of do what you want
sometimes there's glitches you know but
you know it it does the job okay
on Windows
okay now go back so Apple for Apple you
just installed there's quite a few so
the
you know Carolina is the the most
popular you know there are other
utilities some are building how to swap
Keys how to use the default uh Mac you
know default to
for example you can set up your keyboard
to type Emoji uh then Carolina is the
most popular for swapping keys or
depending on which app is
the current you know you can do lots of
things then there's also
Apple Mac OS also allows you to change
shortcut it's system-wide okay you know
there's some disadvantage but you can do
that without installing any third party
okay so then there's you have app
launcher you know Quicksilver you know
this is one of the first Innovation
actually which allows you you to type
some word to launch any app or file okay
let's begin with Quicksilver on the Mac
free okay about 2006 or something 2003
even so for 20 years quick silver and
there's quite the other quite a few
others Alfred I haven't used another mag
and Hammer spoon I haven't used and this
keyboard my Astro right now is 15 years
old you know then then you have USB
overdrive all these almost all these are
free on the Mac you can you download you
can you know keep you know this USB
overdrive is low level so you can do a
lot of things okay on the Mac easy
on Windows you know you take a day or
two to to learn all the hard key and
stuff and then then your work okay and
today you have Microsoft power toys it's
this is this one is from power to for
Microsoft which allows you to just use
GUI to change keys and quite useful okay
what a [ __ ] [ __ ] ass pen it
is what the [ __ ] [ __ ] Linux [ __ ] it
okay
I'm a programmer I'm a nerd I'm into key
mapping I'm into programming languages
I'm you you know I know all the Unix
command line tools okay what a
[ __ ] pen the Linux when you
want to remap Keys okay first of all
first of all of course depends on your
distro are you using Debian or are you
using red hat or you know each one The
Gnome whatever you know can file manager
you know the windows man of [ __ ]
[ __ ] okay you know you have to
choose one then once you choose one it's
it's it's it's it's just impossible okay
this X11 which remap only works in X11
then you if you want your key remapping
to work somewhere else you have to do it
impossible okay basically you spend days
months to try to find it and it doesn't
work all the time oh it works on my
machine
oh I try to do this I follow this
instruction patch this script you know I
type that and I restarted it but this
doesn't work you you post understand oh
it works on my machine
out of [ __ ] Linux fuckets
okay so that's about key binding okay
then I think maybe that's it for my uh
video today so it's a rant about you
know so that's my experience okay why
you know my I thought on Linux you know
I bet I never looked into it but in 2016
I I you know I'm on Linux is my desktop
machine my main machine I thought you
know this this would be fantastic again
you know but it turns out not it turns
out the Linux is the worst [ __ ]
that's why so that's how all these
articles on on keybinding how to on
Linux started you know I write down I
have a habit to write down you know
things
okay so big rent okay so what I ask
questions have you tried net BSD no I
haven't really tried BSD I used it in
1996 a little bit I'm not our operating
system guy okay I'm not I don't have
much interested interest in operating
systems you know some some nerds are
interested in operating systems I'm not
to me my favorite operating system would
be some operating system where I can use
it easy and can program it you know I
can change my app or whatever you know
as a user I'm not into the operating
systems
specific you know their design the
kernel how the kernel works you know
memory Pages I'm not into that okay oh I
care is when I go to you know I'm a
programmer though I'm a programmer you
know I'm a mathematician oriented
programmer what I want in our operating
system I want the best scripting
language bash okay
whatever okay I want the best control
you know writing a script and there Mac
is the best the and today Windows you
have Powershell Linux you have the
passion script the [ __ ] okay Unix okay
so anyway my point is that when it comes
to app operating system my concern is
that I have the great user interface I
can change maybe the looks or whatever
or I can easily okay I don't want to
spend a year just to know how to do this
do something and then I and I can script
it okay Mac is the best
Windows secondary and Linux is just no
good okay no good in every way the Unix
[ __ ]
so
yeah I'm not a you know operating system
guy
okay that's it
yeah so there's uh you know uh track
says when you have not a programmable
keyboard you can buy a hassle converter
in programming yeah of course yes you
can but you have to spend money you know
that's more nerding you know you're
gonna spend you know a few days on it
you have to pay then you have you know
today you can today you can just buy a
programmable keyboard very easily okay
so today
so what am i showing my screen okay
um
so what is this so let's just go to
emacs let's go to keyboard plug showing
browser and let's go to ergonomy
keyboards review and there is a page
best
on programmable keyboards with onboard
memory so here is a list of them
and see what key to magnify here here's
a list of them or these are programmable
keyboard today it's very easy and common
okay not like 10 years ago so starting
around 2010 there's a tremendous growth
in program programmable in mechanical
keyboards which in turn programmable
keyboards okay and also over there's a
evolution
kind of a revolution in ergonomic
mechanical keyboards so starting I would
say with a truly ergo
there's one called truly ergonomic
keyboard starting around
2000 and
13. okay and 2013 is also the year Ergo
docs begins so anyway and why is the
revolution because gaming because Gamers
okay Gamers basically that's where the
money comes not from the Linux nerds
okay so Gamers idiotic Gamers teams you
know they want beautiful they want
lights you know on their keyboard they
want mechanical because somebody said
you know you know because all the gamer
Stars they sponsored by you know
whatever whatever by razor razor the
most idiotic never buy Razer keyboards
okay
so anyway because of the gaming industry
more or less significant part of the
reason the gaming industry they they
they revived the mechanical keyboard so
and and also China you know China in the
past 10 years just incredible they they
create lots of things cheap
and just works fine works fine okay not
the best quality but they just work fine
and tons of it you know all the
mechanical keyboard so anyway so this
page is a list of programmable keyboard
with onboard memory that's a key with
onboard memory because many for example
Razer they don't actually they require
you to connect to the cloud to register
a
account and connect to the cloud
otherwise you your keyboard your keys
your program doesn't work anyway anymore
so anyway these are keyboard with
onboard memory so these are great okay
great choices so
so
um
somewhere else yeah so what I'm saying
was is that today programmable keyboard
is easy
okay
with a hassle converter when when I tap
J I get J when I type twice J I get uh
something oh command modifier okay you
are talking about home mod keys
I have an article on that
oh mod keys
uh it's got problems okay Hallmark Keys
it's got problems so start a search
let's say home
mod
yeah there it is
problem of Dual Purpose keys or also
known as home roll mods okay so you are
talking about that yeah that's good
that's
that's that's good idea at first but
actually it's got problems okay one of
the problem is that when you have that
then that key you won't be able to press
hold down that key and have it repeat so
this is a problem when you create these
keys on
and delete key on the backspace key on
the space key
or on the enter key any key that you
sometimes want to hold it down and
repeat
those keys if you make them
you know
also a modifier that you got a problem
so well then you have a you know walk
around so that some of these you know
homework mods allows you to press that
key twice then you don't then you
temporarily remove the modifier
functionality so that you can hold it
down then you'll repeat so it gets
company complex that's what I'm saying
Serenity OS yeah I'm not the OS guy okay
so you know there's quite a few out
there I don't really
really care all I care is what
applications are there you know and like
I said before
uh
yeah yeah the price does not matter okay
that's it for today
okay not many questions I guess I just
rented for an hour again
oh
this should be adjusted
no okay now it's what
now it's like
okay anything else I think that's it for
today
random I talked to I talked for one hour
by now
yeah
okay that's it thank you guys because
shutting down
so Billy Billy they have now a
international web version Billy Billy
Billy Billy Billy Billy dot TV okay they
have an international version
interesting mostly in English okay
so Google
YouTube is gonna be threatened
yes I intend to keep the glove I'm gonna
keep using it for probably more than a
year
that's true thank you that's true
yeah so I'm doing okay
uh close pdb clothes
you know so
you know the there's cultural
differences you know like uh like like
Billy Billy you know Billy Billy is
China's like you know you can think of
it as
China's YouTube I think it's the biggest
video platform in China they have
there's a few okay but bdb is one of the
biggest so you can see let me tell you
guys about cultural differences you
white people don't know
the worst is the social justice scan the
[ __ ] you know they they
Proclaim
Multicultural reason oh we need
multiculturalism but they but they but
they are multiculturalism it's just
quite ISM with Chinese eyes and and and
black people's black skin and whatever
[ __ ]
social justice scan [ __ ] okay but
let me tell you about the cultural
issue here you see you are looking at
bdb.com which is in China you can see
all the Chinese it's primarily you know
for Chinese people also popular in
somewhat popular in Japan Taiwan Hong
Kong you know
so you can see they have they feature
this little girl little girl oh Peto
white people's Obsession everything is
paid a lot better
so you see what they are saying here you
know they are asking you to scan you
know the QQQ code whatever so you can
download the app you know so you can
download bdb app on your phone and they
ask you you know login you know logging
or which is the new account right I I
think I have a account I don't know
I don't use it often really video okay
so anyway so here's a page they show you
they tell you to log in but on the side
you can see detailed little this little
girls you know anime you know Japanese
anime thing
but
do you think YouTube do you think
YouTube is gonna have this no they're
gonna they're gonna have problems so
these people white people oh my God just
be Peter or whatever oh this is uh this
is this is objectification
objectification of women or whatever
[ __ ]
[ __ ] the white people the fact is the
social justice Kansas especially
uh
you know that little thing I just show
you is show you is not just just this
Speedy Billy website you used to see
it's everywhere that's the that's part
of the culture okay
you know like the Japan like in Japan
you see this
this you know 13 years old anime girls
over you know with
little skirts or whatever
okay bye
actually I shouldn't close it because I
want to do some screenshots so I can put
it down