good morning welcome to another episode
of startup show
today's topic is going to be random okay
so anyway so today's so I created this
talk show page you can find it on solid
our info and at the bottom you'll see a
link to it and today's topic is any of
these so you can just pick a topic and
I'll talk about that but let's pop this
out
so I'm waiting for people to coming so
today's today's Thursday okay
topics what am I gonna talk about lots
of things so usually my videos are not
scripted so I'm not like prepared and I
kind of like it that way because people
asked me questions and they can see my
response and reactions in real time I
have things to talk about and I talk
about them so you can ask me any of
these questions actually let me copy
that and paste to the the video chat box
hello guys so those are the topics
actually I mean go to my Emacs copy that
find and replace that by that okay back
to Chrome
copy paste in today's date I need
today's date okay Excel table show so
start up show the format here is you ask
me questions and our answer otherwise
pick any of the topics in the info box
and I'll talk about them so usually when
you have like when we are chatting or
when I'm seeing on something you know
then I start to have opinions I'm gonna
tell you so I mean it's not it's always
not scripted so keep the comments coming
okay let's see so
okay so let's begin so so anyway this
this is my music blog sorry music dog
and bark box piano well temple crabby oh
that's that's my favorite music of all
times
I mean if you ask me to pick one music
like if you if you can only have one
album in your island which would it be
that's probably going to be Bach's
well-tempered clavier and let's go to
the piano piano section Bach's
well-tempered crab here and enlists
transcendental you kids do come home
greetings Giacobbe motley greetings
great to see you guys oh I want to thank
I want to take I want to thank you I
want to thank the young D young for my
patron yesterday he was a patron and he
increases the amount but anyway I just
want to say thank you
D is my regular watcher I break the loop
do you know how to play a musical
instrument yeah I played piano you know
I was fascinated I'm you know fascinated
by pianos
well actually got another guy who asked
me about piano because I have written
about piano quite you know quite a few
times but however I haven't touched a
piano since 2004 so you know it's so
kind of history you know I don't I mean
I I don't have a piano now you know
digit digital piano that is I never had
a acoustic piano so I have written quite
a lot Holocaust in the 2000s about piano
but anyway let me finish this topic sub
so piano so I got this page so my
favorite
music okay so in music there's classical
music then there is pop music today's
modern music so I do listen to pop music
and I'm on pop music my favorite my
favorite pieces are the tense tense
transitions
typically the electronica electronica
tense music and there's quite a lot
let's hear let's let's let's listen to
one so this one is funny let me see I
mean turn on the volume so let's see if
you guys can hear it
let's play
okay that was initial d heartbeat let me
turn the volume back so can you guys
hear hi Scott great to see you Scott hey
break the loop I was listening to Prince
this little red Corvette yeah you know
yeah it's fantastic song you know so
backing like 20 years ago
you know today when you play video games
there's a rating you know this is like
there's a rating that began when some
senator or something you know she I
think is she or he when when when her
daughter you know was listening to
Prince's read little covet and she
thought you know this couldn't be you
know we cannot have girls listening to
that song so she began that's when the
waiting begins you know the cameras
rating like this is rated or whatever in
a video game so I mean of course the
movie industry they have their own so
that that begins that but of course you
know today how things have changed you
know you you use you see you see I don't
want to say the word in case Google is
going to pay me but you see this you
know everywhere and they are like they
are they are done by you know or can go
all these come girls like everywhere you
know and they are not anyway that's not
going let's not talk about that so
anyway so that's how that began Prince
Prince is little covet
so anyway initial d so initially you
know I didn't know what song is this but
it actually it's a Japanese animation
you know Japanese is thriving with
animations so they have tons of series
you know series Mac you know American
the cause Magna or animation but anyway
they have like tons of it so this is I
mean someone put this video together so
and it's a good song so mostly I like
the
music the electronica and usually they
have let me show you these you know they
have these girls you know they oh it's
almost like Oh
dance music like you can just go to
youtube and youtube and search for
electronica and they are like
youtube.com they are like tons of them
and usually they have these chicks at
owning the the the the oh my god what
are these you know yeah so pop dance mix
Korean stuff and you know yeah it's all
girls yeah because you know okay I'm not
sure I want to go into that topic but
yeah anyway so let's go back to yeah so
I was going what I was saying so this is
this upgrade song anyway yeah so these
are some examples you know the house or
whatever so dance music so that's so
common the pop music my favorite
favorite are the dance music and some of
the a la this this a lot of topics to
going into that so so keep the comment
going so you know I know you know
whether I should go into that you know
that's another topic you know the rap
and the grab the black people with the
rap songs and the the social the
politics of it you know that's a lot of
things there so the I mean so that's the
pop music then the classical music
actually among the classical music I
almost I almost exclusively listen to
only keyboard music that is piano
harpsichord
organ mostly piano and so that's the
classical music I
really like symphony I almost don't like
any Symphony and oak Orchestra and
string quartet or piano you know string
quartet that is okay yeah but I mean in
general so I mean of course there are
some exceptions but anyway so piano
keyboard music that's the classical
music I listen to and among all
classical music there are two pieces I
like the most like if I can only pick
two one is the box Bach's well-tempered
clavier okay I don't know if I should
play that okay that seems safe you know
don't don't post oligo or things like
that okay I don't want Google to pay me
so piano music ba a way out him but crab
ear and the other guy's lists
transcendental etude you know least you
know you know so box music it's it's
cold and austere like is it's extremely
cold in Ostia and and usually people say
it's Mathematica which is true I mean
it's just it's like the perfection of
notes you know combined together and
when you listen it just hits your brain
my brain you know if you don't like it
you know it does does nothing to you but
for many I suppose math oriented people
it just hit your brain you know they say
you know music is your emotion like like
when you listen to music I mean it
doesn't matter what you like I mean even
jazz or pop songs sometimes they they
get you emotional you cry and that is
true I mean I listen to parks sometimes
even in the background like I'm coding
you know I'm doing I'm coding and matte
box
music or lists or some others playing in
the background and when it reaches you
know like oh no way Oh
where to me like I'm just coding and it
suddenly reached some section and it
just you know it just hit me so and you
know and that's also a philosophical you
know perpetuo philosophical question you
know why does that happen basically we
don't know that means today you know
there are newer newer science Sciences
you know we are trying to find some
answers but then but basically we don't
know why that happens
so box music is extremely cold in Ostia
and lists music okay they are totally
two different styles you know in
classical music you have two different
styles like in the 1500 1600 there's a
aristocratic kind of style I can show
you some examples you know I can give
you a introduction to classical music
you know the history of the period but
anyway so there's Bach whose style is
mostly fugues then after that there is
what's called romantics and and least is
one of the representative you know one
of the big names in romantic piano
thesis era and his music you know he's
made music also I would say it mirrors
my personality and also least the guy
I've looked into at least the guy he's a
great you know guy he's also a
philanthropist
you know how today when you have a pop
concert and all the girls you know
crying and go crazy and you know
throwing stuff on stage like their
personal stuff they are they a bra you
know that began with least you know at
least was performing on the piano you
know other girls ladies you know back
then you call them ladies they they
crack you know they so at least is an
idol you know idol to them and so but
least music you know his personality his
music is like the cruelty of nature
okay they let me read this
okay so one of his composition is
transcendental attitudes
it's called transcendental attitudes
twelve there are twelve of them twelve
pieces and my favorite one is number 12
now this this piece represents the what
I would characterize as lists music okay
well to me but you know some other
people may choose other songs but this
is one one of these pieces and when you
listen to this piece let me read it in
escapable darkness and gloom each note
is a knifing on your heart it repeats
over and over with greater intensity and
sternness forces of nature in execution
sense mercy so that's how I perceive
this music but you can I mean similar
opinions you can see elsewhere so it's
like this cool end code I don't know if
I should play it because so you know
keep the comments going and let me know
so let me read the comments listening to
trains
yeah Prince little covet that's that's
that's a great song yeah actually that's
a great song initially the morning and
I'm praying is oh yeah I don't know why
I have to you know I'm keep learning
about music streaming I have to adjust
it
I'm using the OBS software which is open
source by the way so I found this
recently 80s powerhouse aerobics let's
look at that oh okay let's go back
yeah stupid stupid Chrome let me pop
that out again
so
yeah listen to music like sometimes you
know I listen to music when I'm coding
but usually it must be piano classical
pieces when yeah rarely I listen to pop
music when coding because I'd you know
it doesn't it it distract me so Jacob
says hi Jacob Jacob says warning of
warning of current topic I was trying to
find a way to view an XML file as a tree
XML tree view at work today and and
sorry I couldn't find a way in Emacs as
a tree I think I've came across a
package recently on reddit it could be
half a years ago yeah I'm pretty sure I
remember there is a reddit some post
about showing XML as a tree not in fact
not just XML any kind of a nested thing
they'll show us a tree but I didn't look
into so I don't know I saw I you know
you might look into that I think it's
mention on reddit or you know oh we can
do as such yeah I'm pretty sure I came
up first it was mentioned within the
last half you know six months I would
say unweighted our Emacs yeah it's a
package that shows anything as a tree
you might look into that yeah off of
hand I don't know you know you Emacs you
have a in Emacs you have an xml mod let
me talk about that a bit so so this is
an XML file and it's showing an XML file
in an XML mod let me just let me just
mention this okay the minute mentioned
is quickly so if you go through my email
Emacs blog and you go if you go to
practical Emacs and search for HTML
okay so you get these Emacs a HTML tips
and you hit that so I give you some
introduction and by now it's it's
history of HTML and XML mods in Emacs
and one of them is the N X in XML mod
now this this is worth mentioning
because a an XML mod is one of the he
it's created by James croc very famous
you know the almost the most famous guy
in the XML community back then and he is
a big open source fan and he is also one
of the great coder so he's XML parser in
C is he is used everywhere you book you
big quotas you know it's is you know he
rode a see parser for XML and I don't
know about today maybe that's you know
but back then it was like the every you
know that's the one you use you know see
XML parser and so he also he's also a
eMac beast coder so he wrote in XML mod
which is 10,000 lines let's say stuck in
XML mod so describe function so you can
see the talk here and good jump to the
source code that's how you jump to
source code in Emacs any since any
source code so you can see you go to a
button 2,000 lines they must they must
have refactored it it was 10,000 lines I
mean not counting sgml mod also he wrote
sgml mod so I mean he's so he's a big
big guy he contributed significantly to
Emacs yeah they'd be factored it so
you know now you got a bunch of you know
in xaml en si UTSA yeah so anyway it was
more than 10,000 lines of emag beast and
and it has this inner innovative feature
that that is when you open an XML file
it validates the the file for you on the
fly as you type you know it validates it
will tell you for example let's go to my
blog programming block let's let's put
let's create a go to my atom RSS file so
this is this is XML you can see the file
name is plugged up XML so if I for
example you can see it's it says valid
on the on button now if I delete this
opening tag no it says invalid you see
it does that on a fly so I mean at the
time I mean possibly even today I'm not
sure about today but at least 10 years
ago it's it's the there's nothing
comparable to it you know it's the best
yeah but so but XML kind of fell off
they they got wiped out by the html5
group which is a kind of a enterprise
cancer started by Apple Opera and Google
Chrome
they created because money because Apple
at a time they created Apple iPhone
right Apple iPhone you but you want
canvas you want other bunch of things
you know that's good for phone for a
proposed phone and the on the other hand
Google also is the one wanting to push
you know the web because that's you know
that's Google that's where Google lives
you know they want to push technology on
the web anyway so that's how html5 group
started and in fact it's you know the
web standard is is w3c right the w3c
organization
but html5 you know the that group is
called let me type it out so that group
is called I always remembered it as what
the group okay
okay let me show you a plug-in let me
show you
javascript block so you go go to my
JavaScript blog you can just search folk
sorry JavaScript web dev blog you'll
find it then you go to top HTML
validation history and politics
so here the story of XML then here this
article wh ATW gee that's that's the
html5 groups organization's name they
stand for working group so what working
group the last two characters stand for
working group I forgot what it is but
anyway they and w3 split so actually
today since about you know five years
ago three years ago you actually have
two standard HTML standards I mean
literally you have to its new your
standard and they fight each other you
know the w3c they say our standard is
the correct you know the Fischer one
that the what the weg group is you know
they say it's they that's their you know
standard they fight because you know
from political political reasons and the
programmers are idiotic programmers in
good ignorant and you know you the
programmers or the hacker types they
used to sing about standard all the time
especially the UNIX types you know the
elite hacker which I hate I talk I talk
about this many times you know they any
opportunity they'll talk about oh I have
C go read IFC oh we need to standardize
Oh
Microsoft is evil because they don't
follow standards that's all
standard organizations as I
learned you know as I realize now they
are actually just they also I you know
many of them up nonprofit nonprofit SoCo
nonprofit but actually they make money
like especially today many of these
nonprofit they they they are tax exempt
but they they are just greedy they they
make a lot of money actually to the top
guys you know the top view leaders the
boss anyway so w3c is one one of that
org
and then then you have this WH a twg
they fight and you know that's that's
just a side story I'm mentioning so okay
that's about XML let's let's read the
topics so Tory Tory what's Tory Tory
that name sounds familiar but I forgot
what that is dori dori smell DK
butterfly yeah dance dance revolution
yeah that's another thing you know that
instance you know the gaming thing
yeah that's it's quite interesting let
me let me scan the comments first so
because I don't want to wait for too
long so have you ever been exposed to
audio file hobby yeah when I was younger
you know it's you know who are into
audio files yeah let me scan finish
scanning the topics the questions I'm
also interested in how you learn English
okay I actually I talked about that a
little bit
a few last week you know ten days within
maybe within 10 days I talked about how
I learned English
you know I have like I mean okay you
know I have a lot topics I can talk
about that you know the the problem is
truths want to stick to at the moment
you know like if you go to what my woody
blog okay so let's let's go to saw
English so if you type sorry in English
you'll find my what I call woody blog
woody English calm so in this domain I
it's all things about literature vocab
vocabulary okay the do of vocabulary the
depth love literature the question of
style the logic of linguistics and the
Yeo's of English in the cue or by
writing so it's all related by those
topics and over here I talk about how I
learned English you can read for example
how to increase your vocabulary okay so
in this circle I basically summarize how
I the way I learned English but I talked
about that for a length for maybe half
an hour's few few days ago maybe 10 days
something like that that yeah do you
prefer listening to music while
programming okay we talked about that I
find out how to multitask okay maybe you
can write a blog post about good music
for programming well the problem today
that with blogging is that nobody read
it you know I've written tons of stuff
basically nobody read it because part
because the how the traitor how the
Google they push quick baits so all the
commercial organizations organizations
big and small they push out quick big
baits every day including programming
you know stuff like JavaScript for
example they push up for example on
Twitter if you subscribe or oh I can use
if you subscribe to anything programming
related every day they tell you oh we
got a new library
you know how advanced
you know yeah you know but basically
they are like zero content they did you
know they just like groups or
organizations or even individuals like
yourself like me like when you when you
create a library you want people to know
right so you you know you you post it to
hacker news but also you try to meet you
know to click page you know oh how I
created this and that revolutionize
whatever you know so most of them it's
like zero zero content it's you know so
today it's even hard to find anything
that has you know value you know all you
see is you know when you search try to
search something everything is a quick
bait you know so the the real good
content is buried and also they you know
the social justice movement they began
to censor you know many things you
cannot say so you you you don't you know
you don't see anything anymore so so I
have you know all these plugs but
actually nobody reads with them they're
very few I mean it's not like you know
say let's say 10 years ago and yeah so
something so what do you think of these
HTML element presented like periodic
table of chemicals I'm not sure about
those things I mean just judging by the
by the name because it's probably some
fad or fashion let's see
okay so okay so then in term of I mean
term of auto click copy link address and
go here paste you know this Google is
becoming so evil now like when you click
something on YouTube it goes outside you
know tell you like do you do you want do
you really are you sure you want to
leave YouTube it's just incredible
periodic table of HTML elements yes I
suppose it's fun you know I'm not into
these kind of things yeah periodic table
so increasingly internet standards or
whatever Google says yeah exactly
because you know you know it's it's
speeding or old horse you know Google is
becoming this evil empire and they you
know they just do whatever and also you
know recently there's a article Google
actually I meet so evil so you know like
Microsoft they created their edge
browser right it's the entirely new code
you know totally entirely new browser
new browser engine edge created almost
like 10 years old by now ten years ago
now maybe maybe not yet ten years but
anyway the edge browser so you know
Microsoft you know they they of course
they want to show you know how good is
their browser so they have comparisons
house you know speed comparison it's
loading page you know JavaScript
rendering speed and so on and there was
a story where then Google Google saw
that so I mean a Google engineer you
know said hacker news you know so they
change they tricked you know the Google
Website that YouTube so that so
intentionally basically they
intentionally change things so that you
know the Microsoft edge browser is not
it's no longer fatso poke you know they
did that I mean the stories like this
I'll you know it's like almost like
daily happening dailies now and the
other thing is you know they say you
know the general population they don't
have memories so we don't remember so I
mean every day you hear things you know
if you ask me what are the list of
things okay what are the list of things
Google has done that's bad I can't you
know I can't remember I can't miss them
I have like I have to dig you know I
have like some articles I mentioned oh I
have to take my you know blog history
but in general like if you ask anyone
you know it's hard to come up you know
with our things you know so you know
Google did this or that you know they
know because they know they have
psychologists you know they have you
know they study the marketing they they
know human you know psychology they know
you know they did something wrong
Oh tomorrow nobody will remember you
know they just do something else they go
on and then they they have a entire PR
department you know oh we are we could
go out helping you we are helping the
world to you know create a better world
you know we we help people and stuff and
and open source is part of it so I know
I thought it was a short food to eat I
mean kind of Virginia so Scott says I
agree that it's super hard to get anyone
to look at a blog post but it's same
thing put the same thing in a social
network like the book face and they all
get more engagement unfortunately oh I
haven't heard of a book face before how
look located okay so the comments I
cover the comments so so what was I
talking about before about learning
English the way I how I learned it i I
learned it by brute force
anyway I talked I talked about that a
lot the other day so it's keep that
vocabularies you know I so I
have a habit to write down any word I
don't know so here's a list of
vocabularies you can if you are into
vocabulary vocabularies I was very into
vocabularies so for example let me just
show you a link so random let's pick one
random order arms cry for arms I
remember that word I learned from you
does any guy remember where does that
face came from arms I learned it from
Hemingway Hemingway's book this is back
in early 1990s like 1991 Oh 8 1987 1988
1987 why I was you know reading all the
literature's Hemingway For Whom the Bell
Tolls so a fail the sea and the Oldman
one of these book For Whom the Bell
Tolls I learned that arms from that book
I remember conjoining okay conjoined
conjoined twins is a fascinating subject
you know there's a there's a famous
conjoined twins called Hensel twins have
you guys heard of it let me know
type type let me know I mean I want to
see your expressions you know face
expressions so I can you know I know
where I'm going
so anyone heard of hands or twins
okay hence though twins oh they are
getting married
so hence out means they are conjoined
twins they are girls basically it's like
one body with two heads and that is just
amazing that that is amazing because
it's amazing philosophical as well
because in philosophy we have the
question of body and mind I mean as a
classic topic of philosophy body and
mind the question is I mean you can you
can look up Wikipedia the question is
you know how does your body connect to
your mind you know for example I can
talk I can move my hands I can raise my
hands exactly how they work I mean so in
other words what what is a soul you know
what what is the I mean that that's so
that's a deep question nobody knows the
answer but to me the conjoined twins is
is is like one chapter I mean it's part
of the puzzle so actually so it's
actually two persons let me show you
some
so that's conjoined twins so so they you
know so they have two heads and they are
independent you know they don't share
thoughts other than you know they are
twins but biologically but they do they
have two brains and they don't share
thoughts but they have one body so so to
me the question is so how does this how
does this and so touch relates to the
mind and body problem and you know
actually I don't know what philosophy
think about these you know they must
have you know already thought about this
or or discussed when these when they
secant conjoined twins but by the way
conjoined twins they are quite a lot you
know not just the AB ago and Britney is
the most famous today auditioning
America but they are I mean if you look
at you know you know if you look at
YouTube or if you start to search for it
they are quite a lot different conjoined
twins they used to be in a circus you
know like a sideshow the what's called
sideshow not-not-not
AB AB ago and preening I mean used to
like 50 years ago 100 years ago so yeah
so anyway so this is vocabulary page
when I talk about so let's look okay
maybe it yeah I got a myriad of things
to talk about aggrandize aggrandize is
like you know the hacker types the elite
hacker die types agonizing about
themselves
exactly let's see what as it says here
after all such individuals aggrandize
themselves by pushing hard on young
people who don't understand how they are
being taken advantage of
I don't remember where this patch
passage came from usually I cite the
passage where it came from Pew tative
code warriors TV show Tyra Woody Allen
as a putative spy with
dum de Louie's Michael J Fox and so on
anyway so yeah that those these are j GI
u was GI e is like the Graduate Record
entrance exam something like that that's
that's an exam you have to take when you
apply for master or PhD PhD degree at
least used to I'm not sure about today
but anyway so that's my vocabulary page
book face face book okay yeah exactly so
the social media so they kind of like
they are ruling the you know the
information you know and also Google
cute blogs basically it's it's a mess
you know and also because of social
media you know it's it is because of the
social media that created the reason you
know they are hugely responsible created
for the reason you know political divide
in USA you know it's going it's going
crazy now you know because the social
media you know what they want to do is
make money you know like just like every
company and you know let's talk about
Twitter for example same thing with
Facebook I stopped using Facebook like
four years ago I haven't logged in since
four years four or five but tweeted so
for example on Twitter you know they
want they want to make money and they
you know to do that they need a lot
users and they needed users to post
things so they want to encourage you
know they want to get people to keep
posting things but you know you cannot
just keep posting things for example I
am a programmer so I I you know I have
for my followers and I follow
programmers you know at least before
2016 mostly and let's see Wow anyway so
so you know let's show some other page I
don't want to show some of the
controversial stuff yeah anyway it's
just changed mother page yeah you know
you guys you know the politics is too
bad today so anyway so Twitter they want
people to post things so I'm a
programmers so suppose I have some issue
with Python my post today you posted
after one hour is it's done for you know
basically dude okay you know you already
posted what you're gonna do so you know
so that way you know treated but treat
her needs you to keep posting you know
they need you to post every day you know
like every few hours they need to post
but if you have a programmer you can do
that you know you post something and
that's done for you know what about else
you're gonna do so so what happens you
know by the Twitter push you know they
do everything they can because they they
need to make money otherwise they won't
exist they need to make money so they
they want they do everything they can to
make people post so so so so the
situation the phenomenon what they
created is that they get people to post
basically random things you know they
for example my for example if I have
something about Python some some some
problem I run into I post today but I'd
tomorrow I need to post it again so I
may be rephrased part of it in post and
and you cannot new you cannot but you
cannot keep that up you know you just
want you got one article you how can you
you know make it but people try that's
what Twitter pushes so so what end up is
that you you just get oh you know all
the posts are just like zero content you
know quick baits you know especially
with the news organizations like for
example Google Google has their blogs
right so today maybe they are now some
announced some news about something Oh
Google Google is going to Kio Google+
you know for example then all the news
organizations they create their own page
they copy some snippet from the Google
block and they put some you know padding
you know like you know as their own
report so it's mirrored on their own
website with their own ads so that and
then they put two traitors so they you
know they go to their website you know
each organization do that you know so
you got all these click page but
actually you know they don't they always
say you know they add content they add
content by adding their own you know
opinions of phrasing but usually you
know not much
Vito like you want to I mean the
original post is actually from Google's
blog but anyway so this been going on
for more than ten years so you know you
got all this click page and they repeat
I mean they are like they are like many
of these they speak on media
organization for example the verge the
the the the many of them like like lots
of them some of them are new or vice
vice media or you know lots of them the
verge is one example and there's another
example it's like actually lots of
examples the i-90 something some
sometimes tech things and you know lots
lots of them you get ideas then they you
know they'd BP and they are like they
they have like staff there they are
dedicated to to make money like they
have statistics you know running from
Google Analytics you know tell you which
post got most users so they constantly
you know but you know perfection you
know the perfect the clickbait title and
so on and this this been going on for
like more than 10 years so you know and
they you know they then they know you
know angry treats to also get kids more
traffic and so on and so you create this
situation
Google is finally it's terrible social
network Google+ what do you mean yeah
Google first close down you know Google+
is shutting down on April I believe they
announced that like half a years ago
anyway so back to the music or I forgot
what topics yeah I kind of you know so
so about the evil you know Empire of
Google and all the news media that's
kind of odd topic I mean I talked about
that a few times so least least
transcendental attitudes that's my
favorite yeah so back to the music so
among classical music my favorite is
Spock and the least and among all Bach's
music my favorite is the way out
tempered crab here and among lists music
my favorite is the transcendental
attitudes so what what what other things
what other thing is happening 15 minutes
so I've been talking about 15 minutes
so let's see programming blog okay so in
any anything interesting Philip Glass no
I haven't haven't listened to Philip
Glass I'm not sure what that is is that
done by grasses if that's done by
grasses I think I've heard of hints of
trains yeah fascinating
you know when Hansel trains comes into
the news you know I was reading Time
magazine like from 1990 you know around
1991 - you know most most of 1990s to
1997 maybe well at least for three years
I was reading Time magazine you know
Time magazine is a weekly magazine I was
reading Time magazine cover to cover you
know every word for for two years and
that was how party how I learned English
you know I look up every word I don't
know but Time magazine was a great
magazine back then but not today today
it's the social justice stuff it's lies
you know blatant lies and fake news and
you know feel grass
lots of piano minimal music oh I didn't
know no well the the yeah I didn't know
feel grass metamorphosis complete but
okay I was saying okay piano yeah so so
yeah I look ya know and and Chopin was
great you know but Chopin if you compare
two lists list is much better so I heard
this art ago you can let Chopin versus
list
I mean put it here read it offline
you know don't don't read it here so you
know so what else ya about piano
Margeaux machines piano technology yeah
here oh yeah here a piano keyboard
action well I'm not sure I'm gonna talk
about these but anyway so what cuz you
know because if I'm just going to talk
about a topic without any introduction
without any context and then it's kind
of dry you know I'm just going to
Beethoven I don't like much of Beethoven
stuff not really Beethoven and also
Mozart's actually I dislike Mozart stuff
I used to call Mossad a soporific ball
yeah but Mossad is a genius he's one of
the prodigy you know this there is
something interesting about prodigy like
like the concept of prodigy itself is
interesting because some people when
when they were born I mean it relates to
what's called savant they call idiot
savant or something like some people
they when they were born they just have
a natural gift so so Mozart is one of
them but however Mozart you know many of
the prodigies they you know if you look
at the prodigies I mean there are piano
prodigies they are you know musical
prodigies they are mathematical
prodigies they are human calculators
like if they can calculate faster than
then you can use calculators but usually
they prodigious usually they turn out
they don't do anything they don't do
contributions to the world like if you
look at all the greatest mathematicians
or musicians or composers you don't
almost like you don't see prodigies with
this with some exceptions for example
Mozart is one example but in general the
prodigies they just they don't they
don't do well they of course they are
also you know
example Ches apologies in chess and
someone savant what's the problem
word idiot savant yeah idiot savant I
guess that's how the coin or at least
used to I guess they don't call that
anymore because you know so there's a
movie by Tom Cruise very popular called
Raymond I love that movie so it's an old
movie and this movie shows you what a
salon is you know and also you know
salon for example for example take for
example a book let's say Bible
okay because that's well that's popular
in America in many of these cases well a
Bible or a telephone book you know they
can read the whole book and memorize
everything that's how they are you know
these these savant idiot savants they
can memorize everything so that's
incredible I mean from from a scientific
you know the point of view so you know
how your brain works and basically you
as far as I know you know we don't know
the answer we don't know exactly how
that happens and by the way also there's
also a myth you know people like to
believe that it's a myth you know you
know what's called modern urban myth
that you know people like to think okay
so we are using only 10% our brain but
actually everybody can you know if we
can use 100 percent then we are all
going to be geniuses actually that's not
true that's just a myth it's started by
some guy you know usually many of these
myths are started by some maybe some
author you know sometimes only sometimes
intentionally sometimes unintentionally
you know they write a book or they'd
write an article in academia you know
then they contain some phrase and that
phrase became widely
sited and then it becomes idea itself
you know one of the famous example is
like Eskimos has like 100 words for snow
in things like that so eating us around
yeah so they have this incredible talent
but by the way I was looking at this you
know I you know I study you know I'm
interested in these kind of things you
know since twenty years ago I so before
the internet I actually went to read
books in a library about these kind of
people you know so you know there's
documentation about what they what they
do who they are you know and today I
mean today of course technology and
YouTube you there's a lot more you can
see on YouTube actually if you follow
Wikipedia I was I think I was reading
this article just a few months ago two
or three months ago because they are
modern ones like today who is living and
you can see them you can see their
performance performances and their you
know what they do on YouTube there are
painters okay they are pianists okay
they are there are others you know and
okay so if you go to Wikipedia I think
they are listing yeah here notable cases
some of them are still alive I mean some
of these are modern ones like young
still like 20-something you know some of
them are blind and and this idiots off
servants they are like they are cripples
I mean they are social creepers like big
they are unable to function in such a
society they don't know how to tie a
shoe you don't know how to dress
themselves but they but you know like
give them a keyboard they they they they
play Mozart they play park you know you
know in just incredible so that's that's
just fascinating and also by the way
there's also a separate thing about
memory you know like memory is an
integral part of intelligence I mean and
you know there's so there's also I think
there's a competition
memory like you know you and there are
people practicing that I mean there are
people who give you guides or you know
the winners of such competition they
they teach you how to memorize things
you know for example I mean this is a
silly example but there are people who
remember digits of pi - you know 10,000
faces and it takes them like more than
one hour to cite them you know pi is
3.14159 six you know so they can make
about ten thousand faces or more I
forgot what's the number but but the
those people are no more people they are
not idiots
idiot savants but you have to put effort
into it and they they you know you
develop ways to memorize certain things
font made before numbers or digital pie
they teach you you know you can look
into that they'll teach you how to help
you how to do that so Mozart brain takes
too many energy to only be 10% used
evolution will shrink it otherwise the
brain takes too much energy to only be
10% used evolution would shrinking yeah
my god I suppose you know of course I
you know I am NOT a neuroscientist so I
mean that makes sense to me
so there is a Korean acoustic guitar
savant called Sangha Joon his parents
were filming videos of him for YouTube I
see that's interesting yeah I look I'll
look up so idiot savant
so what's what else so this this is my
home this is my apartment back in 2000
you know I moved to my own apartment
back back at that time I was working in
a company not Opia and I was making some
money so I got this
you know and this particular model is
one of the more more expensive you know
high-end ones I recall it's $4,000 back
in 2000 so I got that I play piano you
know I'm very much interested in it but
so I mean when you buy a piano well
that's you know that's okay I don't I
don't know if this is a topic I want we
should go into but yeah so there is a
book code may of mathematics actually I
have it right here let me show you
men of mathematics this is all dusty
it's dust there so let's see if I can
see yeah so this is middle okay so May
of mathematics I got this book like this
is almost with it this book has been
with me for 30 years in the nineteen
nineteen nineties you know I was so much
into math and so I got this book and I
read it you know I read I read it you
know 1990s and by the way actually this
book turns out he's actually not good
history of math I have several books
about history of mathematics because I
mean I'm interested in that topic and
later on I learned as the internet you
know becomes more popular and they're
more if there are more informations on
the web especially Wikipedia I learned
that this book mathematics is not it's
not really it's not a good history I
mean it's not it's a little bit in other
words it's it's a bit more dramatic I
mean the author tries to paint you know
a more more of a dramatic picture but
however there is one thing about this
book there's one thing about this book
that I have memorized to this day okay
that is the first page there is a quote
let's see
introduction where is it
you know of this book the mathematician
I remember the most of course it's also
the most dramatic is a gallery genius in
poverty a bow yeah a bow is one of the
guy and Kalwa I think the way you
pronounce this name is khalwa he is the
creator of the Galois theory which is
basically solving the fifth power
polynomial in fact that is not possible
but he is the one who began to give us
insight about why it is not possible and
under what circumstances it is possible
basically yeah genius and stupidity
Galois 1811 to 1832 but anyway there is
a quote I was I'm trying to find ok I'm
not going to you know spend time to
waste time to try to find a quote but
the quote says the quote says they say
what they say let them say now that
quote is supposed to be from a college a
University's motto but I never
identified you know the exact motor
motor or photo of that motor of the
University but anyway on Wikipedia you
can find you know this article about men
of mathematics so I learned later on you
know that this book is not you know
really good if you are reading into you
know serious history then that is not a
book but if you want just a general idea
you know that gets you interested in
math then that's a great book
so let's see the printing ugh okay so
there is a book called mathematics some
big mathematicians in history were child
prodigies yeah fascinating stories in it
yes oh yamaha crab carve anova I don't
like the Yamaha Clavinova so Scott now
you gave me a topic now I'm going to
dive into that okay so um
stupid you stupid links copy link
address but actually I've been talking
for how god you know this you know this
evo you know this Google whatever like
when when you are a Google search page
you know for example you go to cook you
go to google and you search something
and there are lots of links if you copy
the link the link looks like this it's
not a direct link but actually you know
a link to the Google own website then it
has you know parameters that shows shows
the other win think why they do that
because they track you they want to see
you know which thing do you click it's
so bad with all these companies like
hung on a Twitter it tracks your you
know it tracks you know when when you
pause like when you when pausing here
for you know a period of second then
they know I'm looking at this particular
tweet tweet post you know so so their
ads do you know there are algorithms
where you will start to show this so so
you know they are trying to find out you
know they monitor exactly what you do
everything the way they track this you
know where you pause is because from
from JavaScript and most of most sites
today you cannot you know use without
JavaScript the other way you you notice
when they are tracking your
but it's basically every website trusts
you you know where you pause today every
you know there are JavaScript libraries
and frameworks they do that basically
every website oh let's say top what top
1000 top 5,000 website so the any
commercial website they do track
anyway it's let's go back to go to the
Scott's link so Yamaha Clavinova I don't
I I don't I didn't like the crowd Novak
Yamaha's although I do like see AMA ha
stuff in general oh you got this one oh
my god this one is a this one this one
is the expensive one I guess one of the
good ones yeah this this this with the
back I mean those are like miniature I
mean they are they do they have like do
they have strings inside
like some of the pianos they you know
most digital pianos they are just all
electronics but some of the very
expensive ones they have like strings
inside so they are not just purely
electronic they are actually
semi-acoustic so the thing when I was
you know looking into pianos right so
one of the very important things about
yeah let's let me talk about this how
long I've been going maybe for 10 more
minutes okay so maybe five or 10 more
minutes then that's it for today so one
of the interesting things about piano is
that the keyboard okay now when you play
when you know you can go to a Walmart or
anything you can buy a keyboard
you know like for $100 or $300 you know
maybe for your kids okay now the first
thing you want to look for is velocity
sensitivity that is if you press it
harder it's louder if you press it
softer then it's quieter you know so
it's it's called velocity sensitivity
basically most you know anything more
than $100 they have that those these
days okay that's the first thing you you
you must have okay let's say you must
have then the second thing is now if you
are playing keyboard music now there are
different types depending on what kind
of music you want to do if you are doing
pop you know you know pop songs you know
rock and roll stuff so that's one thing
the other thing is play piano like
classical piano not even classical but
jazz you know you know piano music so so
depending on which type you want to go
into the keys feel is critical it's it's
it's it's critical I mean it's not just
preference it's absolutely necessary
tuned because there are two types of key
what's called a field key action okay
what's called key action
now if you are playing piano music you
want the piano key action if you want
play you know a modern pop music you you
don't need that you don't want the piano
action so what does that mean on a
traditional piano like acoustic piano
you have elaborate hammers and vocals
behind it let's see if we can I don't
know if I should show why not I mean I
like on one hand I was concerned about
you know how much time I'm gonna spend
on talking but what but piano action so
you can see this is how a piano key
works but let's look at that
you know you you have probably seen it
on YouTube so it's fairly complicated
but the point to the player he said when
you press a key there's a weight it's
like a keyboard it's it's like
mechanical keyboards you know like when
we when we type programmers we talk
about you know mechanical keys because
why do we talk about mechanical keys
because there's a feel you know the feel
is very different from robot tom keys
when you when you're typing for a long
time the mechanical keys is much better
it's it's healthier for your fingers it
feels better it makes you you know want
to type you know longer you don't mind
but on the other hand a bad keyboard
Roboto mechanism it's you hit buttons
and also the other problems so in the
same way with a piano keyboard keys now
the piano keys is is the perfect the
ideal you know you want to feel the key
I mean they if you press the key you can
feel it you know if you you know one day
you go to try a piano you can feel it
yeah it feels very good and if you have
a pianist and you know if you are
practice piano you want that keyboard
you know because a bad keyboard you
don't you don't do well so this this
thing is critical to to to anyone who
wants to play piano now but on a digital
keyboard a digital piano you don't have
you know you don't have the hammers you
know you don't have let me show you some
other ones for example you have
different types you know it's so you
have that one and this one this one I
also bought in 2002 around there and I
like this but back then I was like I
surveyed all these different keyboard
but anyway so a real piano crispy an
acoustic piano you have all these
hammers you know going on in the back
but on a digital piano you don't know
more one you don't have that is but
however
they try to emulate you know they try to
emulate the hammer
you know the elaborate hammer and focal
action but usually they can they can
emulate it to certain degree but never
as good as if you actually have the you
know acoustic piano the whole you know
hammer mechanism so I mean usually of
course I'm a digital piano like this you
have Springs inside and they try to have
mechanisms so that you feel you know
like acoustic but not really but however
this one I bought back then 2000 it
actually has hammers inside you know so
so you know just for the sake so that
you can you when you play on this
keyboard it can feel like more like
actual piano but actually it doesn't you
know later on I learned you know it's
actually I mean that for example today
if you if I'm going to buy one I'm going
to get this one anyways you can see the
Hammers you know there's this guy this
these are not not my pictures but the
keyboard is the same as you know the one
I had and they you know he opened it up
he showed you all the key actions inside
you know it's made of wood but anyway so
I was studying about these issues you
know there's a lot of things to dig into
about about these different actions but
anyway so
so I know what you speak of my friend
has an acoustic baby grand yeah
drivin by digital solenoids I forgot
what is solenoid it's some kind of
electronic components yeah but I yeah I
know what you mean yeah so I mean so
today I mean well anyway so is there
anything else I think that's it for
today
it's 480 minutes let me so Raymond is a
great movie ok check it out also the
main man has a album a CD album well you
get what we don't have CDs anymore but
you can buy the album every song I love
it so much every song on this album
Raymond
so that's Raymond that's idiot savant ok
feel guys I'm gonna look into yeah so
that this another topic there you know
there are many mathematicians who tries
to create atonal music and I was you
know looking into them for a period of
time I look into them I don't ideally
like them
atonal music is like well that's another
topic so so so easy you have to explain
musics scales of it anyway let's see
what our outside stuff Twitter Evo
Twitter reddit reddit is same thing Evo
Evo Twitter so and piano keyboards key
actions piano music that that's
something I need to retry to suffrage
keys yeah so let's see I think there's
maybe something I want to mention
so ok that's it for today I think thank
you guys for coming
where are you we are you scarred are you
still in California in Southern
California quasi quotation okay thank
thank you guys for coming out see you
next time bye
since yeah bill again is reddit where do
you think is the best place to find you
in UX update yeah I know you are in
hamster hamster I think that's how you
pronounce it but but last yesterday you
are in Southern California right well I
don't have a suggestion for reddit
alternative well actually there are
quite a few alternative social media now
I mean because of the social justice
situation so they are quite they are you
know they begin to have several
different social networks that that's
kind of different but actually I've
never used them I'm not actually again
is to Reddit you know but you know it's
just there but you know is it's like
what can you do I mean I'm you know all
this I mean they are done you know the
word is remember Google and Facebook you
know and Twitter and you know that's the
most popular for now you know who knows
you know it's like you don't know what
will happen next actually you know
because things things come and go and
politics may change they are cutting
trees outside they are cleaning the
street so thank you guys I'll see you
next time bye