hello guys welcome to another episode of
exan talk show today we're going to talk
about random random stuff okay and uh
we're going to code eag lisp so if you
have questions ask ask me
anything and uh put your money put money
in my pocket okay okay let's see Super
Chat Show support fori Super Chat make
make your message stand out yeah you can
pay me PayPal patreon and
uh if you watch me you know on my
website you can find my stuff okay so
Random okay random
topic uh like the usual what I did this
is a comedy
comedy okay random topic ask me
anything and mean while I'm going to
code
elisp
fantastic so now you are
so and uh follow me on my Twitter
Twitter wait where is it
oh so here
Twitter so you follow me on my Twitter
and uh and follow me on Kar Discord you
can find Kar Discord ons.info
okay fantastic first question Rudolph
says how fast are you with the swar
board at this point oh yeah so SW board
uh well actually I haven't really been
using it I haven't started to learn it
so yeah but I I really am going to uh
Master it so it'll take a while because
I've been coding a lot I've been doing a
lot busy coding and stuff because coding
is more
important I mean this is just I mean
this is I love this extremely magnetic
but it takes a lot of time to learn so I
haven't really uh get onto it that's
why I owe to the guy who gave me this so
that's why I put on my live stream every
day to promote it but unfortunately I
haven't really got into it so but I've
been looking so that's why in the past
few month you have been seen so this is
by the way swab board s v a l b o a r d
search for it and you'll find it on the
website or search for data hand and also
I have a video review and I have an
article and uh lots of
photos
so I I think this is a great device but
I haven't got into it yet I will uh show
you guys down the road yeah so for those
of you you got to be more patient okay
because that's a complete new thing so
I've been doing a lot keyboard study in
the past two weeks lots of U so let me
introduce my keywords and let me go tell
you what I've done so this is SC of 80 I
talked about many times this is Ultimate
hacking keyboard they are
fantastic okay let's switch to the am I
doing good am I alive alive and
kicking okay
so so yeah I've been coding a lot and uh
Discord you uh you guys
join so I want to code some em yeah so
okay so let me tell you guys about what
I have been
doing uh so busy you know coding and and
also partly because of the swoard I've
be I've been doing huge amount of update
on keyboard on my keyboard blog in the
past about two weeks so in fact fact the
past three videos I was talking about
keyboard and you know keyboard layout
the
fastest the world's fastest typers you
know the you know I so I compiled I
looked into the speed typing community
and here is a collection of videos of
the fastest people uh I won't be talking
about it today because I I talked um I
mean there's a lot to talk about but
um you know so anyway I collected all
their videos so you can see each one is
a video with their hand with a camera on
their hand so you can actually prove you
know this is and you can actually see
how they type you know many of these
people actually use like seven fingers
some of them like they just use seven
fingers and some of them use uh eight
fingers okay so it's like like uh it's
like that okay some of
them so and sha Wana you know the the
one one of the top five fastest shanana
very famous you know he's created a
theory about how how you should stick to
quy I mean kind of like that I mean
because he he kind of sneer vorak and
comac which is extremely idiotic anyway
I talked about this topic um in my last
video or the one before okay so huge
amount of update and huge amount of
study of ergonomic keyboard layouts you
know and in particular this page now you
can you can see all the different this
is a JavaScript application you can go
to it so just search for ergonomic
keyboard
layout. info and you can see all the
efficient layout vac comac uh work
Norman these are kind of popular comac
DH
minimac uh and these are less popular
and then there's be and I also added
holac which is like three years old you
know newand like brand new and uh in
Ingram layout and also Canary Canary is
a community effort you know a bunch of
layout Fanatics they think they can
create a more efficient layout you know
and also but particularly I added in the
past few days all the European ergonomic
layout for example Neo is designed for
German and admw is also for German bot
is for French most popular and and here
you see French AER which is the the most
idiotic in efficient layout and PD
navito is Brazil's efficient layout and
you can also change language for example
uh
P naito for Brazil which speaks
Portuguese I don't have Portuguese but
you can use Spanish they kind of similar
so you can change to Spanish for example
let's see quy okay so quy you can change
to English Spanish German
French and pin pin is for typing Chinese
so you can see how they differ and also
there's Russian so for Russian you need
to switch to uh junkan the Russian out
this one then you can see very extremely
inefficient in
fact in fact the all the international
layout are the most inefficient okay let
me let me show you like extremely all
the standard international layout for
um um let's see idsy of international
keyboard layouts okay let's go there you
know like many of this keyboard in in
United Kingdom in Norway in Finland in
northern Europe in Germany in France
they have this symbol section sign you
know the generalized currency sign you
know the the superscript two the one
over two 1 half sign and the the logic
not sign like what what kind of idiot
put those sign there you know you wonder
so you know so you can look at the
international
layout uh
so you can see where are they used
so so the green is quy which is American
okay the green the Orange is qus that's
used in Germany basically German
speaking countries then the blue is ATI
basically just French French and Belgium
that's
it extremely inefficient like all the
way like the extremely idiotic you know
like they put the they put the section
sign like what the what the heck and 1
half you know if you want to type one2
you type one slash two right that's the
most that's actually better um so anyway
so you can see all the like extremely
incompetent so for some reason I guess
so these layouts are were created in I
guess 1960s 19 you know computer is
basically invented in America you know
we are Supreme America so for the first
50 Years or or so mostly I mean I mean
micro computers let's say well I mean
computers in general is mostly Americans
you know pioneered
it so usually it's just American
happening right but so so gradually I
suppose that's I suppose that's a
history gradually in Europe you know
they they need a keyboard layout so each
one creates their own incompatible
incompatible and extremely
inefficient it's quite idiotic quite a
story and you know what the most idiotic
I mean they are so all of them are so
extreme idiotic it's hard to say you
know it's hard to say this is the most
idiotic idiotic but French as a you know
in
French you know in French they have this
Capital acute e okay this character
Capital acute e now but if you are using
a French layout it is impossible to type
that character this is how idiotic it is
how extreme to a extreme degree and then
when you need to type other French
characters so you know so I have for
example French letter frequency so you
can see all french letters and you can
see what does French alphabet constitute
so French alphabet is exactly the same
as English except they have these and
only these accent accented uh characters
okay so when you want to study a
language and their keyboard layout you
need to know you know exactly what
alphabet you use what kind of accent
characters so they you know French has
this so but it's impossible to type the
capital acute e imagine that like
there's no key for it and that made the
French people the common French people
thought oh you know that letter should
never be capitalized which is not true
so the French government in
2019 finally created a new layout that
fixes many of these issues you know you
know so this is a new aery French
keyboard layout came out in 2019 but
it's also idiotic but you know anyway so
if you want to type French you should
use the people layout this is a
efficient layout designed for French and
you can type all the characters used in
French for example in French they use
this uh let me show you in emac let's
demo so in French they have
this uh let's see
uh
what yeah so that and
uh you see this
is the quotation mark used in
French okay so you can see this is the
uh the character name is
left pointing double angle quotation
mark okay that's a French or
gulet so in French they don't they don't
use the CI quote or the you know the
single quote they use this that's a
French convention which is actually uh
better so anyway so you can type that
basically you can type all the you know
French language uh
literature or orthography whatever you
know characters and symbols they use in
French so if you uh you know have two
type French uh use people
layout so anyway digress into so that's
what I have been doing a lot you know in
the past three weeks research read a lot
and you know about the different layout
and also look into uh let's go back
to uh you know let's go back to my
keyboard blog so you can see all the
news uh German also you know lots of
Research into the German layout what
characters they use so in German their
alphabet is exactly the same as English
except they use this omelet a o u and
also with this Sharps symbol so let me
show you here so these These are the
characters the German use so let's copy
actually not okay that's that's
basically the extra characters German
language language
use okay so you have to study their
frequency and so on so there is a German
language character
frequency so anyway that's about
keyboard so how many people watching 13
oh a million fantastic got questions for
me so Rudolph did I answer your question
you're going to say yes thank you about
swbo
uh now I don't know says does it make
sense to learn about group theory yes of
course for someone who doesn't know a
lot about math to get a better
understanding of functional programming
oh okay
so if you have any interest in math at
all group theory is a must go theory is
like one of the most
fundamental um
in in general so the most fundamental is
actually linear algebra
calculus and group Theory okay so if I
can pick three the most fundamental real
mathematics not arithmetics like 1+ one
fraction how do you you know combine
fraction you know that's that's great
you know that's great school math but if
you want to get real mathematics like
mathematicians level the three most most
fundamental math things you you want to
study is calculus okay just get basic
calculus like what's derivative
derivative integral how do how do you
use them what they mean you know
calculus linear algebra okay linear
algebra is very broad very useful and of
as you know in programming it's you know
for gaming for 3D Graphics it's all
about linear algebra okay then the third
one is group Theory group theory is is
about structure you know I talked about
you know on my website this there are I
talked about live stream teaching group
Theory uh two years ago or one years ago
search for it okay search for on my
YouTube or search on my talk show
homepage you can find it so first first
of all let me put this
into
um you see this is this
is oh wait I put in the wrong place
uh so so I'm using emac of course soft
FL
Keys okay fantastic soft keys uh if you
use emac you should use it more
efficient than VI than Vim keybinding
system there's a video and there is the
you know key binding supports lots of
layout voak comac Workman a French uh
German key German keyboard and you know
all that sof like ke and on the pink
window is all my command call the
command name and the keystroke I type in
real time as I type you can see uh let
me adjust
this so it doesn't hide in the
bottom okay so you can see
yeah okay and uh I was talking about uh
what something like is close close okay
yeah I need to so I'm using S HTML mod
select select actually I don't want to
select that select select cut close Okay
close and go to talk show programming
blog open back close next S Talk Show
showing browser that's today's topic and
let's paste it here so you can see the
French characters we talked about so
yeah group Theory calculus linear
algebra that's a three
fundamental
math you want to study if you want to
study math now your particular question
is about functional programming do you
need to know a group theory if you want
to know more about functional
programming the answer is no in fact in
programming functional programming you
don't have to learn any math you know
don't have to know group Theory you
don't have to know calculus you don't
have to know linear algebra okay it's
like almost irrelevant like complet
completely okay so for functional
programming
you you know actually you don't need you
know just just code okay my favorite
function of programming language is
wolam language and the and now a new one
fop fop from microsoft.net easy to
download just in one minute you you'll
download it I talked about in my my last
five fifth video you know function f
shop okay FSH is a a variant of okamo
which is a variant of meta language you
know which which has scar is a variant
of okay I recommend
FSH now if you are on l luux you have
the option of ok camo but fop is so easy
to download in in course platform on
Linux on Mac too so F okay so if you are
into functional
programming don't worry about
mathematics okay like the hascar people
the hascar people will tell you oh
category Theory oh Monet okay crap
you don't need to know n well it's it it
it it's related it's it's it might be
helpful but you don't it's not practical
okay you don't like forget about all
that you want to learn functional
programming code read the
documentation like I do you know like
for example lisp is a functional
programming one of the earliest just
code just code do a project just code
every day code okay don't worry about
the hasc oh monad oh curing or oh oh the
theory of category
pure Dil pure okay when are
they useful they are useful for
theoretical uh theor theoretical
computer science okay then you learn
type Theory type Theory and category
Theory they are kind of related okay
type Theory category Theory proof Theory
okay that's when you want to study
theoretical computer science such as
Lambda calculus
you know Lis is based on Lambda calculus
lisp common lisp scheme especially
scheme but you don't really need to know
any like Lambda calculus okay that's I
tell you
the the most important thing to know
okay you don't need you don't need to
know this just learn functional
programming is fantastic just code read
the documentation practice if you have a
question ask don't pay attention to to
any oh you know somebody some hot shot
blogger is talking about uh category
theory help you think oh oh has is this
or that okay they don't that they
don't help you and most of the time they
are talking they don't know
what they talking about
okay so uh glove 80 is fantastic yes it
cures my RSI but recently I've been
typing so much
um but today is feel it today is good
but but I I I have a chronic chronic
repetitive strain injury so right here I
talked about many times I have like 50
blocks on repetitive strain injury so
you can just search my CI website
uh search for injury you see like like
10 articles or or RSI
uh okay not not as I thought or typing
you know you'll find uh tens of articles
about
that so that answer your question I dek
I don't
know
next thank you Rudolf thank thank you
Rudolph also say theory is fundamental
tons of things are defined in term of
sets uh I'll have to I'll have to say
not really okay not really set theory is
is kind of the
foundation of mathematics and also it's
it's it's being displaced you know you
know set theories has its own thing but
it's it's not really like fundamental
it's fundamental in a sense that you
just need to know what's what's a set
you know the you know you don't need to
dive deep like one chapter you know you
know like it's not
really it's not really math it's rather
say theory is more about logic and
Foundation of mathematics how do you
Foundation you know I also talked
about that topics you know so let me
show you so you go to c talk show let me
repeat this c talk show homepage then
you have c talk show clips index so I
started to
collect you know the topics I talked
about in the past so and grouped by
category so programming programming
languages uh and wolam language and
keyboard layout typing hand injury you
know they talked about it so much
uh and hacker culture Unix Linux y i HC
for
example and emac this there's like three
200 videos on emac and emac disc coding
and Life Society and Humanity so this is
non- technical uh and math and geometry
so so they are several you know about AI
about chat gbt about uh bog gosper uh
lots of math you know because I do s
talk show live live stream for like
three years now so usually it's lots of
topics in one hour so I started to kind
of
collect this
information so if you want to learn emac
workflow or the you know all these
collected are usually my best
ones uh and emac LP if you want to learn
emac LP code coding so you know watch
all these
videos and uh some you know coding
videos right the search
engine okay and this is about wam
language symbolic
computation
okay so that man from Germany says I
type German English and polish and I use
KAC DH fantastic plastic with German ums
but with the E2 keyboard driver I don't
know what's E2 keyboard driver I can
type all European languages with that
with that layout yes yeah so some of
these you know some of these
layouts I mean some of the um efficient
layouts they are designed so that you
can actually
type uh or you can actually type all
EUR European languages with accents so
let me show you guys a relevant page
okay Unicode blog so go to Unicode block
so you can see so there's a section on
Latin
okay so you can see hundreds of the
weird decorations of accent
symbols okay so so you can see you know
first of all English alphabet or
important or Latin alphabet then there's
a decorated English alphabets so you can
see all the
variations okay the those marks are
called diacritics technically
diacritics and uh so you can
see and here is this section is the
story of of
O now if you don't know what that is
look at look it up The Story of O
Okay
and
uh there is article accent marks tra
umot marum circumflex so these are
commonly used in European
languages um and uh each a ENT Mark has
a name so here's a example and also
example in English acute accent
Cafe Deco Deja Vu resume RIS risky you
know the they borrow from French prud
eud
fian something like that grave
accent acute accent grave accent
circumflex
diuresis and omod now this one is
interesting T thank you
Rudolph diis and umod okay now this one
is interesting for example zology
reenact naive claw and
cooperation this Mark is actually came
from two different separate semantic
meaning marks you know so one is called
diuresis one is
and they but they have the same symbol
so they kind of
merge you know how do I know because I
read a lot you know uh you go to
Wikipedia you know you can I read it you
know like 10 years ago or multiple
times uh you know so umot so this three
omot is mostly used in
German and this s s sadila also used in
German you know fa facade and mang and
so on and brave and
Kon and till till that till day I'm not
sure how do you pronounce that but this
one this one is actually not an accent
mark this is this symbol and with a te
te is actually an alphabet of the
Spanish language okay n
n so you know interesting stuff
okay so that's about that so what
next I was going to code some emac
anyone is here for coding emac like H
put some HS and I'll C I'll start to
call emac this you know I've been doing
a lot videos so um so I be you know so
I've
been have I have been thinking about the
humanity you know usually anything I
think about is usually with respect to
the whole humanity and history like what
does it mean I mean even programming
language like python you know functional
programming what does it mean in the
context of whole Humanity you know few
millions of history or
4,000 years of written history which is
the part we really know but beyond 4,000
years ago we don't know
much so any anyway so I've been thinking
yeah video so you know it's a phenomenon
in the
past decade or two you know you started
to have videos you know the technology
technology is really the fundamental the
the one most important force that
changes Humanity the structure how we
behave what we do every day you know the
society the structure of the society
technology changes it okay okay for
example the common example is Industrial
Revolution you know uh then there's
invention of printing press invention of
paper invention of gun gun powder you
know that change society so today in
this decade we have computers you know
well I mean in this decade we have
internet and cell phone that that
changes changed the world truly you know
truly you you a fundamental way so so
I've been observing you know the first
video for example in
2005 okay 2005 that's about 20 years ago
is that right yeah 2005 20 years
ago that's when YouTube began you know
YouTube Google bought YouTube from the
other company I forgot
what so anyway we started to have videos
you know you can watch videos right
actually video began in 1990s on the
magc you know the quick
time you know you know I have blogs
about it you know I have like 30 years
worth of blogs so when you write blogs
over you know basically over your life
you can see what happened before it
serves as some kind of
documentation and you'll find you know I
often find in my blog 10 years old 20
years old or 25 years old blog that
links to articles then it reminds you
what's going on at that time you know
the thinking is different you know for
example 20 years ago you don't have like
social justice War years you know you
don't have
that and uh in anyway so back to yeah
video so in 2005 or late 2000s you know
when the video just start you know
sometimes you have a wellknown person
like Professor for example one of the
famous Cod programmer they give a talk
you know you know like gu steel or or
Richard storman for example Richard
storman you know live stream you know
and they give a lecture or a talk you
know at some University or somewhere and
you have live you know big camera
equipment go there to try to do the live
stream you know live stream on YouTube
and all the news website you know
they'll say oh the live stream you know
this guy is talking and everyone is go
watch
it because it's it's rare I mean like
like before before
2005 you almost never seen any you know
let's say famous programmers or
well-known professors talk
talk you cannot unless you travel to to
there but now with technology you have
that right so when it begin everyone is
like oh this guy is talking you know oh
go watch it but now but now all the
famous people is talking nobody is
watching it because there's so many you
know every every Joe every idiot you
know or every girl is like live stream
every day 10 thousands of
them and the professors well every
almost every not almost but I mean
there's tons of it like you tons of it
the the the best mathematicians
they get they have a YouTube you know
the best like the top 100 best
mathematicians you know they many many
of them have videos you know and or
programmers or the top computer
scientists you know you like you you you
know so much information today
so okay so
that anything
else what's next next topic nothing
okay so we talked for 40 minutes now
let's
see uh Unicode okay so some Unicode news
finally we have this power symbol you
know this is a frequently request symbol
power on off but it's not in unic code
until uh I guess two or 3 years ago so
finally we have that that's Unicode news
and there's some update on Russian
alphabet I'm doing the update because I
was studying you know Russian layout you
need to know what characters are
there uh okay Russian
alphabet and of course this Chinese
and this is interesting this is a
Unicode art you know the asky art or
text
Art very beautiful and they are program
programmatically generated by scheme
list people there's a website I I think
I have a source somewhere here
yeah so you can see I don't know who who
what's that website some kind of forum
but this skin people they created you
know this this text this is not drawing
you know they they use skim here is a
code you know they created this
fantastic asky art fantastic beautiful
and look at tilings
amazing okay I want to open them so that
I can link to my talk show
later uh okay that's about
Unicode what am I drinking just coffee
just plain coffee and
milk do you think you are a skeo yes
I've read L one's books and I found it
very relatable I wonder if you have any
other
suggestions did you see Laurence book on
my website because I have a few articles
about schizoid and in fact if you go to
my
YouTube you can also find my Asian
article about I mean I talked about
schizoid uh where do I search
here schizoid Personality Disorder so
this is
2019 my
earliest that's a year I begin live
stream
regularly you know
so and here that is the book you are
talking about by Lan okay schizoid
personality disorder yes I'm a schizoid
I'm a my schizoid now to avoid
drama what you know so let me tell you
guys what skizo mean skizo basically
means a
loner you know it's a particular
personality such that the person do not
enjoy working with others usually they
avoid other people they they prefer to
be
alone you know so it's a unusual trait
unusual like most people are not most
people are they need social interaction
you know for example in prison they have
this isolated cell you know usually you
don't want to be put there you know they
put you there you are just by yourself
um usually they you know it's a
punishment you know in prison but for
skid personality like me oh we love
it you know so we don't we don't enjoy
we like we prefer to do things
alone so I'm kind of mild in in schizoid
there's more severe ones uh in fact in
in sou Forum there are several you know
those who follow me you guys a lot of
you are I know I can see uh and you know
some of them some some are more severe
than
me like they don't they don't they don't
talk to other people at all like they
they they
live they they live in a like P town
like for example in
USA in 10 miles there's no one else you
know and they keep birds or whatever you
know there are something like that
extreme but I'm not that extreme I can I
still talk to people but I'm able
to you know I'm fine if I don't talk to
other people for like for one month I
don't have a problem you see that that's
a thing that's an interesting thing for
most
people if they don't talk to another
human being for a week or for a month
they go crazy they you know they they're
going to start to think about suicide or
whatever you know that's most
people so skizo is kind of opposite of
that okay anything
else is it
interesting give me some feedback oh 22
people yeah so back to the story about
YouTube so I've been thinking you know
the evolution of videos online you know
beginning about 2005 right or
technically beginning about
1990 you know even before that on Unix
you have like stamp-sized video anim GIF
for example but anyway practically the
online video thing began around 2005 you
know YouTube
basically okay so the it's a phenomenon
then around 2010 you start you know the
cell phone became very popular because
apple right so everyone can you know
like before that before the cell phone a
lot of people don't have a computer you
know they don't mom and pop you know
they they don't they don't know what is
they don't use computer Windows what's
Windows you know and but with but the
phone is a giant huge Evolution yeah I
mean huge technological
Evolution so so all these people who
otherwise never used the computer now
they do on the phone right and they can
watch videos so then after another 10 or
15 years everyone can stream like today
right so the online YouTube phenomena is
not just you can stream but you can talk
to just about
anyone in the on Earth anywhere in China
in Russia in Europe like I mean I mean
USA right you can talk to anyone instant
ously in real time you know even even
just 15 years ago you know you have to
buy webcam you know via the chat you
know instant chat message then you have
to check compatibility you know lots of
trouble and and internet is not fast you
know you have little videos to see your
grandma or whatever granddaughter you
know little video sometime it doesn't
work you
know and I remember in the 1980s if I
need to call my dad in Taiwan from
Canada you know you call hi operator I
need to call Taiwan you know it's like
$40 a
minute 40 like $30 USD per minute you
know
1980s so it's tremendous you know
technology improve in change and of
course changed so Society so you know so
much so I mean yeah so all these videos
and today every minute you have like
what a million new videos
right uh so it's amazing you know then
we haven't you know then then there's
Tik Tok and the YouTube the YouTube
shorts you know idiotic so so it become
a situation that um all these videos
like basically everyone
anyone stream
live stream their life or whatever you
know so it's not you know so there's a
change of mentality kind kind of okay so
for example 25 20 20 years ago in
2005 when there's someone talking you
know a celebrity or a programmer you
know you are interested you know it's
news like you it's a rare rare happening
you have to go watch it but but today
the video is
become it's like
um you don't have to like do do you care
about what your neighbor is saying every
day no right I mean because everyone is
talking I mean the world seven billion
seven billions of people they are doing
something every day seven billion what
it 8 billion you know everyone is doing
something you know like every day do you
you and you can't you can't watch them
you know you can't you can't
be you know you don't have time to look
at 8 billions of people is what they
do uh do you listen to any podcast no
not really I don't really subscribe to
anything uh and usually I don't like
podcast you know like for many people
they like podcast because they can play
it in the backround ground and they can
do whatever especially when you are
driving right in USA but I don't drive
you know I don't I rarely drive
so and for me when I listen to something
I need to have the whole
attention it doesn't work for me to just
play in in the background no it's either
I put whole attention to it or I don't
listen so that's the way I work
so what's the other question
uh so there's a question hi the man I've
been looking for translation to this
song okay so let's copy that let's
see uh what are you saying
what is
this okay what what what is this
thing because I don't want to run into
some kind of controversial
stuff okay that's okay that's a song
about
Pakistan okay very political thing okay
I'm not going to talk about
that and I hope you are not trolling
okay okay I think maybe that's it for
today we talked for 1550 minutes
yeah okay if there's any questions ask
okay so meanwhile let me go to my talk
show and just put the links of things we
talked about today's talk show I was
going to do some Eis coding but I guess
forget
it uh
close Okay
copy now you see I need to
raise can you see you see I raised my
glove 80 with
tilt uh boxes so now I need to raise the
middle this higher so I can press that
easily uh okay that's about it for today
unic Code art make it
link unical
Chinese
link Unicode user interface
link quc Russian off a
bit fantastic close
close accent mark
umlet okay link it
The Story of
O and lots of keyboard stuff okay is
there anything
interesting
uh okay close that so talk show Clips
close that search programming okay uh
not going to talk about
that s FL Keys okay you should try
it German character
frequency sh thank
you bye-bye
speaking of keyboards and layout what do
you think of
typo I have not heard of that
that t a i p
o let's
see what is this t
uh okay so let's try typo
layout typle inclusive keyboards
offensive okay the first impression is
very offensive inclusive keyboards there
is zero consecutive hand or finger usage
okay let's see what it is
okay looks like they need JavaScript
okay second bad impression they need
JavaScript okay I'm not sure I want to
turn it on we Embrace we embrace the art
of staying true to our Roots while
gracefully learning from the word okay
another bad impression they are trying
to sell you
something some like like what that you
know they are trying to sell you some
kind of political thing our menu is a
celebration of diversity of B and
flavored Fusion that breaks free from uh
what the what the is this okay
that's not
it oh wait type of layout
sorry okay there is zero consecutive
hand or finger usage when using it when
two hands in typ of bigest benefit is
its consistent flow and ease of access
to all symbols here are some visual
aids okay
well you see they require
JavaScript I don't I don't really want
to okay let's turn on
JavaScript uh I don't think I'm
interested in it it because oh
that wait what
okay
uh okay so this is a coding layout this
is a
code that's new okay that's interesting
thank you I'll have to read
it this is a coding layout that means
you have to type two keys at the same
time to type
something uh yeah bye