good morning everyone
you are watching Kesava talk show today
is September 25th Wednesday 9:30 in the
morning San Francisco time and how are
you guys so let's see what is today's
topic if no topic I'm just going to go
random okay so battle um you say is so I
changed my time you know it's it's going
to be 9 o'clock
every day this week ok this week now
crock every day but yesterday I slept
late and I thought oh but you know I
said late so I change it to 10 but in
the morning I just I woke up two hours
ago I woke up early so you know I wanted
to change back change back to 9 o'clock
but then I thought I already put out 10
yesterday so maybe it's not good because
people come in 10 that's already
finished so I change I change it to 9:30
thinking that 9:30 is like in-between so
that so that you know people will see it
you know I shouldn't change the times
that's no good
it's because the schedule so let's see
what's the topic let me refresh the
window refresh the window and coffee
milk and milk and the coffee
coffee powder so I'm in my life it's not
too sure what's what's with this
starting it should say live zero
watching now this is incorrect so
definitely I'm broadcasting and so I
have myself do you see finally how Derek
good morning Derek good morning
Bartholomew
okay so so so Bartholomew says number 13
question number 13 how to deal with runs
on different operating systems and how
to handle none utf-8 input when runs are
expected you know you shouldn't code one
because it is you know you should just
call it Unicode Unicode characters you
know Unicode consortium is the
organization that created this thing and
the Unicode characters and run you know
the word run means two things in : they
invented the word you know in :
they created the jargon runs to me
Unicode code point now you got you guys
know what code code point is right so
you know in : they they created that
jargon that means basically just means
Unicode code point
Oh in other words it means Unicode
character now I talked about this
Unicode stuff so anyway you in Unicode
in : they call it one but one is also a
Asian language should I show it let me
show it then okay
so let me show Kassar Unicode okay and
sorry : ok so let me explain that :
Michael and tutorial you can go to types
: types basic types but before we talk
about about that let me talk let me tell
you what does run means the word run in
english so unicode my unicode you go
down search for run there it is run okay
this is what one looks like for example
for example what you see below run it's
kind of a asian language
using Northern Europe so this is what
one looks like
but however in : you know the LA Pike
and Indian friends they just they just
robbed they just borrowed the word run
to stand for Unicode code point okay so
so learn in go line is several things it
means one integer from 0 to 2 raised to
32nd power minus 1 it's an integer okay
and it's also a colon type there's a
Golan type named one it's it's alias to
int 32 and it it also means a Unicode
code point you know those integers
stands for Unicode code point and it
also means a character because that's
what code point is unicode code point so
let me explain what is unicode code
point so guys comments ok types types
that bottom your type stuff let me know
I'm here so Unicode so Unicode is the
standard that has all the world's
languages characters you know and so
each character but why don't they just
call it character they don't call it
character because because for example
space the space character space it's not
really a character but and space and
return and cap you know those are white
spaces you know you call them white
spaces but they are also I mean in some
sense they are characters from a
computer point of view they are
characters because you need to represent
them but from a writing point of view
they are not characters they are just
space you know so but but in a
programming technology point of view you
have to call them characters I mean so
that's the thing you know you have
different you know whether space is a
character or not or line return or tab
you know depends on the context
therefore therefore in Unicode they call
every character
kote point they don't call it character
they just call it a quote point but in
practice you can think of them as
characters now Co point is just a
integer it's it's like an integer ID
that identifies the character okay there
you go so I just went online [ __ ]
there's some long delay I already I
already talked for like five minutes I
already talked for let's see how long
for seven minutes I started like five
minutes ago seven minutes ago there must
be you know yeah anyway so I was talking
about Unicode code point and I was
talking about Unicode code point so I
was saying you know you shouldn't call
run so anyway so bottom us question is
how to deal with runs or unicode code
point unicode you know on on different
operating systems in how to handle non
utf-8 input when ones are expected so
what you really mean is that how do you
handle non ASCII characters that's the
proper way to what kind of that's a
proper way to say it how to deal with
non-ascii characters on different
operating systems and how to handle non
utf-8 input like depends on what you
mean Bartholomew so if you if you can be
more specific and I can tell you because
because what you mean for example what
do you mean by how to deal with them
code okay so maybe maybe here's answer
okay so when you see a file you know
each file have a different may be
encoded in different encoding systems it
can be utf-8 it can be utf-16 it can be
used here
thirty-two or it could be you know
what's uh what's some of the names
coding systems okay so let me explain
cuz Rd Unicode encoding okay I have a
page that experienced that so
Bartholomew says the reason for the
topic is that I was writing an app for
Windows including runs and only after
that I found out that Windows is very
weird about text encoding okay I would
recommend then that you fully understand
I would recommend that you you you read
this page okay so that you have complete
understanding of Unicode so this page is
not too long it's only like three
screens four screens okay so you read
this page or maybe we can talk about
that we can like yeah maybe we talked
about this page so it's it's it's
incorrect to say that you know that
Windows does not support Unicode you
windows support Unicode fully in fact I
think the you know they set this for
Unicode fully you know there are a lot
misinformation and propaganda from the
UNIX people you know that like those
kind of people I hate I talked about
this all the time like UNIX philosophy
the Linux you know those people they
spread misinformation about Microsoft
Windows all the time so Windows can just
they can unicode hundred-percent
you know even even even better better
than unix better than linux like five
years before linux actually even
supports utf-8 so what is so so let me
try to answer the practical answer to
that question so i was writing an app
for windows including once and only
after that I found out that Windows is
very weird about text encoding it's not
very very weird okay this is a
mischaracterization you know
each operating system they handle único
differently including programming
languages for example java java source
code is encoded in utf-8 camel script
string is more even weird okay they are
they are quite a few topics to talk talk
about this in depth ok java so you have
the concept of source code you know what
is the encoding system useful source
code depending on the language each one
is different okay some of them can be in
computers they don't care like you can
encode the source coding any any
encoding system for example for example
JavaScript Ruby you know and Python and
Perl the source code can be encoded in
any encoding system
now that's one thing now a language is
stream you know every language has a
string almost all languages string that
string that string is a different issue
you know what what exactly does the
string mean so that's a different that
again depends on the language for
example in in Java it's just a sick it's
a sequence of sixteen bytes that's it
it's not character it's not Unicode it's
not a ski it's a sequence of sixteen
bytes based on utf-16 encoding the the
topic actually gets complex ok anyway
that's the string in Java now in
JavaScript again a string it's a string
is a sequence of sixteen bytes based on
utf-16 it's I think it's I think it's
the same as Java
okay that's JavaScript now in : a string
is a sequence of bytes eight bits you
know eight bits so again that's very
different from Java or JavaScript now in
Python in Python to a string is a
sequence of bytes in Python to just just
like
Oh almost is just like : almost exactly
I think they are slightly different
anyway in Python to a string what does
the streaming it's a sequence of bytes
okay eight bits but in Python 3 a string
each each string a string is a sequence
of Unicode code points okay
so so this is a another concept this is
about what does a streaming in each
language on Emacs emac please for
example a string is just a sequence of
Unicode code points you know so so again
let me summarize there they are so there
are two different concepts when it comes
to you know character set on Unicode of
a programming language one is what is
your source code encoded in I mean you
know in in Perl Python Perl Python
JavaScript it doesn't does not matter it
you can encode your source code in any
encoding okay
Oh Chinese encoding doesn't matter as
you know as long as then you have to
specify what encoding it's used
they are makani's there are ways to do
it so some languages you know the source
code can be encoded in any encoding but
however in in in Java for example in
Java they must be they must always be
encoded in utf-8
okay that's Java now in JavaScript it
doesn't matter but by by by convention
it's always typically always utf-8 okay
actually I have articles for for all the
details for each of these but
so let's see so many questions so make
sure I want to make sure that I don't
get distracted you know like so I you
know so that the topics we are talking
is organized so first are we talking
about Unicode issues with respect to
programming languages okay one is first
issue is what is the encoding used for
the source code okay I'm making a list
so that it's more clear to you know the
video content so you know we know what
are we talking about so the first issue
is what is the encoding used for source
code different languages have different
ideas okay for example in Perl Python
Ruby JavaScript the source code can be
in any encoding but typically you have
to specify it if it is not if it's not X
such as utf-8 okay
encoding source coding coding that's one
thing now the another thing is stream
what does a string me different
languages has
great greatly different approach to this
issue okay for example in Golan string
is sequence bites in Golan and in Golan
and Python two strange the sequence of
bytes okay
showing browser does that make sense
okay so in Golan Austrians the sequence
of bytes in Python 2 strange the
sequence of bytes in JavaScript a string
is a sequence of 16 bits or 2 bytes in
JavaScript in Java and JavaScript string
is a sequence of 16 bits based on utf-16
encoding
okay so what is encoding we can talk
about that so basically when you deal
with unicode stuff you have to
understand all this fundamental concept
and you have to understand them well so
so bother me I would recommend you study
this page it's copy that okay so so
that's what we talked about so far and
we will be using utf-8 until we die no
more transitions that's not true that's
false
okay Duncan Oh Duncan there's something
I want to mention ok Duncan then Duncan
did this
oh god I'm starting to digress and I
need to finish reading the comments so
many topics like in parallel right now
now Duncan
you did a lisp labor is like right [ __ ]
I have it somewhere here but I get that
there it is
Duncan home yes exactly that's you so
don't come home did this look at this
beautiful Lisp sticker
you know you dunka made this do you
still have them so Duncan made this you
know you so you can stick on your laptop
that's at least this is the future this
is the future my friends so Duncan right
right so let's pick this put put that
here so let me answer that question okay
we will be using utf-8 until we die
that's not true okay that's for example
entirety of China they are using or
different oh so Duncan still have
stickers so you guys if you want it so
Duncan are you willing to sell you know
so you have to send like st. st. $20 to
Duncan - here's ship you this Lisp
sticker maybe so anyway so so god I have
to so many topics so let me read the
comments okay let me just try to see
what are the questions out there so if
you find so schedules of other misses so
you the reason for the topic okay so
windows broke the utf-8 processing of
the input that's not true
okay Bartholomew that's again each each
operating system is different so you
just have to know what is the windows
way they don't just break you know utf-8
processing of the input I change to
utf-8 bit better on Windows I did not
ask UNIX people I read Wikipedia and it
said that Windows is weird about that's
[ __ ] okay like point point out the
boutique Wikipedia article and let me
dissect it
on the spot you know I can tell you what
is correct what is you know wrong
botany says it did not work on Windows
it was printing useless characters yeah
that happens all the time that happens
especially with Python - you know so
yeah so you have to first of all you
have to understand fully the concepts
the core concepts of what is character
said what is encoding you know what is
utf-8 utf-16 seen and how is it
different from for example some other
encoding Chinese encoding for example
character name encoding 6 in encoding
systems you know this Chinese characters
I'm trying to find a Chinese encoding
systems it's written somewhere here you
know every every time I have to
I don't remember offhand so anyway they
are different there are so many they are
quite a few different encoding systems
and it's not true that utf-8 will be
utf-8 is today is the most popular at
least in or in non Asian countries at
least ok in Western countries French you
know Spanish English things like that
and Russian you know the European
languages yeah you go with utf-8 and
looks like yo P V encoding for you know
for the next ten years at least possibly
after 10 years you switch to utf-32 okay
possibly and but also utf-8 also by the
way Java Java Java and and windows file
system and Mac OS file system they are
stuck with utf-16 so you know don't
believe what you read online you know
the online people I know you know mostly
switch you know most of them I take
opinions they came from the UNIX MINIX
people they talk you know they
to talk they's that's called food you
know spread fear they play Microsoft
furred fear uncertainty what is T for
that that's why I despise the the the
Linux we UNIX philosophy people thought
fear fear fear becomes a unicode
character I don't want to become fear
okay and certainty certainty and what is
d4
okay I'm gonna explain that okay fear
uncertainty and doubt oh my god I
haven't seen this face used for a long
time you know eunuchs philosophies you
know pretty much dead today's young
people especially in many Millennials
they don't have respect you know
yeah the hacker basically the whole
hacker community is dead
you know the hacker kind of community
and today yesterday you know a few days
ago Richard Stallman is gone so you know
the UNIX philosophy kind of thing is
gone you know today's people don't know
about it but anyway in the 1990s and
2000's UNIX people they used to spread
this jargon you know food acronym food
fear uncertainty doubt okay they they
say this is Windows you know windows is
spreading fear and certain uncertainty
doubt I think actually the UNIX
philosophy they you know the the UNIX
people they are doing that for example
let me explain all these character
encodings okay for example a bottom you
says windows one two five two what is
universal about it about this how is
this normal let me explain you know how
UNIX you know UNIX is the operating
system that is most obsessive about
backward compatibility UNIX okay
among all operating systems Apple
Windows UNIX okay UNIX compare it
compared them UNIX is the one that is
most as an AI you know obsessive about
backward compatibility
they you know they are the most okay
they want everything to be backward
compatible back to like 1980s they don't
want to change anything that is why you
know in many of the shell for example
shell bash we still have turns of
convention that doesn't make sense at
all today but that's just that's the way
it is you know you next people don't
want to change that they you know you
know it's just this that's their nature
okay it's not the intentionally you know
oh I want to this or that it is just the
way they think you know they they don't
want to change anything
so like today we still have sudo like
sudo and the pseudo sudo is extreme
complex [ __ ] ok soo doing a bunch of
things and tah and look at you know ty
is like 30 30 40 years old you know the
free software foundation they are still
sticking to tah you know you know what
is Utah you know what is tar right on
your next our main page tah and in the
main page itself is you know still there
nobody is actually using my page anymore
like you know like today all the
programs they start to have program name
- - help instead and in fact that's
better
you know the main page and you know tah
and also the UNIX file structure it's
all [ __ ] up you know it's old
you know but you know so you don't get
me started on UNIX ok sudo is extremely
complex you know back in 2000 I was
sister to me and I was deep you know I
was diving into UNIX very deep back then
and so I know you know I can I can do
surgery what they call surgery today you
know like you type like configure like
who can use to do like today don't
nobody do that anymore you know today
you have you know Tucker you don't even
you don't nobody even go to SSH much
anymore you know back in the days you
SSH into a co-located machine and you
know manage your server and stuff you
know you don't do that anymore
you have Tucker you have a server less
you know whatever server let's
programming I don't actually know what I
type that is but anyway the point is
that you don't you know the concepts
concept of going log into a remote
machine it's almost kind of it's not
that yellow of course a lot of you I
know I still use but it's in general
it's kind of that's going away and so
back then so today you don't actually I
I think most of you don't even have the
experience of logging into a UNIX system
where they are ten other people also
lucky you don't you don't have that
experience anymore you know he's a
it's like you don't do that anymore so
pseudo back then was you know you have
to use to do because if you are sister
to me I mean even a word sister mean
it's good today you have the dead up
yeah you Dave up you know you know it's
all change change so the UNIX philosophy
the UNIX the hacker community kind of
died
okay so pseudo back then when you man
Caesar being a machine where ten people
you know all the developers locking you
have a tape machine that's what I do you
know so people logging you have to
configure pseudo so that for example
this guy have certain this this that
privileges that guy has root privilege
and things like that so you need to
configure to do so I have to do that you
know pseudo config file it's like it's
like garbage you know it's just like
everything about UNIX config files
everything every every program is
incompatible with each other extremely
[ __ ] extremely esoteric like like
it's impossible to believe who [ __ ]
designed that okay okay let's in general
describe every program about UNIX sudo
is one of them so I was you know I dived
into Sulu 20 years ago because I have to
you have to configure who can I'm
talking about configuring pseudo he's
yeah and that's what I'm talking about
you know like you can you you can check
you know just by man page man page to do
I mean today you guys don't even haven't
read this to do anymore
you could anyway I'm not going to go
into that we digress so much I want to
go back to the character sets and stuff
and okay so I want yeah yeah let's go
back so I was talking about I was
talking about how UNIX compared compared
to Mac and Windows UNIX and Linux is the
one that is most most obsessive about
backward compatibility and and that's
why the shell and all the things
everything you use our Linux is back is
kind of have all
lots of complex baggage attached to it
okay so that's about backward
compatibility on UNIX you know but
however I mean it's backward compare the
compatibility is important I mean it's a
practical thing you cannot just always
move forward for example let me talk
about some industrial backward combat
compatibility issues for example
javascript you know today we have
javascript 2015-2016 every year we have
a new javascript spec but javascript
people they decided they want to be
hundred percent backward compatible
that's javascript okay
python for example Kaido decided now
we're gonna you know we are progressive
we want to move forward into the future
so Python decided Python three you know
which is not backward-compatible so you
got paid down to is you know then you
got Python 3 okay so so that's about
backward compatible bit compatibility
it's you know different different
programming languages they have
different like idea how progressive they
are how how obsessive you know they want
to maintain backward compatibility on
the other hand compared among our
operating systems Mac is the most
progressive ok Mac is the most
progressive they are backward compatible
only as far as money is concerned money
that's right they want they are
aggressive about going moving forward
making things not backward compatible
for example their ports you know if you
know like everything about Mac basically
the way they decide about something
whether something should be backward
compatible or or they should move on
with the new you know new system or new
syntax or new you know ports and
peripherals and things like that
the way Apple decided about that is
money that is for example every day a
machine maybe have five years lifetime
so once that five years so after five
year basic so what so for Apple
basically they move about 5 years
backward that's it you know you just
have five years backward compatibility
you know then if you want to oh but I'm
using my program that you know long it's
five years old no longer what's you know
it's six years old no longer works
apples answer is that oh it's time you
buy a new Mac you know that's Apple now
Windows is in between okay now now I
talked about you know now you you know
so you know no you know backward compare
compatibility is a issue okay it's an
important issue now let's go back to the
Windows character encoding the windows 1
to 5 - what is that you know I don't
like it okay I don't like it I'm and I
never like the Microsoft because I don't
like big corporations but windows 1 to 5
- what the [ __ ] is that
well that is backward compatibility
windows ok if you are the boss of
Windows I mean suppose you are a Linux
phonetic and suddenly with Microsoft
bankrupt they release everything
open-source you are now the boss you are
controlling you are deciding what should
you know what host how things should
move on you are going to still going to
have Windows 1 to 5 - yeah that's what
you're gonna do because spec code
compatibility because Windows you see
Windows they are used by like 90% of
population over the world for like 404
for 30 years you can't you can't it's
not up to you you can't just say Oh
from now on Windows 11 we're gonna pitch
you know no more windows you know with
no more windows 1 2 5 2 encoding no more
the old stuff you can't do that okay
just like JavaScript JavaScript you know
you have the you have the word of a
concern that's going on it's not you you
can't just say oh we're gonna we're
gonna you know do some switch to you
know we're gonna teach x11 yeah another
Linux [ __ ] except I'm a UNIX [ __ ] you
know X you know
like for example in UNIX x11 is is is
the thing today like that Linux people
realized we need to get rid of but you
just can't because all the programs are
written exe jebin you know you have this
typically you have nice niche group like
me or my followers who wants to move
forward oh oh we should use the what's a
new name you know the new windowing
system no but but for the most part you
can't just do that you know because they
are you know there are systems the
nuclear facility CDs you know they are
education institution all over the world
you can't just change your system you
know backward compatibility that's an
important issue it's not up to you just
to teach and you know change that that
is why you have Windows you know one to
five to encoding you know that I suppose
that yeah I don't know Windows Tech okay
so but we can let's look it up so that
is why you have that encoding Windows
one two five two and when it comes to
our wiki okay on you know when it comes
when UNIX people when they see these
they all just say oh [ __ ] stupid you
stupid UNIX they don't support utf-8 or
they don't you know they don't do this
that they they are weird you know fact
than you in UNIX [ __ ] that's not
that's that that that is my dissection
of the UNIX you know this UNIX
propaganda you hear every day UNIX since
since like since at least 1990 s UNIX so
let's see wind what is Windows 1 2 5 2
when Windows 1 2 5 2 or CP 1 2 5 2 is a
single byte character encoding of the
Latin alphabet ok that's Windows
invention used use by default in legacy
components of Microsoft Windows yeah so
bartholomew you run into this because
you know because you don't you don't you
don't know that you don't know the
windows system you have to understand
the windows system just like when you
learned in linux like when you encounter
encounter linux problems mean
Lena's captain ten times more programs
name than Windows you know you go to
stack flow you go to Ubuntu you know you
know open to you know a wiki you go to a
kleenex wiki and you know then you spend
ten hours to figure things out and you
don't complain you you are thinking oh
this is so so great so many information
therefore the Linux [ __ ] wait how
come you don't think of that for for
Windows you know give Windows a break so
Windows and and by the way in anyway so
that's the issue that's that's my
complaint about the UNIX people okay
they are spreading fear uncertainty
doubt about Windows and another jargon I
was popular is embrace and the extent
okay that's another UNIX you know
[ __ ] they create things I let's
talk about that some other day because I
saw I saw people mentioned the other day
in my chat you know I I know about this
you know all these things and yeah okay
so we were I was talking about you know
originally we were talking about the
encoding system kind of some technical
talk
I was wondering should we still do that
you know because I was going to give you
a kind of explanation you know of what
is character said encoding and utf-8
utf-16 and all that you have to
understand so we you know read this
article you understand it well then if
Windows here is your main operating
system then you have to actually
understand how Windows work you know
first of all you you understand about
this encoding issue now this issue is
kind of permanent issue I mean doesn't
matter what operating system you have
this issue when you want to do computing
of characters you know characters needs
to be needs to have an encoding to work
you know to have a you know in order for
computers to have to display characters
so that's one thing you need to
understand that's part of computer
science then depending on what
language programming language you use
what operating system you use then you
have to know that you know particular
operating system or language how they
you know how they deal with the issue
this is typically my approach to
everything computing you know first of
all you understand what is the issue
involved you know kind of you know what
is the problem what is the issue then
you learn about specific technology how
they deal with that issue so you have to
do that so okay so let me read comments
so so comments so and we haven't
mentioned Chinese encoding yet okay so
some people like a lot misinformation
out there are saying okay utf-8 you know
we're gonna use utf-8 forever that's not
true the entirety of China which is
about one-fifth of people in a world
okay one-fifth you know Chinese Chinese
and India has the most population if you
count the number of people you know in
the world so entirety of China they are
using an encoding code called C t18
something okay let's see let me see if I
can find it I have like I have so many
articles about that specifically did I
mention it here
okay maybe not here so saw the Chinese
encoding I have like several other
articles about it so for example here's
what he is one article what character
encoding to do Chinese websites use
that's one alkyl okay okay let's go just
go there so back in 2012 I did a survey
what character encoding to Chinese
website use back in 2012 okay so I look
at I looked at all the most popular
Chinese websites and I made a report so
you can see the encoding here you have
utf-8 you have GB 2 3 12 ok GB 2 3 1 2
okay then you have gbk you have you know
so anyway Chinese encoding basically
China ok so anyway that's that's about
Chinese encoding and the Chinese
government they have you know they have
standard so basically every computer you
sell every computer you sell in China
they must support the GB let me tell you
what what is the encoding ok
intro to Chinese encoding every every
computer you sell every computer vice
must support GB 2/3 112 okay that's it
that's that's a law so in China the
entire almost almost the entire website
in China they are using they are not
using Unicode ok then I know the UNIX
people will say oh that's problem that's
a problem the Chinese government so Evo
they don't they don't go with
international standard okay that's wrong
that's like you know stupid that's
that's your bias ok the GB to 312
encoding is is you is Unicode compatible
is it's it's they call a transcoding
format for Unicode meaning that every
Unicode character every Unicode
character all Unicode character is also
present in GB to 312
and likewise you know vice versa
so they are kind of the same however the
encoding is different the character said
is the same okay now why do why do
Chinese not you use let's say you TF you
know Unicode let's let's say when what
what did Chinese not just use you TF you
know you know maybe utf-16 or utf-32
well at that you know they can you know
so they have to make a choice I mean
it's so in the in this case they choose
their own encoding this also backward
compatibility reasons okay before
Unicode is invented they have you know
they have gbk okay and they have you
know big five which is used in Taiwan
okay
so Big Five is used in Taiwan that's
before Unicode okay you don't have
Unicode yet so you need to you know so
you know just like UNIX and Windows you
need to have backward compatibility so
they invented the encoding that you know
gpk is I think it's backward compatible
to part of the Big Five in things like
that so they then you know after ten
years they they need to create a new
encoding because gbk is two or thirty
years old things like that ten years or
so so eventually you know you have gb
and 2 3 12 which you spec welcome back
compatible with gbk things like that in
the same way in the same way utf-8
encoding is backward compatible to ASCII
okay if you have a file every character
is ASCII characters then if you encode
that file in utf-8 then that file is
exactly the same as as the Seaview
encoded in ASCII you know because why
because backward compatibility utf-8 is
designed so that is backward compatible
with you TF is with the ASCII okay 100%
as long as you don't have non ASCII
characters you know backward compatible
compatibility is backward compatibility
is a
practical issue you know you cannot just
ignore it it's it's there it's practical
but meanwhile it's also kind of nasty
you really you know you rather want to
move forward you know move forward to
better design you know remove the old
words you know the old design problems
you know you want to move forward but
you know this conflict you have to you
know backward compatibility is issue so
okay so let's see how long I've been
talking 14 minutes
so let's read the comments let's let's
read all the comments then I start to
talk again so you so now it's a good
time to post comments okay post
questions whatever
so I got a few how do you say
distractors disagree I got a few people
who disagree okay
Israel says your credibility is going
down the drain and Bartholomew says why
do I have to treat an OS special there
is a thing in German that is called
extra worst extra worse how do you
pronounce that you should look that up
okay let's look that up
Oh God
what's going on hush [ __ ] this mac os/x
traverse they seem extra burst German it
means a smoked salmon something like
that okay so I guess a cold cut yeah so
in America we call this cold cut below
claw sausage so is that what you mean I
think this is what you mean German
expression okay German Idi Amin idiom
German idiomatic expression extra verse
is also a frequently used German
expression of disapproval relating to
someone wanting or receiving special
treatment okay
I would say something something
something okay special treatment yeah
okay but do I make sense I mean bottom
you overall after what I have said
do I still mix do I make sense or you co
disagree I mean you know yeah let me
know if you do disagree let's go back to
comments
let's go back it's okay people's
comments away post comments in my you
know make it orange so let me read the
comments
good morning Seamas good morning max
Loretta from Russia so maximum axe
Raider terrorists what is the encoding
used in Russia he said utf-8 and the two
Russian have their own encoding and by
the way I did also Japanese has their
own encoding okay so it's like you know
the social justice scan they would say
you know the many of your opinions are
you row centric everything that's not
you know Europeans is all oh government
you know Evo government or something
it's not true and unit eccentric okay
so max the radar says what is a rule of
thumb for stream should we adopt to
programming language or OS what do you
mean like for a stream in programming
language like we talked about that
before you know I mean today in early
today so a stream if each language deal
with it differently you know and I don't
think there is one solution for all I
mean my goal and has its approach Python
3 has its approach javascript is the
worst ok javascript its worst anyway so
to me I mean I don't know oh you know
all the languages approach but to me so
far I think I I feel like go lines of
poetry is the best ok a string is a
sequence of a bytes meanwhile you have
the run character type you have then you
have the slice type that can deal with
it I talked about this in in my video
about : strings so this is for people
who are doing : ok it's you gets very
technical yeah so what strings
what does a3 mean in a language that's
actually very technical you know even if
you programmed in a language for 2 years
average programmer in your company you
would not know ok you would know after
maybe three four years Oh
or unless you actually deal with string
conversion or you'd unicode a lot then
you wouldn't know for for example in :
you have this issue stream byte stream
versus pie slice versus run size so
string is a sequence of bytes okay eight
bits then you have the by slice concept
per slice is just basically a mutable
array each element is a byte okay
string is immutable that that is why you
have bite slice mutable so that allows
you if you have a long you know 10,000
characters you can use by slice so you
know so you can change you know some
characters however each one of them is
dealing with bytes but Unicode character
is not one bite
you know many Unicode characters are two
or three or four bytes so that cut so
then you come come up with a concept of
run slice where basically it's a mutable
array where each element is a character
okay so you have these three different
concepts then it's kind of tedious like
every time you deal with unicode then
you have to convert between one of them
like you have to oh you know this
function you have to know which type it
returns exactly then you have to decide
whether whether are you going to change
it or are you not going to change it you
know oh oh if you are dealing with
unicode or you are or you are dealing
with let's say audio stream or video
stream where you are dealing with bytes
so Deventer depends on the context then
you have to choose the right type like
this in colon there usually your
function has have three versions one
deal with a string one returns the
string one returns the pie slice yeah
typically AB and then you have a package
that deal with runs so you have to so
every time you have a string you have to
consider you know which one is it you
know what how you're gonna use it then
you have to switch you know you have to
change type things like that so he's
it's kind of tedious on the other hand
for example pythons approach Python 3
approach where a string is always just
Unicode characters a string is 6
sequence of Unicode characters okay
that's that's it but then you got
problems like a lot of people complained
Khan Train about Python 3 string
because often when you do network
programming you you need to deal with
sequence of bytes you are not you don't
want to deal with characters you want to
deal with bytes but often you know
string is a very convenient type so you
again you run into a problem oh you know
you got a string in Python 3 it's always
unit UTF you know it's always it's
always a UTF I think it's utf-8
but anyway so you sequencer UTF unicode
characters then you have to change it to
a byte stream type you know used you
have this problem too but I think colon
is better
okay colon is better I you know I
learned this I find it so great it's so
great on the other hand let's look at
you know JavaScript okay I have articles
for each of these okay so so that's for
you if you are look if you are
interested in this kind of topic then
you have to look into detail okay so
let's show let me show you the articles
okay and it's supposed to be here so
that's about goal and then let's go to
exile a JavaScript stream okay Java
JavaScript string is the worst okay okay
I actually have several yeah I did
several video talking about that I guess
I guess so JavaScript string I have a
detailed very technical detailed article
diving into the meaning of JavaScript
strings okay
so string overview temporary string
character code unit code unit code point
okay so you can go to string overview
and you can go to this article in detail
very complex JavaScript JavaScript
string is the worst okay so string is a
is 16 bits unit sequence
so in a string Chaves we scream each
unit is actually it's not a character
remember this is important critical it's
not a character okay it's not a unicode
character no no is it a 8-bit byte you
know it's not for example let me show
you
you'll be surprised ok this article so
so I explained what is a code point for
example look at this JavaScript code
okay let me let me copy copy it and run
it let me show you okay
create a JavaScript okay new buffer
magnify okay paste so let's say we're
gonna add when this okay console.log you
know we we want this this is a string
okay and it has one character an emoji
we want to see what hum you know how
many characters are there okay run it it
returns true
so this stream the length of this string
is two characters what a [ __ ] you know
it's a one emoji you know this is not a
combo character this is a single
character for example in Emacs we call
describe cha okay so the code point is
one two eight five one four o in in
hexadecimal is one f60 - okay and this
character's name is faced with tears of
joy okay it's one single character it's
not composition that's another
complexity of unicode you have composed
characters but anyway in this case is
one single emoji characters it's not
composition but in JavaScript it says
linked to you know what the [ __ ] in fact
every or JavaScript 3 method have this
problem okay every string method ok it's
a serious [ __ ] you know [ __ ] you
[ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] all [ __ ] up problem
in JavaScript
okay and to this day there's no fix for
that I mean like every JavaScript
function that you know string methods
have this problem because big why
because job a JavaScript string is a
sequence of two bytes you know sixteen
bits that is why I mean so so when you
deal with Unicode if you work with
Unicode if you are writing an
application that process Unicode you got
this problem so every time you need to
use the string method basically you
cannot rely on it so you have to go with
walk around and this this problem is so
deep and serious that you know the
JavaScript 2015 did not fix it 2016 did
not fix it 2017 18 it's not going to be
fixed forever you know it's not fixed
why because why because backward
compatibility okay they don't want to
fix it so it's a it's a big problem okay
so the here's a javascript and by the
way this problem what you have seen here
happens with java - so you see when you
program when you do programming you have
lots of these details you know this is a
I mean this is a major [ __ ] this is a
major [ __ ] and imagine if you work in
Java you do you have the same problem
exact same problem because Java they do
string I believe is also 16 you know
it's almost similar to JavaScript each
you know each element in string is a
16-bit value and also in Java the source
code encoding is 16 bit bits
why does though this problem happen
because you know this is 20 30 20 30
years ago 25 years ago Java in truth in
1995 back then the thinking was that
pactum you don't have emojis okay emoji
is 10 years old you don't have emojis
back then the thought is that back then
everyone is still using ASCII okay
stupid ASCII ABCD efg to Z that's it you
don't have you don't have you know
Chinese can you cannot do Chinese
Japanese Korean Islamic ocean you cannot
do it it's you know that's that's the
back then but so back then people are
most USA Europe European they are all
ASCII okay they are all ask well in
Taiwan in Taiwan is Big Five in China
you know GDG gbk like we mentioned you
know they they have today you man
they're all in Japan you have like XJ
XJS you know to something something
Japanese encoding okay for Japan you and
and Unicode Unicode just begin around
1990s okay Unicode is not popular yet
you know the every time you have a
technology each cooperation to power
struggle like we nobody is sure it's
going to survive well not you know
anyway so Java have the same problem why
do they have a problem Java in
JavaScript because back then the thought
it was that 16-bit is enough you know
it's like a big jump from ASCII ASCII
only suppose 127 characters that's it
but with 16-bit unicode yeah
so this unicode you know unicode six 16
bits the thinking was that oh my god now
we have like two million something
that's plenty that's in fact that's
enough for entire world's languages
including asian languages like Egyptian
you know the logograph the Egypt a graph
you know Egyptian logograph so the
thinking was I it's enough 16 bits yeah
yeah yeah that that's enough of you know
for the future of humanity but things
change you know it turns out you know
then we after ten after twenty years
years we decided we decided oh that's
not enough then then we then this
problem happens we have legacy okay
but if you are younger today you don't
know you don't know this you see things
oh they are not UT Aveo they are stupid
you know that's not that's not true
you you look at window oh they are you
know furred fear you know fear
uncertainty so they fear uncertainty you
no doubt yes that's not true okay so we
talked about so so that's about strings
in Java in JavaScript we talked about
strings in Python 3 we talked we talked
about stringing unicode I mean :
so the question is is there one single
design for a languages string such that
it's so good that everyone should adopt
no as as far as I know no so far we
don't we haven't seen it okay so that
answers that question I hope that that
that question from from from the Russian
guy good mornings each round crazy thank
you for coming by Maxo Reiter
so that's max Rita's question so
comments ok ok so nobody is addressing
me okay okay good
so green deck says in Russia we have
utf-8 we use utf-8 and windows one two
five one okay so it looks like windows
one two five one is it's kind of like a
ski so let me let me read the comments
okay so back to the beginning
okay so
sir Bartholomew says I did not ask unit
UNIX people and so on by the way but
both of you as you know I'm not
criticizing you or Israel right yeah I'm
not right you know me that you guys know
me okay to offload my my hatred again
it's the UNIX people okay you can
disagree or not you know bringing
printing useless characters okay so so
what is z h z CH z I don't think there's
a CH physique Chinese encoding okay you
see show okay what are you say use what
is okay yow
now in Emacs in email is the encoding is
again interesting okay it's different
from colon Python 3 Python 200 C or or
Java or JavaScript okay also I don't
know see okay but I think C's see string
is just a sequence of bytes okay it's
the sequence of a bytes so if you want
to deal with Unicode I don't know how
you deal with it I guess
I don't know see so you know in sleepers
first
I guess you use a library you know and
see oh my god C&C press service then you
have include [ __ ] fact in UNIX
include you just slow ping of whole file
like no no no like no library system no
no modules no name is space include you
slurp in a fire and if that fires uses
include I just slapped in you know so
you have variable names stamping each
other the [ __ ] UNIX that's so that's our
range and all the problems of the of
computing
you know as I don't know if you guys
read it you know the worst is better you
know go read go read the lease article
okay there's the article very popular in
1990s called worse is better you might
have heard that phrase that came from
that alcohol it's a long history I can
talk about that that Uncle Al articles
history and who wrote it and how it
became popular for one hour as worse is
better okay look it up what is better
that's a that's one chapter from a
article about from from from Lisp this
Common Lisp guy who created the company
lucid which gave us XE max back in 1990s
ok 1990 and involves jwz jwz jamie
zawinski you know who created netscape
and so on he made that article popular
was is better ok jwz was hired by this
guy Richard Gabriel which are he goes by
our GP Richard G P Peter something
anyway you can look up watch this better
ok so that our Co discussed two
philosophies of design harmony system
design basically it's one philosophy is
Lisp MIT philosophy the otherwise UNIX
[ __ ] from New Jersey
ok anyway go read that so so you have C
so everything is UNIX is the virus you
know you get you become very popular you
get it to learn fast you know the
primary concern is just get it to run
fast simplicity and and you get everyone
to use it then everyone become familiar
with all the Watts and complexities like
[ __ ] up then every everyone is used to
it thence the then you know they started
to improve a little bit like fix this
bug fix that bug you know so so see so
we begin with C [ __ ] then you have C++
[ __ ] then you have Java then you have C
sharp there
a script you have pearl you have
seashell or you know that's why I see
syntax the worst syntax [ __ ] possible
see syntax that's that that's standard
that that's how it becomes standard you
know every time you use you know that
that's why that's why it you know it
gets people used to you know habituate
you know it makes people you know used
to it Israel I use man page every day
yeah that's you
by the way did you know man pages was
you know if I can name one documentation
that is the worst among my 30 years of
reading documentation programming
language spec programming language
documentation programming language
official tutorials and and software
manual or documentation such as Emacs
manual Apache eMac lists manual you know
I've read you know Mathematica the whole
book I talked about this many times of
all the documentation if I can name one
that's the worst of the worst
that's UNIX man page okay now in the
1990s or even in 2000's whenever I say
that nobody believed it you have all
these UNIX [ __ ] they call you a TRO
okay but today actually people believe
that a lot in fact there is a movement
there is a movement to rewrite the
everyman page okay on github I've seen
that like three years ago there is a
movement to read to completely you know
removed we write the mem UNIX main page
I've seen that on github I don't know
how popular is that github UNIX main
page like they want to rewrite it
let's see maybe it's that
no that's just that's just my page so we
need to search for we need to search for
the project that we that rewrites all
UNIX man pages so let's see if we can
find that
does anyone know does anyone came across
so green deck says if C syntax is bad
what syntax is good
well Lisp is an option and you also have
Haskell syntax Haskell F sharp metal
language ml standard ml o camel they are
all all of the same syntax but I think
that sin x is bad ok mathematical syntax
I love I think that's the best syntax
math mathematical syntax syntax is
actually your syntax system ok it's not
just one-time syntax it's a syntax
system ok that topic that topic
you know kindig if you ask me another
day I can talk about that for one day oh
all about syntax because because I have
like I have like 100 few hundred
articles about syntax you know the
syntax is a huge project a huge topic
involving formal languages anyway so
let's talk to men ssin that we talk
about that next day so we were talking
about yeah so you have Haskell's haskell
syntax this syntax i don't like how the
Haskell syntax ok I have articles on
that yeah that's gonna be another day 20
minutes talk about on that by itself but
right now we are trying to find the
project that we writes UNIX spam page
unikz rampage rewrite project
what is I I see it on github
you know and then you have this Linux
man page project you know that's idiocy
the [ __ ] open-source you know this
this project this Linux man page project
and and also and there's also a Linux
documentation project I'm not sure if
they are the same thing or not you know
it began around 1999 something like that
the idea is that we need you know Linux
nice documentation because that's one
major flaw people criticize Linux you
know so Linux people thinking they need
a documentation but anyway in 20 years
after 20 years we are nowhere today you
still go to stack overflow you dive you
dive through our clinics wiki and
especially our psych overflow most you
know night 80% of the Linux answers are
like 20 years old 10 years old you you
know you every time you have a problem
you go through you find the answer so
that answer is 10 years old this answer
is 5 years old the [ __ ] fact that
Linux so to this day what happens you
know the idea back then this is 20 years
ago and I'm not sure it's this one
there's a Linux documentation project ok
Linux documentation project this is back
in 1999 or 90 or year 2000 this is this
one ok this one very old
I think they died 10 years ago this is
the first was first one Linux the Linux
documentation project the idea is that
typically in Linux you know or open
source you don't have good documentation
so you know people OH
we help each other open source you know
free software foundation we you know we
let's help and and today it becomes
social justice [ __ ] [ __ ] you these
people with the help mentality today
becomes social justice they just kicked
out which a storm and what what do you
think about that what what you gonna do
stand stand up and say things you know
say things help help humanity stand up
you know the [ __ ] the Linux people [ __ ]
the open source
you know helping Google now become they
they become the the criminal idiot you
know the criminal can Google Facebook
Twitter so anyway denotes documentation
project you know this is a 1999 20 years
ago it's it's a long time dead you know
it's long time dead
you know it's don't I'm dead and then
they stackoverflow come up stack over
for the commercialization the
gamification [ __ ] you know and but they
say they say open source so we are open
source stack overflow we help you know
everything our side you know is is free
open source you know you can copy you
know the [ __ ] and all you people Linux
programmers but into it you know that's
a situation you want to be practical you
want to look at the reality not not
following ideology okay so anyway the
next documentation project you can see
some history here and in the what and I
don't even know what the [ __ ] is this
Linux main page project it you know it
happens often you know you you try to
find some when you work in Linux you for
try to find answers all the answers like
10 years old five years old or 20 years
old like if you are young people today
you you you maybe if you know Google
they probably don't show this page
anymore but if you run into it oh oh
what is this oh I need to find out how
do you do firewall you know in ox and
you spend you spend two hours oh then
you realize this is like no good that
yeah that's Linux life and and also then
in github yeah everyone supports github
you open-source [ __ ] speed hope
today they are owned by Microsoft what
do you do what what do you think where
does where does your help mentality are
you are you doing good
are you helping humanity it becomes
Microsoft what you're gonna do so now
you're gonna postcard now you can avoid
scott github
now you switch to the get the new one
the kid whatever what's what's the name
get lab get lab yeah
ricky lab has this
great logo gate and and three years
later three years later Google says hey
collabs you know that you know let's
talk we're gonna give you ten billion
dollars you know because we really love
your project it's gonna be sold just
like exactly the same decision you would
do if you started the open source code
you know you right now suppose you are a
good open source phonetic you know three
software phonetic you created the
software yeah I'm gonna create this
project this is pure open-source we're
gonna help humanity
you know encrypted and all that then
after five years you you walk to every
day you know your life you get nope a
little like no pay but after three years
you become successful you are happy then
Google comes you know Google yeah we are
Google we help humanity and and we
really love your project yeah I think we
you know we we give you awards you know
Google words and whatever and we're
gonna buy you know we are thinking you
know maybe you would be interested we're
gonna you know you know give you money
in 1 billion dollars you're gonna be
sold
you're the [ __ ] you go [ __ ] yourself
open-source phonetic you're gonna be
sold right away then what you say oh
they think you have different reasons so
you you you know and you know you're
gonna start a blog you're gonna write a
blog on some open source web site you
you now say oh today we are happy for
the open source community
our project is fine finally adopted by
by you know by something safe someone
who is safe the Google you know they're
gonna help us and they're gonna expand
you know all the good things yeah all
the good things
yeah so yeah we get we got into a rant
again so I think maybe that's it for
today I haven't actually finished
reading the comments like my hate for
Linux you know hate hate you know I'm
alive because of hate that is the story
of my life I'm alive because of a hatred
I have so much you know I have I have a
fucked-up family you know
okay that's good so so so many comments
I know that is too many for me to read
so I guess you guys are talking to each
other let's see what else is addressed
to me in Russia we use that if you stick
did you stick your list stickers on to
anything oh yeah I remember you gave me
a few right I even forgot about that
no because you know I'm I'm I'm my life
I you know I'm doing pretty bad okay I
was like I am you know like the easiest
way to convey my situation is like if
you look at the homeless on a city
street you know are you going to I mean
if you give him a sticker you know he's
not gonna do anything with it so I'm not
homeless I you know I'm better so I'm
one level better but you know like you
see you know if you see I'm have a
computer and you know I'm but not much
better okay so I don't have a car I
don't have I don't have anything you
know I I could be die I could die any
day you know if I fall down tomorrow
I'll be done yeah I don't have I don't
you know I can't don't have money to
visit doctors anything like that I don't
have insurance
what nothing if I if I ride my bike
tomorrow and I fail down that might be
that not yet and you know so that's my
situation so you give me stickers I
don't I don't even have you know I I do
have a Windows kind of a laptop kind of
the windows surface book I can stick to
but I don't
so yeah I don't have you know I don't
have that's my situation it's kind of
chaotic you know I you know I have to
see what happens you know
so SEMA says 2005 is young for utf-8 yes
is utf-8 invented in 2005 yet even I
think it is yes so 2005 is young for
utf-8 and China just chooses what they
want it doesn't reflect technicality on
utf-8 right but there's also another
issue because if you let me tell you
this okay if you encode Chinese in utf-8
versus if you encode Chinese in utf-16
the utf-16 encoding will have much
smaller file size
you know because each Chinese character
will typically be two bytes in utf-16
okay but if you do it in utf-8 then each
Chinese character will typically have
three bytes okay that is in general the
case so so I mean if you are a nation I
mean if you are Chinese review a Chinese
you know obviously you utf-8 we are Inc
you know every file for the whole nation
will be 11.5 times larger if you do it
in utf-8 so that that's you know so that
there's a issue of that so that's why
you don't you know so utf-8 is not like
me you know the Utopia like you know I
know and I know this many Linux
phonetics UNIX you know philosophy
people they are like everyday they are
they are telling you oh utf-8 should be
the universe of [ __ ] you know they are
they are just spreading the proper
propaganda
politically biased yeah because that's
because if you are Western people you I
mean how do you know about Chinese I
mean you don't you don't know yeah I
mean you it's not like you intentionally
it's not like you know about this but
you intentionally try to be evil that's
not a case but however on your
and you don't you don't spend the extra
time you don't go extra mile to actually
study Oh what but how did how does
Chinese do it
how do Indian do it how do you know
Islamic to it you know how they affect
Islamic you know you don't actually
think about that much like once they
published it all ago if you are just
European you read it oh yeah that's
that's so true you know we should all
utf-8 and then you tell everyone else
you to tell your friends you know that's
a that's the thing meanwhile I'm not
saying since same thing happens for
Chinese people in China you know same
thing exactly exactly same thing you
know they don't think see other Western
ways because they live in China you know
that's the thought that's your you know
so if that's that's why we have
different cultures and and there are
four different biases from different
groups yeah
so green deck says no s keys it's not a
ski is windows 1 2 5 2 window 1 2 5 2 is
Cyrillic a windows one two five one is
really ok
Joseph Smith who said that name sounds
familiar
and for the record Google and the
Internet are good start
[Laughter]
okay that's it I think that's it for the
day today yeah one hour one hour one
hour in 22 minutes okay let's have two
more minutes okay if you have any
questions address to me let's talk about
two more minutes okay yeah two more
minutes that's it okay and two more
minutes
I'm gonna shut down you know you know
every time I talk about like you know
now I have 17 Watchers I notice every
time I talk about if I do if I do very
technical talk usually that's you have
less people but if I talk about non
technical like just random opinions
especially if I go into a rampant you
know rant mod you know lively then
people want to watch it because it's
drama it's dramatic but you know that's
actually not a good thing you know
that's that's how you know that's part
of the reason all the Creek baits you
know all the creek every day every day
you see every any article their name
their title is just [ __ ] Creek Creek
bait you know so so after today this
video we are named you know this video
we are named
okay I'm gonna name to this window
today's video why Linux sucks donkey ass
okay then I need to spend time to cus
customize to customize a icon for the
video you know that's what people do
like every you go to every YouTube
channel every video they have customized
icon so why is that that's marketing
okay you you actually you almost always
that icon you will not find that icon is
not in your video that like you will not
find a frame your video
having that screen but you you customize
it so you create a screenshot you know
you know some drawing or whatever to
represent this video I don't like to do
that so in my video you don't see that
every video almost you know the icon
looks
the same but you have to do that's
that's why I despise this all the
commercialization [ __ ] and that's why
also I don't make you know I don't make
you know much money you know I I don't
want really do that you know I don't
that's I don't really want to do that
and with quick baits on and so on so for
example so today I need to for example
what what is a good icon for dramatic I
come forward like UNIX [ __ ] sucks
I need to create some you know some
simple graphic outstanding or even just
with the words
you know UNIX sucks donkey ass this big
poet title then people will actually
cricket where they they will start you
know I will see you know with the
googles you know the analytic [ __ ]
Google will tell me oh you know this
show me all the graphs
oh these videos have so many how many
people how many you new people watch
this video at what time and so all these
square [ __ ] fact the mock marketing
[ __ ] you know Google of course Google
wants to Google wants you to be
successful as a YouTube creator you know
YouTube YouTube [ __ ] marketing term
YouTube you know not just someone who
use the YouTube but YouTube [ __ ] Google
and Twitter you know Twitter tweeting
tweeting you know each like each
platform they create their words just
for their own use so instead of posting
on Twitter you say tweet tweet you tweet
something you know and flag them and
master they're in same thing with a
[ __ ] mastered an open-source
[ __ ] they have no print they don't
they don't think for example master then
they in a beginning at least they want
to call they opposed to be what they
call it I forgot but anyway they try to
have a would a term for for the word
posting when you using mast and
student to post something so anyway
Trudeau has you know treat and anyway so
Google YouTube have YouTube and YouTube
creator
anyway YouTube YouTube want to be to
want you you know the Creator to be
successful like if I go to my youtube
channel as myself I see the whole bunch
of you know like YouTube they're gonna
try to help me help me how do you
increase your audience how do you know
let me show you guys okay
because I'm guessing most of you don't
you know don't do YouTube some of you do
I think for example let's go to my
YouTube my YouTube studio beta okay so
this is yoga you're gonna see my private
screen okay YouTube beta so let's look
at this channel Aled you know this is my
dashboard channel analytics current
subscribers 1100 something 94 increase
in past in last 20 days you know it
makes me happy what you want to keep me
updated like how many subscribers I have
now oh you know if my subscribers is
down I need to do something you know so
you got these statistics and how many
you know top videos how many are
watching my latest videos or whatever
then you can go to Google Analytics go
to channel analytics the [ __ ] Google now
this is not the common opinion you will
hear from youtubers okay you know
YouTube creators typically they will I
will be happy oh my god Google is so
great oh look
you know they provide you know my chats
you know how many people I have how many
people subscribe to my channel and look
out at all these [ __ ] statistics how
can I make it so that how how can I
quick create a quick paid you know so
that I can see oh this quick paid has
got more more viewers oh that quick paid
did not have more viewers so next time I
need to do more click paid in that style
okay
you know so Google is doing this and
what they say they are helping you of
course Google is so nice they are
helping humanity they are helping you
create us to make your YouTube popular
for spreading information for the good
of humanity humanity [ __ ] look at this
look at this news boost performance with
playlists you know these nice people
diversity diverse you know diverse guys
diversity creator insider Oh creator
insider make more money on yellow dollar
videos I don't even know what the [ __ ]
is the yellow dollar videos and another
another dashboard ideas for you make
your next production shy the [ __ ]
YouTube so you know they you know and
every youtuber so so what's the
consequence of these well the
consequence is that YouTube grows and
grow and every time you go to YouTube
you see all these quick baits everywhere
you know then why is YouTube doing this
of course they are not doing this to
help creators they are doing this so
that the more YouTube videos the more
people watch the more money they make
okay you make and they make every time
you make they take they remember they
have to have or sixty percent something
of the ad money goes to them YouTube
that goes to Google so we have this
commercialization situation you know
that's you know then so what's wrong
with that what's wrong well on the
surface it seems nothing wrong but there
is a accumulative consequences the
consequences today is you know we have
the canceled culture we have the
Millennials we have the social justice
cat who care about nothing just
attacking you know don't you know the
people don't have like principle or
ethic they don't think anymore you just
you know lots of things you know then
then you have the you have one of the
most important consequence is
divide you know divide you divide people
in our nation for example USA into you
know right right-wing or left-wing each
one only see their you know like Bobo
did you call it bubble you know each one
only see their opinions you know they
don't see you don't see anything outside
of it why what does that happen because
each of this YouTube Twitter Facebook
when you go to youtube they only show
you what you liked based on you know
your past experience why they do that
because when you only see what you like
you like it more so so you only see what
you like to see you don't see opinions
that you don't like you know outside so
so eventually so it becomes you know so
us a people becomes very very narrow of
you you know you only see thing one you
know you only see one thing you know
that's what happens so there's a
question component five Matt five says
what do you think about
subscription-based model or SaaS what is
what is that
so some service or something
well the subscription-based model is
good okay that's fantastic that's the
best however the situation is that it's
not it's not working because most people
they are so used to three things I mean
the free concept is kind of the
universal way to get people to it's kind
of like everyone love three things I
mean we have the phrase there's no free
lunch okay it becomes so popular I mean
it's a human nature everyone just want
to take things for free whenever there's
three things immediately you become
popular this is also why open source and
free software foundation they become
popular because actually because it's
it's free meaning you don't have to pay
the moment open source of whistle where
the moment you actually have to pay
for every software immediately free
software will die open-source we--it I
like wiped out what immediately the next
day the the [ __ ] almond sauce
ideology [ __ ] they don't they don't
believe they don't realize this the the
reason you know the major what the most
important reason that three so firm
foundation the idea ideology or the
open-source ideology
the most important reason they survive
okay
they are kind of all of you okay believe
me believe me believing in it it's
because they are actually free meaning
you don't have to pay okay
if tomorrow every open source of free
software you have to pay for it yet you
have to pay to get Linux immediately the
idea will be killed will be dead okay
there's a [ __ ] open-source ideology
[ __ ] they are believing the the you
know fantasy that is a reason free
software and open source they they
thrive but however they say oh because
we are you know of be a free free us you
know for yours free speech not PL [ __ ]
no you you are here because it because
free P oh that's that is why you are
still here without free PA you'll be
dead nobody will use it okay the the
concept of soft so three things is one
way is one of the most fundamental core
human psychology that that gets
something popular okay that's that's a
phenomenal thing that is also why tech
you know Donald Knuth tech latech
becomes very popular refused to die it's
one of the worst technology okay big big
but is everywhere it's also part of the
reason many of the UNIX systems and C
programming languages see they strive
because three okay meaning you don't
have to pay that is or engine how they
become popular okay so that's so what
what were we talking about
I was talking about something else
before that came the branch into this
free thing oh yeah what do you
think about subscription-based model
okay now that's a good idea
because because you know if you want
something you pay for it okay then you
the quality is good such as Apple
product you know when you buy Apple
everything is good I mean even they do
Evo and stuff but but they're the
software their hardware is just good you
know it's just good same thing with you
know Microsoft is it's not as as good
but it's still you know on the other
hand on Linux everything is up to
yourself first of all you spend two
years to you know to be a nerd to know
how Linux works then you can install
Linux like the go up the boot that this
is the disk partition then you know then
you learn you know yeah that's that's
when you use Linux your mom cannot use
it okay you have to be a nerd first
spend two years to be a nerd
so anyway what about subscription-based
model I think that's good but but the
its kind it kind of failed it didn't
pick up because because somewhat because
of the nature of the web you know we are
used to three websites we don't want to
pay nobody like like am an open source I
hear a lot okay I'm an open source and
free software phonetics they say or even
sometimes they tell me my website you
know ah don't you know like we would
donate we're happy to donate don't you
know we don't want ads you know we happy
to donate you but but actually in
reality nobody do what nobody does okay
the moment I put ads I have 100 times
money then no ads then then just
donation because I I had that you know I
was dying of hunger I had that nobody
nobody actually do anything but they all
say the open-source [ __ ] phonetic
they all say oh we actually love to
donate if you don't have ads will donate
you know that's not true
you actually anyone knows the fact the
truth if you actually really if you
actually you know if you run a company
trying to do open source immediately
right right away you realize nothing
works
what you thought is all wrong not you
you cannot survive okay no donation
nothing that you know it's contrary to
what you want to believe there are so
many stories but they get buried over
the past 20 years you don't hear it
because every time you post you have
that story negative about ovince or
someone you know some really believe who
believed in open source who will try to
run a company
but run into all kind of problems then
eventually they close down for example
think TB the the math software by this
mathematician based on Python you know
what's the name I can find it you know I
have a vlog about it lots of stories
lots of you don't hear because every
time you post on a canoes reddit people
vote it down that's what happens you
know then it part part of you did has to
do with these commercialization Fox you
have this like a dislike thing instead
of saying opinions you have this like
and it's like people wrote it down so
you don't get to see it so you're
leaving a bubble you know then less and
less people everyone's is the open
source phonetic so back to the substrate
subscription-based model that's a good
thing but I don't but because of partly
because the kind of the nature of the
web everyone is just used to free things
so they don't want to pay okay and also
because the web everyone can just copy
like I spent years reading my tutorials
Emacs Oh JA var script you know
JavaScript in depth I spent like almost
basically full time for two years all my
MX and eMac this tutorial I spent you
know you can say food you know if you
say food you know basically I wrote my
Emacs and eMac this Victoria for 15
years you can say basically one hour a
day on average
so maybe full-time three years full-time
but once you wrote it everyone can copy
it they can just they see you know oh
this is how how this works
they just rephrase it and become some
Wikipedia and become some Stack Overflow
but what can you do
there's nothing you can do I mean on the
other hand you cannot say oh you are
wrong you know because it's really
information I mean you don't want to say
you know you see open information you
spend a time you help other people you
know but but then it does happen there
there are all these people and sometimes
intentional and that sometimes naively
you know they just copy your stuff and
it becomes on Wikipedia so you don't
make money no money
I looked into how much money program a
book writer can make you know I have a
article somewhere you know if you just
such sorry
how much author makes you know I
researched if you are for example if you
write a JavaScript book javascript is
the most popular language if you write a
JavaScript book and if that book is
number one top seller in JavaScript okay
how much you make yeah maybe $1,000 a
month maybe four five months for a year
one 1000 for one year okay now if you
are a software engineer if you are
intern at Google you make [ __ ] 10
10,000 a month so so book writers in
Tosa matter how good you are even if if
you are a number one seller you don't
make you don't make money that's that's
when you are making writing books for
all righty for example all righty but if
you are like me just ready on tutorial
then you don't get nothing you know you
don't get nothing and people yeah so
there's a lot these issues sub sink
subscription is good but nobody but it's
kind of hard to get it moving
so Matt says I think I got you by the
way sorry I'm not against
subscription-based service but it's sad
that this becomes the standard and not
all these services are fair to the users
this becomes the standard what do you
mean I don't see what you mean
so dingo says the whole thing assumes
software is a good thing why would you
be dead broke and maintained Sophia
anyway I think I'm talking too long I'm
you know I think I'm talking to though
I'm getting hot and one hour and 40
minutes so that's it for today yeah
imagine every YouTube channel was not
free trigger words but you would need to
pay a subscription to every channel if
you have to pay your subscription if you
have to pay a subscription for
everything that market would break down
as nobody could afford to subscribe to
100 different things they want they need
well I don't know I don't understand why
is Google censoring this you know there
is no swearing word in this post why is
you know Google has become so [ __ ]
these [ __ ] social justice facts their
idea why are they saying this this
comment I have no idea like yeah so
thank you guys for watching now I got 20
videos done 20 watches and 21 watches
anyway that's it for today bye guys I
you know I have 1000 videos so I can you
know press the buttons and say apply so
that I part you know so I can monetize
on my YouTube but I'm not sure you know
I'm just so many things going on
politics you know I just I'm not sure
about that on one hand I talk about
sensitive issues and I swear you know so
Google is gonna do monetize me even if I
have if I have it on it's probably gonna
happen often well also if I try to make
my account monetize then then you know
then if Google shut me down in it it
becomes Google we are watching more
carefully because now now you are
monetized Google will start to start to
watch it you know watch every every [ __ ]
you say every you know every anti social
justice whatever you say or men men and
women you know they will start to watch
it more closely then you know
I get more problems because if they
Google shut me down they shouldn't like
Gmail and my my website account down
that would be bad you know because that
would be bad so I need to actually I
need to do backup I need to move out of
Gmail I need to there's so many things
I'd need to do but I don't have I don't
have lots of means to do it so anyway we
see up what happens okay who knows who
knows that what the future lies we'll
see bye guys