Good morning. Good morning everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Sound Talk
Show. We are coding emacis today. Uh
it's going to be eag session. So I'm
going to code it and meanwhile also
explain. So this is for those of you
programmers who are interested in Emacs
lisp the programming language for text
processing. Emac this is the best
programming language for text
processing. If you are watching this
offline, play at 1.5 speed because I
ramble and skip around because I go all
over. If you are here, say hi. Love to
see your comments. Okay, my keyboards
glove 80. Fantastic. Ultimate hacking
keyboard fantastic. Newly attractable.
Fantastic. Logitech 455. Got the spin
wheel
502.
Fantastic. And uh my hands are suffering
from hand pen so much because I typed so
much. So I'm going to try to use this
again. Uh it's been a year delay. I
haven't done so yet. So this is called
board. S V A L B O A R D with mag
magnetic walls. Fantastic. This is going
to save me but I haven't done it yet cuz
I got so much uh coding to do. So now
let's begin. Uh okay. So play at 1.5
speed if you are into uh programming. So
otherwise this video is not interesting
to you. Okay. So let's begin. So this is
a continuation from from about uh three
weeks
ago. Well, has it been well about last
week? So last week we did we tried to do
it. We didn't finish. So we're going to
continue this. Okay. So let me show you.
Uh so I'm okay. Let's just start to code
quickly. Okay. So paste that actually.
So start a emac list block of code.
Paste it there. Pop it out. Uh, pop it
out. Okay. So, CSS code. So, what we
want to do, uh, put it
back. What we want to do is, okay, let
me show you quickly. So, JavaScript. So,
I've been working on JavaScript a lot.
My JavaScript in-depth
tutorial because JavaScript every year
there's a new version. So, I've been lag
lagging behind for like three years. So
there is a lot news in JavaScript. So
I'm working on it on it. Lots of update,
huge amount update in path past month.
So okay, but what is it we going to do?
So if you look at this uh is finite
function in JavaScript. So there's this
topic box. So let's go there. Okay, I'm
going to go faster. Okay, let me do it
quickly. So you got this topic box.
So on my website there are 10,000 HTML
files. So on certain pages you have this
topic box dive topic Excel. Okay, it
looks like that and this is a group a
group of
related pages. So when you are reading
about JavaScript is finite a function.
So you might want to know about what is
undefined. You might want to know about
what is new. So they are related topics.
Okay. So let's go to uh undefined. Okay.
So let's uh use that page as an example.
So um okay. So let's paste a link here.
So we have a record of what we are
talking about. Now let me show you
another page. Okay.
uh
go lang my go language tutorial. Okay.
So you go to uh my go language tutorial.
You go to
[Music]
um find and replace. So this script will
do find replace on 10,000 files or more
uh of multiple find replace pairs. You
can do it one shot. So this is in
written in Goland. I use it every day.
So at the bottom you'll also see find
replace scripts. So they are available
in Goland. So this is find string web
you know just find node replace. Then
you got got find replace multiple pairs
of regular expression in directory. Then
you got Python. This is how you write it
in Python. Okay. And then you got um you
got pearl version. Pearl version is
written around year 2000. Okay. So you
got the per pearl version. Then you got
emac version. So so so the point here is
I got this topic box. Topic box. So you
see they are related pages. Uh allows
for convenient navigation.
Uh okay.
So okay so let's uh yeah so let's
actually go to the go find replace. Okay
so let's paste there. So if you go to
the go language find replace go to the
bottom search for topic. So you see this
is a topic box. Each page may be in a
different directory. So what what is a
task? What I want to do is that go
through search for 10,000 files all my
HTML files find this dive class topic
okay
then so this topic you know there are
hundreds of topic boxes but but this
group of
pages are one set they are all related
by this uh they they are about find
replace scripts okay so they are like
hundreds of topic boxes is but they can
be they are grouped into sets. So this
this is one set among the 10,000 pages.
So what I want to do basically is to
want uh I want to add ID. Okay. So ID
equals to something. So for
a for this one group uh one partition
you know this set of topic box they all
should be they all should have the same
ID. Okay. So that is what we are doing.
Uh we uh you know I explained in my last
talk show uh on May
3rd 2025. Okay. So let's begin to code
it. Okay. So so go to Emac
Lisp. Okay. So let's see. So we're going
to do it one file first. Okay. We we
wrote this last time. Go through go
through the web directory. 10,000 HTML
files. For each one, find the dive class
topic Excel. Then add an uh add an ID
attribute ID equals to something. Then
for each of the page link in the topic
box, same ID must be
used. Okay. So let's um let's
see. So for each of these file you know
whatever the ID you are using that needs
to go there. Okay.
So okay that's a task. Okay. So let's
um uh
let's okay
so so that's a task and let's do it.
Okay. So this define a function this
will process one file uh of a given file
path you know. So we write this function
to process one file then we'll write a
another function that traverse the
directory that goes through 10,000
files and for each file call this
function. Okay so this is just for one
file. So we declare a hasht uh hasht
test equal and uh so with temp buffer
this is how
you quickly open a file for read this is
the most efficient okay with temp buffer
so you with temp buffer then insert file
content file path then go to point mean
beginning of the file then declare some
variables then search for word for this
topic and h4 H4. H4 is the
um basically I was using it as ID. H4 is
the header. Okay. So you find that
pattern then you set X begin for the
beginning position of this dive. Then
you go to the beginning position. Then
you forward one character move to the
right. Then SGML skip tag forward. That
will jump to
So if your cursor here it will jump to
here. Okay.
So you see uh wait uh okay so selected
uh
wait what selected okay you see
so that you know go to the beginning or
end that's what this that's what this
skip x sgml skip tag for what okay so
you go to the bottom then you set end to
the end of the dive. Then you grab the
text. This set text a substring
beginning end. You grab that dive text.
Okay. Then we start to add it to a hash
table. Okay. So, but there's one more
thing I want to do. Okay. I want to grab
the title.
So, the title is between H4. So in this
case that's going to be
um title. Okay. Uh let's put it here. X
title. So X title will be set X title
match string. Okay. Match string is how
you extract the the group in a regular
expression. This part.
So the first one, yes, that's the first
one. Optional string, we don't care
about that. Pify the code. So that is
it. So you got a title. So now we start
to push it to a hash table. This table
thing.
Okay. Uh check if it exists. If not,
add. Okay. So what I want to do um you
see I'm serving hand pen here and
actually not you know right hand too. So
typing too
much. So am I going? Let's check. Let me
let me check. Five people watching.
Okay. Say hi. Okay. If you have
questions, just ask me. Okay. So the
pink window shows all my command calls
such as moving cursor or delete uh or
delete. You know, they update in real
time. And the left hand side is the
keystroke I'm using. I'm
using softly keys. Okay. Uh this package
which is the most efficient keybinding
for Emacs. You can get it for free on
GitHub. Okay.
So, so now let's begin to add it to hash
table. Check if you know. So add to hash
table. Check
if check if exist. If not add but if
exists push.
Okay. Okay. So that's uh
so so X key. So what is X
key X table? Okay. So X key val why
don't we highlight it? So key val is get
hash to see if it's in a hash table. If
there's a value and not neo you know
otherwise it return neil. So if it is in
the hash table
you the value. Okay. So in the hash
table the key what would the key
be? Uh let's see. Let's say let's change
something. Okay. Um the key should be I
think the key should be the title should
it the key should be the
title then the value would be uh yeah
the value would
be the value would be a list of file
path containing that topic box. Okay. So
the key key vow. Okay.
So so actually this should be just named
the key not key vow. Okay.
So wait this is this means the keys
value. Okay. So value of a key. So get
hash check if it's there. So if it is
there then put hash. I don't want to put
the text you want to put the title.
Okay, that's a key. So push app put put
into the hash table with this key. Then
value
is add the file path. That's right.
Uh now what does push return? Last time
we tried to check it, we forgot uh
because it's not well documentated
documented. So let's see what what does
um push return. Let's try it. So three
uh
list one, two, three. Okay, so nice. So
evaluated
uh void function. Okay, so what? Oh, the
this needs to be a variable in order to
use push. Okay, so let
um
let
xx okay is a
list. So that sets xx to be a list. Then
you push. So let's see what it returns.
Okay. Okay. So it returns the full
result list. Okay. And uh now but what
what does um yeah once you push I think
the variable is also changed. So let's
try
that. Yep. Okay. So that's that's some
test. Okay.
So okay. So this push returns the whole
list. That's what we want. You push
put hash to uh wait this is not this
table this is title
okay so put hash title is a key then the
value it already exist you add it
to you add the file path to the val
existing value to this table correct
okay now you need you don't you only
have a single line. So you don't need
that P R O GN. Now if it does not exist
then it's easy.
So push the title and create a list of
single item file path to a table. Okay.
Fantastic. Now okay so now this is
adding to the hash table. Wow. I think
isn't that already done?
Then
uh so let's compact this a little
bit. Okay. So that's so far so good that
we'll push to the hash table. So after
this function is called we
got hash table.
Okay. So we can try that. So let's let's
try that. Okay. So clean up the
code. Uh so this we don't care. Clean up
the code. Now let's add
a let's add a lexical
binding. Okay. So make a backup. Go to
the
directory. Uh delete all these backup
files. I've been working on JavaScript a
whole lot.
And uh
this make a
backup compile bite compile it
successful no
error I do bad compile so because when
you do bite compile it we will report
you know syntactical errors or other so
no error so that's good so now we can
try to run this yeah okay so let's try
to run it okay so
So call that and you need a file path
now. So let's find a file path. This
one. Okay. File path. So once you do
that, it should create a hash table with
um how many item? Let's see. Go find
string hash table of one single item
because there's only one D box.
Okay. Yeah.
So, but how but so you need to print the
hash table otherwise you wouldn't know.
So, so yeah. So,
now let's say
messages hasht is okay. So, X table.
Okay, good. Evaluate that code. Then now
run this code. Fantastic. Go to the
messages buffer. Here is the
result. Fantastic. Because we got a hash
table and we got item and the key is
find replace script which is this
title. Correct. And the value is this
file path. Correct. Okay. So that worked
for one file. Now let's try some other
file. Other file that's got more than
one topic box. Okay. So click close
that. Uh okay.
So keys need to mention it. That's the
best package I've done. Check it out. Uh
so this we don't care de blog. Uh where
actually uh okay. So
undefined you want to find some page
that has more than one topic
box. Okay. So where do you find that? I
know uh in array JavaScript array array
prototype because there you have lots of
array methods. Uh so for example let's
say map there it is. Okay. So the array
map function in JavaScript, you got
related topics about loop and iteration.
Then you got array prototype box. You
got two box. Fantastic. So copy that. Go
back
here. Uh JavaScript undefined. Paste it
that there. There. Okay. So Oh yeah. So
we want copy the file of path.
Close. Go to the code.
Paste it there. Okay. Copy. Paste.
Delete. That that that that. Okay. Now
this run. Okay. Now let's look at what's
a hash
table.
Uh it seems to show only one hash table.
I mean only one entry. Why is
that? Okay. So this this
um it seems to show only one
hash entry
uh JavaScript loop iteration. So that's
the first one, but it skipped the second
one. Oh, I know why. Of course,
obviously, because you are not doing a
loop. You see, once you found it, you
add it, then you stopped. So, you need a
while loop.
Okay. Okay. So, let's add a while
loop.
Yeah.
While while you search forward that
thing, then what do you do? Then you do
this.
thing. Okay. Pify the
code. Okay. While search
forward then set up a bunch of
variables then
um yeah as long as search forward when
it's found it will return true. So um so
let's see what ar what par what
arguments I have neot.
So bound Neo no error
true. Yes. Okay. Yeah. So that's
correct. Evaluate it. Okay. Wait the the
the wait this this print message should
be outside of the while loop.
Okay. There. Okay. Evaluate the code. Go
down. Go to this one.
evaluated show message spuffer. So you
got one key entry then you got second
key entry.
Fantastic. Now this hasht this is hasht
literal expression. It's hard to read.
Let's print the hasht one entry per
line. Okay. So how do you do that? I
forgot it. I I forgot it's uh building
or not. Uh okay. Okay. So, why is this
um is it too small to read? Uh let's
increase it. Okay. Hold on a
second. Am I doing good? Am I doing
good? Say hi
guys. Okay. So, this basics that's
correct. This is Lisp programming
language fundamentals. You want to go to
the data structure. Then you want to go
to the hash table. So hash table, you
want to print the hash
table. Check key exist. Remove all
entries. Apply a function to all
entries. Uh yeah, you can do
that. Uh do I have a print pretty print
hasht there? So kasa format hasht. Okay,
so actually I have that command.
Okay. And uh let's look up the
documentation. It will format it and
uh Okay. And you just print that. Okay.
So, okay. Let's do that. Now, that is
inside Elisp utilities. Okay. this uh
print and this eaglist utilities use you
can also get it free it's you can
download it there okay so copy the file
path close that go to the talk
show paste it there emac this utility
okay so that's good to
know and go back to the
code and here we just want to print it.
So, so messages is just um actually we
can just say
print. Okay. Uh do we need format? No.
So, because it's all here in nice
predefine the code. Evaluate the code.
Evaluate the code. Okay. the wrong
number of
arguments. Oh yeah. So yeah, of course
we forgot to give the table
arguments. Print evaluate the code.
Evaluate the code. Show in browser. I
mean show the message buffer. Fantastic.
So you got you see you got two hasht
entries.
Fantastic. Now what we want to do is we
want to go through a entire directory of
files. Okay. So that is traverse
directory. So how do you do it? Close
that. So you want to traverse directory
which um that would be
emacisp section chapter. Then um
traverse directory would be let's
see buffer file file directory get file
info walk directory there. Okay so copy
that
uh paste that. So we have a record you
guys can check out later. So you want to
list all files in a directory
recursively. Yes. Okay. So get this one
uh directory file recursively. There's a
sample code. Let's use a sample
code list directory and all sub
subdirectory. Okay, that's the one we
want. It returns a list.
Okay, so go back to the code. Now if you
want to traverse the directory. Okay, so
this this directory and all subdirectory
of files extension eel. No, not eel. We
want
HTML. Ignore the whose names start with
dot.
Okay, that's that's this. Okay,
so right and uh give a file path. Okay,
so you need a file path. So this path
JavaScript directory. Okay, remove that.
Okay, html files. Then skip dot
skipfiles. Okay, so that returns a list
of all files in a directory and
subd. Okay, once you got that, then you
just want to map this function to every
file path. Okay, so that you can do map
C and map C is this
function lambda. uh we can actually just
call the function.
Okay. Yes, this function and the
sequence is just this thing.
Okay. Okay, that seems it. Uh evaluate
that code. Let's let's um Okay, evaluate
that code. Then we can call this now.
That should
um now make sure now since we are
traversing the directory we don't need
to print because wait
uh because the okay so you
actually you can this won't work because
every time this function is
called it recreate the hash table.
So, so that won't work. You need
actually to move this hash table
out. Yeah. Okay. Teddy. Okay. Uh, yeah,
you need, you
know, Okay. So, yeah. Can we do that?
Yeah. And let's say define v
um define v x table option initial value
neo
hasht key
is
title value is list
of file
path. Fantastic.
Now set X
table. Uh so initially make a hash
table. Okay. Then you don't need this
part and uh actually then you don't need
uh this
part. Okay. So then you don't need the
let anymore. So actually delete
it. Pify the code.
Okay. So, we got this
um snail. We set it fresh. Then you
Okay. So, let's do
it. Okay. So, let's see.
Then then you don't want to print it.
Okay. So let's
see. No. So remove
that.
Okay. Remove that. Fantastic
code. And uh where do we want to print
the hash table? No. No. So once you've
done that, you print the hash table. Is
that right?
Yes. So once you recurse the directory
call this function on each one. So this
basically this function basically go
through a file and build a hash
table. Okay. Then
you print it. Okay. Now let's double
check one more time. We have the hash
table. Yeah, that's that's good. So
evaluate. So make a backup. Go to make
byte compile. So you got some
warning. Dynamic variable X table lacks
a prefix. You see that's kind of
um you know it's kind of warning. It
wants a prefix. Okay. Yeah. Okay. Let's
add a
prefix. Uh because Emacs doesn't have
name space. So that's why it require
everything to have like a
prefix. Uh okay. So let's change the X
table name
to X dash table. Okay. Do it. Do it. Do
it. Do it. Okay.
Now, now this part.
Um let's remove those. Okay. Let's
remove those.
Go to the directory by compile
successful no error. Delete it. Go back
here. Run the code. So it's running the
whole
thing. Good morning guys. How are you
doing? Fantastic things going on in the
world, especially artificial
intelligence and
uh uh wait, it's already done. I forgot
that it's already done. So, go to the
messages buffer. So, you can see wow.
So, we actually got a whole lot of hasht
entries you can see. So, let's
highlight. So
actually copy it new buffer paste it and
uh stop that. Let's see all the hash
table entries
starting.
Uh okay. So that's all the hash table
entries.
It's
fantastic. So now let's check some of
them.
The file path uh should contain more
than one entry. So let's
see. Let's highlight
it. Okay. So all these are just one
entry. Uh so
uh one entry would not be right. Okay.
So
wait, so each
key some of the this key should have
more than one. I mean their value is a
list. So some of them the list should
contain more than one item. Are we
seeing
it? No.
ACP. Hello. Any comment on the new pope?
Uh, not really.
Uh I don't pay attention to that too
much because I'm not Christian and I'm
not Catholic and Pope you know that it's
a
Christianity thing that is for western
society Europe Europeans the the god the
Christianity the religion is like the
central history of Europeans.
Because the in a religion Christianity
you have a king and that king is called
pope. And for most of the past a
thousand or more
years, the head of
the church, the pope is also like the
king, the the the the leader of the of
the nation or even continent.
So there's huge amount of fight
and and lots of other things you know.
So but in the past 100 or two years that
kind of went away that power
structure. So now you have a
pope which is semantically still the
head of the Catholic branch of
Christianity. but does not have real
like like like serious political power
such as like controlling a military and
stuff but it's still someone people look
up to because religion you know so
so you know and they have you know
that's part of human history of the
western people's history because it's
you know for the past 200 on 2,000 or
more years. So they have rituals, they
have, you know, they have like rituals
and and the rules to select the new pope
and stuff. I don't know much about it.
So okay so we are trying to determine if
our code actually does the right thing
but you see but let's
see so if we go to this array prototype
map you see there are two topic
boxes. So if we search for iteration
they should have this list you know a
list of all these entries. So search
for loop iteration. So loop
uh no it
doesn't. Is it because my print hash is
just printing one items? This doesn't
sound right. You see it's only got one
entry. Okay. So that's not right. So
delete that. D that. Now maybe my print
hash table function is not
correct.
Um. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. Let's just write
it. My let's write our Okay. Uh well,
okay. So, let's look at it. So, map hash
p map hash lambda key
values.
Um I think it should be correct. I think
my I think actually my code is
incorrect. So, key value format key and
value. So value format to a string.
Value may is a list format to a string.
It should contain multiple items if it
does. So my code for print hash is
correct. I think our code here is
incorrect. Okay. because it uh so search
forward for that topic
then get title begin position end
position and get text uh actually we
don't need the text
part okay
so oh wait oh that's why this should be
title that's why it's
Check for title, not the text. Okay. In
fact, I don't I don't need the text.
Okay.
So, it's very annoying that in lisp you
don't have a way to comment out a word.
You know, if you want to do that, you
have to like comment out a line like
that. Kind of annoying. Okay. So
anyway, let's just delete the text.
Okay, we don't need
it. Prefy the code. Okay,
so remove the comment.
Okay. Okay. So evaluate that. Actually
we can evaluate the whole thing.
Evaluate the
whole show message buffer. So you got
copy it new buffer and uh so you
highlight that
part. There it is. Okay. So wait, close
it. Reopen it. Now
highlight this.
Okay.
Fantastic. So you can see for each hash
key you do have several items.
Fantastic. So we are
successful.
Uh fantastic. So let me make a
screenshot of it.
actually forget
it. Okay, just close it. Okay, so go
back here. Go to the code. So it's
building the hash table successfully.
Now what do you want to do
next?
[Music]
Um so actually yeah so you now you got a
hash table. Now you can go through the
hash table and
uh so for each
[Music]
key you know so we can actually start to
um do the find and
replace you know. So yeah, so what we
can do is
that right so for each key so let's go
to hasht. Um how do you how do you do
hasht? Okay. So, showing
browser. Yeah. Not there.
What? Okay. So, go back to hasht
practical emac this. No. This basics.
Yes.
Hashtable there. So, you want to map
through hasht. So, the function
is map hash. Okay.
So map
hash. Okay. So you map hash table
to this table. And what is the lambda?
What function you want to do? So for
each hash key. So this is key. This is
value. So for each key. So what body? So
body.
Okay. So actually so let's start a
let so for each
[Music]
key for each key of the hash
table. Okay. So actually you do
need you do need the full text not just
the
title. Uh you
got so
the you see so we got the
um topic box like that. So for
each. Okay. So I want to capture the
entire text instead of just the title.
Okay. So for each
key then you go through you open each
file of
that you know the the the keys value is
a list of file path. So for each
key you get their list of file path. You
open each
one. You open each one and search for
for the text on of that in that
file. Then at the at the then you add
attribute of a unique ID. Okay. So
something like that. So first of all, so
map hash let uh random string. Okay. So
let's say random string uh you need to
set a random
string random. Okay. So
uh random. So let's
say this means hexadimal.
So this actually you know this means
hexadimal input number. So hexad decimal
of 1 2 3 4 five six seven digits. Okay.
So if we so if we run it you see you're
going to get a like a number. You see
run it run it run it run it. Okay then.
But you want to format into hexadimal.
Okay. So you
format and the X. Okay. And put that
there. Okay. So you run it, run it, run
it. You can see. Run it. Run it. Run it.
It give you seven digit hex a
decimal.
Uh, okay. So that's a random string.
Okay.
So, let's let's do it here. Okay. So
actually
set rand string. Okay, let's just say
ID. Okay, ID is this random string.
So you got
ID.
Now for each key you want to get a
value. Okay.
So okay this is going to get
complicated. Map
C the value is a
list. So let's rename
it so it's easier to understand. XV
means file path.
Okay. So for each key map hash then then
then then for each
um you generate ID
then for each file path you need to open
it. Oh Jesus, this is getting big. You
need to open the file. So you need to,
you know, use temp
buffer. Okay, I don't think I can finish
this because this is a big task. You
know we are
uh so let me
just you see
so so for each hasht
key you do this you generate the
ID unique ID then for each of the file
path file path you open it create a temp
buffer insert the file path contents
into it you go to the beginning of the
buffer. Then you
search you search
for you know you you search for uh for
example uh what's the example
undefined you search for this title
actually so you basically you want to
search for search for this. So anyway,
let's we need to make some changes to
our code. So instead of using the title
as key, I want you use the whole text
block as key. Okay. So let's add back
that X
text. We don't need it much. Okay. So X
text is the is the actual body.
dive text. Okay, let's just say that
dive
text. Uh, okay, we deleted our previous
code. Now we want it
back.
So, yeah. Okay, so beginning end. Okay,
easy to set.
set dive text buffer substring no
properties. Okay, so that's how you
capture that dive
block. Uh so let's rename
it dive block.
Okay. So you capture it then use this D
block as a
um as a uh as your hash key. Okay. So
not title you get the D
block. Okay. Put hash
that. So your key is actually this whole
big string.
Okay? Because this
way once you got the hash table
then then when you want to modify it all
you have to do is just search for the
entire D block because if you search the
title it might you know some other place
might contain that phrase then you got
to the wrong place. So you want D block.
Another way is
actually actually more efficient is that
when
you you know add to the hash table, you
also save the beginning and end
position. So later on you don't have to
search for that text anymore. Just go
jump, you know, just replace this by a
new
one. Actually, that would be
good. That's uh Yeah.
So, so D block is a
[Music]
key. The value is not just the file
path, but the value is a list and each
element is
the file path and beginning and end
position. How about
that? That will be good.
[Music]
Uh oh god my
hand hands like right
here is hurting because typing
Let's have some chocolate. God diva qual
elite chocolate.
Okay. What are we doing here? Is this
trouble worth it? That's the question.
You see, I need to do this for
myself. Um, this is going to be a
one-time script because once I do it, I
don't need it anymore. Once I added the
ID to through all these D
block. So but however the the list code
is getting slightly complicated. I mean
I can do it you
know you see but uh it's interesting the
other way is do not write the do not
write the emac this
script instead you try to do this
interactively because the full power of
emacs and
gm so for example I can search in this
directory this directory of javascript
is
got 900 files. Okay, n 900
files. I can search for, you know,
search for that. For example, let me
show
you. So now you got a list of all these
files. You can go down. You can, you
know, press enter to open any one of
them. You can
see. So, and you can list all the files.
So here are all the
files. Okay, there are 500 files. 511
files that contains a topic
box. So you can get you see
so and this is
interactive you know then all you can
say is
that you know for example I can I can
show you okay open that showing browser
this is about creating a dark theme
in in CSS okay I have showed many times
for example if we go on powershell
Oh, toggle talk theme. You see CSS?
Fantastic. Now, toggle it
back. So, so but you go to the bottom,
you can see all these topic boxes,
right? So,
now if I want to, I can do this
interactively. what we wanted. So, copy
that. Call this command which is find
replace text. Okay. Paste. That's what
we want to find. Enter. And what to
replace? Well, replace by
uh the ID. Let's say
that. Okay. Now, enter this directory.
Yes.
Enter. All HTML files extension. Yes.
Enter. Write changes to file. Yes or no?
Let's say no. Okay. So you can see this
is the result if you were to change it.
Three files exactly. One, two, three. Or
you can navigate by the file path. You
see? So do it again.
That's repeat complex command. Now let's
just say write to file. Yes, do it.
Okay. Now go here. Open it. Show in
browser dark theme. Go to the
bottom. You can't tell the difference,
but you you look at the code. You can
see you can see it's got a uh ID.
So this is doing this interactively much
simpler and meanwhile as you do it you
can check for the validity of what you
are
doing you know for example if I can call
this command which is html
validate all files in a directory do
it so that means all the 1,000 files in
this directory is
valid. But if you just add, for example,
if you just add greater equal sign
there, save it. Close it. Close
it. And okay, close this. And uh and
what is this? Close it.
Uh close it. Okay. Back to this, you
know. So now you call
uh wait what uh HTML validate. Okay. So
call validate
again. So validate
uh XML directory tab ur. Okay. So do it
in JavaScript
directory. It will tell you there's an
error. There it is.
HTML XML error at this file. Open it.
Then you see that's why. So if you do if
I do this, you know, delete that. If I
do this interactively, you can check for
your errors or whatever. you know, you
can go as you um do
it and you don't have to know you don't
have you don't need like one year or two
years of EMAC this
experience such as what I'm trying to
code here.
The advantage of writing a script is of
course once you got it it's one shot you
know 10,000 files it's all done but if
you do this manually like interactively
it'll take a bit more time like 3 hours
uh
yeah so is this
interesting damse hello damse try I
think maybe we stop here okay we u
So you know I can do this manually
or or I can do this
um you know like a script but the
script needs one more one more hour of
work.
Um yeah. So so we are already 1 hour. So
I think we stop
here and go this is going to be so let's
clean up just a little bit. Okay.
So so for each hasht so right now so
with the D block is the hasht key.
Okay. And uh then yeah, so we were
thinking of pushing the pushing the
beginning end
position. Yeah. More code. Uh
then then we insert file. We didn't do
anything. Uh but actually what we want
to do is search for Yeah. Search for the
key. So this
key is dive block.
Okay. So now you just search for the die
block. Okay. Search for
that. And
uh option of bound bound neo no error
should be true. No error should be false
because there should it should find it
otherwise it's an error. So remove
that. So you search
forward that that will find the dive
block. Then you need to search backward
so that you go to you know it will
search for like the cruiser will end at
the end. Then you need to go to the
beginning of the block then search for
the topic then insert that. Okay. So we
almost done.
So, should we push
on trying to work on some lead code
questions? Uh, that's good. That's good
for you. Programming
exercise. Uh, okay.
So you
see so actually what I want to do is
actually since we are doing it we want
to I want to add the beginning and
position to the file path. So you don't
so you avoid this inefficiency of
searching for the text block and then
like go back to the beginning you know
you have to search backward again for
the
topic but if you just add
that it will be uh yeah it will be
extremely more efficient. Okay let's add
that.
Okay. So, beginning end position. So,
for
each value of a hasht key, you don't
want just to add a file path. You want
to
add Okay, here's what you want to add a
vector. Okay, a vector is like a tuple
in Python.
Okay, so vector a file path and begin
position and end position.
Okay,
fantastic. And similarly here. So, oh
yeah, so it's actually easier if you
just actually do it. Okay,
similarly
push this vector to the value of a hasht
key. Oh my god, this is actually easier
than I thought.
So the key of a hash table is a list and
each element of a list is a vector and
the vector will be file path beginning
position and position. Okay. So once you
do that then for each hasht
key you just then the
value you just
um you just um create a ID you don't
actually don't even do it there so
actually
uh open the file path okay the file path
okay wait this is
wrong. So this should be value
uh hash value.
Okay. What should
be file data? Okay.
something like find out
data.
So yeah, I need to
break. So actually just let me do it.
Okay.
So file data data and this would
be this would be
uh
vector vector you want to get the first
element. Okay, that would be the file
path. Uh okay. So actually so let me
create
a yeah actually
uh this is the file path. Okay. File
path would
be set. file
path would be
that the first element of array is the
file path. Then you need
begin. Okay, beginning end. Uh you set
beginning position
is
array first. Okay. Then do the same for
the
end
array two. You see these three lines is
how you get the file path and beginning
and end position. Now there's a better
way to do this. That would
be sequence set. Okay. So let's do
that sequence set file path beginning
end and that would be
uh what is array of file
data file data vector. Okay. So
that you see.
So so you see
um these three lines is equivalent to
this line. So this much
better. Fantastic.
So delete delete delete delete.
Predefine the code. That's what we will
do.
So you got a file path, you got the
beginning, you got end position, you got
file data
vector from this um from this vector.
That's right. Then you map a lambda
um and uh you insert the file path
content. Then you don't need to go to
the beginning anymore. You you just go
to X
begin. Uh actually you don't even need
that. You you just delete the block. Oh
god.
Very Yeah. So you open the
file. That's right. So you open the
file, then you just go to the beginning
position.
Then you just then you just you know
then you just search for
word
that okay then search for word there is
there is search for word
uh what you want to search for okay
um search for word for
this.
Okay.
Then then uh search for word for
that. Then all you have to do is just
insert search for what that
insert. What do you want to insert? You
want to insert space and ID. basically
that. Okay. Format
uh X
ID. Okay. Uh you need to Okay. You need
to escape this
again. Okay. So, let's do that there.
And this is that and
that. Okay. Search for the topic. Then
just
insert insert ID equals to this X
ID. Fantastic.
Now before we do this uh before we do
this I'm not too happy with this ID
because this ID which is hexadimal based
which can get slown okay I you know I
want a shorter
so but you know
uh yeah but let's leave it because then
I you know but you know let me try to
just like complete complete this job so
we are we can be done with this
video. Now the pain comes only when you
are typing. So if I take a break of a
day off it goes away.
uh you know it it happens only when I
started to type a lot
especially when you are not careful like
for example when you have online
argument you know I have online argument
with the nerds about bit dling and other
things so you you know so in your
argument like you are not paying
attention you just want to keep typing
so that's um usually
That's a problem. And also coding does
not
uh
exacerbate you see coding is not really
heavy typing. The
real heavy typing is when you try to
write you know like you know when when
you when you write this you know
um
English that's really heavy typing
because you are doing it continuously
for 10 or 30
minutes you know so most programmers
they don't need you know they don't know
anything about typing really they they
say they type all the time they don't
really you know you you want to check
with
data entry clerks, which is a profession
that no longer exist
today, you know, but I used to be in the
90s, you know, you just type, you know,
like you have to transcribe some some
written text into a computer or via
dictation, you know, a salesman read and
you type it. Uh, back then it's
letters.
So, so anyway, but typist is still you
know very relevant. For example, writing
programming documentation, writing
programming language specification, you
just have to type a lot or writing a
tutorial JavaScript, you know, what is a
property, what is object, what happen,
you have to type tons of text, you have
to type
um a large part of that is solved by
dictation, you know. So I started to use
again for example let me show
you for example we can use Microsoft
dictation. You see
You see dictation is fantastic. It saves
you a lot hand
pain.
Period.
Enter. Now, dictation is also known
as voice typing these days or it was
also known
as speech recognition.
Now, dictation feature these days is
very popular. It's available on Windows,
also available on the Mac or iPad or
iPhone or Android. Of course, if you are
the Zoomer
generation, you know it well on your
phone.
Period. And
uh you know so anyway this is a
demonstration of dictation period.
However, there is a problem that is if
you are trying to write
a programming language
tutorial, then dictation does not work
well because the things you need to say
is
not average daily speech.
you need to talk about properties,
objects,
functions, you know, things like that or
brackets,
braces. So, dictation doesn't
work
well.
Period. Okay. Anyway, so that's that's
the, you know, dictation. I think that's
it for
today. How do you correct? Well, it
depends on you know what what you are
using. Usually you can just manually
click manually correct it or anyway so
you can learn it.
Um yeah. So that's it. Bye guys. Thanks
for watching. So if you like my stuff,
go
to.info. Go to kasadi.info homepage. Go
to the bottom. Donate me. Patreon me.
Amazon gift card me $100. Okay. PayPal
me or you can buy my entire website
$300. I send it the whole uh sadi.info
which is
technical website about programming
about mathematics. There are about 5,000
or
6,000 files articles. Okay. Uh yeah, if
you count images, then it's going to be
like 20,000 files. So there's one person
who sent me uh who bought it. I haven't
sent it to you yet. I will do so tonight
because I need to generate this again. I
don't get much, you know. So So yeah. So
if you like my stuff, pay me. Okay. So
that's it for today. Bye guys.
Uh I hope there's some useful um you
know emac bisp today. So put the code
back syntax color show in browser. So
this is what we have today.
Fantastic. An excursion to text
processing in eacisp which is what
eacisp is most best suited for. more
powerful and more flexible and more
easier to code than any of Python,
Pearl, JavaScript. You know, some people
say Pearl is the best language for text
processing. That's totally forced by a
magnitude because Emacs this got buffers
got you know cousition you can repeat
regular expression you know you can do
lots of things in pearl or python you
got this static
text you know you can't you can't do
much compared to like this. Okay, that's
it.