Good morning. Welcome to another episode
of S talk show. We are going to do
advent of code
2025 day three part two with wufam
language. The fantastic wufam language
the most magnific magnificent a
magnitude higher level than all other
programming languages including Python,
Lisp, Haskell, Rust, F, Julia.
One line of wine language is 10 or 100
lines of Python. Okay. So, Wuam language
you can download it here. Just search
for.info
wam language tutorial you'll find it.
Okay. Uh so let's begin. So aluminum
code. So part two. Okay. Uh now let's
check video check. Yes. Audio check.
Yes. If you are here say hi. If you are
not here, play at 1.5 speed or two times
speed. Okay,
that would be optimal.
So, adv of code. So, let's see. Uh, day
two continue to part two. So, the
problem was advent of code day three was
that um you are given a list of numbers.
Okay, such as like that a list of
numbers. For each number you have to
pick two digits. Okay, it says here. Now
the advanced code is pretty lousy. I
talked about this before. Watch my
previous videos few days ago. Um they
for example their website is hardcoded.
You see you cannot so if you enlarge the
font you also have to enlarge the
window. Also you see they use the dark
theme background. very annoying,
unreadable,
illeible. You know, these people, they
don't know these industrial coders. They
think this is cool. This this looks
cool. But but one way to tell now you
you might be a dark theme fan. But one
way to tell it is not good for your eyes
is that when you do live stream uh v you
know live stream video you can see as
you watch my screen this dark dark theme
is just not good. If you if it's white
background is much more easier to read.
Okay this is one way to tell why dark
theme is actually not good for your
eyes.
So the vent code they they hardcoded
their website layout and they use stock
theme. Okay, this they they got um
issues. Anyway, let's continue. So you
the problem day three is that you are
given a list of numbers. For each number
you want to pick two digits.
Okay, pick two digits. Then you combine
the two digits into a number. You want
to find the maximum. Okay. So for
example this A1 A19 one one two one one
one the result would be 8 N. Okay. Then
for each the two digits you picked for
each number you add them up. Then that
should be your answer for the first
problem. 357
for this example input. Okay. We solved
that yesterday. Today let's go to part
two. Okay, part two. Now, let's read.
The escalator doesn't move. The elf
explained that it probably needs more
jaw to becomes static friction of
something something hit something. Now,
you need to make the largest jage by
turning on exactly 12 batteries within
each bank. Okay? Instead of picking two
digits, now you pick 12 digits. The jage
output for the bank is still the number
formed by the digits of the batteries
you've turned on. The only difference is
that now there will be 12 digits in each
bank's shortage output instead of two. A
bunch of fairy tale mumbo jumbo. So what
it is saying is that given a number you
want to pick 12 digits
and in order from left to right you you
can pick 12 of them. Okay. Then you
combine these 12 digits you picked in
order from left to right. You cannot
randomly mix them. Okay. Then uh you
want to pick digits such that they they
create the maximum number. Okay. Now so
so so blah blah blah. So let's copy so
we can begin to code actually. So let's
just copy
advant code previous uh we did this
yesterday.
I still have a code. So I got cough
very painful.
Okay.
Okay. Let's let's start to code. Um
okay. Let's uh begin
a pre-blog of woofer language code.
Paste it and pop it out. Here is our
previous code. It's so trivial. Now we
just pick 12 digits instead of two. Um
okay, hold on a second. Let me go cough.
Okay, I'm back. Dearly beloved,
anyone here comment? Okay, so now you
pick 12 digits. Let's see. So,
previously we are picking two digits. Uh
digit one we actually hardcoded. So, so
now you the job is to pick 12 digits.
So, let's do like before.
Let's say let's pick um
let's see 12 digits.
So let's say let's say that's a number
you
okay you turn into a list okay integer
digits list
okay
that will give you a list of digits then
you
let's see
okay hold on a
Okay, you give uh you return a list of
digit. Then you pick one. You you need
to pick 12 of them. How how large are
these digits? Let's see 15 characters.
So there are 15 digits. Now let's look
at my advent of code personal input to
see
how many digit. Okay, so there's plenty.
So let's try 100 characters. Okay, there
are 100 them. Okay, close. Um, now go
back. So,
so now you need to pick 12. But how many
are there? 15 here. Okay. So, you need
to pick 12. So, you
turn it into a list. You pick the
Okay, you you you must pick.
So are there any zero? Let's see. We
need to uh are there any zero? There is
no zero. Very interesting. You see
tricky this advent of code tricky elves.
You know if there's zero then you have
then the problem would be more
difficult. Okay. But there's no zero.
You see this personal input? There's no
zero in it. But it didn't say it doesn't
tell you. You see? So it needs, you
know, but how do I know? So maybe
someone else um their puzzle input would
in would contain zero, but I doubt it.
Again, like I said, advent of code is
quite lousy
because the spec does not say the number
does not contain zero. Does does it
actually say
search for zero or search for digit and
see search?
You see it doesn't say it doesn't
mention there is no zero in these
digits.
It doesn't say. So that means according
to the spec you must assume
your input might be zero might have a
zero
you know in one of these you know
digit zero in them. However,
if so if if there's zero, your algorithm
will be more complicated
because when there is zero, you need to
deal with um
uh well anyway it's going to be more
complicated. Okay,
but but it's likely it's not just going
to not contain zero. So if you do not
consider
that it contains zero, your algorithm
will be much simpler. But however, it
technically it would be incorrect. You
know by my personal input I might get
the right answer but some other people
might get the wrong answer using my
algorithm because their input has zero
in them. So this advanc code is not very
good if you know in that case it's not
fair. Uh anyway, so let's just assume
there's no zero. Okay, so you you you so
you got bunch of digits, a list of
digits, you pick the
you pick 12 of them. So that means the
choices must be uh you must leave 11 of
them behind. So you can only pick the
front
something because you need to have 11
digits behind. Okay. So,
so we can actually just start to modify
our code.
Let's see. You see this drop this drop
one Y one because previously we got we
picked two digits. So once we pick we
have to drop the last one to leave room.
So now so two two uh um
one because 2 minus one. Okay. Now in
this case it will be 11 because 12 minus
uh 1. So that will be 11 negative drop
the last 11 digits. Okay.
But um okay you need to modify this
algorithm because this algorithm
hardcode two digits. Uh now you need um
okay so should we should we directly
work on the algorithm or should we go by
like first do a example step by step
let's do an example step by step okay
comments if you are here watching
comments okay so
so you you you you need uh you need some
kind of slot result
list. You need some kind of result list
of uh 12 items like 1 to 12. Something
like um
let's say
okay.
You need like a slot a list of 12 items.
That's your result. Okay. So, enter. So,
wait. Where's the equal sign? Now, in
the beginning, actually, it's going to
be empty. Okay.
Watching from Sweden. Fantastic. Magnus
Olofson.
Now, seen wam language before. Very
never seen wam language before. Oh,
okay. Okay. Let me focus in it. I need
to do a good job.
Okay. So, so result is a um
empty list. We're just going to push it.
Okay. So, um so first of all, you pick
one. You need to leave room.
Okay. So let's let's start to like um
digit list equals to that. Okay. Um
uh then
then result list. Um then then you pick
one. So you do this drop
drop drop digit list
and pick the maximum that's a digit one
you push it to you append uh append pre
prepend okay so you append
append actually append to So when you
have a variable you append to
append to is like push okay to to the
end like push in other in Python or
JavaScript append element to the value
of X reset X to the result. Yeah. So you
append to
X result
by
by this thing.
Okay. And you need to repeat this 12
times.
Let's see. And each time
each time the number dropped would be um
wait
hold on a second. So you
you drop
the right hand side then you pick a max.
Uh wait. So you need to um
Okay. You you need to
you pick a max then you need to know its
position.
Okay. Like here you need to know the
position. Okay.
Uh
let's do this. Let's hardcode this for
now. Okay. So
xdigit one equals to let's just hardcode
this for now. Okay. So it's easier to
understand.
Uh then you append to the result. So
actually let's just say
x result
equals to
append x result digit one. Okay.
Then you do this again. Let's just
repeat this. Uh let's see if that works.
Digit two.
Let's see.
So once you you drop you pick a digit
then you must know the position. Okay
this you do this only one shot one time
then you need to know the position. So
uh so digit one position
so let's
okay position is like index so digit one
position equals to
the first one yes the first one among
So if there is more than one let's say
there's eight
this is not a good example so let's pick
some good example let's say that
okay so if that if the
you see that's the result.
So if the So there are several eight
uh you pick one.
So the position you you pick the first
one. Okay, that would be the leftmost,
right? You want the leftmost. Then you
need to know the position. Then we set
it here. Then
then you pick um yeah. So then you pick
the digit two would be equals to
um let's see
now this time you drop in front of it up
to the digit position. Okay. Then you
pick the max. So that would be digit
two. Okay
then.
So, so then
so let's forget about the result list
yet.
Okay. So now digit three would be
okay. Now digit three
you then now you need the digit two
position. Oh god.
So let's not do this yet. Okay.
Yeah, let's not.
It's so digit one
then digit one position
and digit two
then digit two position.
Okay.
Uh it looks like that.
Check. Let's double check. Digit one.
Digit one position.
Digit two. Digit two position.
Then let's do digit three. Is that
right? So
digit three. Uh
okay. Looks like that's the pattern.
Now the exception is just the digit one.
The digit the first one is -1. Okay.
Wait do we uh we need the max. We need
to apply the max here.
So max
max at at just means is a shortcut for
the square bracket. Okay. So, digit one
and then then digit one position, digit
two, digit two position, digit three,
digit three position. We can just like
we can manually repeat this until digit
12. But that's a pattern.
Okay. So, let's write a uh loop to do
this.
Now, Wam language is a functional
programming language.
predominantly
pretty much like lisp.
Okay, so we're going to call this loop
in a functional way.
Let's see uh how do we do this? Okay,
let's color this. Okay, save it, close
it, reopen, and uh recolor.
Okay. Dig one, dig one position. So,
so they are kind of nested. Dig one, dig
one position. The whole solution is
going to be one single line, very short
uh 200 characters, something like that.
So instead of using drop we can use take
drop uh take from digit one position
doesn't matter. Okay
so let me think
recursively. Yes, that is the right way.
Either we're going to use fold also
known as reduce or we're going to use
the nest function.
Uh okay, I shouldn't digress but you
know so let me well this is my tutorial.
Okay, so tutorial you go to list section
introduction to list. Uh then there is
list operations there list operations
then you have lots of recursion. So
map iteration uh combinators transpose
padding uh map function to list scan
fold loop recursion. So there's lots of
uh recursion related. Let's look at
recursion. Okay. So you can have nest uh
nest while which basically does
recursion for any function you know any
function you that function is not
recursive it it does not call itself
however you can uh call nest this allows
any function to recursively call itself
okay then you have nest while which lets
you uh specify a condition when should
it stop the nesting while the nest is
just a number of times uh to stop. Then
you have have fixed point which is it
will just continue to nest until the
result remains the same. So the result
then feedback to the function a new
result. If the new result and the last
result is the same it stops. That's
fixed point.
Then you have recursion uh involving two
arguments as fold also known as reduce.
This this is the most generic loop
construct
in a functional style.
Okay. So I think we're going to use uh
either either fold or the nest. But
let's let's get back to this.
So each loop you can uh so after you
done each one of the selection you can
do the append to the result list. Okay.
So you can um so you need to do this 12
times. Um
do it 12 times. So
you need to do this 12 times. That's the
thing. That's a key. So,
okay, this this requires some thinking.
Okay, this is incorrect. This part is
digit two position. Now, color helps.
Now, it's better,
right? Yeah, the color helped. Um
so given a number given a number you
want to
do some kind of loop you every step you
extract the thing you want to extract is
just a digit. Okay.
Every time you extract a digit um each
the so the function takes this number
then it will output
the function takes this number each time
it will output one digit basically.
It will output the chosen digits and the
position of that digits. We need that
which is the index of that digit. So the
chosen digit the position of that digit.
Okay. So each loop the function returns
the chosen digit and position of that
digit. Now this can be improved. Instead
of position of the digit, we just need
we in fact just need you know the
remaining digits to choose from for the
next iteration. Fantastic. So we Okay.
So
fold.
Okay. So let's write a function
document. write a function.
Okay, I'll go steps.
We going to
do recursion
write the function f.
FF takes a
list and return a list like this.
chosen digit
rest list. Okay. Uh
uh
new input list. Okay. So,
so the function takes a input list and
return a list
like this. the chosen digit digit
uh and the new input uh okay chosen
digit and new input list.
Okay, so the function takes
so you need to make this function be the
same for every loop. So the the initial
Okay. So this is about design of this
recursive function. So instead of that
let's modify
the function. It's
takes two AS
something like that. Okay, let me show
you.
My god.
Result list
input list.
Okay.
And uh
return
return basically the same thing.
New result list
where
where new result list is
has a chosen digit appended to result
list
And
uh and new input list is
rest of list
to pick a digit in next round.
Okay. So that is a design
of our recursive function.
logically laid up laid out. Okay. So, so
then
we just going to
bold
FF.
The result is the first part.
of
that. Okay.
Okay. Let's write this function.
Now this ff let's name it pick digit.
Okay. Fantastic and beautiful.
That's algorithm steps. Okay. So we
going to write this um function pick
digit.
So good. So good. Very good. Okay.
Describe description. So we going to
start.
So we're going to write the function. Uh
so let's let's put um let's let's clean
up a little bit. Okay. So
put the code back
and paste it there. Uh let's comment.
Let's make the comment
experiment. Okay.
So the
the code will roughly
have this structure.
these steps.
Okay. Then
then then this uh argo description. So
let's do that.
Let's
syntax collect show in browser. So first
of all we experiment it uh then we have
the outline of algorithm structure then
we can write it. Okay then we now code
um
okay so next so
now remove this um so
pick digit that's a function okay so the
function now let's
copy that so people can D
okay pick digit is a function
uh two arguments okay so
now wam language
uh by default I mean by convention any
symbol Starting with capital letters are
building functions. So all building
functions start with capital letter
letters. So your own function always
start with lowerase letters or
variables. Okay. So that's a convention.
So result list
and input list. Okay.
So what you going to do? So it will
let's see
uh it will so now we need to copy this
code that we have um so this is the
function we need to do something like
that okay
we don't need and
so digit list.
Now let's rename this twodigit list
shall we
now in in the end we need to do
okay fold pick digits It's result list
is empty
and the digit list is uh let's take an
example here
wait
let me show you okay the function is
simply pick digit initial condition
two arguments
Oh, so uh initial condition two
uh well
okay the initial condition uh takes two
arguments. Okay. So well
so the result list is empty and uh the
digit list is going to be
this drop 11. Okay, let me show you. So
initial condition
Yeah, initial condition and uh and the
digit list is going to be integer
digits. Okay, copy.
So, do you guys see what I'm doing? Yes.
Do you guys do I make sense? Am I like
going too slow or
integer digits? Okay. So
integer digits.
So
so fold
by that function and here is the initial
condition and uh
Oh god.
God.
What am I doing?
So initial list is input list is integer
digits.
That's right. Does that make sense? So
use that function. Initial condition I
mean initial input to the function is
this
is this thing.
Wait, it takes uh it just takes a empty
um Oh, okay. So, wait, wait, wait. Don't
tell me.
What?
Uh
so, actually,
right. So, it's going to be like that.
the the final result. The final result I
mean this is just this is just for one
digit. Okay, for I mean for one number,
one input number, you turn that
into integer digits, then drop the rest
uh elements
then you apply recursively this pick
digit initial argument first argument is
that okay yeah that's I think that's
that's that make it one line now now we
need to write this pick digits. Okay,
we saw list um
digit list. So what you going to do?
So, let's
Okay. So,
remove that.
Remove that.
In fact remove that. Okay. So make it
people can see.
So the function
X2 list
result input list result list input
list. Okay. Uh
so you just apply max. Okay. So max at
that you don't even need to drop.
Okay. So let's make a local variable
uh local constant. Okay. So,
okay. Choice digit equals to
to max digit list. Okay. You pick one.
Then
then what do you do then? Um
then you just push uh I mean you you you
return okay you then you need to uh need
you you need to know position okay with
again
let's just say digits let's not to get
wordy okay
position equals to
uh Uh
position equals to do we have the
position? Yes, we do. Something like
that somewhere there.
Position equals to
position
X digit. Wait. So this is
pos position of xdigit from
xdigit list.
Let's turn that input in uh let's change
that into input list. Okay. Rename.
Save. Close. Reopen.
Now
input list
result list. Okay.
So digit equals to that then
position equals to that. Is that right?
Okay. Then what is your expression? The
expression would be you need to return
remember two things.
So the first thing is
Append
result list
X digit.
Fantastic and beautiful. The second part
is
second part is the drop thing. Okay,
let's uh the second part is
drop input list and
okay I think that's it. Drop input list
flatten drop the first from one to the
position
I think so.
So can you guys see
this code? Does that make sense this
code? So if we copy it began wam
language
notebook
question lemon leaf says thoughts on
Apple's RAM prices
and they uh they are huge scam okay
that's about it Apple you know you pay
you pay for the brand name you pay for
the convenience you pay for the
trustworthiness iness. So you don't have
to spend time
on these issues like if you are not a
computer savvy person most of us are but
majority of the population they don't
know anything about computers they don't
know what's a RAM okay so they pay very
expensive that they buy Apple you know
if you want 16 gigabyte RAM or 32 you
pay like two or three times more than
normally
But you don't have to spend time. You
don't have to hire a computer expert.
You know, I hire you one hour for $100
an hour to tell me about to advise me
about which RAM fits in which computer
uh what is the quality brand of RAM, you
know, memory chips. And then you have to
take the computer apart, put it in, you
know, you don't have to spend money or
time on that. you just go to Apple store
here is $3,000 I want 32 gigabyte of RAM
you know
on the other hand
you know so so that's the brand you know
that's that's the point of brand you can
trust Apple you can but you have to pay
okay so it depends on you but if you
know about computers then obviously to
you Jesus Apple is charging 10 times
more Jesus my god. So you go to store,
you assemble your own PC, you know,
cheap, but you spend two years to study
about computers, you know, that's what
you do. So that's tradeoff. Okay, that's
tradeoff,
you know, but to a lot of these people,
we would think, oh, Apple is like a
scam. No, they don't. They didn't force
you to buy their stuff. You see, it
depends on you. You have a choice. If
you don't know computers, it's like
McDonald's. You go to anywhere in the
world, you see McDonald's, let's say in
India, you can go there and eat. You can
be sure it's safe.
But otherwise, you know, because there's
a name McDonald's
trust, it's a brand, they guarantee, you
know, you can. So on the other hand you
go to India somewhere you don't know you
don't you don't speak the language
there's a restaurant how can how can you
be sure you know you go there maybe they
kidnap you something happens right so
that's the purpose of brand okay anyway
I learned this from Thomas so well basic
economics
so it's contrary to the popular belief
oh they are scamming money well you
don't have to buy theirs You know they
they they serve a purpose for so
different so so in this way you have
brand names you have unknown names you
have knowledge people you have you know
so many choices depends on you you so
you can have the best choice
okay so this uh this wra language this
uh so that's the formatting okay so wait
so you don't want this semicolon
you See, you don't want that semicolon.
DD.
So, that's a cool code. Okay, let's
magnify.
Can you guys see this? Can you guys see
this dynamic realtime formatting?
Beautiful. This this technology has been
around since
1996.
Wuam language Mathematica version 3
1996. You see smart formatting on the
fly in real time. You see
instead of the Python idiots, the C C++
plus the Rust idiots, the Hascal idiots.
Let's format let's indent. Let's decide,
you know, we have let's write a
programming style guide. Let's write a
tool or two format. You know the [ __ ]
idiots.
Uh in that's what I call industrial
coders. They don't know about this. If
you want wolf language, you have to pay.
Very very expensive. But there's a free
version you can download. Okay.
So um
I like the retina screens
but still using a think pad. C is fine.
No C is not fine. sees the worst
damage in computing uh uh in computing
history industry. C then came C++ they
are the worst they are the virus you
know you see C is a virus that it's like
a cancer uh malicious um cells
they form they grow like uh how do you
say cancer cells they grow so C created
C++
C++ and C and then they created
JavaScript
you know they created Java and they
created JavaScript. So there's a [ __ ]
pile out on top of [ __ ] the syntax and
all that. That's the damage of C to the
computing industry.
C++ is worse than C. Yes, of course. Now
I can tell you are not a functional
programmer. So anyway, so like like
between the nonfunctional programmers
among the C and C++ and Java or C those
type of people you know this like this
constitutes the majority of industrial
programmers may be webdev may it be a
Linux kernel may it be drivers whatever.
So most of them are imperative or
procedural programming language you know
coders. So to them
to them you know a lot of them say C is
far better C is the best C++ is worst
cancer cell okay to some degree that's
true I mean you know I would say that's
true but
to those of us I grew up like my first
language is Wuam language 30 years ago
in 1993 okay this language I'm coding so
I've been coding it for 30
So two to two to us as functional
programmers, you know, we we consider C
and C++ like the [ __ ] same thing
the same [ __ ] One one is just a bunch
of [ __ ] piled on top of other. C is the
[ __ ] here. C++ is this piles of [ __ ]
okay, on top of C. And they they go by,
oh, we are we are the most popular. We
are compatible with C. C++ first
[ __ ] the bajaman stroes. [ __ ]
the the most damage to computing
industry and Unix. C and Unix they
bootstrap each other you know like C
Unix C Unix C
[ __ ] them.
Okay let's go back to this code. Okay.
Okay. We already spent 60 minutes. Okay.
So, do you see
do you guys see what I'm doing? So,
actually so we don't need that. Okay.
So,
so this is uh so I need to do some
indent
so that the code become more readable.
Okay.
Now double check. I'm not sure this is
correct. Okay. But first of all, we need
to
clear.
Okay. So let's see. Pick digits. Result
list.
Input list. Digit equals to max from
input list. Then get the position of the
max of the x digits. Okay. Uh get the
first position of
that.
Get the first position then. Okay. Then
you return this pair. The first is
append result list. Append or prepend.
Uh append. Okay. Yeah, we want to
append. Then the second result is you
drop from the input list
you drop yeah you drop the beginning
right right you picked
something like that I think I believe so
okay let's try it
so if you do that then let's say uh
Yeah. Now you need a number. Okay. So if
we do that, so let's uh
we don't need you anymore.
So now you pick a number. So let's say
that.
Okay. So actually you need this part.
Okay. Let's uh
do it.
So in the beginning you got this choice
A1 A1. Okay. So you need to feed that
feed that into
that's the input and uh the beginning
result is empty. So let's run this code.
Okay. Uh do I make sense?
Are you guys following this? Okay. So,
let's select all paste and uh
shift enter.
Fantastic. It picked eight. Wait.
Uh wait a minute. It picked eight, but
we tr uh we truncated the whole [ __ ] Oh
god, that's not good. So we need to we
cannot do this. You see do you guys see
what I'm saying?
You you can't you cannot on this first
step remove the list 11 items.
So you need it to be intact.
Oh okay. So I got it. So you f Yeah. So
that's the first step. But um
wait
wait wait wait. So I know I know wait I
know. So this this fold what we should
do is
okay we don't want to drop there. So
okay then the second part is the uh
initial step. Okay so we need to do the
drop as initial step.
Oh god.
No, you can't.
So do you guys see a problem we are
having?
Oh [ __ ]
So op is a issue. I think yes. O I do
code in functional languages. That's
fantastic. I use O camel mostly.
Fantastic. And this recently fantastic.
Okay. Uh [ __ ] we we got into a issue
here with this recursive function.
So we need to think about the design.
Okay.
So because you see the first step is
different from the rest. The first step
is that given a list of numbers you need
to truncate you need to take the
previous
um
So this design is not good. So the
function should return the position
instead.
Should return the position, not the um
not the input list. But let's make sure.
So you begin with the list of numbers.
The first step is truncate the rest 11
of them. Then you pick
then
you need to rest them back. Then you
need to truncate. Okay. So the truncate
step. So initially you should do this.
Okay.
Then the the
what?
So the function takes
this you pick from.
You see because the first step you have
to truncate
the tail of the list but every
subsequent step you have to truncate the
head
of the list. So so the first step is
special.
So, so when you can't have them special
when you if you want to use a recursion
unless you do the if unless you manually
hardcode the first step then you do the
recursion for the rest. So,
so what should we do? One to make them
in sync to make them not special. That's
one step one way or just manually do the
first step then apply this recursion to
the rest to to to the subsequent steps.
Okay. So there are two approaches. Now
which one is better?
So what if the sequence always feeds on
the input string?
the input string is not not large
anyway.
I mean the input list
but it would be not efficient but then
again a vend of code doesn't give a
[ __ ]
So if the function always takes the
input string like a global variable then
then all it needs to return is basically
the uh
god this is not good. [ __ ] this is now
70 minutes.
Anyone anyone is watching seven?
[ __ ] I we digressed too much.
It's not good to digress when you
cannot solve the problem in one hour.
Yeah, we can we can solve it. Just need
to concentrate.
I don't want
you know I want it I want to code this
efficiently.
I don't want sloppy you know I don't
want to just assume just let the
function take the original list
available you know I don't want you know
because suppose you know the given list
the integer integer digits is like one
one billion then you get [ __ ]
Yeah. But event code doesn't care. So,
so only the first step. So, if you
truncate,
so the first step you truncate the tail,
but then you need a tail. So,
but what if each time the function
returns a position
and something like a position or
uh
okay so you do have to manually do this
the first time.
Very interesting. How can we elegantly
make it one function, one single
recursive function? But there is the
exception of the first step.
The first step is you have to truncate
the tail.
Uh, alternatively,
right? The first step you you have you
need to truncate the tail. Then
subsequent steps you need to truncate
the head. So you got this incompatible
you know.
So how do you you need to distinguish
the first step versus the rest
steps.
So one way then you you just hardcode
the first step. So if you hard code the
first step.
Yeah you can hardcode the first step.
Yes.
So if you hardcode the first step then
what does it looks like? Something like
that. Okay.
No, no, no. Because once you truncated
the tail, it's gone.
The function don't see it anymore. But
then in subsequent steps, you need it.
So, so if you want to hardcode it, then
you basically
Okay. So, here is how you going to
hardcode it. Okay.
Uh let's try this. Let's see.
So you call pick digits
empty initial result
and the starting list is going to be
that. Okay. Then
then this is the
first result. Okay. Then you fold.
Uh, hold on a second. So fold. Then you
fold.
Pick. Uh, then
something like that. Okay. So if you're
going to hardcode it,
maybe this.
Okay, this part would be
Hey, this part would be
hold on a second. Uh this part would be
not that. Okay, it would be something
like
Then you need position. Jesus.
Jesus.
Okay. Okay, this part will be
position of
Okay. So it's going to be like that.
First then fold
three arguments the function first
result
and uh
and that. Okay.
So, you do this until
until the list is empty. That's right.
That's right.
Wait.
And you do this until the list is empty.
No, no, no. You do this until God
very annoying.
Oh god.
Okay, this is very annoying. You do this
until the god lots of thinking. You know
when you do a loop
in functional programming, it makes the
problem much harder.
uh whenever you do a loop
and when you when you want to do in a
functional programming style
using recursion that makes the problem
harder.
Okay. So,
so the first step let's see the first
step
not
So what are we doing?
Okay. So the first result is just that.
Okay. So
not that. So we need to do that. Okay.
And uh
so can you guys see?
So
you see that
uh you need to first result
actually.
Oh god,
actually you are incorrect. You need you
need this first result variable because
it happens again with the position.
So
So this is happen this is what happens
if you want to do the first step
manually.
Okay. Okay. But then
pretty ugly. I mean this not but then so
you can you think about
can we just make this one function
recursion then? Uh
so you pick the first digit.
Very simple problem.
Okay, let's think about the new
approach. Is there some other way? You
know, you you just going to get um
what?
You know, you just have a bunch of
digits. You want just you want to pick
12 of them.
So, can't you just
pick a maximum? Oh, yeah.
You just got the bunch of digits. You
just want to pick 12 of them. So, you
just pick max 12. What's wrong with
that? What the [ __ ] would do you need to
do recursion for? Just pick 12 numbers.
Oh god.
you know, do you know? Do you know? Do
you know? Do you know what I'm saying?
Um, so wait,
so if you just got that um
integer
digits,
you got this
big wheel of fortune. You got this big.
Then you just max 12 of it. Okay, I
think Wuam language has that feature
yields the numerically largest of X
the largest element of any of the lists.
Oh god.
Take largest. Okay, there. Take largest
gives the n largest elements of data
sorted in descending order. I don't want
sort.
Okay. So take largest they came about in
year 2015 15 years ago this function.
Okay.
Take largest. So what uh if you do that
that
then take largest 12
okay return
this case it's all nine
uh this case is not interesting so we
need to have a interesting case
what about that.
Okay. So,
what?
Okay. So, copy
copy paste
delete delete
there. Run it.
Okay. So, you got that. But what do you
mean by
you see it uh reorders them in
descending manner? That's not good. So,
let's do a simple example. Let's say
just take three of them. Uh let's say
one, two, three,
nine,
seven.
So in this case it should be 87
9.
Okay. So but we we you see we don't want
to reorder it. This is a better approach
then
um
sorted in descending order. I don't want
to sort. Okay. Is there an option that
prevent it from sorting? If so,
then it's good.
Wait, does this actually work?
This a sanctuary walk.
A7 take three digits right you take the
largest
9 A7 but you don't want reorder
so [ __ ] you see you got them so um
building functions it's all written for
you already So
take a largest by let's say maximum by
return a list of elements e of data for
which the value fx is maximum a list of
elements for which that function is
maximum. Okay so position largest give
the position of the numerically largest
value of list. Okay, give the positions
of the first and largest values.
First and largest values. So suppose one
of them is A9.
So the order will should never change.
So each number 8 n largest. So you just
pick largest.
and 12 digits. Yeah. So, this should
work. Yes.
Position loges. That's what you want.
Okay. That's That's you want. That's
what you want. Okay.
So,
No match. Jesus. This function is new in
2022.
Oh god. So we are using like new
functions 2022 3 years old.
Interesting.
This function
is new in 2022. So we are actually using
um new functions. So
okay that will return 87
9 the position. Okay. So then you just
take
uh you want to extract element by
position. So how do you do that? That's
either um
extract.
Okay. So look up the documentation.
Extract. Yes. Extract by position. Yes.
Exactly. So what you have to do is just
that
extract
this list
by this position. Okay,
that should be A79 exactly. So this one
single line of code that's it.
Okay. So let's try
for example now let's try the huge
number this is uh
this is 9999
three four five six seven eight nine 10
that's too many nines. Okay. So, what
about that?
Search for one, two, three, four, five,
six, seven, eight. That's too many.
Nice. We don't want that.
We want
let's say that number. Okay.
So, position largest this huge number.
Okay.
Uh let's say
number equals to that
actually
let's just do that. Okay.
So that's a long list. Okay. Then we
then just that that that that that
12. Okay. It
Oh. Uh because we didn't evaluate it.
Okay. So delete. You need to re-evaluate
this together otherwise x list is not
defined. There it is. Wait. Depth
of object. Uh
what?
Why? Why is that? I don't understand.
It works here.
logs there.
So why is it not working here?
X list equals to that and run extract
that
run it.
Okay, you got a problem.
This is not good.
This is not good. You got a problem.
What is the problem? I don't know. What?
Why can't you just do it?
Okay, suppose that you made it shorter.
Do you still have a problem?
Yes, you do have a problem.
Depth of object is depth of object is
not
uh sufficient. What are you talking
about?
Well, if you're running wraebook,
it will be much easier to see past what
is the problem.
Okay. So, let's see.
Shift enter.
Now what what is the position largest?
That's the that's the question.
Oh, it started to give a this kind of
thing.
Okay, you need to So it started it's not
just position. It starts to give
repetition
gives the positions of the numerically
largest values in list. Gives the
positions of the first and largest
values. Okay.
So,
so if you say three largest values,
why is it 42315?
One, two, three, four, five.
One, two, three, four.
Oh,
two
and four position largest. So if you
specify a second argument give the
positions of the first and largest
values.
So it returns a result of three
elements. Okay.
So if we do this,
right?
It gives a result of three
largest. Okay. the second element. Then
so there is a repetition for two.
Wait, this is not good.
The result is not
consistent.
Because in this example the result each
element in a result is not actually a
position. is
you see the second elements of the
element is actually
the time it repeats.
100 200 100 100 200 one two three four
So 200 occurs twice.
Oh wait. So,
oh wait, so 42
4 and two.
Oh, okay. So when you extract, so I I
think I I got it.
So instead of that, so let me show you.
Okay, so integer list
X list equals to that. Okay, let's run
that.
Okay, you got that.
Okay, then
then you say position largest. Okay,
then you get um
right you get that 612. Okay.
Then you have to uh then this part is
actually wrong. What you have to do is
that you
X lists. Okay. Then you need to actually
map
extract function
to
um
to this position largest. Okay. So this
is X list.
Okay. So delete that there.
Okay. So can you see what I'm doing?
Uh
run it.
That would be 98.
Okay. Wait. No.
It should be 987.
Why? Why is that? Um
six. So largest is six. So it again it
reordered
but I don't want it ordered. [ __ ]
Oh god. This may even be the problem. I
don't want it old. Okay. So what we
going to do now? I think we going to
take a break.
Okay. Take a break for 10 minutes. Oh
god.
Okay.
I saw date four.
I saw four.
Do I have people watching?
Annoying problem two. Okay. Well, people
are going
Okay, we're going to be back anyway.
Okay.
Okay, I'm back.
Now, this problem is very simple. But um
so given a list of numbers you just want
to take
maximum number of them. Okay. So what is
the position largest
the first and largest values? Okay. So
let's just study this this position
largest.
Okay, let's just study this position.
Not just
let's say
let's introduce a repetition.
Okay. So,
so position six.
One, two, three, four, five, six. That's
nine. That's the largest.
Okay. Then second largest is one and uh
three.
So you got that three and one.
Okay.
So they are uh do they return the
position? They don't return the
position. They return the index.
by default compares values by numerical
magnitude returning a list of positions
of the largest value. Okay. Gives a
single list of the largest value gives a
list of n sublists or n largest values.
A list of n sublists
or n largest values or as many as are
available if fewer than n. Okay.
expect object to be comparable with one
another based on the ordering function.
Okay,
so they actually do not return the
position, they return the index.
Okay, let me check again. So six is a
index. That's right. Six means nine
here.
And uh three and one is index. That's
this number eight. And two is the index.
Okay. So they they actually return
index.
Okay. So in order to extract them you
need to use parts.
So parts x list then you
let's see okay six
that should be nine okay so map
so you got a a bunch of indexes is
flatten.
You got a bunch of indexes.
Okay, you flatten.
Okay, so let me show you this thing. So
you got a bunch of indexes.
position. Okay. So,
flatten.
Okay,
that's what we want. Then we want to
sort
Now we want to sort in a reverse order.
Okay?
Because we want to order them by their
index. One, two, three, six. So one,
two, three, six. That's right. Sort uh
Oh yeah, we don't want reverse order. So
that's perfect. Then we just
part
extract.
Okay, so that's what we got. Okay, so
this these are the
Okay, position largest
three. Okay, so that's these are the
steps. So effect effectively we have
found out how to do it.
Okay.
Then we repeat this into um
condensed way. Okay. So
let's see
x list equals to that. Okay.
Then
that okay.
Okay,
that's right.
That's right. These two are identical,
are they? Oh, yeah. The number. Okay, so
we got a number. Got to be careful. We
got the number repeat. Uh,
we need to use this number, not that.
Okay. So that number
get the position largest.
Okay. Then then you flatten
flatten.
Okay. So that's
okay. Then you got a FL then you just
sort okay
so simple
then you sort then you take the part.
Okay. So
that is a sort and the list part is x
list. Okay. Just like that.
Run the code.
A7 a9
beautiful and fantastic. Okay.
Now and and now combine.
So you don't need that variable. Okay?
Isn't it?
As simple as that. Fantastic and
beautiful.
Now, uh, now what are we doing here?
We doing extract. Forget about that.
Okay.
Okay. So I found a issue with wam
language because there is according to
me appears to be a inconsistency
because in wuam language
the concept of position and index are
different. Okay. So let me show you.
So given the list you have the concept
of index which is familiar to everyone
to Python to
uh to JavaScript to every almost every
language you have index of a list. So in
Python for example in JavaScript they
start with zero.
So three is zero, four is one, five is
two in this example 3 4 5. So that's the
index of the list. Now in wam language
the starting index is one. Okay.
However, wuam language has another
concept besides index. Okay. So here you
got a index to an element. Okay, that's
one concept. Now what if your
list is nested?
So if you want to specify this element
you have to say you know the first index
then the second index. So you you you
use like nested index and that is called
position.
Okay. So given this nested list.
So index one is a the element a index
two is this like this whole nested list.
Index three is e then you can go down
further. So index pos so in other words
position the concept of position in wolf
language is a list of indexes
that allows you to identify a specific
part of a tree or branch of a tree of a
nested expression. Okay. So it's very
simple nested index. So I mean list of
indexes. So when you have a single index
that's an index but when you have a list
of indexes
that is called position of a expression
or sub expression. Okay. So when you
when your expression is a nested list
you can identify any
specific element in this nested list by
using a list of indexes.
And that is called position. Okay. So
remember two concepts index and
position. Index is a single integer
in wam language is start start with one.
Now position is a list of indexes. It's
a list. Okay.
So
two concepts. Now, but the but the the
but the woo fam language this function
position largest
okay they
this this function is new in 2022 3
years ago
their result the result it returns as we
can see here
position logic the result it returns is
not positions okay position means
list of indexes. The result it returns
is a list.
It's just indexes but grouped.
Okay. So, so for example, this 31, this
list 31 does not mean it's at index
three then of that expression index one.
It does not mean nested index. It just
mean there's a index at three and
there's another index at one. they group
it because
this is the second largest you know so
this function name position largest is a
bit
inconsistent
is a bit confusing okay
yeah it should be largest you know index
you know it's not position because wuam
language do make this distinction so
um
That's my
impression.
But I know that Wuan language is very
meticulously designed and this is 2022.
Stefan Wuam goes on YouTube
talks about design every every week.
Wuam language new features. they they
they they you know a bunch of woof
language
co-workers designers who implement
woofer language they they talk about
they go over about the design of new new
functions so this this function in 2022
I suppose is very carefully designed so
so I could be wrong
likely I don't know but you know so but
you see wuam language has grown so large
from two 7,000 functions. So um
so why so so my question is why is this
function called position largest? Why
you know because um I mean what what
would be a better alternative name?
Because there are many constraints. You
see
when you say position largest people
kind of understand what it means.
But if you want to be like I thought
consistent then you have to name it
indexes group of the largest something
like that
you know so it's very tricky
but my point is that what this function
returns is not position technically it's
just a grouped list of indexes.
Okay, do you guys see what I'm saying?
No, you don't. I don't think you guys
are
paying attention because right now I
have like only me talking to myself. I
think three people.
Okay.
So anyway, we understand this position.
Um
yeah positionable largest randoms take
largest
Oh, there is another take largest. Did
we explore that? Yes, we did.
So,
we can think about the optimal approach.
But basically, we already you know this
this line is a solution. Let's let's
just do it. Okay. So, this line is a
solution. So all we have to do to solve
the problem is just now is just this
this line is a solution. So
what is uh
so forget about that okay
integer. So we are exploring take
largest. Okay. So,
okay. And turns out position largest is
what we want. And just that code and
what are we doing here? We can actually
delete this part.
This part we were using extract because
I thought the result are positions but
they are not.
Okay. Now let's just work on this code.
So we
let's Okay, let me do this. Okay, hold
on a second.
Um
I mean let me do the cleanup so that you
actually can see
what are we doing.
So this is approach we were doing
before.
This is an approach
abandoned.
Uh
because
the first iteration
defer
from rest iteration.
The first
iteration
needs to truncate
list from tail.
The rest iteration
iterations need to truncate list from
head. Okay. So,
so they are separate. So, so you cannot
make it into
one recussion.
Therefore,
you cannot make them into one single
recursion.
You need to either
do the
first step first manually
Then recurse
or
redesign
your function
so that
they are
consistent like so so
it does not have this issue.
Okay. So let's put this back. This is
our first recursive approach
uh
experiment on the final
recursion.
Okay. So put it back syntax color it and
you show it. It'll be very clear. So
first of all we did the experiment
to see the nature of solving the problem
manually. You know we create digit one
first digit second digit third digit we
have to do it 12 times.
Then we try to condense that into one
recursive function and this is the
design of the function. Okay. Then we
realized the first iteration and the
rest iteration
are different because the first
iteration you need to truncate
the list of input from the tail
then the rest iterations you need to
truncate from the head. So you need to
you know you know so that can work
unless you work on more redesign the
function. Then we realized this simple
problem. You just take the largest you
know n items of this list. So position
largest logist is a solution. The
solution is simply that line. Okay. So
let's code that.
Okay. So in fact we don't want take
largest. We just want uh position. Okay.
can use this.
Okay. Then then here is our code. Then
here is our code. Then then actually we
just start to solve the solve the
problem. Where's the input? And we have
the input from
Yeah. So the input is uh
from from yesterday.
Yeah, there is the input copy.
Okay, so
Okay, hold on a second.
compact it.
Okay. So that's the um
Okay. So that is the uh gist.
Now,
I'll now start a new Wrame and
just copy that.
Now, let me show you guys syntax correct
show in browser. Can you guys see?
So, we have a new section. We discovered
we can use this. Then now we work on the
final solution. Okay.
So this is just this line.
So this line
um
okay let me just start to work on it
final solution. Okay we don't need this
uh this this drop
this total. Okay. So actually total
map you need to map a function to the
input. Okay. So but first input is the
um
okay so hold on a second. X is
integer digits.
Okay.
Run it.
N uh you need 12. Okay. So the problem
says 12.
Run it.
Okay. Now, copy that. Let's try a
different number. A11. Okay. A one one.
Run it.
Fantastic. Now, let's just try and then
you need to submit, right? So, once you
get that, you need to
combine digit to
combine a digit to form a number. Okay,
so from digits
I believe that that's a function that
turns a bunch of digits to an integer.
Okay, so let's just say that
run it.
Okay. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12. Wait,
wait a minute. We only want to extract
12, but now we got more than 12. What's
going on?
One, two, three. Wait. One, two, three,
four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, 10,
11, 12.
Why am I going getting more than 12? I
just want 12 position largest.
Okay.
What's going on?
Uh let's just say four
four
then
five.
So okay this is not a good number to
begin with.
Oh, okay. So, you need to limit. That's
right. Because when there is a
repetition,
uh, do you guys know what I'm talking
about?
You see, when there is a lot of
repetition, let's let me show you this.
Okay. So, let's say we just want to pick
four numbers out of this number. Okay.
So when you do that when you call
position largest
it gives you four largest numbers but
however in this input
the four four largest number there would
be nine 8 one and that's it because
there's no more largest. Okay. So the
third largest the number one is actually
repeated many times. So, so this
position largest in fact returns um do
you guys see what I'm saying?
This position logist actually returns uh
let me show you.
Okay.
Uh wait syntax in invalid. What? Oh, we
you you got extra um
you see it returns more than uh more
than the 12 numbers. So what you need to
do is you need to truncate. Okay. So you
can uh the way you truncate the number
is you can first of all flatten it
then take
take this input then you just say
three uh let's say three okay then you
just get three indexes Okay. So if you
say five then you get five.
Okay. So you basically you need to do a
take you need to do a take
something
12. Okay.
So
let me think about this.
thoughts.
Function
uh function
expression
take x12. Okay.
So that would be the function to apply
to. So you put it there
at okay. You just take the first 12.
Okay. So if we run this, it's going to
result is going to be identical for this
case. Oh, wait. Yeah. Right. You see?
Fantastic. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12.
Beautiful.
Okay. Now, in this case, it's the same
number as before. So, delete that. In
this case, you need to add the take
or let's just copy this and uh put this
number there. A
one completion
ddet
digits. Beautiful. Okay. Then you don't
need you know then you don't need this
and you don't need that that that that
that.
Then you put from digits in front of
them.
Uh wait.
Okay.
Then it will return actually a digit.
Fantastic. Okay. Fantastic and
beautiful.
Turn it.
Fantastic and beautiful.
And let's try a different number. So
copy.
So next number two three four
completion.
Do it.
Fantastic and beautiful. Okay. So now
now let's just combine them.
You don't need you know
uh what
so what do you doing? So
you need that. Yeah. So you just uh so
all you have to do is now just see
this is going to be a beautiful solution
even though we spend like two hours
total uh map a function to it. Okay. So
this is a function we're going to map
and we need to because it's a function
so we need to say function. Okay.
Function
then the expression part is this. Okay.
And the input is um
x num. Okay. So xnum
the input is going to be xnum.
Map that to input. So each input is a
number. Xnum. you need to turn xnum into
a list. Okay. So,
so let's
let's with
x list equals to
uh integer digits
at x num.
Okay. Then cut cut
Then this is the expression. So do you
see do you guys see what I'm doing?
So that's it.
So
this part is a sample. Okay. And this
part is a solution. Okay. So in fact we
don't need the sample. Okay. If we run
this it will then then you need total.
Yeah. So we add it. So in fact we can
run this can we? Yes I think so.
Let's check one more time. Xnum is the
functions argument.
So first of all turn xn num into digits
into a list. Then then you do this. And
so run this. It's the result is going to
be
what is the
part two? Okay, the result is going to
be 31219
something.
Okay, let's see. Run it.
Okay, incorrect. You idiot.
My result is not his result.
The total output voltage is now much
much larger 31219. Okay. My result is
not his result. So
So let us
from digits. Let's not use a total.
Let's see what we get. Okay.
So that is our result.
987 811 23 4
9 87 7 811
Oh 434.
We got 234. They got 434.
There is the problem.
Oh, okay. So you Okay. So then A18
then the result is A9. We got A18. That
is incorrect. So let's focus on that
input.
Okay. Interesting. tricky.
So if you have this number what you get
A18
Wait,
you should be A89. Okay, the result
should be A89. A89,
but you got A18. So why
um
okay there's something position largest
A1 A1
Oh god, this tricky.
So position you get their positions
then flatten.
What does this return anyway? So
then you don't want to sort it.
You don't want to sort it. Okay, I know
what to do. Okay, so
right.
So you first do that, then take the
first
and don't sort it.
What? Why are you doing sorting?
You should not.
Right. So,
your code only splits the beginning of
the values. Uh, no, I don't think that's
a problem. But look, I think I got it.
So, um,
so this number, you don't want that. You
just, uh, don't sort take. Yeah. So,
let's run this. Let's see.
You see? Wait. 988.
Oh, [ __ ]
Wait. Why is it nine?
Position largest.
Okay. Now you need to think about
position largest. Okay. You need to sort
somewhat.
Oh god, nasty.
You see for this number the solution
should be 88891
what one? Okay
88 a89. So
so what is that you want to do? So let's
see position largest. Okay
returns that.
Then you need to
you need to sort
you need to first of all take.
Okay. So you need to first of all
flatten then truncate. Okay. Uh in fact
does flatten has option of truncate
flatten to level and flatness of the
expression. No.
Okay. So you flatten it then you take
the first 12.
Okay. Then you need to sort
because the first index those with with
less index come first. Then you need to
sort that.
Okay. Beautiful.
Do you guys see what I'm saying? So, so
this is the wrong. So, let's run it. Aa9
something. There it is. Beautiful.
Okay. So, now you just copy that and
replace this part by that.
Okay.
Then we run the whole thing, it will
work.
Um,
well, let's comment out first. Okay. So,
now we run the whole thing, it should
work, right?
So, 9876
check. 9876 something one check. Then
811 9 811 9 check. Then 3434 something
3 uh 43 43 27.
Okay. Wait. 43 42 43 42. But we got
3 43. [ __ ]
the then the last one. A8 91. Okay. I
think I know what's going on.
The last one is correct. Yes. But the
third one we got wrong. So we have 3 43
43. The solution should be 43 42. Okay.
Very tricky
from this example. You can see um
there's a lot of tension went into
creating this puzzle.
Okay. So I I kind of know what to do.
Okay. So basically it's a sorting issue.
So you want to sort
like
you want to
you you you want to flatten it for sure.
Okay. So this part
this line flatten is so sure for sure
you got a bunch of indexes. Wait,
wait. Not not sure.
Okay. So, so it's so Yeah, this is uh
Oh, God. This is
this a lot work to do.
Okay, copy. Now, let's try this new
number. this magic number that [ __ ] you
up.
Okay, now run it.
You get 3 43 4. This is even this is a
tricky one but according to the result
correct result should be 43 42. Okay.
I still don't know if I like the syntax
of WAM or I hate it.
Yeah, I don't I don't know neither. But
I can tell you for the first 20 years I
think it's the best possible.
But now I'm not too sure because um
it's super flexible. you know, you can
you can make the whole thing just like a
list, you know. So, all these um all
these special syntax like the add sign
or uh all the braces all be can all can
be changed. So, you end up with just
purely nested square brackets with
comma. So, the whole thing so you know I
can show you but anyway it'll take a
minute or two. So you basically it's
become it's like a list. Okay. So you
like kind of like that. But even here
you can change for example this ad you
can change it to just that. So that's a
standard form. So it became fully nested
uh thing
anyway. So that's um anyway let's let's
let's get this to work. Okay. So,
so this this thing, so the tricky I know
I kind of know what's going on. So, you
see this position largest return this um
grouping of list. Okay, so you want to
know first of all how many items are
there.
If it's 12 then it's perfect. Okay.
But uh let's see.
E one, two, three, five,
six. Wait.
One, two, three,
four, five, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11, 12. You
see, sometimes you you got more.
So when there are
so the when when the result of this
position largest is more than 12 when
you flat after you flatten it then you
need to
truncate certain tail of these
subgroups. So in this example the this
these subgroups you need to truncate
those uh a642
Okay. Then um uh actually the problem
example is here. Okay. So um so what
does this return then? Okay. So God
let's try let's see what that returns.
Let's see.
Actually can just put it there. Okay. So
there
you see it returns that.
Now this uh let's just do this here too.
Okay.
So now
so how many are there? 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
10 11 12 13 14 15. So there's more than
12. When it happens there's more than
12, you need to
truncate beginning by you need to
truncate some of these subgroups.
Oh god, that truncation would be uh
tricky.
So within a subgroup
god.
Okay, this is pretty tricky. So within a
subgroup,
you actually want to not truncate. You
want to remove the head. you you want to
remove the largest index.
So you you need some kind of recursion.
So check the first largest if that is if
there's enough if there's more than 12.
If not, get the next one. Total are
there more than 12 digits? No, then get
the next one.
Okay. For each one of these subgroups,
first of all, you want to sort it.
So, you need to apply to Can you saw the
whole thing? Let's see.
What what happens when you sort them
like that? Okay. No, it so what you need
to do is you need to sort
you need to sort it like that. Okay. Let
me show you.
Yeah,
then you need to flatten it. Okay, let
me show you guys. So, by the way, that
slash add that just means map map this
function to to that expression. Okay, so
once you get that, you flatten it.
Okay.
Then you take the first 12. One 2 3 4 5
6 7 8 9 10 11 12.
Yeah. Then you take the first 12. Okay.
So that means
let's just trial and error. Okay. Let's
just uh trial and error. So, so what are
we doing is you
you
get that then you sort
through each.
Wait, wait, wait, wait a minute. You
can't
Okay, wait. So here I know what to do
now. Now for each of these each of these
number is a index.
You you need to start from the smallest
first.
For example, here it would be one first
then two.
Wait.
Oh god. This.
Okay. I'm like
suffering from this problem because
this is this is
this needs thinking. Okay. You can just
trial and error because then you might
go on and on.
Uh because I thought we got this
fantastic function that just solve the
problem in one line but then there
there's this issues that then you need
to think about but basically it is
kind of the thing.
Okay. So then you need to think about
again. Then it's almost 2 hours
or was it 3 hours? [ __ ] I need to take
another break.
I need to take another break. So
position largest. Position largest.
That's the largest number there.
Second largest
third largest occur four times. Okay.
So,
so that's what you want. But uh so all
these Okay. So among these numbers you
need to you only you must take only 12
of them. Okay. is five
seasons.
Okay, you must only take 12 12 of them.
The rest must be deleted. The question
is which one to delete and what is the
order? Okay,
so the question so the order would be
the smallest index first. So
wait,
not exactly. Okay.
Oh god, I I thought this would give you
the solution already. Position largest.
The beast says, I think it's basically
what you already do, but here is how I
would solve that. Give a unique index to
every number.
Then do a sort on the list of unique
ID based on the value they point at.
Remove the last three digit from the
list of uni unique ids.
Yeah, I think I I think I get what
you're saying. It's basically what you
already have, but give a unique index to
every number. So you mean combine the
number with the index
then do a sort on the list of unique ID
based on that value they point at
then remove the last three digits from
the list of unique ids.
Go through the value check if their
unique ID is still in the array. Okay. I
I think I you know we I think we might
be thinking I mean we I get what you're
saying but not the detail. So I think
yeah we I think we pretty much know what
to do but it's um
they just [ __ ] I need I want to take a
break.
Oh, the end of code is such a pain
because every time I do it, including
last year and the year before. I thought
it's I'm going to finish it in 10
minutes. But but usually
many of them ends up several hours and
it's not done yet. And then I'm
thinking, why am I doing it? Because it
looks bad on me. you know like oh you
don't you you know like you you you are
not expert
and then the other thing is then it's
like wasting time I got lots of actual
coding things about wam language for my
website I need to do then but then you
end up spending like hours on this
on this like
problem for problem sake you know for
nothing
[ __ ] never
I need to you know so this problem I
have to think about it I think about it
I cannot talk if I don't talk I cannot
do live stream so it's like you know
I'll just need to stop talking and think
for 10 It's
position largest it returns the largest
first.
So but the problem you so you want to
pick 12 digits in order.
Okay. So cases
what about other ways to pick
12 numbers? Yeah, another way. Okay,
let's digress. Okay, let me just I mean
do whatever thought flow. So another way
to pick given a list of numbers you know
like a digits list another way to return
them is you select
select by a functional criteria
or you can use cases
um
cases okay for example look at select so
you have to give a function that will
pick about values. But in this case,
select
is not applicable
because in order to determine what you
know which digit you want to pick, you
need to you need to judge there are
several dependencies.
One of them is is like um
You see when you select you need to
select 12 of them that's for sure and uh
but but what's the judgment the judgment
must be that digits must be one of
the first 12
uh largest
like between one to nine or zero to
nine. uh what you know one of the first
okay so the criteria is it must be on
the leftmost first first and the largest
so leftmost is the first criteria
wait so leftmost means the element has
the least index the index is the least
and then
you can do that with select because
first of all the total result must be 12
of them and select has no way to
determine how many result it returns
with the function. Okay, so how do you
logically um describe this situation?
Select is like filter in other languages
in Python.
The function has no way to know
how many results to return. Okay, you
need to like return 12 results maximum
and uh the but you can return more
though of course but then you need to um
the criteria is that. So in other words,
how do you describe
this problem of selecting 12 digits from
a list of digits
in terms of a filter? Is that possible
at all? First of all, so this is an
interesting side question, side quest.
Is it possible to describe this problem
in terms of a function that
determines whether element must be part
of the solution?
Uh, I think
I think
I think technically yes, but the
function needs to know
actually no because the function needs
to know how many it needs to know how
many member has already been selected.
You see it's kind of that way. So but
so no it cannot be done
with select.
But how do you describe this in a
logical way? In other words,
describe why you cannot
use a filter kind of select um
way to to to solve this problem
in a logical way.
We know we can't do it because you know
you must the result must be 12 elements
and select has no way to
to know how many other elements has
already be been selected. In other
words, the the criteria a function to
determine a member is is the item we
want
is dependent on
what items we already have.
So you can so you can do this select in
one shot. In other words, you need to
you need to repeat this uh you know.
So this is um this is not but anyway. So
the other way is cases. Okay. Now cases
it won't help neither because cases
is using pattern matching.
Cases is using pattern matching.
So,
so you cannot so each element you so in
fact cases and select they are the same
thing because a pattern can be turned
into a function. A function can be
turned into a pattern because for a
pattern to
behave like a function all you have to
do is you add a condition to the pattern
saying that the function must return
true. So using a function and using a
pattern are actually same. So in both
cases the select and p and cases they
are both just a filter function. They
apply function basically or a pattern to
to a element to see that's the one you
want. But then ultimately you cannot do
that for this problem. Okay.
So analogous problem is max you know the
max function
pick the max element of a list that you
cannot do with filter because you need
you so in that case you need to know all
the elements
when you determine a given element must
is the one you want you need to know the
rest of the element. Okay.
So technically though it's possible. Um
okay that that's that's a digression.
Okay. That's about logical analysis of
these mathematical issues.
But the then um you see then uh wam
language has so many uh others. So uh
for example being list what bean list
delete cases. So collect, let's see what
does collect do.
Download the latest version of Firefox.
Life Firefox is very annoying. Collects
together terms involving the same powers
of object matching X.
Same power. Oh, okay. That's that's kind
of that's more mathematical.
That's not what we want. That's like
that's like uh simplifying algebraic
expressions. Okay. Uh but what we want
is
let's see together. Together is some
kind of another type of sorting.
Together puts terms in a sum over a
common denominator. Oh, that's combining
fractions. Okay. So, but what we want is
pretty much this um
I know from experience what we want is
pretty much this taken take largest by.
Okay, so this techn largest by use a
custom function
instead of our um
position largest. Okay,
you see position logist. So,
so
I should have written this with two
focal val
So, okay, I think you have great ideas,
but I need to work out my own flow.
Um,
yeah, I just need to work out my own
flow cuz if I follow your algorithm,
that's just that's just like starting
over, you know.
Anyway, so
so I'm pretty sure this you just need to
uh do this take largest and uh um and
you need to think about this truncate.
So I need to think about that.
Okay.
So what you need to think about is this
uh
so this this thing.
So first of all you know for sure you
just want 12 of them. Okay. So if this
list is more than 12 of them in each
element then you you need to truncate
somewhere.
Now when you truncate you need to okay
so you need to truncate beginning
with the you need to take the smallest
index first. Okay. So for example in the
first group you take the smallest index.
So for so for the for the first group
you check if there's more than 12 or
not. If not then you take them all. In
this case there's only one number.
Okay. So this 15 means you know it's
it's a number way
at the tail. So that's not what you
want. You you want you see you want this
this first one here.
So again it's a bit tricky. So like
which to take which to drop that's a
that's a question and the order. Okay.
But the position largest gives you the
largest item.
So the largest item. Let's see. So we
can work in reverse. So
the largest item. So
right and 12 of them, right?
But there's no 12. Okay. So that's a
that's a problem. So can you actually
have a option that you just say a
maximum of 12 items
instead of instead of 12 different
ranks. You see that's the difference.
Right now you are saying 12 different
ranks but it turns out this number only
have one two three four five five of
five different ones.
So when you have position largest is
there um
okay you can have a order function. Okay
so it gives you the largest
12 of them.
Then now
can we ask are these
12 of them?
Um
you see when you say 12 it's the result
is always going to be more than
items because the the distinct number
digits there is just 10. So the result
is always more than 12.
Uh yeah. So
okay. Okay. So, but but but which one
should you choose?
So, if you go by the smallest.
Okay. Now, now my question is can you
actually use this? Does this actually
work? Positionist Jesus.
then because now I'm thinking let's go
back to our recursion
approach because that's that's surely
going to work. We know because each step
we take out some numbers, remove the
tail or the head. That works.
But then
we run into like separate the first step
versus the rest step. Then we have idea
of using this like functional
mathematical approach. But then we run
into this um
this this. So you need to think about
which one.
Okay. At least for each of these group
sublist you need to sort them so that
the smaller one comes first.
Okay. Then
then you need to drop some items. Now,
how do you start to begin to drop items?
What's the order? What's the first item
you should consider to drop?
First of all, which group which of these
group to drop?
Then once you found a group to drop,
which of the number to drop?
Okay, that's the two questions. Okay, we
know for sure this this list of list is
going to be more than 12 items because
the maximum number of different numbers
digits is just 10.
So when you select the 12 largest is
going to be more than 10 indexes result
for sure.
So which group to drop? First question,
which group of these two drop?
Um
can can you come up with a criteria in a
mathematical way?
Alternatively, we can do a procedural
way then it's easier.
Well, procedural way then you go through
each one of them.
No, this is not good. Wait, such a
simple question.
You pick 12 digits. Why can't you just
do it?
Pick 12 digits. Do not reorder them.
That's the thing. Because this position
largest is like
did they reorder them?
They did because the they put the
maximum first. You see the 15 refers to
that eight at the end.
You don't want to reorder them. So if
you don't reorder them, then what what
is that? Um
then basically you just reorder then you
just uh then you just have one for
right. So but
okay. So I think
okay so new new approach new think so
given this result
you
you sort each sublist first like that.
Okay, you sort each um
what?
Why is I return that? Let's do it again.
Wait, not that. Okay,
this this is wrong. You don't want to
sort like that.
You want to map. So let's write this uh
okay so that's that
um then you
you sort each
then you.
One, two, three, four, five, 6, 7, 8, 9,
10, 11, 12. Then you take
then you flatten it. Then the take the
first 12.
Okay. So did we
swords?
Wait, wait.
So then
So then then flatten. Okay. Then you
take.
Okay. So that's I think that's that.
Let's try that.
I'm getting tired. I'm getting pretty
tired here.
Getting pretty tired. Don't know what
I'm doing now.
So, can we just comment all this out?
And uh too many to comment out.
So, but basically I just want
Okay, let's just delete it. [ __ ]
Okay, let's just that.
Sew them, then flatten, then take the
then flatten. Then then then take the
first 12, then sort again.
Let's just see what we get.
Did
we get the right solution?
That's like before.
Hey, two three 42 three.
No, that's Wait, that's incorrect.
Should be 43 42.
This is incorrect. What?
Sort apply to that.
Then flatten.
Then take the first 12.
Okay,
take the first 12 then sort. Then take
the least
of the first 12 and form a digit. Then
you are wrong.
You are wrong. What about A1 A1 A19?
And the last one now we got it wrong
too. Before we got it right, but now the
last one is wrong too.
Oh [ __ ]
So So go back to what we doing here. So
we have to again think about this. Um,
it's 30 3 hours almost 4 hours. Oh god.
Yeah, no worries. Do your way. Okay.
Okay. I'm going to take a break. So you
guys take a break or go off heaven for
the holidays Christmas.
And I think I'm going to continue
because
you know it's a matter of um you know I
let's just finish it. Continue. So let
I'll be back in 10 minutes.
Be back in 10 minutes. Okay.
Um yeah let me take a break and let's
see what happens.
Test, Piss.
Fatten
soul each.
So each
Latin
take 12
then swords.
Okay.
I don't know why
why is this uh it's not do from digits.
Okay, let's just run that.
Uh where is the output? What?
Run it.
Okay. So,
2 3 4.
Now, this number two, three, four. If we
take 12
So it should be three four not two
three.
So there's priority in taking the first
Oh god, this
is priority and taking the first
[ __ ]
One, two,
three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, 10, 11, 12.
So
largest
nine of them.
So I'm thinking the position largest
is not good.
I mean the
Where's the position largest
maximum by
maximal by a function.
Okay, that's just the maximum.
Take largest
sold by reverse. Sort by.
So another way is you get the
technologist.
So
position largest. Where is position
largest?
First and largest values.
Order function position first and
largest values
position largest. Okay.
Okay. So we
we are using position largest and uh
And uh it's not
so we are using position largest
but the problem is that it always return
more.
So even if you say position largest
even if you say position largest 10
that's going to return
same thing exactly
you see it return exactly the same
thing.
Um
so
position largest. Okay.
13 10. So 15 is eight. 14 is seven.
Then the third largest number is four.
Four occurs in
36 92.
Okay. So
Okay.
So you want to sort it first.
Okay. So So wait. So, let me do this.
Let's see what we get.
Right.
So,
right. So, this 11 moved up. This group
moved up.
You want to sort by
You don't want to sort You want to sort
by index or length.
God, it's tricky.
So
So yeah, I'm pretty sure you want to map
to swords.
That's what you want.
Okay. So
map
your number. So 12 from there
one would be wrong. So in this example
our number is 2 3 23. Okay
our number is 2 323. According to the
solution the answer should be 43 42.
Okay. So 43 42
that means the first
item is index one.
So from this one
wait four is index three. So index three
is from here.
So if you just saw them all
then takes the So eventually at the end
the index must come in order smaller
first.
So you just flatten it. sword all
and take the first 12. What What could
be wrong with that?
Okay. So, if you just take
this is no good. So if you just take
just flatten the whole thing
then just take the first drop then
flatten the whole thing then sort it
and then then just take the whole thing
what you get.
Okay.
What
is still incorrect?
It is incorrect because you got this 2
three four. Okay. So it is incorrect
because you got this 2 three four that's
this from here the number one problem
mean that one index is incorrect.
So why is that? 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
and 1 four. Okay, one is this number.
Four is this number. Okay, so let's
let's let's do this so that it's
Okay. So,
right. Returns exactly the same thing,
right?
Uhhuh. Then
then you
so if you sort
let's see 7. Oh okay. So 13. So this
group.
So the first thing you want to sort by
index.
You want to sort each subgroup.
No, wait. How do you figure this out?
So,
so it's the problem is very simple.
Okay. So, it's you simply pick pick 12
digits.
So, simple.
Pick 12 digits.
Uh where wait, it's not that simple.
Pick 12 digits. But
but
okay. So so it's um pick 12 digits
such that let's simplify. Let's say you
pick two digits
but
the maximum but the you must pick two
largest number. Okay.
So if you pick two largest number
so the smaller index come first.
Oh god [ __ ]
So the problem the way we are coding it
the problem is to describe this
selection process in a mathematical way.
Uh you can do it procedurally then
then we can use our recursion algorithm
but we are not doing that. So we are
doing this in a declarative way.
So the problem is in essence specify
this problem in a mathematical way
declarative not procedurally
and uh and there seems to be some
difficulty
because if you describe this problem in
a procedural way
what you can do is you first pick one
number
and But
drop the you know you you you must have
room for the rest of number. So you must
drop 11 digits on the right. Then
you pick the one largest digit.
Then you do again but this time you drop
whatever is in front of the digit up to
that digit. Then you pick another digit.
Okay? So this way you repeat this 11 or
12 times you get the result you get what
you want
procedural description
but now okay this is a procedural
description
you want to turn this into a
mathematical description no steps no
order just like criteria
so the criteria here is
to begin with is still we pick 12
numbers. Okay,
let's see. Let's turn on my face.
So, so describe this problem
mathematically. Okay, first of all, we
know it's going to you know we have a
string of numbers. What? Whatever we do
is going to be we're gonna pick 12 of
them.
Okay. And
so which one to pick? There's like
hundreds or whatever number of slots you
need to pick 12 of them.
So simple.
You need to pick 12 of them and such
that
they they are maximum. So
12 of them. You pick 12 of them.
Can you do combinatorial method
or can you pick starting from the right?
Previously we picked starting from the
left.
Can you do this procedurally but picking
number from the right instead?
or what's some other way? So,
okay, describe this mathematically. Um
well the mathematically is that you just
pick 12 numbers
and the result is the largest among all
possible 12
numbers.
So if you want to implement that way
then you can do brute force
basically means given a list of 100 or
whatever number of items you pick 12
items
you pick all possible 12 items from a
list then you turn each into into a
number and you select the largest
So this is brute force.
Find all possible selections of 12
numbers of given
uh given how many digits are there. No
given [ __ ]
Given [ __ ]
what
language tutorial to do.
Uh you can let's see input
search for text.
Okay. So
again
so that you got 100 characters. So a
list of 100 items
and you take 12 of them.
So that would be possible tpples.
Okay. So I can you know we can we can
start to digress and into another
um
form but um you know we digress a lot of
course.
So but we can try just since we are
stuck anyway.
So turppos will return all possible
tpples.
So let's say uh given uh digits let's
say
integer digits okay
uh let's say random
okay possible turbos three
run it
okay so you you become very large okay
yeah possible topos
then you just find the maximum. So if we
brute force that way
what would happen actually it's
interesting
because if you have 1200 digits so uh
let's say length
what
what' you that length
512.
It's not too big. Not too big. So, but
here you got 10. You got um 100 digits.
Okay. So, let's see what uh
copy. Okay. So, let's say that and let's
say
12.
What's your length?
too many. The length of the output of
Tupus should be a machine integer. Okay.
So you cannot do that. It went beyond
machine numbers.
So we are doing the brute force way.
Yeah.
Okay. So
the brute force were interesting.
Let's copy the screen.
So, boot way is no good.
Okay.
Then what we doing? So,
so,
so what we doing? Close that. Close
that.
Close that. Close that. Close that at
the end of code.
At the end of code. So, let's do that.
Yeah.
So again, a list of items, you want to
pick 12 of them and pick the largest
number. So
So let's think about, you know,
you got you you you like shift your
pick. You got, you know, a long list.
You shift your pick pick pick.
The best way really is a procedural way.
You pick the first number by remove the
last 11 items. Then you pick the
largest. Then starting from there, you
pick the rest. Then you repeat this 12
times. This is the like the simplest
procedural way.
Okay. Now the mathematical description
of this is you just
generate all possible 12 to tpples 12
post
then find the max the largest one. Okay
uh that
that is actually a mathematical
description.
the largest
of them of all possible
12 tuples.
Okay, but that is in you know that's
impossible to implement.
Uh but is there a way to simplify it? So
we can implement it.
Well, yes. If the
then we can think about given the huge
list, if the first item is like one, we
can drop it. We can drop drop
12 possible tles. Okay, that there. So,
so there's a combination is huge.
So
um and uh so
so but this should be simple. But what
what what is another way mathematical
description
for this problem other than just largest
of all possible 12 tpples.
So again you got at least you pick 12 of
them and in order and this should be
largest. So
let's think about like the physical
geometry something.
Okay. Just shift shift shift slots.
What determines if one of the item
should be picked? Again we are back to
the theater problem.
So
each element in a list is is one of 0 to
9, right? And there's no zero actually.
So we can determine how many um but we
need to so uh
so is there a way to describe this
mathematically? Okay. Is there a way to
describe this?
Oh god. Mathematically so
just a bunch of numbers.
So if you say the largest position like
we did before
like we were doing this position largest
that is not helping much
because
there's
um
so another way is two.
Oh god,
Max.
So, the problem is so simple. You just
need to pick 12 items.
So,
Must you proceed procedurally? Well, the
mathematically the all possible tles.
How do we how do we optimize it? How do
we cut corners?
All possible 12 tles.
Can we actually cut corners?
So what's another way to describe this
problem in a mathematical sense? Is
there some kind of number theory?
Like given a number you want
you know given a list you want to pick
12 of them
such that the result digits combined
forms the largest.
So but procedurally you start with
picking the first number first.
So procedurally you start picking the
first number first and remove the 11
tails
so you have room for the rest of it.
So what is this procedure in a
mathematical sense?
You pick the largest,
but you have room.
So So you you just pay pick the largest
12.
So can we actually use this position
logist
position largest you need to. So if you
do this uh
position largest.
Got it. So you got this one there. You
see that's tricky.
That one that index one should not be
the end result. That's the number two.
So it should be 4 three 42. So
10. So 12 largest numbers. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
8 9 10.
So you can see the first group. Is it 12
yet? No. Consider the second group. Is
it 12? No. Consider the third group. Is
it 12 yet? No.
So given the result of these position
lodges you need to truncate some of
them. Okay the question is which
so you so that's the question. So one
way is go through it procedurally
consider first group is a 12 number yet?
No.
Wait, does this actually work?
So consider one, two, three, the fourth
group. Is there 12 number yet? No.
Consider the fifth group. Is there 12
numbers? Yes. More than 12. So then you
need to drop.
So when you drop
one, two, three, four, five, six, seven,
eight, nine, 10. So so far there is 10
digits.
10 digits. You need to pick two more.
So why would you pick? So one and four
is two two. So why is two not selected?
because it's uh Oh,
okay. That's the one, two, three, four,
fifth largest.
That's two.
What? One, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, 10. So 10. You need
12. So what is this?
One, two, three, four, five, 6 7 8 9 10
11 12. Right. So you picked 43 4 23.
So 43 4 23
then 4 278
then 42 78.
So it works out. So this I this is
correct.
But how is it compatible with this
position logist? Okay.
So
needs to be three.
One, two, three. So, it needs to be
three.
Three is here.
So position.
So is it 12 yet?
No. So you need to add
and drop some here.
Drop some here.
Oh, okay. So, when it's not enough, you
need to drop. Not in the beginning,
you want to truncate. Okay. New insight.
When you start to get more than 12
elements,
you want to truncate the ones
that
has huge index.
I mean, wait, you want to truncate the
ones that's that has u index is low. You
don't want the one in the front.
Okay? So you want to truncate.
So when you take take take
then when you reach this part you want
to truncate this
143 and take 10 and 13 instead.
Something like that.
Okay.
Uh, so one, two, three, four, five, six,
seven, eight, nine, 10, 11, 12. Right.
10th and 13th. Let's see. 1 2 3 4 5 6 7
8 9 10. So that's
two
11 12 13 2 and two. Something like that.
So 10th and 13th. So
wait,
that's a currencies of two.
Four and seven. So it is actually taking
four and seven there. Dropping one
and dropping 10th and 13th.
You see? So this is tricky. It's taking
four and seven. dropping one and
dropping 10 13. So this indicates this
position largest may not work.
So we need to go back to the procedural.
No,
we don't want to do that because we were
trying to make this arrogant.
So you see this indicates you cannot
actually
do this.
So how do you judge? Why do you so when
this given this
why do you pick four and seven? Can that
be determined from these numbers here?
Two, three,
two, three. Two, three, five, 6, 8, 9,
11, 12, 14, 15.
Oh god, I'm having a headache. I mean I
don't have a headache but right but this
is
so this indicates that apparently
it's taking four and seven because the
result is 4 3 42
then 3 42 so
4 3 4
two
312. So the
Let's think again. So, you just got a
list. You just need to pick 12 items.
And uh
so it seems to me there's no way to
describe this problem in a mathematical
way other than
the list of all possible 12 tuples.
The maximum number one of them
So you need to do this pro.
So are we sure that this problem cannot
be solved with the position largest?
Not sure about that yet. Not 100%
certain
position largest.
The largest.
It may not be able looks like it cannot
be done with that
wasted happiness.
So use position largest.
Okay. Then number from a number point of
view
does this make sense? Like can this be
discussed in a number theory point of
view?
Like basically you have a function that
turns each fun each number to another
number.
So you are turning this number into a
another number into a 12digit number
uh
which is made up of picking 12 digits.
So
so is there a mathematical relationship
between the input number and the output
number? So that's another kind of new
way to look at
Is it
is there a mathematical function? So
instead of doing all these picking or or
possible tpples if we know a function we
can just turn this number into the
result number. Such a beauty. And would
that be unique? So another question is
given a number is that the new number
unique?
Well yes but but the return number could
come from many of these numbers
right? As long as you know for example
one of the example is one of the
result number is a substring in this one
of these numbers.
So in other words
this is not a one to one function.
In other words given a result number
there can can it can come from many of
the input numbers.
But uh
but all these numbers still is there a
relationship?
Relationship means can you specify it in
terms of arithmetics?
Arithmetics.
So now if you think of a number as just
a quantity.
So 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 they just form a line.
So any point in space they map to a
different
point. So and it map to a different
point.
So the larger the number
does not necessarily map to larger
result of course. So what would the
graph look like? I don't know. It would
be interesting to plot it.
So, but
so you specify number in terms of like
picking 12 digits
of it.
That would be
what would the graph look like?
So if the whole number is all just
single digits
then the result would be very low like
one one one 12 digits.
Now let's simplify. Let's just say we
pick two digits.
So
the number real number line the integer
numbers you know one to a billion or
trillion
in in this number there's so many digits
they are ga billion
uh so many of them become just one one
of them becomes one zero but there's no
zero okay so so one one or 11 or 12 or
okay so they all basically mapped into
11 to
99.
Interesting. So they all get reduced.
They map to 11 to 99.
So if you pick 12 digits, they get
mapped to,
you know, one one repeated 12 times to
9999 repeated 12 times. they get mapped
into that range
and uh
and the mapping fluctuates of course
uh and uh yeah
but can the relationship of input and
output be specified in terms of
arithmetic relation
like as a elementary function.
What we are doing is like picking the
numbers apart. But can can can the
process of picking numbers apart be
specified in a mathematical way? Well,
then we have to think about
okay picking numbers apart you know then
you each number becomes their nth 10 to
the nth power you think of that in terms
of that series powers of 10
series.
So you specify each number in terms of
their powers of 10. Then you basically
got their each digit.
Then you
you want to pick the maximum digit that
would be become
to pick the maximum digit. You cannot
you can't you see you can't
mathematically describe
a single digit whether it's should be
picked or not without consider the
whole.
That's the thing that's a that's a main
issue.
You can't
pick a single consider without
considering the whole.
So,
hello everyone. Hello Stefan.
Uh, not having a good day. Creeper.
Um,
we stuck
and we went a far.
[ __ ] [ __ ]
So,
so let's get back. So, so this position
largest, does it really work? I don't
think so.
So, you just want to pick 12 numbers.
So, simple.
So simple. Say, so can you instead of
the recursion, can you just
pick the first 12
then try to move them to the right
or pick the f last 12 then move them to
the left?
That's another procedural way. You just
pick 12 numbers
and move them towards the left.
Right. You pick 12 numbers, move them
towards the left.
So or another way.
So this is
Oh god.
You Yeah. So you just pick 12 numbers
then you start to systematically
shift each slot towards the left.
If
there is a slot that's larger than the
current number.
So that's another way. So,
so once you move the first digits to the
leftmost, then you start to move the
second slot
to the leftmost to see if there's room
until there's no room.
Then you stop.
Okay. So this is the second procedural
way we discovered beginning with the
rightmost 12 digits.
But does this save time or does it is
this more is this way more efficient or
uh we don't know. So
no, I think our original recursion
our original recursion procedure
is the best. So where is it? So day
three part two. Yeah, original like this
description is the best.
That's the best that's the most
efficient procedural way. Okay, we just
need to you know we manually code it. Um
that's the most efficient procedural
way. Okay,
by this
by this method just repeat it 11 times
or 12 times.
But now since we went into this
mathematical maximum way can we still
save ourself? I mean either we stop
at approach we go back to this
elementary
basically every programmer is doing this
essentially
or
we continue to think about this this can
we somehow get the largest
in a mathematical way.
You see this is where I often stuck
because if I abandon this new way
then I went back to the original like
fundamental like the most instinctive
for programmers way and solve the
problem. It doesn't look good because I
spend three hours, four hours, others
spend one hour, you know, 10 minutes.
So, but then if we push for this
mathematical way,
first of all, we know the generate all
possible 12 tles is is impossible.
But if somehow we go through this
we we use a mathematical kind of
description algorithm to solve the
problem.
If at the end we came out with a
solution then that would be great. We
spend five hours 6 hours but at the end
we did it.
Uh
most other people haven't done it that
way. is novel.
So
it's best for me for me I think for my
live stream to try to persist with this
mathematical way.
So right now it's like four hours.
So let's think again. So just so simple
pick 12 numbers. How could it how how
how difficult can it be? You know, just
pick 12 numbers out of a list.
So, position largest. Now, let's look at
let's look at wam language. Maybe we see
some inspiration. Take largest give nth
largest element of data.
Okay, that's what we want. Take largest.
That's right. [ __ ]
[ __ ] [ __ ] That's what we should do
because this guarantees whatever you you
know when you say take largest 12 it
guarantees to return 12 items
then you figure out their position
that's it Jesus
new revelation okay so these are past
experiments Let's now go back to uh
new revelation. Okay. So now
let's forget about that. So the huge
number. So take large.
Okay. That will do. That will be a um
something. Okay.
Superb. Let's let's let's do our supreme
programming.
Not not not not some [ __ ]
So take largest. Okay. Integer digits at
two three. Okay. So
let's say 12.
Take largest. Are there 12 of them? Yes.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10 11 12. Okay. Then
you say
wait then then what you do
take largest
then you just sort it like be to be
sure. Yeah. And you just sort it.
[ __ ] idiot. You idiot.
Then you just take the position. [ __ ]
Then you just Okay, let's do this. X
list
X list in equals to
that. Okay. Run it.
Fantastic.
And then you just have um
then you just run that.
Uh what?
Okay. So, let's let's
fantastic. I think I got it. Okay. So
run it
take not why is it return twice and you
don't need that. Okay. So that is a
return value. Then you got then you then
you just sort it. Okay.
Okay. Then you just sort that.
Okay. So,
uh
sort Okay. Then um this sort um
okay then you just
pop
x list
wait
you want to take those indexes Okay,
fantastic. I think
and sort it.
Wait, wait, wait. We already saw it.
Hold on a second.
What?
Let's try see
21. That would be 32. Okay, that would
return 32.
Oh, they need um
that would return 32. Yeah. Right. So
when so then you just apply the indexes
then you then you combine
3 three 44 44 4 two two three no that's
incorrect
because This 2 3 42 should return
43 42 something 78.
So,
so what's take the largest
integer digits take the largest.
Oh, wait. Take the largest. That's
right. These are the largest items.
Then you need to take
your position
position from X list.
Uh yeah. Okay. This gets a bit tricky.
Okay. position
and uh x. So you need
map
function.
Okay, function. What we do is you take
the position and the list is from
largest. We want to know their position.
Okay, that's a list of largest items.
We take their position. Okay.
Do it.
All right. Yeah, that looks familiar.
You see? So, let's see.
One, two,
three, four, five, six.
Wait. Largest.
Okay. So, these are the positions. Okay.
Then
wait.
Eight. This is seven. 44 44 44 44 44 44
44 44 44 44 44 44 44 4. Then 33 33 33
33.
Then
then uh wait
what?
Take largest. Those are the largest
numbers.
No, take logistics does not work because
if you have
why technologies does not work because
if you have a number
that's let's say uh 77777
Right.
Okay. Something like uh let me just show
you 666
78 9. Okay.
When you have that number,
the result should be six 666 12 times.
Okay. But you if you do take largest,
they're going to give you 789 in front
like in front and there's no way for you
to remove them.
Uh [ __ ]
So there's the there is interplay play
between largest and their index
their position. The index must be small.
Yet it it's dependent on which digit are
we talking about. So it's like all coin
independent
from a mathematical point of view.
You see the first number you pick is a
number in a list such that
it is the largest among the numbers but
such that
exclude the last 11
slots.
That's how you describe it. Is there any
other way? I think none.
You see the first digit
among them
is really the the the largest
in a given list but except the last 11
items.
So that is really the
definition.
The definition re really depends on the
position, you know, it just
so except the last 11 items, the the
maximum except the last 11 item. Is
there any other way around it?
Because if there's no way around it,
then then you just cannot describe this
in a mathematical
way.
Oh god.
So the first item so
so that so take largest is not working.
Take largest cannot work.
Okay, I think I'm going to stop
largest.
So, but uh but but but but but but but
but
Memory core sorts
drop largest position largest
function repository position largest
wait that's repeated. No wait look look.
So someone wrote this functional
repository. So someone wrote this
function uh position logist. Then it
became part of Wuam language building
function in about 3 years ago
2022. You see position largest building
symbol. You see however
however you can see there is this
position largest. Let's open a new tab
in function function repository. So
let's look at that. I think this is
created by a wolf employee
Bob Sander Hinrich
Sanderhine Reich or something German
name must be so position largest you see
is a function someone wrote but now it's
in wam language
so
you see as a version 13.2 two position
logist is a building symbol.
So that is interesting
and
and we assume this person is work works
at Wuan research this
uh you need to turn on JavaScript. Yeah.
Uh, I'm pretty sure usually there is a
link to his to the author.
Where does this take you?
Creative comments. Okay.
So it was created in 2018 and now it's
part of wam research
mean wam function.
Okay. So I think I'm going to stop.
So what is the condition of the problem
now? Well, it's just that
I abandoned the procedural, the
recursive coding and opted for the
mathematical, but it turns out it's not
working.
Yeah, but there is there any way to
savage it?
Take largest by
I don't know.
Extract. That's not what we want.
Extract by position. Sort close
from digits. Okay. Yeah, we know that.
Flatten. We know that. Select. We talked
about that together. That's for
fractions.
Okay. So,
I'm going to stop. So, this failed.
Well, too bad. Bye, guys.
Five people. Well, I'm going to stop.
What's the meaning of purpose of life?
You ask in the wrong time.
I
uh I talked about that two or three
videos ago
uh about religion like what do you
believe in religion? Okay. So so
stop. Bye guys.
We shut down in one minute. Okay. Shut
shut down in one minute.
Uh
so this is about
won't work because if
input
is
result would be 6
six
but
take largest would include
7 8 9 in
But can it still be solved though? Can
you like ignore 789? No.
No.
So we can remove that. Yeah.
Okay. So that is that doesn't work.
So we can annotate
can we annotate what we did in well
this is procedural so exper so let's
annotate okay
most intuitive
procedure Oh,
did I spell it correctly? Procedure row
way. Okay, that's what those are.
And then we have
let's see syntax color showing browser
intuitive procedural way then we try to
make it into a algorithm
into a function then we apply recursion
okay so we started to do that then we
realized
there's a issue because this recursion
the first step you need to
truncate ate the tail of the list by 11
slots. You need to truncate it. That's
the first step. But the rest of the
step, you need to truncate the head
of the list
depending on where you picked your
number. So, so these two are
inconsistent. So, you cannot have a
function that recurs. So, you either
need it needs to amend, you know,
redesign your function. So, there's no
special step. There's no special first
step or
you do a um you do a manual first step
then you use recursion of this function
to generate the rest of the digits. The
first digit is is a manual step. Okay.
Then we thought we found that this
position largest is a functional way
mathematical way. It returns all the
largest numbers.
So we we started on this idea. We
thought it's going to be one simple one
simple line
and that's a mistake. Then we end we
spend the the next three four hours on
this.
It's like almost working but something
is wrong. Uh four hours spent on that
doesn't work.
Then we got I got really pissed. I want
I I really want to have mathematical
description of this. I went start to
think about deep analysis.
So this problem can be described
mathematically
that is
given a number which you turn into a
list of digits. You know given a list
you create all possible
12 tuples of it.
Okay. Then among them for each 12 tuple
you combine the digits to form a number.
Then you pick the maximum number of the
order tpples all the possible tpples you
generated
and we try that you know given a digit
the user input you have like 200 100
characters at least of 100 length.
So the possible purpose for
you know picking 12 out of 100
is beyond machine number.
Okay. So that that that ruled it out.
But however that is a valid mathematical
description of the problem.
uh if we have a you know large computer
in fact um can we do this if we have uh
like enough memory
the length of the output of tpples okay
so should be a machine integer yeah so
the number of such tuples is beyond a
machine number
uh yeah so But
can we actually like make this work? I
don't know. But anyway, that's a
mathematical description of the problem.
Then I thought maybe we made a mistake.
The take largest will work instead of
the position largest.
Uh then obviously no, but take not. So
we have an example. So that's where we
are. And we didn't finish. That's well
it's been somewhat fun.
Um yeah the so we realized confirmed my
experience that advent of a code has
always been kind of
not not trivial. Okay not trivial. Bye
guys.