welcome to another episode of xa talk
show
today is 2020 september
7th monday five o'clock in the afternoon
and today's slaver's day a holiday in
united states
you are looking at the background image
is my
microsoft surface pro
so this is a tablet and that's a
background image for today
if you are wondering so i have a page
reviewing this product you can go
and read about just search for the title
uh search for xari with the title you'll
find it
and so today we are going to do
emacs lisp i'm going to show you
uh let's do together we you know
actually i'm going to do
i'm going to do emac this coding about
date and time how do you insert how do
you write a command to insert date and
time
of various formats is iso formats
you know uh each region each country
have their different formats for
date and time so i'm going to show you
how to do that and also
the more difficult topic about how do
you pass
data and time so i haven't i haven't
been done that for a while it's
uh the last time i've done that it's
like five or ten years ago
so we are going to do that okay shall we
begin so
by the way so the tablet i started to
use it
about four years ago and uh this is my
first time using pen computing you know
this digital
pen and that is fantastic you can
actually write notes you see right
chinese
chinese or uh especially you know
when you write notes like drawings you
know these drawings you cannot do
uh with a keyboard you know so
if you are doing math you know
explaining things or notes to your
friends and so on or teaching
this is fantastic so you can buy and by
the way
uh of course this is not the only item
you can buy
uh tablets is pretty popular today but
um so there are a few ones for example
you can get
let's see let's let's show emily's
stuff so who is here
raise your hands okay we don't have
anybody here we have five people am i
talking
am i doing fine am i alive check video
check audio good okay so we're gonna uh
do emac these
okay so meanwhile i'm gonna chat uh
two minutes about this uh pen computing
so
emily emily is a
eminent uh member of our discord
okay you know this code is kind of
annoying because
every time it hold on second
so i'm back so emily is a eminent member
of
our discord group she always have
interesting things
uh to say uh so anyway she she
she's got this uh ink
ink display uh technology phone from
china fantastic you know you uh
i'm not sure it's i don't think it's
available in usa
this is a high sense ai
proc cc phone okay so i don't think
as far as i know it's not available in
usa so anyway
ink display uh cell phone you know and
she also got the
this zoom tablet which you can buy
on amazon you go to you know search for
display
search for xally uh displaying phone
you'll find my page okay you can buy
so this is a zoom tablet and there is
some chinese on it
okay so let's see can you read chinese
well i can read chinese
so you see this chinese this is this is
uh
taoism the way that becomes a way
is not the immortal way the name that
becomes the name
is not the imoto name i don't think
that's a good translation okay there are
tons of translations of this doubter
gene
but anyway so let me read on
the way that becomes a way is not the
immortal way the name that becomes the
name
is not the immortal name the maiden of
heaven and earth has no name the mother
of all things
has a name thus in innocence
we see the beginning in passion we see
the end
two different names for one and the same
the one we call dark the dark beyond
dark
the door to all beginnings
this is the typical chinese taoism
uh kind of thing philosophy which is
kind of
nonsensical well in some okay
either nonsensical or multi multitudes
of interpretation you could you could
see it any means you want
that's uh characteristics of chinese
language
in fact but if you read
in this in this passage in chinese is
it's actually
it's kind of more interesting because
you the you have to use the original
language that has
there's more poetry but anyway
so you see it's hard to explain
there are tons of translations and
interpretations
written by different authors you can you
can go
buy so you go to amazon you click link
link and go buy
english versions of it.gene
fact we have several people western
people who are interested you know it's
one of the things that western people
are interested
especially today uh so anyways
so dao you know it's it's kind of uh
deep shall we say okay so let's do emac
list
okay let's uh let's hide the discord
email like this so who is here who is
with me weenie
07 good morning so eight people okay so
let's begin to do emac this
so we are going to do emacs list
past date and time so first of all let
me show you a
um let's begin from the easy stuff
to the difficult so the easy stuff is
first of all is to insert how do you
write a command to insert data in time
so you go to my emacs tutorial
just search for practical emacs lisp
you'll find it okay if you like my stuff
buy it okay that's what i'm doing video
live stream for to marketing product
uh part of because i enjoy it so anyway
print date and time and so you have a
command
here it's already written
i'm going to show you this command you
can grab the code on this page so let me
show you the code okay
so on the pink window you can see all my
commands
course okay so on the pink window you
can see all my commands and keys
i'm using stuff like keys and using a
vora keyboard so let's see
so first of all uh let me show you the
command about print date and time so
show in browser this is my talk show
page for today
okay so back to back to emacs
and let's so i want to insert a date
then and time so i just press a key
there it is and the command is called
uh the command is called it shows up
right here
uh wait here select date
and the key i have is space e u
you know that that you you know in this
command log mod
it because i have a brief i have a brief
let me show you okay
so i have a brief that turns
uh let me show you so you i type you
space and it becomes ylu so that is why
you see this there it should be
space eu so i need to do something i
need to turn off a brief
over there so you also you can see this
uh new empty buffer the key is
delete c n
that end is n okay so for example i type
i type n press space it becomes
end so you and me
you and me
you and me fantastic
the power of a brief search for
saudi emacs brief i have a full tutorial
on that
uh brief is the most fantastic thing in
emacs
so anyway insta date you see i press the
key like insta date i can insert several
formats
so i do universal command ctrl u
then press my key and and you can see in
in the mini buffer i have several
choices of formats
you know one or two you know these
uh sequence of digits three you know
different choices of let's say let's say
i pick one
okay enter so let's do another one
and magnify let's say two okay
then i got string of digits so that's
that's the command so
let's do describe key and press the key
then you can see the documentation the
in
inline dock for that command so this is
insert date
and you can jump to the code source code
is in
stuff like he's smart so enter so
here is our code okay let's copy and
let's not copy it let's just magnify
let's
let's do this okay so so from
here to um
here narrow to region so you can just
see the whole thing
not too many lines for 30 lines okay
so that is the command and okay let me
let me let's
explain let's explain how this is done
so
so insert date time is pretty easy so
first of all you have this part
uh this part about about style so this
is when emacs
emas emacs ask you for what kind of uh
format of date and time you want
i'm not going to explain this in detail
you know you're gonna study it read the
code okay so
but i'm going to explain the formatting
itself
so i so we have a first of all
so if this line says when there is a
region
then delete it okay
then delete the region because so it
overrides it
for example i create a new buffer
same thing okay i select it now i call
the command to insert the date
okay then it just delete you know the
overrides
the region selection okay that's what
this line does
then it basically just insert so the
whole
the whole code is about inserting you
know which one you want
so so insert let's go back to insert
magnify so you can see there's a
condition okay let's switch
to the you know the courier
i mean the mono space font you see
you can you can press the key to switch
font style
uh proportional or mono space
so this command is called
variable pitch mod okay so you can you
can you can do that yourself
so anyway so insert okay so condition
condition now we said a style before we
have style
zero one two three you know depend use a
picture style so
if it's style zero that means this
format this kind of universal
uh format then you just say
you call this function format time
stream
now so so this is how you format data in
time
okay then then you give this kind of a
key
special characters capital y means
year four digit year lowercase n means
uh two digit month and
lowercase d means two digit date
so i guess this this is uh kind of
common in many programming languages
so if you want to you can look at the
detail you know just called describe
function on format times
string so let's do it describe function
format time string so there is the
documentation for
format time stream and you can see
it gives you all the details here about
what
all these cryptic um
key codes to you know to insert date or
minute or
hour you know things like that okay so
so overall here is the insert code and
condition
style one then we do format you know
string
here and if style one you you add extra
a
capital a that is for spelled out full
name for the week
day name and so on
you know some of the formats require a
little bit
coding for example if you want just a
string of digits
this is one of the iso format
you know for example here is 2018.04
means april 12 22 o'clock
means yeah it you know 22 o'clock means
10 o'clock
in in the afternoon in the evening 40
minutes and 15 seconds 15 seconds so you
have to do a bit coding
uh you know you have two for in example
you have to delete the uh the colon
remove the colon so anyway so that's the
code format
uh time string this is the the key
function is format time
time string okay so that's about that
code okay so uh widen
undo okay that's close it
okay so we have several so so date and
time okay so let's just um
okay showing browser so that
is about inserting time okay now let's
uh let's put that new at the bottom okay
showing browser any questions
comments or questions
so the next thing we're going to do is
to talk about
how do you uh pass time date and time in
emac business
now that is a quite complex
thing to do in fact that is complex
in basically any language any
programming language
morning derek a so the question is how
do you pass data in time
okay so how long have i been talking
we've been talking for 16 minutes okay
let's talk about let's
talk about how to how do you pass data
in time
uh okay so let's look at um
so i have another article here
uh in my emacs website about print date
and time which
basically we just covered you know you
you want to print data and time in
several formats
this is what you do using the format
time stream
uh function
okay so that's that's about that article
so now let's go back
now now the next thing we're gonna talk
about is how do you
um pass data in time which is this
article okay
so here is uh you know past passing data
and time is a
is a very tedious and
complex task in any programming language
and this this problem is such a problem
that
there is no designated
algorithm for it you know it's it's kind
of
it's kind of like it's one of those real
world problems
there is no actually fixed algorithm
like mathematics you know for example
the greatest common
divisor the the you know the 11th
prime number how do you factor a number
you know
those are how do you multiply a matrix
you know those are very
concise concrete problems and you sh and
and or how do you sort
how do you sort a bunch of numbers or
strings so these kind of problems we
you know over the past 50 or 100 years
we have a
we have a lot of algorithms you know a
lot of people study it
but for date and time it's just it's
it's such a
complex problem partly because the
calendar you know the
how did we come up with you know such a
date and time like 12 months
and seven days for a week and how many
days in a year
you know 365 65 days in a year that that
is actually a very complex
extremely complex a strong astronomical
problem planetary problem so it's you
know so
calendar the fact that we have calendar
the calendar itself is non-trivial and
it takes
centuries you know for for us to come up
with calendars
so anyway so so anyway first of all we
have a calendar then then we have you
know in english we have these
strings to represent date different kind
of formats
um and now we want to pass them so it's
it's
it's not trivial in any language but
but usually you know today we uh
any almost any language they have
building library that
that does that but depending on what
language
they they are usually income
incompatible or complex you know they
have different levels of features you
know abilities
how they can pass a date so in emac this
it turns out you know i studied this
back in like uh
10 years ago 2011 that's the first time
i
i dive into how do you pass data in time
so let's let's do actual code okay let's
instead of talking let's actually start
to do code let's see how
uh what we're gonna do so so the problem
um
so what are we going to do so there is a
so we want to pass data in time so given
a string
you know we you know for humans we can
understand what this
means but you have to let computer
understand
you know what this string means that
that is what passing is about
so the problem is given any of these
state and time you want to convert it
to into this universal kind of universal
format okay that's a
that's a problem that's the idea that's
a problem we want to do
so the solution in emac this there is a
past
time library okay with this function
past time stream
but it's not it's not all that powerful
uh if i recall correctly because some of
these state time strings it cannot
understand it doesn't understand
it should because even the the
even though the you see the the problem
about passing date time
is not a difficult problem you know it's
not like solving one of the great math
problems where
no mathematicians can come up with a
solution it's not like that
but rather it's a it's a complex problem
in a tedious
sense you know it's quite tedious to you
know like
for example one solution is just try all
possible ways
there are not many uh varieties you can
try
all possible ways so the emac this
doesn't do
do well so so here
i try to use the e-max list building
function pass
time string to try to see which
format it understand and which one it
doesn't
so let's do it okay so let's let's go to
the code so
um okay make a backup copy
and let's show the code so here i have a
code
okay so it says
testing for supported format for past
dating datetime string okay
now as of 2016.
so i did this in 2016. uh that's emacs
version 25 but today
the e-max version i have is emacs 27
so you can see press ctrl u then meta x
then type version you see
now we got emacs version 27
so four years change let's see what has
changed okay let's
let's gonna do it evaluate this require
pass
time uh and unixy format okay so unix
format this is
you know this string is from unix unix
uh love this string
uh let's see if they are equal okay
janet
neal okay so
something changed
you know something changed in the past
four years
so past past time string it returns a
list
like this okay but um
okay let's see what what it actually
returns
so let's paste this here ctrl u
run it so it returns this
thing
so how how is this differ from
that
oh okay so instead of neo so here is a
neo
but here it has a value of negative one
uh so what does that mean i don't know
you have to look at the
dot stream for past state path time
string so
uh describe function
so let's see
so pass the time in string into okay
the format it returns second minute hour
day month year
and uh year and the dow i don't know
what that is
and dst is the time zone and tz
i don't know what that is so it says
um okay string should be something
resembling
an rfc822 you know this unix
fox they love these rfcs
you know they love to say site rfc
ifc is kind of the unix unix
affiliated uh standard
even you know for example on the other
hand there is iso standard and other
standard much more
um actually much more um
universal than you know much more
established
but the unix people they always love our
rfc
so anyways a string should be should be
something resembling on
rfc822 okay or later date time
okay in case let's let's you know in
case
in in case you haven't you guys haven't
seen rfc
you know here is rfc
uh you know these days you young people
you you guys haven't seen rfc
you so you see so ifc822 is august
1982 um
you know the standard the standard for
the format of
of up oppa
internet text messages
god 1982 this is ancient
okay so anyway so what is dow okay let's
see
so anyway let me read the read okay so
string should be something resembling
an rfc822 or later datetime for example
friday something something blah blah
blah but this function is somewhat
liberal
in what format it accepts and we attempt
to run
a likely value even for somewhat more
formed strings
the values returned the values returned
are identical
to those of decode time okay
okay there's a decode time but any
unknown value other than dst
are returned as neo and an unknown dst
value is returned as negative one oh
okay so that's what nick the that's what
the negative one means
let's go back to our code you see
you see uh let me show you okay so
here over here here's a result
from e max 25 and here is a result from
e max 27 the difference is this negative
one
this negative one is the the second last
element of this list and according to
the documentation it's the dst now this
documentation
it didn't explain what this d o
w
or d s t or t z means now that's the
flaw
of documentation you know so if you guys
are a fan
of gnu emacs or free software foundation
go tell them to change it
i'm not going to do it because i i've
done this a thousand times uh
and it
tastes like a greasy coin
in your mouth okay so
so you didn't eat it so you see it
didn't it doesn't say what dow
and dst means you know so you can look
at decode time so let's look at decode
time
so decode time so what's what's the
difference decode time wait
uh
so for so past time string is
from this pass time dot el so let's go
to the source code
so path time string is this code here
and it's written in emac list okay
so it's here so it's written in emac
list
so apparently the decode time string
so let's close that so let's go to the
decode time
now decode time it's written in c
now i i always pay attention to that
because when something
is in c usually means it's much more
faster and more fundamental
usually you know e-magly's e-max is
written in c
and the lisp you know you have uh
you have a core c code then
then a big chunk then then
a big part of it is this written in this
itself so anyway decode time string uh
probably introduced so before emacs
version 19
uh version 19 which is around 2000 2000
also year 2000 so this function does not
change global state yeah okay um
including the match data you know i'm
not sure why they mentioned that
of course it is it seems irrelevant
because
the match data is only usually changed
by
by functions that deal with um search
string when you do a search
string yeah any anyway so so decode time
uh decode decoder time value as
second minute hour day month year d o w
d s
t u t c off okay
the option time is the time value to
convert
okay the option time so
okay so uh
so anyway i want to know what is dow so
search for dow
okay here it says dow day of the week
oh obviously an integer between
zero to six okay where zero is sunday
okay dst
is uh daylight saving time oh okay
and tc utc off
is an integer indicating
indicating the utc
offset in seconds oh that's
advanced offset in seconds
well that's that's just the time zone
isn't it yeah
so it's a you know so em at least did it
in kind of a weird way
so in other languages i think usually
you know the utc it's like a zone
difference you know like for example
some
california san francisco is eight hours
uh slower than the green switch meantime
than the utc but anyway emacs has this
utc off and that's in terms of
seconds yeah the number of seconds is of
green switch
greenwich
okay so decode time
anyway
uh i think so how am i doing
am i doing hey good morning kang xiao
guang
so we had to talk about mathematical
language today
day of week yeah
so winnie says i enjoyed reading rfcs on
my e-reader for bedtime reading
yeah you are probably a unix fan
you know unix is dead today it died
it's killed by linux
uh you know linux is sometimes supposed
to be unix sometimes not depending on
on on the politics at the point at the
moment
so anyway so anyway unique
so what what are we doing are we going
to continue doing this
this is tedious okay so anyway so
there's a difference
here let's make a note of it let's just
leave it okay let's try the next one
so the unixc format i guess it's going
to be different too
and you know the problem is that
it's probably the same but
the basically the the last number will
be different okay so xo so let's do this
so let's copy this pc here
let's um wait so let's
evaluate that so yeah so it seems
all the same you see the difference
the difference is just the
how do you call that the
the dst okay so before
apparently in e-max version 25 it didn't
understand
daylight saving time wait let's see what
does negative one mean
so dst
oh unknown okay there it is so unknown
dst value is returned as negative one
while before it's just near so it makes
no difference
you know this is for some reason e max
27 decided
that unknown is negative one instead of
nil
i don't know why but
so let's try this okay so let's just try
it
yeah so it it it it always return neo
now so it's annoying so i have to
you know why don't we just change all
the values
in this buffer change the last nail to
negative one
so that for example we change this to
then we run this and it return true then
we know there is basically no change
yeah so let's do that so neo-neo
parenthesis
go to the top uh find and replace
neo-neo parenthesis
replaced by negative one nil okay do it
uh yes here yes
yes yes yes yes yes okay
so now go to the top and
and change this to negative one two so
we're gonna
evaluate to see to see if this
uh to see if uh past time string in e
max 27
understand this this format unixc format
okay
if it returns true because there's an
equal comparison that means yes
otherwise no red true okay next
uh remove that format reminder okay
remove the
let's ignore that so when it's true
uh this we don't care we just added that
today
and when this true
when it's true right
true red true
right true right true it's all true
delete the buffer close that undo
back to our html page
so all these sections these
formats okay these are supported formats
of past daytime string
it they are still supported now what's
interesting
is this section this section is
unsupported let's see um
okay i'm hot here
in california we have a crisis emergency
actually you know the on twitter it says
you know from the government it's an
emergency
because of heat and there's also fire
burning
burning in the mountains so it's super
hot
so let's let's test let's test uh see
this unsupported format to see if
there's any change
supported format and what is this
testing for supported format for
past time string oh we have a
uh jesus here is a 2016
what's the difference e max 25
wait why is it repeated twice
oh it's not repeated i just separated
because we are testing some different
formats
uh yeah usa convention like formats
okay we should combine these two
together
you know it's just uh so next one
so test iso iso formats
yes yes no no okay this okay
so you can see some of them return snow
you can see this uh okay so that's what
what shall we do here uh
make a backup of the of the buffer and
uh let's um
okay let me let me think what to do
we're gonna do this faster because right
now it's becoming a rambling
okay so okay so what i want to do now is
to merge
these different sections of code so we
have just one
that's a decision about um
okay here go to the bottom
and here
delete that paste the code
here then
here delete that
then paste the code near the bottom so
we have
all the code together
so and uh let's search for that that's
the same
for all three of them let's search for
that
one two three three occurrences so we
delete that
delete that and this this part is also
repeated several times
require pass time so we don't need that
we don't need that okay and meanwhile
let's add a
code section
let's add a code section here so that
you see so that we have a code section
yeah so okay so
and and now let's again uh
change that to negative one
um
okay so we did this before let's see
uh so this part
this part is no the date is new
okay so let's try try this okay try this
part
so we want to check if it understand
this
this format august first one
one st so
um so let's copy
paste it here let's put negative one
here run it true um
okay true means no no good because
august august is eight
however the date part should be one but
it says neil so it didn't
understand this one st
thing okay
so that it understand
let's run it okay
and this part right okay so anyway i
i think um
so now some us formats so you see
this format is very common in usa
number slash number slash year very
common you know
usa is month date slash
you know month slash date slash and the
year
so let's see if it understand it
so if we copy the code put it here
control you evaluate expression
it doesn't understand it because you see
you see it returns 2001 jesus
completely wrong so that's why i say you
know the
emacs pass time stream facility is not
that
flexible um because this is
a you know this is a very common format
in usa
okay but i think you get idea what uh
what i'm doing you know you you get
ideas you know you
of this function you know this it
doesn't also doesn't understand this
format
now what about the iso 8601 format
so uh this one let's say
1 8 2007 so it understand and this
format
just 2000 just a year it understands
and this format a year two digit year
dash two digit month it doesn't
understand it
neither okay let's try it uh
ctrl u evaluate buffers so it doesn't
understand it it's all neo
hot
so you can see you know the iso is a
universal it's a it's kind of the
the iso 8601 format is kind of the
international standard format and that
is
that format is used in terms of
technologies
in atom you know in iss feed in
on the web most and the most on the web
too
um you know the americans americans
don't like this format because americans
they like the unix thing the unix
like like this one this is a
typical the unix
um thing okay that that's it i think um
that's it about this thing
let's let's just close the whole thing
okay d the buffer undo undo and do
return to our
two way where it
where it was
so we we explained you know the so
that's the main thing past time string
that's a function to pass them
it's possible that emacs added more
functions
since since five years ago i don't know
i
i'm guessing not i'm guessing not
but you never know so you have to look
at you know see the
let's let's look at okay because i'm
using emacs 27 which just came out uh
two weeks ago so control h
n for the e max news
so you can see here is uh
uh this this this is the installer
you know emacs 27 news file
uh then now let's search date okay let's
just search for uh this
matching line state to see if it
oh there it is you see a new package
to pass iso 8601 time
date durations and
now now after after 20 years now
e-max has this feature
let's look let's go there and look
and the proportional found for reading
so a new package to a new package
to pass iso 8601 time date durations
and intervals has been added the main
function to use
is iso 8601 pass
but there is no but there's also iso
8601 pass state and so on okay
so the main function is this one now
which
package is this form i probably the same
package fantastic okay anyway
so i'm we let's try it right away let's
go
and try it uh you know reading
reading the news file paid off so
actually today
is worthwhile we found the new uh
functions
this this is the function so let's make
it a
uh you know let's go let's try to pass
it just like before
so what's the
so here's the code okay magnify
so here's what we need to do let's um
let's
let's uh first of all describe function
there it is oh it's in a different
package it's in this package
it's not in past daytime okay so open
the source code
magnify magnify so this is the function
and go to the bottom
it says provide and also you need that
so instead of provide we say um
require okay
so uh
r e okay uh uh q-u-i-r-e okay so that's
how you tell emacs to load it so run the
code
so we loaded that then we describe
function yeah that's a function so
so the syntax is like that okay
and the string okay so we we have to
type some
some kind of date there and but what
does it return let's look at the
uh describe function again
so it says pass an iso date time string
and returns a decode time so it returns
the same thing
as the past time string okay
so so far so good and
optional form so what does the option of
phone mean so let's see
what's the second argument form the uh
so
strings like that like that that that
incomplete strings like that that are
valid too okay fantastic so we have
so emax has improved so we can look back
at the page
and look at some of the things it did
not support
you know no no no so you know you see so
so um wait
yeah that's why i separate them into
different sections for example this one
and this one it doesn't support but now
it does
so let's copy that let's try
let's try it here so paste it
so actually let's just let's just
put that out okay
so let's see if it supports now
so that's the stream we want
okay now run it
it works because you see 2007
august there it is 2007 oops
so so yes
okay yes and what about this one
okay this one okay what about it let's
see
uh wait
okay so copy that paste it here replace
this by by the iso thing
ah there okay wait
okay so here here it is so we're gonna
run this code
shrink a little bit we're gonna run this
code to see if it works
control u eval last
so this is 2001 check
august check first check
11 o'clock check 15 minutes check 37
seconds
check and this is uh
negative o7 time zone so that's
california time
uh does that check
it seems to check i'm pretty sure that's
probably yeah
you know stupid emacs it uses a number
of seconds
so 7 times 60 times
60 is this number probably let's let's
try it okay
7 times 60 times 60
okay there it is
2 5 2 0 0 a check
so okay so that's it i think that's it
for today we talked for
long um philippe
philippe says negative one is no info
available right did you do a stream
about
numerical integrators double
integrators yet oh my god that's a
that's a serious math topic no i haven't
done that and i wouldn't know what to do
about that
are you talking about math the
numerical integration
well actually numerical integration it's
not difficult
it's popular it's calculus you know it's
calculus
i can i can do that so is that what
you're talking about
philip thomas but i think that's it for
today uh so we talked about emac this
inserting date time in different formats
and passing day time
so i'm going to you know so i'm going to
update my page you know i'm going to
work
offline i'm going to update my tutorial
on this page after
you know after uh four years basically
so there are some improvements in emac
lisp
so actually i i wrote a daytime password
function
that passes some of the iso uh
time formats that emacs didn't
understand
so i you know so i wrote it before so
now i can improve it
because there are some building uh
things okay so i think that's it
for today uh if you like my stuff uh you
know if you like my talk show buy my
emacs tutorial okay
we talked for 53 minutes
thank you guys for coming
bye
you