good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show today is September
6th Friday
niall o'clock p.m.
San Francisco time and I am three
minutes early
so since I'm famous early I'm just going
to work on something on my blocks and
heal until people come seen then we're
gonna do something okay so right now I'm
just going to walk on my blog so you see
this window is all my Emacs commands if
you don't know what I'm doing you can
just look at it
it will show my the command name so so
here is my Emacs blog so people if you
are here comments and let me know what
topic you like me to talk about today
okay so right now I'm just going to work
on my blog okay okay so I need to work
so yesterday we did a talk show on Emacs
Lisp regular expressions so if you are
Emacs user or if you are interested in
coding eMac B's you know check out
yesterday's video Emacs this tutorial
and what I need to do is that I have
this tutorial that I need to add some
more information because yesterday we
talked about a technique to
automatically convert regular expression
syntax from interactive commands to a
string to be used in eMac this function
so there is a way to automatically do
that
so which is actually here this is my way
this is my talk show page you can see
every time I make a talk show I kind of
log it in my own website so here's a
video
I have JavaScript off but if you have
JavaScript on you can see it and here's
the URL sorry that info this is my local
version so we talked about you know
these subjects and here are the in tech
you know the notes you know I was
talking in a talk show I also write it
down so so you get a sense of what we
talked about and so there is a technique
to convert okay which is here what I
need to do is I need to put this into my
Emacs this regular expression tutorial
so that's you know so I'm just working
on my blog hey good morning
uber fun uber fan mm haven't seen you
before
where are you from it's open to upper
Francis augmented reality I love your
live stream thank you always a pleasure
to hear that was just in San Francisco
wondering what you think about augmented
reality I tried the magic beep had ATT
flagship store by Union Square have you
know you know actually so I don't know
anything about augmented reality morning
good morning Barry Oh Perry Oh another
new guy so where you from say you know
type a country or city so a buffin says
about augmented reality you know that
thing has been around for a while now so
I I joined
Second Life I don't know if you guys
know Second Life let me show you ok so
by the way type of topic ok so if you
guys want me to talk about Python Kol
and eMac be something type of topic so
we talked about that otherwise you know
it's just bit let the thoughts run free
so let me show you
my second life second life what's going
on okay so second life blog is your blog
okay so in browser and second life
introduction to Second Life this is
second life and it it it is was
fantastic this is kind of the first well
a virtual reality you know Second Life
kind of so they have you know all these
are inside Second Life for example this
thing rpoud by people everything in
Second Life you see is filled by people
second life in general is just like a
it's just like a 3d game you know today
you have lots of 3d games first-person
shooting or Zelda you know very
realistic graphics so what is Second
Life Second Life is kind of you know it
appears like a 3d game except everything
inside is actually built by people it's
not exactly a game because there is no
call there is it's nothing like you
going and you have to you know take that
you know beat the monster so or do
something nothing not no code no go
whatsoever it is it is exactly just like
be your life you know what you want to
do depends on you you can you can be a
politician you get you know anything you
know there's no Naoko or anything so
everything is second eye there's you
know thousands of different communities
just like real life you know people two
different things you can be a politician
you can be against a prostitute
businessman or just normal people or
artists Oh weird
you know weird people oh you know you
can be a hobo in fact they're people you
know in second I hope hobos you know
like living on the street you know kind
of so so it's extremely diverse you got
furry this particular place math so you
can walk around inside the dome you can
look around you know just like a 3d
stuff and people have peered incredible
amazing things for example this place is
a
emulation how you could emulation of the
wheel this place Mont saint-michel I
think that's in France or somewhere
around it's a you know it's it's kind of
a castle like what year is it
so anyway anyone know this face it's
kind of you know it becomes tourist
place you know in France or somewhere
around there or Italy or something so
you know it's a it's a it's a monk's
castle something like that you know
monastery so Mont saint-michel is a
rocky tidal island and a commune in
Normandy France okay
it is located approximately one
kilometer Braga and anyway so this is
there's a Wikipedia article on it but
anyway so people have build all these
interesting things and there here it is
avatars you know the you can you can
dress yourself however however you like
for example if you have a girl or even
if you are a boy you can yourself can
look like Alice this one is this is me
this this girl with this funky hair
that's me and that's my friend she is
fantastic she's and in this guy but ok
so sick when I talk about second life I
lived in second I for four years so
almost like every day I spend four more
hours every day for at least four years
from from 2007 to about 2011 every day
for years so I you know it's like your
life you're living it basically so your
life you know a lot of people you met
people and and sometimes you met in real
life afterwards so she her she's janessa
oh I hope I'd know her you know she's
Janet janessa I saw I haven't talked to
her for like
nine years her name is janessa and this
guy was my is is her boyfriend [ __ ] you
know we are friends we are all know each
other so they they actually met in real
life and became couple so anyway so you
know so you have Alice you have you know
you have tremendous bunch of things and
so that's second life and here's another
Alice Alberta and she's another friend
she's in Sauk Sacramento in USA you know
and okay look at this skeleton you know
this is a variation of the sonic sonic
hedgehog that is me you know you can
change your avatars but look at her she
is sexy you know the oldest avatars you
can be anything you know you can be you
know a girl a dress a pretty slave so a
monster a dragon a furry or a soldier
like this guy we were playing
first-person shooter games in Second
Life so he is he is one of the our team
anyway that's you know there's a huge
amount of story so you know these are
some animals or furries you know today a
lot of people that millennial generation
they like to be furries and and this
these are not exactly
furries you know like these are just
animals but they are also furries I'm
gonna show you well you know because I
have like thousand hundreds hundreds of
pictures so he's gonna so I may not talk
talk about that and these different
buildings cathedrals exact is exotic
buildings you know all these are like 3d
stuff like you can walk on a you know
you can walk on this bridge and look
around or go inside you know so it's
quite amazing and remember let me say
this again everything in Second Life is
built by people just like you you and me
I you know I've never been to something
great like this but
there are so many odd eccentric people
and artist types you know they just do
this and yeah so you know and you play
you you know you just have fun to
whatever you know here is some high tech
architectures and this one for example
is build a by a mathematician
this is rhombic buildings you can
actually go inside and then you have
some company companies via this ok so
back to the question ok augmented
reality augmented reality I actually
never had any experience except second
life which is not exactly reality I mean
I mean when we talk about you know
virtual reality today we think of
goggles right yeah but also I never
actually know much or anything or done
anything like that so yeah no no because
partly because I don't have money you
know you have to have money to buy those
goggles and you have to I saw I never
looked into any of those but there is
like today you have augmented reality on
earth on the phone on a cell phone where
you know when the phone shows a camera
right you see you see stuff but then
some 3d object can appear in the phone
screen you know and you can rotate it
that I kind of looked into a little bit
I'm not I don't find it particularly
interesting yeah so anyway that's that's
about second life so you know if you
want me to talk about more second life I
can and so second life you know these
are second life here is a pregnant woman
and he is a woman girl with you know
nose rings and stuff
okay we're getting we Kenny we're
getting into some realm
anyway so let's show okay and also this
is fantastic this you know this one this
is a kind of a vehicle okay so you see
this giant mo night you know it's a it's
a extinct animal this thing but you can
write on it so she her name this this
woman Beth Bathsheba
she is a mathematician you might have
seen her sculptures because she sell her
sculptures let me show you so I met her
she is also she was this she was in
second life and she make these math
sculptures I don't know if you have seen
you can buy they are you know you can
buy these masks cultures and she's got
okay so that's what she look like right
now
anyway so look at this one crank climb
bottle now this is actually a can can
opener so you can open pierce with it
let's see if I can okay I don't have
JavaScript own but you can so anyway she
you know she make those and she in
Second Life she be oh this thing this
thing is you know what you call it's
called a veto so basically you can write
on it and this thing blow fire you know
that's so we had a lot fun so second
life is fun like that so you write this
thing you know and you just chat you
know talk about just like we are doing
right now you you know which you chat
about whatever technology whatever
interest to you and for example this
someone build this this is this is you
know in religion
in Asia in China you have the concept of
hell I mean in Western you have concept
of hell but in Asia you also have that
however the the concept of Hell is
rather different okay on a whole they
are kind of similar you know where it's
you know when you die you go to hell in
western religion you go to heaven or
hell
okay similar things happen in China you
know in Chinese religion you have hell
when you did bad in life you go to hell
and hell looks like that so this is the
you know the Eastern ASEAN can't you
know kind of picture depiction of hell
and you have okay then you have Japanese
you know Japanese buildings then you
have this what what is is 18th century
how do you call this rigged shape you
know they have names you know for these
ships very technical jargons you know
people build it so anyway that that's
Second Life so okay let me go back to
read comments
okay so comments guys not not enough
comments comments so I don't know if I
let's see how long I have been talking
sixteen minutes okay comments and pick a
topic so good morning Abdul so Barry Oh
says hikes on uber phone is in Toronto
oh okay
visits pay area every few months Isis oh
that's great that's fantastic opened ooh
uber fun uber uber fun uber fan so you
are are you following me because of the
my eMac stuff that's how you found me oh
oh how did you find me okay okay Barry
oh is from Houston Texas Texas Houston
okay which is famous for Houston we got
a problem
and good morning George where's George
from oh my god you know he's
embarrassing if I forgot are you the one
from Sacramento okay either Sacramento
or Southern California or Australia yeah
if you put some more info I remember
so Berio says personal question how do
you manage to live in one of the most
expensive places in North America advice
it's not admirable at all well how do I
you you just do I mean I guess I mean I
have roommates you know we share
roommates you know I have and see one
two three four four other guys so total
of five people and right now the rent is
$2,300 yeah two rooms two bedroom two
bedroom apartment one bathroom $23,000
in Mountain View which is the most kind
of the most expensive place right now
because you know because Google Facebook
you know all these programmers are here
and my roommates are they are they
working restaurants they don't know
anything about technology they didn't
you know it's um they didn't graduate
high school you know they never went to
high school so they are not they don't
know what the [ __ ] is you know
programming or physics so you know so
they but they work in restaurant right
well typically so if you go you know
work at McDonald's for example you make
about three thousand dollars a month
three thousand dollars a month if you
work in McDonald's you know minimum wage
that's basically how much they make and
I make I make one thousand dollars a
month so I'm I'm below the minimum wage
you just you just one day I'll be gone
you know I don't know what I don't have
a plan so you know so George so okay so
Barry Oh Houston okay
so Barry oh you also found me from my
Emacs tutorial right or something else
let me know
so George says interested to hear your
opinion Oh ms in SQL okay what is our ms
getting really sick of our ms lately
don't see the problem with just using
SQL so I don't know what is our ms I'm
actually kind of old and outdated with
regards to technology object object
relational mapping okay that is the
worst [ __ ] possible okay I never I will
never use it
if a company use it I will not work for
that company whatever that is I don't
know I don't actually know much about it
but one time this is like three years
ago I started to you know kind of trial
in this company and they use a you know
they use Python and you they use a
object relational kind of database so I
try to read about it
it's crap okay I I not okay that's fast
opinion but I don't I don't like it at
all I don't like anything anything
object-oriented programming like I said
many times in my life in 30 years of
coding I never caught anything
object-oriented unless you know you know
company if you you know you have to
follow whatever is already there but in
my own thing I never ever use a object
never so in JavaScript for example I
just do in JavaScript IG so
you are functional so yeah so that's
about object eight object relational
mapping what the [ __ ] you know that it's
no good that's my personal opinion I
would not even learn it SQL now SQL is
classic and it's unavoidable
you know database in fact database where
but you do programming and when there is
a database that's kind of a hallmark of
industrial serious programming you know
whenever you got the database involved
so it's kind of so that's critical
SQL I haven't actually coded SQL for I
guess for 15 years okay but I know desk
you inside out okay it was you know I've
used Oracle database but mostly I've
used MySQL I've read the entirety of
MySQL documentation kind of from cover
to cover at least in 2005 that's when I
did a contract job for Stanford
University the Hoover Institution they
abuse you know they you you got someone
who abuse EE you know I got paid very
cheaply but you know she is taking all
the money so Hoover you know Hoover
Institution is kind of a organization
that's related that somewhat I don't
know exactly what's a relation but it's
part of the Stanford University in Palo
Alto here you know the Stanford
University it's a big Ivy League Ivy
League university so they have this
Hoover Institution which is I think
right wing you know whatever they you
know I think like think-tank Hoover
Institution is kind of like right we
think tank I think so Hoover Institution
and they need you know they need some
they need to create a website so anyway
so apparently there are a lot people the
independent mat managers they don't code
okay so that she you know she took the
job and she has me walk walk on it so I
get I get paid pretty I think you know
it's like dirt cheap you know it's
almost like and she she she gets the
money yeah I don't know how exactly how
much but but anyway this is two thousand
five so I did that and so yeah so at
that time I read the entirety of my SQL
manual well I read basically or manuals
before I have read but that's just
almost like a second time anyway that's
about SQL and I have never used
basically since that that's my last big
project I can kind of my last big
industrial project so that's 2005 or
2006 and in the end I have not used any
no SQL database you know that Gradius or
whatever among [ __ ] and whatever I have
not used it I you know I don't know
exactly what you know I never used them
so so okay so today's I guess just
question-and-answer session random topic
so keep the comments coming okay guys
come on ingesting keep the comments
coming so Barry oh say is okay so George
says interested to hear your opinion on
him okay so yeah I don't do him George
say Second Life trolling griefing videos
are my guilty pleasure yeah so in Second
Life
I also learned you know I'm kind of
older like I'm 51 now so back back then
you know doing the my second life days I
was like 45 whereas most people are
you know king or 20s you know the gamers
you know and so I learned you know I
like to explore different people and
what they do and stuff so I learned a
lot the gamers jargons what they are
like for example you know we play
shooter games let me show you okay so
here are furries okay
so you got these furries we are part of
this group this soldier group called
Sonic Syndicate in Second Life you know
we are so Second Life it's very diverse
so you have people playing in
first-person shooter games you have
artists you know just like real life
they are like infinite number of the
worst things you know you can do
whatever you want just like real life
so anyway one of the community is where
not a lot of time is first-person
shooter with teams so I mean this
military called Sonic Syndicate it's all
created by people you know so if you you
know you can start a military and you
know you can start then there are other
militaries this tremendous amount of fun
okay and for example I remember this
girl she is a woman from Florida or
somewhere around there okay oh my god
she is you know so and she's a gamer
girl you know she take money for guys
you know and she got me to pay her I did
I did too
you know anyway so she is a leader of
this Sonic Syndicate and by the way like
I said everything you see in second life
is spewed by people so including the
avatars whatever whatever you see you
know this you know the gun or whatever
you know anyway so here's a furry this
this is me okay and this soldier is from
another military I forgot the name
anyway there are some videos ok so we
had tremendous amount of fun well okay
so I don't have JavaScript on here so
you don't see the videos so let's go
here
go to Chrome and now you see the videos
so this is a battle this is Sonic
Syndicate this is our pace and this
another military is invading us so we
have you know the ground fight we also
have airplane in fact you can you know
let's play a little bit so that's our
base it's kind of a this is a my let me
show you okay
I remember her she is a mixed Asian I
think he's eonni and mixed with white
people blood I think you know so this is
so we were fighting and there's also
airplane above the you know the airplane
fight so this guy just died so that
that's why he got respawn back here so
this is Second Life you know
and this is our base Sonic Syndicate you
know everything you see is peeled by
people you know and and you know so you
know we had a lot of fun the weapon
systems everything weapon systems you
have to write probe you have to code it
so I code a lot you know I caught a lot
of things so here's another video
MongoDB is [ __ ] ok so here's another
video this is professionally made by
this odo ok another military group is
called Auto Imperia Imperial s ok and
they have a professionally made video
let me play it what the [ __ ]
wait this shouldn't be so they banded
this music wmg music group banded based
on copyright and I don't think these
companies so this is old dog very you
know if you are in second life and if
you play you know meet at secondary
military in second life then you know
this this group odo
which is which which is the largest
military in second life in their video
is down you know I haven't been to
second life since about 2012 so I guess
you know maybe it's all guns you know I
don't know
and here's another video this is another
military group called mustn't here's all
the videos gone
Jesus anyway so that's about second life
so let me let me see the comments oh
yeah so about trolling
I also learned so I learned tremendous
things about trolling and griefing and
stuff you know the cave mass of the
things they do in there jargons so let's
see and they are trimming there's so
many jargons you know the gamers jargons
once you are like there are so many
different games in full you know gamers
community so that ye you know you have
jargons you have you have to be there to
know because you have to be inside oh
just like you know programmers like and
and often they are they are on the spot
so they are so much fun you know like
they capture the memes or the you know
the meme of the day or whatever it's
it's a lot fun I forgot where but
there's a grief grief is what what what
grief is about is that there are people
you know in Second Life or I guess in
other games where there's they just go
in there their purpose is just to
to break anything by all means possible
you know they go into they do things to
violate things to you know make a mess
of by all means possible sometimes using
variables or whatever you know stuff so
that's queefing so in second life that
happens a lot for example you can you
can go in you can well it's hard to
explain you unless you know you know
once you know a lot to say about that so
okay so let's see what other comments
second electron in Griffin videos yeah
and actually you go to youtube you'll
see it you just type search for a second
I've griefing so urban uber uber fan of
offenses try the magic leap Gaga said 88
AT&T flagship store I don't even know
where that is because I don't go out I
don't have a car so it's free it uses
SAR am to position itself in a room it's
interesting my name is Emerson Emerson
by the way M I don't know what aim stand
for thank you for your response
so SEO am I don't know what that is
single-lens something so yeah you know
virtual reality you know that's coming
you know that's becoming more and more
of reality you know like we're gonna
leave believe me matrix and yeah that's
that's a big topic I don't know what you
know what will happen but but right now
for me I have not tried anything any car
goes you know I'm but it's this is very
interesting because I look forward I
mean not exactly but you know imagine
there's a human brain and machine into
that's the ultimate virtual reality yeah
you know like like the matrix where you
just connect and you you are into some
warehouse you don't know it's real or
not and that's becoming more and more Bo
more interesting
pareo says I believe I found you through
the Emacs tutorials okay great but later
realize that we probably share many
thoughts and thinking style great
so Barry oh and and I'm schizoid - oh
okay
with some paranoid tendencies int P cool
Barrios so Barrios from Houston okay so
let's keep in touch you know you have
you know like over the years because you
know as you know as a ski sword usually
you don't make friends I mean like II
thought so let me you know I'm telling
you my experience you know because in
the past 10 or 20 years I've met you
know kind of few people who are you know
also INTP and ski so it you know we
share a lot common interest and
personality - and a lot of you I suppose
you know you know or hope you probably
we share a lot of things but but it's
like over the years I realized you know
you you know I don't stick you know like
like doing this week you know I owe you
guys we talk a lot but then after we get
after a month okay or after year it's
good you know you there's no like
permanent kind of friendship or
connection why I think because it's
partly just because schizoid oh yeah you
know because of me
I don't you know and on the other hand
what do I do
I mean I don't what you know so I don't
know what to think about that you know
so yeah but anyway so what I'm saying
what I'm saying is that you know
in the past 20 years I know a lot of
people who have you know strong interest
and and what can you do you know it's
not just about me but also I guess in
general friends you know unless you
happen to work together or nearby they
may be you us establish more permanent
and seeing each other you know at least
every year or so but otherwise online it
tends to just go away you know he tends
to just be a fumarole so above so okay
so maybe Barrios
so Aptos says can I ask you about your
opinion about sale force to build up a
row I don't know nothing about sales
force I heard about it
justin is trying to say oh I am is [ __ ]
read it is [ __ ]
oh let Redis is pretty useful oh okay
and but MongoDB is [ __ ] okay show show
they are all [ __ ] except Redis is useful
okay I never used any of them so Aatish
says sighs a question about the topic
UNIX sucks do you know Nix OS I know
Nick OS never use it or do you know GUI
x SD no I don't know that one seems to
be the evolution of Unix I recommend
that you take a look okay sure Oh
griefer oh no I never thought about that
George say squivers could do a lot
damage with a direct interface to your
brain yes yeah so we haven't you know so
you know the AI is coming and the
automated you know driverless car they
are prone to be hacked you know that's
gonna I think that's bound to happen
you know like on one hand you think you
know with you know we can we can create
a system that is full that's that's you
know proven math mathematically proven
to be unhackable you know on one hand I
think you know maybe you know because
math you know yes you know you you know
with the proof systems proof theories
you actually could have a system that is
bulletproof you know software but on the
other hand you can be quite sure because
well first of all many of the hacks are
not necessarily you know it's not entire
software especially today many hacks are
done by human you know so-called social
engineering
you know I call your phone company I say
oh I forgot my phone number I need to
change it something then I got your
phone number then I break into whatever
your Google bank accounts you know
that's that's hacking but but not by
breaking password by by by social
engineering so yeah so you don't know we
exactly what's going to be happen you
know all these driverless cars or if you
have you know direct interface to the
brain you know then it seems likely it's
gonna be problematic I mean it's gonna
be chaotic just like today you have
hackers every day you know it's more
almost every day we hear new so hackers
spoke to this AT&T and beaked you know
why maybe and one medium passwords in
the banking information every day and
you don't you don't you you know it's
like every day you know every every
month
well at least every year you have that
you know the big companies doing that
you know yeah that's that's a problem
and I got a you know so I feel that this
is going to keep happening
you know regardless whatever you know
proof systems in software you know this
hacking is gonna just keep happening so
it's gonna be with us so it's like we
have this rather dystopia kind of in in
many science fiction movies you have
kind of this dystopia where the future
it doesn't looks like one great bright
city rather you have this little camps
talk you know ugly messy hubs you know
different faces talk and you know you do
do all kind of things different groups
like actually we are like that today so
many different little groups you don't
know what they are and you know
different communities you know you know
underground your otherwise then you have
these mainstream corporations they're
doing their things you know it's
and look at today's politics you have
you know China Western powers and you
know Western countries you have left and
right you know social justice can
fighting each other
and you know and then you cry Russia you
know the poutine OSHA is doing things
and you know so it's kind of I think
it's kind of chaos chaotic so yeah with
the future I think it's it's not going
to be a pretty picture unless unless you
are just a Everage person you don't want
to know them to nothing you know you're
happy just you are happy just to be to
be the matrix you know you have a car
you work hard you know you get a car you
get a wife you have a house you know you
go your normal way you live a happy life
like a pet like a pet you know like your
pet who doesn't want to go outside you
know who live and die in your home so
you are gonna be unless you are like
that you know you are no more people you
know leaving a matrix you are happy but
outside of this you have you know all
these different things going on that's
what I think that's that seems to be the
case so let me continue the comments
okay Barrios Justine says MongoDB
Schoeneck saw question okay so at a
stash says some question about topic
UNIX sucks do you know Nix OS yes I know
Nick OS Nix OS is basically a correct me
if I'm wrong okay because I have egg
this is this Common Lisp phonetic friend
okay I have a friend who is him he's a
common this coder and he he used he at
least used to work for this company that
creates this I think airplane tickets
website you know you buy a plane tickets
that's written in common list and Google
about it whether word anyway any anyone
know the name type it okay I forgot the
name you can google such you'll find it
so there is a company that do airplane
tickets that's written in common list
and Google about it like you know
probably seven years ago or ten so
anyway I have this friend who is very
much into common list and he told me
about Nick's OS like he's a big fan of
Nick's OS he tells me to use it every
day on Google+ back then you know Google
cured Google+ but anyway he he told me
about Nick's OS so as far as I know
Nick's OS is a Linux distro that that
you use functional programming to manage
all the packages and dependencies that's
idea Nick OS now I don't know what is
GUI X s T so you know so let's let's
look up then okay hold on a second where
is the
oh how do I get back to God curses GUI x
SD GUI oke my god you know wherever I
seek no I know it's not gonna be good
you rather just use NYX OS so I suppose
this is a ghost version of NYX OS so new
GUI exists a cross-platform package
manager and the tool to translate and
manage an operating system to
instantiate and manage an OS for
unix-like OS based on next package
manager with Kyle scheme API and
especially I seen forever okay I don't
you know offhand I immediately know this
is probably no good because it doesn't
work lots of bugs you have to do this or
that then I'm on the people every day
they are going to tell you oh you know
Linux oh free software foundation you
know they are you know they are living
in this ideology and you will make no
money
whatever whatsoever doesn't matter how
much you contribute it and every time as
soon as you say something different
opinion they all the people will
alienate you you yeah that's that's what
this is like like Emacs in any way so
where is my I want to get my comments
back Jesus you know Mac OS you have this
issue once that wants you
but heck
I want to get the comments back
he stole a chat okay
so - - we are you from like what city or
country so Abdo says that make
developers in sync I'm very special what
makes the better person silk I'm very
special I don't think they are special
programmers here they are special
because they can say on the resume oh I
work for Google and Facebook you know
they all think there are big shots
that's that's what makes them special
they think they are big shots they think
they know everything they say they think
they can they think they can solve
humanity by technology you know that's
the people at Google Facebook you know
and today you know back in 10 years ago
or 20 years ago if you work at Google I
highly respect you okay you are the
great you are a great programmer you
know so much you know you are far above
average but today if you okay Google
you are probably I don't know what what
you are and I don't even know what you
are you know and a lot of Googlers you
know they are many of them they don't
even know I don't think they know much
about programming and stuff you because
they are today you know they are into
social justice stuff and and ok Google
yeah they are a dime a dozen you know
Google so it becomes so yeah so what
makes developers in Silicon Valley
special
yeah well offhand you know I I'm not
sure what you are thinking but what I'm
thinking is nothing is special except
they are full of themselves you know
when you you know when you when you work
at Google you know the big companies
then you have a fancy car you have money
you have lots of money this [ __ ] you
you know you you drive Tesla and you
think you are above it you know but you
know when you are like when you have
money or when you are rich you don't see
it you know like I remember where I was
working our company I am I'm like above
you know I'm above others you know
because why because I know a lot of
program
you know I worked I worked myself to get
that you know I think you know it's kind
of like it is it just happens naturally
so these people you know and these
Google us you know this Facebook they
think they think they also think not you
know they think they are better than
others because they are smarter
you know they know programming and stuff
in there that's why they are at Google
that's what they think generally if I
mean this many of these are subconscious
you know and also they think they are
morally better superior than all the
others you know yeah because they yeah
they did they do think that in general
that's my thinking yeah and so GUI xst
package manager' use skya scheme for
package definition also use kaya scheme
software to manage demon called Shiva
it becomes the Kuno official
distribution yeah okay I don't think
it's gonna go anywhere in fact I would
not be surprised this GUI x SD will will
become absolute or somewhat you know
nobody heard of you you know in a few
years maybe right now it's hard yeah I
don't think he'll go anywhere that's
typically the case with the open source
of especially free software foundation
stuff then they are just you know it's
you know you are probably a free
software fan that's why you why you
heard of it and that's why you are
suggesting it you know I was I talked
about this many times you know in my
videos I was a free software foundation
phonetic
I was Pro Richard Stallman phonetic I
was a you know his fanatical supporter
back in year 1990 starting starting in
year 1998
but not today and in fact he's become
bad rather he's become rather kind of
bad person
no anyway so if you like to hear my
opinions about that just such my YouTube
videos in the past I have many few times
I talked about that for one hour my
story with open source and free software
yes okay so Thank You Justine so ITA
Software is the company that uses common
lisp to do airplane tickets stuff like
that and got bought by Google so
attached ish is from Chile oh wow
amazing now I'm in Toronto Canada oh
okay that's great that's fantastic I
have other people over the world that's
I cannot imagine you know I was also
surprised not well not exactly too
surprised because you know a lot of my
in is you know it's kind of okay so I
don't know the you know I don't know how
to make all of these but but somehow I
think a lot a lot you know I'd like all
my stuff is in English but I I think a
lot Americans they don't you know they
don't they don't exactly like me because
because I flame you know i flame emag so
open source all the time so a lot
mainstream Americans for example those
who work at Google
those who big shots you know from the
Emax community there are quite a few you
know famous package Emacs this package
writers they don't they don't like me
okay they I know and kind of no they
don't say it because they are the type
they don't say it
you know they I kind of I can feel it
and also they are kind of in social
justice today you know they are oh we
support women like days we post women
stuff every day and and stuff well but I
don't want to I don't want you know
there are exceptions I you know I don't
want to generalize but
I think is it is true that other
Americans they don't you know they don't
follow me but on the other hand I have a
lot of followers from from Chile or you
know over the face and anyway but maybe
that's just misconcept maybe you know
that's a missed information because
maybe I'm thinking maybe actually Emacs
people actually are from over the place
you know so so I'm guessing if you guys
are following other Emacs video
youtubers and and from that account from
he will also see horse all kind of
people from from all around different
places so so what else guys what else
comments what how long we been talking
we've been talking for one hour now so
let me have a drink and today's drink is
today's drink is again it's apple juice
tree top apple juice and it says you
know it says never from you know it says
hundred percent pure pressed and it says
never from concentrate so what is what
is a difference by the way so you know
like what is exactly the difference from
and and I'm mixing it with energy drink
sugar free energy drink so it
concentrates juice you know as far as I
know you know by the way I never drink I
always drink hundred percent juice you
know it must be hundred percent so no
sugar no extra you know it was just
stuff added it's just juice but
typically it's concentrated meaning they
you know they squeeze make juice then
they perhaps try it you know evaporate
the waters out then they add water back
something like that it's concentrate
no comments guys guys say something say
something and so so that's concentrated
juice and now this one is pressed so I
guess that means you know they say never
concentrate that means they never
evaporated the water out but what is the
significance anyway
Oh George says cold-pressed preserved
more nutrients concentrate is heated to
a high temperature oh I see so that
makes sense okay so next time I always
get the 100% pure pressed apple juice
instead concentrate because usually you
have a choice and usually they are the
same price you know oh okay
oh and changes flavor once you have the
high temperature that's right
I guess that's called pasteurized right
pasteurized is like high temperature
right and okay so anything else after
says thank you for as awesome
Abdo which one is empty oh okay yeah
about Silicon Valley so after where you
from again let's pop this out
after way IFOAM again so George says
have you heard of sv3 Ridge no what is
that - - says where are you from do you
think China will be the future of the
technology you should watch my video
about Hong Kong like I had like two
videos about Hong Kong especially the
one I think yesterday you you know check
it out attached - where I talked about
where I found I talked about this few
times I was born in Taiwan at age 14 I
left Taiwan I lived in South America
Paraguay for a while then in Central
America Paraguay for a year Central
America for half a year then Canada
Vancouver and montreal montreal for
three years then in 1989 I came to an
age 21 I came to USA California so for
the past 30 years I've been living in
California USA
and about whether China you know China
is today is tremendous you know I you
know actually I think a lot of people
don't know actually screen deck here
because the other day yesterday I got a
sense he have no idea you you know you
you take a look you know like take a
look you know I'm surprised I'm a
American by the way I'm Chinese broad
but I'm American citizen since 2001 I
think 2000 or 2001 so I feel you know
China and USA is kind of like enemies
you know saying in many ways you know
but you know I have you know if you know
I've thought about if what happens if
China and USA go to war you know we are
you know who would you support it's hard
to say you know I it's not it's not like
I'm gonna support one or the other but
you know yeah so I thought about that
you know it's you need hard to say but
anyway so but you know what once the you
know I I have feelings for both you know
I'm not gonna just support one or the
other it's like you know it's not to say
it's a it's like when civil war happens
in USA you know the left social justice
[ __ ] you know versus the Conservatives
if that if I would see what happens who
you cannot support you know if you are
American the question is similar like
that but anyway so so about China
so yeah China it's amazing you know they
they have space stations they sent you
know they right now they are you know
they're sent to the moon they visit they
landed on the back side of the moon my
you know about they are tremendous you
know they are you know if you look at
the photos or videos you know just go to
youtube search for some cities and Jen
some any almost any city in China you
know you see those skyscrapers is like
Tremont
prosperity okay it's like you know like
I'm surprised I never went to China okay
but but but you cannot stop you know
seeing them I mean if you at least you
know look a little bit you you know is
in their trains you know super speed
trains and oh like and also super
computers like you know they the the
world's fastest supercomputers was China
you know I think two years ago it's USA
again but few years back it's all China
supercomputers and all that so China is
growing tremendously and they have you
know they have their own Google right
they have their own PI do and they have
you know they're shopping system is far
more advanced than USA
you know like in u.s. you have oh you
know we hero Apple pay oh you know Apple
pay or whatever Google Google Wallet
wallet but in China it's all use it you
know you don't like USA you still write
checks you don't even use credit cards
like check the credit card is not
popular in China every like the common
people not should not take heads
everybody you have a phone you just
swipe swipe it you know what you know
yeah they use what's called WeChat you
know I never used it but anyway but on
the other hand you probably heard the
the the American is talking about you
know the China credit system you know
the way the government is monitoring
everything you know that's American
that's a very calm Papa ganda okay I
tell you anyway so China is this
tremendously technological going thing
you know it's it's becoming it's a
regional power you know and you know and
in right now USA is considered you know
the global superpower and I'm not sure
how you qualify you maybe maybe China is
becoming a global superpower but anyway
it's a big thing so the question is what
we of the future be like
in ten years we all like wheel china you
know takeover USA becomes the world's
superpower or will China be fighting
with USA like the two superpowers or or
maybe other countries okay you excuse me
if I didn't mention other big countries
actually actually actually nothing comes
off hand right now it's like just China
and USA but if you have some ideas say
it okay post your opinions by the way
you know keep the comments coming so
anyway and so so the question is we what
will happen in ten years or 20 years we
will you know it's gonna be China versus
USA or is your possibility or is it just
USA China never actually you know maybe
you just stopped progressing or or maybe
China took over or some other things you
know so what will happen I don't know
actually so the my answer you know my
thinking about everything I use actually
I don't know you know no I think nobody
actually knows you know there are many
experts you know there are economic
experts they are AI experts they are you
know many China specialists you know
experts you know typically they are
Pradesh predictions historically or
wrong okay so yeah you know and so I
think did you know so I don't I don't
think anyone knows actually and also in
science fiction seeing American science
fiction's you have a lot of science
fiction's that say you know in the
future China China is taking over or
China is something or the world is
becoming three powerful global you know
groups one is like China one is USA and
Western or whatever anyway so but I
think nobody actually can say for sure
nobody knows yeah so that's what I think
yeah so
so what is what is the sv3 wage what is
it is is a guy he's some kind of a drama
YouTube you know I'm the main thing okay
so it's a guy so let's see okay that's
too big shrink so this guy cut his last
ings paranoia's sv3 which goatees is ale
latvian youtube anti-vegan activists he
is known for eating raw raw meat at
vacant he events oh okay he also
supported Flat Earth theory okay I don't
know I don't know him yeah well no I
know it's kind of the intern internet
weird yeah so are you like are you into
which it is invasion or are you into I
know there's a guy who eat did was it
you who told me who eat raw meat you
know all these internet stories Abdo is
from Egypt okay I remember and George
George is from Australia because now
once I see George type Chinese I
remember no fan that's his favorite food
that's great food ocean do van doodle
fan yeah that's a as kind of Chinese
Taiwanese rather dish that's in English
it's called how do you call that English
basically it's rice you know with
chopped-up meat you know chopped-up meat
processed chopped-up meat with sauce it
kind of like teriyaki oh yeah braised
pork rice okay let's let's braised pork
rice okay you open yeah that's his
favorite I haven't had that for for ten
years oh my god
yeah a qr-code so what about QR code I
never used to our code actually I never
used QR code in my life
so apto is from Egypt okay
and attached - attached ashes from Chile
he said is it pronounced chile or geo so
tish-tosh says what i was a beautiful my
girlfriend is from there and when I
visit her country I failed love I fell
in love of the landscape in food okay
hotpot yes so George George says I was
surprised America still make money out
of paper
when I went there what do you mean I
mean in China you also and me almost
every country that you still print paper
money right yeah so is anything else I
think that's it for today we've been
talking over now yeah so if not then we
were shut down in one minute so within
one minute you type your questions then
we may be out you know answer it
otherwise we shouldn't down in one
minute I think yeah let's see what
so back Lemieux is not here he want okay
so tomorrow actually tomorrow what time
maybe I'll do another one okay so I'll
do another one at San Francisco time 6 6
o clock
in other words 8 hours from now I think
I will do another one 8 hours from now
past you know maybe not well I think I
will I think I will 8 hours from now
8:09 okay so if you are if you guys are
interested check back my youtube yeah
eight or nine hours from right now and
George says George Neace also went back
nice nice yeah so you speak Chinese for
sure because you can type Chinese or do
you you speak and you speak and listen
Chinese right and you also write with
Chinese George George says money has
been made out of plastic in Australia as
long as I remember oh really
how is that possible I mean the kind of
paper money on so member ha okay
you mean paper money in parallel be
plastic epitope great so otherwise
that's it for today yeah so thank you
guys for coming
uber fun
whoo boffin Berio and everyone just in
by
let me try this let me try stop video
from here I cannot
well actually let me try this I want to
try this huge YouTube this control this
you know YouTube changing stuff every
every month so I you know so anyway the
video ended okay thank you guys I'm just
gonna try something and if I screw up
that's good you know it sinned so go to
live control room okay let's do that
a new stream from previous this is very
confusing what the [ __ ]
yeah okay