we decide what is right and what is an
illusion good morning today's is 2019
October 16th Wednesday 10 o clock a.m.
in the morning San Francisco time
good morning DP welcome to another
episode of Santa's Show so I have some
topics set up for you guys if you have
any questions or comments or topics you
want me to talk about type in the chat
okay good morning Liam so I'm going to
actually so I'm going to offer a Emacs
technical tutorial YouTube one on one
good morning Cathy YouTube 101 tutorial
on programming on Emacs or Emacs Lisp
from the ground up or JavaScript for
beginner or JavaScript in-depth so I'm
going to I'm going to do that for $100
for 3 hours now if you do that you know
I'm going to guarantee you for example
let's say Emacs Lisp you going to learn
Emacs Lisp you're gonna be your expert
after 3 hours so so you know or
JavaScript raw JavaScript in-depth so
I'm going to offer that so if you like
to do that
teenee email me oh you know talk to me
on Twitter or anywhere else and we can
do that this is one-on-one tutorial on
home video so that is that and ok so
let's talk about random things today
I have several topics topics here so
again if you like me to talk about
something
just just say it okay now let's say
let's go to a guru bus travels okay it's
not a code map guru bus travels so let's
search all links I have on this project
to Google Maps
okay so such Google
okay such Google enter not Google
Analytics map okay so math okay so
actually search for maps.google.com do
it again such that that that okay so oh
these are links to Google on Google Maps
they are about 20 of them so let's look
at the first one
showing browser okay this one is
commented out so this is about East
Indies search for East Indies okay so
there is my annotation oops
one second good morning Abdo good
morning - to Egypt
good morning happy to London and Liam
Liam w-where are you from Liam are you
the Liam I know and good morning to DP -
DP - Germany
okay so good Ava's travels so there is
East and the West Indies now this is my
annotation is in West Indies Liam is
from London okay great
East and West Indies it means is in this
means into Indonesia the term is
sometimes used to refer to all of
Southeast Asia historically he refers
chiefly to India okay so you have
Wikipedia article and you have Google
Maps so you have East Indies and West
Indies
let's look at Google Maps JavaScript
okay turn it on
where is very spot Bartholomew so we
have here East Indies let's see shrink
shrink why is it not showing anything
shrink shrink shrink
okay okay finally oh wait is this
correct even I thought is India so here
what is his face what countries is
Philippines Oh Indonesia right so okay
so anyway so that that is that
Gulliver's Travels and let's look at
this West Indies now these are old
jargons
Wesson Dizzy's Caribbeans why is why is
Google not showing
West Indies indeed West Indies in Cuba
okay yeah so well so is Indies in West
Indies they are far apart they are just
not easy in west of one place so West
Indies is like in Cuba so anyway that's
I wanted to show the Google Maps links
because because at some place in
Gulliver's Travels they mentioned the
eluvian Islands let's see if I can find
it
so located at South certain island of
Japan south of Korea so this is
gulliver's travels to Japan it's such
full Cape of Good Hope that's on the tip
of Africa so lots of places leeward
island so leeward islands keenya Cape of
Good Hope Laden and I'm not sure what is
that southeast of Amsterdam okay New
Guinea ax and Amsterdam Amsterdam is the
city of prostitutes that's that's how
that's what he's my impression of it
because every time I read about it it's
something about that Amsterdam so it's
such a mess okay where is that a city in
an Netherlands Laden okay
on the 9th day of June 1707 I arrived at
Nagasaki after a very long and
troublesome journey I soon fell into the
company of some Dutch sailors belonging
to
- the ambarina of Amsterdam a stout ship
of 450 tons I have lived long in Holland
pursuing my studies at Layden and I
spoke Dutch well okay this Gulliver's
Travels
there there are a lot seafaring jargons
sails you know you know this is 300
years ago so they were traveling around
the world you know that's a big thing
the Westerners exploring the earth so
deep he says I wish Google hadn't
divided
Panoramio oh they they deleted I did I
didn't know Panoramio is like a para
Rama website so many geo-located images
lost like tears in the rain yeah Google
Google started to do all sort of things
so let's look at this map this is
supposed to be Amsterdam Oh busy very
busy let's look let's shrink Zuma Laden
okay the city laden fascinating places
of the world the world is a big place on
the other hand you could also say it's a
small face the world is pretty small
Amsterdam you know that's the
flexibility and imprecision of English
because you could say you know you could
say something that's syntactically
semantically opposite yet it means
something you could you know either way
you say it's true for example you could
say politics is truly complex you know a
lot of people we are not their heads or
you could say politics is truly simple
and a lot of people we are not their
heads you see because the interpretation
is entirely a different thing so anyway
here is Amsterdam Holland Netherlands I
don't know anything about that but okay
so Amsterdam but every time you hear it
it's about drugs or prostitutes that
that is what the place is known for that
is what the media say about it all the
time you know certain countries you have
certain associations the reason the
association came up because it's
dramatic you know that's just what
people say about it
for example Germany oh it's noisy okay
and BMW and nice engineering you know
German people they have always great
engineering yes German people they are
great engineers they produce great
things
Carson stuff so number so number of
Germany where I live is supposed to have
more sex workers than Amsterdam do too
lenient leches legislation oh where is
number --g nuremberg how do you
pronounce that new nuremberg so where is
that I gotta go there okay and Kathy
says Amsterdam adult in Dodi's needle
land okay so that's that school of us
travels it's actually the Gulliver's
Travels is fairly boring okay close that
guru verse travel is fairly boring I
read it oh yeah so I was talking about
they you know they are seafaring you
know these school of us traveling around
the earth and in many of these phrases
it's not real you know half of it is
real half of it is not real and
sometimes they give the wrong coordinate
or wrong names or you know fantasy it's
a Fanta
see so for example they have one place
called la puta
okay la puta which in Spanish is like it
means prostitute or [ __ ] something like
that I forgot la puta the land of la
puta so let's let's look and it's it
became famous it became Sammy la puta
okay because it's an island of floating
islands so let's turn you know one thing
where you are knowing about DuckDuckGo
such engine is that if you have
JavaScript off like right now I have
JavaScript off you search something and
but I want to do image search but there
is no button that you go to image search
so what you have to do is you have to
turn JavaScript first of all you turn
JavaScript okay no more II for example
on Google search you after you turn on
JavaScript then you can go to an image
actually it you don't have to turn Java
scripting orders to search images but in
inductor Co ok you want to do images
image search there's no link to it then
you turn on JavaScript there is still no
link to it there is no way for you to
navigate around then go to the image
search after you turn on JavaScript
there's no way
well there's one way like you go all the
way you go all the way to the DuckDuckGo
home website and there is still none
okay then you click on the logo you go
to about then you scroll all the way
down to to the duck duck go home page
again you still cannot do it basically
you have to type your search word again
you know truly annoying Laputa
you know this is one of the interface
design issue many corporations they they
are just idiotic you know they're just
idiots okay so you see now you type the
such phrase again now you have you see
images so now we click on images Laputa
oh Jesus [ __ ] save such save such Wow
that's not okay save such ok Laputa you
have to [ __ ]
now I what do I do with that you know
now Google is gonna censor me and this
is live so I have to edit the video
afterwards god that's gonna be ours I
haven't done that before
laughs or that so I wanted to show the
flying island you see it's very annoying
that thing Google censorship Google
image via direct um information and
respond and being image via phone well
yeah you are saying using direct URL but
that's more work because you know once
you type it you have to edit you know
that's more work
of course another option is just you
know I can write scripts in Emacs but
the point is just it's just more work
so anyway right now I want to show the
flying island of you know from the memes
Laputa but now it's just going to show
me pong but I can turn safe such on
strict but if I click images I'm you
know some simple images where goes pass
through maybe you know I don't
do that very annoying this this is this
is annoying for several reasons because
well mostly because censorship and the
attitude towards pong and meanwhile it's
going crazy you know it's anyway so
wikipedia has article Laputa you know so
it came from Gulliver's Travels so this
is supposed to be this flying island and
it becomes very popular because this
floating island it's you know in cool
Ava's travels he visited this place and
they have floating island it's it's near
the end I think it's near the end of
okay this is my let's go to sorry
gurus travels because this is my local
fire which does not have JavaScript and
you cannot turn on JavaScript in brave
for local files so you have to go
through my website so near the end I
think it's one of these phase part three
a voyage to laputa Laputa there so one
of yeah Laputa it's it's a sub it's a
place where technology is beyond humans
technology so it's you know very highly
highly advanced but anyway he's he's
writing this there is some of the you
know here's a castle in the sky black
food this Japanese anime version so he
become it became a theme a meme you know
today you go at me where you have a lot
comics or animations talking about this
space but originally if you read
Gulliver's Travels it's it's
Google Gulliver's Travels is sarcasm
sarcasm you know is suppose is said to
be the best sarcasm he English
literature
so anyway
guru verse travels okay I'm I'm pissed
off about that
phone showing too because because now
I'm not sure what to do with the video
because I have to edit it you know I
have to edit it but that's gonna be like
two hours or something to do that to
just remove that you know one-second
creep but also I mean even before I
edited you know Google is gonna have you
know they have algorithms they're gonna
scan everything so they might flag me
for something truly annoying the
situation we are him [ __ ] Google and
also this you know the the social
mentality towards phone you know they
and in anyway so anyway that's Google
Maps about Guru of its travels so let's
go back what else I was going to say
yeah so I was going to find actually I
was going to find Google map let's do
the search again Google Maps
I was trying to find there is this place
called alluvia Island against it I do
not see it here
Levin Conwell UK West Indies is in this
okay
so let's search for Al are you okay
illusion Ali odd illusion illusion
okay let's search for ALU value
salutations value value okay it's a
whole bunch of value okay that's such
for space ALU none
okay let's search for space capital a
how are you not okay let's search for
space al l you illusion elude anyway in
Gulliver's Travels in one of the place
it points to nowhere on earth like like
I'm gonna show you is points to here
like the points to here somewhere and
it's it's just wrong okay because you
know remember this is 300 years ago they
don't have they don't have accurate map
of the world in fact 300 years ago I'm
not sure the West Europeans have landed
on America yet so TP says cool of a
political polemics yes TV says maybe you
can blood offending second in this
stream with YouTube online editing
editing gimmicks yeah yeah that's that's
what I'm saying but the thing is I
haven't edited videos before so I'm not
sure how to do that to do that it's
going to be like two hours you know to
try to explore you know find how to do
it that's the thing that's what I'm
saying so anyway so these some of these
maps okay close okay let's go to next
topic then guru ass travels tactile
keyboard shall we shall we talk about
keyboard or shall we talk about
JavaScript and other things let me know
okay so here I'm going to show you a
track trackball and this okay so I need
to go through my website in order for
the video to show
okay so sorry trackball spin so you can
see all track balls you know which one
spins you know if you are buying a
trackball that one thing you want that's
the best thing is if it can spin like if
you push it your spin for a few seconds
you know if it spins forever that's the
best but but no trackball actually does
that
well there's this one prototype it's
fantastic okay so refresh so let's see
what's on discord chat forum Laputa so
Laputa is one word first SafeSearch
works for me
one doctor go oh one word save such okay
so you see they some people someone
field a prototype of spinning trackball
so I guess you guys cannot hear it right
but anyway so they got this boy you push
it it just spins like for 10 seconds
it's fantastic but I'm not sure what is
the status of this trap oh it seems
nobody has made it but anyway so I ever
collected videos of all track balls
showing how much they spin for example
here's another one and I rank them this
is the second best you see now if you
can hear the sound then you can you can
see it actually spins quite freely but
this one is hard to buy it's like I
think it's 150 or 200 dollars it's hard
to buy it's not on Amazon so I have
collected several of these tripe track
balls and how much they spins perpetual
spinning tripe oh yeah that's that would
be nice okay so that's that's about
track board so JavaScript or keyboard
okay so I'm just going to go random then
so that's how keyboard there's a news
about this keyboard this is a
do-it-yourself keyboard and I've tried
this keyboard for one minute at keyboard
meetup in San Francisco I met a guy and
this is I would say it's one of the best
this one is actually better than my
Kinesis I think it's better than the one
I have this one is commercial it's
better because the thumb the thumb keys
are more fitting to dock to my thumb at
least for small hand and this is
extremely light very elegant so I like
this one very much right I find it
fantastic so this is a do-it-yourself
keyboard so you can peeled it you go to
he's got a video talking about how he
created the
keyboard from scratch and so I met him
you know at keyboard Meetup
I tried it it's fantastic and he has a
website where you go there and you can
find all the build information you can
buy the parts and build it yourself but
what's new what's new is that you
actually can buy it now pre build
everything built for you by going into
this link good morning Bart so you go so
now you can buy it for $350 you can buy
it okay you need to turn on JavaScript
when when the way I'm doing streaming
everything becomes slow I have to wait
so you can buy it and you can buy there
are several variations you can also buy
this one this one is called tactile
manual form okay so let me show you the
pictures tactile manual foam Sontag show
so you have doctor like that then you
have that Oh
tactile manual foam like that where they
put the thumbs you know you have to
press it like that instead of pressing
it downwards you press it in words they
think this way is better I'm not sure
about that anyway so this is a variation
and you can buy it now $350 pre-build
now I don't know who created this
website so I'm not sure how trustworthy
it is I think it's it works so anyway so
you can buy that's that's about that
it's a news so justin hays Justine's
good Moni interesting what do you think
of the brave browser cryptocurrency I
don't know much about it I haven't
looked into so the you know they created
a way so that while it operation fail
try again I think I turned it off
something like that I haven't looked
into and I should because actually they
have promotion where for example I can
put links to web browser and if people
use it you know I put links on my
website if people use it I get paid I
get money but I haven't done that and
also they have this program basically
break browser is trying to do a
revolutionize the ads the way ads are
running on websites because today as you
know we are very annoyed part by ads
especially Google you know Google
becoming extremely evil Google because
they used to be do no evil right and
their ads used to be for example let's
go to Saudi JavaScript okay oh you go to
my JavaScript website you know I'm using
Google Ads I make some money and you
turn on JavaScript okay so I have you
know great browser has ad blocker
building so you won't see ads with grave
you have to go here then you create a
new window and paste my link JavaScript
then you can see Google ads plastered
all over the place you know like like
this repetition like right in the middle
repetition to this is this is this is
what you know you know in the beginning
like 10 years ago Google specifically
wanted to avoid this because Google's
they are chanting they are chanting you
know we are the good people we are the
good guys
yes we do ads but we you know because
people needs to survive you know the
content creators and we do it in a
non-intrusive way
things like that that's the urge you
know marketing pro update that's their
chant and that is why many of us
supported them and now they become this
you know pass your hats ready in the
middle like twice like if you go some of
my page view these wars for example
javascript basics so ads ads ads and you
know if you are using a phone to exceed
access this website it's far worse
because when you when you're using your
phone the screen is small and they have
ads over like then you have to press a
button to shrink the ads you know like
to they don't even actually you don't
even you cannot even shrink the ads I
mean they they have a button so that the
acts at the
comes a draw like a slide or slides back
so that you so the the so the thinking
is that you can press it again the ads
will come back like like you know in
case you need to watch the ads again the
[ __ ] Google you know so you might be
thinking you know why don't I you know
remove you know the frequency of ads I
did that you know because I don't want
this so I go to Google website I try to
redo them I want to you know less ads
you know and they still doing that you
know they have a slider that says you
know how intrusive you want to be so I
want to be you know the normal not
intrusive and this is a result extreme
evil so Google ads what what so what
what else we were talking about so let's
go back to yeah brave so I wasn't so
brave he's trying to solve the ad
problem not by the open source niche
thing you know let's go goes nowhere
forever so I recommend you guys through
support brave okay this is a
organization commercial organization
trying to solve the ad problem you have
to pay I mean you have to support it for
society to change you know supporting
open source and free software the niche
things they never work we've been doing
that for the past 30 years so brave is
trying to do something about it so they
have adblock blocking building you don't
have to install ad blocking but however
they try to somewhere to web creators
content creators how they get paid so
they have these kind of you might go at
micro payment mechanism so every day you
visit you know you use brave to visit
websites they tally like what you know
which website you visit the most often
then then you can pay it's optional you
know you can you can start to I have it
I have it turned off
you know you can turn it on then every
month you pay automatically to the
website you you visit the most often
things like that and they are using
cryptocurrency bat the code bat
something I haven't I haven't looked
into basic attention token yes how long
does it take to get used to a keyboard
like that
the Kinesis well it takes like I would
say a month okay if you type everyday if
you use a keyboard every day one month
will be good one month will be you'll be
pretty good with it you know two months
to be truly fluent I would say but also
when you learn touch typing of course if
you use this type of keyboard
ergonomic then you have to start to do
touch typing you have to learn touch
typing because otherwise is easy it's
not suitable for hunt hunt and peck you
have to learn proper touch typing which
is very easy so let's read the comments
how much do you pay all day long very
every day all day long every day uh-huh
so I'm also used to Maki bow it's
extension of my soul Mac Mac Mac
keyboard is the worst yet with respect
to organ aam ik's so do you have any
repetitive strain injury issues I guess
not so bad for me sir is special Thank
You weak max maybe it takes longer than
week I would say maybe I'll get over by
sometimes learning Emacs was awkward for
a week I for one TV says I for one never
got paid per line of code written since
adopting Ruby philosophies the opposite
is true
okay not by lines of code okay the lines
of code the concept of lines of code is
the most extreme idiotic concept that is
widely spread in programming community
where does it came from UNIX [ __ ] UNIX
okay weather why because UNIX the
hovering system and does in the
community and see they began the concept
of lies everything should be lie lies
you know line oriented so when when you
have a line longer than 80 characters
many UNIX utilities they just simply
truncate it like cut it off without
warning or anything that is UNIX in the
1980s and 1990s they simply cut it so if
you do PS you know that the UNIX shell
to PS you know and PS okay
PS a you wwx okay so that's you know
that's that's UNIX that's UNIX PS
command okay it shows all your processes
now you see many of these lines are
super long you see this this is like
1000 characters or 500 characters this
is today on Mac okay but in the night in
1980s 1990s when the line is more than
70 or 80 characters it just disappears
just cut off [ __ ] unix this is this this
is the UNIX philosophy this is you know
how it began you know the UNIX people
philosophy Linux view or they got
brainwashed they never you know they
don't see these I mean they did they see
that but they ignore it's like
propaganda you know it's like today's
political news you don't you don't you
don't think you know you just don't come
up in your brain meanwhile every day you
are chanting oh UNIX philosophy
you should be everything should be UNIX
philosophy okay so so this is the
example of a ps2 it just Strunk it you
know it doesn't it doesn't happen now
because now it's you know thirty years
after
if they still chunk aid you know people
go crazy you know but so actually so
this is and this is also true for table
will be basically all Unix commands and
email it became a email standard email
protocol you know I have see something
something so I have like five or ten
articles about line Trump truncation so
such folks alley line truncation okay so
why am I saying about line truncation
because you know the lines lines of a
code okay the lines of code is so my
claim is that the like that the concept
of lines of code is one the most idiotic
concept as a metric to measure colleges
of program okay that's common you know
everyone knows it's common you measure
how big is a software how complex is a
software you know one of the easy most
common ways how many lines of code okay
that's one thing now I'm saying that
measure is the the the the the most
idiotic measured way to measure how
complex is a software okay that's what
I'm saying
now another thing I'm saying is that the
lines of code where does the comp why
why does that concept became popular I'm
claiming it's because UNIX [ __ ] UNIX
UNIX philosophy created this because
UNIX philosophy because in UNIX
everything is you go by lines because
every you know one of the UNIX
philosophies everything is a file
anyway you go by line it's like grab you
know grab and and all that tool okay so
this this is this is one of the big
problems you know it has significant
consequences to this day it hum you know
so like so I mentioned a few things so
let me write it down so it's clear so so
I guess today we become this topic
Blanche okay truncation Unix
okay let me write it down okay what we
are talking about so one is that lines
of code okay
number of lines of code as a measure is
a common measure comma metric you say
metric of how complex or big of a
software okay that's one thing now this
is lines of code is the most idiotic
metric okay that's what I say and lines
of code originates from UNIX okay UNIX
in 1980s and 1990s silently truncate
lines that's beyond 70 or 80 charts
including PS taw like when you do at all
when you have a directory the full path
is more than hundred something
characters then you tar those
directories then all those file path
will be truncated so when you untie it
everything is [ __ ] up for example if
you have directory of HTML files you
know they have links local links like
that they link to each other but now
Utah and aren't are all the links
doesn't work because the file name is no
longer correct because tar truncated
them [ __ ] UNIX this this happened up to
including 2002 okay so because why
I have I have lots of articles and
backup about these issues for example
you can see one two three three articles
more than three articles this is
significant consequences about this UNIX
line and thing issue like permeates to
harm to the programming industry to this
day for example so I was saying you know
you know PS truncates
let's search for it so let's show some
of the articles UNIX RFC lines from
truncation okay so let me just type
something quickly and because I have
quite a lot of things to say about this
okay so that's that and email RFC so
because you UNIX truncate lines so when
they do email we know in impact in 1980s
1990s email is mostly sent to UNIX
servers okay so when they do email
because UNIX just truncate lines so they
they they made the UNIX way of trunk any
trunk Indian lines into the email
protocol so basically for the email spec
they say lines should not be more than
70 characters these actually they say
that because the UNIX [ __ ] cannot handle
it so they they so they tell everyone
this is the way you know the from now on
you know email should should be only 70
characters today you don't hear that
much more you know because it's just
gradually you know it's idiotic right
anyone you talk to today we don't we all
know it's extremely the other concept
you know you don't truncate lines and it
has great consequences to this day like
Emacs in Emacs if you have a long line
let's say 10,000 characters one single
long line 10,000 characters Emacs freeze
freezes okay this does not happen you
other
but Emacs fries why because because the
UNIX way you know Emacs mostly grew up
from the UNIX environment you know it
reaches someone hated UNIX but that's
another story but anyway Emacs grew from
the UNIX environment so in UNIX people
do not have long lives you know it just
became a habit programmers do not have
long lines so you don't have a problem
but today is so different because today
if you visit many of the website for
example you know dr. Koh you look at the
source code command option you let's
look at the source code okay you see
this this is one single line many
websites are you know doing this one
single line including Google Microsoft
since ten years ago so you copy this you
go to Emacs I open a new buffer now if I
paste that Emacs is gonna be very slow
yeah I might have to with you know force
force created let's see how what happens
I paste the line okay paste
okay so go back okay this is pretty
short I mean this is fits one page one
screen this is not too big so anyway so
it still works but if for example if I
can copy this line paste it again paste
it again copy the line paste copy the
line paste now okay so now now if I move
kusa up
Emacs takes half a second to move it up
you see let's magnify you see who's up
half a second to move it up okay
now let's copy the whole thing copy
paste let's double it it's I I press up
arrow you see now it takes more than one
second to page up to two two arrow up
let's move move closer backward word
let's see how it long Halloween takes
okay so it's it's you okay so anyway
this happens a lot when today many
website you know this
this happens anyway let's close it so
consequence harmful humph so what are
the harmful consequences of the unix way
of truncating lines for example email
spec says everybody must truncate lines
ok the problem of email quoting you know
you know today we have we used the
greater than equal sign to quote to
quote what other people said right that
became a convention where does this
convention came from it came from UNIX
because in bash prompt how do you use
echo okay echo something how do you
start cat okay anyway the UNIX prompt it
came from that convention UNIX prompt
and what's the problem so what is the
problem using this this greater than
equal sign to quote things the problem
combined with the line truncation is
that often you have several levels of
quote like you know and that is
extremely hard to process because
sometimes it mess up that's you know you
probably have seen this before you have
experienced it before not much today
that but let's say 10 years ago you have
seen you know sometimes the quotation
doesn't walk like some like it mix mix
up some quote and other people scored
into one things like that it seeks is
the pain yes what really should happen
is that you should use matching pair to
quote this is the proper way actually so
so and so many many consequences and the
and another big consequence
is the design of programming languages
that are line oriented we have this up
to today this began with C okay we have
this up today for example one of the big
major harm is the JavaScript JavaScript
you have the semicolon that's optional
but javascript is did it so bad that
that is you know it's a well-known issue
very bad and so so I blame that on the
line truncation in the UNIX convention
that's that created that problem not not
simply because JavaScript did it wrong
anyway so many confirming language today
they are lying oriented and the console
you know it was why is that bad that
that's bad because then because if you
when you have a lying oriented
programming language that means you the
language appearance appearance is
hard-coded okay hard coded formatting so
what does that mean that means such as
ASCII ASCII diagram you know for example
when you have a programming language and
you have comments sometimes people draw
a box you know like a head of things
like that
that's so basically that means you are
using ASCII you know you are manually
trying to align your characters trying
to draw boxes so you know things like
that
that's hard-coded formatting you don't
want that what you want what you want is
a mock-up such as mock down such as egg
mod such as HTML so once you have a
markup syntax it's flexible you know you
can display you can render it for
example for HTML you can have CSS that
changes how things are rendered you know
for markup McDow oak
you can you can have a program that
converted to any other format you want
just by pressing your key so these are
all consequences of the line oriented
formatting that begin with the UNIX
there's a lotta so okay so here's
article line hot rap 70 characters from
punch cards our crime okay so why 70
characters where's our engine because
punch cards has 70 70 horse okay and and
another problem is line rap you know
today you know for example in Emacs you
have a hard rap for example let me show
you you have this command that okay so
you see okay let's shrink and shrink so
you see here we have a long line but in
Emacs you have you have this command
called feel okay it's idiotic name let's
go it feel paragraph okay so what it
does is that we it will truncate your
lines
let's show let's show the space okay so
let me do this again paste pay paste
paste paste paste paste okay so I have
one huge line so you can so you Emacs
you can call fee or paragraph so what it
does is that it will make every line
less than 70 characters also so so with
the with the 70 characters mind set from
UNIX you for programmers you created so
everyday every programmer started to do
this manual formatting you know everyday
it's a habit it becomes a habit
every programmer does the manual
formatting that's no good you should not
do that you should have margin you know
I Emacs does
have that but anyway in any editor you
are see in any text editor or word
processor you can have a margin you know
I didn't turn it on for example let's go
to reach text okay there you have it you
see let's
you know you have a marching concept you
see even though this is one long line
that we are not fit your screen but you
have the marching concept it candies
you know it will wrap in emacs is it you
also have that is but it's hard to do I
I'm not going to call it actually I can
call it let's say a novel reading
actually I'm not gonna do it so anyway
there are a huge number of consequences
harmful consequences one of them he said
it gets programmers to manually indent
also indentation like today you have you
know programmers manually indent each
every line is [ __ ] [ __ ] UNIX this
these are all consequences of the line
oriented thing thinking so that's one
consequence and the UNIX top problem in
this page I document the top problem in
fact you can see it mentioned in in
MySQL documentation or was it Postgres
I don't know if I mentioned that in this
article but anyway in the official
documentation of MySQL MySQL or Postgres
they linked to one of my website where I
document the top problem the tardis
truncate lies so for free imagine if you
are a database you know at mean you work
at Google so you need to move your
database you know some chick about
something you tie it you move to another
machine you untie it they all book a
book because touch one kated your
[ __ ] database where is the link I
cannot it says search ok such sorry tah
SQL truncate something like that there
it is ok there it is you see this
article server fort SQL Server 2005 2008
does full backup truncate the log you
know faculty [ __ ] UNIX [ __ ] Linux you
know they don't talk about this like
because you know back in you know for
example when when I mentioned this in
UNIX forums they pan you they bang you
that's what they do
so what is this saying do they actually
link to my website or something saw ok
they didn't mention me but I don't
remember what's the deal bane anyway
there is a from the official document
documentation they mentioned on a Mac
one of my pages about that UNIX tons of
problems for anyway today we are
focusing on the line truncation issue so
you in UNIX top problem file length
truncation Unicode name support what's
about unicorn in support I forgot
so here is another article okay I was
talking YouTube about that San talk show
closed that this this quite a lot other
issues but where do I talk about that
okay there here here this article MySQL
reference menu to point 12.2 Mac OSX
notes okay now this website is gone but
I have a gzipped version let's click on
that now this is this this one is stated
in 2002 I think ok and here is another
article essential command-line interface
tools for Mac OS X 2003 so its article
also gun and I also have a backup
version they are in gzip actually I
should we do them because you know ok GC
that's another thing changed in the
browser you know you know past 20 years
about 10 years ago when you have a
gzipped
GZ link you click it it will show in
your browser
ok Google will just show it in the
browser not download you just show
directory but since about seven years
ago so he stopped doing that you know it
started to download how do I know
because once I realized because back
then 10 years ago that that this this is
why you have you know I'm working on my
website all the time so 10 years ago I
discovered you know if you have a GZ
file you show in a browser you know
so I started to make all my local
archives into gzip file so you know
people can just click it and view it but
then but you know he just changed you
know you just changed now it's a problem
because because you know you see for
most people when they download GZ they
don't know what the fact that is you
know a lot of people they are not like
us phonetics you know open-source
phonetics they are take kickers hackers
you know they know oh you know GZ versus
a bunch of others they don't know they
don't know what it is so especially
today it's become less common
so DP says okay DP says to be fair pkzip
messed up my stuff more than once as
well okay I have I have I have three
totes on that but let's not so DP also
says so UNIX is supposed to be blamed
for the constraints of punchcards
Tech does not compute it does you see so
so punch-card
you know we you know computing evolved
from punch card right so if we look at
computing there's always you know this
always progress needs to be made you
know there's always problems you know we
can we can't look back and say you know
everything is perfect but however you
see the thing with UNIX is that when you
become you know it when it becomes
computers you are no longer punch cards
you know you can't we can understand
okay because of some backward
compatibility you know at some point you
know punch card to digital computer or
electronic computer it's not a clear-cut
transition typically computer technology
progress is not like clear-cut like one
day it's this and next day is everything
changed it's not like that
so it's gradual so at some time some
point in time I don't know the details
you know but but you know it's likely at
some point in time you know punch cards
are gradually being replaced and
meanwhile doing those times they are
machines that needs to read punch card
and also has terminals something other
inputs and things like that therefore
you need you need this compatibility
thing you need to be compatible a Poe
command a bit of you know compatible
with the or way but the thing about UNIX
is that I mean they ignore I mean okay
so so we we understand there's this
compatibility issue but as long as you
move on at some point you remove
compatible you know you remove the bad
design things like that right but that's
not the case that's that's my point
that's not the case with Unix
in fact they are the people they don't
you know in fact they never mention a
punch card okay when Pete when UNIX
people back in 1990s they chant about
UNIX philosophy and truncate lines
little you don't even mention truncate
lines they did they just that's just the
way they live okay they don't know where
it came from they don't know they don't
end they don't talk about it they just
chant about all the great things of a
UNIX philosophy you know that's the
point if you have opinion that's
different they ban you that is the key
point that is that is my main point why
this UNIX people are [ __ ] okay that
is my main point you see I understand
all technology has problems you know
maybe you don't have enough people you
don't have enough resources including
Microsoft or you know you just made a
mistake human mistake things like that
that is not my complain about UNIX
[ __ ] they are the people
intentionally push push a kind of a
gender you know fake news that's that so
that's what they do
UNIX people that is my point you know
you have the people like Eric Eric Eric
Raymond you know es ah Eric s Raymond
you know the he's one of the primary guy
that pushes the UNIX philosophy [ __ ] you
know this this problem you have tons of
problems ok ok so today is kind of a
rant and that's so how long I've been
talking so Scott is saying it's
something I cannot read when I'm doing
YouTube videos so how long have I been
talking Gulliver's Travels where's my
YouTube page okay that's you know that's
on Google Chrome
one hour in 6 minutes ok that's maybe
that's about it
so DP says most dascomb and still
assumed an ad character white consul
okay that's another valid be taught okay
but I have retort to that retort okay
you see Microsoft you can blame all
problems of Microsoft all you want but
you see understand that Microsoft is a
commercial entity okay well what is so
is Unix okay how do I say this okay so
so my my you know Microsoft make they
got a lot of problems okay it's not
Microsoft was not better than Unix you
know back then you know in the 1990s you
know Microsoft didn't begin until late
1980s right you know they got problems
you know the Microsoft and also they are
commercial so they are trying to
especially in anyway they do have
problems but what I'm saying my point is
about the UNIX people the UNIX people
they are they are a code that that is my
point
okay they are a code they are they have
this UNIX philosophy I mean the very
jargon itself UNIX philosophy pushing
for the kind of basically force
propaganda that is my point yes
Microsoft has problems in you know they
you know they take technology in the
beginning not so great or things like
that you all have problems
Mac OS got problems okay but it is with
a UNIX coat it's a coat that's what I'm
saying that is my main point they
created the UNIX philosophy crap you
know the fake news force they push it
and if you do not agree they ban you
that is my point you know this this is
strong you know you know if you are back
you know you met you you may know about
that you know it's a code everyone know
about that it's not a controversial it's
not a you know debatable UNIX is a code
that is my point they pan you if you
disagree just like Emax you know like
they have banned me because I said you
know you should you should change the
name metal keys to something because
that should be bet that would be better
you know
they disagree and they pan you you know
I say you know for example in 2006 I say
Emacs keybinding sucks
Emacs keybinding creates repetitive
strain injury today most people will
understand you know it's accepted but
back then in 2006 people banned you if
you say don't use Emacs default keys
they pain you that's what I do
it's a code that's that is my point okay
once you have a code you have you create
a lot harmful things and today my focus
is about the line truncation that is my
point okay 9 truncation created not
created lots of problems it'll you know
like you know creates like perpetual
harmful things in industry even even
today you know you know the top problem
that he has problem counting software by
line lines of code and stop you know it
stops creating programming languages
that's that's in the right direction
because every language is just lying
based you know every language including
: including : slime based I can show you
examples for example for example let's
open a new buffer magnify save this file
is xx start go okay a temp file okay
then our type go then I have a template
okay now I can run this program it
trains 33 right now it's so this is now
is this is a go program now go program
has a go come go language comes with it
a tool called go for man okay for
example I can screw up the formatting
here for example I can still run it okay
I run it 33 okay it's still valid okay
this is a valid program but I can cocoa
form
okay it's a command-line tool but I have
I have a Emacs wrapper
command to it so I can code by just
pressing keys look okay I just called go
format you see you can see the command
name on the Left window so it formats
the whole file for you okay so this is
this is fantastic you know Rob Pike you
know Koch language I love go language
they started to fix many of the problem
from the UNIX philosophy kind of they
created that you know one of the theme
part one of the problem they fixed is
that they basically they eliminated all
the formatting manual formatting thing
eliminate it eliminated it okay that's a
great thing that's one of the reason I
love go format but however there is a
residue from the UNIX philosophy lines
from truncating [ __ ] ok the lime lime
based line by line based programming
language design which colon is one over
them why because let me show you an
example so go format is supposed to
format your code you see we have seen
you see from this from this you know
these two things in one line we can call
the go format and it becomes this you
know line by line default line by line
kind of formatting okay but this kind of
problem let me show you so let's do this
again okay let's do this let's say let's
put the whole thing into one line
okay let's with now we put the whole
thing into one line let's run it to see
if it's still valid syntax run it it's
correct okay it returns 33 you see so
this is valid now let's go go format
let's see what happens you see you see
this it failed to reformat it to the to
the default you know the canonical go
away I failed in this part you see why
well I don't know why
technical detail why because but I can't
my guess is that my guess so what what
happens you know what happens is that
they the go format has ability to
reformat a single own lie into several
short lines okay it has that ability but
it is not 100% okay it's it does like I
don't know exactly why when it does not
happen but you can see from this example
when you Coco format it doesn't you know
it doesn't break it into it doesn't
reformat into it like like that so so
why is that you know because we only
have a short example here if you have a
long program I've done it before
you know if we are not reformat your
long lines okay you know summer lines
some lines will become long end like
that you know one long line so we felt
in some cases to to change long line
into short lines why I would say it's
because the remnant of the you know the
the line based somewhere okay because
the line based formatting the co itself
is still line based language it's you
know the gold syntax is still basically
line by line you need you need the
semicolon okay and O's it's optional
it's well designed so it's it's not like
JavaScript well anyway so why am i why
do I want why does anyone want you know
wants to have a format that changed long
lines you know why does anyone wants a
one long line in the first face many
reasons okay for example we have seen
HTML we have seen let's look at the
source code of this page YouTube okay
we have seen the duck taco example but
let's look at the YouTube source code
there are many reasons you want one
single line okay so you see this is this
this is a huge
Paige okay now we can copy select oh
okay let me select all it's it's this
page is huge so I guess let's see select
or okay now it's like okay this is
really big file because it's taking a
long time to even do anything so select
all again it will take three seconds
okay
now copy switch to Emacs wait it's a
rainbow rainbow of death let's copy
again copy
okay switch to Emacs open a new buffer
paste okay
four thousand lies now let's go to the
top okay let's move arrow down okay it's
not too bad okay so so so why why do you
want sometimes you want one line because
for example here is an actual practical
example why do they want you know why do
they put all this this is JavaScript and
CSS into one and they have reasons okay
for example wild reason common reason is
that you can compact minify the code so
it's smaller than size so when you
transmit it's smaller than size things
like that and you see many many of these
lines are one single single long line
you see this is a JavaScript one single
long line so let me switch to HTML XHTML
mod okay so anyway so let's magnify you
see here is a JavaScript this is one
long line this is one long line and
things like that and here you have a
another long line you know there are
there are many reasons to have a long
line for example here here is
CSS stylesheet it's one giant [ __ ]
lie okay this line is for example copy
it open a new pervert paste Zurich or
call count count words so it's seven
thousand characters
okay this single line is seven thousand
characters many reason and okay now so
now so this is a CSS file so now let's
switch to CSS Mart okay so CSS mod okay
so CSS mod there it is okay
magnify okay now let's remove the HTML
style tag okay now now this is a pure
CSS syntax now what I want to do is I
want to press one key
I wanted to reformat the whole thing
into you know the proper format you
cannot do that okay it's a problem why
why can't you do that because you know
today we have a I you know we have
robotics that we have [ __ ] this or
that AI engines you know why Cannot you
have a tool in your editor in the in the
most [ __ ] powerful editor you cannot
change the whole thing into you know
just reformat you cannot and this this
concept is not actually common across
programming languages in editors for
example you right now you you copy this
you know CSS one single line try it try
adding your favorite editor in vs code
in Visual Studio in one not [ __ ] ok Adam
Adam slice you know the the sublime
whatever [ __ ] your favorite editor Xcode
by default there is no command or no
tool to reformat a single long line okay
in general there is no peered in okay we
are talking about building to or command
in any common popular editor to reformat
90% of programming languages that's in
one line to single eyes
so what I'm saying is that this concept
is simply not popular why because the
[ __ ] the eunuchs line based ideology the
idea that that because programa do not
ever think about long lines you know
because programmers are habituated to
you know you always you always line
should not be you know more than 70
characters it's you know that's that is
why so that here is an example in my
opinion my claim
it's a damage to software industry
because otherwise without a [ __ ] UNIX
code we would have in every editor
piolin a command that you press a button
let me show let me first of all you
press a button if formats into single
long I press the button again it becomes
line by line okay let me first of all
try to make this nice to be so what we
do we is that we replace the end curly
brace the curly bracket to replace it by
with a law with a line return okay so
replace all so that's one step we need
to do another step by okay replace that
by with a new line okay okay now that's
better now let's replace or replace or
semicolon by semicolon with a new line
okay okay now this is much better this
is this is the way we want okay this is
more typical okay the they are using
this complicated style of CSS you have
like tens of classes here anyway so my
point is that there is no tool to do to
do this to change in between and and
that's you know that's a consequence of
the you know lying on oriented mindset
that is embedded into every
today every you know it's like you know
if you don't if you do not do it many
like right now if I go to treated I say
you know you should not have you know
you should not cut your line said every
every Eddie characters you'll get a
bunch of flames you know people will
immediately immediately say oh no you
are wrong because visually human eyes
needs to be this or that you know
complete idiot that that thing is soft
by you know autorad you know the margin
we talked about but but but you see the
problem is once you have a coat with
this embedded concept they don't they
stop thinking they cannot their brain
stops working they cannot think anymore
because when you if if I go to Twitter
right now say that you should not lines
should not be forced into 70 characters
immediately you'll get a bunch of
reprise including many of my followers
they all say oh actually X I like I like
your opinions but you are wrong here
because human you know we need 70
characters because otherwise you know
it's too long you know human eyes cannot
do that you know it's a visual isn't you
know it's a problem that's idiotic
because that that thing is soft by
marching look at this marching okay
idiot you know you know and and also
look at you you go to discord you go to
Twitter you you go to Gmail you don't
you know trunk you don't press ENTER
every time your lines goes through the
right side you know because it's
automatic that's the way seen things
should should be but in programming
programmers are still you know like
trying to manually do it so the reason
they don't think is because it has you
know because the UNIX philosophy is a
code he has become a code it programmers
are unable to think you know whatever
the the code touches anymore so that
that's my point
so actually back to the go format you
know so go format
you call that you know the it doesn't do
this you know why it's a problem you
know and also why do you want a language
you should have a programming language
not that's not lieing oriented okay so
actually I've been talking for long so I
think I should stop now
okay let's see some comments and we
stopped in two minutes or so yeah
so to be fair okay so most arts commands
never mind
I agree go format is a step in the right
direction
Rus also has a Auto formatting feature
on the other hand CBC beautifier goes
way back yeah that you have a bunch of
that so called linked tours but but they
are kind of idiotic okay so is in the
same way you know you have lots of those
tools but the thing about those tools is
that they do not they do not change the
fundamental the idiocy of the line lying
oriented format okay rather they are
piggyback they make things worse okay
these tours like beautifier tidy
you know the link you know you have a
bunch of those you know then you have
JavaScript versions and so on they are
like first of all you begin with [ __ ]
you know the line the line truncation
[ __ ] okay then you try to pile on top of
it that's what UNIX to you know you have
you have you know the she'll be she'll
punch a seashell then a bash is easier
than fish you know new shell it's like
it goes on forever because the
fundamentally you got something wrong
you know yeah the pattern then you have
the sea then [ __ ] tsipras press come
up then then Java C sharp you know C
then then you know that it's like that
that's all from UNIX [ __ ] you know you
need UNIX philosophy [ __ ] C and UNIX
they put strapped each other without you
know that you can you know they they are
together thing to strap each other so so
so you are saying beautifier so they
they don't fix a problem rather rather
they you know so what they do is like so
first of all you have the line
truncation right then you tell
programmers every line should be no more
than no more than 70 characters you know
deeply embedded into their brain well
that's a bad idea
okay so programmers manually you know
press return oh you know they worry
about each line on each every line
[ __ ] it [ __ ] then the UNIX [ __ ]
created this this link you know they
have this job
Lindt or beautify or you know two tries
to automate that concept okay so so so
you run the lien program on your source
code so when they wherever lines more
than 70 characters they automatically
add a new line add you know alec new
line to your code here truncate it you
know not truncate but you know they
automatically do that so to them you
think they they think oh my god Oh UNIX
is fantastic we have automation we have
we even created automated tool that's
that's what they are thinking but to me
it's a [ __ ] [ __ ] another on top of
another [ __ ] you should not have that in
a beginning line should be long can can
be long okay can be thousand characters
no problem in your editor you just
create a soft wrap okay that that is the
point
you're the [ __ ] idiots UNIX [ __ ]
so deep TP says that's one statement
block which is okay to put into one eye
it's idiom not not really not so because
you could you know I don't have other
examples of hand right now but but in
Cola if you caught more your teeth I
think okay I'm not too sure I think this
is true basically my point you basically
go format it is not hundred percent we
are not do it hundred percent
it's not about because you you could
sometimes you I have like very long
lines the go format we are not firm at
it in two separate lines I don't know
exactly why that happens possibly is
because of flaw in go format you know
because not most people we are never
begin with one long lines in the first
place
you know because UNIX you know
programmers have been you know
brainwashed to never do that so so you
we don't really see such an example so
so therefore you know it doesn't come up
as a bug you know maybe it's a bug in go
format or or maybe possibly it's go for
my intentionally did that for certain
long lines they don't do that but I
don't
that's the case because one thing for
sure is that it's not true that whenever
when you co co pham Co format something
ends up in one line that's because they
intentionally intentionally think that's
actually should be one night that's not
true that is not true for because for
example even even in this example that
is not you know go programmers do not
consider this to be well formatted Co
programmer would consider this to be the
way to be the canonical way so I think
it's a bug in code for metals I don't
know exactly but my blame is basically
it's all came from the UNIX philosophy
you know the the line oriented [ __ ] and
also when you know remember we talked
about why line based line oriented
programming language syntax is not so
good for example one of the example is
Python you know Python went all the way
to have the heart formatted appearance
you know so they made they you know they
make they made the line returned
you know semantically significant Inc in
Python and because of Python then you
started have a bunch of you know this
CSS you know templates javascript HTML
templates tours for example SAS SAS or
you know why mo or something you know a
bunch of them mustache that's based on
the pythons layout
you know oriented you know syntax which
is very bad because once you hard code
hard code you know your syntax then
there is no you cannot have the concept
of rendered renderers or automatic
formatting because if you have a markup
based syntax then you can format in any
way you want
automatically you can even render it you
can even
at semantic meaning like HTML or XML you
can you know you can check out any any
format you want but once you have a hard
hard coded formatting it you are fixed
into that one thing and and typically
it's manually intensive you know
programmers you have to type them
manually okay so I think that's it for
today 15 watches okay so that's it I'm
gonna shut down in one minute
so we were talking about something else
they became it became the UNIX frame
inevitable this you know this is this is
my big thing you know I've been flaming
alright this is you know my heart for
you know since since about you know 1999
being you know fighting with these UNIX
[ __ ] fought for 10 years 20 years
now the UNIX people they did huge damage
like you know we have seen you know the
line the the the line of you know number
of lines way of counting you know yeah
okay let me continue on that you know I
was kind of an organized so over you
know first so why why do you want not
you know line based syntax you know
because you know it's my claim because
the unix-like location today we have odd
almost all languages are lying lying
oriented syntax the syntax is all line
oriented now Lisp is the exception okay
we talked about this in one of my videos
Lisp and mathematical syntax they are
not lying oriented okay Lisp any
mathematical you can have you can have
the whole you can have your entire
source code you know when when one media
lies in one single line okay single
physical line you just press a button
then you will be reformatted displayed
you know in nicely in in the in a
kinetic canonical format okay you don't
have to worry about anything just press
one button reformat it and it's
trivially done because the Mathematica
has regular syntax I'd you know there's
a one video I talked about that for one
hour so so that is the power you know so
why why can't Mathematica do can do that
because in order to do that your syntax
nice have something building it nice has
it needs to be a unit okay
seen tactical unit oriented syntax okay
not line based you know in in Cola and
see see the see [ __ ] the syntax you know
: is based on CC syntax the syntax is is
somewhat line based but but but somewhat
not okay some part of it is lying you
know what I mean by you know when you
have a programming language syntax you
can say each you you have the concept of
the same tactical unit so what does I
mean a Singh tactical unit is a part of
a syntax the smallest part that has
meaning that has semantic code you know
meaningful semantically okay so for
example you could say this in goal and
for example this is one syntactical unit
okay this is one syntactical unit and
and okay so this is one syntactical unit
and this is once in tactical unit okay
but however if you look at them some of
them are line based some of them are not
for example this package main is line
based syntactical unit import is line
based synthetic unit the function syntax
is not is not because you you because
it's kind of you know is it's irregular
you have this word word then you have
these curly braces
you know the curly brackets is not lying
based okay it's not lying based but then
but but this part is again line based
you know the format printf is line based
synthetic unit unit so in C based
syntaxes you know part of it is kind of
line based aligned oriented part of it
is not so it's like it's just the [ __ ]
up [ __ ] okay but
anyway so but so if you have a language
that's where you design the syntax such
that the whole language is syntactic you
know the syntax has clear syntactical
unix units such as Mathematica and Lise
Lise Lise Pisa example okay except the
comments index but though otherwise is
pretty much syntactical unix based
language once you have that then it's
trivial to write a program to pass your
entire source code and reformatted to
any other way you want another search
for example is XML you know you can in
XML editors you can press a button you
know reformat the entire thing in one
single line or in multiple lines trivial
okay anyone can write a program without
studying you know knowledge about parses
things like that when your syntax is
irregular such as C then you start to
worry about a lot knowledge about pauses
and stuff so that so that is my point
about why you want a programming
language you want a syntax to be based
on sing the concept of syntactical units
okay and vast majority of language today
are not not Haskell not C C++ Java C
sharp Odyssey derived languages
JavaScript and not PHP not perl not
Python not Haskell or camel or any of
the fancy language not name okay this is
so crap they are all kind of like they
they are all kind of like C okay most
most part of it are line based
syntactical unit they don't have the
concept that the bottom line is that
they don't have the concept of
syntactical unic that like you know this
far into them why because the UNIX
philosophy [ __ ] created this situation
programmers can do not know they they
are not aware there is such a thing in
UNIX for us
we [ __ ] that is why you see so I'm
talking about you know why I hate it so
much you see my expressions of gayness
eunuchs this these are the reasons
because to me the eunuchs has done huge
damage to the industry so you know I
like to say eunuchs and see everything
wrong in programming industry began with
eunuchs and see and today we only
covering one part of it about the line
truncation you know and there are
consequences that's what we're talking
about today so one of the major
consequences is today you don't have you
bet you almost don't have any language
that that where the syntax is based on
the concept of syntactical units okay
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching if you like my stuff
donate okay you go to X Ollie not info
there is my patreon and stuff bye guys