good morning everyone
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santa's show there I got some
problems today with the YouTube setup
and today is September 4th 2019
Wednesday
now it's 9:47 p.m. San Francisco time
let's see so so you guys see me
let's see check click on that okay so
finally so morning everyone
I had I'm having problem with this
today's our talk show today is September
4th 2019 and so I struggled for 40
minutes
it looks like YouTube had some change
you know I'm not sure for sure because
YouTube changes their interface all the
time you have you know and today I try
something different I tried you know
using you know that first line to start
the stream and everything went bad you
know the thing with software is that
usually if it works don't touch it so
today I try something and new and things
went bad and so it took me 40 hours to
figure this out you know YouTube changes
their interface all the time because now
you have YouTube studio you have YouTube
studio beta and then there's also the
YouTube YouTube creator studio classic
so it's very confusing because it's you
know they have options to allow you to
switch back to classic or back to the
you know the beta but it's very
confusing because in some features for
example if I want to go to the live
control room I have to click what
appears to be the classic you know the
link that says you know some features
are not there yet so you have to use
this thing but I use this link then but
it actually ends up this seems to be
YouTube better you know I'm not sure
this page is whether YouTube's to do
better or the classic and this looks
different from what I see normally
let's see if this work okay so I'm life
and I guess nobody's here let's see how
many people does they say peak
concurrent one total view times zero so
how many people he does not even say how
many people always watching
okay so good so today so this is
actually a experiment then yeah
and someone thumped it up don't know who
that is so close that so I'm going to I
guess I will just random chat then and
unless you guys have a question let's
see if C check if this is working it is
I think and I'm just gonna I think you
know I think what I'll do is I'm going
to delete this video away instead
oh hi hi green tag i green deck have you
been waiting all this all this time i
had some problems with youtube so green
deck you are in russia right so let's
look up Google Maps so I think let's
just random chat about anything
non-technical today and at the end I
think I'm going to delete this YouTube
video because it's pretty bad actually
you see over here
I've been live for 20 minutes yeah so
anyway that's let's just random chat so
what's up green deck it's Google Maps
and I'm hungry
now it's 9:50 p.m. it's like p.m. night
and I woke up about 3 hours ago so much
sleeping schedule has changed again I
woke up three hours ago and let's look
at Russia
you know Russia Russia is this big huge
country but most of it is eyes I guess
snow and ice you know the top and Moscow
is on the left side you know it's like
near Europe you know I used to think
that Moscow is on the east side but
because when I think of Russia I tend to
think of the part above China because
you know I'm Chinese but Russia is on
the actually on the west you know Moscow
is busy and green deck if I remember
correctly you are somewhere here like
somewhere on the east of Moscow you know
so today I have some arguments with
Chinese friends actually some Chinese
friends I know in here well we had
arguments online because of the Hong
Kong situation you know the Hong Kong
protests black violence rioters
you know that's a happening it's a
happening big time so among Chinese
people some for the Hong Kong riots of
protesters tomorrow and some are anti so
it's a problem you know among so many of
us you know it's like your friends is on
one side and you are on the other side
or you know your friends and family so
you kind of see this diversion and so
among my friends you know among the
Chinese friends I know I mean let's stop
let's limit to the people I actually
have seen face to face in real life you
know they are diversion like like some
up for some are anti so you know it's a
big problem but I was talking to some of
them you know who who are pro the Hong
Kong protesters and the conversation
didn't go well didn't
oh that well you know because it's
almost like okay so let's you know
from today on let's stop talking you
know it's it's almost getting to that
point you know there's nothing I can do
I mean even I understand this is very
hot topic to talk about and but I want
to but there's no way to almost stop
this happening you know even though I'm
very careful and I'm respectful but it
seems for some political problems this
just happened so green deck says I
wanted to ask your opinion about Hong
Kong I heard that almost all Chinese
people are again its Communist China
it's not true at all that's pretty much
I mean if you are outside of if you are
not Chinese that's what the Western or
the Western media is like that you know
they want to say they want to I mean
because you know as you know there are
so many fake news when it comes to
politics depending for example this a
and B again is to each other so
depending depending on who are you for
you know so you tend to hear all the
news of one group as far as the Chinese
the Hong Kong issue is concerned I'm
guessing most you hear you know the
Western media is China bad Hong Kong
good you know you want to support Hong
Kong people and you see videos footages
and you know news and footages and
photos every day that's basically
Chinese cops beating people I mean have
you have you seen that that's what you
see right that's my guess but if you are
Chinese then of course you see different
stories you see the other side you know
the Hong Kong protesters they beat the
they beat the the civilians you know who
do not agree with the protesters they
they you know the damaged properties
massively there you know they go to me
into a subway station they just they
just hammer everything down you know
massive destruction
so that's a situation I am you know if I
have to say I'm I'm anti the Hong Kong
protesters the anti the riot riot right
us very much
hey Yad yeah taco wicker you from Riyadh
so today I think I'm going to talk
random and I think I'm going to delete
the video maybe yeah probably delete a
video afterwards because it's I don't
know because I think it's it's pretty
bad it's you know I don't know when did
I start you know anyway so yet Tucker
where you from and green deck so green
deck so what do you think you know
answer answer the question its chat so
green tag is yeah Corinne bug
Yekaterinburg okay here
yeah katha rine bug so here is like a
very interesting you know I have no idea
what is it is like to be in Russia and
let's drop in street view
let's see if we can see some in street
view oh so Russia Russian so green deck
says where Russian government media are
against protesters okay but that opinion
is unpopular in the Internet I see could
East and part of Iraq oh my god you are
from Iraq that's that's that's more
troubled country I mean yeah I well
because the Iraq war I guess you know I
mean America I mean American so I don't
know how you know what's going on there
but but as far as I know you know
correct me
you know correct me if I'm wrong you
know just say your opinions so you know
so people can see what is Iraq people's
opinions at least for you you know you
know so as far as as I know the USA our
government is very bad
you know they so in Iraq war they say oh
there's weapons of mass destruction
you know nuclear war Iraq is creating
this nuclear weapons and the Iraq
government is very bad like you know
like people would say like China you
know beating the beating people
totalitarian you know no free speech or
that so you USA wants to free Iraq so we
started Iraq war in 2004 basically you
just bomb out of them you know bomb and
you know civilians six hundred thousand
civilians died and okay so that's you
know this is 15 years ago and what
happened so he is Iraq better no it's
not better so is it better is it better
than before what do you think Yad so you
know tell us what do you think and you
know in USA when Iraq was happens USA
forbid you know it's forbidden you
cannot show pictures of the war you know
people like people dead on the street
it's not allowed no media do that you
know it's not allowed and and also and
also you are not allowed to show dead US
soldiers you know typically when you are
you know US soldiers died in Iraq you
ship the coffins back you know with
flags on top you know you have some
photos on that but even that but
typically you don't that you know you
don't allow that you know in USA
technically it's a free country you have
free speech you are allowed to say
anything you want yeah but that's that's
not totally true because for example all
the major companies or the CNN MSNBC you
know news news media New York Times days
they do self censor that you know they
don't do it so you don't you do not see
those pictures also especially in
YouTube you are not not allowed to show
for example video footage of any war
Iraq war you know today we everyone has
a phone you know this is a large camera
so you can win what happens you know or
even on the street violence you know
there are thousands cell phones taking
you know videos you know and and anyway
anyway so there is censorship so yet
says the north part of Iraq is way much
better OBO which is a city in Iraq now
it's like Dubai in the 90s so what do
you mean like Dubai in the 90s so it's a
very rich or what the north part of Iraq
is way much better
oh that's anyway so you know talking
about Iraq with Iraqis so you are Iraqis
right
you said correct to say that because I
don't know nothing about you know Iraq I
you know I
as far as I know they are different
different like subtypes of religions
Islam you know one organ is the other
something like that yeah so I don't know
so what yeah what you know keep typing
you know what what else are we you know
we cannot talk about so we can go look
at Iraq so what is where am I so are we
back to amount of you
so we look at Iraq hey good morning
Kimani Abdo he wrong here AK and you
know I think our government USA is very
bad but because Saddam Hussein you know
who was Saddam Hussein is supported by
USA I think in the 1980s
you know USA support him why because USA
because you got oh you're here you know
you got oh yo in these countries Qatar
and you know Kuwait and USA wants a pie
of course USA it's very bad you know it
has you know this has been written you
know there's a lot of information if you
dig you know in these books written
about that so USA once basically wants
to have control some control you know in
Middle East so they can say oh so that
benefit us for example I learned you
know in Saudi Saudi Arabia or was it you
know in some of these countries you know
they have oh you all right also you AK
and we made agreement with them so that
when they sell oil the only way to sell
oil is via US dollars you know I you
know I learned from another from some of
the you know I know it's true you know
is it it's no secret but I only I
learned that you know let's last month
so the only way you know what they say
oh you're so the only way you can sell
agree you know you have agreement with
USA so the only way you sell is is is
via US dollars anyone who buys your oh
you're has to use US dollars that is
evil you know that that is how USA
control many things
okay yak-yak says but I live in UK for
ten years okay so so right now you are
in UK is that right that that's um what
makes things different because because
if you know I thought you are in Iraq
and then you know I you know I was
getting a feeling maybe I shouldn't talk
to you because YouTube is going to pay
me you know the FBI did they are
watching all these things you know but
if you are in UK then that's that's
that's different that's better
Abdo hi Abdo I'm doing great
Abdo Hebdo where are you from and Abdo
what is your question type of questions
so we can talk about things because
today is just random okay III think I'm
going to delete this video because this
is so after says Saddam Hussein had a
fight with Kuwait for oh yeah okay
so Craig greentech says I actually see
many Asian tourists on the street I
don't know if they are Chinese but they
are very likely oh okay
so I guess you cannot tell Chinese from
Asian faces right like Japanese Korean
Vietnamese yeah so you cannot tell I can
but of course on the other hand I cannot
tell Russian people with you know
there's like yeah yeah Russian or or you
know all occurs Bursk it's 10 of these
people you know so Abdo from is from
Egypt
oh are you oh yeah okay so from Egypt
that's
that's new to me that's - that's new but
yeah so oh my god so you guys are from
all these countries so that's you know
it's novel that's new for me because in
real life like in USA here you know I'm
I mean I mean here
you know I mean here this is Silicon
Valley San Francisco this is called San
Francisco Bay Area so in here I don't
think I have I never know anyone in Iraq
or Egypt or Russia yeah I don't know any
here is Silicon Valley this is called
Silicon Valley where Google Facebook
YouTube you know PayPal Apple over here
and Yahoo all these tech companies and
here the the people here are very
diverse meaning because this is a big
city you know in San Francisco or Los
Angeles or New York here New York
somewhere here that's or big cities and
in big cities you have all kind of
people you know diverse people from
other countries but for example I know
Indians there are a lot Indians
programmers you know but but I don't
know I don't know anyone from Egypt or
or Iraq or Middle East
oh yeah do you so you are you are
actually in Iraq okay okay so yeah it
says by the way I'm also asking my ug
students to watch your Emacs videos oh
great
what is ug University of something okay
so you see let's look at a globe so you
see a Middle East you know like I really
have no idea what what what what's going
on there so and as you know US has you
know it's very highly very sensitive
topic in USA so when it comes to Middle
East you know I'm just telling you how I
feel you know as a American I lived in I
lived I live here for 30 years
you know I'm I'm 51 years old so I live
in USA all my life for that since 1989
so let me tell you how I feel you know
so you get a sense you know what you
know what American I'm probably not
typical American because I'm Chinese so
you have to talk to white people then
they can you know then you get a sense
but as far as I know you know I read
news you know for 30 years I read enough
news so oh I know oh I know is this
Middle East is troubled
it's troubled place so I know this Iraq
war and today USA wants to go to war
with Iran you know we could you know
this on the news you know they it's on
the news I think you know I don't think
our government USA is good because they
lie you can tell because you when you
actually look into the news you know
there are many people you know from the
mainstream news typically they say even
is bad okay they say Iran is bad Iraq is
bad
or whatever or CVR is where is Syria
let's see where is Syria somewhere here
okay let's see Syria they were there
okay so yeah so USA you know drop bombs
on them and also there's the Israel
question you know the is Israel Israel
is a country supported by USA us you
know I have his Israel friends online
but I also have pallet Palestinian who
is Palestinian Lebanon I think so
Lebanon people are Palestinian he said
am I correct something like that you
know I also have online friends I know
who are Lebanon's who told me you know
like this war kidding every day you know
so they told me this stories and I also
have online friends who are in Israel
and he told me his stories so so I know
is you know this war kidding you know
bombs bombs from the sky and killing
people every day you know and I you know
but if you read the mainstream news
media the mainstream the ICN this is
your almost doesn't matter
it's a left-wing or right-wing pretty
much all Americans agree most Americans
agree you know they just want to bomb
bomb Iraq bomb you know bomb Iraq bomb
Iran bumm bumm whatever Lebanon bomb
Syria you know all the almost all US
mainstream is like that but that's
mainstream you know doesn't matter
left-wing or Democrat or Republican most
most of them okay but they are you know
different voices you can see that expose
so it all lies you know it's just you
know they wipe out because it's good for
USA you know because
we are the most powerful you know we
just go there do whatever we want
that's that's us a so that comes to the
Hong Kong to let me you know I know a
lot about Hong Kong okay so let me tell
the Hong Kong story Hong Kong so what's
happening in Hong Kong you know you see
so I don't know how what you guys see
hegemony George
Palestinian is Israel Paris Paris
Palestine is Israel actually so you
cannot see Palestine on map oh okay so
you see on Hong Kong for my point of
view okay because this is also
contentious among Chinese they are some
for the riot Hong Kong incident sabab
pantai okay I am anti-de Hong Kong riot
and so this is my own perspective let me
tell you why
USA you know the whole Hong Kong riot in
my opinion from what I see okay I you
know I you know I am NOT dummy so I go
online I look for information right just
like everyone else you know I don't
trust the mainstream the mainstream will
tell you is that China is the
dictatorship evil you know they carve
speeding people every day you they show
videos and photos but I don't trust them
so I look and then you can see videos
and and you know all the videos and tons
of photos now thousands of photos and
videos you see the different story
it's you know the whole thing so from my
perspective from what I see is is
created by USA it's set up you know you
know depending on how controversial you
want to go you know like according to
some videos the whole thing is planned
it's like you know there are some people
in Hong Kong very rich and they are paid
by USA by a branch of CIA CIA code net
and et that Central National Endowment
National Endowment T for something you
can just look look it up Wikipedia and
et okay so what does this to I mean this
is a branch of CIA because it was you
know at one time in a history the the US
law says okay you CIA cannot do that you
know what CIA CIA to is they go around
they pay all these rebels in different
countries
to overthrow to make trouble in a
country so that so that you get a
government that that is pro USA you know
in other words
puppy puppy States so USA can say oh you
should do that and the leader of that
country does that puppy state okay you
know when I start to talk about this I
start to get angry you know because then
I started to have a lot to say and I
started to you know think about you know
all those people my friends they think
you know they look at they are on the
other side but I disagree so I started
to have a lot to say because I want to
tell my story because this is what I see
that is the truth
what they say is not true you know big
because then so so I want to convince
you guys but anyway let me talk about it
led so you have this this led it with
any dig organization in USA which is a
branch of CIA because at one time you
know four years ago something CIA you
know the US government decided Oh CIA
you are not you cannot do that it is
illegal you know it's not right to you
know to spend billions of dollars on
other countries to change their country
to change their leader to create rebels
to create what you know this so called
grassroot party protesters you know to
you know to violence so overthrow the
government so that so you get a new
leader that's your puppet you know
that's not allowed so USA made some
change in law but the CIA so what did
happen is instead so CIA created this a
needy branch you know kind of
organization so so the NAD does that so
so CIA doesn't do that so it becomes so
it's like a loophole and you know the a
needy they spent billions dollars every
year to stand you know so USA the
strategy is you know first of all you
you can bomb them although all these
countries if you if they don't like you
know they are enemies you know if they
don't do good for USA you bomb them you
know us we are the most powerful we we
spend you know
the most money our military of you know
of all the rest of the world combined
and we spend more money a military you
know so we are the most powerful so if
you you know we either bomb them but but
for example in China we can you know you
cannot bomb China because China has got
nuclear weapons now if you bomb China
you cannot you're gonna have of your
people half of us will die too because
the word Weald you know the earth will
go away you know new nuclear war so you
cannot just go there and say Oh Chinese
see what we're gonna bomb them that
doesn't work okay so so instead you have
this led you know net spin speed ian's
of dollars each year that's tax money
that's our money you know tax money you
know you pay P to people you you you
make trouble you know you pay to those
people who does not you know who may
have weird ideas for example you pay
them and so they you know then you make
you create this violence you know lies
you know you spread lies and create you
make people angry and create violence
and blame it all or blame it all to the
Chinese government
you know the Communist Party so that's
what happens that's that's my story you
know that's I have a lot you know you
you know to believe me or not that's you
know that's up to you but I can show you
actually
I don't know sure I want to because then
it becomes then it becomes opinion you
know then becomes you know I just want
to point out that's all you know I could
show you because I've written a lot you
know the AED the document you know it's
all it's not secret by the way this a
needy spending billions of dollars to
change your other country is it's called
regime change you know by the
presidential candidate Tulsi Gabbard
she's a great person I think so you know
she's talking regime change you know she
she wants us a to stop regime change
okay his code regime change it's public
information it's not secret you
go to the AED website you can see it's
all public you know let's go let's go
there
you go to the NAD website you can see
they tell people you know actually they
tell all the other rebels in all the
countries you know come to us we all
help you you know if you don't like your
country come to us we'll give you money
and you know it's all open information
you know and they have you know so this
is not a conspiracy theory this is you
know what you know so to think a bird is
called regime change
if you cannot change your country by
money you know by creating this problem
then you just bomb them eat one you know
one way or the other
that's what USA us are doing is
extremely evil so that's my opinion
about that so let me read the comments
so Aptos says so Abdul is from Egypt
thank you so so you are showing my
tutorials yeah so how does that work out
you know showing my Emacs tutorials to
your student because on my YouTube I
have lots of random things you know like
today so after and George says good
morning George and George were you from
again
you are either from Australia right or
Southern California I remember I don't
remember which George says
neoconservatism has become the
bipartisan position unfortunately what
do you mean
thank you know like political phrases
and things are very complex I like what
do you mean neoconservatism like the you
know like the same word have so many
interpretations to different people so
neoconservatism that's kind of like the
hawk right like the American who wants
to bomb other countries once wants to
control other countries and bipartisan
like what does I mean yeah so I don't
think it so okay so George George is
input right Perth Perth Australia so
yeah so you know I haven't talked to you
for a while I haven't seen you for a
while because my life stream has been in
the morning for the past weeks so green
deck says so as far as I can tell people
who support Hong Kong I want I want to
win over China they say that Chinese in
Taiwan or Singapore act the way better
than China
yeah that's let's force you know like
like green deck I can tell you right
away that's all that's it's so force
it's impossible to believe you know it's
really you know you like you you know
like like and you know like I don't know
what have what pictures or what things
you have read like and I know you are in
Russia right so you probably you don't
see Chinese much you know you don't have
so you know so what so like right now
I've what I feel is like how can I
possibly try to where do I begin to tell
you you know they like I can immediately
show you there are so many photos and
articles and pictures that's like that's
so force I don't know where to begin
you know and also you know and also it's
rather it's more complex complicated
it's not like you know for example
Taiwan then we have to track in history
like how did we tie one become that that
that part maybe you already know okay
and Taiwan people they are too there are
civil parties okay some party like a
minority they want Taiwan independence
meaning like meaning like from now on
time is gonna be a country by itself I
know it is not okay right now yeah so
it's getting getting more and more
complicated when I start if I want to
start to explain it because Taiwan the
official name right now is Republic of
China okay it's it's still a kind of
China Republic of China
the the main the China here the big land
here that's People's Republic of China
that's their official names and so they
are they are different government
systems okay there are different
government systems but now in Taiwan
there is one of the party now remember
this is just one of them
there's like maybe I don't know thirty
twenty percent thirty percent people I
mean this is controversial depending on
who you ask you know the Western people
for example they would like you to think
all the people in Taiwan wants to have
like independent declaration of
independence you know anyway in what
does in tirana let me get back okay
anyway so there are some percentage of
Taiwan people in my opinion maybe twenty
percent okay maybe that's pious maybe
thirty percent okay they want so-called
independence meaning meaning that they
don't want the name Republic of China
meaning that they from now on you know
today they want to they want to have a
new country called just Taiwan you know
that that's that's that's one of the
thing ok did you know there's many
details so it's not totally true that
Taiwan and and also do Taiwan people
support Hong Kong
I don't know taking I don't know exactly
for sure but I'm pretty sure one thing
I'm sure for is that not all you know
maybe you have have yeah maybe you have
have saponin Hong Kong's to have
supporting not supporting Hong Kong okay
and even Hong Kong Hong Kong people by
itself you know today I have argument he
heated argument with two Chinese guys I
know I met face to face here you know
what we had argument online but we've
met he they are around here okay they
are you know we are planning to meet
face to face but we I had argument with
them so they you know they tell me you
know they they tell me like blatantly
they tell me oh all the Hong Kong people
hates China they want to you know Hong
Kong people they want to you know they
don't like
they let and to me that's just so forth
you know but what can you do you know
it's like we you when you have I mean
like let me try to convene convey this
to you like for example in your country
now you maybe you have different parties
right so you you believe in this and
your friend believe me in that so what
he say is totally forced to you but he
believe is so strongly you know and he
think whatever you say is totally
you know that's the situation
so when I talk to these two people by
the way these two people they are Pro
Hong Kong but you have to realize I know
a lot of other Chinese people like I've
met here not a lot but at least one
let's see this too they are pro China
prob you know they are anti Hong Kong
you know so it's not like like I'm
talking about this true guy and you
think oh maybe your Chinese support Hong
Kong that's not true you know so you
know if you get all those people getting
together basically it's chaos you know
you know political situation is chaos
okay more team you know you are here
wait today I have you know I had I tried
to change your time and actually so
bathroom you I'm going to have another
talk talk show in about in about seven
hours if you go to my YouTube you will
see it I have another one coming up
seven hours so maybe that but I was I'm
surprised you are here what time is it
in Germany let's see let's see
nine eight seven seven o'clock in the
morning something like that bathroom you
so you joined my talk you are low your
fan I go okay so today we are just
talking random we're talking about some
politics you know and I'm thinking I'm
going to delete this video afterwards
what do you guys think should I delete
it because
you know because first of all this is
not a good video because I was like I
was not focused you know I was and and
also because it's politics it's not good
for my channel I mean it's like going to
be a thing on my YouTube YouTube we all
like you know kick me out any time when
I have too many of these kind of things
so in Perth Australia so George so what
do you think of Hong Kong maybe I
shouldn't ask in case we are totally on
the opposite opinions so should I know
don't delete okay yeah okay that
actually I can guess that's what you
would say bathroom you but but you know
you know it's not good for me for
YouTube you know I know what you're
gonna say I mean you gonna tell me you
know to just you know what I do you know
you like it and I like it but but his
reality to be concerned about you know
I'm living on you know this little ad
money if Google Keo it kills me kills my
account I'm going to have a problem so
you know so I'm sure I'm doing a little
bit this a little bit self-censorship
you know you know like yeah so these are
these political problems that's a
problem you know and
so green deck says so green deck say
hold on a second let me catch up with
the comments so green deck says so far
so as far as I can tell people who
support Hong Kong okay we covered that
it's not true okay you know if you ask
Hong Kong people I think it's like 30%
who are pro 30% are anti and the other
40% don't care they just they don't care
about politics they just they just want
to you know leave a good you know div
with you know have a good life and and I
think that's the that's that that
percentage actually is true for most
political things around the country like
in USA you know in USA you have maybe 30
percent you know on the left you know
poor Democrat or whatever 30 percent out
you know Republicans the other 40
percent don't really pay attention to
politics you know that's the situation
so George says how we trans how we
transition from a word with one
superpower to a word with multiple
superpowers is a big issue in my opinion
and more worried about that then then
climate change yeah okay I don't I see
what you mean but I don't quite get it
get it it wasn't like what were like
what do you mean transition from one one
one superpower yeah I mean so you know
it's a problem with the politics aside
you cannot explain where with just few
sentences you know so so I get I kind of
get what you mean like you know it right
now u.s. is one superpower but okay then
China is rising and
so you know so yeah I know I'd get
something like that you know so green
deck says I'm just saying things that
some people around me think and say I
actually don't know anything about this
issue okay so yeah of course we have
different opinions on Hong Kong in
Russia okay but if actually it actually
touches problem of communism and that's
a whole other problem for us in Russia
yes indeed exactly communism and also
wait wait so what does Russia you know
say I don't know anything about Russia
again you know like it's so like like
last week you know someone hung Master
Dan was telling me my friend okay he's
my follower and and he said you know I
don't think it's you so he's telling me
about Russia and I wa I was just
completely confused like he he's
mentioning poutine this okay when puku
people for poutine you know the current
president or whatever you call it but
then there is you know he's telling me
something just totally like I don't get
it rather I'm totally confused I mean
that you have several parties okay I'm
just totally confused you know yeah so I
think this is true for most people when
it gets out of the country or your
ethnicity you are concerned it's like
you have no idea what's going on you
know so that you know so this this this
is politics you know I think either rich
people the powerful I think the the one
thing to blame is actually the rich
people the powerful people because they
are doing these things and usually they
they do it why all this happens why all
this misinformation happens because
because all the people what they want is
they want to become richer the rich
wants to become richer and more powerful
you know the human and
that's kind of insatiable you know you
just you just want more and more money
more powerful so they they do whatever
that's good for them each person do
whatever is good for them so then so
that's why all this happens that that is
my thought that is my ultimate you know
reason for why all this happens and this
this is bad because you cannot talk to
your friends because when something like
Hong Kong you know oh you know I don't
want to focus you know because I want
you know Hong Kong in any country in any
place when this happens you know then
your friends may agree you know is on
the other side then you start to fight
you know that's bad for every person you
know because he believes something you
think is totally fake you believe in
something he think is totally fake you
know so you two guys start to fight and
you two guys you know but actually it's
all these problems are caused by people
who are above you and he you know today
the Internet they you know people spared
massive force information fake news and
Twitter Facebook or doing their part
because Twitter and Facebook they don't
actually care about what is true what
they care is is about making more money
for themselves so they create you know
you have text limits then they do
censorship and and you know you know
they say it's good for Humanity but it's
not you know these right now they are
sensor in China you know like right now
the Twitter Facebook they are censoring
a lot Chinese Twitter accounts because
they you know they they up for the Hong
Kong why because uncle you know it's
created by us a you know Hong Kong USA
wants Hong Kong to fight China so
Facebook is all doing censorship on you
know imagine you know on one hand we say
oh China doesn't have free speech
because they censor the internet you
know why China sends the internet
because USA because if US
doesn't exist why should China censor
you don't need to censor anything it is
because USA creating the Hong Kong riot
you know washing people's brain you know
they did help people force information
that is why China do censorship what do
you think or in other countries you know
do censorship what what do you think it
we need it for why would China do it if
if USA doesn't exist
of course USA the you know it's the
most powerful in the world you know
spent more than any country's military
combined and you when when this happens
then the small country to censorship
because they are because USA invented
Internet you spread all the false
information you have means to do that
why else what possible other reasons
would China do censorship well you know
why would they
because USA and now you see now China is
fairly powerful and in Hong Kong did you
know in the Hong Kong situation there
are so many Chinese because I know who
not government not okay not from the
government the Chinese people in China
they are angry because they are anti
Hong Kong they sing what happens they
are anti Hong Kong okay
and they started to they they
voluntarily to to to get on Twitter
okay Twitter is banned in China but they
good they go through the PPM but they
voluntarily go through vpm joining
Twitter to say good things about China
this is happening okay you might have
read on the news they say it's a Chinese
government it's not Chinese government
okay they are Chinese command government
also do that I suppose their butts you
know they pay people cheaply you know
few cents to for them to tell good news
about China but they are also a group of
Chinese citizens who are doing it
voluntarily you can see them a lot and
in today you know since two weeks ago
Twitter Facebook are banning them can
you imagine so Twitter Facebook are
painting Chinese citizen
and there are people in USA okay
Americans white people they looked you
know every time these kind of things
happen you you know you look there there
will be people looking into the issue
you know they exam you know they get all
the data of all the panda count they
they look into what those accounts are
is it really true they are you know the
Chinese government you know parts you
know trying to say good things about
China it's not true you can look and you
know that is this is rather more
complicated it turns out as far as I
know I read you know I looked into those
spent account are about most of them
about another issue not about Hong Kong
there's another yeah so it's getting
complicated there's another guy there is
this Chinese speedy Amer okay who
recently had a fallout with a China
China government government his name is
yogge way something like okay you know I
don't remember maybe a gray something
his name but anyway that's a you you can
look up you can find it you know that
just such for Chinese billionaire
controversy okay so you you'll probably
find it you know New York Times they all
report it because they they are on the
US side but anyway that is another big
issue okay so oh as far as I know the
Panda count about that guy not about
Hong Kong most of the panel count how
about that guy so anyway so that's so
let me read the comments so so Abdo says
but sometimes many people really be with
rebels this happens in the Middle East
to with after that they regret about
asking for the change and getting the
change already things called worth after
that
yes exactly you know USA Iraq war they
cured six hundred thousand civilians six
hundred thousand civilians this is 2004
you know I've lived through it
you know I because this happened in 2004
I was
in when it happens I was actually in
Taiwan okay I was actually in Taiwan
this is the only time I went back to
Taiwan for six months in my life I went
back to Taiwan for six months living in
USA for thirty years this is the only
time I went back to Taiwan six months in
2004 and that happens to be the period
Iraq war happened you know so I I see it
and you know and 600,000 people died
civilians not military in Iraq Iraq
people is us did that so you know what
what the
so is that for you know that's supposed
to be for democracy this world war on
terror and it turns out we cannot find
weapons of mass destruction in Iraq you
know and after that then us bombed you
know other places you know I haven't
paid that much attention you know but
the Iraq war was then at that time I was
paying a lot of attention to see what
you know who is doing what you know you
know what can you do and you know from
what we know that you know all this war
on terror you know you used to be that
phrase want a rose by george w bush want
arrow you killed so many people and the
many of these countries after war they
are not better
they you know they are not better they
have you know terrible terrorist groups
the you know local minute malaysian
militias you know local militaries it's
not better
but something made people so yeah the
says I would say that since it's not
related to your channel then would be
moving the video it's not a bad idea
yeah maybe I'll delete that yeah I think
yeah right now I'm undecided
I think maybe one after one day I did it
but you know right now I have I am eager
to show these to those to my Chinese
friends who didn't agree with me you
know he we argued I want to show them
because you know because you know
bathroom you says you should worry less
about what YouTube wants and worry more
about what you want I guess I understand
what you're saying yeah I understand
what you're saying exactly path on your
says you won't be kicked out because of
these there are tons of videos that talk
about politics and they on Kika that's
true yeah that's true yeah that's
actually very very valid reason so maybe
I should not delete that's yeah then
George says you know you know one thing
you know let me tell you something
bathroom you you know because from 2012
about 2011 okay to to let's say 2004
2005 I being you know I had very severe
financial problem okay you know right
now I'm making $1,000 but before I'm
making like $50 $100 okay not even you
know I wasn't making any money at all
like zero zero dollars for ten years
because I didn't walk okay zero dollars
for 10 years so so how do I live you
know I'd be very you know you know is
it's like you know you've seen a movie
matrix the first time matrix you know
you eat porridges every day you know
porridge is milk porridge is that's
that's what I do I see I'll do that but
now I'm better okay now I'm better
anyway for from you know like I guess
some of you have seen my other videos
when I was having troubles you know five
minutes video about food you know I was
like that so anyway so from that's about
2011 okay to 2014 anyway so in for a
period time you know I used to be this
troll troll ish guy you know I'd show
with people I know I argue about Emacs
about emag bees you know flame flaming
the open sores I say what my opinions
directly so bathroom you so you can see
you can tell from those my history you
know I'm like you you know I believe
like you know I don't care you know
off I don't care what you say I am
strong and I was younger okay back then
I'm getting older when you get older you
worry about more things you know and I
know for women you know I know the
eunuchs I know the eunuchs inside out
you know this UNIX philosophy you
know I just argue with them I don't care
you know and I can I can I have money I
have a job you know I owe I can find any
job I want because I know I'm foodie you
know they are not tons of places once
wants me you know I can code that was
back then today I'm not sure yeah
okay anyway let me continue the thought
so I was you know I was like above it I
don't I don't care I'm just gonna say
what I want I believe you know and I
believe you know I believe I'm pretty
good person okay yeah this I'm not a bad
person okay
as far as ethics and moral morality goes
I believe my deeds what I've done in my
life private or public is better morally
better or ethically better than many
many of these you know open source you
know the the free software foundation
people you know this I believe I believe
that is true better than them and I
don't mind it you know like you can you
can look into my life I don't care let's
see you know you you know if someone
argument you know that that's then back
then okay so I was this very cocky guy
and and also flamboyant okay but when
when I don't have money for 10 years you
know I kind of
you know I kind of like when you don't
have money you kind of hide hide
yourself in a sense you know so
especially like especially in 2010/2011
to around 2014 you know I stopped I
stopped all my flame was in emacs for
example I you know I read my Emacs blog
I used to say everything anything I want
died then I start I kind of started to
stop all kind of that because on one
hand because you know is easy it's not a
it's not like one day I made a decision
it's not like that rather I gradually I
thought you know I mean on one hand I'm
getting old older when you are ordered
you know things you know you're thinking
change a little bit and you are less
aggressive you know that's generally
true and you know and on the other hand
you know I felt like maybe I should you
know maybe I should change you know
let's see what happens you know let's
not let's not just go to you know that's
not when you argue with the UNIX people
it's not you know don't try don't just
say go yourself and say you know
give my reasons solid reasons and and
you are the idiot you know I was
thinking is you know for a change you
know let's see what happens you know I'm
always like experimental and exploration
kind of people so I let's say for a
change and you know stop you know try
not to do that so for for like five
years I stopped doing any of that you
know what happens it turns out here's a
key point this is a punchline so are you
guys still there say something okay the
bathroom you yeah so bathroom you see oh
there right and checking if I'm if I'm
still alive let's see YouTube what's
going on with
okay I'm still alive yeah so you see the
YouTube interface changed
what's the brother so I so yeah so five
years bathroom here so five for five
years I kind of may load down you know
and here's the punchline it turns out
that's no good it did no good for me
okay it kind you know then I becomes you
know what then I become like I started
to shrink you know like oh don't talk to
don't don't don't do this don't do that
I started to become shrink okay that's
no good
it only until recently like let's say
two or three years ago let's say two
years ago oh three I started to become
myself again you know like like right
now that you know in the past few days
you've seen me Swiss waving at the
eunuchs okay I started to do
that again I mean that that's actually
me okay that's you can sometimes you can
you could say you cannot change yourself
you know there's a saying like be
yourself you know this is a saying you
know be yourself that that is actually
very good advice that's valid you know
of course the the the the detail depends
on the interpretation you know what do
you mean be yourself you know it's like
if you like if you go to an interview oh
you you can't just go there oh oh you
know I don't like open source I think
they are that's that's not
let's not really be yourself okay so I
mean the interpretation is that you know
you want to be because when you be when
you are be yourself you know whatever is
natural you know your personality
whatever it is you actually have the
most express ability and control and
direction in in controlling things you
get you get the most you maximize your
own potential that that is what it is
you know that's be yourself so for me
you know I'm just this type of guy so I
am NOT a leader type I'm not a smooth
talker I'm not a politician type I'm not
the salespeople you know
you know social you know I I just be
myself you know the raw kind of draw
nerd programmer and you know
philosophical kind of I think thinker
kind of people so that's not yeah so so
if if anything you know be yourself is a
great advice now I don't know how old
you guys are because because I know my
followers this is quite diverse you know
from different countries some are
younger you know I know some some of you
are so bathroom you know what age group
are you like twenty studies I think I
probably asked you before but I I know
some of my followers some are younger
some are you know 20s 30s 40s and I know
they are yeah so bottom you says you
have no idea how being myself has got me
into the engine trouble lady yet I won't
surrender I will deep understand for
myself okay that's good you have to take
care of yourself you know not not you
not extreme though you know you don't
want to be Oh be myself then I'm going
to be extreme green deck sighs thank you
for this stream very interesting to hear
other opinions because for China opinion
is highly associated with our government
media okay so yeah so I didn't know at
all so I guess in seoul in russia
government they want to be poor Chinese
I know half as young as you okay you are
25 great great I'm halfway into the
graves you you are a quarter way so
actually I think that's about it today
Oh 48 minutes okay actually we can talk
a bit more okay let me drink the milk
drink something so anything else guys so
Sammy Sammy ma where you from
good morning Sammy MA
Saamy ma are you someone I know actually
so guys talk okay talk pasty-faced
insane talk so Abdullah says I'm 23
great they employed and really applying
for jobs great
so Abdo so after or didn't you say
you're gonna show my stuff to
undergraduate students or something
wait Abdul is from you know this is one
of the problem with Abdul is from Egypt
lived in UK for 10 years I think and and
right now in Egypt
oh yeah so Egypt what what is Egypt like
you know that's so many people so
interesting Egypt like Egypt you know
Egypt is the is the cradle of
civilization you know you have the
Egyptian pyramids you know - you have
every sounds extremely idiotic you know
but that's what I know
yeah in anyway so Sami ma you are from
China fantastic what city so Sammy do
you mind tell us are you
are you more Pro pro the Chinese
government or are you more Pro the Hong
Kong protesters tell tell us just you
know give us your opinion say that
answer
so today I have one hut 100% orange
pepper juice let's see if you can see
that okay 100% Oh in Japan for juice I'm
getting pretty hungry I think I'm gonna
go eat and so bathroom you our next
video is going to be programming
language style
I mean programming style functional
programming style and my programming
styles so we miss talking about that the
other day so we gonna talk about that so
night but good morning night but one big
equals one respect for my total that
died from drowning one like equals one
respect for my turtle turtle that died
from drowning what do you mean so
actually actually I think I should get
off my roommate is back
okay Sami Maher says you don't know okay
you don't know whether you support you
know Hong Kong or China
okay so Abdul says haha so true we have
very good history but modern history is
not that good anymore yeah iris kasha
good morning
bathroom you know the video today no
tomorrow I mean the the the the I mean
for me it's next day I mean in seven in
seven hours right in several hours or
something like that I'm going to have a
new another video stream so for that one
I think we're gonna talk about are you
able to go that one bathroom you in in
about seven was six to eight hours I
forgot exactly what but it's you know
are you able to attain that if not then
maybe not
so so we have I gained it bamdeck get
great greatly appreciate if you
subscribe what what do you subscribe to
your channel our bathroom you says is so
it's today so are you going to be able
to attend that one okay so okay so we
will talk about programming language
programming style then you know I hope
that I'll be energetic enough to give a
good talk
so anything anything else guys so Sami
Sami ma yo Mayo went to Yomi or some
Emax went to you has so much it has some
moment he jumped out rendered so Sami MA
so are you do you have any questions are
you finally following me because of my
eMac stuff how did you find me so if
there's anything else maybe that's it
for today so you know type it okay guys
type it this I think there's a 10 second
delay from the moment I asked and the
moment I see whatever you type so if you
hear this you know just type something
or say goodbye then that'll be it for
today you know say bye
then I'll be it'll ask or ask some
questions yeah
so Sammy next time okay thank you guys
yet and thank you guys for coming so I
think I'll keep this video up yeah for
for a day maybe yeah it's good for at
least you know we oh it's about 20
second delay really okay how can you
actually tell yeah thank you guys so
Sammy
you know I can what what knowing good
someone either the channel know I'm
gonna talk to you in Chinese for a bit
so you're eating one non good song with
someone she's a sham known so one day
you wait so Johnson went oh ha ha
drj from being something were you from
internal senses Google droop over Fabian
AHA just saw yeah so if you don't mind
then say what city you are in
yeah thank you guys Thank You Abdul bye
for now
Shanghai great fantastic Shanghai
Shanghai is one of the biggest city in
the world
Shanghai za Mingma path army says it is
maybe 10 seconds but I want to be more
patient so I said oh ok Samton santana
is from Beijing Beijing I hope to see
you
oh yeah I'll see you guys next time
Beijing Beijing Niihau chances again
shot suits are made known zone women bye
bye