Hello guys, good morning.
Welcome to another episode of Excel Talk
Show. We are free wheeling. We're going
to talk random topics today. If you are
watching offline, play at 1.5 speed.
Now, this is a kung fu dummy.
Actually, it's not it's not very good,
you know. I bought it for $10 and I
realized there is a lot of limitations
to this dummy but it's fun you know I I
love you know this kind of thing uh this
is my first one actually so but for
example limitation for example if you
want to do a salute you cannot do it
because the arm here for example is not
too flexible so this is the maximum you
can do so you cannot do a
like a salute
you know this is like the closest you
can you know you can get so it's not
very good and also let's suppose you are
Bruce Lee you want to do a sidekick you
cannot do that because the legs you see
you can move forward and you can uh you
know you can move forward and you can
move backward
backward you can see this uh this groove
But you cannot like move to the side
which so which is incorrect incorrect
human anatomy.
You cannot move the leg you know the
thigh for example to the side. So if you
want to do the Bruce Lee kick you can
sidekick you cannot do it. So this dummy
is like sucks [ __ ] [ __ ] you know $10
you know. So by the way are there
dummies that can actually be flexible?
for example, you can do a salute. Uh,
I'm not sure. I'm pretty sure there is.
So, for those of you Japanese
figurine fans, you know, Japanese create
all sort of these dummy toys. Uh, let me
know if you if you there are actually
models, you can do that, you know, like
do a salute.
So, this one is sucks.
Anyway, so that's so today's talk show
is just random. Okay. If you are
watching offline, play at 1.5 speed.
Okay. So, hello. Hello. Who's here?
Nobody's here. Like, like my my live
stream. One one person. Okay. So, I just
had a drink. I had one shot like
actually half of a shot of this glass of
Jean. You know, turns out I think I love
Jean. So, here is a Jean.
You know, Jean is great. It's better
than vodka. And I also found out I don't
like um I don't like the tequila, the
Mexican tequila thing. Vodka is
tasteless,
but gin is great because gin it smells
good. You know, you got this flavor
and red wine is not not too good. Red
wine is like bitter. Doesn't taste good.
So, I'm having some gene,
you know, just have a shot. Uh, I'm not
a drinker. So, as as opposed to you
people, white people, you know, a lot,
you know, because I'm in America, so
most of you guys are I suppose white
people. So, you guys are sess
susceptible to the alcoholic problem.
But I don't think that's the case with
Asians, you know, the like with the
white people uh and also Russian I guess
like like they they tends to be uh you
know having drink problems like they you
know like like whenever I say I'm going
to have a shot of gene or something and
they they they they go into a panic. Oh,
you got to be careful you know because
actually they got the problem of
drinking. But I think not not so much to
Asians and we don't drink much you know
and actually I don't like drinking
uh I don't like drinking actually
because when you drink you get drunk I
mean you get this dizziness like like
right now uh you you become stupid you
become more stupid which is in a state I
don't like.
So right now I'm drinking Coke. This is
just Coke. I rarely, you know, I never
drink sugared water like Coke or Pepsi,
but maybe once a once a year I drink it.
So, right now I'm having a Coke.
Now if you are watching this offline
and I and presume with a presumption you
are a studious guy you know you want to
get information in the shortest time
possible like one like many of the
programmers or nerds this video you
should not watch like get off turn it
off
in fact in fact you probably shouldn't
watch any YouTube
But if you are watching, you can play at
1.5 speed. Okay. Now, my keyboards I've
said a thousand times. Here's my This is
a tiny mouse. So, that's ultimate
hacking keyboard. This is um glove at
keyboard. Fantastic. And this is Nia
Track. Fantastic. This is This is
classic Logitech gaming mouse with a
spin wheel. That's the best thing. Okay.
and and I got this SWA board which I got
like a year ago, more than a year ago,
but thanks to the guy. So, this one is
called SV A L B O A R D SA board.
Okay, so look it up. I have video
reviews for all of them. And I'm going
to, you know, I still claim that I will
be using this once I learn it um down
the road, but still I don't have any
promises.
So that is kind of the introduction.
Okay, let's switch to my screen.
Okay, so what we going to talk about?
Well, today's topic is random. Okay, two
people. So if you are watching here say
hi. We got two people. ACP says do you
have a theory of learning?
If you want if you wanted to learn
something new and master it what is your
approach? Good question. Let me answer
that. I looks like that that kind of
question has been asked a few times but
I'll answer that. Okay. and Dosi says
good morning s okay so again today is
random topic so if you guys have any
questions you know you can post it I'll
give you my philosophy of it
okay so since we are not doing any you
know we are actually not coding anything
but I was going to go through my like my
blogs you know and tell you guys what I
have been doing in the past week.
Tremendous coding again. Tremendous, you
know, tremendous coding. Math, Emacs,
programming, webdev, you know, like
tremendous coding. So, I was going to go
through tell you some of the things I
wrote or stuff. Um, but basically I
spend, you know, eight hours a day
coding and coding nonstop. And there's a
huge amount of updates on PowerShell.
Uh, PowerShell better than bash bash and
Unix. [ __ ] Okay, PowerShell
lots of update and webdev and you know I
was going to go through some of these
but anyway so let me answer your
question. Okay, let's go back to this
um
let's go back this
dummy dummy talking you know. Hi guys.
So how do you learn? Okay. So let's see
the question. Do you have a theory of
learning? If you want to learn something
new and master it, what is your
approach? Uh now I assume the something
is related to technology like
programming, mathematics, right? Which
is what I'm that that's my audience
which is what I do. But it could also be
I suppose tennis you know sports running
or whatever or learning a skill in
uh in
a skill in what what what is a skill in
weaving in quit in whatever gardening
uh but anyway let's assume it's studying
computers mathematics algorithms and
data science and all that science and
engineering and physics in chemistry.
Okay, let's assume that is the topic.
Yes. Yes. Yes. You know the head. Okay.
Yes. Yes.
So if you want to learn something new
and master it, what is your approach?
Okay. The first you know by the way you
said do you have a theory of learning?
Now that's like kind of academic mumbo
jumbo way of of of saying things you
know theory of everything. theory
anyway. So how do you learn? So the
first the foremost important thing about
learning is you you got to have the
desire. Okay, that is the foremost
important.
Now there's a question how do you get a
desire? That's a different question. But
let me tell you about the desire first.
You got a desire you just want to okay
when you have that desire you are pretty
much set. Okay. For example,
uh you know, do you want to learn a
programming language? Do you want to
learn uh like HTTP protocol? How the web
works uh networking technology or game
programming or how graphics card you
know the graphics technology works? So
you know like like there's so many you
know or programming language Python,
Pearl, Ruby or a functional programming
language uh such as Haskell, F um or
camel
uh or you want to learn some like fancy
math, you know, math oriented scientific
programming like Julia and Wuam language
symbolic, you know, uh computation term
rewriting system, you know, I talked
about that all the time I have like tens
of tutorial just search for go to
kassadi.info info you'll find it you
know I talk about it every day so so
what was I talking so uh yeah so if you
want to learn the technology or even
chemistry engineering engineering like
how um you know like chemistry there's
there is material science there is in
earth chemistry what what's the name for
it I forgot or organic chemistry organic
chemistry is chemistry about biology
like your body your cell your how your
blood or you can learn anatomy and the
human biology which which uh physiology
you know how your vessels blood brain
works how your nerve works how your
heart works what is pain you know that
is a very interesting question actually
we don't know the answer what is the
pain the sensation of pain so anyway all
these are academic subjects so the
question is how do you want how do you
uh if you wanted to learn something new
and master it. What is your approach? So
first of all the meta answer is that you
have to have the desire.
How good you will be or how will how how
will you stick to this learning process
mostly depends on your desire. Okay. You
got you really want to know now what so
what is the example of the some some
example of desire from uh human animals
such as me and you and everyone else
human animals we are okay you got to
have a desire. So where does desire come
from? You know for example many many so
for example when you are hungry you know
first of all when we were born we have
innate desire to survive that is the
most powerful desire you know doesn't
matter what how you who you are what you
become you all of us have the most
in fact that's the most powerful desire
that is to survive you will do anything
to survive life you know for but for
most people you don't feel it because
for example me talking on YouTube and
you guys listening to me you know we are
like in a fluent states you know we go
to Starbucks have a coffee you know we
wake up you know have a coffee or
whatever your favorite drinks and you
chat stuff
so when you say a desire to survive you
know The most Americans like them what
what
they don't they don't understand they
don't understand because you never been
to a situation where your survival is
threatened.
Okay. So but for example today you got
this thing going on in Gaza. Okay.
That's a word we shall not talk too
much. But they are the people they
you can see the survival instincts.
Okay. So there so that's survive.
Survival. So survival is a build in
innate desire and it's the strongest
desire in basically all human animals.
What about some example like some people
like today's Zuma generation. Oh. Oh,
why don't you kill yourself? You know,
there's a lot suicide, right? So, what's
what's happened to them? Well, they got
mental problems. In other words, they
are unhealthy. So, they
you know, they they end their life and
stuff. Uh but usually that's a
exception. Okay. So, anyway, let's back
to the topic
about desire. Okay. So, one example of
desire is a desire to survive. That's
the strongest human instinct. You may
not feel it now, but it's in you. Okay?
So for example, if one day you went to
camping in USA or in uh Canada or in
whatever Australia or in UK or in
Germany, you know, the wealthy
countries, you know, you went to camping
with your friends, you know, or
girlfriends, you know, you have fun, but
all of a sudden for some reason you
slipped into a valley
or your rope had an accident, you know,
that is when your survival instincts
surfaces, okay? Because then you have,
you know, you're going to die. You, you
know, after a few days or you you you're
going to have no food, no water, you
know. So, you're going to you you're
going to start to become all out
thinking, struggling for survival. Okay,
that's your that's a that's so that's an
example where the survival instincts
come up. There are other examples. for
example this um
uh so anyway
survival is one of the uh innate
desire for all humans okay that's one
example another innate human desire
after survival is sex
okay that is very strong and that's in
all of us for example for us males when
we see females we want them you know
like the females today, the teens, the
you know you you can see it on YouTube,
you know, on YouTube, on Twitter, all
these girls, they do things. Uh but for
us males, when we see them, we get
there, you can see the desire, we want
them, you know, but of course, most of
us pretend to not care. Like, oh, that
those thoughts or whatever, especially
teen teen boys, you know, you pretend to
not care. But
but that is another example of the most
basic desire after survival. Okay, that
is sex.
Uh so that's two example of desire. So
what about another? So let's see. So
desire. So besides these two there are
al there's another um
uh
you know the there there's a wheel the
power of the wheel. Okay so that's
related to desire the power of the
wheel. For example,
many not all but many billionaires or
success or successful people they
they have a desire to succeed you know
or to become rich or whatever they you
know they choose to do a very strong
desire how that you know how that came
by usually it's by the environment okay
uh there are some examples but I mean so
for example I know Steve Jobs. Steve
Jobs, you know, the founder of Apple.
Are you guys still here? Is this
interesting? Say something. Okay.
Current viewers five. So, Apple
computer, Steve Jobs, you know, Steve
Jobs was an orphan, you know, orphan.
His parents abandoned him and uh but he
wanted to,
you know, so he has a strong desire to
succeed.
um
you know so I think it's true that in
general when you have when you have you
know there's a like a saying when you
have hardship then
you have a urge to succeed
to overcome the hardship you know
hardship meaning like you are poor your
family is poor like you have to like
kind of like survive Okay.
Uh
okay. Thank you guys. Hey. Uh so Steve
Jobs. So he he work hard you know. So
those people so once you have the desire
for example why do why does Steve Jobs
have the desire? Usually because of the
environment the situation you know. So
he wanted to make a computer. He thinks
that there's a lot of stories about
Steve Jobs, you know, interviews of
Steve Jobs uh you know he he thinks that
computer is really uh tremendously
powerful and we can build this tool to
help help humanity and he just got a
vision. He really want to go for that.
So Steve Jobs is a example of this
strong desire. So once you have the
desire
then you can learn uh kind of learn
basically that set sets you up then then
you will find a way it doesn't matter
how difficult or obscure you will find a
way to learn new things and master it
okay like typically
you know that so
anyway so desire is the most important
okay so the um and so and where does it
came form some of the desire the most
strongest for survival and for sex or in
other words reproduction is inherent
that's buil in okay that's in our genes
because those who do not want to survive
those who do not have a desire to
survive or they do not have a desire to
have sex they die out okay they become
you know because you don't have children
then you die out so the rest of us alive
we all have that desire, you know, to
survive and to [ __ ] including women. You
know women also want you know they like
very strong you know you can see that
that in teen girls they you know and
they in their makeup you know like the
the the entire makeup industry like you
go to YouTube the media makeup you know
um you tutorials for women because the
makeup attracts men which means they you
know they get to have sex.
So desire okay innate is survival and
sex. Now other desires are including to
have you know um to be wealthy for some
people not all. Uh so it depends on your
uh background your upbringing and stuff.
Okay. And and the other thing I
mentioned is that often times hardships,
hardship, you know, poverty or whatever
that gives gives you a like a a strong
desire to uh succeed.
Okay. So desire is one thing and uh
so so there are now two questions. What
about how do you get the desire for
example learning how to program?
Um and the other thing is okay so okay
we understand that desire is important
but what what is the technique when you
want to learn something new and master
it okay what is your approach so let me
address the approach like the more
practical so the approach you know so
you know right now I want to for example
let me give you my example I want to
learn the functional programming
language F which I talked about in my
live stream about a month or two ago. Uh
I've been wanting wanting to do that for
like 10 or 20 years ago. Okay. Anyway,
F. Okay. So and I also the another one
even stronger desire for me is to learn
the proof system like um proof theory
like uh for example the programming
language um
god so what is the programming language
I was thinking uh
ling okay l e an that is one of the
proof proof so-called proof assistant.
Okay. But basically it's a programming
language to do proofs.
Uh but also it's a g general purpose
programming language and there are
others like it like cog uh I mean coq
cog and several others. Okay. So I have
a desire. So anyway so I want to learn I
want to master the ling programming
proof system and f.
Uh so how do I approach it?
Well, my my approach is pretty dumb and
pretty nerdy. Okay, so my approach is
usually
dumb, not smart. My approach is usually
brute force. Okay.
So like you know ling is not easy to
learn because I I have been reading it
for like over a month and F is much
easier for me uh because I've I'm I've
been functional programming for 20
years.
So how do I approach you know so how do
I you know I want to master them they
are new to me. I mean ling is somewhat
new. I mean ling is totally new to me a
proof system. F is some you know not
really new but it's a new programming
language so I want to master it. What's
my approach? My approach is just brute
force and just study it. Just read it
every day like so you know typically I
would say spend one hour a day. The key
is persistence. Okay you really like you
have to be persistent which which
relates to your desire. So again this
desire is the most fundamental thing.
Okay. Do you really want to learn it?
You know there are many programming
language right? There's also game
programming. Do you like to learn game
programming? Do you like to know all
about network programming? you know be
become a master how cellular phone
network uh cell phone works how internet
works you know config your routers
whatever or you can become a hacker you
know how to break into you know
networking systems do you want to learn
that do you want to learn game
programming you know 3D engines do you
want to learn you know uh or do you want
to learn like wam language mathematics
you know or for example tiling theory
you can spend few years you know like
actually your entire life on theories of
tiding you know so can you see actually
can you see my screen let me show my
screen so for you know titing theory
okay uh you know do you want to learn
uam language so the point here is that
there are 1,000 things you can learn and
usually you know like this is a million
things you can learn and and there are
1,000 things you actually want to know
but you don't you you can't be like
nobody can learn all these 10,000
things. So the question is do you really
want need to know do you really do you
actually have the desire to learn that
thing that's an important question okay
related to your question like today you
know you might say oh I'm going to you
know if you are younger young people you
know oh I need to learn I need to master
JavaScript web programming or you need
to master you know
uh machine learning or you need to
master network programming or whatever
game programming or whatever or
operating system. How do you how how
does operating system works? You need to
work on Linux kernel you know there's
many many you potentially want you know
you enjoy all of them
but you want to be realistic. Okay. So
is this thing you really really need
want to know? So set up a goal for
yourself like imagine yourself in five
years what are the things you really
want to know. Okay, then you know set up
you know set up uh an hour a day or two
hours a day.
But the key is persistent. Typically
what happens is that you know you you
really want to learn something. You
decided okay I'm going to learn this but
after month it petered out you know
after a month like you're gonna you know
I'm going to lose weight. you know in
the first week you are you know you work
on it a lot but after a month or two you
know you forgot about it that happens to
me a lot too happens to everyone you
know like I have some you know I wanted
to do push-up more than 50 you know that
never happened you know so you know on
and on
so
so let me summarize okay so first of all
desire is what drives
your chances of mastering something.
Okay, desire. Then there is your uh uh
there is um the question of you really
want to be sure that is what you want to
know. You want to be realistic. Okay.
Then you can set up. So what is the
technique to learn master something? For
me it's basically just nerd done brute
force you know set up like an hour or
two a day continue that for like you
know for a year you know maybe start
with begin with three months and see
where you are you know because once you
know you know certain like 90% of
something you might change your mind you
know because you don't need to know the
more details like typically that's The
case for programming language once you
know 90% of it you are pretty good you
are professional already you don't need
to dive into the esoteric you know in
this language if you actually give this
argument what happens you don't need to
know that becomes like impractical
so be be so be realistic okay
be persistent
persistent realistic in what you really
want to master and be persistent Okay,
persistent is actually the true key you
know. So think about in five years what
you want to do. Uh you know what you
going you know so once you are realistic
you can you know don't be like oh I'm
going to master in a week usually that
won't work. If you are young you can you
know you can still do that you know but
um persistent is the key. Okay.
uh so yeah desire and that's basically
that's what I have to do uh that's what
I have to say okay so my approach my
approach is just uh like dumb bros
okay that's it for that question
so right now I'm drinking tea
tea makes you calm there's some chem
chemical in tea you know like For
example, me
uh I'm a master of programming languages
and uh I'm fairly an expert of of
computer science.
Uh you could say I'm a professor level.
Okay. I never had any degree though. So
and uh I'm somewhat um you know I know
like I you can say I have a like
bachelor's equivalent degree of
mathematics. you know like all the
mathematics I do
um
uh and I know programming you know
computer science a lot so uh what is my
point
yeah okay so that's what I know but
physics I never learned much about
physics nor chemistry okay physics
chemistry or electrical engineering or
mechanical engineering I do not know
like not much at all about them
and also there's biology there's uh
cellular biology that's also very
interesting and human you know the you
know so
you know so by now I'm kind of old you
know I'm like pushing 60
um
do I want to know learn them yeah still
I still very much interested in
chemistry and you know uh but I don't
know much about it and looks like I'm
not going to going to because for the
rest of my life let's imagine 10 more
years while my brain still works I need
to spend time on proof systems math uh
and differential geometry and you know
algebraic geometry
so that's you know so that's that's
going to be where I need to go into I
also interested in game programming in
um you know but I just don't I can't I
cannot realistically imagine I'm going
to actually spend time on those.
So be realistic and be be practical and
be persistent. That's my key. And also
you can so how and desire is the most
most important. How do you get the
desire? you know, you have to think
about, you know, like this is my goal,
you know, I I I want to learn this
master this because because I have like
a vision or whatever, you know, like
like because I uh you need to go into
that industry, you really want to, you
know, have, you know, if you are young
to have a job in that field or whatever,
you know, you gota
So that's how you get the desire. you
really want to, you know, you you you
want to do that.
Okay, so that's it. That's about that.
Uh maybe that's it for today. So that I
talked for 40 minutes. Actually, I need
to pee. So thank you. ACP says, "Thank
you. I also use brute force. I accept
that there is no substitute for hard
work." Yeah, that's kind of that's
that's that's how I do things. You know,
sometimes it's inefficient.
Uh but but that's pretty much how how I
do things just like brute force just
like do something one hour a day keep
doing it.
So I mean as as far as efficiency or
proper you know proper way there are
some tips for example you want to begin
with a
begin with a beginner beginners's
material you don't want to jump into
random book you know but um you know
like if you want to learn math
especially math you know you want to
begin at the beginning
um but um anyway that's I think That's
less important you know because that
will gets into you know you you're going
to spend days on which is the best book
you know but actually you are not
learning anything
I tend to do that when I was younger you
know like which is the best book for
calculus you know I spend days or month
like just to research on which is the
best book on calculus what this guy say
what that guy say oh this one is
considered classic and whatever but you
Actually you you you didn't actually
learn it learn calculus. You just like
going about which is the best
book on calculus because you want to be
efficient. You you have a master plan.
You you know first of all first of all
I'm going to find the most efficient the
best book the most comprehensive you
know book then I'm going to read it
because then that's going to be very
efficient. Then I'm going to learn
everything.
But but you spend a month learning
nothing. So that's a key today. So
that's that's another tip. Okay. Just
get on get get your hands onto it on the
subject. Start to do it every day and be
persistent. Okay.
Uh is it good to try to study two
different things at a time? For example,
one week one, the next one the other and
then you go back. Uh I guess that's
depends on you and for me I tends to do
that you know especially these days I
tend to do a lot of that. So
and and sometimes you know switch topic
in a day because when you if if I think
I used to like when I was younger I used
to like stick on one thing at a time
like um but I don't think that's very
good you know because you know because
my my mind mindset was that you know
first of all I'm very brute force I want
to go hardcore like when I learn Unix. I
want to learn the most difficult Unix
book, you know. I don't want the
beginners guide, you know. I don't want
like beginners, you know, like like Unix
for dummies or whatever. I want the I
want to directly read the man page. That
is my attitude.
And and so it's that's not very good.
Okay. That's not very good, you know.
So anyway, so
uh
so I used to you know like brute force
but also stick to one thing like I'm
thinking I'm going to master the entire
thing about this subject
then you know and and and I'm going to
be a superman. I'm going to drink coffee
every day and I'm not not going to sleep
until I master it in a month. Then I'm
going to switch to another. But that's
not a good thing. Okay? Because then I
found that when you learn something you
you'll be stuck somewhere sometimes you
know some concept especially in the past
today you guys you have a lot resources
you have 10,000 Wikipedia pages you have
stack overflow you can ask people
questions you have 1 million forums or
Twitter you can or today even you can
ask AI bots you'll just it'll just
answer whatever ever question you have
directly and interactively and
instantaneously
you know so today you guys are you know
we are here you know so you can learn
lots of things easily not so not so 20
years ago there's no Wikipedia even you
go to library you find the books okay
and then you find you know you read
books so anyway so
if you I used to be in the 90s when I as
you know 20 something I want to master
something and uh sometimes you get stuck
um you know for example in math there's
complex numbers and other things okay
sometimes I get stuck I I just cannot
get my mindset to overcome this you know
I can't see why why it should be viewed
that way and I refuse to take their
perspective you know I want to insist on
my own perspective and understand this
thing, you know, like I'm like very
obstinate, you know, brute force and
very obstinate and I think I'm just
gonna push through via brute force. But
usually, but so what happens a problem
with that is that I just got stuck.
Okay, I stuck there and that's you you
never go far. Okay. Like
so I noticed other people for example if
you are going to study proof theory or
category theory or or anything like any
advanced math or programming you don't
want to be like like so strictly logical
like like A B C D E F G until I fully
understand A. I'm not going to into B.
then I need to fully understand B. Then
I need to read about C. Don't do that.
Okay? You want you want to be flexible.
Skip around. Skip skip. If you don't
understand, skip. See what's the next.
Okay? Skip around. Be flexible. So
that's that's so that I, you know,
that's a tip for for the technique of
mastering something to the original
question. You know, don't be stubborn
and stick on some be stuck. Okay? be
flexible. Uh Wikipedia, there's thousand
pages,
AI bots. You can ask random questions.
Skip around. Your goal is just to
understand the thing, not follow some
logical step like build some tower.
Okay, so that's my other tip. Okay, I
think that's it for today. And uh I need
to go to pee
too much drink and uh we talked for 40
minutes. That's it. Uh, some more Pepsi
Coke.
Bye, guys. Now, donate to me, okay? If
you appreciate my stuff, you know, go to
kasadi.info,
kasadi.info, my website, my
website of 30 years history, and go to
the bottom, PayPal me, Patreon me,
Amazon gift card me. Okay.
Uh
be generous in what you accept.
Be something something strict about what
you give.
That's a idiotic chant from the Unix
[ __ ] about the HTTP about HTML.
Okay. But you guys, if you work a day
job, just pay me a hundred or a
thousand. Okay. Actually, some people
pay me a thousand. So, do that. Thank
you guys and like my stuff. Bye, guys.
Have a good day.
We shut down in one minute. So, today is
just pure talk. Today is a real talk
show. I haven't done just like pure talk
for uh for like two or three years. Two
years.
And hello my Discord friends. Hello
Dion. Hello George. I don't think they
are watching.
Bye.
Oh, there's another question. I would be
curious if you talked about GPTL EMAC
package. No. Uh, you might try ask me
next time. So, GPTL
GPTEL. Oh, yeah. That's about that AI. I
did a AI episode installing a plug-in
for Emacs about three months ago. So you
might check