hello hello hello good morning good
afternoon good evening today we're going
to do s talk show Welcome we're going to
do emac this coding and maybe random
hello timer ch ch ch Coke and the
tequila okay let me get my tequila
all I need is a drink now and
then let us go through the ritual of
drinking a man needs a
drink okay that's
cook and uh here is
the
tequila the thing we
need you know I recall there's a
book what does a man need to
leave well you need some
wine and
Mathematics and women
that's what I think you
[Music]
need if you are here say hi love to see
your comments if you are not here play
at 1.5 speed and uh skip around okay so
let me have a taste of the
pure
Elite drink
very good
smooth
okay okay coding let's do coding coding
is
necessary to make Great
America to make America great again emac
the most efficient
Supreme text editor the most powerful
text
editor uh and the pink window is all my
command course and uh keystrokes so I'm
using a Vora keyboard layout uh let's do
this uh I'm using a Vora keyboard layout
I'm using sof FL keys so as you can see
all my command names are in the pink
window okay there so
okay wi sis me wi please and the
keystroke on the right on the left side
if you search the command names you'll
find it for example s smart delete uh
but that one is not on my website so
let's go to c talk
show uh is today's talk show so talk
talk talk talk talk talk talk talk you
ask questions I talk that's what talk
show is show
okay this is what we're going to code
any questions comments okay let's begin
coding hello say
C content web three web 3 web 3 is a
scam okay you assuming you are I assume
you are a Zoomer are you from the my
lady
G I'm guessing so
web 3 is a scam sponsored
by quy Deep State something like that
okay it it's it's like it like nobody
can really Define it it just means it
feels good you know it's it's new
technology nobody can say what it is but
it's something involving crypto money
bit money you know money made of
bits that's what uh web 3 is a scam so
whenever so here's a recommendation
whenever you guys hear web
3 uh you know it's a
scam
AdSense I turned off all my
AdSense uh I don't know what you guys
saying so okay so we're going to write
this command CU I look up Twitter okay
uh do I need introduction to S like ke
or stuff I guess not let's just go right
into so I have done you know by now this
is episode
622 so I have done 600 YouTube videos so
there are hundreds of them on emac and
sof keys and my setting my system and uh
why are you using Windows uh which one
is better Windows or Mac or
Linux you know answer those questions
1,000
times okay so today let's go jump right
to the code okay so emac this so we
we're going to write this function so D
for defend and the function name will be
S lookup Twitter and what is that that
is you search Twitter okay so Twitter is
the Elam musk
x uh you know starting about two years
ago Elam musk took over Twitter and then
so it's much less censorship there's
still some okay but it's so so there's
much less
censorship and uh one of the great
information very dense on Twitter Rich
information is about
politics
politicians the current events around
the world you know what's going on in
different countries is there earthquake
is there famine is there Mass killing uh
and who is doing that uh you can find
that information on Twitter so for
example if you want to know about
programming or mathematics Twitter is
not a good place okay for programming
for mathematics mathematics you want to
go to Wikipedia for programming you want
to go to stack Overflow or just ask AI
Bots okay so there are different
resources that's more suitable for
different kind of information so if you
want to to know the dirt about
politicians about those Mega reach Traer
okay so and since LMS trador is you know
so you got you can uh search so let me
show you for example search let's see uh
search okay you want to expand the
window so so I'm going to write a
command that I just press a button for
example let's say uh um Ukraine okay now
ukra
ukine is a hot news in the past two
years three years because we send them
what hundred billion
dollars and have disappeared and there's
massive killing massive death how many
10,000
100,000 something like half a million
okay dead so in America USA United
States of America whenever we here oh a
girl got dead raped it's national
news but over
there 500,000 people
dead okay yeah you know I can still
enjoy my tequila and Coke here doesn't
affect
me so if you want to know information
search Twitter so Twitter you go for
example search you can type there and
there is
your you know current uh Ukraine results
on Ukraine you can you know there's lots
of lots of information from from fake
news from Real uh truthful journalist
from massive spams
massive uh part agents you'll find all
sorts okay but Theo information is there
you just have to find and you will often
find pretty girls when it comes to war
too pretty girls pretty girls girls the
center of humanity Humanity what is this
one one about I wonder how much it cost
to make Po War propaganda in
Ukraine I don't know what that is but
girls okay just watch the
girls okay you know so search tra okay
search um okay let's write um so for
example this uh let's let's remove the
this offensive word okay because uh
let's find something uh more
pleasant
blue
eyed girl okay now I press a key boom
boom
boom you see I can in emac press three
keys then you see the is lookup web
that's a command okay then it goes to uh
Brave search so you can search and then
you can click image search blueeyed girl
oh my God
amazing so turn on turn on
JavaScript uh turn on JavaScript so you
can
see blueeyed girl amazing oh the cat wow
beautiful cat mixed with uh vase this is
AI generated I'm sure okay so you can
see press a button is search then if you
want image search press press
press it goes to image search directly
close close okay let's try again press
press press you see uh let's see brown
eye girl let's see uh let's see blueeyed
Chinese press press
press do we get any pretty uh no no oh
oh this one is not bad that's brown eyes
that's not true and you know one of the
trick if you want to search
images outside of the American mentality
you go to the Russian one Yandex for
example uh blueee Chinese let's say
press press press
there it is Yandex then you turn on you
need to turn on JavaScript for images
then you just click
images blue eye Chinese okay yeah oh oh
my God this one is beautiful
amazing you see this is Russian Russian
search um okay so this is just the power
of emac you see I just press a few Keys
you can search you can search Wikipedia
uh let me show you okay
so so here is a source code and go to
the Top This is go to the directory this
isar lookup. close it and here's a URL
open it showing browser so you got look
up web look up Google look up Yandex a
Russian search engine look up by to a
Chinese search engine controlled by
CCP and you can search Wikipedia and
internet archive you can search look up
street map okay uh let's see street map
okay
so street map so here's a source code
source code search for street map what
is the key for street map I forgot M
okay so let's
say boardway
Street okay so press press
M there it is Google but you need to
turn on JavaScript Google Map okay turn
on the Broadway
Street San Francisco this Broadway
Street is where all the strippers are in
California you know California we are
far Advanced oh wait this is
manhatton I'll take manhatton New York
okay New York New York Broadway okay
whatever ever so you got these commands
so you if you want it pay me okay uh
used to be free but I you know I become
tech support like El musk so donate you
know send me a $100 or to uh I'll send
you the package okay so the convenience
the power of it you can look up synonyms
Wikipedia YouTube Yandex by do uh
YouTube let's look up YouTube um blueee
Chinese girl okay let's say so what is
the YouTube Key you so press press
press let's see if I get some YouTube a
blueee Chinese girl oh YouTube
Shorts YouTube
shorts girls the center of
humanity are we doing good
skater three I don't understand what
that is uh damx says I'm using softly
Keys fantastic I was wondering if it's
possible to quickly select text between
quotes yeah you know so go here so you
can see this quote press one single key
now look at watch the pink window okay
press one key there it is
uh so check out the documentation okay
sof FL keys so that's one of the most
you know one of the top Keys you need to
know for single quote the answer is no
okay so if you have a single quote let's
say
uh wait what what is you know for single
quote it doesn't work because single
quote that's
Apostrophe a
okay apostrophe is often used for
apostrophe purposes so you know so you
got it's not always quot quote so I
don't do that so okay so answer that
question yes Brave not yet yes short
okay pretty girls Center of
humanity uh okay she's not that pretty
but there are so many you know this
there's so many white girls of course
but there's also Chinese girls not this
one
though girls that's all they
do uh but okay so back to code so you
want to write this lookup traitor
extremely easy trivial in fact let's
just copy some of them copy and paste
the most efficient the best tactic in
programming so you want want to look up
Twitter so let's just copy um let's say
dictionary let's copy something uh well
known okay so now look up web look up
Google let's let's do Google okay go
there go there there there is the code
copy it
close Okay so we just going to copy it
[Music]
basically
uh okay let's quickly write this okay so
let's start to code uh let's get
serious uh version date look uh so
copy so in fact
actually uh let's use this Google
template you know we already have that
code uh then created update it paste it
there
so am I doing good you can you guys see
me yeah everything
good um
uh yeah so let's go back here so this
part we don't need so look up Twitter uh
look up the word look up current word or
text selection in Twitter okay in
Twitter search okay
then uh look at browser table is checked
for what browser to use that's a option
we don't care for now
um okay and look up what World on
internet so there is more generic
function you call so you call this
lookup World on internet and the current
word if you don't pass any word you'll
just pass the current word okay just
leave it so the key thing you want is
this URL you know how do you uh search
the Twitter URL there it is so copy
that okay
so
paste so and the query the query Dy is a
keyword okay so the query is this this
and Source type query we don't want
those tracking [ __ ] okay so that's a URL
for searching Twitter so then so this
lookup internet takes three arguments
the word an URL with a dummy in it then
um what browser to use you know you know
like a browse browser function so uh in
fact all you need to pass the actual
thing you need to pass is the second
argument which is the URL with the Dy
because the other part if it's NE then
this
functional word on internet we take care
of it so describe function to go to the
documentation you'll explain here and
jump to the source code do it so here is
the function I look up word on internet
you see optional word URL browser
function so if the word is near you'll
just grab the current word under curer
so you'll see uh the code here you see
if the word is
new then I mean if if the word is
already given then just use the word
condition you know this is a conditional
statement if the word is not NE is given
then just use that otherwise if region
is active that means you have a
selection then you do BU of string no
properties region beginning region and
you select the active region the text
selection otherwise if there's no
region then but is your curer if your
curer is a at the beginning of a
um beginning of a
line like that you'll just use the whole
line as a phrase because that instead of
selecting the line you know that's kind
of a little convenience but anyways then
if otherwise you know anyway Pro you
know it make sure the line is not too
long sometimes you have a sentence of
200 300 or thousand characters then by
mistake you look up you know you send
thousand characters to the web you don't
want to do that so if if it's more than
you know 70 characters don't grab the
line
okay so so anyway this is a a generic
generic function about um this generic
function look up on the Internet okay
close that close that so uh then let's
just write this so I think that's done
so so um evaluate the code let's try it
we can try it this way in this code so
let's say look up
um blueeyed Chinese girl now if I search
that it's probably going to show lots of
P I think so Twitter is you know girls
that's the center of
humanity and we stuck with it for
millions of years and forever
basically
uh uh so blue so let's blue-eyed cat
okay let's say blue-eyed cat well most
cat got blue eyes let's search it anyway
so press eval buffer okay so it went to
the
yeah so it requires log
in I don't want to log in here so we can
go to the bray browser which I already
logged
in so all we have to do CH let's trick
trick the browser what browser it sends
so uh so let let me adjust it okay
so uh list
get so yeah so you need to
um look a browser table okay
so okay let's
try Okay so this a bit complex let me
show you
okay so
okay so let's try to use this function
HTML open in
Brave uh no does it I don't think that
will
work
um
because you need
a what does youu take it takes a u uh it
takes a URL the function needs to take a
URL so
okay
so so we need a a
function with one argument a URL and
we'll go to Brave and open it so do I
have it I think I have so let me check
copy defend this all keys involving
defend so you got to look up Ur open URL
in Chrome in Brave that that's the one
we want go there copy it close close
close Okay
so this function okay so this sets up a
table that means this is a command so
when you are calling this
command call that
um browser function uh in this case our
Command is
uh look up Twitter okay so our Command
is this look up
Twitter
copy what is this close close close
close go
go go
go okay so there so when this function
is called call this URL okay so evaluate
that make a backup go back to our
Twitter code
evaluate it now evaluate this one do it
there it is it went to Twitter and it
showed all cats blueeyed
cats
beautiful
beautiful oh so
cute blue eye C okay fantastic I think
we accomplished our mission mission
complete now random chat for a few
minutes I guess okay so I'm going to
read comments random chat pay me okay go
to
PayPal PayPal
Amazon uh Amazon uh Amazon uh you know
on my website let me show you okay so
first of all let's put this back and uh
let's delete that okay now showing
browser that's today's code now syntax C
show in browser that's the code you can
copy and you all have it look up Twitter
and oh but you missing the look up
internet no no worry about that because
if you actually want anything you search
on my website
okay
uh look
up uh info search no okay
emac
look uh emac Dictionary lookup emac
lookup function
documentation uh let's see emac
Dictionary lookup there it is uh where
where is
it there
so wait that not this one okay
so go to emac tutorial go to
search look
up look up function documentation wait
what is it is no that's a lookup
function documentation Dictionary
lookup
uh I have the code somewhere showing you
how to
um oh okay so I know I don't I remember
now look up
okay and
search okay yeah search is a word uh
search text in
directory I search by
Arrow command to search web there it is
so there is a code so in fact you can
just copy this code and you can have
your own look up the web uh function you
can customize it you can you know look
up Wikipedia or Google or PHP
documentation or whatever your
programming language documentation or
dictionary or search the image search
Twitter search all you need is a URL
format you need to know where is a
keyword so which is easy to get you just
search on the website you want and copy
the URL and and check what uh their
format okay so that's a page you want
okay so you don't have to pay me to get
my stuff so you know but you can write
your own uh but you can pay me you know
pay me to donate me
for for learning stuff okay so that's it
for today I think uh yeah so one more
thing let's test okay so one more thing
okay so I want um red eyed cat okay now
meta
X look Twitter
do
it red eyed cat what is
it oh
what oh I mean languages
okay how do I become like you uh how do
I become a programmer like you in one
month please I'm studying 20 hours a day
do you recommend any website to learn
logic and language and
programming how do
I how do you become like me so the
precise phrase of that question would be
how to be you know how to become
studious and
uh how to become a
Chinese well that much of that has to do
with your mentality your attitude okay
so if you really really want like how
much do you want to be that way you see
this pros and cons you want to be like
me yeah sure you can you know you're
going to be a master of emac you're
going to be smart you're going to be uh
you're going to know a lot mathematics
and dive deep into the things of the
politics and things but I'm poor I'm
poor S I live on
$3 a day struggle to
survive you see that's a downside do you
want to be like
that but anyway on the positive side if
if you want to be you know
again the most important thing is about
your mentality so if you really really
want something you know when you want
something usually that means you have to
pay okay but otherwise yeah I I want I
want I want beautiful girls I want you
know I want a big house I want a big
swimming pool I want to be the most
beautiful
man but
but that means I have a lot things I
don't want to do to be the beautiful man
I need to start to you know exercise or
or or or or do operations on my face do
I want that not really so if you want
really want something you know you have
to pay for it but even that some people
what really want to be to do something
if you have the desire then you are
almost all set okay it's that's the most
that's the most important element okay
so um yeah so ask yourself how much you
want you want it and uh Chase
it it's like almost like it's the same
way how much you want a
girl then of course there's a difficulty
part you know for something you want
maybe it's not that easy you know for
example here's a pen I want a red pen
that is very easy you know I can get a
red pen I can just go out and buy a red
pen I can get a dozen it's
trivial but if you want to be a million
air oh it's not that so easy okay so
then then you got to do a lot of things
and take some time if you want to be a
mathematician it's not so easy okay uh
if you want to be the best
mathematician essentially that's
basically impossible already okay so if
you
want so depends this there's a different
prices to pay so if there's this girl
you really want you try to chase her but
you find it's extremely difficult then
maybe you know maybe you should pick
another you know so it things may also
change
um godson says can I hire you for
private tutoring tutoring on a project
I'm considering making it's a emac
project yeah
sure usually I go for
$80 an
hour uh but I'm not
you know I'm not a good negotiator I
know the stuff of course and I can teach
you really well okay I can teach you
whatever you want to you know as far as
emac goes I can really teach you but I'm
not the the type to talk about like how
much you're going to pay me uh stuff
okay so if you want just send me PayPal
me $100 okay then I'll I you know I'll
do I'll you know tell me what you need
to learn I'll give you a few hours
provided if you want to do that you know
you if you watch my videos you know how
I talk how I do things then that's good
okay so yeah you can you can you can
contact me offline but best thing is
just just PayPal okay PayPal and tell me
on Twitter or on Discord I paid
you you know so
um because because then I got a lot
emails you know I got emails in all the
all the offers like s you are really
smart I I got this project you know uh I
think we uh we'll make it big we can
gonna be rich uh you do you want to join
me this on this fantastic idea you know
I got lots of that each they all have
fantastic ideas but they don't have
money to pay me
you know I don't I don't want to be
become the most bilon a with you okay
what I want give me money now
cash then I do some work for you okay
that's what I
want uh so I think that's it for
today can you email me about
it just send me money okay because I got
a lot emails I I I hard re check
it yeah you
can uh so there is Discord so who is
asking yeah so Mr trading okay so yeah
you can but I I don't usually answer
emails I mean that's the thing you know
I got a lot emails or uh Twitter
messages you know private I don't know
who they are uh they always interested
in my opinions you
know I'm too old I'm too old and I don't
get
paid godson love you videos I will pay
you time no problem
uh oh God s oh fantastic okay
great yeah so i' I've taught someone
actually before I mean several uh person
uh on video live
to yeah several at least three one of
them is a
professor uh actually more than one
Professor
but the the the thing I really important
to me is that you have seen me before
like so you know I'm not a like smooth
talker like again I'm just like this
okay I talk straight you know so you pay
me I you know I do I do I can teach you
stuff
uh don't use Bitcoin because I have a
Bitcoin yeah don't use
it okay I think that's about it that's
it so we tried the so this function
Works beautifully and uh it's going to
be very useful for me but there's one
more thing I want to add because on
Twitter it's not just search your word
because usually you need to search a
particular person's post
let's say from specific year period
let's say 2002 to 2003 I want to find or
whatever Elam musk has said about let's
say blueeyed cat you know so you need to
type this and then you'll give you a URL
then you need to
so so this
um this function um because because
right now it doesn't do that it just
search a word but usually when you
search Twitter you want
to you know search a particular person
or if he replied to someone things like
that so there's a lot um things to
improve anyway that anyway that's it for
today thank you guys bye
40 minutes perfect okay
bye Discord link my Discord uh just go
to kali. info kali. info there it is my
Twitter and my Discord okay my Discord
is right here I've been slacking so I
haven't been reading much in the past
week because I've been busy on
Twitter okay that's it bye
uh let's see okay so close down close
down in one minute okay
uh Today's Show yeah close close um got
that close search close close beautiful
girls okay yeah Center of humanity