[Music]
good morning guys how are you guys doing
that was Bach's well-tempered clavier
that was previewed number eight what a
wonderful song and the best of them or
is the next one fugue
number eight so today I'm going to do
some Golan kind of a like a basic
tutorial so what am I going to do much
depends on what is is okay this is this
is my Emacs channel people post stuff ok
close that so I'm going to talk about
Golan and what where am I
where I am going depends on what you
tell me to so you tell me what I want to
do but you know questions or type
comments or opinions and I'll go into
that direction you know either like go
into detail about Golan or something
else
so keep the comments coming here so hi
Rex wait we are you located with five
people hi guys say hi so I'm going to
Golan and I was waiting for people to
come me and I thought I just listened to
Bach so do you guys hear echoes let me
know do you guys hear echoes like
yesterday I had echoes but I think it
set up correctly today because anyone so
five people watching so let's see Golan
so this is my goal and tutorial : is the
most simple and fairly very elegant
language and also practical and also
widely used in industry like everywhere
so that's why goaline is a great
language and it's truly simple to learn
you can you can learn it in you know two
days you're like you learn actually the
entire language in two days I talked
about that I talked about this a few
times in the past videos but
hey guys say hi here say hi here are you
guys here cuz let me know because I
don't know where I'm going so Prince
lice let's see let's go to slice slice
I'm doing some Corrections okay I'll be
right here
so you see this is a tutorial on go
slice data type and I'm going to make
some little little like editing
improvements to my go tutorial you see
this part it's such for that human so
it's right here and what I want to do is
you will see copy that I'm gonna start
in just a minute
don't no worry about that so for example
and let's go here
for example yay now look the change now
look over here
refresh you see that's what I want well
you need to refresh sub print F this
this blah blah blah prints sizing human
readable form for example these and yeah
that's what I want to do but anyway
let's start okay so nobody is saying
anything nobody is saying hi okay I'm
going to I guess okay so I'm going to
start okay let's see what we want to do
we're gonna talk about Golan I'm going
to give a like a basic tutorial and
basically tutorial and I'm going to
write a prime sieve you know like right
now I mean you know in real time so
let's see how you know how good you know
let's see if I can do that but okay so
anyway so if you just go to : sorry goal
and so if you guys are here new you know
type the question box so in my actually
you know sometimes like people like last
time I was talking and the audio is not
hungry so you guys are here right like
say hi in you know in the box to let me
know
so I wrote a : tutorial here you can
just search my name is our goal and
tutorial and why : because colon is one
of the most simple language I mean
literally you can learn the entire thing
in a few hours I mean really you know
every book says like you can learn hi
Rex
so it's Oryx where you are a where are
you baited so go line is a simplest you
know language it's it's it's great and
also it's it's very small I mean it's
like see okay it's very small
and it's very fast the speed of Golan is
like sea okay
and Golan is a static language and you
can compile it like C C++ Java you know
you you you compile the code into a
binary then the binary binary becomes a
program and you can send a binary to
your friends they don't have to install
: they can just run it you know you you
know you create binary program but you
can also run it like Python Ruby or not
Gia's you know you just type something
and read for example it let me show you
let me did start to show you okay so
let's go to my goal and tutorial and you
can see here's my local copy and let's
see compile run let's go to the first
page you know compare compile and blood
so you can see that's the code and let's
go if I go to here you see that's the I
mean in this section and I press the
button and the code is right here
magnify and I run it is he it says I
love cats me too
you know I don't have to compile it you
know it just run just like a ruby you
know just like Ruby or Python for
example let's do Python set this to
Python mod actually set it to a Python
mod and save this file as xx py 3 okay
then let's say print Python 3 I love
cats
okay that's it you run it you have it
here so that's Python do you need it so
by the way the program I used to run doc
my goal command if you are a Mac user is
this command sorry on current file you
can you can install it I mean you can
you can grab the code so let's see so
this is the sorry on current file and
the UI is actually here so it's not you
know it's just like okay 50 lines of
code you can grab it and in any buffer
in any buffer you can just you know for
example this is : you can just ring it
and you're up with the result it can be
Python it can be Ruby and or JavaScript
learning art and so on okay know it and
so on so so that's a simple goal and go
:
script so you can compare it or you
don't have to you can just run it and
and most importantly importantly why :
because many languages they are good but
they are only academic meaning that
nobody use it except you know in
academia you know just a tiny fraction
of a people like skim this you know or
even Common Lisp but Golan is like
industrial language is like the top 5
most popular language yeah so it's
fantastic you know you get you don't get
these properties easily you know me
simple elegant fast like C and compile
old as a you know a scripting language
and widely used in industry meaning that
if you are good at go you can easily
find a job you know you get you know ten
thousand dollars you know a month or
more actually in over here so so hi Rex
I hope I'm not sidetracking no not at
all but how how were you able to change
the top power color of your Emacs okay
that is actually a bug of Emacs 26 you
see you see is this top that's actually
a bug you know you know when when when
this happens at first I thought it's
kind of cute but you know actually you
don't want it you know you see
what happen is that if I go to my Emax
study and I go to the directory you can
see there's a desktop file now the
testifier is where Emacs sets or your
your the Open File the files you have
opened they is they are all recorded
here because I have the desktop mod on
now if you do not know what that is
just search for sorry Emacs desktop
you'll never find the tutorial but
anyway so so this file is a you know it
records your Windows position records
the files you have opened the records
and some other things so when you quit
Emacs and you start Emacs again it will
open you know oh you'll reopen the file
but however there's a bug because the
window position is recorded here so if I
delete that
okay dd-dad close it close it and quit
Emacs to do I want to save desktop no ok
let's restart Emacs
okay so you see that pie is back this is
normal but however if I quit now and I
you you know if I restart again then
then the bar will disappear it's a bug
so you know saw start command log mod so
on the Left window you can see all the
commands I call so yeah go line is a
great language let's go back to let's
see the chat hi hi green tag hi green
deck is that for me this config yeah so
I hope that answered your question Rex
yeah it's Joe it's just a bug I was you
know you know yeah I don't know how to
you know it's not something that's easy
you know one can easily identify and
actually but anyway that's that's just
an Emacs problem so green tag says what
is the best way to fix one letter miss
pairing Emacs one letter I guess you
just have to like delete a letter then
retype it is the efficient way
mmm I don't think so
for example let's see I have ch ch ch
hate here I want to change the edge to e
I just go there I don't think there is a
better way
oh you can use spell actually spelling
doesn't always work you know okay yes
you know the spelling integration with
Emacs is pretty bad because in every
dictionary like in browsers or
everywhere in word processors you can
spell check the entire file it's very
fast and you can correct and you give
you the correct suggestions then the
Emacs usually even the
even very simple spreading arrow you
don't get the correct word yeah so
that's a issue so I guess we are we so
are you guys interested in Golan at all
because I'm gonna talk about : five
people watching so I guess I'll continue
with : then yeah I'm just you know doing
your basic intro so goal and so : has
these qualities you know fast you know
and so on
so that's really good I really like it
it's it's kind of my favorite language
now and okay when you start : you have
to of course you got go to the goaline
website do you guys okay any of you what
programming languages are you guys
typing Oh emoji I don't want to emoji so
what programming languages are you guys
oops
what's going on
20 minutes okay well yeah so okay so
Golan Golan is great you go to the Golan
home page to download it go to Golan
Golan programming language you
downloaded you know different operating
systems you have different ways to
download it you know on the Mac you can
just use you know prove okay where is a
your download they don't even script
Prague blocked script aloud
download go yeah you just downloaded go
once you download go you can see you can
see you know you just type this okay let
me start to give you a very like very
basic tutorial big button
what do you mean big button so yeah let
me give you a quick : tutorial for em so
every file in : you must have a package
so every file belongs to a package if
you know if you are just starting out
you are not writing a new package you
know you just want to use : for reading
some scripts then you just say package
min okay and every package must contain
a function named min like like this and
that's that's a function that will be
called so but essentially you know
basically when you start to learn go you
know you just put this this whole thing
you know in every file so that's that
and okay let's get rid of that
so go line that and the go lines fire
sauce must be utf-8
okay so you can mostly for this and
Emacs okay I'll focus maybe I'll put
some you know focus on that got on is
great from what I've heard I think and
quark is written in go oh I didn't know
what is in broke let's see and grow oops
and work so green text green tech says
I'm a yolk programmer but right now I
mainly use oak mug for taking notes okay
that's all Martin is great for that
so in Quogue is a secured interest
spectable eternal to localhost secure
introspective eternal to localhost oh
this is a tutorial I'll do using word so
what what does I do a secure
introspective alternate to localhost why
you need eight turn on to localhost okay
so maybe you know it looks like a lot of
people not many people are you know
interested in go at the moment so maybe
I'll talk something else then okay yes
maybe we talk about something else and
just change the topic change the topic
so [ __ ] [ __ ] yeah so today should it be
like technical topic or non-technical
like oh I can act you know we can do
Emacs demo
well maybe it's not good idea to change
topic because because I told people to
that I'm going to do go so we got five
people watching you know if you you know
if you have questions so opinion just
say something so you say hi you know
type you know say hi so I know what do
you like to do so I'm kind of now okay
so so green tag says I hope not too
distracting
no from main topic but weiying stuff
like is Tiki didn't even character
doesn't delete opening it does okay let
me explain that okay
I think let's scratch the goal and then
because that's kind of you know you know
only for some people are interested in
that so it's yeah so let's talk about
Emacs he likes the great you know X so
okay so Frankie's is my is a package
that has efficient key binding and the
question is this command okay
sorry lead back or chart to bracket text
okay which normally does this for for
example okay I press that you see it
just delete backward one cha but if I
have hoops
ABC okay now something okay now I call
the command it just did it backward like
delete delete delete delete now watch it
deletes the whole parenthesis now undo
now if I move the cursor here TV TV TV
TV TV TV you see whenever it sees the
parenthesis you delete the whole thing
this applies to applies to any bracket
like whenever it see a bracket your TV
the pair now however here's a problem
however if you have you know if your
bracket is not matched you know you'll
tell you area of for example let's try
it
delete delete delete it says scan arrow
and balanced that's that's actually kind
of intend intentional so to cut to the
chase if you want to delete a bracket
like that you know not matched you call
this command instead which is the key
number five you code in each ah it's
bound to you know the key five so for
example my cursor is here for example
let's see D TV you see over here TV you
see so does that answer the question
so that that's that's kind that's why
you know because I want you know I
wanted to always be paired you know and
also it's a good tip that for
parentheses parentheses or brackets
always type them in pairs like always
you know and when you delete them it
just delete you know always go by pairs
yeah thank you
hey George I could George for you from
were you from China so hey Nicholas hey
Nikolas Nikolas were you from Hong Kong
was that you so okay so that's Sophocles
and George is from Australia oh my god
are you are you like Chinese and you
speak Chinese you know of course wait
are you a Chinese I know like are you
the what's a name Rick something
Nicholas is from Hong Kong okay cool so
learning Chinese cool hey what about
Nicholas are you Chinese so okay today
maybe we just random chat then so let me
type Chinese let's see if I can me mija
mija
wore tight tight tight tight tie one
then sir tie one then your wife is from
Taiwan cool
okay Nicklaus is Chinese okay so what
we're gonna talk about I kind of so we
kind of don't tight tight tight tight
so I speak some well I don't I I can
understand Taiwanese and Cantonese but I
cannot really speak them okay so what so
what what is today's topic then you know
guys good let's go let's you know pick a
topic like you think I might be
technical you know that so I have you
know on the YouTube you can see there's
a link you can go there and find a topic
and and we're gonna talk about that
so are you guys do you guys program
Jorge and Nicholas yeah so we kind of
don't have a topic now because we need
to we need to get on a topic we need to
get on topic because people is gonna
watch after the life you know the chat
so all the other people watch watching
you know say something so not so so this
ink work I'm not sure what it is public
URLs for exposing your local web server
oh that's interesting okay so your local
web server but public URL okay anyway
else
okay let's go then go on tutorial close
bar talk about go okay okay learning : -
okay okay let's yeah let's do go Landon
okay so I was saying okay so okay : lets
this go back to the so so I was saying
Colin's got these qualities you know
very fast as fast as C and extremely
popular why do you use the industry you
know the top five languages in the
industry you know we see Java and so on
in Python and it's very fast and very
it's very small mean minimum you know so
you can learn the whole language in you
know in just a few hours like spend the
whole day so and you know I have a
tutorial so if you just search focus Rd
:
this is my : tutorial on my logo so if
you are learning : you know give it a
shot you know try my tutorial so I was
talking about so : is great to learn
then it's very simple then you you
download you know the :
you know the binary file you download it
and you can just start to run this you
know just : yeah okay I know what to do
now
so for example this this is city code
you just run it and you get you know the
result you don't have to compile it but
if you want to compare you can you know
normally you you just type : test you
know your file name but if you want to
actually compare it to a binary then you
type go build test dot geo let's try it
so for example it's so here's my goal
and file and the file name is okay oh
those needs TV dad so this is the file
name let's rename it because it's too
long so let's just say X X Co okay so
this is my file name you can see and
this is the file content now if I just
want to run this file I can just type
first of all which go okay user loco
bingo that's good
go test go wait run okay
I have to type run oh no such file
that's right my file name is wrong xxxx
start go that's the correct file name
okay now it this is output so that's
good now if I want to compare it let's
see it's to go be owed xx start go then
now if I update the diet you can see it
creates this file xx now this file is
like 2 megabytes
now this xx so I can run it xx you see
it runs now I can send this X X file
this binary blob to you and you yo run
on your computer you know so you can
send it to your friends who is using
Linux or using Windows they don't have
to have Co installed you know because
you know it's compiled binary so this is
a great thing this is different from
Python or Ruby or JavaScript for example
because if you have a Python program
used you you cannot send it to your
friends they have to install Python so
this is great thing about another great
thing about : so if you look at the file
you see it's open airy file and the
compile time is extremely fast so anyway
so let's delete that we don't need it
anymore
so that's that's the very first thing
you do with : you thought you go to the
colon website you download the you know
the compiler of the program then you can
start to you know just like
we did you know create this file and
start to write programs so that's the
about compile and run and encoding
source code is so any go file must be
encoded in utf-8 okay and packaged okay
let's check a little bit for the
comments web tab at the moment no ok so
web dev so George is doing web dev in
Australia which city in Australia can I
like like I have some you know I have
some acquaintances you know some friends
at in Australia so running colons talk
about go okay let's talk
stick with go yeah okay so I want to
know your thoughts on typed verses and
typed okay that's the interesting
question because basically I came from a
math background so in my first 10 years
of programming which is with Western
Australia okay so my first 10 years of
programming which is 1990s okay starting
in 1990 what and the language is mostly
Mathematica FM the language or Perl and
my opinion about the typed versus
untyped was actually back then I don't
know much about computer science like I
have zero literally zero idea of a
comeback of anything about computer
science like I don't know what's the
compiler like I have no idea about its
you know even a technical definition or
whatever I don't know what is the
operating system well I know you know
you know you have Mac you know Windows
operating system but I have no idea like
what is supposed to like do you know
so in fact back then so basically most
of the 1990s antio until 1997 or 1998 I
started to get into UNIX and Perl you
know Solaris you know it's back then
and that's when I started to pick up you
know learning programming stuff
industrial programming stuff like
compiler used you know you start to
learn these jargons you have compilers
you have interpreters you have data
types you know so-called data types you
have you know array you have int you
know you have float this this byproduct
of computer engineering so anyway the
first time you are exposed to it it's
kind of strange especially if you are
from a math background you know what
what the [ __ ] is a int you know then you
have float then you have turbo that's
like complete idiotic concepts so anyway
so so up to you know most of 1990s I
have no background in industrial
programming like I don't know anything
the only thing I know is Mathematica I
was fairly oh the expert in Mathematica
because I read the menu or three times
you know that's 1,000 pages Mathematica
is a math oriented language in fact it's
the most advanced advanced language to
date okay it's far more advanced than
let's say haskell
or anything has Co F sharp or camo or
whatever have you or pure you know
whatever it's it's not just like better
more advanced but it's like one
magnitude more advanced than all these
tasks or whatever languages okay that's
Mathematica it's still true to this day
so but back in but it's not a industrial
language you know I talked about this
before a few times there's a you know
industrial in this scientific languages
scientific or math or Indian languages
including Mathematica Judea okay Julia
is a modern example so Mathematica Julia
APL MATLAB ah these are examples of math
or scientific programming languages
which are entirely different from the
industrial languages so anyway so back
in 1980s I don't know anything about I
don't know what does the protocol mean
you know
what the [ __ ] is a protocol you know I
have no idea about internet you know you
have Internet protocols you have HTTP
protocols you have you know tcp/ip you
know lower level you know do you like so
back then I have like I remember when
reading about you know let's say in Time
magazine people start to talk about
cyber you know say but when you know
when the internet just began or
cyberspace
yeah the internet was known as
cyberspace and so people you know and
hackers you know though you know the
kind of the early sci-fi the what she
sky de the guy who wrote the fiction you
know and remember the early cyberspace
let's see cyb space so like in the early
days 1990s the internet is called
cyberspace and it's kind of associated
with a sci-fi cybernetic and stuff but
keeps on yeah that's right it keeps us
so he wrote the book I forgot I forgot
the name what's the book he wrote this
he wrote a few very popular books but I
never read it
actually but anyway so so I was saying
ok so back then I don't know anything
about like I remember reading Time
magazine you know Time magazine was
talking about cyberspace and they also I
don't remember what year but they
mentioned you know how you know hackers
or companies they create color
you know like web crawlers okay and this
color can you know go to the side to
side and do stuff you know and and back
then I remember to me I was what what is
color this is amazing how is it possible
so I mean you know so so you have this
like thing that can you know go in into
the cyberspace and can hop around how is
that part of my how is it done of course
I know today you know like web color you
just write a program that just visit
websites
Python web koalas so I have a web color
here like in you know 20 lines you know
so I learned I mean of course I'm now
old I'm getting old you know I'm like 50
years old now but back in 1991 I was
like 21 or something so I didn't that
you know so when they talk about quota I
was like totally amazing and you know
captured you know fascinated how you
know how can you yeah what does it mean
so of course today I you know of course
I I know a lot so today our web Korra is
you know a computer program you it's
just it's really it looks just like this
you know you you you you visit website
by via you know it's you know tcp/ip
stack you know the HDTV photo and so on
anyway so back then in 1990s so what do
I know I know math okay I'm from a math
background so I was back then very much
into math so I know about algorithms you
know but from the math point of view oh
like oh math math algorithms and you
know but I you know I don't know so the
only language I actually know and in
fact no very know very well that's
Mathematica which is you know very
advanced language you don't have like in
those scientific programming languages
you don't have references you don't have
float what the [ __ ] you know get [ __ ]
yourself float int you don't have that
if you have pointers you don't have
these unnecessary like by what I would
call byproduct of computer engineering
okay that's that's you know that's you
have that because other practicality you
hack and you created those like int
float turbo you know and you know
references you know those things but
anyway so I I you know most people have
asked mature people they they don't have
any experience with math math
programming languages or scientific
programming so most people when we talk
about programming languages they are
mostly industrial programmers so what
they know is about like C C++ Java
Python Ruby pearl JavaScript and they
are concept about you know programming
language design or computer science is
like they you know make some of many of
them go to colleges and what they teach
well the ecology teach you know the
basics of data structure the basics of
algorithms the basics of operating
systems the basics of internet protocols
or communication protocols you know
which you know tcp/ip is just one of
them the most popular impact your well
and you know so so anyway I'm getting a
little bit off topic so what I'm saying
is is that okay so back to computer you
know you be aware that there is actually
a good distinction between computer
science and computer engineering okay
don't you know I'm not sure about that
George because Google is gonna ban me if
they see that yeah yeah so so you know
so computer science think you know
beware of there's a huge distinction
between computer science and computer
engineering now a typical programmer
like like all of us let's say you know
whoever works like Google most most of
them ok or Facebook or Microsoft most
programmers they when they know is like
what they know like is like limited to
computer engineering what what I call
computer engineering okay now however
that's different from computer science
now when I say computer science it's
more like theoretical computer science
now what is this this this theoretical
computer science basically 99% of
programmers in
practice they don't know nothing about
okay it's in theoretical computer
science so in in this field you have
data structure that's part of it okay
and algorithm that's part of it
okay these two subjects actually a lot
industrial programmers know and are
aware of you know okay but not some
others many complexities in in and many
other things
so anyway I'm getting far from the
original question so what I'm saying is
that in the back in the ninety nineteen
nineties I actually don't know anything
about computer science eager ones like
you know what the industrial program is
no no the theoretical ones I just know
some math okay and I I know a lot about
you know Mathematica but starting in
1998 I started to learn Perl and I
started to learn UNIX you know I read
books you know back then there's not
much online you know you like you go buy
books that's how you learn things you
know alrighty books and other other
publisher so you know I read lots of
UNIX book saying I became I joined you
know I joined the startup you know then
I start you know it started to program
start you know start my programming
career well I was you know working for
Wolff and research in 1995 for half a
year anyway so so way back then when I
first encountered the concept of types
in programming languages I think it's
the most idiotic [ __ ] possible okay
because you know the type
okay the type doesn't matter what what
do you is strongly typed old or you know
whatever the the very concept of a type
such as int float you know a reference
type or double or long you know Oh
string the very concept of type is a is
a byproduct of computer engineering why
why do I think that because you see it
they don't they don't exist new
mathematics okay like in mathematics you
have
well you could say you have types you
have real number you have complex number
you have integers these are types okay
yeah you know that you can call them
types different types of numbers but you
but okay so anyway let me see how do I
say okay yeah so you know since we are
talking about types versus and typed
languages first of all let me just say
so okay that that was my impression okay
number doesn't actually exist okay so
anyways so this is this is the 1990s I
don't know anything about computer
science of you know industry programming
that was my impression because I was
very big on math and math America I was
a expert in mathematical language which
is even to these days far more advanced
than all the other languages even ask
okay so I mean I'm kind of a weird you
know back in a kind of a weird person I
mean it's very pretty uncommon to have a
guy like that who doesn't know anything
about computer science but you know read
Mathematica book like 1,000 pages three
times and you know know it so well so
anyway so my impression bad thing is you
know type is just stupid you know you
should never like never programming
language should never ever have types
you know except the only exception is
that when it is math types mathematical
like me or number rational number that's
the so type integers okay complex number
you know then you talk about abstract
algebra rings field theory you know
that's that's my concept you know watch
it should be but that's back then you
know I was you know when I was you know
literally you can ignorant about you
know computer science and lots of things
okay so but then but then even up to
let's say up to 2010 so I you know you
know
today you know I have learned quite a
lot languages you know Perl Python Ruby
JavaScript you know I've you know 20
years of experience coding of you know
many things and but mostly okay I
usually don't like any of the typed
language okay such as C Java
I know Java okay I don't know see but I
know Java typed language okay
the actually the only two languages I
know that uh that are kind of like
strongly typed is is Java and Java and
and : okay
I know you know only a little bit about
Oh camel o camel is also very strongly
typed Oh camel is like Haskell okay
except it's not as pure as cow has got
to now like do not allow mutations at
all but okay mo allows that that's a
major difference but other otherwise you
know have Kokomo is you know you can
think of it as a more practical Haskell
f sharp is a version is a variation of
Oh camel if F sharp is Microsoft's
implementation of okay mo you could say
that I mean they change it a little bit
so okay mo is very strongly typed
statically typed okay so the only
actually the only language I could say I
actually know that is typed is Java and
Golan okay and okay so in general I
don't like typed languages because
because I still have the concept with me
that when you have types like : you know
for example colon has types you know
let's look at yeah :
it's like you know like okay so let me
mention another thing in many
of these languages especially okay let's
go to job okay let's go to Java okay
let's say array it just let's just say
string something simple you know for
example here is a Java Java code okay
when you so s1 is a variable you have to
declare a type so you know to me my
thinking is that how idiotic must be I
mean I mean I mean I mean okay when you
want to add two numbers or if you want X
equal you know x and y are variables for
example I mean think about math X is a
variable Y is a variable you want to add
them you just add them I mean who like
in math do you ever see people say ok X
is a number you know do you have to
declare it to be a number of us then Y
is the number of us then you add them as
a city in the same way I look at this
it's extremely serious specially Java
you see you have to like declare a
string first of all the very act too
thick you have to declare a type is
stupid
secondly suppose okay suppose you have
to declare but look at this you know you
know something equals to act on an
actual string you know so apparently
computer can figure it out why me I hate
anything that when computer can easy the
machine can easily figure out but the
language you know does not automate that
so you know apparently if you look at
this obviously you know the machine the
compiler should be able to figure out
you know because I'm saying you know the
he is a string you know so why do you do
I do I have to you know type string
there so it's you know it's stupid in
that way as well so two things one you
know declaration of type is just stupid
by itself - okay even let's say you yo
you want your language to declare types
but you should it should be automated
you know in this case like this it's
just stupid too
to still need to type type you know the
type you know type that I'd type the
type and but this and more things stupid
about Java but is unrelated now because
Java not you have stream buffer cleaner
Java is like so complex you have stream
you have buffer then you have file
object then you have file handles
handlers then you have file content file
stream handles you know it's like it's
like Jojo eyes like that like read read
file yeah look look so it took to read a
file you need a file object you like you
you need to create a file object then
you need to quit create a reader object
so anyway yeah so so Java is like kind
of one example where the type just Park
you down you know this is just stupid
anyway but back to so but okay let me so
so : you know today's newer languages
they have what's called type inference
so : you also need to declare types for
your variables so for example you have
these you know these are the basic
primitive you know you know basic types
in :
every variable must must be associated
with a tight and very every value and
very every variable as well so and let's
go back to stream so when you have var X
you don't see the type here because
colon has a feature called type
inference now this is true for Haskell
and other languages well ok MOTU they
have a feature of a type inference so
that in in many cases you don't have to
type you don't have to you know enter
the type input the type anymore because
the machine can figure it out you know
it's it's logic you know it just so that
does you know that that's that's
tremendously good you know this is the
right step forward tremendous good but
still ok now back to the original
question still we have the question so
do you prefer untyped language like
dynamic language or typed I mean so the
question is you know okay so you have
type inference but why do we need type
at all I mean what way you know back to
my new math oriented idea you know type
is just a byproduct of computer
engineering what do we want to have
types of course the industrial
programmers the common answer is that
types helps you prevent errors you know
well you can you know that's kind of
true but that's not the whole story
but anyway so back to my own you know so
I have to deal with this question
because I'm interested in languages ok
so the short answer I mean ok though the
final answer is that yeah ok so I was
going to say so in the past few years
like the past three or four years I
started to have a different perspective
on typed especially strongly typed yeah
ever yeah I have a different perspective
now strongly typed languages like :
as in Haskell and oak ammo because they
because when you are using these
languages they you know the type are
very strict you know they are strongly
typed you know you know the issue about
types in programming languages is
actually fairly complex like if you go
to Wikipedia you can see many articles
discuss it in detail so so it's not what
typical programmer would think but
anyway that's let's not get into that
but anyways right now so they are the
issue about strongly typed languages
right you know for example Java colon
and Haskell or camel so I started to
appreciate them appreciate them because
when you program in the Indies strongly
typed languages
you are you are like so I start to think
of them as a very strict as a large
ecosystem that's a key points as a
logical system so are you guys still
here like I just mother logged for one
hour I think say something I think we
almost and but anyway they answer back
so so I started to view these strongly
typed languages as a kind of a logical
system and this is necessary because
especially when I started to look into
proof systems you know math proof
systems hi George
so so you when you when you start to you
know study approved systems in math you
know computerized proof systems you can
see that type is important in fact you
know there's type theory you know for
example type theory and you know logic
systems symbolic logic and you have type
theory it's one of the philosophy of you
know automate you know Farsi of
automated math systems there are several
different philosophies meaning with
different approaches so type Theory
typed system is one of the approach for
the foundation of math and so I started
to see they are critical I mean they are
important and critical because I started
to view them as a logic system so yeah
so so I no longer you know like before
you know type is just a byproduct of
computer engineering you know that is
still true for Java you know for the
Java and C and C++ that is still true
there are types is like just a side
effect of computer engineering okay now
the the viewpoint of looking at strongly
typed languages as a logic system
applies to Haskell okay mo F sharp
and you know you can say Golan - you
know so that's that's what I'm saying so
you see I started to look at that look
at them strongly typed programming
languages as a logic system you know for
very strict proofs and stuff so that's
so that is basically my perspective so
but what about so let me just like
resolve you know my parrot the paradox
so you know what about my my younger
self you know where the type is just a
byproduct of computer engineering
so isn't you know the types in Haskell
they are just byproduct of Computer
Engineering no because when you actually
you know look at computer languages as a
logical system type is actually
necessary I mean that's what you want I
mean I mean that's you know if you look
at Haskell or Golan or you know okay mo
as a logic system and in the outset your
goal is to want to have the type you
want a type that's like that's the main
dish you know so that's why I appreciate
them but not not the types in Java or
C++ or C I think those those are like
those are crap so that so that's that is
my that is my opinion about typed versus
dynamic I still like dynamic and I I do
appreciate type so if you ask me which
would add choose well that would depend
I mean I cannot I mean I couldn't say
you know I just
just pick one answer because you know
because I'm really interested in
improved systems that's what I want to
do you know but meanwhile it's it is
true that if you just want to plot you
know like mathematics when you want to
you know do scientific programming
usually you don't want types because
because types actually bug you down when
you do a plot you don't care about yeah
I mean you are not doing proofs you just
want to see the graph or if you are
doing statistics you know I just want to
do
riveted oh you know integrate you know
some equations you know
solution to a matrix you know equation
you just want to get the numbers you
know you are not doing proofs you know
you want to you are doing computation
with math you know so so forth you know
for scientist or you know for many in
many cases or even if you are writing a
script to clean your disk or whatever
you don't want types you know usually
they park you down even even with type
inference but if you are you know do
improves you do want you know types you
know for example in Python actually I
noticed that colon is actually more
verbose in Python you know it's like one
point one point five more verbose you
know like writing the same program in
Python is 100 lines in colon will be
like 120 or 150 lines that you know it
turns out to be that case and you know
other people say that as well so even
you know you know even go has a type
inference but still you know usually
typed them so anyway that I think that's
it so today we talked about typefaces
and type languages very interesting
topic so Finch teaching them so which
says statistically statically typed
first drawn type inference equals
through good place to be yeah yeah
especially I mean especially if you
viewed as a logic system I mean
especially if your goal is to actually
you know do math proofs you know or oh
yeah if you want you know like
verifiable you know programs you know
something right
you know Finch
Finch Fitch says that I'm starting to
like dependent types more and more and
type inference doesn't walk much yeah
dependent types
what does I mean I'm not much i i'm
still learning the subject I don't know
I haven't coded Haskell actually
actually so depend depend on type is
like I forgot what it means dynamic
languages for prototyping but not for a
big project yeah that seems that seems
reasonable
yeah okay so I think one hour in seven
minutes I think that's it for today yeah
so yeah so thank you guys for coming
thank you everyone
I'll see you next time bye