good morning guys good morning Bart good
morning Emily come on in Freddie welcome
to another episode of Santa's show
today's 2019 October 31st Thursday and
today we have several big topics so guys
pick a pick a topic I don't think you
guys have picked a topic yet let's pop
out the chat and we're gonna have big
topic this time you waited you know so
Halloween Halloween special what
Halloween special I don't have anything
special about Halloween
pick the topic guys from the description
let me check out the comments so you
guys are talking about see and
programming see stuff so pick a topic so
today's topic is gonna be Emacs
miscellaneous Emacs stuff my workflow
and miscellaneous Emacs stuff that's
number one
or to install web pack from scratch and
ran for one hour about modern JavaScript
development 3 install Emacs and my setup
from scratch so that's also about Emacs
so for you Emacs people we have not
talked about Emacs for a while so you
have two topics to choose from or the
JavaScript modern JavaScript development
in the web pack okay so what which is
gonna be which it is going to be and
yesterday the hello beautiful people
suggested a fantastic solution to the
JavaScript generating a array problem
range function and his solution is
actually the fastest I as you know I
made a mistake yesterday his solutions
actually the fastest Oh fastest his
solutions here and I think he's from
Germany so and he sent me an email
saying that he can be here today he
wants the time to be earlier you see the
timing is a problem because you guys in
Europe you were you know this is the
right time or earlier for you guys but
you know the people in Asia which is
populist far more people then then
Europe they they don't get to see the
live show so I'm not sure about the time
man you know and the other thing is if I
I can have a fixed schedule but I have
to put some effort to it on and the
other thing is if I just go by my usual
wherever I come up where I wake up
scheduled in that case the talk will
usually be better because when I wake up
you know after basically usually when I
wake up after two hours and I start a
media talk show and that's usually good
because I just woke up okay so let's see
the comments and the topics guys hard
choice number two okay so we got number
two about JavaScript the modern
JavaScript crap so Emily also wanted
earlier Bay Area base yeah okay so let's
see what other comments so but is asking
me about my opinion of bash I think we
didn't talk about that before wasn't did
you ask that or somewhere else
basically patchy is no good fascist crap
bash is the one of the worst language if
you not use bash use / oh okay even pro
is dead
so bash is no good bash is crap as far
as language is concerned bash is crap I
mean when we talk about which language
you know what's your opinion about
language there are many perspectives I
mean first of all I mean the the number
one is what what is your
if you are concerned about technical
quality of the language bash is crap the
worst language possible the worst
scripting language possible to and but
the on the other hand if you want to
consider practicality in today's world
in real life what do you think of bash
bash bash is there batteries it's gonna
be patchy it's gonna be us for a while I
think and because it is on every UNIX
system when you install when you install
any program today you go and bash you
write a bash script so that is the
question that is the answer my opinion
about bash now what are you do you have
something else in mind but about bash
say it I know you posted a link I think
that's a link what is that about because
I'm going to we are going to focus on
that you know one of the topic today so
so far it's gonna be JavaScript modern
JavaScript framework problems okay so
let me finish reading the comments and
let's see I if I'm alive yes indeed not
scream and six people watching okay so
let's see magnify okay
everyone honest most would agree that
recency is popular because historical
reasons indeed it's a momentum I mean he
sees means reading see see see crap how
has my UK knees slipped out you told us
the other day Emily oh by the way yeah
hold on wait a second mm never mind
so by the way I got now I'm a youtuber
monetizing youtuber I am a monetize me
I'm now officially monetizing YouTube
Google has granted
Kazaa okay we let you so do you guys see
the super chat like do you have options
somewhere super chat you know I have
dollar sign in my eyes so Emily you guys
says same he says okay so let's keep
read the comments Emily back I didn't
know so many UK people United Kingdom
I was always assumed they are Spanish or
something because of their English guys
guys
yes yo yo okay so where are you from but
I always repeat it
Germany body is from Germany therefore
usually wakes me misery breaks the
mystery mystery everyone knows everyone
else because that's the question I ask
often on my channel you know if you
choose to tell that is so most people
here Germany UK Germany UK and also
because of my timing emam I am emos come
on I am emos so where are you from
Amy most so Alan says you are dressed as
a casual hoodie open-source software
developer for Halloween now I know I
need to put on my hood I need to be
yourseif Sith Lord I second that boat
okay so webpack gets to wear pack
Poland good morning to Poland
geography 101 Poland to is to the right
of Germany okay and UK is to the left of
Germany so you have Germany on the right
year Poland on the left of Germany you
have Switzerland is as Switzerland or
Holland then below a bit below you have
friends then below that you have Italy
to the left of France you have United
Kingdom and they are enemies forever
let's I'm gonna do let's start to do the
JavaScript okay let's start with the
JavaScript web pack so let's go to let's
do web pack indeed let's see the wonders
of JavaScript web pack and who are you
guys so you guys which of you do
JavaScript death now usually I can tell
after a while for my comments from you
guys like what do you say so I can tell
wit pack web dawg
there's a guy named web dawg he he is a
JavaScript code I mean when I mean
JavaScript code I don't mean you know
you die boarding it you know you have
you know a lot of people we have dabbled
in lots of things I mean they work in a
company or something you know writing
JavaScript every day for years I can
tell so there's there is a guy web dog I
know he's a JavaScript coda and Daniel
Anglo is he was he was here yesterday I
think he also is probably your
JavaScript code and I know from King
hearings because he he told he told us
that he is also a JavaScript coder you
know for professionally and I can tell
right away that yesterday
hello beautiful guys he's a JavaScript
code
okay so web pack you see weight pack
let's go to documentation web pack let's
start from scratch okay so in this
episode you if you are not a JavaScript
coder you might learn something from it
you know for my rent basically and if
you are a one of those JavaScript coders
front end then you can you know comment
and correct me okay correct me because
I'm picking up the mod and JavaScript
crap the react angular web pack grunt
the bunch of garbage npm so that's
speaking okay so let's go to web pack so
what we need to do first is we need to
let's go to the directrix our talk show
okay we got lots of things and we're
gonna make a directory create a
directory okay create a directory web
pack let's say X work web pack okay so
like experimental web pack so we need to
npm install so speak the window go to a
show npm install let's see if I remember
the modern JavaScript stuff I'm learning
so NPM store install NPM in it NPM in it
- why that will create basically oops I
got it in a run directly shipped
okay so NPM in it will create basically
you just create this single file but we
didn't in our own directory so let's
delete that let's go to this directory
instead this directory now split window
now go to shell close that kirusha let's
MPM in it again
so it says a new minor version of NPM
available so anyway so you refresh the
directory so you can see MPM package
star Jason basically just create this
file now this is a kind of a config file
that tells you everything about what
package is your project use so basically
we are creating a new project you know
patch I don't know what is a bad batch
SS that's a new shell you have to say
anyway we today we're focusing on the
JavaScript NPM you sign away maybe you
need to be like various bundle so NPM in
it - why so we got this in e-file
basically it tells you the name of your
project the version number the
description something let's say Sartre's
rant on JavaScript okay so the main file
index dot J's so you got a bunch of
things that like that so if you go read
web pack documentation they have a guide
and they are excellent so this is
actually a great web web pack is has one
of the best documentation so you go to
concept you go to guide okay you go to
guide and they will give you getting
started like complete tutorial so
basically we are basically almost
following it so now let's do the next
step
MPM install web pack then - save death -
- save dead
yes that's that is the correct correct
command let's run it so we are
installing NPM
what oh my god he read it and didn't get
it
hardcore cringe my deepest condolence I
don't get young people's thing okay
patch what is what what is that
I don't get that okay so so yeah I don't
as you don't get that
so NPM install now you see it says it
added 390 packages patch I don't get it
so NPM is installed 390 packages okay
let's refresh the so let's look at what
directories we have so you can see here
is a directory so it created not modules
you see now this is the 390 packages
libraries what incredible incredible
crime it's a crime it's a major crime so
you have package lock Jason you can you
know ignore it okay it's basically it's
used by NPM for internal stuff to make
sure the package are installed like
uniquely or something
so package that Jason that's an
important file you want to know you want
to check so you see it added this thing
dev in dev dependencies web pack that
means this project you have this
dependency web pack however it's used as
a dev meaning that when you when you
create your software web pack will not
be part of it it will be just your for
your death when you are doing you know
developing your JavaScript project you
need web pack so that's what dev
dependencies me and if you want to
install something of dev dependency
you use these save dev option for NPM
MVM is though so let's go to the
directory and let's look at 390
libraries dependencies like what what a
school what a crime and you know some of
them for example some of them are a lot
of them are just ten lines of code ten
lines of code lets us let's look at for
example this array flattened so this
this library array flattened a basically
flattens array like if you have a ray a
nested array array whose elements are
arrays this this library let's look at
it ten lines of code okay this this
library ten lines of code we are
flattened you know the array what
incredible idiocy and in fact flattened
array I have written a function you know
myself let's go to my JavaScript
in-depth now guys this is time to buy my
tutorial JavaScript min depth this is
the best JavaScript language tutorial in
depth of in English literature does not
matter it's printed or not a fusion is a
good dog and the Sun and the mountains
of dependencies well that's true I mean
web pack truly have the best talk
because I've read you know I've read
lots of it by a they are huge okay I've
read you know the the beginners guide
the concepts you know I've read several
chapters for as a beginners so and from
what I see web web pack documentation is
one of the best industry name in my 30
years is and among JavaScript libraries
and community communities web web pack
they are excellent
you know the documentation at least the
web pack package itself
would also say is excellent but I'm
criticizing you know this bunch of I'm
criticizing the modern JavaScript way
you know the modern JavaScript you know
that the 300 you know you install one
package this package installed 390 other
packages that is a situation I you know
I cannot possibly imagine
you know I will like this kind of system
this workflow this is and this 390
systems you don't know who wrote them
like any take you know they begin a
college student you know wrote this
array flattened function and it becomes
a package it's all open source ok Oh
part of the reason of this kind of bloat
and the bad system is because open
source you know I'm I'm not going to do
a random open source today but it is my
opinion part this you know this
situation if you agree with me that it's
no good you know where you have like
hundreds of dependencies if you agree
and if you if we ask why is that why did
did this happen I have not researched
for it but but I would say one of the
reason is open source because once you
have open source you prevent people from
making money then one of the things
people do is trying to get Fame famous
so you get a bunch of you know students
or whatnot
they try they try to make famous so they
can say oh look I have this library five
lines of code that is very popular you
know hundred thousand downloads you know
that's one of the reason you and also
white why did npm create you know this
doesn't this kind of things doesn't come
by just you know it doesn't just happen
there must be some reason social
historical or whatever reason or by
design intentional to to have this
situation where you know you have
hundreds of packages dependencies and as
a normal you know like every time you do
a java script this is normal where pack
is one of the most
popular used JavaScript ponderous okay
bundlers is one one of the two were
JavaScript's development need so web
pack is one of the most popular you know
the top two web pack and the passo is
the top two most popular bundles
bandulus right now they change every few
years you know javascript land things
change every few years Paso is this one
okay parc ljs now in comparison I've
also read I've also tried to read read
the parcel documentation it's one of the
worst criminal parcel documentation now
as far as I know I've learned you know
from my sources the sources I trust
people who I think who know JavaScript
you know the people I trust one of them
is the the creator of Nadia's you know
Ryan da you know I trusted him so he's
you know he is very very much into Paso
he says this is the greatest thing so
Paso but he's so so I started with
possible I want to you know learn Paso
his with webpack Paso is newer than web
pack and I read the documentation it's
crap you don't understand what's going
on you don't know what they are talking
about they don't you know they don't
know how to write documentation there's
no documentation things like that pasa
crap
so I you know because I'm new to the
modern ways of JavaScript you know this
MPM you need yet you know so I am not
familiar with this thing I'm not I'm
learning so we're you know I begin with
Paso I read a dog I don't get it
crap documentation so I stopped so I I
try to focus on web pack you know then
after a few months once I'm familiar
with how all these things work then I
can go back to par so possibly but you
know by next year there may be there
will be new things you know in
JavaScript land you know Paso so so this
puzzle
and webpack they are called bundlers
spondylus what they do is that they take
a bunch of JavaScript source code and
they will generate one single JavaScript
source code that's what they do
basically and that's and the these
spondylus is part of the component of
modern JavaScript framework I mean the
modern JavaScript workflow to set you
have to use it we're gonna get into
details okay so anyway let's look at you
know for example now we have 390
libraries you know as a curious person
as a Explorer I look at them I see what
they like what they are you know I know
JavaScript very well so I try to look at
what what these idiots what are they
trying to do you know so I spot-on I
spotted this one you know array
flattened let me show you my own
function for that array flattened so you
go to sorry sorry sorry dot info
search for JavaScript in depth then you
go to array okay you go to scroll down
array understanding array creating array
sparse array array like object array how
to you click on array how to then you
can find there is a flatten a way how to
flatten nested array here so look at my
Oh God you know okay so let me tell you
what this story in JavaScript 2019 a
comma script 2000 night 19 they added a
method to the JavaScript language flat
so so in fact you don't need this array
flattened library anymore you can you
know it's building you have a function
flat there flattens array what do you
mean by that for example this is Ray
it's a nested array you've you flatten
it you can say how many levels to flat
you know you know like get rid of
honestly
so that's that's the array flatten now I
have written my own version of flatten
before you know before these so you know
and so it's called Pony feel you know
polyfill is another extreme idiocy the
jargon created by the tech nerds in this
case it's created by this kind of the
new generation of nerds called poor
coders bra coders you know they in
JavaScript land in particular polyfill
came from the JavaScript land poly feel
feel feel feel your ass you know they
like this they like this you know so
this you know you see if you are of the
UNIX philosophy type of people you know
you love jargons right grave group
whatever you know cat you know UNIX crap
but in the new generation you have new
bunch of these millennial coders mostly
they are from JavaScript and Ruby you
know they they are that generation they
are JavaScript and Ruby coders and they
they also created jargons different from
yours
okay so poly Theo is one of the jargons
they create they created others include
you know in the past ten years shot I
think shot for example in database shot
shots poly Theo and they are they are a
few okay anyway
poly fear is one of them it's an idiotic
jargon I'm not going to go into details
about that but anyway so I I have
written a function to flatten away
before you know before the ACMA script
2018 sputum function so you look at my
code it's ten lines of code okay
I bet it's better than these guys you
know I'm confident it's better than
whoever who wrote this way flattened
so let's you know let's put my coat out
there that's compete head-to-head let's
see who is better you know I want to
okay wait wait
so let's see JavaScript so this is my
code
flat a nested array so this this is the
wait why is that every time
what
anyway so let's get back to this so
array flatten so this is my code fatten
array
let's read of the comments okay let's
read the documentation so it's ten lines
of code and then then we have test then
we have yeah let's let's do some live
JavaScript session and let's copy this
guy's code okay copy it close it and put
it here let's go to the top put his code
there and save these us save this okay
save these hold on a second go to Mike's
a talk show open it
so that's today's talk show then go to
create a javascript file paste the code
show him browser color it showing
browser now we're gonna coded so modify
the code so so let's let's do this array
flattened so by this guy let's let's
have a look like what kind of people are
there I mean who is he
Jong Jong Shin Lanka his name is John
she nunca
okay let's you know let's have a look at
the modern ways of programmers the
modern the new generation the
Millennials stuff so John Schillinger
Curt shilling cuts something so he has a
github so this is array flattened this
is one single function ten lines of code
to flatten array in JavaScript and you
see this github you got pinch mark you
got editor config you got es lint you
got Keita tribe Keita tribes you got
kitty
you got Travis dot yml this is
continuous integration Travis I don't
know what ten lines of code continuous
integration you have dot verbs whatever
whatever that is you have license
you have read me you have app veilleux's
obvious you have power Jayson power is
some kind of I think he's also a
JavaScript bundle you have index okay
that's the main code indexed RJ's now
another thing to notice is that in
JavaScript land apparently you don't
name your library in the same name as
your file name like typically I've
noticed because I was exploring you know
they they name your library just like
indexed our chairs every every libraries
file name is indexed RJ's it's almost
like that you know that's so that's you
know you you look at things you look at
things from all aspects not the dogmatic
you know view of the Jedi okay you you
want to look at things from all aspects
so so I look at things you know I was
you know looking into modern JavaScript
web pack you know so I look at all the
things whatever comes interest to me
so one thing for example one thing you
will learn is that you learned about
this you might call it peculiarity you
know so javascript libraries they they
always name it like index touches this
is for example this is in contrast to to
eMac this to Python to Pearl to Java to
Golan to almost every other language
because in those languages you have
library systems you have named
namespaces typically the package module
library however the language cause it
typically the name is the file name of
the package is related to the module you
know the namespace name
they are synced but you can see it's not
the case with JavaScript why I can tell
you
because JavaScript do not have a library
system only until recently and it's a
big giant mess that's why you need all
these
that's why you need Pandora's actually
you know like I said before bundlers
take a bunch of JavaScript source code
merge them into one you know doing some
transformation in meanwhile but anyway
that's a the ultimate goal is to much
merge you a bunch of Java JavaScript
source code into what why you need to do
that because JavaScript do not have a
library system they do now but it's a
mess that's why you need bandura's this
mappack web pack this puzzle this this
power you know the power touches and
it's you know let me show you power
power J's I think that's what it is
so you see power J's you see a package
manager for the width whatever okay
power is a package manager like NPM it's
it's got displaced by NPM basically I
think no no one uses power anymore I'm
not sure
anyway that's you know in JavaScript
land you have 1,000 things so back to
the github of this guy who wrote a Rea
flat flattened array
so you got this bunch of crap then you
have you know ok so then then let's
let's look at his package does he does
he also loads 100 dependencies for 10
lines of code okay so he's got the
dependencies indeed apparently he is
loading
he's got dev dependencies meaning you
know it's not part of his library but
from here from his dev dependencies you
can see apparently he slowed in several
other JavaScript libraries that does
flatten away so I'm guessing you know
he's doing comparison like he can load a
bunch of others and
compare which one is faster or whatever
ten lines of code 15 dev dependencies
Jesus and you see ut-oh flat and all
these are you know all these and look at
this one the naming of this one just
flatten it okay am i a man doing good
am I being funny or am being not funny
that's not funny he's you know he's got
a 10-10 fat and other fat and rate
dependencies okay and related Jesus
related okay that's that's he stuff I
think so okay this guy he wrote this
package you know and there's a
documentation of a flat and recursively
fatten array always install install
usage okay
why another flattened utility oh yeah
that's important why I want the fastest
implementation I could find with
implementation choices that should work
for 95% of use cases but no craft to
cover the other 5% so he does he does
not want 100% correct flat array fatten
yet but but he does want it to be fast
the fastest what what do you mean 95 use
cases like are you saying that you
cannot I mean I mean what what are the
issues are there situations that you
cannot flatten an array 100% I mean this
is not we are not talking about AI
engine that cures cancer right are we
talking about AI engine that cures
cancer where you only solve 95% of cases
like what what do you see talking about
but anyway he claims that his code is
the fastest I want you see he says I
wanted the fast
implementation I could find okay so
let's see services Jang Jin Ling cut
services millennial cassava versus pro
coders let's see whose code is faster
let's get serious about this so let's
see so he's code let's let's get that
spring of the book in this library
system it's just just let's just remove
the export so flat
so let's rename his function let's
rename it to what John okay let's just
say his his function is flat John and my
function will be flattened let's let's
say okay let's rename my function flat
saw okay did we play so that's good so
we got two functions
he's function fat John he take it takes
an array and it takes what so what what
is this resolution is the idiocy of the
naming of parameters of this millennial
generation of coders so where's the
document let's let's see the
documentation usage Fratton required a
flattened okay so it takes one argument
right but here it's taking two arguments
so what the what the he is using
the cursed recursion recursive solution
recursion so the second second argument
is you
for the function itself you know so I
can tell you a problem you know the you
okay he's using recursive solution but
however you see the second argument is
not exposed to the user well on one hand
it's not supposed to expose to the user
but the actually it is you see what I
mean so you see so this guy you know
this flattened weight I also have to
rename here so flat okay so rename here
so you see this this function cause
itself and I suppose you know I have to
look at what is he doing but basically I
imagine he is feeding you know the rest
argument you know the feeding or Reyes a
second argument to itself so what I'm
saying is that on one hand when you look
at this function you know you are coda
you need to look at the source code
sometimes right there's no documentation
because I don't see it
you know there's no you know there's no
actual documentation there's just a
usage example and in this usage example
we only see one argument we don't see
the use of the second argument so what
I'm saying is is that he's using
recursion but however the second
argument is exposed to the user
interface so that's not no good well
that's a minor my criticism okay it's a
minor issue it's a okay that's how he do
it so I don't know how he actually so
for let's see for is irate that that
that anyway it's because if because he's
using solution now let's let's look at
how I how I did it so Excel flat array
actually I have documentation let's copy
back my documentation where is it
so I'm a fat and fat initiative array in
levels I can have levels
he doesn't have levels so immediately I
win one point you know I can specify how
many level you want to flatten it and
devotes to 1 so n can be lodged such as
thousands because when array no longer
has elements that is an array the
function returned immediately
okay so so yeah if you want to flatten
or you can just just put one thousand
you know so this is the URL so copyright
free use copyright sauce copyright free
use must include link and credit oh my
god this is what license is this this is
this is great license oh my god this is
better than GPL and better than MIT
in the better name open sauce
look this guy is also nice free use must
include linking credit anyway so let's
see how I do it so if n is int undefined
something something something you see I
am also using a recursive implementation
you see it's recursion it's calling the
function it's you know by myself but I
do not expose like the way he did you
know expose the internal stuff into the
parameter so so so we want first of all
so let's we can run this okay we can run
it it returns a bunch of answers you
know I'm testing so so this is what you
see it prints you know it's supposed to
it works now what we want to do is we
want to we want to write another
function that compares the result of
both of us given the same input so that
we can say you know they are correct
let's do that
but before we do that let's look at some
let's look at the comments okay
it's search is it a tragedy or comedy
indeed in JavaScript land the messiest
land in programming languages not
necessarily okay not necessary in the
missus because if you called see the
language see the low-level see black we
will have to see which is Messier see
the C language no namespace no nothing
include include the whole one thousand
five and for forty years now they don't
have they are not going to have name
namespace or you know library system
JavaScript at least for all its parts
you know it's kind of high level and
sees the worst so animos says regarding
trust what's the relation of this not J
sky to Paso is he truly neutral I trust
him
I don't think there's a relation but you
know I I don't know for sure but I don't
think this is the Association he he gave
a talk you know he sees a creator of not
yes and he is a nerd type kind of like
me okay like you guys okay he's a nerd
type he doesn't he's not a you know very
smooth person he speak what's in his
mind you know not jaya sky ryan da if
you search sorry Ryan dow you'll find
several of my articles about him his
videos I recommend you watch it so Ryan
Dow is a nerd guy he's very smart he's a
mathematician okay he was he was
originally PhD you know research
mathematician and he you know that's
anyway I like him so what day he
recommended parcel you know there is a
thing about him though he likes
JavaScript
he likes typescript you know he says Oh
Thomas crib is the best thing and in the
typescript you know he's oh he's he's
kind of like happy
javascript land I don't think Java you
know I think JavaScript is one of the
worst that yeah so but anyway I liked
him very much
I've I you know I like his stuff his
opinions the word blowed he's very apt
here that's why minify packages is
necessary so slim stuff down yeah but
the there are many aspect to it though I
mean yeah JavaScript anyway so let's
read some comments okay I guess no
comments so if you have come and typed
now okay so because next we are going to
dive into this you know it's all code
it's about JavaScript we cannot compare
these two solutions so I want to see if
at least he claims his code is fastest I
want to see that if that's true you know
I want to see if if I if I actually have
some force behind my grants this man a
noble millennial idiots okay so so let's
see comment so MC we'd says JavaScript
is as messy as human are we should
identify and feel close to it no except
no expectations if excellence on either
side no expectations if excellence on
either side keep it simple and deliver
Lee okay so name three names we says
isn't free use contradictory to know
that's anyway that's not important
that's it's just stuff now it's getting
interesting okay so let's do this so
first of all we want a function that
compares the output to make sure though
yeah I know what you mean
MC we
so we want a function to compare these
you know both of our information
implementation returns the same result
so I so you need a function that
compares array like array equal you know
another big suckiness of javascript is
that there's no way to compare two
arrays are equal no way you have to
write a function and it's not trivial to
do it so it's and I'm sure actually I'm
sure if you look at the let's open a new
window let's go to the web pack X web
pack I'm sure one of this module
actually compare you know lo - does it
lo - for example such low - or is it
such low - okay it's not there yet so
anyway in the in the web pack
installation you need to install web
pack but you also need to install web
pack command command line interface web
pack command line interface so let's
install that then you're gonna add
another 50 libraries ok it's done now it
added another 64 libraries now let's
look at the libraries refresh so we have
a total of 318 what 300 you know 10
libraries something like that so that's
such 4 wait didn't didn't web pack
itself installed 390 so web pack
installed 390 laibach edges and web pack
see how I installed 64 packages but why
is my not module directory only 300 eh
King directories okay maybe that's
because some libraries do not create a
directory okay that's another thing you
pick up maybe some library just create
something else right does anyone know do
we do we have JavaScript coders here
Alan Alan you caught some you-you-you
kochiyama Scooby I walk right Oh am I
wrong so oh maybe I have some
system-wide well because I both both of
them I say save dev you know that should
be you know because those are dev
dependencies so Alan okay
so Alan give us tips okay whenever you
know you correct me or you know give us
some tips okay so let's look at you know
I want to look at lo - and let's go get
on to the the other issue wait
solo - is is not required here anyway
let's go back so so we need a function
to compare two arrays are equal
JavaScript does not have that so let's
go back to JavaScript in depth let's go
to array my array test object equality I
have written a function to do that
function to test object equal equality
you know there are lots of JavaScript
libraries that does it - and this is my
own okay I haven't read any of any of
theirs
so let's and there is a function that
tests if two arrays are equal here this
is what we need copy it go to the top
paste it here so you can see this block
of code size array equal does it does it
you know this this function
so now we just need to call them and
compare so okay so let's let's see if we
hold on a second
so she's function flattens all the way
right
he's function flattens all the way yeah
so so in order to compare let's call his
function let's do this
let's rename it okay so they hold on a
second
because this is hard to type yeah let's
it's not rename so there is his function
and here is my version okay and let's
console.log print to see if they return
the same thing okay
vennett cannot read property push of
undefined okay somebody is wrong okay so
someone is wrong let's see
let's try my ok mine works
let's try his he's got a problem
okay maybe I use I did not use it
correctly Jesus you know I hope I'm not
rep misrepresenting his stuff but what
is going on here it's only one argument
so why is that Jesus now I'm I'm pretty
sure that he's must walk because it's
part of the JavaScript ecosystem oh did
because did I'd rename his stuff wrong
let's see did I renamed his stuff wrong
okay let's see let's see the comments
yes fit Freddie one way to compare a ray
is to make them Jason or make an object
Jason but that doesn't that's not
reliable because when you have an object
or a race you know by expect the items
are not ordered so when you string to
string of I into Jason the the odor may
be different so that's it's not a
reliable way to do it and it yeah but if
you have like just a few items usually
it works so I using underscore yeah
underscore Dargis they have function for
that underscore is one the one of the
most popular back then they are kind of
being replaced by low - low - is the
newer version of underscore basically
wah-wah what are we going to do next
load a JavaScript file in script to
transfer data between applications what
do you mean no we are doing this array
comparison for now and let's see how
long have I been talking today 58
minutes okay so so Alan says if you dig
into not module you will find that there
are more not modules directories within
some of the dependencies oh oh that's
interesting
let's see if we
we can we can you know maybe it's there
maybe not see that's the why don't you
think that's semantic versioning madness
is very confusing that's why we don't
have an NPM install NPM audit in still
doesn't work Neverending in front of
text text lines containing the string
NPM but the other but the ordering are
very matter though so we different we
different the other way or not equal
okay so anyway so so so what are we
doing yeah we are trying to figure out
how to use his function did I like it's
a problem right because I didn't change
his function why is it not walking now
let's let's look at his original code
array flatten okay here is the code here
is the code you strict okay we are using
strict always so he says flat module
exports oh god there is a there's a
layer this module export so forget about
my previous criticism about his exposure
of the second argument to the interface
so actually he has a kind of alias here
so you see the real function he export
is this one with with with one single
argument but internally he is actually
you know calling two arguments right so
yeah okay okay so let's let's let's this
do this again
it's common this let's move the used
strict to the top that's that's one of
the JavaScript pragma kind of thing it
will take too long to explain so anyway
so he's function the way to call his
function is that you need to give it a
second argument of empty bracket I mean
the his internal function so that's so
when it it walks okay
now comment this out now second comment
these two line out and let's make that
now that's two comparison Gwinnett error
okay so you need a empty array here
vennett it's a it's true so that means
given this array both are functions
return the same answer correct that's
good so now the next thing is to
actually should we do more tests or
should we start to do timing let's see
what are some other tests okay let's
ignore the tests because I'm just
testing how many level to flatten so
let's ignore that suppose both us both
are both both of our code returns the
same result correct so next thing is to
do timing
how do you do timing guys but the other
but you're very matter so MCB thanks for
the - tip so let's do timing okay so
timing now I'm not familiar with the
proper way to do timing but I have the
classic way to do timing that that works
so timing JavaScript code so this is how
you time it okay so let's copy it so we
gonna time compare who is faster
oh actually in order to do that we need
like hundreds or thousands of nesting
because otherwise you'll see no
difference
hmm you know meaning that we have to
write a function that generates a
randomly nested array to you know lots
of nesting because that's that's when
you can see the difference of speed
because otherwise they are all just a
few microseconds so yeah so so how would
we do how yeah that's a problem you know
this is a problem of me not knowing
modern JavaScript workflow because if I
do I can simply github his repository
and I can see you know that he's got
benchmark you know I can just run his
stuff code fixtures you know yeah that's
what I have to learn you know because if
I know that I can simply do it quickly
but because I don't know that it's gonna
be probably take too much time you know
for me to doing a video on it okay so
what do you guys think so far so should
you should we you know wait so how do
you is there something we can do we want
to compare these two functions speed
what
anyway so yeah you really if you want to
do that you need a big nested way to do
that so let's see maybe he shows some of
that sweet request benchmarked and stuff
let's go back checked rjs
fixtures what the are these
fixtures
you know this truly annoys me you know
the JavaScript land you have files of
single line five lines truly annoys me
but you open a project you don't know
the project
oh he this one it's still too small I
think you know you open a project you
know it may have hundreds of files and
each one is like one line five lines so
it becomes a pain to look at them so
he's got a big nested array let's see
let's copy that so he's got one big
nested array that's knits
let's do that let's see okay
granite
what
oh yeah timing so yeah so this is the
code here should be commented out
Bennett true yeah okay so our code our
code are both correct
but we need to do timing and let's let's
try it okay let's try to compare the
timing so so this one so let's try this
first
so here is a function to try okay let's
try it in browser open a new directory I
mean a new tab start the JavaScript
console
type his function type my version then
let's do timing timing you need to okay
you need to put this inside actually it
needs a second argument and you need
okay that should be it copy it so we are
coding these 50 times one second
you know so it does not zero second I
want to get the microsecond so let's say
500 times zero second wait oh wait we
didn't do it correctly the argument
should be a a wait how is why is his
function not generating error when you
give it an integer you should create the
error
yes depth and breadth yes exactly that's
why we need to write a function that
generates a random nested array actually
we can do that anyway let's continue
with this let's see what is the timing
eleven seconds now are they they are
microseconds right oh wow they what I
forgot
nice okay nine eight eleven eight okay
now let's try my function copy that
let's try my function okay
my function is just gonna be 99 okay
copy that
my function is much slower oh my
god my function is thirty times slower
ten times what three times yeah three
times slower okay hi
I can I can improve it because I haven't
thought about you know I haven't really
tried to make it really fast but
algorithmically this is optimal as far
as I know I mean that's typically the
way I code but but I you know it's
possible to make it faster by let's see
if I can anyway in any way so I think
you know so yeah so his code is two
times faster than my for sure three
times
Oh April Kenai anyway so trying to post
the link does not seems to work okay so
live chat so okay so try the link again
so exhausted you are right that yours
has some cool features like specifying
number of levels though yeah
catalog dot catalog dot theta dot gov
has plenty of big data sets you know
yeah I cannot just use random Jason
because Jason will contain objects this
flattened array only works with erase
you you only need nested arrays no
objects so anyway that that's that's
that's that I think that's that okay
that's that okay so what what's the next
thing how shall we proceed to the next
Oh one hour and 12 minutes and maybe
that's it for today so guys comments
okay guys guys but where are you guys
comments so what's the next thing we
want to do so hold on a second this copy
that paste it here you know so we have
today's kind of thing then after the
video I probably gonna do some cleanup
and you know then I start to spend time
to look into why is my code
slower actually I can I can actually try
to do that you know I want to see why is
my code slower than his code so what I
am doing is you know a buddy but looking
at the code needs concentration you know
usually and it's gonna be boring for you
guys so N equals two if n is undefined
they make n equal to one okay so this is
error checking I can remove because
that's specifying the level you know I
think I can remove that
so if N equals 2 is n greater than 0
then of a protocol some call and and if
this is true son okay son oh that's
another error checking array array is
array wait is he well he's also doing
that anyway you know to look at the code
you can't I can I cannot just look at it
I have to think you know then I have to
look up documentation through a lot of
it
that's probably boring for you guys
computational speed stuff is fun too
though yeah it is yeah you know because
you can see here I'm using tail
recursion it returns you know recursive
call of the function and what is he
doing he is doing for array length
length egos array length and loop
okay he's using a loop then current
current item is array I so it goes
through each member
then then a course then it's also
recursive except the way he does it that
he applied recursion to I think each
member of the array so his thing is not
tail recursion yeah he seems not care
tail recursion you suck memory man yeah
well yeah he's things not tell recursion
you see he's doing a loop he is looking
at each element of the array then apply
the recursive you know it applies
recursion to each member of the of the
elements of the array and and and again
doing the same thing for each every
nested array so it's not tail recursion
but it's it's not parallel neither
because when you are doing a for loop
it's not parallel
so he is actually generating a new array
you see so if it's array if it's away he
because you know into it if it's not
array if the element is not array like
it's a number it's already a nest lessor
number then he pushed to the result so
IES is the result okay then he pushed
into the result and in in the end he
returned our yes yeah okay so that's how
he unravels the nesting he simply
eventually I mean he is creating a new
array just push item to it now the way I
do it is if n is greater than one then
you call a ripple drive some core so if
any of them is array you do that a
report I've conquered array
okay anyway so my approach is more
functional and functional and recursive
yeah yeah
so computational speed reminds me of an
old movie other people's money I don't
know what's that when we move movie
I gotta go already okay can I Freddie
okay I think that's it for today then so
one hour and twenty minutes and about
webpack we haven't finished you know
what's going on with the web pack thing
so if we go to so web pack you know we
have this almost four hundred three
hundred modules then oh yeah there's
more things I want to show you we're
back to actually when you actually use
webpack so you need to create you know
you need you need you know we haven't
get into how do you actually use webpack
like what what it does actually do you
need to create this JavaScript and HTML
files then you can test it I'm not sure
maybe that's it for today maybe we can
do it should we do it okay we can let's
say we're gonna shut down then but let's
try let me try to do this let's see how
long it takes you know into in five
minutes we shut down so web pack you
need you need a javascript file and so
let's create a javascript file okay so
hold on a second you need to create a
source directory and the here is a
JavaScript file save it as index dot
JSON server script file then you need to
create a distribute directory T is T now
this D is T directory is the output of
web pack okay so we create the directory
open it
create a new file and this file is gonna
be HTML so let me show you what this is
going to do so save it as index dot HTML
so here's a HTML file it's going to call
no - you see it requires low - get it
from the web No - the library which is a
bunch of little utilities of functional
programming utilities is almost exactly
the same as underscore as far as I know
like low - is the next version kind of
under school so low - you loaded and you
low JavaScript source code so in the
Java Script you know the JavaScript oh
it does is oh it does is that it it
creates a function components this
function named components and it just
called a component function and attach
it whatever is its output into the body
of HTML so it's gonna create a HTML tag
basically and attach to the web page and
but what does it do so you see it's
creating the type element then it's
using a low - joining function to
joining a string it's trivial you know
you can join your string by just plus
sign but however they are trying to
demonstrate you know the webpack thing
so they are calling the low - function
no - name space begin with an underscore
that's just the way they do it so
underscored are join join join then
hello we're back in our HTML so you
basically create a dive that says hello
way back then you attach it to the HTML
page that's the JavaScript so you have
this JavaScript then you have this HTML
page but
let me show you how that works okay so
hold on so web page okay so first of all
you need to move these up let me show
you split go up a directory move this to
the top okay so you can see HTML pages
here the HTML page the HTML page loads
the the dough - let's put it here
actually let's put it here so loads the
dough - then call a javascript the
JavaScript we open it you know like we
explained before he just created a dive
element so if we show this page in
browser it's just going to show hello
web pack so close that new paste link
enter so you see it says hello web pack
and we can change for example JavaScript
hello you okay so refresh you see that's
how it works
now remember it's loading the HTML is
loading the lodash from the web from
this you know this distributed you know
this this website but the purpose of web
pack the javascript bundle this bunch of
bundle of tools is that they you know
the problem with this you know the
script tag in HTML is that this
javascript file which is your project
have lots of dependencies and each one
of them you have to you know script
loaded that's a problem because you
don't have a mechanical way to control
libraries like in a typical programming
language you you know in colon in
JavaScript I mean in colon in python Pro
any any language you have libraries at
the beginning you say import you know
import something import something so so
you have a nice easy way to
know your dependencies and you can
control it programmatically you know
like what libraries you load but in
JavaScript it's a you don't have that
because JavaScript did not have
namespace so the way you load code
there's no library you low code is just
by coding you know just by using the
script tag so this is a problem once you
have several libraries you use it's a
problem sometimes one is to go before
the others it's a headache
that is why so people don't want this so
over the past 10 years 10-15 years
people started to create a system where
you simply load one single file like no
no such thing you logged one single
javascript file for this HTML in that
javascript file you should have all your
libraries in one file you know put
together because javascript did not have
namespace no package system so you you
know you need all the libraries you need
you put them into one file so that is
the purpose of bundlers you know these
bundle tools web pack is one of them you
know it does that and also the parcel is
one of them and that is why I'm looking
into how to do these things so now we
are going to demonstrate web pack so
once you have this so what we're gonna
do so let's look at the web pack
tutorial so they tell you so this is the
structure okay they tell you to let's
follow it
we can finish this in five five minutes
ten minutes just to show how web pack
works the basics so we go to the package
dot JSON we need to modify it it says ok
so it tells us to do that
so we don't want min and we add we say
it's private okay whatever
private I guess it means don't load
don't know don't upload myself to MPN
something like that
creating a bundle okay now we're gonna
change HTML structure we're gonna open
the district this distribution directory
and move our index file there okay move
our index file there that's right and
and in our JavaScript source code we're
gonna open it we're going to change
we're gonna say import underscore form
lo - okay so we are actually importing a
library this is by the way this import
statement is from Ahmed script 2015 so
Java Script 15 2015 they introduced a
library system so the JavaScript now
import lo - okay by this sly and
and in the HTML file we don't need we
don't need this line anymore because the
JavaScript isn't is doing the import now
okay
then also it tells us us to change this
line this Magnemite change this line to
men Dodgers okay
you see this this is what we were doing
before but now we just say men Dodgers
mean men Dodgers is the final output
file name of the web pack okay so we
just load this one single file okay so
okay and and now we need to install a
low - okay because we didn't install Oh
- before we need to install it now
yeah so let's do that
NPM install or - NPM install low - save
no - okay no - is not dev it's part of
your project you need it so it's safe
not safe death okay NPM install OH -
save okay do it Russian guys I don't
know I don't understand Russian type
English
yeah oh yeah
does anyone else understand Russian yet
yes we have the guy what's his name
green tag green tag is not here today
what MC weed what is he saying okay so
we we have installed low - now you can
see now let's look at the directory
let's go to nod modules yeah
so now such for low - okay so now he's
here
no it's he no it's here once again huh
what does good well it's uncle my that's
my roommate he's asking me for something
he's going out to work so we're gonna
install Oh - I mean we already installed
it so here is the low - tag - yeah it's
a problem anyway so so low - it's
actually the the final file is this one
you know it's this one No - but for for
some reason they split each function
into a individual file I don't know why
they do that because they have better
management with with the JavaScript -
was I guess anyway the DA - library is
just supposed to be this one 540 kilo
bytes this is the low - library
altogether 17,000 lines
that's too much anyway that's slow - and
they are still using they are still
using before yech Eggman script 2015 you
see they are used to using boss they
should have used yes 2015 instead but
anyway we installed low - let's go back
to the HTML file
so so we look at index so you see this
is the man okay so you see we comment
about the loading of low - and we just
have met means the fire we don't have
yet
webpack is going to generate it for us
okay
now the next step is to run web pack so
it's let's run it so we're gonna say MPX
web pack okay and let's see yeah so MPX
MPX means execute execute the following
command
now web pack is actually about is a
command an executable because if you
look at the directory not modules there
is a bin directory here and you open the
bin directory you can see web pack no
web pack is a is a it's a utility you
know it's a command line it's a command
line utility so you cannot run we are
going to run MPX
web pack I think that's it let's just do
it okay so MPX web pack what it will do
is that you will look at your source
directory it will find this javascript
file it will try to analyze it you will
see that it's importing lodash so it
will take that blow - file you know I
mean it will it sees that you are using
low - so you will generate the the the
final JavaScript with that into it so
let's run it
MPX web pack
so what is the Russian guy typing is
sorry but I got a drop out as well
okay thank you guys for watching Haitian
American
let's stop let's go to top shots so
maybe he stuffed one show I don't know
okay so it's done basically we are done
now so if we look at wait yeah if we
look at the district tree you see we got
a min dot J's we look at the index.html
we look at the main duck Dodgers you see
that is the that is the thing where PAC
generated its minified it combines the
entire lodash library with your
JavaScript it generates this
incomprehensible thing and let's go back
to load our file
you know loaded it's not there anymore
because remember we change the HTML path
so it's going to be D ist index there it
is you see still walks so that is the
purpose of lodash it combines all your
JavaScript into a minified version you
could have it not minified you know so
there are tons of web web pack options
so that's it for today how much the how
much is the clock will you live I'm in
California Eric I mean California time
437 indeed Pacific specific
Pacific Standard Time
okay so he's a troll we can ban him Luka
what are you using to load obliged
single line files quickly without lag I
remember you had that as a complainer of
Emacs you see this large single line you
can you cannot navigate that's I mean
this is not too long a lie you see when
I press the arrow down you can still see
the cursor moves so this is okay this is
not too big well you see I'm trying to
let's try page down no it's stuck okay
it doesn't yeah so so Emacs has this
problem anyway that's it for today so
what is this guy doing stop
around oh I kick you out you know okay
thank you guys for watching by the way
so do you guys see the super chat option
or something like that like I'm not sure
first we wrote what are you doing old
man then lodash safe no - oh
execute low - I don't know the word
execute that's what he's saying
okay see you guys obviously see you next
time
thanks thank you for watching bye Z
trunk crazy bye Alan I look hot by MC
red and bye everyone
closing down in one minute