good morning guys welcome to another
episode of our talk show today is
October 18th Friday 10 o clock a.m. San
Francisco time and I'm doing the tip
where there is a significant delay with
my videos okay
San Francisco time 10 o clock a.m.
Friday October 18th 2019 welcome to
south talk show good morning Bart
good morning League of noobs but there
is a issue with the link you see now I
am live chat you see I'm showing live
chat but I don't see your links so I
don't know what's the problem
okay today's topic Bart says talk about
netiquette okay let's talk about
netiquette I don't have a topic prepared
oh but before anything I want to mention
thanks to sin two mafias Henri net Cox
and for sponsoring this show and of
thanks for macro work macro work for
taking my video tutorials and I don't
know why YouTube blogs hit zonings
so yeah I don't know what I said so the
part says fire Bobby fire Bobby Kotick
the gym position it says it explains the
system very well by using a real live
example of what happens what system the
YouTube
see there is a significant delay on a
second I think there is a delay do you
see this is my mouth synched paste I
don't know why there is a delay CPU
memory cannot ask CPU oh yes
why is there delay
there is a delay because
it's synced okay oh wait it's not synced
it's synced again oh what's going on so
video capture oh I think I know why it's
not hold on a second I mean it fixes
remove that yes and new video capture
because I cropped that's that is why I
copped my head oh my god I need a new
more powerful professional computer now
it's better because okay now yeah now
it's now it's better is apparently when
your video is larger it sucks
CPU why is that because it doesn't make
sense to me because you know because
ultimately I'm streaming this my full
screen and so doesn't matter how much is
my video head here it shouldn't matter
well probably because if I cropped it if
I crop it here then the computer needs
to process it and show it on this screen
maybe that's it that is why cpu-bound I
don't know so good morning league of
noobs so but says this topic fire Bobby
Kotick I don't know who that is the Jean
causation I think I heard of that
channel so let's have a look and O's
okay his begin this video began by
swearing fire Bobby Kotick okay I don't
know who is that Jim sterling I don't
know who is that
Jim position I don't think I've seen him
people and he's talking about Bobby
Kotick I don't know who that is and
typically this is my normal way of
watching video like my saw this I play
it for one second you know ten seconds
then I I have to search I have to look
for who is this guy you know before I
watch the video and then I have to
search this guy Jim sterling eight
thousand eight hundred thousand
subscribers okay but is he about okay
now let's look at the Bobby Kotick quick
so Bobby Kotick so magnify magnify Bobby
Kotick boom 1963 five years older than
me so he is 56 is an American
businessman who serves a CEO of
Activision Blizzard oh okay that's why
he's on the news and he was the head of
several technology companies early in
his career he purchased Activision in
1990s okay Blizzard okay CEO okay on
February 16th 2012 he was elected an
outside director of the coca-cola
company okay so he's the head of
Blizzard and he is on the news because
of China China China China China China
China China Chinese China fire Bobby
Kotick
okay so he I assume from the outset he
is
American and he is white American you
see his home almost always okay so what
I assume you see I can I haven't watched
the video yet but what I'm thinking is
that he is for democracy American okay
and by that
that also means he's white American yeah
right he always raised ratio race war
this is critical this is fundamental of
human animals hold on a second so I
assume his opinion you know because the
blizzard what did pleaser do yeah the
Hong Kong situation you know the Hong
Kong situation divide and conquer
are you as your assumption about hundred
percent wrong second I haven't you know
I haven't made my conclusion yet I'm
just you know putting out my thought
flow so you know like it at this moment
I'm assuming he's white American and
looks like he is you know but hold your
horses okay I have to James sterling
okay anyway so so why is he talking
about that I assume I shut up shut shut
up [ __ ] okay shut up
the addictive cost of predatory video
something something
okay the [ __ ] position is a videogame
current affairs show video game gamers
by a person who says words you will
enjoy those words no trust me
no and thank God no for me no no no no
okay so Jean but I want to ask so what
game do you play what I mean
you are gamer right well I mean you are
younger people so I assume you played
some game so but do you play a lot games
like every day or and what games do you
play
he means mentions Japan once that's it
so as you assumption your thought flow
started with China and has nothing to do
with China no go down second I'm talking
I'm giving you my walks of walk thought
flow not well you know it's not it's
just it's thought flow means it's inside
of me you know a bit it's only because I
speak it so you hear it I haven't made
any judgment so bad says I haven't
played a lot I'm interested in making
games oh okay okay so what were you
talking about so this video so you want
my opinions on it it Oh is there
something you want to say okay so anyway
so so Bobby Kotick okay so he's a paid
oblique visa so I'm assuming this is
about Hong Kong situation because on the
news
Hong Kong is a you know gaming
competition or something there's a big
shot player training some kind of card
game or something some some game you
know cameras thing and he said he
mentioned Hong Kong yeah he's support
Hong Kong independence or something like
that you know democracy [ __ ] and and
it's over the news so so in China you
know China are censored it
well not you know China fired him oh
okay
but our toad please her to shut down
yeah
to kick him out you know something
that so that's that's why so over the
news so the basic issue is that
Americans many of them let's say half
Americans USA citizens they they want to
support Hong Kong because they because
it's democracy okay meanwhile most
Chinese people in China I would say ya
know 99% of Chinese people in China they
support China maybe that that's a
controversy so when I see the title of
fire Bobby Kotick and and he is the CEO
of Blizzard so that that is what I'm
thinking
that's this topic is about and if if we
judge by the title then maybe that is
his opinion you know he says we should
fire Bobby Kotick something like that I
don't know see that I have to watch the
video to see what he's saying so what is
your point about the video so far says I
showed you the video because you are
very confused about my opinion on a
current system and this video resembles
my opinion in the best clearest way okay
so what current system like what what
system are you talking about your
assumptions are still very wrong yeah
it's not my assumption that's it's not
the assumption it's just I thought flow
I haven't watched the video yet because
Activision fire yeah I don't know what
these so what what system the system the
system like the big brothers the
government so you are trying to tell me
your opinion about a system something
should we like watch it and talk about
it it's it's gonna yeah I don't think so
this is 18 18 minutes and I cannot
you know 8 18 minutes unless that's
going to be oh I want to thank these
people I did I oh I did yes oh thank
them for paper and stuff patreon
okay watch after stream okay so and Bart
says we're gonna talk about netiquette
anthropology okay netiquette
anthropology so that is the that article
you will find in if you go to my home
page and scroll down then you go to
hacker coat and scroll down and this is
the page of network could also apology
on a second so hotel click yes
netiquette anthropology tales of tech
giggles when a person sanity is at
balance when human passion is raging no
etiquette must get in the way sorry 2001
back in 1990s and 2000s netiquette is a
very popular term among tech kickers
because every time you use you know
because when you go online you know back
then internet is not like today
Wikipedia started around 2003 and hacker
news reddit started around 2004 or 2005
so they only begin you see reddit hacker
news which they they just started so
back then as so and before how can use
reddit and all that you have new scoops
you know you have a few online forums
Slashdot for example and the netiquette
is very popular because they are
thinking that you know when you join
your forum you're supposed to stay there
and read what's there things like that
before you open your mouth so in fact
there is a whole document 8 document
written about
to quit okay let's search for it okay
okay so so far says what's that video is
about I got six person watching okay I
don't have a topic today so what how are
you doing so we are going to look at
network what okay you cannot even find
it anymore because you know the erasure
of history by Google and all that so it
used to be for example in 1990 so 2000s
when you search netiquette you will get
into these several versions of
documentation about netiquette
netiquette means net etiquette means it
means as a person if you go online there
are certain rules adequate you should
follow for example you should never when
you join a forum like how can you is
already something you are not supposed
to join and start to talk right away
yeah okay well the netiquette is that
you should haven't you know join the
forum let's say programming language
Perl Python
or any other topics like sex sex
BDSM you know that's one of the popular
topic back then
BDSM which stand for poundage discipline
sadomasochism okay that's a sex thing
and today it becomes it becomes a
monster it becomes this huge monster
over you know you know especially the
American Americans take mixed in with
the social justice BDSM
back how to do it how to sign a contract
how to sell how to how to be your slave
okay
BDSM okay I'm kind of into okay so that
that is you know BDS range is one of the
big topic of the you know the the online
stuff back then so anyway you have the
concept of netiquette people say you
should when you join your forum you
should not you should not start to talk
right away you should
wait weed you know get the Saints get a
feel of what the culture of that forum
is about you know the rules and stuff
then after week then you can you know
ask your questions or things like that
and also one of the rule is that you
need to read the FAQ typically often
every forum have have a FAQ frequently
asked questions basically those are
compiled you know people go to a forum
ask questions about all the time for
example you go to P DSM you go to
programa forums people ask functional
programming language forums for example
comp comp dot land dot function
functional ok comp dot land art
functional you have lots of these forums
so you go to a thunk functional
programming group there is a FAQ
frequently asked questions because
people go there usually you have certain
questions like 20 to 30 questions people
ask all the time
for example Emacs how do you start to
learn eMac B's what is the best book for
Emacs Lisp you know some questions
people ask all the time so after a few
years the regulars you know another
jargon regulars means regulars means
people stay in that forum all the time
so they you know I mean people have been
there in this forum for ten years five
years so they sing all these questions
so they started to collect all the best
answers to that question
so in sex forum for example how do how
do you oh my god
okay that's programming forums you know
functional self functional programming
what are what what are the functional
programming languages for example that
is one of the FAQ so people have
collected the best answers there is also
C programming language forum comp dot
land dot C and comp that land dot C
prayers first okay so for example you
can go to C there are lots of technical
questions about C very common frequently
asked questions
so people have compiled
or the best answers in fact back then
this FAQ are equivalent to today's
Wikipedia it is basically the source
everyone goes to you have a question
about see you go to the see new scoops
forum to look for the FAQ because it's
got all the best answers over the years
compiled by people written by people
like you and me everyone else good
morning
Zizi qs v z z QT so you have faq you
have regulars you have network word and
you go through for example and and FAQ
is high quality extreme high quality ok
and also some of them many I think many
of them has been published as a book for
example the FAQ of C or was it
C++ has been published as a book
basically printed in a printed form so
let's see sorry
FAQ okay so actually I might have some
okay we need to look for FAQ network
words you network add some some example
of netiquette documents you don't find
it anymore you know so so for example
this network word Florida Atlantic
University what is netiquette simply put
it is a it is internet etiquette okay so
yeah so you see they this Florida
University Florida Atlantic University
they have a they have their own version
of FAQ now you see they are kind of out
of touch many of these academic websites
usually their web page is 10 or 20 years
old this is probably example because no
how do you talk about netiquette anymore
but you know you can see your example of
history they are talking about
netiquette for example they are telling
you know look at this
so you are looking at historical
documentation this is about 10 or 20
years ago
you see basic email guidelines mail on
the Internet is not secure never include
anything an email message that you would
not want printed in the newspaper email
is sent unencrypted and is is easily
read okay then it says be careful if you
send anything but plain text also known
as ASCII test text as email some
recipients may use email programs which
cannot open email messages composed in
HTML or they may not be able to open the
attached files that you try to send okay
so this is this is definitely in the
early 2000s 2003 and let's say so you
are looking at a historical document
document netiquette yeah so so I'm
saying netiquette is very popular every
you know every forum has you know
there's lots of netiquette so what what
okay that's an example of netiquette
netiquette and some of the jargons
regulars regulars okay FAQ things like
that okay so in fact let's see if I have
article about netiquette about FAQ no I
don't have I do not have an article
about FAQ but okay but so what are we
saying so yeah I'm going to show you the
let's see what are these Microsoft
hatred FAQ nasty mac os/x nasty Mac OS
extended attribute those with a sign
okay so meaning is per Python a day some
of these are my
new school posts that's 20 years ago so
what is its meaning these are kipo
Python today no that's that's Yahoo
group okay so
so okay so netiquette FAQ so what are we
trying to find we are trying to find
okay so let's go through FAQ okay now
there is this website that is internet
revenue service no not that
IRS this is the government US government
tax department they want you to pay so
we search for FAQ you don't find it
anymore because okay yeah so you see
history changes so you don't even find
the page you know the page doesn't show
up here anymore
so anyway there is a website archive
where FAQ archived so this website
internet FAQ archive let's look at it
yeah so this archive at least 15 years
ago around 2005
it's an archive all the fa Q's so you
have like I think over thousands of them
thousands of them and they you know so
FAQ as I said it's the best thing it's
like Wikipedia today but however this
particular website as far as I know they
become corrupted just like every every
website today so you go here I'm not
sure if you you know if they actually
hold the original FAQ anymore and last
time when we were doing a video last
week also we have seeing ads for example
if you turn on ads you see ads and you
see so it's corrupted you cannot trust
this website anymore
but anyway fifteen years ago at least
you know in 2005 I can say for sure this
website collects all the fa Q's original
FAQ some function of programming on C
and C++ computational geometry or the
best best quest you know all the most
frequently asked questions and as
computational geometry you know the
other day someone asked me how do you
find interesting algorithms so there in
that FAQ you have huge amount of info in
fact you know they are book they are
professional book quality so fa Q's
let's see if we can find user net FAQ
index yeah I I cannot trust this website
whatever you know what they were but if
you if you you you if you try you know
in within an hour you you will probably
find some examples of FAQ let's say
functional programming functional
programming FAQ I don't think you can
find it this yeah I mean it's hard to
find yeah today you just find all the
other websites talking about it you know
what I'm trying to find is original comp
dot land dot functional programming that
forums that new schools FAQ beginner's
guide to functional programming FAQ cut
lean programming language functional
programming yeah you take sometimes to
find it so FAQ is hugely popular around
1990s and up to say 2005 and some of
them became books like see I remember
this one C or C purpose I forgot which
ok so about fa Q's Bobby Kotick I don't
know who that is but let's copy this
video here so I can watch it later and
you guys can watch it later so close
that seven people okay so what are we
talking about FAQ ok we're talking about
netiquette anthropology so on this page
is my collection of many things written
posted to the net
from 1999 to about 2012 I stopped using
user net around 2011 or 2012 mm yeah
2011 is about right so I stopped using
using it so this is an index of most
articles I posted to the user net relate
that's related to network word or FAQ or
the the not the net culture okay and
it's filled with hatred you know that is
that is my life
okay let's read the comments watch after
stream I was wrong okay so there are
things in this word you didn't write are
there they are things in this world you
didn't write an article about yet yes
well of course actually a lot I hope
they are still good what do you mean you
mean the FAQ they are still good you
know but they are kind of outdated many
of yeah they are kind of outdated you
know because now it's 20 years for
example
computational geometry FAQ or the ffq
about c++ it's outdated
you know because zippers first has large
changes so so did computational geometry
so did BDSM you know the sex sex topic
you know in 20 years you know today if
you want to know yeah a lot of changes
and also the reason this FAQ don't show
up stop search because it's because you
have lots of more better information now
you know you go to you go to Wikipedia
for example you have no computational
geometry then 10,000 links to different
articles
so why stop good morning Freddie Freeman
why stop about what part of bar says the
size HTML name is very fitting oh yeah
so you mean my website oh you mean some
other side do you still play any video
what is video for true v but true V what
is video so what are we talking about
we're talking about FAQ but let me have
a drag of this PHP the essence of Marcia
wanna and it is V go in California
okay him in my face it's V go in your
face it's illegal is is illegal in
Germany but and and but which what city
are you in Germany
can you guys see the smoke you know when
you do the vape the fun thing the fun
part is the smoke that's well I like
that part but but I suppose some of them
they don't they try to not have any
smoke at all because they don't you know
you use these some people use this in
public they don't want anything to show
but at home you want the smoke so you
can it's fun to see and on YouTube they
are a lot these young people they have
competitions and they and it's going
crazy these days you know yes I'm
getting old
but the young people they have vapes all
colors you know green red blue yellow
and they can blow over sort of rings and
stuff very it's fun to watch you know
actually a lot of their debts let's go
look at some of them YouTube wave you
know these like competitions it's very
fun to watch they can blow all kind of
things wave show
okay these amazing vapor trick
compilation okay so you can watch some
of that 20 million views okay let's
watch this one 20 million views that's
boring
okay so you get you know you see what
that so have you do you guys see this
I mean of you young people are there is
this something like your friends to
making in college or in high school so
green deck says glorious chat in
glorious chat what glorious chat video
game so so why did I stop using user net
well because it becomes spam like not
like around and I talked about this last
week or so so if you search you go to
YouTube my channels search for sorry
search for Network what I think you'll
find it oh you just go to my mic Sontag
page okay so talk you know our talk page
then such of the let's go to Chris our
talk okay search for Network quote there
it is so actually what way is that what
is this one
no that's not it yeah sometimes I talked
about it 10 days ago or something
so anyway why did I stop because it
became all spam a few you know the real
users they they all left on new scoop
because you know the internet you have
raided you have a canoes you have you
have slack you have you know you have
slack you have discord you have old you
know thousand things you know you you
have Stack Overflow so people don't use
new scoop anymore so those people are
only the old people like 50 or more
person and they are fewer and fewer
because they got married they are busy
with their life they or they died so
nobody used you you know basically net
news group is dead in 2010 that's
probably the the good year to put it and
nobody use it so it's also
them 99% opposed his spam and in fact I
talked about it in one of these articles
here so netiquette anthropology tales of
tech geek owes a net ethology otros
confection you know they call me a troll
so I'm was a metro so one of these
articles let's see program death of
troll my memory of Eric nagging
that's Eric nagging is so-called the
most notorious tro one of okay actually
there are a lot but he's the most
notorious in lisp language forums come
land-lease eric nagging if you if you
call this view you know him you probably
heard of his stories so i was going to
say so why do i anyway so there's about
articles it's all all these articles
death of new scoops okay this one death
of new scoops i talked about this so i
wrote this in 2010 and I discuss why
it's dead
you know you can read in detail thanks I
see read it okay so they can blow all
kind of things okay oh the all the pot
heads in green fact okay I'm gonna be
let's see shall we shall I get stoned
today just for the show you know for for
a little bit color should i since we are
not talking about topics do you like any
video games yeah I love it but I don't
have money to play so I about that
yeah I don't I don't I have not really
play the video games except second life
I lived in Second Life for from 2007 to
2010 i living it like eight hours a day
you know in second life you know we I
can talk about second night
because second knife is its it is human
human animals community and women okay
you can talk about women because well
because second second life is a new
technology you know the virtual world
and every new technology is filled with
pong that that's how that's how Paul is
one of the major push of technological
advancement Paul so in second life and
today you okay let's not talk about sex
related stuff huh so Bart says how much
for your BDSM part from second life but
which one what which what you which
pager what
don't don't help don't post the link ok
don't post think about that what which
what party are you talking about well
eight hours yeah because basically the
whole day you know when basically
I wake up snow I I said about this I
don't really enjoy this mashup wanna
because it gets me it makes me it makes
you stupid that's that's it yeah
then you start to smile you know you
just smile and laugh it makes you stupid
and if I do a bit too much alright maybe
I should stop now because it-it's is I
can feel it now but if you if I take a
few more tracks then there I cannot you
know it's just gonna be sliding all the
time I can you know you cannot program
you cannot do math you cannot think you
cannot think it shut down your thinking
you know it plug plugs you're thinking
neurons it make it tells them to sleep
then I have to go to sleep after you
know it when doing that so what is the
difference between your peas and hippies
according to your free dictionary
according to you mean in my world well
well your peop and hippies yup he means
you know the basically white
white-collar young people who work who
working offices in cities like that's
what you call your piece so the best
example illustrating your piece is this
movie let me show you sorry
movie okay this is class favorite movies
movies screenshots okay open that
Logan's Run open that movie 300 and the
Battle of Thermopylae okay open that
intro to video codecs okay Emacs Shou
entranc a movie Tron okay and let's
search for sorry
fave fave with
movies best movies okay that's my best
best movies best social commentary
movies best codec best video codec for
screencast screencast on animation okay
well today you just gonna watch me get
stoned today that is today's topic oh
your piece yeah let's not forget let's
not get distracted we want to talk about
your piece okay but let me go through
these tabs movie 300 and the Battle of
thermo-pile okay okay let's not digress
remember we need to show your piece okay
remind me okay please there's a movie
about your visa like actually let's do
it right now
let's search for cute girls oh god I
need to buy this what is this Oh
[Laughter]
clothing or shoes shoes and clothing
Jesus
okay so movies sorry
[Music]
Fight Club
fake up so if you want to know what does
your piece mean you watch this movie
Fight Club
okay now Fight Club you have two
characters [ __ ] [ __ ] YouTube [ __ ]
YouTube okay [ __ ] Fight Club you have
this character okay is he you know you
have this character what's his name guys
what what is that character's name okay
but anyway he's you got you know this
guy you got two versions of the
character dun dun dun dun duh dun da dun
something guys type it you said I've the
narrator is no no not jack no not jack
the Turton yeah well god that's so I am
dizzy Tyler Durden that's right
if anyone who watched right who loves
fight curve we are not remember that's
because it Tyler Durden has become me no
because for example someone there's a
one website I forgot what what's the
website name but it's a American right
right wing website news website so it's
Zero Hedge okay Z let me show you Zero
Hedge okay it's question it's question
questionable website this is the website
Zero Hedge you can go to Wikipedia and
read about it that's the logo but let's
go to 0h so it's in you know it's very
anti social justice warrior website but
however the their content is not is kind
of twisted just like the social CNN New
York Times The Verge aj+
you know BuzzFeed they are those are
extreme social justice can American
extreme left websites on the other hand
this 0h is rather the extreme American
right website anti social justice so
their stories are often with you know
very twisted so but anyway so you go to
any one of these let's see let's see
something not controversial okay how
let's say this one lets you know let's
read it harry clinton pitches conspiracy
theory that toasty cabbage geostain our
russian assets
okay that's ends actually that's
somewhat true you see so you go to 0 h
it is this questionable website then you
see this writer this author is tyler
durden okay in fact i think every one of
the article is written by tyler durden
okay
panel says you must write a script to
don't show YouTube videos if they are
deleted yeah I know that that's that's
that's more walk you know I've been
doing this kind of work for 20 years you
check and also these days you call the
web like YouTube they have they don't
want you to quote things like that they
have the you know in general and also
okay okay that's another topic you know
also you know that the the question is
about dead links that links is a
ubiquitous thing happening on the
internet all over the face you know you
have 1 billion websites new websites
every day something like that and that
links accumulate you know you have you
have jjigae pet and billions of dead
links all over the place and it used to
be like 20 years ago 10 years ago in
1990s or mm the mentality about dead
links is that you always fix it there
will be
not supposed to be any dealings but that
doesn't work gradually we see base
because fixing dead links is is
impossible tremendous time consuming and
an auto and an automat the little use
task okay because because you keep
writing websites such as this news
website every day they put out what five
articles every day so in one year you
have 15,000 articles in one in each
article you have let's say five or ten
beings you know as time pass on after
two years three you have 1 billion dead
links you know you you know you you well
you can write a program to call them to
find if they are dead but then you need
to change your text you know and that
takes human to do that so basically
nobody fix that links anymore so dead
links or internally is a concept such
that the mentality of programmers
especially the dica the hacker types the
UNIX philosophy [ __ ] okay
there the mentality typically is that
you you you've you fix tech things
always you know this there should be no
dead links on on the net but gradually
over the years the mentality becomes
dead link is just part of the Internet
okay it's when when article gets old
links become dead you leave it be you
don't you don't go fix it okay that's a
mentality for me you know I'm always
kind of slow to adapt the new mentality
singing anything so I I keep maintaining
links you know no dead links throughout
my website until I still fix links you
know but yeah you know I don't I don't
I'm not aggressive in doing that anymore
these days because I myself have six
thousand articles you know each one
written by myself
oh my god you know you know you don't
know how much time you have to spend to
fix things
you know I everyday that's been you know
three hours well I like I mentioned
before two hours answering people's
questions on you know I read it on my
email on Twitter on you know Google+ on
every social network and answer
questions then that's two hours then
five hours you know maybe two hours
spent on trying to write new new
articles about programming JavaScript
tutorial : - things like that basically
you spend ting ting hours or 20 hours to
write one article but anyway then
another three hours you spend you know
like another two hours one hour
something like that every day you spend
on fixing old articles because as you
write like I said you know each website
you produce maybe you know one for me
maybe one or two articles but for them
you know maybe ten articles a day very
fat very soon you have tons of articles
tons of dead links so so for me every
day it becomes I have six articles out
there some technology I haven't used you
know because it's so so anechoic
accumulate I cannot go so every day I
have more in articles to reread you know
we read what I wrote for example even
let's say justjust let's say this page
this network word anthropology I'd
started to create this index page about
about ten years ago it's probably
already ten years old now but some of
these articles are back from 2000 year
2000 2001 but anyway and there are dead
things you know so for example so this
page many of these articles are I
haven't read I haven't read them for
more than all most of the media for ten
years or five you know so every day
bukey it's impossible to read we read
you know we checked about check you know
things like that so dead links so anyway
the point I'm trying to
communicate here is the concept the
transition of mentality towards dead
links okay that is kind of a thing I
want to tell you guys this is about
history you know the transition of
mentality towards dead links and so that
you know let me repeat today it's just
part of historical document you don't
you don't change it you don't fix it in
same thing with YouTube for example we
went into this YouTube talk and and two
days ago I went to Google's you know you
can win many things many questions over
these issues you can always look at what
other people do for example regarding
dead links you can for example then you
can go check Microsoft you know they are
a big company or Apple or Google they
are big companies so what do they do how
do they handle dead links you know you
can go research you know so is this is
research which is what I do and I've
been doing these kind of things about
that things for you know every few few
years so so yesterday or two days ago I
I went to one of my older article that
goes to youtube you know Google's let's
let's let's go to the okay so many
articles I digressed a lot and I forgot
to address your piece versus hippies
stance on Hong Kong I talked about that
in several times two or three times in
my past videos so just such go to my
channel search for Hong Kong that's one
thing at least there are two videos
about it I think then search for
democracy okay my you to go to my
YouTube channel search for democracy I
have two or three articles about that
you can see so yuppie yuppies and
hippies remind me ok so we can talk
about that but right now so I was
talking ok digression and digression and
the linked digression and Jesus we need
a hash table of digressions so what we
are talking about now yeah deadening
sand there is yeah so you go to yes you
go to I know where to go to you go to
hacker coat then you scroll down then
here are some essays I've written that
contains a embedded video of some famous
programmers talking ok so one of them is
for example the Facebook founder Mark
Zuckerberg speaks Chinese speaks Chinese
he went to China trying to peddle his
Facebook but he failed
Mark Zuckerberg he's a scumbag he's a
scum of humanity programmers okay this
at APL okay so actually there is a
Google search brain okay for example
this one search brain talk on China
Wikipedia search engines this is back in
2005 so such spring Google's
found one of Google's founder he has a
video in 2005 talking about these issues
and the the video is good okay you go
through my live website this is my local
website I don't have JavaScript on but
you go to this page my website you will
see that the video is got deleted
deleted Google erasing history but
however there's a link you see usually
when I write I try to make things
completely so this so the so there's a
link to Google blog you know more video
of Google is at this thing so okay so
let's just let's try to go to that link
okay so this link you see this thing
let's open in grave actually not open
you know over income okay open link
income so you go to Google's blog and
you can see how they deal with dead
videos or dead links you see video gun
Adobe Flash Player is plopped Adobe
Flash history we are looking at history
guys so this article is 2008 so another
video the video is not available because
it's no it has no video stream okay I
don't know where you know it's dead okay
some is available another one dead don't
be not available you see so you see
here's an example of how much how
time-consuming it is if you write blogs
over the years so you see then you have
to fix this for example if you wrote
this blog and now you realize okay Adobe
is dead you know browsers no longer
support or dopey what you gonna do with
this you know that's a question that's
you know that's a writer's question if
you are blog writers if you are you know
book author you have questions like this
you have to make a decision what you
gonna do with this are you going to go
in rewrite the whole thing without the
video or are you going to you know add a
blurb saying oh this video is dead
that's another option oh you're just
gonna leave it like that you know just
leave it like that you know leaving it
like that it's not actually a great
choice because if you just leave it like
that you know with the dead video then
what it means that this page is become a
historical page so people no longer go
to your page for whatever content it's
saying rather rather this page becomes a
historical document about that topic you
know it changed because because then
when people search your page this page
we are
show up it will your page will show up
only when people search the history of
something something that day you see so
in other words but nobody's search
history of something you know nobody so
in other words if you leave or you're
dead links and dead videos that means
pretty pretty much means your page is
dead okay nobody nobody reads it nobody
like maybe one one person a month one
person a year that's a situation so you
so for example me I have written 6,000
documents like you can say 3 thousands
of them 4,000 of them is dead nobody
nobody read it maybe maybe one two you
know 10 person in a year something like
that so you know it's impossible it's
tremendous it's it's basically it's dead
links you know you don't you don't fix
it anymore so anyway back to the topic
so I was saying when when you are right
doesn't matter what you do programming
right or any time you have a question
one solution is to always look at what
other people you know big experts do on
that issue so we got in dead links we
can go to google look at what Google do
Microsoft or Mozilla website you know
you look at them and basically if you
research you know if you do that the
conclusion is basically they don't fix
it did you know dead are just dead you
know once a document is written after a
month it's archived it's kind of like
that you don't fix things you might
rewrite the whole but you usually don't
so that's about technics and and this is
about Tyler Durden
okay let's copy this you know so after
today let's go back to my video Chris
our talk show index
santosh show after today I have to watch
my own videos and kind of walk through
these extremely time-consuming okay
Tyler Durden because I have to write
down what we talked about today okay
Tyler Durden crows Fight Club okay copy
that
fight clubs okay let's read the comments
let's see where we go Jack
yes one of the guy in that video so you
are right true V you are like one of the
guys called Jack the the which one is
Jack yeah basically that's the Tyler
Durden the inferior one the the well the
true when weight is it I think so I
forgot you must write a script okay good
evening good evening Vulcan oaken what
your position politics we I talked about
that in past videos and some Hong Kong
okay CSS course cause brush okay you
guys are new you know and watch some of
my old videos okay so you'll see where
are we doing what are we doing
so panels good morning so can we say
that dead links and strikes out
corrected text is part of some king of
netiquette
websites that are live in part of
history it's part of some king of
netiquette what do you mean
websites that are alive in a part of
history what is AC CSS scripts they are
framework No
wait but don't you have the offline
version can't you offer it download hey
men is it your Satoshi do we do we have
Charles here are you guys are you guys
coming from 4chan or some other Chan so
how long have we been talking today one
hour okay is it enough is it good enough
should we shut down that links we went
through so many sidetrack that I forgot
where is where where were we
so okay Fight Club Fight Club is a
fantastic movie okay we talk about
movies we now here is stop this okay
factor hats okay this article is about
the best video codec for screenshots or
lying animation
okay so Jesus you cannot escape her why
do I want to bandy max what are you
talking about bang keyboard okay I did a
video on that yesterday or the two days
ago there's you know this yeah we talked
about that a lot let's keep that today
well basically because modifier keys the
way you do then that's that's bad for
your hands okay so here is my correction
of my favorite movies best social
commentary movies now I highly recommend
Brazil it's a fantastic story if you
like 1984 kind of thing you
you'll love it so manki go okay so
Brazil okay just watch
check out Brazil fantastic
okay Brazil
check out that movie
you just wish okay so this best video
codec for screen cast online we didn't
talk about it but okay close cycle
screenshots space movies okay
you have several categories so let's go
to a sci-fi okay now back to Emacs show
Emacs and VI a movie Tron so in the
movie Tron actually you can see Emacs
this one this is Asia you see they are
showing this in a movie so you know
because one of the hacker guys is using
it and you can see this is Emacs screen
they are using kind of a glass touch
like giant huge tablet you know so you
have this virtual keyboard and the guy
is typing over there and you have
whatever whatever that is I don't know
and here you hear is Emacs and it is
easier you can see the word is out there
and Ayesha is like that you see this is
issue and you can see the word issue at
the bottom and in fact we can make it a
thing let's try it thing okay so let's
go to Emacs Emacs block go through
practical Emacs then near the bottom is
how do you create themes th e mg color
Curra source code okay not here but if
you go to Emacs in its setup then search
for thing there Li set color thing so
let's do a colored thing customized
thing okay then let's see okay so let's
do that
save theme settings let's see if it's
just one window the whole thing [ __ ] I
don't like themes [ __ ] because okay
there you go
and there here is my Isha again
let's do get let's magnify so you can
see actually yeah so you can see get
status move technology whoa Pasha Pasha
Python son talk show come to keyboard
come to a mouse get add shadow vlogger
get commit ooh oh oh technology whoo
then delete backup
okay CD to the previous day I forgot to
CD to the previous day git status ok git
add git commit to it and any wait I
don't want that ok sync to the sync to
my website do it do it
and now deletes backup great fantastic
this is a show so that is the movie
about wrong
Aisha okay so let's copy the link close
it back to Emacs close a show and back
to close my Emacs block back to my talk
show make the link here
show him browser so that's some of the
topics we talked about then let's go to
what is this
Sergey Brin Sergey Brin lectures so copy
that we talked about that paste it here
did we already know okay so close Sergey
Brin okay XR start command log mod so on
the left window you see all my Emacs
commands
okay and let's go back to Sergey Brin
close Santosh I'll refresh close and the
color theme okay copy that
back to Emacs paste it
this is how to setup color theme okay
close it netiquette anthropology copy it
did we pass it here netiquette
anthropology we did not okay paste it
here showing browser there we have it
closed Network what anthropology
actually that should keep open so
because we were still talking about that
but let's go to bless sci-fi movies okay
these are good movies okay this one is
like in particular Jupiter ascending
this is kind of artistic thing
then okay this is the history of the
movie 333 hundred you know the there's a
history of it you can study history
quick battle 2,000 years ago and also
English and Logan's Run
that's great movie science fiction okay
so what we are we done
I think I'm done I think okay I need to
I need a drink so let's read the
comments and drink and maybe that's it
drink I need to MI stoned I don't think
so maybe through the crystal clear
drinks
then apple juice today's juice is apple
juice
and let us read the comments and and
maybe that will be it now I got 16
people watching Amaya quiet check check
check check check check
the morning dizzy but ruvi having a
favorite currency you aren't quiet I'm
not quiet right I can talk you can hear
me you can hear me it's Chinese you can
hear me right video and stuff
and let's go back here you can hear me
right
you can kill me so let's see comments
okay comments address if you have a
question for me put my name to it so it
shows up orange how to subscribe
subscribe XO d max down ho my god what
what are you talking about where are you
from
virtru v virtru V where are you from
Freddie Freeman we are gonna say it
should be as it's one I'm developing in
what's your github username okay don't
worry no 4chan raid oh wait that's the
proper word yes
I was just messing around okay what is
your opinion on crypto currencies though
what is your opinion on a broad chain
technology I think it's great I
mentioned this a few times in my videos
I don't know much about it but I think
it's inevitability for human animals
it's a matter of not whether you'll be a
it's a matter of when so maybe in the
next 10 years or 20 years everyone
you'll be universal some sort of
cryptocurrency will be v currency in the
universe you know grow body I'm not sure
universally yet because we human animals
have not moved out of earth yet
now that Tesla guy Ellen musk
is leading us to it but we are not yet
we are not Hamas yet so but if one day
we are like in Star Trek or in the Star
Wars universe then we could say possibly
cryptocurrency will be Universal instead
instead of global you see his
interesting thing about linguistics
global versus universe a white global
global map means the pole
well and it means earth why global well
because global means all because that's
where we are that's just on this pole
but Universal is more about the universe
and we are not yet there
so any other questions any questions I
think that's it for oh yeah began
actually today the main topic we were
starting we were talking about
netiquette apology we have not began
talking about that yet or we did before
is just pre lewd to the context of
netiquette that is typically my case in
my talk shows before I talked for one
hour but I haven't even begin to talk
about the topic yet because there are
some very interesting things here
I will build a dam when there is a [ __ ]
flood for I am a collector of nature and
a lover of its treasure
I will use my savings to quench those
thirsty and lubricate those angry for I
have suffered and suffered the pain in
anguish
why can't you be normal
why can't you why can't you be normal
what do tech geek King morons want this
article is addressed to the UNIX
philosophy or philosophers you know UNIX
was free type of people or the Emacs
phonetics type of people so the title is
what do tech geeky morons want what do
they want what the vet what the [ __ ] do
they want they call me a troll sorry you
know I was I was known as a TRO fact you
know if in a mm so but to me I'm not a
true ok I understand I'm controversial
and I understand oftentimes it's
intentional ok [ __ ] you because because
you many of the you know the UNIX
philosophy or the [ __ ] heads they are
just spreading misinformation and truth
so they are [ __ ] so I go there I
tell them to [ __ ] off and I give my
reasons rationale my rationale reality
organized and complete and you know take
me hours to write them but but they
don't they ignore it they you attack me
you know they do a thing they call me a
troll I don't think but to me I'm not a
true ok I understand I'm a controversial
so what I'm doing is in modern society
in America in the democracy kind of
people way of thinking they what I'm
doing is called peaceful peaceful
none conformality
what is it called peaceful anyway so
that's you know so anyway this page is a
correction of my the articles I've
written publicly so what do you take
digging morons once so when I'd read you
know when I argue with them you know
it's usually heated right it's called a
flame war so I argue with them but you
know often it's okay it's like what are
they thinking like it's like you read
that what you know for example we are
arguing about some topic
you said something they say something
you say something they say something but
when I read their stuff you know they
reply I say what are you thinking what
are you talking about I'd you know for
example I just told you why you know
like do you agree or not agree if you do
not agree say something you know about
that what I just said like argue right
we argue but it appears to me you did
not read what I said and you just go on
about some other things you know that
often when you are in argument this is
the often the the feelings you again I
don't think it's just me I think you'll
get that in any kind of argument
political to political religion
especially or any argument with even
your friends or your family when you
know because when you are you know our
heated argument you are emotional you
are not you know really logical rational
you are not really paying the details of
what other people say like when you are
in a heated argument what other people
say immediately it triggers you are not
you know reading between the lines but
but simply the word he mentioned or the
way he is saying about something it
triggers you then you're gonna you know
fuller said you know if I [ __ ] fire
fuller Said's of missiles
the guy so it's back and forth you know
so anyway so so I was reading for
example I was reading what they are
saying and it's like what the [ __ ] are
you talking cop talking about so there
is this article why do take geeking
morons want like what what the [ __ ] do
they want what are they online for so hi
David okay who is this David guy now
this one is written in 2008 this one
happened in comp dot then calm Todd
Emacs or come dot you know okay
it this this piece is falsely to calm
down Emacs or
glue dot help dot E max Agnew dot eMac
start help okay it's posted to these two
new scoops so there is this guy David
okay David is a I didn't say his last
name I forgot what his last name but you
can but he is a Emacs developer okay GRU
Emacs developer David Cass Cass Cass
briefs something like that okay he's one
of the regular regular on the Emacs new
school I think you can still find I
don't remember I think you can still
find his post on the Emacs dev meaning
list like you can search you can search
for the Emacs that mailing list you'll
find it but I don't remember if I have
seen his posts anymore
you know people get old so some some of
them may passed away I don't know it's
it's sad to think about actually so
anyway he's a regular David
so I'm saying are you like trying to be
a dumbass or are you trying to be
divisive I can play a round of game with
you or two in this thread so far there
are two morons one is Pascal
congratulations Pascal
the other is you congrat okay so I did I
started to write so this is why people
call me a troll okay so you know I'm
fighting them I'm [ __ ] with him but
but but it's not their typical concept
of true okay so actually I've been
talking a lot I think that's it for
today so you know the true netiquette
anthropology one hour and 25 minutes
yeah that's a good time to stop
so the true V says you are in tropical
island for your information I live in
the Caribbean Caribbean I don't think so
Yeah right how Roy matey let me get a
hold of the mast okay guys that's it for
today
hi Freddie
so did I miss anything did I miss
anything
any anything else part I think that's it
so we're gonna shut down in one minute
Jupiter okay let's go back to Emacs you
know X things seen so where is it you
better just paste it I don't know well
we're going to close it
copy closed back to Emacs go here paste
copy cuz back here
dad dad dad that moving screenshots
close babe
close so Bart says don't forget the
video after stream okay bye guys thanks
for watching if you like my stuff if you
like my stuff go to my website sorry
not info then you have patreon and stuff
rockin dark theme finally good morning
Derrick directly is a watchlist look see
so we could do this together sometimes
by weibo bye guys