Hello guys. Hello guys. I'm alive.
Welcome to another episode of Sound Talk
Show.
Uh we are going to do EMAC Visp Emac
stuff. I'm going to install SFly Keys in
Windows Subsystem for Linux. Okay, we
installed Emacs the other day, two days
ago. Let's see. Control scroll. So
magnify the font so you can see
and uh we just going to go slowly. Okay.
So if you are here, if you are watching,
say hi. If you are not watching, don't
say hi. And uh this video
uh if you are busy man, you want better
tutorials, you can watch my other
tutorials about stuff like keys and
stuff. So this is just me coding. Okay.
So let's see. Uh check video check.
Video. Do I do do I check out? Video
check. Am I moving? Yes. Uh audio check.
Okay. So let's do Okay.
So Okay. So my Emacs, this is my Emacs.
And here is today's topic. We want to uh
actually I want to write a emac write
sentence case for all H2. That's u kind
of find replacement. You want to change
all header H2's
letter case to sentence case meaning
just capitalize the first
word in the sentence and the lower case
all the others. for example this um and
demo keyboard marker first save it then
write a uh emac this function okay so
okay so let's begin
wsl to begin it
so meanwhile let's check out okay so
this is my windows performance okay
okay so we can start emac Then we
uh where is the delete key? Oh god.
Which emacs? Okay. Now you want to So
this is um you see this Mnt that's
Windows disk. You want to uh
oh we didn't actually install it the
other day but so CD to home the now the
now the I believe they define it as
alias to LS. Uh
yeah. Well,
which the how how did they define it?
User bind. Okay, they got a user bind.
Uh which cat? Let's see what is this uh
user binder.
It's a binary file.
Jesus, I thought there is like an alias
to uh oops I'll exit.
Start again.
Go to um so I want to know what is the
in Unix. Okay. So, so DWZ. Okay. You got
some text here. Use a lip debug
something debug
shab
debug note gnu uh property note gnu
build ID node AI tag femy uh what the
[ __ ] is that? So man the let's see since
they have it then there must be a man
page there it is the list directory
contents
hello Kan Jung what keyboard is that
does it come with its own tents uh no
you have to buy the tent separately this
is um
this is called ultimate hacking keyboard
Okay, if you search kasali.info,
let me just show you for one minute.
Okay, kasali keyboard guide, you'll see
a thousand articles on keyboard. And
this is the one you are I'm using. I
have a review on YouTube UHK Ultimate
Hacking Keyboard 80. Okay, there's a
previous version. So, I got a talk show.
I got a video review on YouTube. I have
hundreds of reviews on keyboards in the
past five years. Okay. Ultimate hacking
keyboard 80. That's a keyboard. Okay.
Back to uh Emacs. So I want to so
so this so Unix got the command. I
didn't know this information about the
files. So
h
interesting because I thought it was
just
like an alias to LS- A or at least it
used to be. So I want to know uh forward
Ctrl F to page down Ctrl B to back now.
Okay. Does my page up down work? No,
because it's I have key marker it that
does switch browser tabs.
So this uh copyright 2023's free
software foundation.
Incredible. Can't believe the free
software foundation. They are very much
anti- Windows, anti-Microsoft. But
magically they created a duh copy of the
Windows command, you know, uh dove
function. Quite interesting. But but bec
because since about 2000 year 2020,
Richard Stman considered
Microsoft a great company because
Microsoft started to release all their
like.NET net o as open source. So
Richard Stman Strowman went to Microsoft
Office to give a lecture.
So you can also find
uh
Richard Stoman lots of articles on let
me find it quickly. Okay. So lots of
articles on Richard Storman. Uh you can
find them all here. Richard Strowman got
cancer 2023.
Yeah. So, so that's uh and the history
of Lisp Emac Symbolics by Daniel Wre
rebutt Richard Stolman's lie about
history of leispman stole Emacs. Okay,
that's from James Goslin the the guy who
started micro semicros systemystems who
created Java the language. James Gossen
who is also the first to create Emacs
and and Richard Stman originally just
took Jim Goslin's Emacs code originally.
So the Richard Stoman resigned from Free
Software Foundation 2019. That's when
the social justice warriors scum started
by this girl Salam Gi tried to remove
Richard Stoman you know because they
want you know they want trans and stuff
they you know lots of stuff and so he
got kicked out this power struggle and
all the you see all the it's quite
interesting history because the free
Sophia foundation the people many of
them are rotten True because you follow
the social justice way you you rise you
got money you know so many of them they
agree you know they they they seen the
song alone yeah rich so is bad you know
so that's the incidents the people
following power 2019
he got kicked out by uh free sophia
found foundation the foundation he began
in 1980s or 1970s and the guy who
created the basically open source.
Okay. And here 2019, Richard Stoman
standing in Microsoft
building invited by Microsoft because
Microsoft released you know like
embraced open source. So lots of you
know the entire net is open source and I
believe the Windows subsystem for Linux
is also open source. Right? Is it uh I
don't know but we have to check uh okay
let's check AI
Thanks mate. Thanks. Thank you. Yeah,
it's uh it's quite expensive though. So,
but on my website I have a lot
alternative choices about keyboard. I
mean auto hacking keyboard 80 is like
$400 to $500. Okay. But on my website
you can find a lot uh keyboard. you are
new here uh so you don't know but
talking about keyboard is one of the
main thing of my YouTube channel so I
have over 100 videos about all these
keyboards
uh so ultimate hacking here uh80 very
expensive $400 to $500 if you want the
stand and you know all all the other
things you have to buy the stand
separately okay
so anyway so here is okay. Uh, Grog,
here's a question I have. Um, the
question is
Oh. Oh, I forgot. What is What is the
question?
>> Yes, I'm listen.
>> That's all right. Take your time. I'm
right here when you remember.
>> Oh, yeah. The question is when did free
software foundation they they wrote the
the utility
the diir
program
around 1990 the free software
foundation's new project released Dio
utility as part of three new file utils
written by David McKenzie. He announced
the package in 1990 with early versions
like 2.1 coming out in 1991. It's
basically a version of ls with different
default formatting for DOSs windows
compatibility and it's been in gaming
ever since.
>> Well, I thought originally d is just an
alias to ls on some window on some Linux
systems.
Actually,
that's backwards. The dear command in
gear came first. It's a real program
that the FSF wrote. And it's not just an
alias. On many Linux distros, people
later made DR an alias, the ls with some
flags to make it behave like Windows,
but the original VM is its own
independent utility.
>> I see. Thank you.
>> You're welcome. Anything else on your
mind?
Okay, that's uh that's uh but why do
they have copyright 2023 here? That's
interesting. So this is very old. David
McKenzie.
Okay. Uh okay.
Written by Richard Stman. So this is
like in the 80s I believe.
Okay. So stop that.
So what we doing here? So, we want to
Yeah, we want to install stuff like
keys. Oh, yeah. First of all, go to my
home. Duh. Uh, Emacs. Okay, you need to
do this. Let's go to Emacs.
Oh, I have a Emacs.
Emacs created the Emacs init. Uh, the
Let's look what's there. cd. EMAC.
Duh.
Auto save. Oh. Uh, auto save. Oh, yeah.
Games. We played Tetris the other day.
Okay. CD back. CD to the Emacs because
Emacs is installed there.
And uh we can uh we can make install. I
believe make install.
Okay. That will put Emacs in the user
bin. So uh oh user be maker cannot
create directory user local share info
permission perm denied.
KPT says are you going to run an Xserver
for the WSL emac or just run a terminal?
I'm going to just run it ter in
terminal. I don't like the emac server.
You know a lot of people like it because
it's like more advanced like oh so Emacs
editor you got a server and client you
know you know the practical reason they
want that is so that Emacs starts faster
because the first time you start Emacs
it runs the Emacs server you know like
web server you know it runs a server
then next time you start Emacs it just
start a client it just connect to the
server so it's basically instantaneous
so people started to like the ser you
know the render emac server in client
this began the server feature Emacs as a
server started like 10 years ago or 15
years ago okay
wait what oh you're talking about
Xserver are you talking about the X11
because I'm talking about Emac server in
Emacs you have a EMAC server okay so
what do you talking about? I'm confused.
Are you talking about Emacs? Are you
talking about X11
anyway? So, so uh I'm not for Emacs. I'm
not running the Emacs server. I don't
like it.
Oh, you mean you mean X11? Well, X11
they um it runs in in GUI. You see,
maybe you don't know. Have you ever um
run WSL? because the WSL technology they
they they made the GUI part of it but
you I uh you know here start uh I'll
show you in a minute. Okay, let me first
for example let's just start Emacs. Uh
which Emacs?
Okay, you didn't I need the permission
to install it. [ __ ] So you need to do
sudo uh
uh sudo. So this key and this key s and
I need to hide my screen for a moment.
Excuse me and see what is this.
Okay. So that is the my keyboard and uh
Okay. Let's try it.
Okay, let's put it back.
Put back my screen. Put back my keyboard
video.
So,
so it's installing Emacs. Jesus. What?
What all the things it's moving to?
Oh, [ __ ] Maybe I shouldn't. Maybe
that's a mistake. just run it in my
home, you know. Don't put it in the user
logo.
Oh god.
Oh god. There's so many things.
And that's, you know, that's a mistake.
I cont contaminated
my Unix system by installing Emacs
because it puts user logo user share and
all a bunch of things.
Kan says uh CA says GUI just works on
WSL2. You don't need to configure X.
Exactly. That's what I meant.
It just works. So let me show you. We we
showed it yesterday. So now which Emacs
you see now Emacs in user local bing
that's a standard directory for like the
Unix convention.
Uh okay hold on a second. Uh wait is the
screen clear to you guys like can you
guys see do or do I need to magnify
further? Mega chigga.
Can you make it mega [ __ ] big? So now
Emacs. Okay. Here GUI version of Emacs.
You see outside of the terminal. You see
now control alt square to enlarge the
window for all buffers. Okay. Now, now
remember when you do live stream, you
need the font size to be like twice as
large, otherwise it's too small. Okay,
now stop.
Now enlarged the window. Oh god, this
god.
It's kind of slow. What? What?
Come on. You see there's a tiny
thing you cannot see.
Oh god.
What? Come on.
Drag.
Okay. Now scroll up. Okay. Now it's
still
You see it's super slow. If you want to
track the window larger for for reasons
I do not know. I don't know if it's
because I'm doing live stream or is it
because something else. So because WSL
so there you have it. Uh GUI oh you can
run a clock. Okay. So now we need to
type FG full ground. Oh wait no
we need to
pause the process. Hide it in the Wait.
Is it Ctrl Z? [ __ ] Unix.
Okay, there. There. The Emacs now is in
the background. Oh, wait. You paused it.
That's a mistake. You don't want to stop
it. Oh, Jesus. Um, foreground,
please. Emacs. But I want I want to be
able to run it, but hide it in the
terminal. By the way, I also learned
you can just start another terminal,
you see, and go to WSL.
Let's magnify so you can see.
Can you see? Yeah. Another terminal. So,
so now you can CD and do a top.
Oh, we are monitoring our pro processes
so advanced. Jesus, I'm a real man. I'm
a real man.
[ __ ] the C C++. [ __ ] it. Now I forgot
what's the command. So, uh, Linux, let's
go to the, uh, Unix tutorial on jobs.
You know, it's called jobs like 40 years
ago. I don't know how you zoomers know
about it. It's called job control. Okay.
Uh oh yeah. So foreground background.
What? So what is the uh key?
Ctrl C. Uh no control Z suspend. No.
Yeah, I forgot. I forgot what the [ __ ]
So, you know, we can just restart Emacs.
But if we restart Emacs, then I have to
like adjust the window size and font
size all over.
Uh where did it go? Here. Too many
windows now.
Okay. Now, control
uh C to cancel it. In insta
death.
Okay. In Unix, it's called kill.
So, so what are we doing? Oh, clock.
Okay. So, you want to know the GUI
there? X. What? X clock. Is it X clock?
The classic X11.
[ __ ] Okay. It's not even installed.
Don't they install it by default? Or
maybe not.
Okay. So,
Oh, yeah. Don't forget the our goal is
to install SFly keys, okay? Don't [ __ ]
around. So now, let me show you how to
start Emacs without Windows. That's a
dash NW. Okay. So now, oh god, now you
got this ugly.
What is this? Hold on a second. Okay,
there it is. Okay,
now I need
so control
X.
Wait, what? That's Windows. Ctrl X2.
Split the window. Okay. Now, Ctrl X.
Controll F.
Go to um
go to Emacs my home. Duh. Oh [ __ ] you
forgot completion. God, the playing new
Emacs is like Ctrl X K to kill.
Now Ctrl X controll F. Now you
metab backspace. Now
tap to complete. Now enter. Now that's
where I want to go. Now, Ctrl X O to
move the cursor to the other pen.
Let me show you the
obscurity, the idiocy of the Emacs
default key binding. Now, Ctrl X
controll F to open to open the
mntount
directory. Wait, did it uh I want to go
to mount. Okay, mount. Mount C. Okay,
mount. So, Ctrl X control
F then C slash then users. Okay. Tab no
work.
What?
Capital US.
Okay. Now, casad. Okay.
Enter. Now that is my homepage in my
home directory on Windows the Windows
new technology file system. Okay. Now
search for uh search for controlF.
EMAC. Oh, oops. I pressed something
wrong. Now this is DS store the Mac OS
[ __ ] file. They litter the ship file.
Now control
slash to undo. Now where is my slash?
I'm using vor keyboard. Okay. So this no
control g to cancel. Okay. Uh control
slash and this one. No. Control G to
cancel. Where is my slash? Maybe that
one. Can try it. That's right. Now kill
this file. Control X K. Are you sure?
Yes.
Now, uh, now you use the arrow key so
you don't control [ __ ] Just arrow.
Okay. Now go to my home Emacs.
Go to my, uh,
initate file. Oh god, now I remember
it's complicated.
my init file. You see, because in my
init file, it
loads this other file which is my real
innit file. You see, and then it loads
the other file. This one is which is my
real init file.
So, you see I got one two systems.
Let me explain. Okay, it's easier if I
just show you in the home in my uh
Windows setting. Okay. So, go to uh go
to the eax. Okay. Go to em eacd. That's
what I want. Yes. Okay. So, uh you got
init. There it is. In it. So, this init
has three parts. The first part is
local. Whatever your system, your
current machine, you know, it mean maybe
a Mac here or maybe on on another
country or running Windows or uh running
Linux. Okay. So, what is whatever direct
setting settings you see in this file is
for whatever your current machine. Okay.
Then it loads this file XAX. Okay. In
it. Now you open that file. That file is
the entire Kasa Emac system. Okay. So
this is generalized EMAC system for can
be used by you anyone. You have to pay
me. Okay. Nobody buys it. But you you
you send me a $100 donation and let me
know I send it to you. Okay. So this
emac system. So you got generalized farm
setup, generalized key setup and uh any
other miscellaneous and oak mod and okay
and then you gota
packages about 20 of them. No 30 oh
Jesus. Okay 30 about 40 of them the
system kasar emacs. Okay so close that
close that this is kasar emac
kasar emacs in it. So you can see close.
So that's this this one. Okay. Then you
uh begin
you start the fly keys you know. Then I
mean you set the keyboard layout. Okay.
It's already started I think.
Then you load this in it. Okay. This is
my personal in it. Okay. So you open
that. Go to the directory. So you can
see this directory is about 40 about 40
files. Okay, those starting with xx that
those are like 10 files. Okay, garbage
files. So 40 files. So basically this in
it set loads up a bunch of my things
that I personally use but is not
suitable for other people. So that's
like 40 40 uh eag files. Okay. So you
can see, let me summarize again. So go
to my EMAC init directory. So you got
the init file. There are two main parts.
One is the Kasar EMAC system in it. You
open that. That loads the Kasar Emacs
system including 40 packages. Okay. Then
you got the Casar personal in it which
is this one. 40 another 40 EMA this
files. Okay, then the rest you know the
rest you see here set frame font you
know that's just for this machine
whatever you know this machine is why
you need to be that like that because
for example console last 18 that's a
font font size
is specific to this machine because on
different monitors their resolution is
different so
size 18 is nice here but it's too small
there is too charge on another monitor
or system things like that. Okay. And
depending on whether you are on Linux,
Windows or whatever, you may not have
consolas. Consolas is a default
Microsoft monospace
font. Okay.
On the Mac, it's Menlo. On Linux, it's
it depends, but uh half of the time is
the deja vu mono. Okay. Uh okay. So
okay, we are not going anywhere. I'm
just like explaining this. Uh the
original goal was to install softly keys
to get softly keys in this
Windows subsystem because otherwise I
cannot use Emacs. I cannot do with a
control X control F [ __ ]
Does that make sense? Am I like good?
Oh, hello. Hello. Uh, hello mass. Hello
more mo.
Uh, ser is a demon. Okay, so what are we
types in volorac? Why not comarmac or
workman? Okay, that's another kind of
frequently
asked question and uh
you know you you got to check my website
you know because I have 1,000 articles
about that topic actually 100 you know
actually 50 about vorac
which one is better okay and I talked
about that live 10,000 times already
okay and again on the And uh you know
Vorak I I I don't like Vorac. I I mean I
don't like Karmac kind of like I don't
like that guy because that guy is
aggressive. He's the first guy who
dissed Vorac you know before the co
comarmac [ __ ]
before the comarmac [ __ ] the word is is
quoty which is very lousy then vorac
which is very uh you know efficient
design. Then came this Karmac guy. Okay,
he says he proclaims, "Oh, by by the
way, Cormarmac is actually not the best.
There are possible better ones." Okay,
let me show you my my my my name is
Comac. Okay, let me show you the
Comarmac way, which is actually better
than Vorac. Vorac is Oh, it's old. It's
before the computer era. I created
Comarmac. It's based on computer
statistics. Therefore, it's better.
Okay, this this we got this comarmac
guy. Okay, I don't think he's a bad
person. Let me mention that again in
case of misunderstanding. Okay, I don't
think he's a bad person. I don't think
he did anything wrong. However, I don't
like him because he pushed Koreac
aggressively. He started to get, you
know, the uh first the Linux. Hey Linux
people, can we include COMAC? Well,
first of all, he begin his website, you
know, massive website with forums so
people can chat, you know, very nice,
you know, FAQ. Why COMAC is better? Is
it better than Borak? Yes, because this
this this this is okay. He began his
website first. This is around 2006 or
so. Then he uh hey the Linux dev private
email you know c can we include comarmac
please because you know I believe it's
better look at the statistics you know
then he talked to the Mac oh that's
that's a difficult one he talked to the
apple guys okay can we can we possibly
include coac as a layout because I think
it's better
you know so very aggressive this guy but
Funny he failed in getting Windows the
Microsoft to include comarmac as one of
the uh layout he failed in that
but is is comarmac actually better
that's the real question is it actually
better than vorac I don't think so [ __ ]
the comarmac [ __ ] you know depending on
lots of things for example if you jump
around uh different languages if you
type Chinese ping, French or Japanese or
uh then comarmac is not better. Okay, if
you stick with English and type in just
English, yeah, com is argu arguably
better, you know, also especially if you
don't like switch hands, you like row,
you know, but if you you know use
different languages then or different
programming languages, it's not
necessarily better. Okay, but that you
know that but
uh he's successful salesman. He sold his
idea to you guys, you know, like
especially the younger guys, the zoomers
or the late Malaysians, they don't know.
They, "Oh, I heard there's a comac. It's
more efficient." Yeah, there's Warak. I
heard, but it's like 100 years old. Back
then, you don't have computers, so it's
stupid today. We have COMAC, which is
computer-based. It's better. [ __ ] the
CMAC. Okay, that's my story. Okay. I
don't think I think he's a
I don't think he did anything wrong. You
know, I you know, probably a good uh
good guy, but I don't like Karmac. Okay.
Because he dissed Vorak. He's the first
one. But he made but he, you know, he
made a contribution to humanity.
that is he introduced the idea that
there are better efficient layout I mean
I mean the vorak is not the best one
okay it's not like vorak is the best one
and period okay since comarmac there's
lots of lots of lots of
keyboard layout uh creators okay there
are tens of them and there's still there
are still so many people like doing the
layouts. Okay, it's like idiotic.
Okay, uh big digression as usual. Uh so
why don't we since I talked about this
so much, why don't I just show the
layout one more time? The 1,1
time about keyboard layout and my
articles. So you can just search on
kasadi.info.
Okay, you'll find it keyboard blog.
Okay, then you just go to you need the
big screen so you can see the side
panels but you cannot see the side
panels. So let me enlarge this and uh
then there is the side panels. So
So you go to the layout section. There
are 10,000 articles on this on this
keyboard section. Okay. So you go to
layout uh keyboard layout. So which is
uh here
u it yourself normal erggo.
Okay. Not erggo. Do it yourself. Not do
yourself. No more for no meanies. No
laptop. No keypads. Oh keypad. That's
good. But no fun history. Ugo history.
Key switch guide. Design of the keyboard
and key caps. All beautiful key caps and
the layout there. Okay. Then this
article ergonomic ergonomic keyboard
layouts. So you got a JavaScript
interactive diagram showing different
layouts. There is comarmac, there is
comarmac, there is workman, there is
mini mac and so on and in grammar and
canary and whole mac. Those are news.
Okay, those are new in the past like 10
years.
Be bo 15, Bo 15, home in grammar,
Canary.
There are lots of these uh layout
special nerds, you know, they are on
Reddit, very specialized nerds. They
learn all these layouts. Okay. And for
European language, you got Neo, you got
AdnW German, you got Beo French, you got
French asserti, you got PT Nivo for
Brazilian, then you got Juncan, that's
not ergonomic, uh that's for Russian,
and you got English, Spanish. You can
try for example Neo on English on SP
let's say quoty the most idiotic on
English on Spanish on Germany on French
on ping in Chinese on typing Russian
okay Russian doesn't work because the
letter alphabets are not Latin of course
uh so you got vorac you got uh yeah quot
v uh Quarti Vorac and Mutron
specialized with with a thumb e and
programmers war and and a lot okay and
uh there are about
uh maybe 50 maybe 30 more articles all
the details about this okay that's a
huge digression that's like 20 minutes
digression isn't
Why not just package install? Oh yeah,
that's good idea. That's good idea.
Okay, that's
actually I can do it easy without
package. So yeah. Okay. So, let's go
back. So, Ctrl X
K. Are you sure? Yes. [ __ ] Ctrl XO.
Control X1.
Now, Ctrl
X
F to create. Wait. No.
Oh, God.
Can we actually do it? Yeah. Okay. So,
wait. So go to find file uh s.emax.
Oh, you need to get um so that's in uh
so that's
get get my friend get then fly keys
fly
fly fly fly fly fly fly fly fly fly fly
fly there okay now control X2 to split
the window then then Jesus I for then
you need to get diet list of files. So
Jesus, what is the D? What is the um
control
X?
Okay, I don't remember what is the
I buffer. Okay, so now Okay, I forgot
what's the key. So meta X
I um buffer list. Okay. Oh yeah,
controll XP.
I remember wait
there it is.
So list buffers. So wait where are we
here is softly keys. Okay XO to switch
pen. Then you want to go to home
XAX home there. Then you just
uh
go. So you need to um
where do I put uh God? Okay. Control X
O. Now put the cursor here. Shift C.
Copy. You want to copy it to um
Okay.
Yeah. Copy it, please.
Crl XO
uh G to refresh. Now you got soft flag
keys. Now you got a unique you got to
create a unique file. Now um control
space to start selection
and uh then how do you do copy? Copy is
uh alt w I think. Please don't close.
Okay, got it. Now, Ctrl XF
find file. Okay, now we're going to
create a new file. Uh, init.
Okay. Now, paste is control Y. That's
correct. You missing L. So, you need to
load that. Okay. So, you need to say
load
emac lisp coding. Load. Okay. Reload
this. Shift that. Okay. Shift quote and
write paren. Fantastic.
And let's delete this. Make it one line.
Okay. Space. Now
error message. What? I don't care about
that. You know there's a magic going on.
L doc. You see it shows the
documentation for this load function
automatically. Anyway, now Ctrl S to
save. Wait, that's not save. Uh, Ctrl G
to cancel. Save is Ctrl XRL S.
Fantastic. Successful.
Now, key fly key is saved. And you can
just load it. Actually, you need to set
the key binding. Jesus.
Oh, God. Jesus. Because otherwise you
got factor of keys. So you got to copy
that. Okay. Go back here. Go back here.
Enter. Then paste. Can you do uh control
V?
Oh, actually that works. I don't know
why that works, but uh
it shouldn't work, right?
Ctrl + V for paste worked. But anyway,
so Ctrl X Controll
S to save it. Now, do we have the init
correct? Yes. Load that. Yes. Okay. Now,
we can start another Emacs. Uh let's
see. Back to the Windows
Subsystem for Linux.
And oh, oh, we are already in a
terminal. We occupied the terminal.
Uh, so now go you go here, you quit the
top, the [ __ ] stupid Linux top and
you start Emacs here.
Okay, so Emacs now I should have Safly
keys. Okay, hopefully
do it.
Do I have SFly keys now? You just have
to try. Okay.
Uh, no. Okay. Warning initial
initialization an error occurred while
loading. Oh Jesus
symbols function definition is void. Sly
key set layout. Oh that's right. Okay.
So close that.
Okay. Now go back here. Now you want to
move this to uh Ctrl A to go to the
beginning. Control space to begin
selection. Ctrl E to move to the end.
Control
uh cut. How do you cut?
Ctrl K. I think please make it. No.
Uh [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] Ex. Okay. Just
paste it here. Just No. Didn't work. Uh
Ctrl K. Ctrl K. Okay. Now, Ctrl Y to
paste. Yes. Okay, now Ctrl X Controll
Save.
Now go back here. Now start emacs. Do I
have softly keys?
Warning initial an error occur while
loading. No search file or directory
softly keys.
Shut up.
What do you mean? No. No. No. Uh what?
What do you mean file not found? is
right here.
God.
Oh, control W. Yeah, control W is for
what? Um, you mean? O W, I think for
copy. Um, so what is this? Uh,
load.
So, I don't know. Load file. Okay.
That way
it should work. I don't know why it's
not saved. Okay, let me do this faster.
Okay. Arrow
home. No such file directory.
What
the file is right here. So,
oh god.
diet.
Okay,
the file is right here. Uh
home exit.
Okay, refresh.
Yes.
So the init file is there and this is
there. Why is it not loading? Error
occur. No such file or directory
homely
keys. Oh.
So it is loading. Wait, something is
wrong.
Uh what?
You need the full path. [ __ ] [ __ ]
Yeah. [ __ ] [ __ ]
Okay. So, God, I don't need all the
default Emacs is such a pain.
Uh,
okay. How do you delete that? That that
that. Okay. Cancel. Okay. Now go here.
Paste.
Now, Ctrl X Control S. Now try again.
Do it. do it.
Okay, now it's better. But warning,
missing lexical binding cookie
inac.
You can add one with elisp enable
lexical binding
missing lexical binding cookie. Ah, shut
the [ __ ] up now. Sh
cookie
missing lexical binding cookie. So they
want no they want to enforce you to have
lexical binding there. Not that. Oh god.
What
stupid Linux. You know when you press
control Z it
[ __ ] you up. You want this cookie. Okay.
Can't you just paste it? Ctrl V. It
works. I don't know why. Uh, so let's
just use it. Okay, now you got the you
now you got the lexical binding cookie
you wanted. Ctrl X control S. Now start
ex again. Do it.
Perfect.
Perfect. No arrow. Can you believe it?
Now the font is too small. [ __ ] is
too [ __ ] too small.
Okay, how do how do you set default
font? Okay, so you know let's um of
course I have a tutorial for that.
Uh but let's not read my tutorial. Let's
just I show let's do it quickly. Okay,
you go to the options
options.
Then you go to the uh first of all,
let's just enlarge it manually. Okay.
Okay.
Oh god.
Okay. Now you go to the options, click
mouse operation. Then you go to um
you see the font there is still small
tiny use system font. Set default font
there. Click
monospace regular font size. Oh, they
got nice graphical system 18. Okay.
Select.
Oh, okay. Now go click option again.
Save options. Okay, that's how you do it
for you Emacs newbies.
Now close this and uh also exit. Well,
let's not exit that. In case there's
some error, you can, you know, go back
to the Emacs and edit here. So, you see,
but now I don't I think it'll be
perfect. Now, start Emacs. Perfect.
Can you guys see the our effort is
working now? Close this. Now, Ctrl XTRL
C to quit Emacs. Now, we you see now we
are back home. Now, Emacs is done. You
can start perfectly. And do I have
softly keys? Wait,
what?
Uh T, wait.
Okay, I think I do, but the key binding
is incorrect.
What?
U is undefined. Wait, something is
wrong. F is undefined. What?
Let's see a new buffer. Okay.
Can you actually type? Oh, actually keys
is not installed.
What?
I don't know.
Okay. I don't know what is the
Okay, the font is not large enough.
Okay, so you need to Okay, the default
font on Linux is deja vu sense mono.
Okay, now the font is not large enough.
What is this?
Oh god, they don't even say uh
set default font. Can you say that
select?
Does that work?
But uh
Oh, you didn't start softly keys. So,
you need to start it. Okay.
Sly.
I think so. Right.
But
yeah, so you need to start it, of
course.
Paste. Wait. Ctrl V to paste. Oh, Ctrl +
V is so good.
Uh, Ctrl K to kill that. Uh, say Q. Use
meta keys. True. Uh, okay. So, well,
okay. Ctrl X Ctrl S to save it. Go back
here. Start emacs. Another instance.
Beautiful. Okay. Okay, the phone is
still too small, but we can now fly
keys. They are fantastic and beautiful.
Can you see how how efficient I am
operating on this [ __ ]
Oh, even that works. Fantastic. Okay,
quit.
Buffer is read only. Wait, quick quick.
What? Oh, you need to Okay. Yeah, that's
right. So, this is good. Now close it.
We don't need it. Now start Emacs again.
Now I can do efficient operation. Okay.
Press. Press. Wait. What? Press press.
Okay. Now jump to um what?
Buffer is read only. Yeah. So what?
Emacs. Oh yeah. So Oh yeah. Habit. I
need to change some keys. So the font is
still too small for some reason.
But so maybe this option is not working.
Okay.
Why is this uh option not working?
Okay. I don't know. So now what? Close
that. Close that.
Critical G gtk attribution something.
Okay. So what the font is still too
small for it's good for me but it's too
small for live stream low lexical
binding cookie. Yeah. Load xx. Okay. So
so far so good. I think nobody's
watching. It's too boring now. But uh we
need to fix the phone problem. Okay.
Let's persist. Persistence is the key to
the universe. Okay. uh go to Kasali
homepage and what we want to do Emacs of
course we need to go to the Emacs
section kasali
that's my name info okay go to Emacs
we need to bit dto on Emacs so the first
thing you want to do is usually change
font size but how do you do that okay
set font so you see on Windows this is
what you see but on Linux you are seeing
society different
you know why is it uh what the you know
so
so but they got uh they got use system
font what does it mean
better not
so okay change font size globally okay
change font size globally by command
okay Change font size current buffer by
command and change font size current
buffer by mouse. Okay, that's not what I
want. This is for current version. I
want a perm version. So you go down here
uh set default font there.
Okay. So all you have to do is put this
in your init and magic happens. Okay. We
tried this first route. It's not seems
work to work on and so but okay copy. Oh
god. Then you need to find out what
fonts are available and stuff. Jesus.
Copy. Okay.
Oh Jesus. Lots of lots of things to do
in either way. So what what is Oh god.
So um
pac.
Okay. So you go to init you paste uh not
that Ctrl V to paste. No. So go here
copy that and
Ctrl V to paste. Yeah. Okay. Now you
need to check if Cascadia Mono is
available. Check.
Wait. Uh wait. How do you do that?
remember that. What?
Hey, this code
there is a mistake. There's a mistake.
Or did I delete it? Yes, I deleted.
Undo.
Uh, wait. and do. Oh yeah. Okay. So now
eval. So that's neo. That means this
line is neo. So now eval this font is
also not there. Now menlo is obviously
not there. So delete it. Now this line
member deja vu eval.
Oh, it's also neo. What the [ __ ]
Let's see. Let's just uh manually
enlarge. Okay. So you guys can see.
Okay. What are we doing? Okay. Now first
so so this Neil uh Okay. Maybe it's
because you put the size. Oh. Okay. So
you cannot have the size Jesus.
So this this is wrong. This is
misleading information. Jesus s you you
got the wrong information on your
website. How how can you
do a screenshot so I'll remember to fix
it.
Okay. Now back here. So that font family
is good. So you want just um
set frame font deja vu. Just do the [ __ ]
it.
Okay.
Okay. So, I don't have this mod neither.
So, what
uh
yeah, but how do you set size though?
Can you um now what what is the current
font? So, you do control H. Uh wait,
sounds like key. space HC which is
describe char. Okay. So let's uh you
need to describe char. Let's see what is
the current font used.
Okay. Are you guys still with me? Are we
fixing Emacs? We we are running Emacs on
Windows
subsystem for Linux. Okay. And I'm we
just installed safely keys on it and we
are I am playing with it. Okay. So right
now this is a way to find out what is
the current font of a particular
character you are looking at. What is
the font use that for that character
this command is describe char. It will
tell you. Okay. So it says it says
display by this font deja vu pf d
something ftcr hb some that's some unix
thing uh Linux thing deja vu sense mono
regular normal uh 37 okay
close that
uh can you do so if I uh wait delete run
it that works now can you actually add
the size here. Let's say 20.
Run it. Oh, you can. Now, let's try this
command. Press press then scroll mouse
to No, press uh wait. Press press. Wait.
Okay.
Let's just say 30. Okay. Now, run it.
Fantastic. It's working. So this is
working. Okay. Now you just remove the
white lines and remove the the the messy
autogenerated code. You see we don't
need this. Delete. Delete.
Now that's perfect.
Ctrl X. Uh well now we have soft flag
keys. So we just space saved
close and uh
close quit and start Emacs again.
Fantastic. Welcome to new Emacs. Oh my
god. Now the font is all correct.
I don't have to enlarge but
but then
but then I need to enlarge the window
still.
Oh god, now it's actually too big.
Oh god. And also
Oh, also the screen got the glue image
is gone for some reason. Got you need to
work on this. Yeah. So, okay. So,
exo. Okay. So
init. So that's the init. Let's not do
that. Let's do the let's try this
this auto way again. Set default font.
Okay.
Deja vu sans. No. Why do they have this
[ __ ] different [ __ ]
What book?
I just want deja vu science mono normal.
Okay.
What
When did they introduce the book? [ __ ]
What the [ __ ] is the book?
I can't even pick a font correctly.
Oh Jesus.
Let's uh let's let's waste time and just
ask AI. Okay.
What? What is better? What do you mean?
What is better?
Okay, I think that's it for today. Okay.
So,
hello Gork.
I'm seeing the font deja vu sans mono
book. What is the book for?
Book is just deja vu's name for the
regular normal weight of the font.
Instead of calling it regular, they use
book for the standard style. So deja vu
s mono book is the everyday version you
normally see, not a special or lighter
variant.
>> When did they start to do that? I don't
remember. They have the the name book in
their name.
Deja vu started using book right from
the beginning. They launched the project
in 2004 based on bitstream vera. The
original vera called its regular weight
Roman but deja vu switched it to book
with a normal style across their
families including sen.
>> I don't think so. I I think the deja vu
found name never had the word book in
it. Can you double check?
You're right. I double checked. The deja
vu project has used book for the regular
weight since it started in 2004. It was
a deliberate change from bitstream which
called it normal style Roman. So the
full name deja vu sans mono book has
been that way from the very first
versions.
I don't think so. I don't think so
because I have downloaded deja vu font
and I I don't remember seeing the word
book in it.
And we can verify. Can we? Yeah, sure.
Uh
deja vu and they used to have a website
but the domain name is gun.
They used to have a dedicated website
about like 15 years ago. This is around
2008.
Deja vu uh Wikipedia. No, I want the
font. Okay. So, let's say deja vu.
Uh
fonts. Got I got so many windows now.
Which window is it?
So, deja vu. Okay. Deja vu deja vu.
Wait, what? DJA. Okay.
DJ Vu
font.
Okay. So, yeah. Now, that's GitHub.
Now, they used to have have their own
domain, but it's gone it's gone many
years ago. So, now let's see. How do I
know? because I blog about them, you
know, like when you have a blog, you you
you blogged for 30 years. Then you have
a record like when you look at your
blog, my blog, I have like 12,000
articles.
So, so sometimes you can see dead links,
you know, dead links and you can see
what people were thinking 10 years ago
or 20 years ago.
But anyway, Déja vu. So, deja vu. So you
see deja vu font did did they did they
when did they [ __ ] added the name
book into the font name B O K search for
it
book italic okay the 10 styles okay so
book uh book
okay so book is
a reference to the regular but wait so I
book probably never appeared in the font
name font file name itself.
However, book is used to refer to mean
regular. But why don't but
is it just usually it's just called
regular? Why is it called book or is
this specific to deja vu or is this
general
scheme for calling regular found book?
That's my question. I want to know
because I that's how I work. I always
know all the details.
So this is uh this is about when when we
are trying to do the Emacs uh setting up
the font.
But anyway in practice you can ignore
it. But the key important thing is about
the font size. Why is the font size not
set?
Okay.
Let's start uh Emacs again. Now this
start from here. Did it set font size?
I'm not sure what the
Oh, you didn't save the file. Okay,
wait. Save.
Oh, wait. So,
close that options menu set default font
deja vu. Let's make it
okay 24. Okay. Select then idiotic
Emacs. You need to go here again then
say save options because Emacs is old.
Okay. So you can see it added this list
code and here is the hey height 241.
Let's suppose that's okay. Now you can
try it again over here. Start emac run
it. Fantastic. Okay, that's that's fine.
But now it's you see it's humongous. Now
you need to
uh set the initial frame size. Uh too
much to do. Okay.
Okay. I think that's it. So Mandela
effect was always book.
Oh, really?
So the question is it better is WSL max
better that is what I intend to find out
that's why I'm installing the softly
keys and everything
you see I'm not focused because you see
for me to actually get things going in
you know the in the WSL emac to to get
all my uh in files
Uh, usually I just work on it. Uh, but
because I'm doing live streams, so I
talk and talk about drama and stuff. So
that never get things done. So
So all the while we are not
all the while uh what do I have? I just
All the while we just have softly keys
and there's a lot setup to do. Okay.
Yeah. So, but
yeah. So, we only just got stuff like
this. You you need to set font. You need
to set You need to set a lot of things.
Um
Well, can we do it? Yeah. Should we do
it? Yes.
Okay. So, now
But how you want to do it? Because
you see because over here on my windows
system
you got you know I got this
somewhat complicated you know I'm
loading two sets of in files
and these are on my Windows NT file
system. Okay. So
over here you need to
Oh, I know what
just load this file. Okay, so let me try
think about this. Okay, just load just
load my Windows init file
then you'll figure out everything else.
Does that work?
I don't think so. Okay, it may not.
Okay. So, you need a backup of that. Oh
god.
Uh, normally I can make a back. Oh, can
I still do? Oh, fantastic. I can make a
backup just by pressing a few keys. This
is part of safely keys because otherwise
then you need to split window then
capital C for copy then type a new name
find the directory you know. But now I
can just press a key. You see press I
got a new fresh backup. Okay. So now
let's try this. Okay. So instead of not
doing that let's just uh now with softly
keys things are so much so much easier.
Okay. And this needs to be on Windows
mount mount. Now on Micros on the the
way Mnt okay mntc can you like complete
mnt
uh what
>> yes C is a directory but why can't you
go into it?
>> I know it's a directory but why can't
you go into it? What the [ __ ] is this
problem? Is it because
close? Okay, let's try again.
Mnt. Okay. Capital
User.
Go there.
Why is it not open?
Oh god. Flame fire. What? I thought uh
why can't I open mntc
users
is a directory? Yes, of course it's a
directory. I want to open it.
What?
Okay. There is something is wrong.
It's not letting me
Okay. [ __ ]
Okay. So, what is going on? Permission
denied. Hila system.
Permission denied. Uh, what? I don't
know what is going on actually.
Emacs.
So,
this is this.
Okay. Yeah. So, something is going on
with that Emacs. I don't know. So, you
go to zot.ac.
So this is my Windows disk. Okay. So
copy
copy the file path. Okay. Now open
now open the home
and open that. Paste the file path and
load that. Make it the list. I mean make
it the string load file. I'll put that
there. Delete that. That. Okay.
Now don't do that. Don't do that. Wait.
Don't do that. And uh this part
you can also comment out. Okay.
And uh so for this let's say
24.
Okay. Comment out. And that's it. Okay.
Now uh so actually let's delete that.
Okay. Now
save it. Okay. This just loads my
windows in a file. You see
we work. Okay. Let's see. Now this one
close it.
This one got [ __ ] up for some reason.
Now we can leave it open to sturdy
later.
Are you guys still watching? Is it like
interesting? Not interesting. Okay.
So, back here. So, well, okay. So,
yeah. Got you know the on Linux you got
this problem. You need to like um Wait,
let's just close it.
I don't know what I did there.
Okay. So, you see on Linux you got a
problem. You have to like
append that. Is that
kind of annoying
warning initialization
problem. Okay, it cannot read
phone spec. Oh, because consola doesn't
exist.
Okay,
you see because consolers doesn't exist.
So you this is the problem.
Okay. Now, can you do it again?
Do it.
Uh, another problem because cannot open
load file. No lo no such file. Get saw
emacs. Okay.
Well, it cannot load the file because
I'm using
uh because
uh that's right because on here
WSL
it thinks this home directory is the
Linux home directory but over here it's
referring to the Windows
disk home directory.
So this home directory is um incorrect
you see. So the problem is the Linux
you see the home directory here
is not the Windows disk home directory.
So that is why it doesn't work.
So in order to make it work you have to
so yeah you actually you have to think
about this how you want to do this.
So you see so what am I doing? I want to
install basically I want to do some a
lot of coding and experiment experiment
of running Emacs in Windows subsystem
for Linux
because it could be faster I've heard.
Uh but there are a few issues because
all my files are on my Windows disk and
when you run Linux on Windows
in WSL
they don't
read Windows files directly. I mean
there's complications. So
for fast file access, you need to copy
your files from Windows
NTFS file system to this to the WSL file
system. Okay, which is kind of a fake
file system
anyway. So you need to
copy the files over. So that means I
need to you know I have like few thou
you know tens of thousand files that
work on.
So if I just access them
via the mount the window disc mount that
would not work
well because first of all it makes it
much slower. So you don't want that. you
lose the point of running Emacs in WSL.
So you do want to copy over some you
know 100,000 files if you want to work
on WSL.
Okay. So before we decide what we want
to do about that, the first thing we can
do is to just test run some, you know,
play with Emacs in WSL to see just if it
works fine and which is what we did.
However,
to really experiment Emacs on WSL, I
need all my init files, you know, or
most of it. So, we installed Softfly
Keys, but there's, you know, there's a
lot there's a lot that allows me to like
there's a lot, you know, all my packages
like 20 packages and other 30 files.
So, I need to install them. And we tried
to do that by simply run running the
load, you know, the Microsoft Windows
disk init file. But you got a problem.
You can't do that because my init file
involves other
init files
which refers to the home. But the home
in WSL is different from the home on
Windows machine home. So they they're
going to say file not found. It says
file not found because you need to you
see you need to copy this emac skit. You
need I need to copy my entire Windows
skit and my homed to the Linux homed.
You see the the WSL homed
if I want to do that way. So what are
the options? I don't know. So anyway,
I'm just playing with it and nobody's
watching I think. So let's have a look.
Um
seven. Okay.
So it's kind of okay. So yeah. So what
so what what is the plan? I don't know.
So actually I need to think about it. So
we did try we did the experiment on lots
of these. Okay. Deja font.
Uh
yeah keys works perfect. Fantastic. And
truly wait undo. Oh wait undo. Oh yeah.
Key mistake, key h key habit.
So yeah. So you need to um
so it's more involved than I thought. So
my system
seems
too complex.
You see it's loading two innit files.
One is the emac system. The other one is
my personal init.
Uh so even if you do I mean it's still
complex. So,
so what if you just load
Oh, yeah. So, you can Yeah, you can
change. You can No, no, you cannot
change. God,
so you can load. Yeah, we have to edit
initate files then.
So you see you need to
open that. Oh it doesn't open because of
again because of the home mess up that's
Windows home
close.
So, open it. Copy or close. Why don't we
just uh try to do something like this?
Okay. Now, we just paste it the whole
thing. Close.
Uh
this is the initial frame.
Okay. Let's see 90 and 40. So, it's not
too big. Okay.
So, and uh that's the that's the initial
font for this system. So we discovered
before
how to what font we have there. So we
want that one. Okay. Let's say 22. Not
too big. Okay. So for this file. So save
it. Okay. So that's for the font for
this WSL emac. Then init uh uh make the
initial frame position at top the
screen. No, we don't care. Okay. Width
and height. Okay. Let that be that
uh load
then just use condition. You can set
load path instead of loading files with
home path. Oh, that's right. Well, yeah.
Yeah, you are right. Well, there there's
there was a reason I'm using you know
load full path because
you see because you see you know each of
these init set they do use this uh load
path right
but if you do that um anyway
it's like uh
anyway so yeah that we can do that Um
but let me just quickly get this to
work. Okay. So over here you want uh you
want for now Mnt uh use. Yeah. What is
the [ __ ] is that? Mnt. So let's try to
open it again.
Mnt
C
users.
Okay. Thanks. Uh open that. Open that.
Copy the file path. Close. Close. Okay.
So, the file path is something like
that.
Okay. So, but but here is like um
get.
Okay.
So, get then. Okay. So, yeah. So cut
paste mnt get.
Okay. Then emac then emac in it. Now if
we open that save it. Okay. Now if we
open that.
Oh god. Then it has home the reference.
Jesus.
Then this doesn't work.
Is that right? Yeah, that home directory
reference. Yeah. So, what you actually
need to do is actually copy the entire
uh XEMAX get home to the Linux GitHome.
Yeah.
So, that's one thing. Then you need to
Yeah. So okay.
Yeah. So
you see so what do you need actually?
You need to copy. So let's see if we can
run some Unix command.
Oh god, this is so slow.
You see, we can let's see. Uh we want to
copy something like that. Okay. Copy
that to
to like to
here. Okay. Copy the Windows mount
C users get kasar emacs. Okay. actually
copy the whole
to
there. Okay. To the
Linux home directory. Okay, that's one
thing. But not yet. There's another
thing. So, oh, let's go. Uh, wait. Let's
go there.
Magnify. Go to the directory.
Then there is
Emacs in it. Okay. So, copy that. Close.
shrink back close.
So you need to
uh yeah so that would be here
there and there
okay I think we need to run these two
copy command
can we do it of course let's run eh
shell you know the tech advanced
technology let me demonstrate okay
e welcome to emac shell instantaneous is
copyr
technology system. Use the kasar git
xmax system to
wslux system home get kasar emac do it.
Make directory creating directory. No
search file or directory home. Oh Jesus.
uh copy you know the Unix copy they
don't create a directory
I mean if you have you if you have
nested new directory they they don't
create it now didn't didn't the new um
I mean man CP did all these years after
all these years did they not add option
to to create all the intermediate
directories
of course if An existing destination
file cannot be opened. Remove it and try
again. Interactive follow command line
symbolic link def reference no clober P
something preserve parents are
recursive.
Did we do recursive?
Did we?
Yes. Yeah, of course.
Uh see. Okay. Idiotic. Okay.
So, let's just do it manually the
trusted way. Okay. LS AEL.
So, make the get
cd get high Linux idiot. LS.
Okay. Make the And what I want to make
now uh XAX copy paste. So, CtrlV. Does
it work? Yes. do it and make the
make the uh Emacs. What's your
uh kasa emac
in it?
Copy.
Oh, you you forgot put here. Jesus,
almost a major mistake.
Copy.
Make the paste. Do it and ls a l
correct. Now can I run this copy
command? Go to eh shell. Wait. Go to eh
shell.
Do it.
Yes. You see the tai chi spinning.
Looks like it's working
now. My XEX shouldn't be too large. It's
done. Okay. Now,
now can we switch? Why is that iso tab
not defined? Okay. So, oh god, stupid.
Okay. Now you need to copy this part.
Copy.
Comment. Save.
Go to ESHL. paste instantaneously.
Do it.
Hello young younger. Then just use
condition to set load path based on
system type. You can set load path
instead of loading file home path. Set
low path use condition. Yeah, you know
those things like like you trick them.
It's like you never reach a final
solution you know this this path issues
because I've been I've been you know
fing about them for 30 years on
different systems like the init setup
like one day you decided actually full
path is the best then the next day you
know like next few months you decided oh
you you know let's use a tear dot
because that stand for home directory
then on another system you discovered
well the teod is not well supported
sometimes you know and then another next
year you decided you found out actually
oh you you should always use relative
path you know
actually that's true that's my
experience okay that is my experience
and also the different programming
languages so the the file path for
example you got the Unix file path on
Windows you got the backslash but slash
is also supported.
Lots of issues. Then on Emacs uh on
Emacs which is different from Unix for
example Emacs a directory should always
end with a slash that's a convention and
sometimes assumed okay in EMAC this
directory should always end with a slash
okay when you have a path that's
directory but in Unix or Linux tradition
never because directory in Unix it's you
know it's just a um a file. Okay, it's
you know you never distinguish which is
idiotic. It's a Unix idiocy
on Unix and Linux directory when the
path for a directory is always without
the slash at the end. Okay, that's a
convention. So whenever some program
asks you for a directory path, you
should not give a ending slash.
I well sometimes it may work but usually
you should should not. Okay. So be but
but so all all these difference seems
minor but actually quite significant
significant because whenever you have a
program that use regular expression for
example r sync you can pass a regular
expression to say what file what kind of
pattern to ignore you know so when when
so whether directory end in a slash or
not create lots of headache when when
there's you know lots of headache Then
okay. So then the
then you know the EMAC load uh you know
that you know set up load library um
what what's so what is the reason that
you see when when you just load the file
a simple file you don't want to um
you don't want to add to list load path
because
well in this case it you know it doesn't
matter because it's going to add to this
low path the emac system anyway but um
anyway lots of issues you see why do I
have them separate like why do I have
this kasar emac set of init files then
another set of init files because kasar
emacs is considered like a independent
package. So at any day I should be able
theoretically
uh be able to pass this entire kasar
emacs directory give it to you to anyone
then all they have to do is in their in
any file all they have to do is just add
this line then they will their emacs
will bear emac system you see that's a
that's a design okay so so
the you know, so so but we run into a is
some some kind of problem. Okay, not
really. But but why didn't we add, you
know, why didn't we use this load path
system
at this first innit file so that we
don't so that then today we don't have
this
issue. So why don't we can we uh let's
let's undo let's copy that for for now.
Let's just paste it just so we can see
it. So let's see load path. Uh can we do
that?
Yes. So if we do that then okay then
this this line is just going to be
uh
just going to be that. Okay. then then
you
don't have this you know we don't have
we won't have the problem like today we
had
so but if you do this then this means
you see any any file of this name this
this is more ambiguity because if you
happen to have this file in any in your
load path
outside of this emacs then you got a you
got a problem because it will load that
file anyway. So, so there's a lot of
those kind of problems. Okay.
Yeah, that so that's my explanation also
partly for myself because you know why
am I not doing this you know I don't
know I forgot um
anyway so
so now we have copied these two files
can we close uh is yes uh and
so what are we doing so we uh we load so
we copy those And then we can just Yeah.
No. So now
we can just load uh what we going to
load
there. Cuz Emac. That's right. We just
going to load that. And we just uh in
fact we're going to load Emacs back up
first. I mean wait uh Emacs. Yeah. So
can we open that? No. Wait. That's uh
Emacs. Oh, [ __ ] stupid. You see you
see the way window I mean the the way
Unix copy file system works. Now you got
um what?
So can you guys see? Now you got nested
directory of the same name. You see uh
Jesus because the way copy works. So now
you want to
Okay. So let me let me fix it.
Select all.
Copy
here.
Close it. Refresh. Refresh. What?
Select all.
Split the window. Go to the parent. Go
here.
Shift C for copy.
Uh, shift C. Okay. Now you need to Why
didn't it um
do it?
Copy that. Get recursively. Yes. Just
copy the whole thing.
Copy recursively. Yes. Okay. Now expand
the window now. Okay. So we let me show
you. So because it's
not hard to see.
Okay. So,
U capital U to remove the marks. Now,
close it.
Go up. Refresh. Now, delete that. Yes.
Yes. A Y S. Okay. Uh, recursive delete.
Yes. Okay. Now, that that should be
fixed. And now you need to do do the
same thing for here. Uh,
okay. Now open it. Select or go back
here. Uh, go back here.
Capital C for copy.
Yes. Yes. Yes. Copy over here
recursively. Yes.
Okay. Done. Now close. Refresh.
Okay. Now what is this? This is Emacs
init my personal init file. Okay. Now
delete that. Do it. Yes.
Uh yes recursively. Okay.
Oh there's a problem. Okay. So now we
fix that. Okay. Now we got them on Linux
home. my git, my init.
Close that. Close that.
Uh, open it. Fantastic. It opened.
Fantastic.
Now open it. Fantastic. It opened. File
exist. Okay. Now this copy is we don't
we don't need anymore. It was uh you see
the also there is that
that's why we copied them by mistake. I
mean it's double
uh doubly nested. Okay. So actually so
we uh load that and set set to roak.
That's right. And this we don't need
anymore. That's incorrect.
Uh let's put them here for comparison.
Oh uh what?
Oh wait.
Oh that's right. So this is incorrect.
What?
Oh yeah. So let's open that. Yeah,
that's good. Open. Okay. Close.
Okay. We're going to load that. And load
that and set softly keys to Vorrack.
Fantastic. And what is this? This is
opening the todo file. We don't need
that's my uh that's my web todo
and uh emac any time. Yes, we want to
see how long did it uh work and view
open the message uh buffer. Then this is
this loads the uh
we don't want this. This this loads the
Okamo mod okamel programming language
like Functional programming language. We
don't want that then we don't want that
and this uh you don't care. Okay, that
was okay. Now save.
Fantastic. Okay, let me try something.
If I move, you see I have the setup such
that if I if Emac goes out of focus, it
will save the buffer. You see right now
you see those two asterisks on the left
corner.
That means the file is not saved. It's
modified. But now if I move to chat or
something, it should save. Okay, let's
try.
No, let's go here. Go back here. No,
it's not auto save. Oh, yeah, obviously
because I have not loaded my personal in
it yet. Okay, but we'll see. Now, save
it one last time. Verify everything is
good. This is my Emacs init file on
Linux. Okay, in WSL.
Now, let's start Emacs.
Now when this time Emac start it, it
will have all my in it. So I should fly
in it. Let's do let's see.
Fantastic. 3 seconds. Is it faster? Uh
well normally on Windows if I'm starting
Emacs for the first time, it has to load
the files init files to memory. It's
about eight seconds. But second time it
will be two something seconds. Okay. Now
this on Linux the first time the disk is
not warm yet. It's 3.6 seconds. So it it
looks like it's half half as fast. Now
if I start again now they should be the
all those in files are in memory in
operating system memory. So if I start
again normally on Windows it would be
two seconds something. So now it should
be if it's let's see
okay so 3.6 seconds. So okay so you know
you know we can
see
Emacs. Let me show you how fast it runs
on Windows.
2.4 second wait but there is something
wrong it's
oh I removed my font that's why
now you can you can return my font okay
do it again
you see 2.4 4 seconds
now. Uh, Emacs.
What?
Emacs. Is it Emacs or Emacs?
Okay.
2.4 seconds on Windows. Now, the exact
same setup on Linux. Do it.
Okay.
3.4 seconds slightly slower. H
I wonder is it uh
I don't know why but uh
also why is this uh you see now because
now you see fantastic and beautiful
so fantastic okay I can fly through it
you see
okay so we uh yeah so we actually
successful. Actually, we completed
completed what we wanted to do today
fully.
I not only I I not just installed
Kasafly keys in WSL, but I installed my
entire
Kasa Emac system and all my in it. Let's
see. Uh so in summary close that can we
like um
let's see uh yeah so
where is my other terminal? Yeah so we
got two terminals here.
Fantastic. Okay fantastic so now let's
see Emacs no um no windows.
So there it is 3 seconds
now but Emacs with Windows
I mean graphical UI system.
Okay 3.3 seconds still the same but now
why why is it so big? I mean the line is
too much. Okay. So, let's see.
Uh,
okay. Init
height 40.
Oh, height 40 is pretty pretty big. So,
you don't want height 40. What?
But what about PowerShell default? Let's
Let's see PowerShell default.
30.
So, PowerShell default is uh
is 30 lines
uh of of of code. A new window. Control
shift N
30 lines. So, why is Emac 30 lines? Oh,
I said 40. So, you need to change it to
30. Save it. Quit.
Uh, what?
So, let's see. PowerShell
settings.
This is Windows terminal. Okay.
Okay. I set it to 30 lines by default.
Okay. Uh, close all. Now,
let's do the same on Emacs. Okay. So 30
close. Do it again. Start.
Okay. Perfect.
Okay. So what's what we going to do? We
can we can write this code now. You see?
Fantastic. Let's let's see. Press press
press press. That give me soft flag keys
source code. 4,000 of lines. You see I
can I can show you everything sfly keys
and let's go to my package there
cascading stylesheet mode
the edit mode diet
is mode fantastic okay uh I think that's
it by guys is it slightly slower on WSL
because a shell is run on top of windows
Uh what what do you mean? You mean the
like um
well they say emacs on window is much
faster but um
but actually I asked AI even in WSL I
think AI told me it's faster than native
Windows
uh but for what reason I forgot. But
anyway, we but uh
so
so I don't know why is it not faster,
but you were saying it's because it's a
shell.
No, you mean you mean the overhead not
shell? You mean some like some overhead
for running virtual machine?
Um
that could be I don't know really. Uh
anyway, so successful. Okay, bye guys. I
think yeah, so I'm going to go
uh then. So next days I have a lot to
do. So we can start to code you know I
can start to do my find replace um or
watch lots of things um in WSL to see
how it performs and also since this is
running in Windows I mean in Linux I can
actually compile them to native code
which is a feature not available on
Windows.
That is you compile
the emac this code. Let me show you. So
you see, so let's open the XE Emacs.
Okay. So packages. So you see there is
let's say um
let's say find let's try it. Okay. So
tell your friend. So I let's say I copy
some let's say I want to find let's just
say find Hascal. Okay. F. Wait what?
Undo. Undo.
What do I have a key for?
Uh, no.
Wait,
let's go to
CH. Oh, I don't have bookmark. So,
yeah, I bookmark is another
in it. Uh
so anyway, let's try coar
find text.
So let's find let's say Hascal. Let's
see if in my all my eaglist this files
did they ever mention Hascal. Let's see
there it is. So indeed they some of them
mention because in HTML you need to have
syntax color for Hascal. So you see uh
HTML mode. So open it. So you can see uh
let's magnify. Okay. So magnify.
So you can see
one of my package that is the find
that's working.
So but what is my point? What was I
trying to say? Uh I was well yeah okay.
So I was trying to say so this is E
which is EMAC this code you can bite
compile it yes so you can see EC so now
this is by compile it will run faster
but however there's a new feature since
about five years ago you can compile the
EIS code to native code but that you
cannot do on Windows
okay so but how do you do it so uh you
want to so I I think uh let's see
compile.
You see you can compile the list code
now to to native code
which I'm not familiar since I'm on
Windows. You don't have that feature.
Emac display by compile. So I don't know
where is it. Okay. So you need to go to
control hi go to the emacs info then you
go to the emac list info
okay then you search for
compile okay by compilation native
compilation there open it so in addition
to by compilation described in the
previous chapter of Emacs can also
option Ally I compile these function
definitions into a true compiled code
known as native code. This feature uses
lib gcc jit. Oh okay okay. We installed
it yesterday. I remember uh which is
part of the GCC. Okay. So you see you
see you see one of the this is one of
the damage of the Unix [ __ ] Okay.
Let me tell you Mo listen pay attention.
Okay, this is one of the damage of the
Unix [ __ ]
You see, you see how the lines are not
well formatted. You see this this line?
You see they have extra word in in a new
line. Why is that? Because let me let me
try to demo this. Okay. Well, actually I
did so many times, but doesn't hurt to
do it again. Okay. Because the Unix
[ __ ] their idea of hard formatted
code what they want is they tell you
that lines must not be more than 80
characters. Let's turn on ruler mod.
Okay. So you can see okay so we got a
ruler you see. So here over here it's 70
characters over here is 80 characters.
So the Unix [ __ ] told us and which
influence all computing programming
industry in Python in JavaScript in C C
everywhere they say they tell you that
lines you should format your lines no
more than 80 characters in fact no more
than 70 typically the convention the
convention came from punch cards okay so
you got that convention because the
reason is that is that because you know
lines too Oh, it's hard to read, you
know. You don't want to turn your head,
you know, like that. This Unix
[ __ ]
Now, because of that convention, now you
got this situation. Can you see? Can you
see this? Can you see this right now?
Because why does this happen? Because
right now, my windows width is less than
80 characters. So you started to have
this situation
where they automatically wrap the line
here to here but then it cut off because
you know then you start a new line. So
so you got this jack. Why does this
happen? Well the technical reason is
because well there's a line ending
because you show white show white space.
So in some fly keys that's press control
and space space. You see, you can see
those are line breaks. Okay, those
paragraph signs unic code
because there's a line break. There's a
hardcoded hardcoded line break. That's
why it becomes that. Okay. On the other
hand, copy new buffer paste. If you make
your line entirely in one line, [ __ ] the
Unix people. Ignore them.
the way I prefer one single long line.
This line is like 100, you know, 300
characters. Okay, one line. Now, you
don't have the problem of of of the like
jack lines, you see. But do you have the
problem like, oh, it's too long, you
know, you have to turn your head to the
right, to the to the left, to No, you
don't have that problem either. What
about the word? You see, you you want to
toggle
uh word rap. You see, so now you don't
you you have the nice world rap too. Can
you see that?
Can you see
the harm, the damage the Unix [ __ ]
created
which to this day we we are we are
feeling it right now at this moment. Uh
control hi you see you see because this
uh now space and space space turn off
the uh white space mode. So see we are
feeding the pain
given to us by the Unix [ __ ] and
Linux [ __ ]
To this day they tell you, oh you you
you should cut your lines at at 80
characters. Why? Because oh because back
then 40 50 60 years ago we use punch
cards and it has 80 horse per row,
80 columns per row. So therefore, you
should follow that. [ __ ] the Unix.
[ __ ] the Unix people. Okay, that's my
that's what I want to tell you guys.
[ __ ] the Unix philosophy. They lie.
Okay, Unix and Created the most damage
in computer computing industry.
um you know it's it's you know it's you
know in history of humanity lots of not
so good or you know less than per
perfect things happen and this is one of
them that's what I want to tell so my
message is that the Unix
operating system and the code its people
the kind of community they created a lot
okay let's say just a lot of harm and
bad ideas in computing industry and most
people don't know it. We still like
believe it. You you know even today a
lot of people you you ask the average
programmers especially those who
consider themselves as elite you ask
them and they will say oh yeah you
should please you know format your lines
according this way or that way which is
harmful
which is a convention that came from
punch cards
and then Unix inherited it they they you
know Unix operand operating system they
truncate lines is silently because they
can't process it. You know, they are too
stupidly designed. The C [ __ ] the
Coders and Unix [ __ ] The way their
philosophy is just do do the fastest
way. Don't care about design. Oh,
extension philosophy. Oh, academic mumbo
jumbo. Computer science is too
complicated. We just want to do simple
and fastest. That's how Unix and C
thrived.
They created and then they created the
code. These people tell other people you
should do this way our way because it's
better that you know that's how this
harmful ideas spread. So we are seeing
the harm right right here. Okay. Because
these lines are truncate you know
formatted 80 no more than 80 characters
per line. Therefore, when your window
happens to be, you know, why is my
windows less than 80 characters so
narrow? That doesn't happen in reality,
right? No, you are wrong because my
windows right now is less than 80
characters because I need large font to
do live stream and I got [ __ ] by this
Unix [ __ ]
Practical. It's not I created this
magical situation to demonstrate the
Unix problem. No.
Okay. I hope you guys uh
get my point.
So comp. So back to compilation to uh to
to the native code. Okay. So we can do
that. Yes, of course. Uh but I don't
know how to do that. I have to read
about it. So, uh, but, uh, so let's see.
Should I stop? Let's see what how long
have I been? 2 hours and 17 minutes.
Okay.
Uh, I think I should have dinner soon.
Let's check. Okay, let me check if I
I don't know where did I put my phone.
So, be right back. Okay.
Tank speedo. Let me find my phone.
Okay, I can I can go on for a bit more.
So fantastic. So let me try to bite
compile. Okay, actually this will be
really fun.
Uh I mean not by compile, native
compile.
So
to determine whether the current EMAC
process can produce
and load native compile list code native
compile available P. So let's run that.
Let's run that Neo. So it says Neo. What
the [ __ ] Wait.
Describe function native compile
available P is a primitive function in C
source code. Can do we have the source
code
on Linux when you install Emacs it come
with source code? Oh yeah because we
compiled it
right. So we can now we are looking at
the source code. I haven't looked at
Emac source code for I mean C source
code for like
15 10 years. So we can directly jump to
the sea source code. Great. So close
that. Uh what wait
close that close that close that. Okay.
Go back. Oh yeah. So describe function
uh return the new. Okay. So, but why
does it return Neo?
Why does it return Neo? So, right now I
don't have this native compile
available. Why is that?
That's disappointing.
Um,
right? Because what?
Anyway, okay, that's it. Bye, guys.
Many windows split. It become
unreadable. Yes.
Yes. Okay. Bye, guys.
Bye, guys.