Good morning. Good morning everyone.
Welcome to another episode of Sound Talk
Show. Fantastic and beautiful. So, let
me show you what we going to do today.
You see this beautiful Taurus? So, you
can rotate it. But in particular, you
can see how it is colored. You see? So,
the formula. So, this is a parametric
equation. So that's the formula cosine
to cosine s you know
uh do I need to explain par parametric
equation
maybe I should but so this is what I'm
going to do today I'm so but this is a
plot of a par parametric equation uh
which is a taurus but however what you
notice is a color so this is colored in
a way that is the it is colored by the
increment of the parameter V. So you see
so as V the parameter V gets larger
value it gets more black you know from
white to black. So there are many ways
to color a surface very complicated. So
this relates to you know rendering you
know what is the color of a object you
know like my pen my cup. Uh, so anyway,
this is what I plan to talk about, but
if you guys have any questions, pay me
ch $10, $1,000, you know, ch
Google, we'll take half of it or best to
go to PayPal, you know, on.info,
uh, as you know, kadi.info, my website.
At the bottom, you can see my PayPal
Patreon. So, PayPal me 100 bucks. Okay,
that goes to my pocket pocket like 90
like they take $3, you know, 3% or
something. And I'll talk about the
subject you want to know.
Cuz you need to learn open scad. Well,
uh, thank you blue three for that
suggestion, but I heard of open scad
open scad like 10 years ago. But in
fact, I'm upset. I'm obsessed about this
3D cat software. Okay. So, can you see
my screen? Yes. Uh let me turn on
JavaScript so Google knows where you
are. So, OpenCat is a 3D modeling
software, you know, and uh you know, so
you know, I know about 3D modeling
software since 1993.
AutoCAD.
It's the most famous then you know the
sil you know silic silicon graphics
which creates
operating system which is a v variation
of Unix silicon graphics they did uh
fantastic graphics movie effects on dur
Jurassic Park around 1998 that was a big
thing but Silicon Graphic died the
corporation
so lots of history 30 years of history
so I am incredibly fascinated by 3D CAT
software but it turns out I actually
never learned it. I tried to learn that
many times but I never did. Okay. So but
I just go back to wam language. Okay. So
um so what were you going to talk about
you know so 3D cut software there are
many types by the way. So some of them
is for creating engineering mechanical
engineering designed for mechanical
engineering for for example if you want
to design a propeller you have to model
it you know some of them is designed for
architecture for example sketch there's
a called sketch 3D or something uh
blueprint of your house design you know
the where are the rooms you know how
many floors you want things like that
and doors. You know, I should show you
some pictures, but that's, you know, I
don't think we're gonna talk about this.
So, you know, so you got this SK sketch
3D. You know, I'm starting to ramble
because if if if I don't stop right now,
like the whole hour is going to be 3D
rendering modeling stuff.
Okay, I should stop. Anyway, so there
are many types. So, some some of them
are designed for mechanical engineering.
Some of them are designed for electric
engineering. So you have electric you
know the resistors and you know the the
you know I don't know m much about
electricity but you know like IC circuit
board computer circuit board that's
mostly two-dimensional and some of them
is designed for architecture like sketch
3D and quite a few lots of others for
the past from the past 35 years. Some of
them are designed for Hollywood special
effect movie movies, you know, like um
the
Scavenator, whatever nator, the
Terminator, you know, like special
effect or space Star Wars, you know,
uh they are different because if you
are, for example, some of the names are
Maya, Mayor 3D, Alias, Wavefront, they
changed the names by the way over the
past 30 years. They changed the names.
They changed the companies. So I don't
know what is called today. So there was
Adias wave front that became uh uh Maya
3D something and might have changed
again and then they got sold to autocat
and stuff.
So if you are using one for 3D special
effects like movie for movies, it's very
different from the mechanical from the
ones designed for me mechanical modeling
because for for the movie effects you
don't care about precision. But for
propellers or these fans, you know, CPU
fans or whatever, you need to be
extremely precise. So you can output a
format that can be 3D printed or
whatever. So they are like very
different. Okay. to to a trained person
you might think oh they are similar they
are just all 3D modeling but they are
actually quite different so there are
many types okay so I've been wanting to
learn one of these but I never actually
um you know and so this is also related
to 3D game engines
you know and which is also related to 3D
mathematics so I'll show you today you
know later today so many of the spectac
acular surfaces. Okay. So this is
modeling you know this is ma
visualization of mathematics. You can
see how they are color differently.
Okay. If you are watching this offline
play at 1.5 speed because I talk slowly
and ramble that way is better. Um if you
watch this live
pay me. Okay that's the most important.
And now let's have a intermission.
Today's coffee is brought to you by this
cup.
This is
ground coffee. Elite ground coffee from
from Trader Joe's or something. And with
elite honey. American elite from Costco.
Elite. Very good. Because when you are
poor like when you are dying of hunger
when you shop every day for 10 years is
at one tree $1 tree store or Walmart.
This Costco stuff and Trader Joe's
that's elite.
Very nice honey.
Honey is expensive.
And now let's have some elite tea. So
let me introduce you you guys. U E
Europe.
Europeans. You don't know Brits don't
know nothing about tea. Okay. This is
China's tea. Also elite.
Okay. Let's pour some of it.
So we're going to talk about 3D math
function. Math function coloring of the
surfaces and so on. Okay.
Okay. So let's switch back to my screen
and uh let's you know this beautiful wam
language. Okay, if you don't know, you
can go to you can just search for
download wam language free.
There it is. Download it. You can have
it free uh since about five years ago or
or six. And so it's the most advanced
high level language. Okay.
And I'm going to do a tutorial about it.
So let's see what you know a kind of
randomish chat. Let's let's this be a
fun and fun oriented. So this is this
YouTube video is classified as
entertainment.
So if I didn't talk about science or
mathematics correctly, consider it just
as a comedy.
You know, so I'm the master of the pen
spinning. Pen spinning. Okay, I'm master
of it. Both hands. You see why? You
know, usually in Asia,
uh especially in Japan, Taiwan, China,
everyone does this. Like when you are a
kid, you do this all day. And how you
know so some some people ask me how do
you learn it okay let me explain 15
views I got a crowd n concurrent viewers
okay keep your comments coming okay and
pay me don't forget
so someone asked me how do you learn
this let me let me do a short tutorial
insta tutorial okay so you begin so by
the way this will take you month or year
and it's going to be very frustrating
okay because you're going drop your pen
like every few seconds you're going to
get annoyed but that's but we learned
that you know like we do this uh when we
are like 10 years old. Okay. So the
first thing so hold your pen like that
by these three fingers index finger
middle finger the thumb. Okay. Then so
you can see this index. So thumb is the
uh form or what what is it called? you
know the fulcum. Okay. So,
so thumb is the fulcrum. So, you can see
these two fingers uh controls the
rocking motion. The pen rocks around the
thumb. I'm pretty sure there are 10,000
uh YouTube tutorials. They do lots of
other things. Okay. Um but
you know, but but I only know this.
Okay. I I only know this uh you know so
when I was younger you know there's like
I can do this for many minutes you know
like you can count uh 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9
10 11 12 and you know hundreds. So
anyway so these two fingers index finger
and middle finger controls the the pen.
Okay. So the first thing you want to do
is just one shot. Okay. Like that. So
try to play the video in slow speed in
snail speed. Okay. So what you do is you
use this index uh middle finger to push
it push it and uh let the index finger
go. So middle finger push inward and let
the index finger go. So you want to
accomplish
what you want to accomplish is something
like that. Just one shot. Okay. So, this
is the first thing you have to learn,
okay? Before you flip it back, okay?
By the way, again, it's going to be very
frustrating because you're going to take
a month, you know, and you're going to
drop your pen every few seconds. You're
going to just pick up and, you know, it
became a habit.
So, you you learn this. So, once you can
do that, then what you do is you uh
you when when this goes over then you
use your
uh pointing finger to like tip bounce it
back right here. Okay. Right here. So,
let me do it again. Uh let me do it
again. So, this is one shot. One shot.
Now, bounce it back.
Okay. Bounce it back. Okay. Bounce it
back.
bounce it back. So you see, so once you
can bounce it back, then you can then
you can kind of start to uh continue
them forever. Then you can uh try
different tricks. You can you can do it
while you rotate your arm so you get a
kind of different effect. Okay.
Uh by the way, heavier pen is easier.
Heavier pen is easier also. Slightly
longer pen is easier. Okay. Then once
you can do that you can kind of this is
more difficult like you you move your
hand
on the side so you can get you can get a
different effect. Okay that's about
that.
So let's see the comments. Uh at this
rate we won't be explaining this uh math
stuff but that's anyway that's okay.
Uh, so Hamza says, "You are so
acrobatic." Acrobatic, Mr. Lee. Uh,
maybe a little bit, but those who are
good at acrobatics are not good at
bodybuilding, you know, like typically
the the white guys, you know, they are
into bodybuilding, they are into uh uh
bench press. How many pounds can you
bench press? you know let's go to gym
I don't like gym I don't like the muscle
building [ __ ] so but they like it why
because they have big body they are good
at it so they are into how many how many
pounds can you bench press press you
know these white people they like they
have big bodies
but um
but me I'm skinny okay so I'm not you
know I'm not into um weight lifting.
So let's see. Uh do you believe in
falong? What kind of shitty questions is
that? Huang falugong is a is a sect from
China. Okay. They teach people they are
kind of they are partially based on
Chinese philosophy and Chinese you know
Buddhism uh Dowoism
and but they are partially they are kind
of a uh coat. Okay. So they teach you
that you can fly you know like you can
levitate you know things like that. They
teach you they also teach you by the way
for you white people here they teach you
that gays
should die. Okay, that's you know they
in other words they they don't you know
they they they don't you know like gays
and they also teach you that medicine
western med medicine is no good okay
that's kind of so it's a quote fongong
and they become big in USA especially in
the past 10 years they become very big
in the beginning so anyway so this guy
uh code leader in China They you know he
began the farugong
at first is for health you know let's
you know get people to exercise to to
cultivate the Chinese you know religion
philosophy you know like peace you know
their sign
their sign is partially swast swastika
from the Buddhism origin but partially
you know and part of it says peace and
stuff
uh but so he began head. Then he started
to like do kind of nasty things.
Actually, I shouldn't talk about this
because Google is going to ban me
because this is heavily heavily related
to uh deep state. Okay. So anyway, so he
started to do things uh like mislead
people. Then China wants to capture him.
He escaped to USA
and USA the white people the white men
or whatever subclass you know subset of
the white
I didn't know who they are anyway I
don't want to get into details okay
escape to USA and uh USA applauds
it why because fingong is against China
then we can say justly flee. Look how
evil is China. They don't tolerate
religion. We tolerate religion. You are
welcome here. You see that's a that's uh
you know that's that's what you know
fallenong is. So in USA they become and
they are partially sponsored by CIA
funded by CIA. Uh, every day they do
basically China bad, CCP, communism,
CCP, this this CC CCP CC CCP this and
that
and and they become but however in the
past 10 years there's a twist okay
fugong become the
major supporter of the Trump camp okay
the right the the rightwing or
Christianity, you know, the
conservatives against the Democratic
social justice warriors party, you know,
BLM trans and all that. Oh, [ __ ] I
think I think this video is [ __ ]
because now I started to talk about
politics.
Huang, it's time for me. you know you
cannot pay me okay for my discussion
about this uh and all the digressions
what kind of question is that okay let
me let me let me quickly finish this
topic okay so in USA in past years t so
USA used falong as a tool to
to spread opinions against China
government. Okay.
Then but in the past 10 years there's a
twist. Palong become a a a very huge
supporter of the Trump camp. Okay. Or
conservatives or Christians. Okay. uh
because you know all the giant
politicians, Republicans, you know,
Fallenon funded them and also on on
Facebook Fallong spend like more money
than all the other politician combined
campaign money to to to support the
right-wing Trump camp.
Okay. And now um and they so they become
very powerful. you know, I don't exactly
know where they
got their money but stuff, but but but
they are partly funded by CIA. Okay, so
that's about that.
Uh well,
Diet Coke is my favorite drink. No, I
almost don't drink Coke at all. Uh you
know, stuff I was just throwing out.
Okay. Uh what's your opinion on India?
uh my opinion on India is kind of
disappointing
you know like
like before 10 years ago I don't I'm not
that much into politics because you know
like up to when I was 40 years old all
my attention is mathematics
engineering programming okay that's like
I that's the only thing I'm interested
and philosophy and linguistics okay but
And starting around 2016 also because
I'm getting old so after I'm 40
something
2016 there is this social justice
warriors coming out of nowhere all of a
sudden you got this safe space
you know you got this safe space stuff
what what the [ __ ] all of a sudden it's
so big safe space oh and all of a sudden
The males are evil. Like I'm evil. You
are evil. We are evil. We We are not
just evil. We are evil since since
kingdom come.
Women's are good. You know, and gays are
good and trans are good. Uh blacks are
good. Uh white guys, you guys are evil.
You guys are evil [ __ ] And me, I'm a
male, I'm evil [ __ ] Am I trans? No. Am
I gay? No. Therefore, I'm evil [ __ ] You
know that's 2016 all of a sudden. This
this lasted for 10 years. Oh [ __ ] We I
you know this video is becoming just
politics. Okay. So maybe so I'll save
this I'll save this talk next time.
Okay. So let's just talk about that uh
politics. Okay. So
yeah. So since lots of you are want to
talk about that. Uh well that's natural
because when you talk about mathematics
or programming your audience all of a
sudden becomes 110 one one millionth
very small
you know if you want to make great
America great again mathematics
is what you want to do okay
if you do not want to make America great
again let's talk about politics Let's
talk about your opinion about uh do you
support men in women's bathroom? That's
what white people do every day. They do
every day on Twitter. Let's make, you
know, let's have a debate. Uh versus
something debate on YouTube, you know,
chipping money. Ching ching ching. Let's
have a debate.
[ __ ] them. Uh USA is so corrupted. We
got lots of lots of problems. lots of
problems.
Okay, let's back to uh let's see so
India. So you are asking my opinion
about India. So, so starting in 2016, I
started to read a lot about this what
what what is the social justice
warriors, you know, and then I learned
so much, you know, I learned a lot of
things, you know, the the re, for
example, recycling is mostly a scam.
Okay, recycling. I'm so I'm very much
into recycling, you know, recycling, you
know, like I would even take a toy
apart. Okay, this part should go to
metals or whatever, you know, like study
recycling, you know. It turns out it's
mostly mostly a scam
like million dollars or whatever billion
dollar scam. Okay, the only thing you
can recycle is glass bottles and metal
bottles. Okay, metal metal like tin can.
Okay, like tin can, Coke, you know,
metal bottle or glass bottles. That's
basically the only thing you can
recycle, not plastic. And by the way, in
California, for example, you you know,
you you you you put things in recycle
bin,
half of it or most of it goes to trash.
You just don't know it. They just like
go to trash. And uh and all the recycle
stuff, they ship it to China. They ship
it to South Asia, you know, and you
know, we ship it to China, ship it to
South Asia, let them deal with it.
Uh, and the China like five or 10 years
ago, they they they refused. Okay, we
don't want it anymore. So, just, you
know, take your garbage elsewhere.
Uh, recycling, you know, a giant huge
scam.
But in California, you know, we
programmers, we think, "Oh, let's help
the earth." You know, we need to help
the earth. Why? Because life is too
good. You know, like we enjoy whatever
coffee, you know, life is too good. Code
a little bit. Um, but you feel like,
well, there must be something I can do
for humanity. Oh, yeah. Let's you know I
I you know I'm going to starting today
I'm going to recycle everything
that that is a mentality okay
uh coming from the result of life is too
good okay so recycling is one of the
huge scam just remember the only thing
you want to recycle is paper okay paper
included paper uh metal tin cans like
from coke or glass.
Okay. Plastic not not much. Okay. You
know you know
then okay India. Okay. So I learned a
lot of things starting in 2016 about
politics. Then all of a sudden 200 uh
what is it 2022?
Well I mean then the COVID came by.
Covid. What a nasty, you know, like what
what what a
what a extreme nasty thing, you know.
Three, how many dead? 300 million
something like that. Was it 30 million?
You know, you can look up Wikipedia
easily. You know, you remember that was
just few years ago. We lived by it. And
it turns out is a biological research r
went wrong
by by USA. We need to you know we need
to research. We we cannot lose to China.
We need to research biological weapons
so that we puff something in the air and
all the different races we don't like
they will die. We'll be okay. You know
we white people we'll be okay. But the
black people whatever or you know they
will die. That's the ultimate
goal of biological weapons
and we are doing it you know then then
it something some accident happened then
we say oh Jesus China did it China bats
China eat bad soup
by the way we funded China to do it for
us we can't do it here because Obama you
know there's a law we cannot do it so
they you They go to pay China to do it.
Uh Jesus, am I going to be banned for
this video? Um I don't know. Very
I don't know, you know. So, let's
continue. You know, maybe I should So,
you guys save this video, okay? Save
this video quickly.
I'm afraid it's going to, you know,
maybe I'll like uh make it private.
So there's COVID. COVID happened.
Then then you say, "Oh, China, China did
it." You know, this white people, okay,
white people, whatever the other group,
uh, China, CCP, nasty CCP did it, then,
oh yeah, let's make let's let's make
money. Pharmaceutical corporations,
let's make billions. This is a great
opportunity to make billions and
billions.
Covid Covid vac
you have to take it if you don't take it
then you are not a good human that's
what they say you you know they force
you to take it co
uh who did that well USA
so there is co you know then 2022
was it 22 or 23 the Ukraine war began
And
you know what? What is Ukraine? I don't
know.
2022. Oh, Ukraine. Russia invaded
Ukraine. What what is Ukraine? I don't
know. So I look up, you know, Wikipedia,
you know, like if you want to know
something, you can today and you can
know the truth. You just have to look
for it. spend time hours, two hours,
three hours, 10 hours, 100 hours every
day, you'll find the information. Okay?
For example, what is Ukraine? Well,
Wikipedia, Google maps, you can find it.
So, I started to learn, oh, there's
Ukraine. Oh, Russia. What what is
Ukraine? Oh, they, you know, they were
like, you know, USSR, they are they were
part of the Russia. And what what what
people are in Ukraine? Well, they are
just Russian white people. Beautiful. By
the way, the Russian, you know, white,
you know, before this.
I find the white girls very attractive,
you know, because well, because they got
blonde and blue eyes. I find them very
attractive and I, you know, they are
from Northern Europe.
But now I know better. I know deeper,
you know. So actually the the the most
whitest girl they are Russian whites
okay like including Ukraine Ukraine
Estonia Russian you know that that
region there's a like technical name for
that group called um
I don't remember exactly but this you
know like diff you know then I learned
so many ethnicities like fine division
you know like very technical anyway
Anyway,
so I learned about Ukraine, you know,
Ukraine war and why did it happen and
and you know, stuff.
Yeah, I know. You don't know, but I
know. Uh
well, then after that there's something
Gaza happened. What What is Gaza? I
don't know. So I looked up, you know,
Gaza. Very sad story. Uh yeah. So,
so, so during these past 10 years, I
started to also uh learn about India
because when you look up the map, you
know, you want to know what you know
what what is Georgia. Georgia is not the
USA Georgia state. There's another
Georgia
you know Georgia you know you know
neighboring countries of Ukraine like
because you hear the news the news says
oh this region whatever you know this
city you know you don't know what they
are so you look up so you you you know
you started to learn more and more
things and India is
kind of part of the news because there's
you know India China China CCP every day
something China China and India Is India
is is India gonna beat China or China is
gonna beat India? You know so and I a
lot of you many of you
uh Indians you know I learned you know
well actually I worked with Indian uh
like in year 2000 in you know in uh in
Ntopia. So my co-workers are actually
four Indians and white one white guy. So
but I don't really know what they are
Indians like. So but until recent years
I started to learn India you know. So uh
India well they kind of very poor and
especially in the past two years you see
lots of India
um
videos and photos because the because of
the racial tension you know in the past
one year there's a lot racial tension
you know Trump and you know the
immigration the Trump and Ella Musk war
about immigration so there's a lot
information about India Yeah. And of
course as part of the consequence a lot
of the European Americans make fun of
ind Indian. So you see lots of like you
see a lot pictures of like very Indians
is pretty poor and they are not they
kind of very poor and uh then of course
you can go to YouTube and you know and
there's a lot of videos like India too.
You can watch those too.
But yeah, my but my impression if you
want my
honest opinion Indian India Indian they
seems they they have a lot way to go.
You know this is interesting because
like in the in year 2000 for example 25
years ago I heard that India and China
and Russia is going to be superpowers.
So this is in the 1990s
and people people are debating you know
why you know this some say oh I bet
Russia is going to be the superpower in
in in 10 years some will say oh China uh
some will say India
but now 25 years is passed it turns out
China is just like rising like become a
super powerful superstar
Russia is doing good and India not doing
too good it turns out and uh if I can
give you extra information about why
well I think part of the reason is India
um I don't know too much about this but
but I think part of the issue I think
India got lots of issues for one thing
India's got so many religions
they you know they are not mutually
compatible you. So, so you have lots of
religion and lots of over 10
like technically hundreds languages
different languages but overall you got
more than five you know major languages
mutually unintelligible
in India and you got different religions
you know you got Muslims you got Hindi
you got Buddhism but you got other so
many divisions of
different Hinduism something. Okay, I
don't know too well but that's just my
impression.
So you got language like fraction you
know then you got uh religion fraction
you got race racial fraction in India
and then you got but then another thing
is that India adopted English as their
main language. So what India do every
day is like all the things they read is
basically western websites like Twitter,
you know, Yahoo, MSN,
you know, like like like the educated
class in India is all just reading
English because English is sanctioned as
the official actual official language of
India.
uh and they are mostly used by the
educated class kind of elite in India.
So it's all English. So that also means
whatever
the western society whenever they have
problems conceptual problems for example
in the past 10 years the trans the
feminism the LGBTQ plus ABC
all these ideas goes to India because
they share the same language English but
not so in Russia and China that's kind
interesting because before I thought it
would be great to have a universal
language for efficiency reasons. So
since English is already currently the
most popular, so why not? It would be
great if the whole world speak just one
English. So you avoid inefficiency,
you know, it's like one language, one
programming language to rule them all.
You don't have to learn oh for web you
have to to do JavaScript JavaScript uh
for for for server use Python or Pearl
or Bash or Shell Ruby PowerShell
whatever you know one language why not
so you don't have to like waste time to
learn different things
so but it turns out one language is not
that good one universal language is not
that good why because it's Like once you
have a virus in that system, it collapse
the entire system
or like when you build a ship, you need
to have compartment compartments because
if you have a hole in one of the, you
know, your ship bottoms, it prevents
other compartments uh go down with it.
So, so one language is,
you know, is not necessarily a great
idea. So, anyway, back to India.
So, India, they tend to, you know, they
they use English. Um, so
it's complex issue. So I think that has
some issues because you basically just
your view you know your your view of
things of the world is basically just
the western view. Um but of course there
are good reasons for it because when
when India began let's say 440 years ago
or something you know they were they
were [ __ ] by the Brits okay the white
guys by the Brits very much so
uh you know so
you know
the academics would say they are you
know they were a colony under British
imperialism.
So they got [ __ ] by the Brits. Uh but
so they so English is very common you
know and their law is so like based on
British you know this you know this
practical
issues. So so anyway that's language in
India ching. Why do Indian scammers get
hacked so badly? Can they afford to hire
a system admin with money they steal?
Yeah, that's you know another thing
about India is like it seems a lot of
the hackers
and uh well not not actually good hacker
like all the scammers you know like they
call you up they say oh you need to call
this number for your credit card because
you know like scammers and and are in
India and they got exposed by many
YouTubers you know so that's another bad
impression of India India. So in India
is not
you know they got a lot issues. Um so
that is my impression from of India and
uh and uh you know we got quite a few
India uh friends on s discord. So I also
learned something from them.
Yeah. Yeah. You know,
so like if you go to YouTube India, you
know, uh scam, you'll see a lot, you
know, uh exposing like in depth.
So let's see what's the next question.
Uh what's the next question? Open Scott.
Okay. Stephan Wolfam is a bad guy. Why
do you say that? Adam YouTube says,
"Okay." Uh, and
do you miss chai? Chai
ham.
So chai for tea. Chai is actually I
think chai is from the southern Asia.
They call it chai. you know, maybe in
Vietnam or or Thailand maybe, but in
Chinese it's
okay for tea.
So, next, Adam says, "Do you miss
trolling internet forums like back in
the 90s?"
Uh, minor correction. I didn't troll in
the 90s.
I my kind of my first post
on
well I mean yeah I wouldn't say you know
I I'm known as a troll on news groups
beginning around after year 2000 okay so
I wasn't known as a troll in the 90s
even though I do I do post on news
groups but I wasn't a troll then it
became
known You know, I I became to post more
dramatic stuff after year 2000, okay? On
news groups.
Do I miss it?
You can, you know, it's not it's not
it's not I miss it or not. I'm just
getting old. You know, when you get old,
your perspective, your behavior behavior
changes. Okay? So like when you are a
teen you tend to do something
and almost always when you are older you
don't like you know you you you find
them silly but teens you know when you
are young teen you got to do what teens
do you know you got you got to be brave
you're going to break some windows
you're going to do some graffiti you
know you got to be different you know
it's part of the
um ritual what you know what what's it
called passage of right you know so
anyway I don't think I miss it I miss
trolling or whatn not um
you know I just get old and uh you know
but but these people you know so maybe
you are aware recently like two days ago
one of my article became popular I mean
got posted on hacker news again about
lisp cons you know I must say this lisp
people are extreme idiots. Extreme.
Okay, are you guys these coders here?
Because I can go into detail on why they
are like they are just like idiotics,
idiots. Okay, and also some people, you
know, a lot of people say I'm a troll. I
don't think I'm a troll. Okay. I don't
consider I'm not you know like the
stereotype image of a troll in their
minds is that you know some people like
they just want to post something that
triggers you and make a mess you know
and and uh you know I'm you know if I'm
a troy like I will be laugh this guy is
so stupid you know it's like a prank.
That's what most these white people
[ __ ] idiots. their they you know
that's their
brain pattern about trolling you know
it's like troll troll is like a prank in
their mind okay like someone you know
just enjoy the misery or the ridicule
other people you know let me post
something you know to the Python or
pearl or list programmers you know like
oh your language is stupid and and
because I think you know something silly
1 plus 1 I think oneplus 1 is three
therefore python is idiots, you know,
like, you know, that's their imagery,
these white idiots.
And so, so the troll, you know, make fun
of people and I enjoy it, but but that's
not that's not me. Okay, that's not
that does not represent my mindset. That
doesn't is not correct description of
what
my behavior. Okay, I can tell you what
my I can tell you what I'm doing. I have
a strong view opinion and I tends to be
very rude.
Okay. Uh may you know intentionally or
otherwise I'm a nerd. Okay. So usually I
don't perceive social you know I'm not
you know very polite person
uh for whatever reasons. Okay. So I'm
pretty rude,
you know, and I don't I don't follow
social norms like you don't, you know.
So if I think Richard Stoman or whatever
these famous people, they did something
stupid, I'll say this these [ __ ]
Richard Stoman did a lot damage to
Emacs. Okay. And the Gido von Russam is
the most idiotic, the most low IQ person
among those who created a programming
language. Gido von Russam of the Python
fame idiots. Okay. And also he sponsored
social justice warrior women. Oh, I'm
not going to uh mentor men uh because ma
males are like aggressive. Males are the
uh evil in in h human animalist history.
You know the G von Russen [ __ ]
Okay. And lots of others. For example,
that Ruby on Rails guy
DHH. He goes by, you know, the short man
HDD or DH, you know, Ruby on Rails.
[ __ ]
Okay. So this because of my manner,
because the way I say things, you know,
disregard social norms and being very
extremely rude and uh post my opinions
in a strong way. That is why people
don't like me, okay? Because they think
I'm a troll.
Okay? But also many of my opinions, they
don't they don't get it because they are
just idiots. Like for example, the least
cons they don't understand because
um anyway that's up to debate. Okay,
whether my opinion is good or bad,
that's up to debate. But that's anyway
that's my description of why they call
me a troll. Okay, I don't enjoy I'm not
the way they think of typical troll or
prank. I I despise pranks. Okay. I don't
enjoy pranking like call someone you
know like you know these hackers you
know they call someone they don't know
who where you coming calling from and
pretend you are someone else you know
prank pranksters and troll I don't I
don't like those okay that's not me but
this white people idiots
okay anyway that's uh that's about that
uh another question
tell us what will happen in Middle East.
Okay, nobody knows. Okay, that's uh I
think I'm done for today and it's
already 50 minutes.
Uh because talking about Middle East
that's that's a big problem. You know
the YouTube going to ban me.
uh and more, you know, something,
you know, I'm I'm afraid to actually
talk about that.
ACP says, "Do I use a smartphone?" Yes,
I begin to have a smartphone in year
2000. Okay. before year I mean I mean in
year 2020
basically when the covid begin that's
when I started to have a smartphone
before that I don't know you know I
never
I don't have a smartphone okay so I
began to use one in 2020
so your question is you are saying I'm
thinking to switch to a less
sophisticated phone to reduce reliance
mobile apps. That's a good move. Okay. I
do use a smartphone but I'm very
reluctant. So I almost never use any
apps. So mostly my Twitter whatever I do
is all on desktop. Okay. I use phone. It
become it became necessary.
Okay. Before year 2020 I don't have
money to have a phone.
Uh actually, you know, something like
that. Okay. Year, you know, the year may
be off a bit. So, I don't have money. I
don't have like $30 a month. I don't
have it.
So, I don't have a phone. In fact, I
don't even have a phone from about year
20120.
Not even a dumb phone because I don't
have $10 to pay for it.
That's how bad that's very bad period of
my life. So, and also so yeah, I don't I
don't use a phone and also the
smartphone, you know, this got so many
apps on it. I usually don't use it but
it became it kind of became necessary
you know because if you you know if you
go out if you are lost you kind of need
a phone and especially smartphone
because the all the maps are on it you
need a map you know if you are in a
different city uh you need to call cabs
you need to you know do banking or
whatever it kind of become necessary
because there's No public phone anymore,
you know. Used to be in the 90s there's
a public phone. You there's no know
that. And they don't have maps anymore.
I mean, if you want, you still can buy
paper maps, but it's kind of nobody yet
do that. So, you kind of need a phone
today. So, but I I don't use it that
much. I use it just for, you know,
contact emergency map.
Um, yeah.
So I think that's it because I it's
already one hour. Um let's see.
Brew 3 says
have you any experience with mapping
projection onto spheres and unwrapping
thereof? I saw a cool demo on Desmos
website called wrapping UV sphere but
I'm too dumb to understand. Well, okay.
I can, you know, so I can tell you
something about it. So this is about
projection to a sphere. So if you just
go to
uh so I have one page about okay there's
a few page. Okay. So let's go check them
out. So there is stereographic
projection. This is how you one of the
way to project
to map between a sphere and a plane.
Okay. So you can see this visually. Uh
actually we did this I think in a live
stream two or three years ago in Wuan
language code. So we can actually copy
the code. Let's demo some technology.
Okay. So paste it there. Run it. So you
can see there there there and this you
know made of lines of sphere then
projected to a plan I mean we also draw
a plan plane.
Okay. Then then then then we started to
color part of it.
Then we start to project. So this is a
visualization
illustration. This is graphics
programming in wam language. uh to
illustrate
the mechanism of stereographic
projection. So this is one of the way
okay one of the way to to map between a
sphere and a plane.
Okay. So in general if you want to map
between two spaces that's called
projection. I mean well
a certain sub a certain subclass of map
between two spaces is called projection.
Now stereographic projection is one of
the projections uh mapping between a
sphere and a plane. So there's a lot
others. Okay. So we can search map
projection
and it's get fairly complicated and very
interesting. Okay. Wikipedia map
projection. So you can see
so Wikipedia you know goes through into
detail. So if you want to study this you
can spend half a year because there's
many so this is pure ge geometry very
interesting topic I have been wanting to
fully understand this but I actually
never did okay so I don't actually know
the answer to your question. So but
anyway I know the fundamentals. So
anyway, so there are many different
types of projection you can study in
detail. One of the most popular for maps
is called um
uh is called this um
stupid name. So Mecca Mecca something
marta maka projection that's one of the
popular one. Okay. So anyway, your goal
is to map a sphere to a plane. uh it is
impossible to to do it without
distortion.
So there are therefore there are many
ways to do it but
somewhat minimize the distortion like
you can't you can't get rid of
distortion. So anyway, so you got
different you got cylindrical um
projection, you got another different
type of cylindrical projection and
anyway so that
so that's uh you know so that's the what
the answer you are looking for different
types of projections okay I don't really
understand it fully okay so but it's a
very interesting topic
The only projection I know is this
stereographic projection.
Uh if you are into mathematics and
geometry, this is the most important
because this relates to the whole field
of complex analysis. Okay, complex
numbers then you got into you know so so
this so you can look up this is called
Raymon sphere
anyway so
so if you are into math you know
stereographic projection is the most
important
so let's see next question so I think
that's it for today so thank you guys
for watching
am I doing good is my video rolling
Okay.
My grandfather said every girl is same
when lights is turned off.
India has thousands of years of history.
Sir.
Yeah, I know. I know that. Hamas, but I
mean so does Greek. So does China. So
does, you know, Middle East countries.
Uh so does Egypt.
But I mean India, I mean, you know, so
you got you guys got to work um you
know, if you want to make India great
again.
I I think you know. Okay.
Uh, the tranquil young says, "Hi, I
always like the vibe with your stream."
Thank you. Just curious what you doing
for living. I'm doing nothing for a
living. That's the honest question.
Okay. So, I'm not retired.
Um, well, if you know a bit of my
history, I was, you know,
dying of hunger. So anyway, I just um
I don't have money. Okay.
Uh
we are divided by language and religion.
Hi. Hi. Do you like pure poor tea? Yes,
I'm a lisper. Okay. Uh another idiot
here by many categorizations of this
channel. Haha. Writing this
professionally. Fantastic.
Lucky you.
Very cool, Rudy. I've been Okay, that's
it.
Bye, guys. Anything else? Your last
chance. We've have been talking for an
hour now.
So by after you know tomorrow or next
few days we going to come back to the
topic of this coloring of mathematical
functions. Fascinating subject because
you got different lighting. Oh let me
summarize it a bit here. Okay.
So what determines the color of a of a
mathematical surface? You know, so there
are many ways there's intrinsic color of
the surface like you can put a color on
each one of these squares, you know,
intrinsic color and there's lighting.
Okay. Now the intrinsic color like you
know what is the color of your pen? What
is the color of your keyboard? You know
there are many different types.
So there is
transparency. You know first of all you
got transparency like a glass. So you
can make a object transparent to various
degrees. Okay. Then you got diffuse
color which is most popular almost
everything you see uh my keyboard and
you know that's diffuse color they
reflect color. Okay. And you know so you
got white keys you this is black this is
red uh this is you know this book is
blue. You got different colors.
Then you can have glowing colors. So
what's what's the example? You see the
lead let lead lights here that's
glowing. So a thing can glow and they
can have different colors. Okay. So a
glow will also affect what you perceive
as the color of a thing. Okay. So these
lights are glowing. So if actually I can
change like can you see
this is my ultimate hacking keyboard.
Okay. I cannot take it. It's hard to
move.
So you see I press this button they
change light. You see that's you see
that this light that's glowing. Okay. So
I can press this button. You see that's
white, red, blue. Okay. That's glowing
color. Okay. So you got then you got
specularity
which is like a metal
a shiny metal. It kind of reflects.
Okay. So you see so all these aspects
you know transparency
transparency
specularity
or diffuse color
you know this is you know transparency
specularity
diffused color then you got uh glowing
color okay so they all affect
How something the color of something.
Okay. So that is the intrinsic color of
a object. Okay. Then you got lighting
you know. So lighting you can have
different light source and they can be
many types. You have like parallel light
like sunlight you know from parallel you
know from one direction or parallel or
you can have um you can have spotlight
you know like in a football stadium
spotlight from one direction.
Uh
then you can have uh
you can have a light bulb light bulb
light you know it radiate from radiates
from one point then you can have
flashlight like outside of the
flashlight it's totally dark then you
can have ambient light. Ambient light is
like a in a well lit room you know you
have light like all over they don't they
don't cast shadows much
so you have different this different
types of light source you can have more
than one they interact and each light
source can have different color you know
you can have red light blue light you
know so so that all affect that interact
with the intrinsic color of the thing
Okay. So in wam language if you want to
so you can have like you can specify
each and every one of these variations.
So they affect how
how how the things you know looks you
know it can be partially transparent and
so on or shiny. Okay that's what I was
going to talk about. So, I'm going to
talk about this next.
Um,
okay.
Bye.
Uh, thanks for the stream. Bye. Have a
good day. Do you exercise regularly? No,
I haven't done for like over 10 years,
but now I just do like some little
push-ups and stuff.
Uh yeah, I used to like throughout my
life I used to be at the level of
competitive athletics.
So I do figure skating, I do swimming. I
was in a swimming team when I was in
college when I was like 22 something.
And I do like figure I mean like
rollerblade. I hold on to cars, you
know, on the street, you know. I I did
that when I was even 30 something.
Anyway, I haven't been. Okay, bye.