good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Santos show today is August
20th 2019 good morning bassam al Bethel
new so today's topic is going to be
bathroom USA's vendôme okay let's do
that
oh by the way battle immune and in other
people you know sometimes I read the
comments but because I'm also talking
and I'm kind of slow so sometimes I
misread you know I skipped I forgot I
didn't see some of the questions so if
that case happens you know you can
always just type it when I'm looking at
the comments you know just type it and
so so yesterday you mentioned that the
bathroom you you mentioned that the the
megaupload guy king kim calm you liked
him okay because i I misread because I
thought you said you disliked him
you know I so I didn't think he's a good
person because you look at you know he's
has histories and controversies and you
know you can Church your person I mean
this is how I judge the quality I mean
the moral quality the moral character of
a person you know there are many
controversial persons in the world
including politicians including a
journalist or any almost an including
any type of person you know for example
me often often controversial so anyway
so the way I judge is that you look at
the deeds you know what they've done
what they are controversial for and you
can get some kind of a sense you know
what kind of person what kind of
character he is you know so so the
megaupload guy of course he's
controversial many people support me
many people organist and they also
priests you know his many politicians so
anyway I look at him and so I look at
his controversy
so I don't think he's a good person
because I think he's you know scum
because you know you look at those
controversies he is you know he's like
illegal in three countries I mean like
he do something he get very rich and you
know he's illegal and he escaped to Hong
Kong you know then he did something you
know made a lot money and then you know
they'd see legal you know people start
to you know the government or whatever
the you know start to you know sue him
or things like that then he escaped to
New Zealand I mean so I mean this is the
outline but there are so many details I
mean you read it and and you know you I
don't think it's a good person for
example let's just give a random example
let's say someone you you know some
people a lot of people are for a lot of
people are gayness
you know usually famous people you have
always have large of supporters almost
anyone once you become very famous
because the word of people are very
diverse you know they are in two
different parties and interest you know
oftentimes it's human nature that we own
you know like we don't really care
someone famous is really good or not we
just care about whether he is on my side
you know whatever I'm interested or my
opinions about politics if he is you
know on my side I support him you know I
say all kind of things say this is a
great guy and fighting with the you know
other people who you know attack him so
for you for a random example let's say
some guy become very famous very rich
and then you look at his past exam you
know past incidents you know you this is
critical because you don't want to
listen to what they say you know
especially politicians politicians is
always like they always say good things
but you know or say whatever the current
you know trend it so they get promoted
you know people like him but you always
want to look at the historical deeds
you know what's his behave
in the past so if you see someone anyway
so that's that's how I think that how I
look at the person's character so Baz
Luhrmann's says all is relative if I
compare Kingdom Come to the boss of
Amazon both of Google both of Microsoft
know and and okay
patthamas says you so if you compare
megaupload guy to Google Microsoft you
know those guys
I rather pick him a hundred times more
than any of those other mentioned people
so so battle mania says that I don't I
don't think so I don't agree because it
is I mean I can see your point and I
agree I've agreed that many of the
Amazon pass and Google Buzz they are
extremely evil you know Facebook boss
okay so which one is worse I cannot say
that for sure but I certainly don't
agree you know Kim is hundred times more
not at all they they are like like in
the same you know they basically the the
so in my opinion they are kind of you
know they they or greedy but yeah it's
hard to say which one is actually worse
but I think they are worse at the same
you know at the same level at Lee you
know one thing obvious is like the king
calm guy he is doing I think he's
actually worse because you look at you
know the thing he do he you know copy
you know man you know create this makeup
upload you know basically the essence of
that company is to grab all the
proprietary you know Hollywood videos
basically that's the most most in the
movies take them and upload and he make
money and also also by the way know you
are a programmer right we are notes you
look III remember I once went to
megaupload back in that time like 10
years ago you you go to these websites
they have like I mean you look at the
web web design it's just it's like a
scam it's like you know
it's a like a more website and I have
actually I have no doubt I have no doubt
that kim.com probably you know have a
lot business with these small websites
you know like I know you up for example
if I'm Kim I know you are a you know you
know you spread more where and you you
come to me you say I pay you you know
you know they say have a median you know
not you know a few hundred thousand
dollars if you if you if I you know this
more way a guy asked me to put a link to
his website you know and he pay me ten
hundred thousand dollars do I do it I'm
pretty sure Kim calm did things like
that yeah I'm pretty sure because you
went to you go to the Omega website you
know megaupload you have these you know
boxes you know tracking and all sort of
things you know so you know so that's
just my opinion so bathroom you say so
the thing I like about Kim is not really
what he did wrong but the way he did it
he did a lot of tricky and ironic stuff
and at least I find it funny
okay he's very interesting person even
though he is not a moral role model okay
hey good morning Dion Dion I haven't
seen you for a while and dr is from
Europe am I correct
good morning green deck green Depp is
from Russia and Dion is from UK I think
can we agree to hate hate Geoff bozos
you know I I actually I don't know much
about I mean I'm pretty sure I dislike
the current Google CEO and what about
Bill Gates actually I cannot say I
really hate him anyway so anyway the
thing Jeff bozos I don't know much about
so many people you know because he's
very big and huge
I can say for sure like be like what I'm
saying is that I don't have I don't
really like immediately I could say I
don't I hate him I don't know I don't
heat I don't know his character so
Amazon tries to be you're the ultimate
monopoly Kim does not therefore Kim is
definitely less the evil no I don't
agree bathroom we escape bathroom you
say that okay so Amazon you know okay
let me try to explain my point of view
okay you know so build a monopoly you
know the concept of Madonna of monopoly
is very misunderstood by especially by
the programmers you see they are -
concept of you know they are - like you
can say there are two perception
interpretations of the word monopoly one
very popular among programmers is that
when you are super super popular in
powerful in one area programmers co-ed
monopoly for example Google search
engine programmer would call monopoly
Microsoft operating system programmers
code Monopoly you know what basically
when you are super powerful where you in
this area or the market you you have 90
percent market share things like that
programmers call that monopoly that is a
wrong idea okay that that is incorrect
incorrect understanding of monopoly you
see monopoly is one of the dramatic
words everyone wants to recite you know
without really understanding it they are
quite a few words like that they they
usually forms the foundation of memes or
whatever you know becomes widespread but
that's a incorrect understanding of
monopoly because for example because
there how do you distinguish suppose
there's a company who is very successful
because people love them because their
product is so great and they are so
ethical people or people love him
love the guy and this company let's say
exact cooperation okay and become so so
big
I have let's say 90% of market share of
Emax let's say do you call that a
monopoly okay most programa do but also
but but actually however most programa
think of it a monopoly concept as Evo
so how do you distinguish you know the
Evo you know some monotony monopoly like
Evo versus someone successful who just
by all ethical means you know because
people love them because when you so
many people love it it becomes so
popular and take over the market how do
you distinguish that there's a
distinction so the so the actual the
correct you know the legal definition of
monopoly is when you tries to prevent
other people from entering the market
that is monopoly okay when you are
successful and you also try for example
imma Emacs okay I have a Emacs website
it's so great a lot very popular then
you started to write a blogs you know
starting to write about impeaching about
you max series then I try to you know
but I usually by devious means I try to
tell people I tell Google to blacklist
your site that is bad okay that is
monopoly that that that is kind of the
legal definition of monopoly you try to
prevent others from fair competition
that is monopoly okay so I don't agree
that you know like I understand you guys
what you guys think you know oh Google
is evil emma's everything big is evil
that's basically the typical UNIX
philosophy kind of you know hacker type
of people or the you know the hacking
type of cryptography the type of Google
people are thinking you know that's my
group of people that's my community I
understand because these people they are
always you know Linux and you know
they'll attack everything that is speak
that's that is that wrong that that's
kind of like doing Direction barking the
wrong tree and the end result is you're
gonna get worse Society
she like today you know Google Facebook
Microsoft becomes was you know they
become evil and powerful I mean we are
evil by you know but blatantly lying you
know
underhand tactic that that's what
happens when you yeah we we all have
ideology you know free software you know
share or whatever good ideology but when
you push it without actually looking at
the truth or facts of reality you go you
your society becomes chaotic becomes
because basically essentially what
happens is that you have so many
different powers each one just want to
push their view you get a mess so in
summary I like to say you know just my
opinion it's not you know you don't want
to you know hold on a second let me say
this okay so we programmers you know a
lot of us and you guys okay they we hate
Microsoft this is like 20 years ago you
know Microsoft is Evo you see it every
every day on slash starred on websites
you know some people won't say you know
my code you know the Bill Gates should
die because this is that that you know
but now look at today now twenty years
has passed has you know has our society
become better is it worse than you know
back then Microsoft it is worse and who
are who are the bosses now it's Google
Facebook in you know Facebook and and
also treated part of it you know they
are doing things far worse than
Microsoft you know Microsoft is 20 years
ago they are kind of limited to the
operating system kind of computing but
Google and also this Apple okay Apple
Facebook you know but Google now they
have like satellite Lee they shoot
rockets they control the whole entire
world information it becomes you know
far more Evo if you want to look at you
know from historical perspective Google
has become far more evil than Microsoft
why because you programmers you know you
open source you know the ideology you
know you you are making things worse you
know that that is
that is my kind of my opinion you know
this is a summarized version because
this is a very complicated topic but
that's what I want to say so I don't
usually you know I'm controversial sigh
I usually have a lot of opinions let's
criticize these typically my the my
target of criticism is this open source
this this UNIX hackers this UNIX
philosophy this kind of underground this
kind of smoke coop niche you know remem
nice and forever is remaining niche you
know like like Emacs users you know so I
like to you know that's just my
character okay so so I in summary I like
to say you know you don't want to just
follow a ideology you know because in
our community you know we just follow
all the hackers so we love hacking we
love them we love Linux we love you oh
everything open source is good
everything free software is good
anything else is bad that's not good you
you want to you know yeah so that's my
opinion so for that you know make an
upload guy he is you know he began evil
you know like Google someone but
Facebook also began Evo okay face
Facebook that the boss you know that
Zuckerberg he is a very bad person from
from the start now but Google is a
different story you know Google that
found us the two guys Larry's search I
research and and and the other guy in
anyways I think search and Larry I guess
that's a day averse name so they
actually began good they may have been
good for the first ten years of their
company and we supported them but for
reasons okay it's how to describe they
become bad and also you know that's you
know this is always a mystery you know
is it true that when a corporation
becomes large and powerful they all they
all become corrupt or are the other
control you know one question I have in
mind is that due to the Larry found us
you know they
they are they are PD on air so I'm not
sure they actually I don't think they
actually touch the day-to-day stuff of
Google because now they have like now
they are alphabet they have Google they
have like so many branches you know
artificial intelligence branch you know
driverless car branch satellite light
branch you know and and they also have
longevity on longevity branch which is a
research on how to make a human leave
can't 200 years you know that's that's
biology and you know they have DNA
research you know Google is this
all-powerful thing so so okay yeah so in
the beginning Google is not evil so this
those two guys I don't think you know I
look I I have looked all these
characters and most of them somewhat
okay I don't know the details except
Richard Stallman and I know that he's I
know that guy very well from his story
history and so on and in Stefan gufa
anyway so the Google founders you know I
I know a bit about their history so I
don't think so they are not evil person
they they are good person actually I
would say but Google today is so evil so
there's a question mystery I always
wondered you know is it true that you
know just when your company becomes so
big I wonder one Google is so evil today
is it because this two person actually
became evil like because because once
you you know money change change changes
your life and changes your perspective
if you were born rich or if you are a
billionaire
you never understand you do not feel you
don't get the best perspective of
someone who does poor you know in
poverty you you don't see you don't
understand because it doesn't matter you
can read a lot books but you don't you
don't see it unless you are actually you
know very poor and and live in that life
so so one question I have is that other
Google founders are they they Google
Evo is it because because these people
you know these Google leaders because
now they are so rich you know they've
been so rich for 10 years they they they
changed essentially because once you
have so many money your interactions
with people it makes a huge difference
you know you are every day what you see
they changed that's that's one
possibility
okay the the founders of Google changed
you know they they actually you know
they maybe they think they are still
doing good but actually they are doing
evil but they don't they don't see it
you know they they have so much money
they don't see it they maybe they think
they are still good that's one
possibility so they change the other
possibility I'm thinking is that maybe
they are they don't have control you
know you see so maybe they think they
agree that Google has become so evil but
they don't have control of it anymore
even though they have a lot of money
because once you have a company it's a
structure is kind of complicated it
becomes big you have lots of executing
you know and and you want you know you
know in USA it's a public traded company
you know you know you whoever have the
stocks control a company in your sense
and it's more than that so so the other
possibility is that you know the Larry
Warren Search Search brain you know
Google founders they did they they are
actually out of control I mean they
cannot just say you know they cannot
just tell Google to oh stop doing this
you know because they are far removed
they kind of not not in direct you know
that kind of control and and when you
are that which you know you don't think
about Google you know you you you are
like you can buy a whole country you
know it so Google whatever Google do is
like you know it's like you know you you
are thinking something else you know so
so that's my question about you know why
Google is become like that so it's let
me read a comment so if you have
anything say it okay
get to it so so today we began talking
about monopoly related issues let's see
nine people watching twenty two minutes
okay so okay so let's do this copy it
copy this way I can read better go to
Emacs paste it okay so the whole
software industry so
green death the young UK DNC in UK okay
patthamas says i partly agree okay
Dion says the whole software industry
and everything involving copyright is
kind of direct industry right what do
you know the ASEAN rudy guy who ripped
off millions of dollars from wine
enthusiasts he allegedly faked super old
wine and sewed it for so that $400,000
what AC and Rudi guy the ruby guy the
japanese ruby guy yeah i don't know what
and when you say why you mean the window
the linux window emulator so let's see
sabatham you so let's see okay next I
think this Ruby rooty guy is more oh
because he took back the money that rich
people stole from us
okay what okay I don't know what what
what why sabatham he says Amazon is a
real-life bookstore delivers food takes
over delivery service sells everything
Amazon he takes over all areas of
business more and more you know another
thing I want to say about Amazon oh
these all these big companies you know
they become powerful you know look you
know we have open source for the past 30
years especially in the past 20 years
because the first 10 years you know in
the 1990s open source or free software
it just began but basically since 2 year
2000 open source or free software is a
public under you know phenomenon people
understand it so we you know so so if we
look at you know we've been doing you
know oh you know you guys and and me you
know doing open source you know shouting
for open source yeah we should open
source everyone but but you know Lou
have a look at society you know today
you can you have you know you program
that we programmers have no power
whatsoever because everything is Google
Facebook Microsoft Apple as you know
Apple is particularly also one of the
big evil guys each of these big
companies they have 100 1000 million
patents is that what you want but but it
is these companies Apple Google
Microsoft they are now all open source
it is especially Google and Apple they
pushed Google of open source it is day
that made open source the concept
everywhere now free software is a
different thing if we software basically
in the past 20 years becomes less less
less nobody and nobody know it you see
why does that happen you see this is our
community our programmer programming you
know programmers so who do you blame
blame yourself that's what I say you
know that's that's because your ideology
made it that way you know in other
open-source requiring oh we should you
know I have you know almost all my
acquaintances or online friends are you
know for open-source because I am you
know I'm open source in the open-source
community I've never coded any
proprietary or Microsoft I never used I
did use to use Apple the only thing I've
actually supported but programming
languages Mathematica in 1990s okay so
anyway but back to the topic so open
source you know in in the past 20 years
oh oh you guys you can see it every day
right before you from your friends from
slack slash start from hacker news from
reddit everything everyone is singing
open source and Linux but but look at
the reality today Google Amazon you know
Facebook they control everything and and
your phone you know Android I iPhone
they did monitor they know every your
movements you know you even if you tired
of they say they still to you know
Google you know they still grab your
data by all means and and today
especially on the phone you cannot even
tell unless you are dead
you spent ten years of a life to study
you know the cryptography security stuff
you cannot even tell and also many of
these things you know moving into the
CPU hardware level so you don't even
know you have to become to study the
hardware expert you know with such
machines take apart iPhone and make sure
you know every chips you know it becomes
like that and you are still you know
look at the result of your of our
programmers you know open source push
what would work where are you where are
you and and look at the free software
the richest Tolman who is like out of
touch you know if you know with just so
many successful so you know you know
he's got great ideas you know he wants
you know free software so in his ideal
world we will we will not have the
situation where we were afraid of
backdoors on the chip because even a
chip is a free software free software
you know open and you know but the way
he goes about it which a storm and
pushing his ideology abusing the word
free and have no idea about economics
you know he's like you can ignore end of
economics the way so he the way he go
about it what we have today what we have
is this very niche free software
proponents like you guys okay and me he
max you know very nation nobody knows
outside the you know like every every
1000 programmers how many of them are
free software kind of full free software
less than one you know every 10,000
programmers meaning any any people who
work who make a living by programming
how many of them how many percent are
for fees of free software
it's like 0.01 okay and and and like 50
percent have vaguely idea what what is
free software reaches home and like oh I
heard of it you know it's like open
source you know that that is a result of
you guys [ __ ] you know etiology
you know every time like Malthus master
done you know oh we got the distributed
mastered an encryption good it has no
effect on society meanwhile Twitter
Facebook Google they are growing back by
10,000 times more than whatever you are
trying to push that that is a result you
have to look at reality what what is
going on what do you do what end what
happens you know so the way I see is
that you know we got you know you guys
put you know I because I am in three
sort of society you know community every
day I have people telling me you know
the this though that encryption you know
this that distributed but look at the
actual result we have free software you
know pushing for twenty years
the your our group you know this we want
we want you know ethical company in this
kind of thought you know become snitch
and nish and not know power you cannot
do anything with it go work for Google
that's your option you know what you're
gonna do you trying to write a software
free and and trying to make money become
powerful no way you don't get paid you
know you don't get zero I live in
poverty I get zero dollars you know and
because I criticize free software and
and nobody won't want to you know
support me nobody like every time I post
to read it it's download or you know you
don't get hurt so you have the situation
and so I mean the point what I'm ok what
I'm saying here is what you're gonna do
nothing you can do because the
open-source has wrapped all power of
programmers the only option you have you
know for example last year the you know
bleeding-heart Berg
you know the bleeding heart then then
the coast something in a CPU you know
believe bleeding heart is about software
you know you know in the encryption
software by this open source guy he
lives in poverty you know this is
critical survey he lives in poverty
poverty once once the bleeding heart you
know poked out then Facebook comes by
you know this powerful John oh let me
help you let me give you you know donate
you hundred thousand dollars you know
the [ __ ] Facebook that's that's what you
guys are doing
you know you have no power you know even
you read the critical software you you
you get no money nobody actually pays
you know every program is online
every time the ads come up they say oh
let's you know use ad blocker oh I would
rather pay then you know ads but
actually nobody pays you know you guys
nobody pays a thing I don't get money I
get to you know I'm patron I get like
$150 a month $50 a month let's that's
enough for you know for food yeah you
cannot pay the rent for if you live
really carefully how do you that's you
know hundred fifty dollars you buy
coffee every day and you know Starbucks
coffee so anyway so so back to the point
you know you you want to
what's my so yeah you know you look at
reality it's like so the way I see it is
that our type of people you know the the
the my kind of perception of the free
software open-source proponents you go
nowhere you cannot you know you cannot
make money the only way you you do you
google buys you out
Microsoft pass you are face you go work
for them go work for Facebook that's the
only way you make money you make money
and you and each one of them has 1,000
patents you know you just work for them
and every day you are singing songs on
Twitter like I got this new iBook look
this iBook got this this these features
you know compare oh the CPU is this or
that you know yeah you you work for
Facebook then next day you are be
Facebook Facebook kick you out google
kick you out is someone new comes by
what you gonna do free software what
what what what is it the good thing that
you pushing free software open source
for you know we the society become you
know MA they monitor everything illegal
it's in USA people like to complain
about China but you look at USA
illegally would you what you'd get what
you know what is the direction what what
do you think we all happening you know
especially so that today now you have AI
a is a thing you know today the
technology they are growing
exponentially you know as people say so
you have like 10 things every day 10
more things every day it's impossible
for a programmer for one person to
actually even know what is going on like
you know I know Emacs
stuff that's whining a million things
you don't know what's going on in
JavaScript whirring ai word in hacker
work cryptography would you know and new
things come up new chips or new you know
things this you know so so when when
this becomes like that the only people
who are control who are controlling them
the Google Facebook you know Mac was
they they are they are controlling so
watch you know and free software yeah
you know in the ideology of Richard
Stallman you know he's just like the no
power is less less people use Emacs with
most people don't like laughs you if you
go outside of the Emacs community they
people laugh at the Emacs nobody use it
so what is the yeah so you want to so
that's what I thought
so what can you do so so the way there
many things you can do okay for example
you could start to do some action you
know use you start a business actually
you cannot survive you know for example
you you see you you like free software
right you you want open-source why don't
you start a open source of free software
where everything is open source you
don't survive you don't survive for a
month
live are they are they are one or two
exceptions like git git lab even you
know possibly they are struggling you
know they are like the kid lab you
compare to github that's ten thousand
times bigger than you you have no chance
and in big key lab is only one of the
very small possibility of existence one
exception you try to do it you know try
to open source you know you it doesn't
work you get no money yeah your ideology
is great everyone shared you you do
things you share you you you you die
that's what happens that's we see the
word look otherwise we would have large
100,000
open source or open source companies
they compare but they compete we don't
have that we just have you know Google
Facebook you know and meanwhile they are
singing the songs of open source they
are saying oh yeah open source yeah as a
society you know we want share help
humanity meanwhile they do all these
evil things there's nothing you can do
with that that's the result of you guys
open source ideologies so what can you
do so so the way I think ok different
people you know I live in my own you
know
narrow is like limited you know opinion
each person in a limited opinion but so
anyway so my opinion so what I yeah and
some somewhat good at is you know I can
I think what is important is you want to
tell people you know you want to tell
people these things you know like what I
just mentioned you know look you look
you want people when when if if all the
programmers are aware I mean you don't
have to agree ok that's a thing you
don't have to agree but the critical
point is a is is about you are aware
what I have just said did this this you
know this you know reality things you
know if you are aware then you can you
know you can make a start to make a
decision
you know what act you actually believe
what is actually maybe maybe you change
your mind maybe not but this you want to
be aware that is a point you know you
want to be aware so my solution you know
my kind of so is that you know in other
words people say it's called education
ok so you want people to to know about
these issues then you know because
ultimately societies or just people all
of us so if overs is you know believe
the right thing then society will be
better because that is that is made of
us but today we have this situation
Google Facebook you know and so ok
so that's about that
so Rudy guy I don't know who is really
going bank money okay so Marisa has real
life bookstore so Bethenny says rich
abuse and of Justice can go wrong if you
follow it through to its logical end
point ends with descending cool acts to
the ghoul acts what's what's cool acts I
wouldn't say I'm against whatever it's
because again it's the detrimental
concentration of power yeah I do we all
hate that concentration of power so this
week Deon says these big organizations
are ultimately providing the majority of
the real benefit to a very small people
yeah
Batman is okay so yeah precision in
concision thirty years ago Apple was
pretty more oh yeah I would yeah I
definitely I I would agree with that
Apple begin big today it's just social
justice stuff and and greed you know
Apple you know every year every time
they have a new phone they act they
intake they they make their software so
your iOS has become slower you know so
you're gonna buy a new Apple and also
oppose the today almost all hardware
they they make it so that it is
impossible impossible to fix
I mean for example you cannot even open
it with a school they they create you
know non-standard schools they they
don't want you to fix it or replace
parts they want you to buy new one
because they make more money that way a
lot more that is you know so all this
you know that if you look actually look
into these things there are so many
details yeah I mean you cannot even
begin to like to a summary it's not
something you can say in one sentence in
the case of you know making the iOS
slower that's that that's the thing you
can say in one sentence but there are so
many and each of the company is suing
each other for patents you know they you
know and most of us you know even if you
are a nerd you know you don't have time
to look
into this detail oh you care is that is
that today oh you got a new phone this
is great you start to talk on Twitter
you know the I got a new phone this is
that you know and and on occasionally
when you see something open-source you
you say oh yeah open-source you know
it's great you know you don't look you
don't actually look into the details of
things because why because that cost you
you don't want to do anything that's
costly that's why but if you actually
want to understand something you have to
pay that is what that is not free it's
not free software you have to pay if you
actually you know so so you know you
know like I said before start to spend
one hour look into things you know this
open-source you know Apple deeds or
whatever or the whatever internet you
know you know whatever you know do it in
such a way you have to sacrifice your
time or whatever you can you know that
that's when you actually know stuff not
just you know you know oh my you know
someone did a new great open source and
you go to Twitter and say yeah now
that's great you know we all should you
know that's that that's what you know
today's activism is like you know
everyone's brain is you just push you
just type push whatever the opinions out
there because you deeply believe it you
think oh you know you know the this or
that so today is another rant about open
source and free software that's that's
so Deon says I think good and evil are
concepts and crude clear thinking yeah I
agree
Google has a particular culture and
incentive structure attached to it and
which make it do harmful things yeah you
know especially in America you know in
America is everything is just good or
evil you know this was America you know
even before today even it's back then
1990s in typically American thinking is
that
you know you just have evil you just
have good verse okay that good versus
evil dark dog Darth Vader is evil you
know every almost every story there's no
like you know people say it's
one-dimensional or two-dimensional
there's no detail this is in contracts
to Greek mythology when you you know
read Greek mythology stories there's so
many detail like each person it's not
just evil you know American like to
think Americans kind of thinking is
typically Oh evil Lord you know Kusum
some Microsoft is someone my crappy or
gates he is evil Lord you know he just
spawn he was boom and he just want to
conquer the world that's not the case
usually what what each person do or what
he became is many complicated stories it
almost doesn't exist you know where
someone is just pong and you know I just
want to control the world things like
that doesn't that that doesn't exist and
also you know American you know they
like they they may be in general white
people countries Europe you know and
they have you know Evo the concept evil
like you don't even know they act like
that's hard to define okay that's you
cannot even define it in absolute way
you know because you know to you China
is evil to too many people
well you know this you are evil you know
white people that you know European
Colin ISM is evil then you know times
change then evil concept then changed
the today is like it's like you know the
the conservative is is evil you know you
know it changes you know in you know so
this is not just evil versus you know
good better Mia says yeah right I
thought but I think there are many
things that are considered considered
either evil good by most people yeah I
tend to use these words strokers yeah
since early life stream has a not scope
for this type of subject as a piece of
different topics yeah
you don't need malicious people for
organization to act reprehensible ways
just people who are cut off from
counterbalancing incentives yeah okay so
anything else let's see what any other
topics maybe we can talk about some
other thing or maybe we should focus
yeah this focus today on these kind of
social issues you know where I get to
rant about organs open source and free
software and you the UNIX philosophy
people [ __ ] [ __ ] the UNIX philosophy
people and okay so let me read more
comments okay so
[Music]
okay Google and Siva because I can click
so Google is Siva because I can't click
on your naming a chat window and get
your channel what do you mean okay you
are too nerdy to understand you Rudy
okay sabatham you better make battle of
muses judy is a guy who faked real wine
to drink okay
people bought it from him for several
million dollars
he only tricked super-rich banksters
okay yeah I don't know what is that
story about why yeah I saw I thought
it's why the you know the the the
windows emulator in Linux fathom you
says I I looked up him up he's you or
Rudy Rudy Cunha we and so what so maybe
it's look at that
Saluda kuhnian wong birth-name xìng wáng
Wong
oh he's a Chinese sky born 1976 about 10
years older than me younger than me in
Jakarta okay is a wine collector and
convicted perpetrator of wine oh he came
to prominence as a wine connoisseur and
was promoted okay anyway
anyway something about wine I cannot
read it offline
so the distance Kwai hi good morning
distance gray the irony people running
Linux VMs on proprietary restrictive as
sure what is actually a Microsoft thing
yeah people you know and most people you
know we open source people you know we
open source or free software guys we we
are nerds right and but but if you look
at the actual people you know the those
who are not programmers they vast
majority people they don't care like we
are concerned about all privacy like
privacy this though that all encryption
all cookies you know but if you look at
our side of us you know which is 1000
times larger ten thousand times the
population they don't care they they all
they care is convenience you know modern
societies like human Mo's are like pets
you know as long as you keep people
happy as long as you know I can have a
Wi-Fi camera how you know maybe your
house name a car I'm happy you know I
don't I don't care about all
controversial political topics so what
did Google is doing Oh Google is you
know Facebook is invading privacy you
know but for most people they don't even
they don't care they don't know they
don't care you know and if you tell them
for example if you go oh but you need to
know Facebook actually did this this or
that you know but for average person
they oh that's you are you are a
controversial guy I'm not sure I want to
talk to you
you know they they are happy you know
you know they are just happy they use
their phone most people don't care you
know and until maybe some days they did
something then they get caught
yeah I mean then you know they do your
lies something wrong it's it's too late
because all the Google control whatever
you know he just get Y proud you know
you raise this guy's name that that's
but that's what happens to motors that's
a situation you have to also understand
that situation you see the other thing
okay the the other thing interesting
about this or these social issue is that
okay so so I was saying you know I
advocate for people to you know to know
and also you don't have time you know
you do you are you actually going to
spend you know few hours of your day to
actually look at all these issues and
this is going to be endless because if
you look at human history you know 2,000
years 3000 years these political things
they you know it's part of humanity so
you know today we are concerned about Oh
Google Facebook but there are so many
you know outside programming there are
so many things going on
injustice evil things or whatever in
China
okay everyone that like to talk about
China now you know so many things going
on although everywhere and this is part
of humanity so to what degree how many
hours are you going to spend to to look
into all these you can't you know you're
gonna spend all your life you know so so
so one interesting thing I think I have
thought about is that what if if you
know actually if you live you know
10,000 years hey good morning telegram
if you live you know like a vampire you
live for a few hundred years yeah and so
you know a lot stuff about you know or
suppose you are omniscient like God you
know you know everyone you know you know
or injustice or lying you know you see
the whole picture what will happen to
you you know I've been thinking so if
you if you are someone who knows all
these things
what what will you actually do once you
know all that it's it's really hard to
say you know maybe maybe when you
actually know this because even history
what we read in history book there are a
lot of issues okay I'm not saying okay
I'm not like some of the controversy
some of the you know cutting conspiracy
will say oh everything you read is
incorrect everything you read in history
book is incorrect that that is not
incorrect okay actually much of it is
true
but there are so many details and
perspectives but even suppose you know
you know suppose today you begin to
spend five hours a day to look into
political stuff after five years you
will become expert you will actually
know you know the details of many
political you know international
relations and things like you you know
the truth but what are you going to do
that that is the question because
because after you know this stuff let's
say me you know I spend a lot of time
you know looking at open source and
stuff stories what am I gonna do it's
almost like nothing you can do because
everything I say nobody listens you get
wiped out you know to do like it are you
tomorrow are you guys tomorrow is going
to say okay so say this great thing
again it's open source are you going to
say that no not likely because first of
all you believe in something then I say
something you might say oh that's
interesting but tomorrow tomorrow it's
same day for you again yeah let's do
open source let's do you know anyway so
back to the topic so once you know the
truth what are you gonna do that's a
question almost like today the
information war you know almost like
this is very hard for you to this to do
anything you know that the society moves
like you know that anyway so that is an
interest interesting question you know
there are degrees of it like once you
know if
you spend five hours you know as a human
animal not huge nuts superhuman but just
a normal human you spend five hours a
day
you look into particular topic let's say
politics international relations or all
about China for example all about what
whatever is your concern maybe in
something in Germany politics something
in you know UK politics I don't know but
you look into so after five years you
really know a lot but the question is
what can you actually do what and if you
do this what are the consequences that
is a one question
okay that's that's one question chances
are I in my opinion I think you know I
don't know for sure I think it is very
little you can do because what you will
become is just like okay here's another
interesting thing today you look around
Twitter there are they are you know
quite a few people they actually know
things but you don't know who they are
you don't know their names
like but but but you know logically you
know they are actually or not people who
know about you know all those details
but but the thing is they are not very
popular because you know the issue going
on anyway so that is kind of an example
showing you what will happen if you
actually become know all these details
if you studied you know five five hours
a day for five years you can you can
actually get the glimpse of what will
happen to you because because we we can
know for sure as a logical deduction
there are people like that you know they
either get you know if you behave too
badly you get wiped out you know you get
killed that that is also logically
possible you know because these they
have you know media mayors you know when
you are that rich you don't even have to
that be that bridge so this is one
example one interesting question the
other thing is that if you actually
become superhuman like
then you and omniscient like a God you
know all you do you see the whole human
every billion you know each person's
life in detail you know all the lies and
everything then what would be your
conclusion what you know what if you
actually know that that you know that
much
maybe then your behavior will be or we
will be different you know maybe we are
you will think oh that's just let's just
you know like we you look at and you
know and you know thousand billions of
ants busy doing their things maybe maybe
at that point us just see that's you
know young you don't care you are you
you so so your behavior will maybe
becomes what what you are doing today
like you just do program ease or
whatever you are interested you know get
a girl get married or whatever you know
maybe that's you know or your family you
know maybe you actually become that you
don't care when you actually know all
the details so that's you know some
philosophy so this is called philosophy
when you yeah so what we have been doing
technically it's called philosophy when
you think about what will happen all
these things yeah okay so what else does
so I've been talking for 57 so I think
maybe five more minutes
five more minutes okay type tap your
questions and let's see let me read
comments
so Dion says Beyonce's I think there's a
tendency to push things like master then
because as programmers the power we have
is basically just to write code we can
control what society does with it
Dion says I share your frustration with
the way things are but it's not obvious
what's the way out is yeah you know like
I kind of think you know the option is
is is to for people to be aware or this
you know like what I've said in the past
hour so but but that is not new that is
basically called education you know many
great thinkers age you know great
thinkers intellectuals they have said
that you know they say the society what
we need is more education so it's kind
of like code and try it
concept you know and it's going nowhere
because you know why I say what I say
but all those people who disagree all
those people in power they will simply
say I'm a you know a my conspiracy nut
case you know and this infowar like if
you if you let's say if you could have
in China whatever you hear is basically
you know that specific perspective if
you could have in USA every day you see
is first you know the kind of us a media
perspective even even if you try not to
you know get into mainstream even if
you're agreeable but still everyday but
you touch what you see is this kind of
perspective in USA that's what that's
the word culture come from so and UK you
know each in Africa or Middle East you
know each one has different thing but
when people get together you don't see
you know you don't see eye to eye even
if both of you are rebels like oh like
like us we see you know because that's
your background you know that's your
that's the thing so like sometimes I
talk to I tend to have people
around the world you know type talk to
all the people around the world you know
sometimes I talked to UK people I have
no idea what's going on UK
as far as politics is goes but sometimes
I talk to them my friends you know and
so I say liberal but they say they say
you know no you aren't wrong because you
know you are just abusing the worldly
bro but that's what American use you
know so there's a lot differences you
know when you talk you know you becomes
you know this is a you know like
conservative you know all these labels
you know there's this different meaning
in different phrases so beyond says we
have to figure out a way to get money to
the people who contribute to free
software in a fair way I don't think
that's going to happen you know we tried
to do that for 20 years I don't I don't
think you walk because fundamentally
this is my opinion because free software
is kind of like a communist ideology
it's just not going to walk it's not you
know it does not reflect reality reality
it does not reflect shall we say human
nature you know like when if I say it
like that then people say oh what do you
mean human nature it becomes dramatic
you know human nature is like a dramatic
word every time you it's like monopoly
human nature you know the dramatic words
every time it's mentioned people have
all 100 interpretations and you know
attack each other but basically so you
know free software you know basic I
don't think you know it's going to walk
the yeah so yeah so instead so what what
should we have instead I think so we
should have more kind of you know you
doesn't matter what issue what's the
politics you look at scientific ly
scientifically you know what reality if
you have this you know if you implement
implement this you know idea what will
happen you know
you look at this society you know many
of the ideas has been tried you know you
can well you can kind of doing
scientific way to look at it that's you
know rational and scientific you know so
but again that's old news that's very
old news you know again you for example
if you go if you go to you know if you
take the scientific perspective on
everything then you lost you kind of a
lost I saw you lost you lost the for
example religious people they like to
have you know like they say you know
scientific you know rational like today
in USA you have all these you know this
kind of group of people who are doing it
all kind of in my opinion bad things
because and they are anti the Christian
in a sense you you know atheism the New
Atheism beginning 2000 year 2000 so you
so the region becomes kind of got
somewhat somewhat okay so the
non-religious people has power and we
look at the tyre society today's society
Google Facebook they are kind of like in
a sense you can say that's a result that
is a result when you get rid of religion
you know so religion you know it's also
another controversial topic but I agree
to some degree that you reach and they
do have some kind of coherence they make
human animals even though they are not
scientifically valid but they do kind of
make human groups some somewhat coherent
and phosphorus not getting not becoming
a chaos today with the progressives you
know Google Facebook that's kind of a
chaos that's kind of going on
so so you know so I was saying the
solution is maybe we should focus on
science and rationalism but ugh so but
I'm also saying you know that that may
not be that's not the final solution
because they are we see today we've seen
the problems it you know it's happening
so maybe so you know I don't know the so
bet on me bet on my battle of muses my
friend has a very successful business
that is growing and based entirely on
open source okay or free software okay
okay so I think that's it today so
so or laughs or laughs okay or laughs
says what do you think of Greta Sundberg
I don't know what's that and Friday for
future movements she started a global
movement okay I don't know what is that
so let's look up Greta humbug let's see
Oh a young girl 16 well I usually want
to see that immediately
I don't trust whatever it is so greater
Thornburg says you know is a Swedish
activist who at age 15 began protesting
outside the Swedish parliament okay her
school strikes for climate began
attracting any response - okay okay what
is the point
so what is her point environmentalism or
something
yeah basically any any person you know
any of these kind of this is very
popular this kind of thing it's a since
the yoke since since year let's say 2000
you know since Facebook become popular
you know since since the online media
you know the Creek Bates you know so we
have the trend where you know we tend to
like you know young people things like
teens teens especially if there are
girls you know we you know on social
media every month we say oh some girl
being created something that changed the
world you know they typically what so
why'd they become popular that's another
thing that's another trauma traumatic
thing like the word monopoly you know
human nature you know it's dramatic
these kind of things is dramatic they
become you know they are the foundations
of means so you know very well going
viral you know if you study viral you
know what goes viral you can you can
find some there are some certain terms
or subject so kind of style they did
they tend to get by row and so one of
the things you know monopoly the word
you know one of the things that like
young girls like you know young teen so
young girls they they amended something
that changed the world that's that's one
of the thing that becomes very popular
why is that because we humans we we
support in general human animals okay we
like to support young usually because
you know that's our children's our
offsprings we was you know when I was
young people support me because I was
like especially when you are King
because that's that's a good part of
humanity because when you see teen teens
are vulnerable you know for example
suicide happens most often when you are
ting and this is also true for other
animals like a little puppy little cats
kittens that's you know turtle turtle
turtles alliance or whatever when you
are young
that you are the most vulnerable
predators you know get you eat you
whatever you tend to die when you are
young so in general doesn't human
animals and also lions you know cats you
want to protect the young so that's why
for example women in children that's
another dramatic word phrase used by
politicians all the time oh
something-something women and children
we need to protect women children and
actually that is true because we need to
protect women and children children why
because that's they are young you know
they are the most vulnerable we need to
you know protect them and also guide
them you know teach them and what about
women women also because women they they
they actually grow babies you know they
grow babies without no humanity you know
guys you can die
you know guys you can go you know fight
was die a million no problem ten million
no problem but as long as all your
females are you know young females are
there they you know no no female dies no
problem you can you can grow the
population just like before no damage at
all almost so that that is why women
children we protect women so when so
these dramatic things when especially
forceful is the young girls you know we
every time young girl so young girls
created something that changed the world
we we tend to this dramatic we tend to
innately you know promote it we like to
you know it gets our attention but but
on the other hand am on all these viral
things there's lots of fake news or you
give exaggerated things for example I
can name off the top of my head you know
there's some it happens every year you
know some some Islamic world or they did
something they want peace Awards you
know then you know Nobel yeah there it
is Nobel Prize nominated for Nobel Prize
there it is
not just her this also and also let me
also mention another thing injustice
okay
typically all these girls they you know
they become popular these variable
things they they also they typically
they they are white girls and well today
you also have black rose okay but
typically they follow the trend of the
the culture what whoever you know made
it popular you know for example for
example let me show tell you your
example in white nations you you will
it's not likely for something to go very
well if it is a Chinese girl in China
ting going in China okay if that's that
you don't get popularity instead white
girls black rose you get popular but in
China
for example let's change perspective in
China they have their social networks
you know which is different from
Facebook and Twitter the the the young
Chinese girls they get popular they get
viral but not not this guy not not this
you know white girl you know D oh but I
go the Chinese people don't care what
the [ __ ] is that you don't care so you
see this is different things going young
so anyway what do I think about her I
don't know any I don't know what's her
deal but I I don't think it's worthwhile
to think you know I think it's just
quick bait and stuff okay so actually I
wish you'd stop so that's it for today
so is there anything I can't read too
much so anyway that's it for today about
open source huge open source rant and
free surfing so long live let's see long
live Emacs okay long leave open source
and free software oh hope for the best
bye everyone
well yeah once I you know I noticed once
I clicked the stop then all your
comments even though I can see it I can
still see it for forehead you know a few
10 seconds or so but they don't show up
on on the video Google view YouTube
video I noticed that so I should wait
for you know 30 seconds for the other
comments to come up then I click the
stop streaming okay good good bye guys