hello guys
good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of
star talk show so today we are going to
do
wufang language coding and i'm going to
generate
uh i'm going to redo these
images i'm going to redo this one and
this this this this all the conic
sections and
taurus and you know i'm going to do some
of the simple
plot of surfaces of surfaces
that can be represented by a parametric
equation so wolfen language mathematica
so
that's we are going to do today is 2021
july 23rd okay welcome
if you have comments and questions post
it okay
good morning bot okay so start warfam
language
that's the first stop and uh
then we're gonna just uh code it
so in this talk show you might learn
some
practical wolfram language a basics
really really basics
okay so the first thing let's do let's
do sphere okay
so i'm going to redo basically we do
this this is done
about 15 years ago and i'm going to redo
them
so today's talk show so we have a link
to sphere
and okay so we're gonna regenerate and
update my website and i'm gonna show you
the woofing language
code okay so go to firm language and
how do you do this okay parametric plot
that plot
there it is uh the formula right there
so paste it okay let's just paste it
there it is so we have a sphere with a
little bit
uh gap you know why why the gap because
you know i kind of like the gap because
the gap shows
you the start at start
and end positions of the of the
parameters
here you see so if this 0
2 pi so the formula is cosine you know
this is a formula
3 uh three functions you know this
the first part is x then the y part then
the z
and the u and v are two parameters
two parameters because this is a two
dimensional surface you need two
parameters to go over to cover it and
the
u and v are the parameters and u goes
from zero to three
so if we change zero to three instead of
two zero two pi then
you see it fills up the gap
uh no zero to two pi wait okay
zero to half pi so instead of
instead of three let's say zero to half
pi
yeah wait what's going on it should be
two pi
uh you know pi
3.16 but uh
okay so let's change this to pi too
you know so let why don't we show a
um let me show you this okay manipulate
okay and we plot this and
the plot point so let's remove the plot
point
the plot points tells ufram language
how many points to plot for you and how
many points to plot for v
the two parameters so right now we have
10 20
maybe that's why the grid does not
get aligned up so if we remove that then
it's automatic
then here we want to
pi do it okay
now you see now the grids are aligned
so so now all we have to do remove the
gap is
change the three to uh
to pi yeah there we have
it okay then we got real problems why is
the grid not aligned
i'm not sure uh you see the grid here
it's not it's not uh refined
there so zetron crazy good morning
haven't seen you for a while
you seem relaxed now woke up properly
uh yes kind of uh
so let's uh let's do the manipulate so
we want to find out
why is the grid not aligned and one of
the easy way
you know one of the easiest way to see
the parameterization of a surface
you know which parameters determines
which
patch of the surface is to use dynamic
visualization so you can have a slider
that
that changes the parameter and see the
visualization
on the fly so that's what we are going
to do so
we're going to cut this formula we want
to plot
cut it and paste it here
and let's magnify so you can see bigger
okay and remove the plot points
and now
the u let's say u
max okay so z u goes from zero to u max
v goes to from zero to v max
okay then we are going to say
then we are going to say yeah
then we are going to say
a list so this is umax
from three to
from one to three okay so that's umax
then v max
goes from zero to uh
from one to pi let's say one to two pi
okay let's evaluate it okay we got arrow
how is that
the function value 0 v max
oh yeah so we got this it should be v
max not v u max okay v max
there we have it okay
now let's magnify so u
let's increase u
so u is kind of the horizontal it only
goes
half of the sphere okay so you see
that's a
u part u only goes half a sphere
u2 umax v2 vmax and umax one two
three so let's check
let's see what does v do
so v goes
to
okay this this parameterization
i don't like it because it's going from
it's doing weird i mean it's curving the
sphere but in a weird
kind of way can we can we make a
parametrization of the sphere such that
such that it kind of swaps the u and v
position and doesn't do this weird thing
i think it's possible
but
okay so i don't know what's going on so
let's say six let's say three here
so maybe that okay so
okay problem hi gamer breakfast
hi breakfast uh
okay so we succeeded in plotting the
sphere
but the thing you know if you really
want a pretty page that lies in the
detail
you know there are so many ways to plot
the sphere you know let me let me tell
you something about math
okay the parametrization of a surface
so you want to plot a sphere
and one of the first thing you want to
find
is the parametric formula
now there are more than one possible
they are probably
they are almost there are so many
there are many ways to have a parametric
formula to
plot a sphere uh
you know they they cover the sphere in
different ways
so anyway so let's let's see what's up
what's the problem of our current
one so the first one the u
the u parameter goes from one to three
so that should cover it okay so u
u parameter goes to 1 2 pi so this
should be
the max is pi okay
wait but if you change it to pi what's
going on
u from one to pi
wait let's say four
uh i'm not sure what's going on here
exactly
so let's let's purify the code a little
bit
so this way it's easier to read so
umax
let's say three two four okay
so first of all we focus on the u
parameter
three two four so the first parameter
actually should be
you know it kind of just cover the
horizontal rotation
let's see the second parameter so the
second parameter is more about
vertical yeah
oh okay so you see ah this
parametrization
sucks because the second parameter not
is not just about vertical but it's also
you see it's also covering part of the
part of the u parameters thing
okay so that is why we we
we don't we know we get this kind of
funky thing so
the best thing to do is just look up
wikipedia see
what parametrization they give
okay so let's go to wikipedia
okay wikipedia and uh what does it say
sphere okay it gives you a kind of a
transparency we can do that as well
and uh so what parameters
so you also have a
equation of formula so here is the
parameter
let's see if we can copy that
let's see yeah
this is tech
okay so that's not helpful so we
rather just write it ourself
so three x y z okay x y
z so x is
r psi
r sine alpha
theta and theta and alpha okay
uh that's phi okay that's v okay so
theta is u
and phi is v okay let's see that
you need our eyes radius radius is one
so let's ignore that
okay so that's the first thing
the second thing are sine
sine okay sine sine the third
the third parameter is
cosine theta okay cosine at
theta is u okay so this is the
alternative formula so let's try that
so
okay so let's try to manipulate this
alternative formula okay
hello bittrex
so copy that
this is the formula
and this is umax
this is v max
okay do it now let's see
three two four okay now it also so
3 2 4 the u should be 2
2 pi
okay so u
yeah okay and
the v let's see what does v do
yeah that's a better now that's a much
better uh parametric formula
okay so so v will be uh
2 pi not 2 pi okay so let's try that
u does that thing v
does that thing fantastic
now this is a better formula and
actually simpler too
this is the sine cosine sine sine cosine
okay what what did we have we had
yeah okay it's about the same you know
if we swap to u and v
we probably get it yeah so anyway
it's you know it's probably the same
formula
uh okay so that's that is what we want
okay now let's now let's do some emacs
to replace this image
to replace this image so we got the
graphics here
so we are we are doing some we are
plotting some wufan
language using wufang language to plot
some surfaces today
uh
let me show you okay so
you know we are going to plot these one
two three four
five and sphere and taurus about
seven surfaces today so the first stop
is sphere so we
done sphere and now the next step is to
replace this image okay now go back to
mufam language now let's
copy the code so this is the code we
want
so let's put it here
v max okay so what's the v max two pi
and pi okay
and here is pi okay do it
fantastic and uh
what kind of orientation do we do i want
let's see compared to here okay
so you you do want to show some kind of
the top
let's uh
let's just do that okay
now why is there some i don't know if
you can see it
there's some glitches on the ball
yeah there's some creatures now is there
there is some transparency let's try
transparency
okay so this is what we want let's try
some transparency so
we want to see options for parametric
plot
okay so let's look at the documentation
parametric plot
options
so axis boundary style color function
evaluate mirror exclusions
automatic endpoints or u u v curve two
curves to exclude exclusion style
uh max recursion mesh style
let's see some examples dark mesh
grey mesh light mesh
themes that affect 3d surface include
what themes
the arguments applied to functions in
mesh functions
and region functions are these and that
functions in color functions
mesh functions mesh automatic okay
so
so here's some examples here
opacity okay plus style directive green
opacity so let's copy that
let's see
let's see what that one okay this one
very good
transparencies okay yeah this is
some sort of propeller pretty so
plus style directive let's try that
okay
okay i decided i want let's let's just
use this okay let's see red
specularity uh
specularity remove
let's see what happens
okay so
let's try red
okay what
okay specularity must be inside the
directive
so here is the plot style
and plus style rule plus style go
you know specify plus style by this
directive
this directive is red opacity
and specularity that controls the
surface okay
red does not look good
yellow not good
okay now there's another problem you see
this
uh you see this grid line
wait okay so lots of
refinement issues
you see i don't want the grid line to
have some kind of you see this gap
so i guess i guess now it's that's when
you need plot points
30 okay coma
okay there's still a gap
okay so minus 0.000
minus a little bit a small number
5.60
what the
okay now i actually now we need to
control
not plot point plot point is just how
smooth
it is we want instead
you see if you change plot point to 5
then it becomes
that if you change plot point to 60
it's very smooth but however the grid
line is still
you know a problem so you need a
directive you need a option to control
the grid lines
okay uh what's going on
so what
what's going on with the
it's not going back not
okay there there is a there's a
there's a bug either with windows or my
auto hard key
is things up
uh alt space
or space doesn't work oh space i was
hoping
to bring the menu
you see now i cannot shrink the window
that's the problem
that's the problem here
old space doesn't work what is this
ah
even
even windows down arrow doesn't work
so let's save save this okay
sphere save it to desktop okay
save close it okay
now now now open the desktop
it get back to this maxed window i
cannot
get out of
yeah okay close it so now what
can we do to solve this problem we are
going to do surgery
on the file itself so go to desktop
directory
emacs comes to the rescue so here is the
file sphere let's open it up
and let's remove the cache and
cache
okay save it close it now reopening
wufang language
okay there's a windows problem let's do
it again
okay so go all the way down so here
is the internal cache information
you see delete notebook online
delete
okay so close it save it shrink the
window
go to desktop
open it what the
f11 does not work
close it god i must be sure
let's open the emax again see what's
going on with
this box data so this is the
this is the post script information for
the
you know the the the part here you see
that's the
post script
format for the image and uh
and encoded in in
uh encoded in the
in what's the name um
but anyway i want to fix the windows
problem
window size full full okay so delete
that
windows margin delete that windows
magnification
dd that okay save it close it
and we can open in external
open external there it is okay that's a
windows
uh option
okay so we still haven't fixed
the it's
we we still haven't fixed the um
the grid problem so we need to look for
options for the grid
so okay let's let's do that
options at parametric plot 3
d okay
let's see options so here are the
all the possible options for parametric
plot 3d
and we want to look for mesh
functions okay
so what is the option for mesh functions
is an option for plotting functions that
specifies functions to use
to determine the placement of mesh
divisions
okay
so mesh functions it's an option and the
the argument is two functions specify
that
measures corresponding to x and y
coordinates
should be constructed so the first
function
controls the mesh around the
x coordinate
let's see some examples
okay so mesh is a simpler uh
option you see here mesh that
specifies how many meshes to draw so
let's just try that
let's say 9 do it
there it is
now let's say instead of 9 let's say
three
and five do it okay
so the first element
is the horizontal lines the number of
horizontal lines so if we
say 30 you see that's
we don't have a problem with that the
problem is the vertical lines you see
it's uh it's missing a line
so here instead of five let's say six
okay that doesn't help let's say 20
you see that doesn't help neither so the
problem
i kind of know what's the problem the
problem is that
when you have the parametric
uh surface the problem is with the
you see this is a place where the
parametric
uh start and end position collides
so
in order to fix that we can
you know we can either overlap it a
little bit
then we um
so again what is v yeah so the
problem is v here so if we say
pi plus pi divided by
10 okay so the vertical mesh
10. yeah you see
now that fix up the problem but however
you can see
there's overlap here and it's actually
more opaque than the rest of it
you see if we say opacity 5
you see there's a particular strip
okay how do we fix this
um jesus a simple thing
this uh i kind of know what's the
problem but
the problem you see the way it the the
old way
this is uh wolfen language 20 years ago
this
is much simpler you don't have this
problem uh but however you can see this
image you can see this image you know
they are just a bunch of polyhedrons
you know each of the square is actually
a polyhedron
but in the current version of wufan
language it's not
just polyhedrons you see so in the old
ufam language
the mesh is simply the edges of the
polyhedron
there's no extra concept of the of the
mesh the grid lines
you know you simply plot each polyhedron
and those are the edges
that forms the grid on the surface
but with advanced uh language
the concept of grid on the surface
and the actual polyhedron forming the
surface is now separate
so the surface is just a surface then
then you can specify what kind of grid
you want on the surface
okay so it's more advanced but however
you run into
into the problem is that
you know it's missing a uh it's kind of
the grid is not
you know it's kind of missing a line on
in a grid
so how do i fix that you know i you know
it's probably
pretty easy to fix that but however i
need to look into
you know i need to read the
documentation like spend 20 hours
i mean 20 20 30 minutes probably to
understand that okay so let's
skip that and let's do something let's
uh
let's let's get on to something else
shall we comments okay
okay but anyway let's let me just use
one of this
image okay let's just use one of these
images so now
let's not say opacity okay opacity 0.95
so we kind of try to fix this
hack okay so pi plus
pi over 10 so let's get it a little bit
overlap and meanwhile
not you know not making or uh
not making it transparent so that you
don't actually see the overlap
so we hack to fix this
okay so now we just determine the
orientation we want
okay
now we export this graphics
save graphics as pdf no
i don't want pdf i want p and p and g
so wolfram language can save pdf png
bmp or web page html
or tiff or other formats
windows meta file and the jpeg
and even pixar whatever that is
let's say png tt sphere okay
save that in desktop okay save it now
another way to capture this image
is just use
capture it manually okay
screenshot let's do both ways and see
which way is better
okay so now we have if you update you
can see here is a saved image open emacs
there it is and we also captured
uh we captured using this program
share x which is a great windows program
for
screen capture okay now let's go back to
the sphere page
okay let's go to the sphere page
make a backup showing browser then let's
start to edit
let's change the
okay let's call this command
that will move the image to
okay now search file directory so here
is the directory
uh surfacesphere
okay so here is the old image close it
close it
save this here
it's going it's trying to optimize the
png file
here shrink showing browser
showing browser there it is now
go to desktop
okay so this is actually the screenshot
we did
now let's try to do the other
okay up to png show in browser
magnify so we have two images
now which is better
uh you see these glitches another
problem
you see these glitches on the sphere
god you see
old mathematica 20 years ago it's
pretty basic but the new one with
anti-aliasing and all that feature but
now you have got
these dirty spots on the ball
anyway now for
to let's take geek about these two
different
image format one is exported for
movement language
the other one is screenshot let's
compare their sizes let's see
which one is better so you can see
so this is old and this is
which one is this form
the first one is screenshot okay so this
is from screenshot let's see
145 kilobytes
okay then the second one is 146
kilobytes
okay let's
come let's put them here okay
so we can have them side by side
are they which one is better
it's about the same
but you have all these spots on the
sphere dirty spots on the sphere no good
so let's remove one of them
okay we don't need and let's copy that
here and the
show
so which one do you think is better
how did you install emacs on windows
with dot exe
or with zip you i downloaded from the
gnu emacs
website so you just you know you just go
to xrd
emacs tutorial where to download
this is where i you know follow the
instructions here that's
how i get uh windows gnu emacs
dot exe uh well it's
if you know what do you mean by dot exe
or dot zip
you know it's uh it's a zip file
you know exe can be zip file or it can
be gz or it can be you know
what do you mean so anyway so that's
where i download
emacs okay so
back to this
oh we already talked for 52 minutes
uh uh and we haven't we only did the
sphere
i want to let's let's go on and do
um i want to i want to do some of the
other
interesting things so this is a
hyperbolic parabola
paraboloid it has this interesting
property where on this surface
for every point on the surface there is
a line
on the surface crossing it so in other
words
this surface is made up in entirety of
lines
you know so you just have lines and you
can form this surface
it's interesting because usually you
don't when you have a surface you don't
have that
you know uh you know you typically you
don't think of that for example
sphere there's no there's not even one
single line
on the surface
so but this is one of them you know so
this kind of surface
where the entire surface can be
generated by moving a line
is called root surface r-u-l you know
it's like a ruler ruled surfaces
and there's a wikipedia article on that
so
this is a rural surface this is also a
ruled surface you can see
and you can see many baskets made out of
this
uh thing foaming the surface so in one
way it's just
lines but but if you look
looked at it from the traditional way
you see if you look at this surface you
don't think of it
as lines but it actually is so
we have many architectures and towers
made of you know
forming this surface by by having lines
underneath
and then here's the funny gear uh gear
okay gear for
a black axis uh
okay you know my pages all these pages
are pretty old
uh like 20 years old it was bleeding
edge
20 years ago but today you you can find
a lot
better websites doing these things for
example this
you know do it yourself uh print 3d toy
you can find this
print 3d you know model to
print it yourself
and this is second life it's a second
life is amazing okay
so there's a lot of mathematic
mathematics in second life
so anyway so this is another rule
surface
uh and you can see
okay so all right uh
i'm just like talking about some
random math stuff because
like taking a break
so here you can see the
the what is this power station
uh you know their chimney
those smoke are not
smokes those are steams
you see uh okay it's much
you know actually lots of repetition
here
so anyway that's why i want to update my
website
to make them modern now and i was hoping
to
do many of these in javascript okay
so back to
uh back to
wolfram language let's plot let's plot
this okay
so this is gonna be more than one hour
let's go to talk show today's talk show
and paste it here link and
i want to
oh let's we need to put
the formula for this
so let's copy the formula
copy it go back to the page
where this is go back to the page
and
oh there's a mathematica file there okay
so
actually
okay let's do this one okay there's a
there is an equation
for the sphere let's try that as well so
okay we don't need that we don't need
that so let's try to plot that
let's go back to fram language now we
are going to plot
con plot these okay how do you do that
i believe it's contour plot
okay
yeah why does it not complete
yeah let's just type it
much better in in uh emac lisp
so x from
x mean y max x x mean x max
so we have a equation of
three variables or function of three
variables uh
you want to
oh yeah so x y z those are
those are what values or region produce
a three-dimensional contour plot
of function as a function of x and y and
z
so x and y and z are values let's just
try it okay
zero two two okay
let's just see what happens
okay that's not so good let's say
[Laughter]
this is what happens if when you do not
exactly understand what
what you are doing
i'm not exactly understand what am i
doing just
trial and error and this is the fun part
of using muffin language
as well and learning mathematics okay
here
we got kind of the
uh contour plot okay
so so we can see a sphere so this is
much more beautiful
so we need to understand what this
function do so
let's try the other way okay so the
other
the other way
is to say that
f equals to g okay so here
plus a contour surface for which f
equals to
g right so f equals to g
so that will be equals to one let's try
this
okay yeah okay so
instead of so negative two to two
okay so what is what kind of thing is
this
it actually should be one
two one okay it's kind of funky
okay so we got we got the sphere we
wanted
okay let's copy that let's let's just
copy these
so where is the image
okay i i want to i want to put all
images
in a directory i okay should i okay
that's not
let's just put the images in the
directory without a
extra directory okay
there there you have it this is your
image
okay now let's put the equation below
them
so here is the way you plot it copy it
there it is and
okay now it looks better
now this old image let's delete it
gun
okay let's open this mathematica file
z z zip file okay let's show the
directory
so here is a zip file we gonna unzip it
in emacs let's do it unzip
okay done open it now it generates a mac
os
you know mac os directory that's a crap
delete that and remove all this
backup files delete them and
so here is a notebook now
this zip file we don't need open it
delete it okay now this is the woofing
language file
20 years old let's open it
open external okay so you can see
this is done in 2005 okay
continue with updated styling yes okay
so it requires a package
contours okay parametric formula
so what what formula was i using let's
double check
so this is a bitmap image or actually
it's a postscript image
so you see we were talking about how in
oh lufan language the grids on the
surface
is simply the edges of the polyhedrons
the poly polygons not polyhedron so
cosine cosine sine sine
sine so it's using um
yeah it's using the formula i was using
okay this notebook we can delete it
so computer graphics methods of
generation okay
in my old writing style i'm kind of
being
verbose computer graphics method of
generation
uh
so actually yeah we forgot wolfram
language actually has
a sphere function by itself so you don't
actually need to plot a sphere
i forgot
sphere is a s-p-h-e-i-e
is a wufam language primitive by itself
so we can look at the documentation
you see yeah i forgot how idiotic i've
been
so that's all you have to do in order to
generate the sphere okay
so let's do it again
paste it here do it yeah so but
but this this sphere is so
perfect such that you don't recognize it
as a sphere anymore
you know it's just a color wheel or
something like that
so this is interesting you know this
gets us to many interesting issues about
illustration
so even though this sphere is
technically superior because
it's technically as far as computer
graphics
is involved it's more accurate it's more
smooth it's more perfection
with respect to you know all the
properties
of sphere but however first of all it's
not
recognizable as a sphere you rather you
more see it as a
circle you know a circle a color circle
something like that
especially without if if without the
bounding
box but however if you see this
image or this image immediately as human
animals human visual system you see it
as a sphere
and our job you know typically in math
content
context we want to illustrate sphere to
for people to learn math right so
so this is not so good we actually need
we need to put on grids okay so
again so here we need to look at the
options of a sphere
okay sphere doesn't have options yeah so
now we need to look at
uh there is also a function of ball what
the
so there is also a building function
represents the unit ball centered at
point p so what's the difference between
ball and sphere
a ball is known as center in turbo oh
oh okay a ball is known as center
interval
disc ball and hyper ball okay so
from this description i gathered the
function ball
in wolfen language is more it's more
about
about geometry why why
the sphere function in language is more
about
computer graphics to illustrate a sphere
okay
right so if you are doing mathematics
you know you might need to use the ball
to represent a
inter interval in 2d or 3d or 4d or 5d
you know so on
five dimensions uh
so bo is added in 2015 okay
now sphere
is added in 2007.
okay yeah so you see sphere is a
computer graphics
uh related thing it's more
commonly needed while the ball thing
the ball function is more mathematics
mathematical oriented
it's added seven years ago 2014.
so we are talking about you know partial
differential equations and so on this
sphere so let's let's look at a sphere
okay
so come back to our question for my
purposes of generating an
illustration for sphere you know there's
a question
which way to generate the sphere using
wufam language is the best approach
and my guess is actually you know use
the building sphere function
all we have to do is actually add the
grid lines but do we
but do we have options for grid lines
for graphics 3d i don't know so let's
check so you know we need to read a lot
of wolfram documentation okay so
you know so that's i recommend wufang
language you download it for free
and why because
you know if you want to write this kind
of thing in in javascript in any
language
you know opengl that's going to be 100
or more lines 200 lines
if especially if you want this if if you
want to plot a contour plot
that's going to be thousands of lines if
you want this kind of grid on it
in language it's just one single line
you know or
depending on how you count the lines so
this is can be a single line or you
count it as two lines or three
uh you know a single line of code
so yeah
so it's great so so now let's look at
how do you
uh
let's see options for graphics 3d
you know there are so many you know and
it's been a while
i looked at them you have to actually
study them
if you really want to control your
graphics
so graphics 3d the following primitives
can be used okay the following graphics
direct
directives can be used so you have
absolute dashing
thickness arrowheads
uh you have
glow you actually have glow gray level
hue
opacity specularity
thickness inline thickness specification
uh and uh okay there are so many
here i don't think there's an option for
grid
so let's go back to sphere so there is
no option for sphere
right
yeah option sphere is empty
so there is no option for sphere but how
do you
what if i want grids
so wufang language sphere function
actually plots a sphere
in arbitrary dimensions
now i'm not sure exactly what does that
mean because
you you know in order to represent the
sphere
in more than three dimensions you
usually have to do some kind of
projection or cross-section
so as far as i know there is no such
function that does
there's no building function to view
higher dimensional graphics
in wufang language maybe there is i
don't think so
okay sphere can be used in graphics and
graphics 3ds in graphics the point
scale and dynamic expression
oh okay so graphics rendering
is affected by directives such as
phase form specularity opacity so what
is the
phase form
okay phase form is maybe face form is
the one we use
to control
there let's try that
no didn't work
edge form
so sphere doesn't have any edges and
doesn't have any faces that's why they
it does not work
scope graphics
specification
styling no yeah styling okay it's only
got colors
so it's funny you know so yeah you got
all these stylings but none of them
you know looks like a sphere like the
way
we want it you just got this color ball
like disc
okay so i think i have determined
now that if you use wufang language
if you oh this simulates moon over
rotating around earth you see
so i have determined that if you want to
plot a sphere using wolfram language
for illustrated illustration purposes
you cannot use the building function
sphere to do it
because if you do want the grid lines on
the sphere
uh you know this function doesn't
doesn't allow you
doesn't give you that option
so here so yeah so you know how do i
know because you read
the documentation for the whole thing
so here what is this one
you know it's interesting
okay
applications oh a bunch of a bunch of
kind of ugly thing
so i suppose this is what is this
uh platonic polyhedra
represented by spheres okay this is kind
of ugly
you know in the early days computer
graphics you have lots of this kind of
thing
extremely ugly
you know it looks like intestines
okay so can you can you actually
magnify the whole no you cannot
here we have double helix
then we have what is this
then you have molecules
properties in relations yeah okay so i
decided that
it is not possible to
to use the functions uh
sphere and
have grids on the sphere
oh okay so wufang language gives gives
you a
example of a sphere using parametric
plot
just like we did uh now
it would be interesting to look at what
parametric uh
what parametric formula are they using
you know so we can compare nodes
you know this is our this is our
original it's ugly
let's see what they did
mention them i don't want to mention it
let's see their version
okay same problem
you see they got the same problem as we
missing a gridline
you see so you are looking at the way i
do things you know i look at these
details i'm
first around all these details of things
you know so this is their official
documentation and they are doing it to
illustrate measurement
but however you know
they they they don't have an example
showing how to use up the gridline
problem
okay so more molecules okay so sphere
one of the great use of the sphere
function
is to represent molecule structures
perfectly you see in this case you don't
want grid lines on the on the on the
sphere on the balls
okay no comments no comments i'm going
to so i'm just gonna i'm gonna start to
do
uh next thing so i'm just this is gonna
be
one hour or two hours let me just i need
to work on this
so
so let me just uh actually i do want an
example of the sphere here
let's see yeah if you turn off the box
it's even it's not
you know it's less uh comprehensible
so you do on the box
yeah i'm not going to have that okay
i'm not going to include that so this is
what we're going to have
now for now
okay let's do the next one so we've done
sphere
save these let's do the next one let's
do
this one okay and let's clean up
this um
yeah our notebook yeah on old notebook
let's look at that
so here is another way by projecting
okay let's continue with this okay let's
this way is by projecting polyhedron
uh let's see if we can do that
polyhedra is a package like 20 years ago
it's obsolete
they have a body i by now i think this
will do it
no geode set is not a type of graphics
okay
uh okay let's try to do this this will
take another
20 minutes
so data the data coherent
there it is
so basically we want to
we want to project the
okay so let me explain how do you do
this okay how do you do this image
you start with a dot cohedron
then for each surface of the data
cohesion each phase
you divide it into five triangles
then for each triangle you subdivided
into
three sub-triangles so
let's let me get let's get get fancy and
let me show you okay
and where is it
so using this pen
so you divide it into triangles one two
three four five
and for each triangle you draw a point
in the middle of the triangle you
subdivide it
so same thing here okay
same thing here
same thing here same thing here
okay and you can continue the process
so again for each each triangle you
subdivide it
like that
for and this one here and this one
here so
once you have that then
for each vertex of the
of the triangle you project it into the
sphere
then then you you know then then
then you got this uh surface okay we can
do this
you know with uh you know this is 20
years old code we can do it
now by using building functions and
it will be just one single line but i
don't
remember you know i don't know how to do
it i have to look
and this will take me 20 minutes about
so why not let's do that
comments no comments
okay i'm just gonna code myself
so first
we want to look into the data cohesion's
documentation
okay
actually a better method yeah i made a
mistake actually the better method
is not okay
you know you can either use a dota
cohedron to begin with or you can use a
isocohedron to begin with
so i think isoqua ketran looks like that
but anyway the what i'm looking for is
to
triangulate uh
triangulate the surface of the
of the dark cohesion okay
let's look
okay this is gonna take me a long time
this is going to take me 20
20 minutes to read about all these
so what i want to do
i want to generate these graphics
uh and in order to do that let's see
okay it's a bitmap image in order to do
that
you know like i said i'm gonna
the way i did this one is to
uh geodesia
geodc8 yeah to break the
break break the face into triangles
then
then project them onto a sphere now what
is the function to do that
let's see polyhedron data uniform
polyhedron
okay that's so i i need to read about
polyhedra
polyhedron collection of polyhedron okay
let's just look at that
polyhedron coordinates alter polyhedron
in a polyhedron cube dot cohesion iso
accusation octahedron blah blah blah
hexahedron
hexahedron is just a cube
oh okay so regular hexahedron is a cube
so but the hexahedron function in
language actually represents a generic
generic hexahedron so it needs not to be
a cube
it can be any you know cuboid basically
uh canalize hexa
polyhedron so what does this do
inner boundary outer boundary
okay i'm getting tired actually so
polyhedra let's see
polyhedra
so back to polyhedron let's see what
else they say
uh mesh region random polyhedron
polyhedron data simplex so let's see
mesh region what does mesh region do
oh here we have something similar what
we wanted
so what is this rendering feature themes
affect the rendering of meshes themes
include
large mesh optimized for large
number of cells
what is this mesh region mesh region
yields a mesh with cells that where
coordinates given as integers
i am finding taken uh
oh there it is triangulate mesh you see
this is what we wanted
triangular mesh generates a
triangulation of the
mesh region mr
so mesh region is a particular object
a entity now i don't quite understand
what
exactly is a mesh region
with respect to the wolfram language
okay so so here is a example so you can
apparently you can
the triangulate mesh function
can generate a triangulation for you
of a mesh region
now what exactly is a mesh region i
don't know
yet but basically it's basically a
rectangular patch or triangle something
like that
uh so boundary mesh region so
okay so it allows you to do this
kind of computational geometry
triangular mesh it's fantastic
so now knowing there is this function
where you can generate
a mesh arbitrarily you see
now we revisit the way we uh
you know this one the way we did it here
is by a regular means
breaking a triangle into a smaller you
know three triangles and into smaller
three triangles
these results you know this way
is not necessarily ideal because then
you get a triangle that's thinner and
thinner so it's you know
like very thin triangle
but if you do it this way it could be
better
so triangular mesh and you know maybe
you want some way to make it regular
of course we can also do it ourself by
yeah okay okay okay there's a problem
with uh
let's see f11 does the f11 don't work
no f12
what is f12
okay i think there's a bug okay so i
think there's a bug with the
windows
let's try again f12 yeah
it doesn't respect your
windows so well oh that's probably
because i have the
windows taskbar on top
you see this is a problem of doing you
know
this is a problem in in software in
software industry
you have you know you you you have a
problem you see my problem is that the
windows sometimes it goes out of the
place
i cannot access to the
window spa or you know to to manipulate
manipulate the window size and alt space
sometimes doesn't work you know we ran
into that problem earlier
and then now it turns out
you know it's possibly because i was
using auto hard key
so because you don't know where is the
problem for example let me show you my
auto hotkey
where is my so this is all hotkey let's
qualify it
okay so here's my autohotkey file and
i have a function that toggle maximize
window which is fantastic because
because it's unlike the normal toggle
the normal on windows you press f11
you don't see the tab tabs and all the
other things anymore so for example if
i'm in a browser
press f11 you don't see all those
switches but you actually
you know it's better if you do so you
can see all the tabs
so this is auto hard key so but now i
run into a problem in
from language i don't know if it's maybe
cost like auto hotkey or it's
something but maybe now i'm thinking
maybe it's because of the
because i have the windows bar the
um
[Music]
the taskbar
on top so wufam language you know the
mathematica application gets confused
let's see if this works now
okay maybe maybe yeah that's why
let's do it let's see
so so here's another lesson the
complexities of the software
industry
the complexities of software industry so
you think oh i can make the taskbar on
top
but then you got problems you got all
these glitches
okay so uh let's see
okay so now i'm going to continue
uh i'm going to continue work on this
yeah i'm just going to continue read
about mesh
maybe maybe that's it for today so
i need to do a lot of readings about the
mesh in order to
in order to do this
using the latest you know wolfram
language functions
yeah that's it thank you guys for
watching bye
you