going live
i'm alive good morning everyone welcome
to another episode of talk show
and today we are going to do emac list
coding
emacs in general so if you have
questions
uh post it okay post comments and
if you have a question for me post my
name to it today today is 2021 august
3rd
and we are going to do emac this so
today is going to be nothing but emac
this
emacs and emacs
stuff in general i want
i wanted to show you some of the
fantastic graphics we did
in wufang language in the past few days
okay
some of the fantastic things we did
you know in the past week
so okay emacs let's let's focus on emacs
this we did yesterday fantastic
okay so emacs so what we're gonna do
first of all i'm going to give you
uh i'm gonna tell you about what's going
on
uh join discord join mike saudi discord
if you haven't already
so okay so let's go to emacs
so emacs what have i been done in the
past
uh weeks so i updated a lot of my
packages you can go to uh star emacs
packages i updated many of the
screenshots for example
let me show you some of the some of the
great ones okay emac
side emac list mod so you can see on the
left is xsa imagly smart
syntax coloring every build in symbol is
syntax colored
and colored differently by their type
okay on the right side you are seeing
gnu emax lisp mod which
does not color okay so that's my kind of
because i want to fix that so the
that that is why i created some emacs
list mod okay
so you might be smart javascript mod
javascript mod is uh
fantastic again syntax colored by the
keywords
uh by all the words in the language and
if it's not colored that means that word
is not built in okay and the color
differently
according to their type for example uh
for example attributes i mean you know
uh in terms of programming language the
jargon
is uh building
symbols and well okay anyway anyway
syntax color okay
so perhaps parameter names uh wait
anyway so that's such javascript mod the
most
this is most suitable if you are coding
pure javascript okay
no no npm no libraries super javascript
uh this is fantastic okay
so javascript mod and math input mod i
updated the screenshot
so you can see all the you know for
example if
i want to type some let's
let's magnify the oh i don't have the i
should
create a key so if i type if i want sum
i just press that key if i want offer
you know if on pi if if i want gamma
okay that's gamma and capitalize okay
you can
copy paste and capitalize
capitalize capitalize and this is a
greek capital
alpha okay uh it appears the same as uh
english a so this is english a latin so
you can
describe key describe character describe
character you can see the name
latin capital letter a and if you
describe character on that
then you got greek capital letter alpha
okay so
this is uh some math input mod and you
can also have emoji okay you can
i forgot what's the shortcut for emoji
but
for example let's do this command okay
so
so d is that cmd
is yeah cmd is the uh
keyboard mag keyboard command symbol
okay uh let's see helm
helm is the this helm is the hindu
religious symbol helm you know it's like
a helm
you know because it's a dharma wheel
it's a wheel of life okay hindu
religious symbol and this symbol this
symbol happens to
also be used uh as a standard i believe
it's
iso standard for control key
so ctrl key okay we are
we are getting into uh some
random topics but let me show you okay
so unicode you can see
search for unicode site unicode you can
find my unicode page
then let's go to keyboard okay let me
show you this
is very interesting topic so you on this
page you see
all the symbols they are used for the
keyboard labels
for you can see let's go down so you can
see all the and i
include photos you know the windows logo
key the windows
microsoft keyboard they use a particular
symbol for control key
which is looks like an asterisk
okay so you can see then there's symbols
for zooming zoom out for
uh photon camera for documents for
caplock
and you know you can see you know the
study
the study of symbols on keyboards
symbology unit and unicode okay and on
the mac you can see
the helm symbol is used here and this
symbol is also sometimes used on
uh on by linux documentation they'll use
this
sometimes occasionally and there's old
key there's uh
uh you know so the study of keyboard
symbols okay
and uh back let's go back okay so copy
that copy that url back to emacs close
this page
go to uh go to talk show today's talk
show let's paste
in the topics we talked about so paste
it linkify
so show in browser this is what we are
going to do today
comments questions it's all greek to me
celtic orthodox hello
himasu hello are you japanese
himasu himanshu
and justin scaffide the mathematician
from
canada uh say something justin i
haven't seen you for a while just just
think so the mathematician
the professional mathematician from
canada you are
are you a professor yet are you a
assistant professor or some
some kind some type of professor
so uh so say it okay adjusting if you
still here
so we talked about yeah emacs
uh i'm i'm talking about some of the my
emacs packages
so you can up you can download it for
free of course
and the free us in free beer also us
in freedom you know the
gnu ideology communism basically
so css mod is also a css mod okay so
we are going to work on css
uh some emac list coding on css today so
you can see this is my
css mod again the salient feature
the feature i mean of course it's my
my code so i did i do i designed the way
i
see the way i judge it is the best
again one of the salient feature which
is that all keywords are colored
that is built in css words if it's not
clear that means you spelled it wrong
okay
so that's one of the uh feature and also
they are colored by the type the
semantics of the words for example the
blue
for example you can let's see if we can
mark let's go to let me show you a real
one okay
so indian ho himasu
okay you are indian is that the indian
name of japanese name
maybe it's an indian name okay so
here is my my website's css file so you
can see
there are 195 uh lines which is pretty
uh pretty pretty com pretty small okay
as compared to most other website
wikipedia or
uh mainstream websites their css file is
like
over a thousand lines okay so this is my
css file and this is
colored according to css mod okay let's
shrink
um let's magnify okay well i want to
show you the
okay let's copy that and and
create a new buffer and paste it here
and now i'm going to show this in
in in
in in emacs css mod
okay which is the default so you can
kind of see the difference
so emacs css mod okay
it's just css smart
okay so this is the emax css mod versus
um okay let's see
so let's split let me show you this
three the buffer and switch
to untitled so on the right side
so okay hold on a second so let's make
them the same
size the font the same size okay
so on the left side is css mod on the
right side is the
um gnu emacs css mod
now i want to tell you you know the gnu
imax css mod here on the right side okay
now i want to tell you some some uh some
difference for example you can see
this nav back some id random string okay
so that's
that is not a keyword in css you know
that is
attribute name in my html so it's
colored black
on the other hand in gnu you know the
default emacs css smart that's just
all blue so i consider that a
advantage you know uh css mod so let's
go down a page let's go down a page
then here you can see lots of the other
you know the black you know those are
attribute names those are not part of
css
so okay that's a difference okay so
close that don't save
shrink it make it one window actually
close this window
and and uh close this window we don't
need it
and go back to this window close that
back to talk show show it okay close it
okay we talked about that uh so
so csa smart okay uh
yeah that's what i'm going to that's
you know and plus it has other features
such as
a brief templates so you can so okay let
me demonstrate okay
so open css again magnify let's say you
want
uh you want all dive
stuff to be colored red so type dive
and bracket then c
space becomes color space again it
becomes red okay
so this is let's say font font family
okay ff space then you got from family
and space again
you got kind of a template so you can
choose between you know you can
choose between uh sans serif or
monospace
and also notice these three
fonts okay aerial consoles and mellow
these are carefully chosen you know
after hours
days of research uh for example if you
want to send serif
the the most popular common across
platforms fund is aerial
and what if you are on a mac well mac
happens to actually contain aerial as
well
but what happens if you are on linux
well in the linux case area is
proprietary you know microsoft stuff
actually
you know font is another typography is
another great topic i talked about many
times in my video
in fact the the uh aerial is actually a
clone
of max helvetica okay
now i i did a talk show about that um
let's see sardi typography
okay so yeah
donald gruth steve jobs and the idiocy
of typography
let's turn on javascript so you can see
my previous talk show
uh we i talked about this many times
okay
so you can see helvetica okay have
helvetica is like a kind of a cult uh
the found helvetica is kind of a code
font
you know in the typography society
community
so they they they talk it to like how
helvetica is all important anyway
so ariel is actually a clone of the
helvetica because helvetica is
copyrighted by mac you know
so you know they have to fight each
other
they clone you know just like open
source they clone you know because
selfish reasons human human animals
including the open source and free
software
phonetics so
ariel is actually a clone of helvetica
so what does it
mean a clone well technically they
designed
they redesigned everything so it's from
the ground up it's not
actually a copy but what do they
actually copy well
they actually copy what's called the
metric
you know in front community is called
metric compatibility
meaning that if you use helvetica or if
you use use
ariel they pretty much look the same
essentially means their height you know
the lowercase height
the vertical case height is the same
font size is the same
if you have font size up so anyway so
area is a
kind of a clone of helvetica okay now
what what if you are on linux
well linux also have a clone
okay it's called um
liber liberation or something you know
the the the open source fanaticism you
know they
they have it the name liberation or
something so let's
you know i have a lot of lots of
articles on font okay
speaking of that let let me show you i
want to mention
uh if you don't know css
oh i was wondering why why is some of my
color become red
you know i that's not in my uh css well
because
well because actually we just added
there
you know actually so we should remove
this i don't want that there so
you know let's refresh and you'll see
the red gun okay
yeah so just search for
saudi css you'll find my css tutorial so
if you don't know nothing about css this
is a great tutorial okay
covering from basics uh tag matching
and selector syntax uh in the entire
selected syntax is covered here
including some of the esoteric advanced
uh
ones then units then color you know
color is and there's also javascript you
can change
uh you know you can use the color wheel
and
uh okay you need to turn on css i mean
you turn
javascript okay refresh
so change your color let's say
green uh the value is wait why is it not
showing
wait my javascript is broken what
ah okay we need to fix that what
what the what the heck
okay let's digress let me fix that so
open the this file css color search for
javascript
okay uh so
so html input color javascript okay so
open that
so wait so what is going on so this
is the file ts um
did we forgot to compile
let's see the javascript let's make a
backup so
color picker x uh display box x
okay so now let's compile the
typescript i think okay press
so how do you compile so the the emacs
command
star type script compile file okay let's
do that
do it okay successful okay
let's see okay successful so it becomes
that
so now let's refresh the page
it's not showing the value the value
should show here i mean the hexadecimal
okay
so let's fix the code what is going on
okay so press f12 to get to the
javascript console
okay type error cannot read property add
event listener
of no
cannot read property at event listener
of new so open that
color picker x
so color picker x
what
so get document element by id
color pico x
so any comments hey emily good morning
emily hello from
amsterdam
hey haven't you seen you for a while
uh
i found you through your emacs blog
tutorial was great thank you
thank you himanslu himanshu
okay so we are trying to fix
this javascript this typescript file a
digression uh
should be pretty easy okay but let me
just let me do this quickly so
so we got so color so let me okay
so since i'm doing javascript let me
also explain so
the color picker part is
that label full color picker okay so
this is the color picker one okay
oh we got id incorrect ah [ __ ]
yeah you see we got color picker one
here
but in the typescript we got color
picker x
so stupid me
i sometimes edit my files and change you
know rename things
so that is why that is why
it got [ __ ] up so let's change this to
color picker x
okay and color picker x
okay and the display box
the display box should be display box x2
okay so showing browser again
now you see now you see the color
value so let's change it to something
green
okay did it did it
update okay so
let's say that
yeah it did update but it's blocking
this
okay you can see it's updated as i move
you know this
is this this is this is part of my
feature of javascript okay yeah so
if you don't do javascript well it will
not update interactively so anyway
so i got fixed this page now
press the key to update the last updated
you see the
last updated april 22nd so press a key
show in browser august 3rd
we updated that okay so back to
uh my talk about my css tutorial so
if you don't know css check it out okay
so
you got color names you got hsl color
okay so you see
so you can change the hue you can change
the saturation
all dynamic you know update as you type
because you adjust this
uh in random colors okay
you can see opacity illustration of css
opacity
you can see then there's a linear
gradient javascript again
rainbow random random random
number of colors let's say let's say
three random random random
number color seven random random random
okay
now direction okay random direction
random direction you can see
it direction changes you know it's kind
of rotate
random direction random color fantastic
okay that's that's css linear gradient
then you have radial radial gradient so
random random random
uh center let's see circle elisp
random random so these are the
parameters okay
then you then you you know i talk about
font
uh common web font these these fonts are
compat
are available in most platforms okay
so you know before we were talking about
font compatibility you know area what
does it
what if you don't have aerial on linux
well
on linux you have you know so on this
page i discuss
basically the most popular and basically
i talk about the font names you should
know about
okay so courier so so uh liberation okay
so you see
so when you choose ariel on the mac
it's compatible to helvetica on the mac
but actually mac also has aerial because
mac is a commercial entity apple
they they paid microsoft so that apple
will also
have the aerial fund exactly but
alternatively they can simply use
helvetica
then the two looks is almost exactly the
same
but on linux so you have liberation
sense you know the open source spirit
they
they also cloned it then
google you know google the empire the
empire google empire they think around
oh we need a clone too they created uh
aroma okay so how do i know this well
days and days of research reading
wikipedia that's what i do every day
for the past 20 for the past 30 years
you know before there's wikipedia
i read encyclopedia obsessively
like every day i go to the library so
there used to be
britannica and encyclopedia
americans uh glorious encyclopedia
in fact if if you just search for the
inside cloudpedia i have like five
articles
talking about uh encyclopedias very old
articles okay
encyclopedias my experiences technology
for knowledge in past 20
uh in the past two decades okay i have
quite a few
uh articles on essays on
encyclopedia so let me show you a few
so encyclopedia my experiences okay this
is a gorilla
academic american encyclopedia this is
actually my
my favorite encyclopedia in the 1990s
okay
it's illustrated you know i read a lot i
read tons of it
i read i read encyclopedia every day you
know so in the 1990s
before wikipedia this you know these so
i also bought i'm the first one
in 1993 when the cd-rom
technology came out you know cd-rom you
know the fact that
the hard disk space is 40 megabyte okay
40 megabyte the most biggest hard disk
well almost the big you know the the the
expensive heart is 40 megabytes
that's 1993 around there okay
or 80 meg by 1993 it's probably 80
megabytes okay
hard disk the high-end hard disk
then cd-rom technology came out you know
where the blg
bioga will say we you know cd cd-rom
it's amazing you know thin disk
it contains 500 megabytes oh my god five
times
ten six times more than your hard disk
you know cd-rom technology
so yes so so okay so that's
so so that's uh uh wait
what happened uh i want to reopen that
go back yeah go back to my encyclopedia
article so
anyway so i talked about encyclopedia
then i i'm the first one when the cd-rom
came out i'm the first one to
buy it 550 which includes
the includes the you know
uh unlike the digital version of the
greatest american encyclopedia you know
i'm the first one to buy it in 1993
550 then later on 2004 i bought
i actually i paid and bought microsoft
in qatar
you know wikipedia began around 2002
for the first five years you know
there's no you know it's pretty
not good you know very few articles and
they are just
dribbling mostly by open source
phonetics and programmers
you know and also in the beginning in
the first five
years of wikipedia whenever they mention
microsoft or apple
whenever they mention microsoft okay
they'll just bad mouth it oh microsoft
is
evil company you know that's that's the
state of wikipedia
the first five years in the two in the
2000s
so anyway microsoft back then have
incarda but
pretty soon about you know five five or
ten years
after wikipedia basically it killed all
other encyclopedias
and also for good reasons too because
you know for my judgment you know i uh
i would you know if you believe me from
my
fair observation wikipedia
after 10 years is truly superior
than basically all others even
including britannica okay but in the
past five years
wikipedia went kind of bad again because
the social justice you know lots of
lots of fake news you know fake fake
stuff on wikipedia
you know propaganda you know the by the
mainstream by the powerful mainstream
such as
you know mainstream people enterprises
establishments
you know nonprofit organizations they
all change they'll try to uh
you know change wikipedia and also let
me
tell you that about about a year ago
google and also google and the other
companies
uh search engines started to not
show wikipedia as much you know before
every
almost everything you search wikipedia
will be the top entry in google search
but not
but beginning about last year it's
google started to not to do that
not do that so anyway here's my few
articles about
encyclopedia and here's a technology for
knowledge in past two decades okay
so my articles uh then the hard
you know one of them the heart of
wikipedia why is wikipedia successful
okay
you know if you are young you may not
know
when wikipedia began there's lots of
you know many nerds are actively against
wikipedia you know
because they they they have especially
the unix
linux kind of people they have a
superiority
you know superior uh mentality you know
when they say
wikipedi when they see wikipedia they
they think oh no that's a
that's not you know that's for stupid
people that's that's done by stupid
people we are the eunuchs people
we are superior we don't talk about unix
on stupid you know
name wikipedia that's the you know
that's the history that's the mentality
of the open source
[ __ ] including especially the most
severe search group is lisp people
lisp programmers including emacs coders
okay
so so when wikipedia began in 2003
you know for the first five years you
know other people contribute to
wikipedia but
when it comes to lisp okay for example
let me talk about programming language
their reaction to wikipedia and let me
talk about the
programming language communities their
reaction to wikipedia okay
so when wikipedia begin 2002 so the
pearl people
the python people the ph people they are
all country contributing you know
you go to wikipedia the pearl on pearl
on python or
or on you know python php
you know all you see basically are the
fanboys okay the fanboys will say oh
pearl is a good you know one of the
great language you know one of the great
the most popular language because this
all that and used by google this
that that that you know python used by
google this that you know they'll say
they'll say
they have a lot articles okay written
basically by fanboys
contributed to wikipedia but back then
when you go to the lease article you can
still verify it today you go to
wikipedia you go to you know let's
search for
let's say wikipedia or python okay so
here is a wikipedia article on python
and let's also uh go to wikipedia
lisp okay so here's a
wikipedia article on list okay now what
you want to do is you go
you want to view history you want to see
the article back in let's say 2005 okay
so you scroll all the way down you
basically you
you um you find the article
written in 2005 okay i'm not going to do
it because it takes a lot of time to
to get to it so you find the
the version of the wikipedia article on
python
and this back in 2005. you'll see that
you know the list
[ __ ] they are the superior beings
in this community they do not contribute
to wikipedia you know to them he's like
oh that's it's
that's for idiots that's for the pearl
php you know those idiots we are
superior we don't we don't
you know if they want to if people want
to learn about this they come to us
you know to to to the this community the
mailing list and so on
and in fact i have article on that but
in particular
so
so if you search for xally wikipedia uh
and disperse okay so um
so this is uh
so i have you know i have hundreds of
articles on this
and yeah and we emacs wiki that's
another you know that's related to um
uh i know where to find article okay so
you go to
you go to um
so you go to my website okay you go to
sar code you go to um
[Music]
netoku anthropology hello justine
say something about how you doing in
mathematics or something
uh netcode anthropology okay so let's
search for
so we have let's search for this okay
search for uh it's not here so let's
search for
okay somewhere somewhere here i don't
remember what's the word to search for
um i can find it okay what is the tech
keycard so let me just read it
what is a tech geeker what is a hacker
hacker versus tech geeker the one true
history of meal
that is the that's that is the supposed
the the
largest flame war on the internet okay
the one true history of
meal okay so let's let's add to today's
talk show so
since we talked about this topic okay
the one true history of male and this uh
netted code anthropology
okay and we talked about
uh why is wikipedia successful okay so
you know i tell you the reasons and
this article about um
the technology of knowledge in past two
decades
hello from saudi arabia fantastic
durkheim durham
so we talked about encyclopedia my
experiences
read encyclopedia is what i do
obsessively
okay so anyway that's a lot
digression so that's so we talked about
python in this community uh yeah so let
me find
actually i do want to find
um the article okay so
neta code anthropology
q of i are considered harmful philosophy
of netiquette old school network
tech geekers vs spammers course posting
and language factions
online posting accountability okay
second life tech geekers and escapism
uh
so i was i'm going to i was going to
find the article where i talked about
how lispers in this community they
kind of distanced themselves from
wikipedia
so so my point is that at that time for
the first five years of
for the first 10 years of wikipedia you
know mostly most 2000s
when you read uh you you know when you
go to python article
or php article or perl you have lots of
great information
but when you go to these articles this
is little information and many
and often incorrect information and the
lisp
the lisp people they refuse to change it
that's the point i want to make okay
that's the point i want to make
you know among you emacs fans you know
you don't know you know you
you live in the emacs this fantasy you
know the community changes you know so
this is part of
history okay so for the first 10 years
that these people they
kind of they do not touch they refuse to
you know to to contribute information
about this on wikipedia
that's also the case on stack overflow
on stack overflow i don't know what's
the case now but the first
for the first five years of stack
overflow
you know when you search for python
questions or php or especially languages
that without a code
you know you have lots of earnest
information people try to
you know answer the question but when
you try to find
when you find the list questions on
stack overflow the first five years
of slack overflow you will find no
information you often
incorrect or people who don't know what
they're talking about
meanwhile the lisp expert the you know
the people who actually code this
every day they kind of they have the
mentality that they don't want to touch
it they they are superior you know
you know that's a that that so that is
what i say that is my
uh criticism of the programming
the hacker cult community or the
the programmers community okay that's
that's
uh i'm trying to tell you okay i hope
i hope that's a good information because
you will not find this kind of
information
almost elsewhere because this is
critical of the community
you know if you say it in this community
or in python you know you say anything
negative
you get you'll get banned okay
so anyway that's a lot of digression
digression into
um encyclopedias okay so now let's go
back so we start to talk about
we we we begin to talk about uh css
then emac this css then css tutorial
then font okay so we talked about
metric compatibility of aerial okay
abrio you know uh helvetica
liberation sense okay and there are also
other
metric compatible fonts for different uh
very popular fonts okay
okay so that is about my uh css tutorial
so
if you like my stuff if you enjoy xa
you know style go read it and also you
know support me
you can buy it you can read the entire
thing offline
so you got javascript in depth which
which also includes
my css tutorial and also
includes um my
html tutorial you know so
pay me okay thank you guys uh
so that is about css so
yeah so yeah i was you know so in the
beginning we were talking about
updates to my packages and we were
talking about css
so one thing leads to another let's go
back to this
my packages yeah okay so that's
uh some of the update my emacs these
packages
and uh so what else have i been doing
in emacs in the past few weeks quite a
lot you know i
updated a lot of my emac list
code and my website okay this is
okay so that's a code update
uh then yeah in the past month i did a
whole lot of talk show about focus on
emac emac these okay in in a you know
in july uh lots of 10 you know
five also pure e-magnesis okay so
so what else uh so
there are some things that's to do for
myself notes
to do uh and more massive tutorial
update okay that's about the
updates so
how long have i been talking 40 minutes
so now let's quote some emac these
comments and questions okay post post
comments
do i make sense of you of those of you
are watching here
do i make sense did i did you see did
did i give you some information you
didn't know before
true or false and or are those
information you find it
surprising like useful or like oh well
you know was it positive
information or you or do you think it's
oh that's
not important you know that's just a
random rant
tell me about it okay
okay so that's about these uh things
okay the next thing let's do some emac
this coding okay
yeah let's do some 10 20 minutes emac
this coding and uh
and that'll be it for today
great hey justine you yes you made sense
great
um true okay fantastic
so let's um now
we go we i only have five people
watching
the poverty of my show
emily hey emily yeah i never realized
about that history with the community
being so
insular yes great great word uh you
proper use of the word insular uh what's
really interesting to find out about
great thank you
so let's do some e-max coding okay so
uh so there's something i want to do
to my css um okay so let's see what
we're gonna do
so i was going to rename a bunch of
commands but
let's not okay because because when you
rename things that's
uh breaks a lot backward compatibility
i'm not sure but
but i do want to rename but let's
i'm gonna do the renaming i'm gonna
think about it and do it offline but now
let me show you what these commands do
and what i want to change
i want to make some enhancements
okay so let's go to css okay so let's
open the sample css file
copy it new buffer paste it okay
actually close it i don't want
here okay paste it save it xs
xx.css so this is a kind of a
temporary file we are going to work on
css
so uh so what so i'm using you know
right now i'm using css mod you can see
in the
mod line okay so what command do i
provide
so press so you can describe
mod okay uh describe mod okay so you can
see
css is an interactive you know blah blah
blah
defined in css mod okay and
uh it's you know the key binding
that is my personal key binding okay to
invoke
invoke the mod the parent mod is prog
mod programmer smart programming
language mod okay
so major mod for css so that's a url
you know open it you know so that goes
to the
okay so key bindings okay so this uh
essentially these are the commands i
provide so let's see
so let's see this one css expand to
multi lines
so you can see right now they are very
compact because
so each line you can see each line is a
kind of a unit for css you know so
kind of a compact so but if you want to
edit this
let's say you know if you want to change
font you know you have to add somewhere
let's say
font family you know then that okay so
you know but sometimes it's already you
know let me show you what this command
do okay so
let's uh let's so let's see what's the
key
okay uh f9e f9 is right under my thumb
okay so let's look okay wait
uh magnify okay so
f9 e so you see now it becomes readable
you see so if i select the whole buffer
code now everything is become
more readable each each attribute is not
on a line by itself you can see
okay so you see so but now if i want to
compact the whole thing again
so what's the key so um let's see
compact
you know um so you call
p f9p okay so
okay that does it to one line that does
it
to another that does it okay
so it it it just works on the current um
kind of brackets okay so but let's
select
all do it okay
so now you can see uh wait
so now you can see it's like that okay
so
let's uh so undo
redo okay so that's uh what this command
do
so what i want to fix is that expand to
multi lines you see
first of all i have to make a selection
first because otherwise it just works on
the current kind of
the css unit so i want to write a
command so
it just do the whole without selecting
all
okay so let's go to um
let's jump to the source code
so expand to multi lines buffer okay so
by the way i'm going to change this i
probably will change all these some of
these command names
uh because
i'm going to you know i probably will
change names so when when you download
my
uh when you download my css mod you may
find you know the the command name will
be different so why do i want to change
the command names because the naming of
things is kind of an
odd okay so for example compact css
buffer okay so
so for example let's select all let's do
e okay so now it's expanded now i can
call compact css buffer
f9 dash okay so it compact the whole
buffer
now so what is the naming kind of art
because
i was i'm thinking of renaming this
compact css buffer to
css format compact okay so
like i talked about in talk show so
let's go to talk show
uh so here so you see
i want to change it to format compact
why because
when you have the name the word format
then people understand what it is
okay it's kind of more general because
what you are doing is actually reformat
the thing
so for example in golan you know the
gold language you have a building tool
called go format
okay fmt go fmt
for example i can show you which go
format
okay so you can see that's from golan
and in deno the javascript compiler deno
also has a deno format okay so which
they know okay
they know um you know so
they know help okay let's see if that
demo help
so you can see search for format you see
you see then i also have a command
option format
format source code so the word format
for the command for many so that's
that's kind of common okay so
so i kind of have a decision to make
when you write this command should it be
compact css re
compact css region this is this
this naming scheme is more direct
you know this for uh you know this uh
pro and cons you know advantage and
disadvantage
you know it's there's no one absolute
answer
but if i use the format compact word
it's kind of more general it's kind of
possibly easier to find i don't know so
that's why i say
the naming of things is an art and also
it's quite
important because it's very important
the naming of things because for example
let's consider bash shell you know the
unix tool bag
bash commands ls cat okay
let me show you my articles okay let's
go to
uh so naming of things so we were
talking about naming of things so first
of all let's go
write it down
talking about naming of commands
naming of things okay so for example
let's go to unix
my linux tutorial okay everything you
wanted to know about unix
so you can so you have
you know the unix bash commands ls
cd pwd esoteric every each one of them
is touch
touch i'm gonna touch you touch
rm rm cp
make mkdir you know mkdir
rmdir mv d u
cat v i v head
tail you know so that's a unix tradition
you know they like that way so
naming of things so so let me talk about
naming of things okay
and and this relates to programming
jargons okay so
so let me so let me show you another
my articles okay first of all let's uh
paste it okay so let's let me show you
so you go to you go back to my linux you
go to my website
you go to the home page of the dot info
then you scroll down then you go you'll
see
a complete set collections of essays
jargons of software industry okay
this so naming of things is related to
jargons
okay so you know when programmers use
math jargon such as
git directed a cyclic graph
or haskell monad or http
edm potency or at least homony
i can't see homo iconicity
they don't know what which side is mouth
which side is asked that's the typical
programmers
anyway that's a kind of a digression
into a separate topic
so in this collection our essays i talk
about
kind of jargons and it's it
um it's heavily related to naming of
things so let me
tell you a pros and cons of naming okay
so let's go back to
the linux okay so for example
so the way unix named their commands
okay
you know first of all there's one
advantage
the commands are short convenient to
type
because you have to use this command
every day every minute almost every hour
you know every five minutes you have to
type all these commands so
short names is great for you know it's a
great help
okay that's one advantage but there's
also a disadvantage
associated with that these commandments
are not descriptive
so when you see that's why typically
when you happens when you see your show
you know bash
script what the [ __ ] are they you know
you like you don't know what they
doing you don't bash script cryptic
cryptic
you know so that's a disadvantage
now in comparison now let me show you a
comparison okay
so you go to powershell you know for
example let's
go to powershell and let me log what we
talked about
so powershell so let me show you some of
the commands okay in powershell
uh powershell the naming of powershell
you can see how they choose their name
okay
so the uh so powershell they decided you
know so they also have the naming issue
which name should we choose we want you
know there are several aspects
the name should be descriptive so that
when you see it your immed your kind of
know
99 of the time exactly what the command
does okay
that's the advantage of naming when
especially when you have long
full names but when you have that you
have a disadvantage you get you know
it's hard to type the [ __ ]
you have to type 10 key strokes to call
command what do you do
so powershell you know the microsoft the
guy
at microsoft who created powershell
around 2003
okay powershell is by by now it's like
15 years old
the first prototype is around 2003. it
was called
it was called um monet
okay powershell the original name for
powershell is
is monad something okay
so so powershell so they how do they
deal the
sound the naming issue okay they want
long names descriptive names
and also they created a scheme so that
every powershell command is 2 the name
is two components
the first part is verb okay so for
example
where object for each object
add something get something set
something clear something okay so
you know compare something copy
something okay so
the name is it has two component
components the first one
the first word is a verb you know it
describes what it
what kind of thing you know it it what
kind of activity it is about
the second part is the is the now okay
so what
it kind it tells you what kind of thing
it works on so so naming scheme okay
but it's a long name so but how do you
solve the typing shortcut problem they
created
they they created a kind of a ada system
building okay so
so so then there's another
question how do you decide which
abbreviation
to use okay
then the way powershell people decided
is that many of the
building ideas is based on you know the
similar command name in unix bash
or or in the command.exe you know the
old
the old terminal uh command line from
windows
so this is so
so what i'm saying is that the naming of
things is a
is is kind of critical and they are
related to jargons for example
scientific jargons
you have jargons in physics in chemistry
in mathematics
how do they choose the jargons you know
there are many aspects
communicate descriptive communication
communication
uh you know and uh
and also connotation and you know lots
of aspect about naming of things
okay so this is one way this this
is the way i'm talking about powershell
so this is
how powershell people they deal with
this issue
on the other hand the unix people i
don't like the unix people they are
you know they are hacker [ __ ] okay
how do they solve this
problem how do the unix people or the
unix philosophy
when it comes to naming of things many
issues you know descriptive
how descriptive the name is you know how
do you um
solve the typing problem you know many
issues about nami
how do the unix people solve it
essentially the unix people
basically everything in unix and c
language
they go by no brain no thinking they are
not designed
you know everything about unix is like
that that's why i
despise very much despise just about
every thing every tool every aspect
every kernel design
and everything about unix okay which
became linux you know unix and
c language it's not like they don't
they don't think okay it's not like they
decided oh
well yeah we we you know like you know
suppose i'm a unix people you know the
30 years ago 40 years ago oh yeah we
know we realized there's a naming issue
but we decided you know
uh you know we decided that for
this or that reasons we want you know
short names uh
you know forget about we we prefer
the show names over readability okay
they
they decided on that no it's not like
that
it's more it's more like they don't they
never thought about the problem
they just at the time 40 years ago 30
years ago well
alex happens to be convenient on this
keyboard 40 years old terminal you know
the
89 by 20 character 24 character
80 columns by 24 characters it just so
happens you know it works it works
it works that's a key word for the unix
and c
design it works it works now oh
that's that's that that is how you got
these command names in unix okay
[ __ ] the unix and the vim too
vi is exactly that way it just happened
to
work you know at that time will you okay
so that is about the naming of things
okay that's uh kind of went into a giant
digression
now
you know it became my one of my angry
rant again is the unix
every everything okay so so now let's
see
do we go back to the coding of the css
smart let's just yeah let's do five
minutes or even
it's still good um so we were we wanted
to code
css we wanted to let's go to star talk
show we wanted to
we want it to
okay we need a version that reformat
multiplies to co her buffer okay so
let's do that
emac this coding okay we also talked
about this okay
cut it let's put it back here somewhere
so we have a kind of a record we what we
talked about
so so that's
uh text so paste it here so that's about
that that is about math input mod okay
so interesting characters unicode
characters
and now we want to go back to this css
right
uh so what is this uh okay close that
with my css
right so
so we want to okay let's let's
go to the source code of this command
because i expand to multi
lines okay open it go like jump to it
so jump to the source code so here is
the command okay
now let's make a copy paste it here
and then we
select it we actually we just call a
command
to narrow to region so that we so all we
see is just this function
so we're gonna name this uh
csx expand to multi lines buffer okay so
this will work on the whole buffer
so all we have to do is actually very
simple is actually just call
that command then buffer mean
uh point mean point
point max okay so
that's all we have to do
so so simple okay so so expand minified
css code to
multi lines for whole
buffer okay that's it
that is it now expand the
you know narrow to region so we actually
we so that's all we have to do
okay so now we need to give it a key so
let's uh give it a key so let's search
for that command
so for now let's just give it a key so
let's copy that and
do that that that that that that what
the key should it be
again the designing of key binding is
another odd so
i don't know which key should it be for
now let's
let it be random okay i so we have
something to
uh some key so i'm going to uh change
them
offline okay that's i think that's it
for today any
comments questions no comments so i
talked for
one hour already so
i think that's it concurrent viewers 11
so now
i have 11 use uh
okay so anything else comments okay
comment
uh and uh so basically i'm we are done
i'm done today for today's talk show
i think next talk show uh i'm gonna do a
wolfram language coding again
so we talked about the naming of things
that's uh
that is one of my great um
did we copy my articles about jargons no
so let's let's go back to it
so let's go to
talk show back to the talk show page
so we talked about linux
linux command names okay then
we jargon yeah so i need to
copy this
uh wait what yeah this uh
okay so actually here okay
so compact so let me show
you know i'm going so this is my
workflow let's compact
this uh this
list id i mean the list
uh so we talked about encyclopedias
we talked about yeah so those are
related topics
so then we we talked about
okay there are there are more emacs
commands i want to do okay so
okay then that's it
so about encyclopedia death of
incarta you know so around 2010
about seven years after wikipedia
so microsoft says that we are going to
shut down in
qatar so microsoft announced it in 2009
you know microsoft to kill encounter
later this year you know
microsoft so wikipedia wong
uh you know on the topic of wikipedia
each programming you know in a nut
community programmers you know they
have
usually very dramatic opinions you know
usually they
many attack it while many embrace
it you know because wikipedia the
foundation the original you know back in
2002 is what is the early days of
internet
it's not like today you have so many
stuff and mostly
you know today in the internet vast
majority is
either you know people just use 10
websites that's
20 websites they are literally
10 000 thousand website there were vast
majority of people
ninety percent of the time they only use
you know basically
twenty websites and they are all just
mainstream
websites google facebook twitter
instagram you know stack overflow you
know that's
that's a situation so 2002
is but in 2002 it's not like that
2002 is the beginning of internet and
back then
it's also it it is also when the open
source
fanaticism begin to a very heavy open
source phoneticism kind of the
concept of uh communism okay so people
are thinking
we should you know they there are some
words associated with that era such as
swam intelligence you know meaning that
the
you know the masses can make actually
create great things actually that's the
result
the result of that is wikipedia okay so
anyway back in 2002 the
mini idea networking effect you know
lots of
keywords you know at that time so people
wanted to
you know so that's why the origin of
wikipedia began by two guys
one is the jimbo whale okay he's he's a
scumbag
i recommend never donate to wikipedia
okay jinba wheel is a skunk
he you know before wikipedia he's he's
running some pong pornography
okay got that pornography he
jimmy whale today is like you know well
you know dressed in entire and
you know giving talks at major
universities or organizations
talking about how great is wikipedia a
vision you know
where human knowledge or you know it's
all free you know
he he he he is running porn websites
he happened to make wikipedia so that's
one of the his way to make money okay
anyway so there's nothing wrong
of running phone website but he hi he
tries to hide that
that is the problem okay also
jimmy wales okay then there's another
guy which is a
vet also a scum he's a very conservative
okay wikipedia founder just search for
i'm gonna i'm not going to show search
for wikipedia founder
there's a wikipedia article on that
which gives you
i believe fair fair uh history of it
okay so two jimmy hey is one of the
founders but there's another guy
who is also a skunk he's a he
i would describe him as a extremist
christian okay
he's a christian he's a you know devote
believers in christianity
but he's an extreme case so in his
opinion anything that's not christian
value
he will go out of his way to you know to
destroy
you basically he's a scum i didn't know
before you know
but but in the past i had some cross
horns with him
so anyway both of them so
so the jimbo whales tries to erase
history you know he's
running from sight and porn says
sightseeing all that he he says
you know he tries to hide it he says he
runs a glamour site you know
occasionally usa
you know when people ask him anyway
but he also tries to remove the fact
that there's another guy who who began
wikipedia with him
in fact i believe that christian guy is
actually
the the more the you know the the kind
of
the more of the original idea okay let's
let's get the names uh up
okay so we can so you see jimmy wales
okay
founders of wikipedia let's go to it
okay there it is
larry sanger jimmy wales
they are about my age they are you know
one is older
one is two years older than me
so jimmy hoyos which is a guy you know
to be the wikipedia founder he's a scum
he you know never never donate to
wikipedia because all your money mostly
goes to his pocket
whenever he give a talk it's like one
hundred thousand dollars you know
and larry sanger is also a scum he's a
extremist christian
okay and jimmy whale tries to erase
history saying that you know he
he don't mention larry zanga much you
know
so anyway that's my take about these two
people
both are skirmish guys
um so what what i was saying so i'm just
going i'm just talking random now
could you talk about accessing deep
b pedia using cell
something in your comment talks no i
don't know nothing about t
d b pedia okay i can't i probably i can
tell you what i can you know i probably
know what is that about
dbpd okay that's kind of open source
thing right
so let's go to what let's see what it is
okay let's see wikipedia okay
dbpedia you know before reading the
article i
you know it's probably some kind of open
source a new open source
group again trying to create a new
wikipedia encyclopedia okay let's see
dbpedia is a project aiming to extract
structured content from the information
created in wikipedia project
okay this structured information is made
available on the world
web db pedia allows users to
semantically query relationships and
properties of wikipedia resources
semantic relationship okay
uh including links to other related data
sets
okay in 2008 tim burnham lee
dbpedia as one of the most famous part
of the decentralized
linked data effort okay yeah i kind of
know yeah
uh it has no future i can tell you right
now it has no future
it's you know it's uh it's you know in
my
the way i would describe it even though
even though i don't know much about it
you know take
about i don't know much anything
concrete or specific about this
project however for my 20 years
experience in the hacker community
especially the open source
you know group of people this is a dead
thing okay it's going nowhere
it's you know every every year every
year the open source people the
phonetics
you know the phonetics uh kind of open
source phonetics they
you know they are going to create every
year you know every few years
they are going to create their own
version of twitter for example
it happens many times they all kind of
died they
all kind of you know very few users
except 10
10 people of these phonetics so every
few
you know they are trying to recreate
twitter open source version
they are trying to recreate stack
overflow okay well not much
that um because stack overflow i believe
it's you know the content is already
open source but anyway
they are you know they are for example
they are also trying to create a
open source clone of the
of the of the
you know discord you know they are
trying to create a open source
you know basically they are just you
know the free software or open source
phonetics
every time they see something on the web
that becomes big and famous they are
trying they
they have a urge you know because they
have a vision they want to create a free
version
you know but they always fail because
they always fail like their product you
know
people forgot you know like today you
know this master then you know
i don't know if you guys still have
heard of it
you know a few years ago it was oh
master then it's gonna you know the new
version of twitter you know the open
source version
and before that there's several
instances you know it's all forgotten
this is gnu something grew network
you know but basically they fail they
always fail because these people
you know they don't you know they are
phonetics so they don't you know
which means they they don't have a
healthy
view of the world of how things work
how reality you know is
but they have what they have is a
ideology driven
view so they you know the open source or
free software foundation phonetics you
know they
they they see the world they they they
truly they
they think that it must be this way it's
so that
you know it's free shared by everyone
okay
that's their vision but they but this
but you know
ideology driven but no not
in touch with reality you know so what
happens when you push
an ideology to the real world that's
incompatible with reality that's you
know that's not how
things works well the result is your
whatever you are pushing doesn't work
you know it dies or it has no effort you
know it
or it creates chaos
it creates misery in the world which is
the case right now
google facebook twitter you know google
is the one who pushed open source
over and microsoft now is the biggest
contributor of open open source you know
so what they created so today you see
the misery
these programmers you know uh condition
okay
and even today these people are still
you know they they don't they don't
unders they don't see things you know
especially younger people
they still think oh yeah we need to
contribute open source open source
what they are really happening is that
they are making this empire google
facebook twitter
with censorship you know more and more
powerful and bigger and now they created
the
kind of the social justice you evolved
into the social
justice kind of thing all over the you
know
white people nations usa canada
australia uk
and new zealand you know
and you know that's getting into
politics so that's
but this is what i believe okay
much of today's society in the past 20
years
much of the change social structure
or perception is actually created by
technologists
okay google us okay google most
you know most google facebook twitter
then they become the info they become
the today they become the you know the
the they control information you know
every day you wake up you go to
twitter facebook you know that most for
a lot of people
you know like more than like 50 of the
people
population in the world so they become
you know controlling information
technologies okay they created
you know us programmers created the
situation
but however we begin with good
intention okay because i was one of the
hackers i
supported google very much and i was
also
a good you know you could you can call
me uh richard storm and fnatic
back then 20 years ago i supported
richard stowman over
actually even over open source okay
because i believe the free software
foundation has a ethical quality anyway
so we programmers in the beginning we
have good
intentions we you know we want to share
we spread information you know
then google came up google for the first
10 years
at least the first five years was very
great company
their software in every aspect is
higher quality than than microsoft for
example
much higher quality you know almost
everything that is why
and with our support and also they are
big sponsor of open source
you know and summers you know some open
source
project they pay you know so open
becomes
more powerful and more powerful and then
then it becomes
evil empire today it's worse than
microsoft ever was
so that's another my rant again is the
open source so
you know so this is what i believe okay
so
programmers you know because the
computers becomes more and powerful more
and more powerful
computers ai robotics you know they are
they all came from computers computing
power
technology changes society in you know
throughout human history what
changes the structure of society what
what what caused society to change
the most by magnitude the most
important aspect is technology
technology
changes then it changes society for
example we have industrial revolution in
and other things uh in history okay so
in the past 20 years it's computers we
made it and then
we have good intentions and become it
becomes bad okay
so that's that is what i say
okay the another question about keyboard
about
you know what do you think is worth you
know about vora keyboard i talked
about i talked about that many times uh
that's it
but that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
bye i'm shutting down in two minutes no
no more than two
you