thank ice hi guys so today I'm going to
going to show you the most efficient way
to switch to Windows for example switch
to firefox switch through your favorite
browser or switch to Emacs and also the
workflow in Emacs for example whether to
use one full screen workflow or use
multiple in Windows so let's let's begin
so let's put this so you can see me talk
and okay so so I'm gonna show you yeah
the most efficient way to switch windows
there are two ways let me just type it
out two ways one is by function key to
is by Mouse Hoover Auto click okay I'm
going to talk about function keys here
first
well unfortunate unfortunately I don't
have I'm not using that right now so let
me show you keyboard so I'm going to my
keyboard block here no no a second yeah
you can see me on the corner in a corner
so it's let me show you PC keyboards PC
keyboards there a lot let's see
kiba in a art history to yourself design
they are key winding typing and it's
saying could achieve I need no design
well okay so anyway so you want to
switch windows so typically what you do
is for example on the Mac you press
command key command tab like that go and
tap command print tab and that's no good
hold on a second let me show you my
keystroke so come on Todd tap yes you
can see my keystroke on the corner here
on the left on the lower left corner and
command tab on the windows his control
tab in Linux control tab of course and
that's no good why is not it no good
because you have to you see that's two
two keystrokes - keystrokes and and also
normally on the normal standard keyboard
the tab key is on the is on the on the
using your pinkies this this window so
using your pinky sets you know you you
you curve your fingers to press the
command or the control key and you press
the tab key so and also so that's that's
two keys you know we can't keep as it's
more scientifically we can't keep as two
keys and besides that's not just two
keys it's actually you have to hold down
the command key first then press the tab
key release the tab key then release the
command key must be that order exactly
you know it's not just like you can just
press command + tab you know like
together it's not exactly like that and
so this is a modifier combination and
that's no good for your fingers in
general general speaking and also it's
actually slower you know there there's a
speed typing contest
this occurs with your champion typing at
some 220 or 250 words per minute and he
also expressed similar idea
I mean confirmed the idea that's the
him this guy the typing speed test
people and Acura type typing games
having tests
typing key how to design layout yourself
history not history design not design
but I'm going to talk about where's my
function keys okay I change D okay so
instead of control tab well haven't
finished talking about command tab
command tab is no good in general you
want to ban you don't want you want to
avoid any key combinations like a
modifier like command alt or ctrl key
you want to avoid that as much as
possible if your goal is one first first
of all to be efficient of it to be
efficient meaning fast okay sit to the
second reason is that if you want to
avoid hand injury you want to be as much
as okema economic as possible so if you
avoid key combinations what you do you
use function keys instead like these you
know function keys that's the best thing
to do you just set f8 to switch to Emacs
f7 switch to browser that's the best way
actually I have I have a lot hotter
costs talking about that ok switched
window apps I have a lot of articles
talking about these things in detail but
right now it looks I'm not like to
concentrate it having difficulties
finding it so one switch ok so what is
this okay why functions keys are useful
right so this this article page talked
about function keys let's go to a
browser
settings okay so let's go to it's just
such my name Ben key combos something
like that Ben shift he king and design
okay Ben shifty so this is one banished
key codes that's the one I want to show
you so he Kiko you can you know you can
read the details and you can you know
you can go to the UI and read it later
so anyway so don't use key codes so I'm
gonna show you how to switch like you
know remember I'm going to show you how
to switch to the app you use most of
often like everyday typically for anyone
you have like three or four apps you
switch to all the time you know for
programmers it's typically terminal you
know terminal or Emacs and browser
that's the that's the things you want to
use the most okay so and and yeah so you
switch programs all the time like all
the time so what you want to do in is to
set one of these function keys to one of
two top three or four of the programs
you use the most often so so you know so
that's that's one advice that's one
advice for me my my that's what I
believe is the best way now on a laptop
you know that table is not so good
because on a laptop you don't have big
function keys and function keys usually
it's like scrunched together tiny in a
thin strip that's how to press so on a
laptop you know you make an exception
you know you you you might use command
tab or control tab other ways but anyway
you shouldn't be typing on a laptop
anyway because laptop its laptop typing
on laptop for for one year
that's how I got is I my first
repetitive repetitive strain injury in
2006 and the since then I got you know I
my hand is not feeling comfortable every
every three years there's another issue
but the the first issue is is due to
because I was typing on a Mac iBook
laptop keyboard you know all the time
without any full keyboard but so so this
is one device okay so the other thing is
how do you say that up to switch you
know pressing one of the function keys
to switch windows so app I have detailed
explanation here you know I'm pretty
sure if you read this article carefully
you'll find the link anyway
somewhere there but anyway I typically
go to key how to so this Microsoft
Windows Mac okay so how to sit okay how
to set key to switch to browser this is
the page that explains how to you know
for Windows for Mac hopeful Linux so
forth for Mac there's a lot launcher
applications it's easy you know
Quicksilver and many others on Windows
you use autohotkey hotkey you know you
just search the web you'll find it and
here's a code you know you'll find how
to have a tutorial here go to a hot key
tutorial this is written a bit out like
the last update is three years ago and
but I you know I'm pretty sure it's
still good
so autohotkey for Windows and on Linux
it's it's a bit more involved you know
you can do that so that's one way to
switch to what that's one way to switch
to
yeah I want the function I want the big
function key photo it's good but so
that's a one way the other way is Mouse
Hoover so right now I'm not using
function keys because actually because
for the past few years my keyboard is
like that and also before this is
connect Kinesis and by the way this is a
great keyboard I want to give them a
shout out ultimate hacking keyboard I
have a unboxing review you know agent
you can just search my let me show you
quickly and I'm going to do a video on
that oh yeah here okay I'm going to do a
video review seeing sorry ultimate
hacking keyboard
so I have a review here this is
excellent
excuse me truly fantastic keyboard I've
been using it for for the past two or
three weeks you know now I've been you
know using it every day two or three
weeks so it's fantastic I have a video
review of unboxing here you can watch
and I'm gonna do another video of the
full review of the keyboard so anyway
but this one issue on this keyboard it
did you see there's no physical function
keys you know in order to press
functions keys you have to pass the mod
key which I get used to but I still
prefer you know function keys you know
like right now this keyboard does not
have function keys
therefore I actually cannot use you know
like we talked before you know press
just like press one pick one function
key and switch to Emacs you know pick
one function key switch to terminal and
browser you know I cannot do that
because if I do that it's gonna involve
holding mod key and you know there's not
many other keys I can do that so anyway
so that's so beast so that's why I'm not
using function keys right now and before
you know before this keyboard in in the
past three years I've been using Kinesis
advantage keyboard which is this one
right now
I set it aside because I want to test
the Ottoman hacking keyboard full-time
but I was using this keyboard for three
years and this is excellent you know
both of them are truly excellent
you know you might question you know so
but which one is the best you know I
wouldn't I wouldn't able to say this is
C you know it wouldn't make it would not
make sense for me to tell you which one
is the best actually because I think
both of them excellent they are
different though so they are different
depends on his best depending on
your preferences your needs for example
to you you need it to be portable do you
want it - how much you type actually
because you know it differs it differs
greatly between people you know some
people are novel writers you know like
me I write blogs all the time and some
programmers if you log your piece
actually you don't type that much you
know so you have to go scientifically
like how much you how many keystrokes
you type per day then you can find out
you know so anyway so it's different for
each person and also depending on your
hand size you know you may not like
Kinesis you know keyboard and also this
is you know so anyway I'm not going to
talk about keyboard today so you know I
just want to say that on this Canisius
keyboard they have this function keys
like tiny function keys show you the big
picture but they are not full-sized
function keys so that kind of that
that's no good
so I mean although this is a great
keyboard but however you know the
function keys becomes wasted so I don't
have basically you know I just I don't
use them because they are hard to press
so so that is why I am not using
function keys as I suggest you to so if
you don't have function keys so if you
are on laptop what what else to do
you - what you do is the Mouse Hoover
switch like right now I'm using let me
show you my mouse you see that's it's my
mouse so I this is how I operate
hi I just this you know this is how I
typically operate I just move the mouse
and notice I didn't I don't have to
click I'm not clicking anywhere so
basically when my mass stops moving the
it does a quick automatically and this
is a software feature on most operating
systems you have that feature on a Mac
it's called rail
so let me show you I don't know how I
don't have been talking on this video
you know I'm not I'm trying to get
better at making videos but the most
quick so I have a page for Linux on how
to do that and I have a page on the Mac
how to do that so first of all I must
warn you that this feature takes some
used to like if you just turn it on
today and after 10 minutes you're gonna
see Anna I don't want it because like
every time you touch your mouse cursor
moves you is going to make a quick so
when you start to use it you'll often
find that you know like you are moving
your mouse and reading this but suddenly
pop the other window pops up you know
it's frustrating so you have to get used
to I mean basically you you you start to
not moving the mouse when you are you
know when you don't intend to and
actually has a good habit because the
one of the ways many people have RSI
with a mouse because every time I see
people using the mouse in in movies like
sci-fi movies like Jurassic Park or
stuff I see them holding the mouse like
that and you know and the moving hand is
you know I feel pain for them you know
they can click and click you you know so
not moving my way Hoover's great you
just you know you know you don't you
want to avoid touching it at all like so
anyway so I think I've been talking too
long actually I mean you know trying to
find my articles spend too much time on
that so anyway here's here's how to
switch windows so you can read it and
how to do it on a Mac it's called rail
it's a bit complex you know you know
well you'll find out it's it's not easy
it's not hard to do you know
so it's great I have been using this
auto click for like six years now so on
Linux this there are two things about
about it two things so on Linux you you
have okay first of all on Linux first of
one of the first thing that is you have
a feature called mask uber to activate
window
you know Linux is a bit more complex XE
Bevans and stuff so activate window you
have you have two concepts focus
window and active activate window focus
window means that I mean for example
this window this Emacs window like right
now the Emacs window is behind you know
behind browser window but you can move
your mouse over there and make it you
know it's called focus window and when
you type the text will go into the
window behind the the window has in
focus that's what beings you know x11
called focus even though it's not in
front
so that's focus window I don't like that
okay some some people swear that despite
it you know some people insist that it
must be that I don't like like for
example one of the popular programming
stars Steve Steve eggs
Stevie egg Steve ye Gigi now he used to
work for Google but he quit last time
Google has been and that's not going to
that so you know he used to work at
Amazon Amazon and he worked at Google
for like six or eight years or something
no more and and then he I he quit last
year or two years ago and he's working
on something else so anyway he's one of
the guy who insists that you know you
must have the feature of focus window he
once that but you cannot do that on a
Mac as far as you know he did research
and he find out that you can even you
can't really do that even though he's a
great programmer so basically so so why
is focus window on Linux the other
concept is I think they could activate
window I don't have a Linux right now
but I'm pretty sure like I talked about
it somewhere here so the other way is
activate window which is when you when
your mouse hover over window it actually
goes to the front and that I like so so
that that is one feature in Linux you
can talk which is not here but
so let's Nitz go let's go find it Linux
keep on in tutorial ok here so you see
they are - there are two things here
Mouse who betrays window that's one
thing then the other one is smart super
quick let's go get them Mike alarm clock
sorry about that
anyway so most who were to switch window
this I like and you can you can turn it
on wait this is Mac
okay so let me go open that yeah otro
race yeah that's that's a word they use
not not not activate hotel raise window
so you can do this in depending on what
you know window manager you are using on
Linux you can you can turn them on in
open box in LXDE
or xfce I'm not going to details right
now you can read it because you know
Linux is a bit complex so that's one
thing
Auto raise window now there's another
thing which is the actual Hoover quick
now the Hoover quick
what does that mean is that whenever
your mouse cursor stops moving it does a
click so you can turn this on in in
Linux it's usually categorized under
accessibility you know you know
categories over there so so the Hoover
Creek is that you know just like the Mac
tree sometimes it's called trail DW dwel
that's when that's what I'm using right
now on the Mac when you're let me go you
show you the extinctions so I go to
System Preferences accessibility
rainbow so link go to keep keyboard and
accessibility keyboard then you go to
trailer options so it's you know it's a
little bit hard to find yes you go to
trade options then you have these
options so anyway I talked about it in
the page in detail how you want to set
up because you have to experiment okay
I've been talking too much too long you
know
it's dragging on so anyway so so
remember on Linux there are two things
Auto raise window then the other thing
is Hoover quick Hoover quick I have
tried to use on Linux it's kind of it's
not so robust but that was there was a
few years ago 2016 2 years ago maybe
they improved I don't I don't think so
but so anyway so you could you want to
try you might want to try it so that's
the so that's the so in summary the you
know what I recommend as a efficient way
to switch window application is buy one
used function peace the end the second
way is used Mouse who you can use you
you can have them both on you know I
used to both on so sometimes you just
sometimes you just pick a key to switch
to terminal and sometimes when your hand
is on Mouse just move mouse to the top
terminal so okay that that's it for
today I was going to talk about Emacs
workflow but you know it's taking too
long so I'll talk to you again see you
guys tomorrow
I mean tomorrow or next day so if you
have questions leave a comment see you
see is pi