Good morning everyone. Good evening.
Welcome to another episode of cell talk
show. We are going to code Wolfram
language today. Pure Wolfram language.
Uh if you are watching this offline,
play at 1.5 speed or faster. If you are
watching this live, say hi.
Okay, so we're going to code Wolfram
language today.
Pure Wolfram language. I'm going to demo
cell Wolfram mod.
And I'm going to demo Wolfram language.
Okay, and demo cell Wolfram mod. You can
download for free. I'm going to show
that. Then I'm going to demo cell
Wolfram mod. And I'm going to show a
problem which I'm going to code. So for
example,
let's go to cell Wolfram mod. So this is
a This is a package for Emacs users. Uh
for you to code Wolfram language in
Emacs.
I'm going to show you a problem I have I
need to do
that involves the symbol concept. The
symbol concept in Wolfram language is
like function names and variable names.
In other programming languages, you call
them identifiers such as C, Java, Java,
JavaScript, C++, Rust, Golang,
identifiers. So I have a completion
feature, but I need to determine what
type of the you know the the name is in
order to do the completion properly. So
if it's a function, you want to add you
know the brackets. If it's not a
function, usually an option in Wolfram
language, you want to add the arrow
sign.
But it's kind of difficult to determine
that. Okay? So let me go over over that.
So basically so that is we're going to
explore. Then we're going to talk about
the Wolfram language symbol.
Which is very kind of very advanced
topic. And this is not a practical
topic. So if you're going to learn
Wolfram Progra- Wolfram programming
language uh or Mathematica
uh for doing engineering, mathematics,
or programming, or artificial
intelligence, or cryptocurrency, or
cryptographics,
you wouldn't need to know what we are
doing today. So, this is kind of for
myself and, you know, this is for those
interested in programming languages and
especially like Lisp family where you
have symbols, okay?
So, let's begin. Let's go from the
beginning. Okay, so so from the
beginning, today's talk show
uh
Let me check one more time. So, we got
three people watching. Say hi. So, we
going to uh is my video good? Let's
check video, check audio, check. Okay.
So, let's begin coding. Okay, so let me
begin from the beginning, of course.
Play at 1.5 speed if you're watching
offline, okay? So, first of all, let's
demo
the Wolfram script.
Okay, Wolfram script. Let's magnify.
Uh control Yeah, control. Let's magnify,
okay? So, Wolfram script
uh Wolfram script, you can download for
free.
So, you got you begin. So, okay, so
let's say expand
uh
expand bracket. Then, let's say
X
squared
minus Y third power
uh times square root
of
X.
Let's say square root of Y.
Okay, let's make it kind of fancy. Let's
see what happens.
Uh now, let's see. Where's the
close key? Okay, so what? Close.
uh
close friend close uh wait
close and we need to make it third
power, okay. Let's see. Let's do that.
Oh, that's simple.
So, anyway, so this is demonstration of
Wolfram Script.
Okay. And so, you search for xah Wolfram
uh you know, xahlee.info.
Xah Wolfram Language Tutorial, you can
find the
Here's my download. I mean, here's
Wolfram Language for programmers entire
tutorial for those of you programmers.
This does not teach you how to solve
equations or do calculus.
There are plenty materials out there.
But, this is for programmers. If you
know JavaScript, Python, Java, C, you
know, if you want to learn this this
kind of artificial intelligence
language, far more advanced then this
tutorial is for you.
And over there you can go download. So,
go to this website, exactly this
website, okay. Don't be fooled by other
website. This will take you to the
Wolfram Research
page. Download JavaScript.
And you can download it, okay. It's
something like 4 5 GB. So, this is a
huge language. You got 7,000 functions
building. Very different from all
languages. So, from Lisp, from Common
Lisp, from JavaScript, from Python, from
Haskell, from Rust, from OCaml, you
know, uh very different from them.
Uh a magnitude higher level higher
level, okay. So, you download it, then
you got this Wolfram Script.
Okay, so that's Wolfram Script. Now,
let's shrink it. Let's do a Let me do a
screenshot for so that uh
Oh, I already did did Okay.
So, anyway, so that's So, that's where
to download for free and or you can pay
and buy it, okay? This download is for
personal use. Check their, you know,
license agreement and so on.
So, let's So, let's go back to today's
talk show. So, demo uh Wolfram script we
did, okay?
Then, we download Wolfram engine. That's
where you download. And if you want to
have graphical user face, so here's
Wolfram language I already opened. Uh
you can
have a graphical, let's say
plot.
Uh let's say parametric plot.
Parametric plot 3D, okay? Let's do a
fancy one, 3D. Now,
it's kind of tedious to type in the
Wolfram language, so I usually do in
here
uh in Emacs. So, let's go uh we need to
go faster because I need I need to cover
lots of other things. So,
start the Wolfram language,
pop it out. So, Wolfram uh parametric
plot 3D, so you want to plot. The first
one argument is expression. The second
argument is the parameters. So,
uh X and Y parametric plot 3D, so let's
just say
So, you parametric plot is a function of
three
a function of two variables. That's the
input. Then, the output is uh
a vector of three numbers, okay? So,
let's say cosine
Let's say cosine
Okay, cosine X
sine
X
then, let's just say T. Okay? So, X from
0 to 2 pi uh Uh, let's say times two.
So, zero to
But, that's basically zero to four pi.
Okay, let's give it another uh,
parameter. This one is T. T goes from
zero to, let's say, five. Okay? That is
the
syntax.
Uh, wait.
Copy it. Copy it. Let's magnify again.
Now, let's go here. Paste it. Plot.
Oh, so you got you got this uh, you got
this cylinder. Wait, we I just wanted
I just wanted to be a hex, you know,
helix. Uh, so what you need to do is Oh,
yeah. So, sine x y. Yeah, so you need to
type
um,
I'm not sure I know uh, this is correct.
But, let's just experiment. Oh, you got
a cone.
Okay, so what I'm saying is that if you
want this graphical user interface, then
then you also need to download, you
know, you download the Wolfram Engine,
which includes the Wolfram Script. But,
this is uh, you know, but but this is
only for um,
you know, text interface. So, let's do
uh,
you know, I was Where's the key? Okay,
so let's say
pi
to
100 digits. Okay?
Enter. There you have it. Pi to 100
digits. So, this is textual interface.
If you want a graphical interface,
you need to also to download um,
So, just read my page. Okay? My page
explain everything. You download the
uh, Jupyter
Notebook uh,
um,
extension there. From by Wolfram
Research. Okay? so this that's the
official, but there's also another one.
So if you go to Jupiter Notebook,
you know, Wolfram Language for Jupiter
from Wolfram Research, the official one.
So turn on JavaScript. Okay, my alarm
clock
My alarm clock tell me to get up every
hour and walk.
Otherwise to to prevent ass rot from
sitting too long. So
you get the, you know, Wolfram Jupiter
Notebook so you can have this graphical
interface.
Okay, and then you also
Yeah, and there's another one.
There's another um
like like competing one similar. But
anyway, so you look, you know,
you know, if you're interested, read my
documentation. So I have a lot of
details, okay?
So that's parametric plot.
Uh we want to get a helix, but that's
not helix. So this is about mathematics.
So what is the
You need to get it right. I forgot
exactly. So
I know, okay, so
you In that case, you just um
But we are wasting time, okay? So but
anyway, so
sine cosine
uh
sine cosine So let's So it's all x to So
the the input is just one variable,
okay?
So sine or cosine, so
I think that, okay?
So basically there there there. Oh,
extra comma, delete it.
There it is. That was what I was
planning to do.
Helix, okay.
Fantastic.
Okay, so that's demo of the, you know,
graphics. So, you need a notebook for
that. Now, I'll put it back. Cuz index
good showing browser. Today's talk show
page, we demonstrated that. Okay. So,
now let's demo xwolf and mod.
In fact, you have seen
This is xwolf and mod. You can see xwolf
from at the bottom. So, this is So,
let's So, this is coding wolf and
language in Emacs. So, I can type par
para
Tab enter to do completion. So, I can
type para
metric, you know, so there's parametric
plot, parametric plot 3D. I can do
completion. There it is. Press enter
again. Okay, there's no completion for
that one. But anyway, completion and,
you know, and all kind of features. So,
press tab.
Then edge, that shows all the commands
you get. So, you can complete symbol
eval buffer,
uh format compact format, you know, doc
lookup.
Eval current line, eval region. Let me
show you some of them. So, this is xwolf
and mod, okay.
So, you go here. It's free
thanks to Wolfram Research. So, on this
page, you go to download, which is
GitHub.
Then you can get it.
Okay. Now, here are the commands. Let me
show you a few. So, let's let's demo a
table.
A table feature, which is most powerful.
So, let's say a list from X and X
squared, okay. And X from 1 to 5. So,
Press press
Uh your Wolfram product is not not
activated.
You get this error when you run too many
instances. So, let me exit this one.
Exit.
Okay, so exit then copy it. Okay.
Great.
Make a screenshot.
Okay, so now exit that then then Okay,
then delete that now.
Now press press press.
You see, here is the output. Now, you
can see the command course on the pink
window Xah Wolfram Eval Region.
Tab R, that's the key. I'm using a Vorak
keyboard, by the way. I'm also using
XahFly Keys.
XahFly Keys, that's another package. If
you watch my videos, you know, you
search for it, you'll see it um
you know, let's go to it. Let's go to
the top. It's on this home page showing
browser. It's a key binding system for
Emacs. I have tens of videos about that.
Okay, so anyway, let's go back to uh
Xah Wolfram mode. Okay, so so again so
um
remove that. So
so you can do completion, you can do
evaluate. Okay, so the let's go to look
at the source code.
Uh
press
Wait. So, what what we want to do?
Uh look at the source code, okay. So,
describe key press press press press,
okay. And there it is, Xah Wolfram mode,
okay. So, now jump to the source code,
open it. Here is the source code.
About 3,000 lines, but most of it is
function names because the Wolfram
language has 7,000 symbols building.
Like out of the box, there are 7,000.
You know, in Python, when you want to do
regular expression, you need to load
regular expression library. When you
need need to go through a directory, you
need to load system
uh
library or file util library. If you
want to do, you know, networking, you
need to
uh load networking library.
In Wolfram language, it's different.
Everything is just a function call. You
don't have to load whatever. So, by
default,
there are 7,000
um
function names built in. So, this will
show them all, including there are there
are about 100 or 200 special characters.
So, this this are all the function
names, about seven about 7,000 of them.
Okay? So, you can see we can, you know,
then you can also so
then you let's
copy from the last
input
that's a post fixed
notation. Then you want to say length.
So, that will tell you how many there
are. Shift enter.
7,500
functions built in out of the box from
artificial intelligence, from
crypto graphics, uh from mathematics,
number theory, differential equations,
calculus, differential geometry,
graphics programming, like uh okay, so
this is so huge. Let's delete the
output.
Uh
you know, graphics programming and all
sort of things. You can build You can
also interact with C
uh or Python or
You can also, you know, for those of you
new generation, you know, you do makers,
like you create, you know, you buy the
Raspberry Pi. By the way, Wolfram
language came with it if you buy the
Raspberry Pi.
You can see I uh talked about here.
So so download Wolfram Engine, go to
that page. You can see if you buy
Raspberry
you know that Raspberry Pi it bundles
with Wolfram Language
for
for computing when you are on the
Raspberry Pi, but you cannot install on
your PC or whatever. It's just for the
Raspberry Pi.
So
a lot of younger people today they are
not you know exactly programmers in the
traditional sense, but they do you know
they build boats you know drones
whatever all kind of devices you know
like but you also need to program. So
you can use Wolfram Language interact
with that. So AI um
you know lots of things um
Okay, so let me so
another feature in so Wolfram mode is
uh for example if I want to know the
documentation for this function I just
press a key
it should it goes to the
official documentation. Okay, so this is
parametric plot. Let's magnify.
Okay, so now you can see
the full details about
this tremendous
functionalities in this in this
parametric plot.
Like to write this function this the
full capability to write this function
in Python it'll take you
100,000 lines.
Okay, minimum.
100,000 lines because it can
not just do you know all you know
two-dimensional or one-dimensional
parametric plot, but it also can plot
part of the region. So, there's a lot,
you know,
like two two just study this function
takes
several days just to know all its
capabilities. This is just one of them.
Okay, one of the plotting functions.
Now, this this this
this thing you are seeing is a famous
curve in
uh differential geometry. It's a model
of hyperbolic geometry.
Mo- model of a two-dimensional
hyperbolic geometry. This
uh this is called um
What's the name? I forgot the name. Uh I
have it on my website. But anyway, so
So, what I want to show you, so, you
know, so we demo we did we demonstrated
many of the
features of the Casio Wolfram mod.
Casio Wolfram mode for Emacs allows you
to code
Wolfram language in Emacs.
Um
So, uh but yeah, so I was talking about
the But what does Wolfram language do?
So, you go to their documentation. Um
you know, so you you just go to building
symbols. So, where do we go?
Uh
By the way, they they just had a new
design of their website. So, this is
their new design. I recognize many of
these images. For example, on left side
left-hand side all of these most of
these all of them are from 1990s
when I began to use Wolfram language.
The one on the left. And then I I think
they are chronological, you know, all
these are like history of Wolfram
language. So, I I recognize most of it
on the left.
Uh
So, anyway, there's tremendous things
you can do, you You artificial So, they
actually talk about it. Economics, data
science, uh uh what is this? Fintech. I
don't even know what is Fintech.
Uh software engineering, statistics,
computer engineering, game tech, you
know, like game programming,
uh cryptography, system analysis,
computer science, electric computer
science, that's that's a part I know
well.
Uh electrical engineering, so they are
showing this is uh
This is inversion. Actually, this is a
plot of complex numbers inversion. We
talked about it
you know, last week or so, many times
before, too. Planetary science, you can
you can plot that.
Uh
can we show it? Yeah, I can, you know,
like all of the management science,
mining, uh automat automotive
engineering, utilities, transportation,
energy. Well, that's getting fancy. You
know, all these like
life sciences
and and chemistry, but main the main
thing is like all this, but
but it's a it's a it's a programming
language. Uh so, it does all mathematics
known to humanity, any algorithm that is
known, any any algorithm in computer
science, including
cryptographics, including number theory,
including
uh computational geometry, including of
course, analysis and algebra, including
uh but in you know, basically
everything, including artificial
intelligence, machine learning. So,
So, anyway, so so that's kind of that,
you know, the the scope of Wolfram
language. That's why I say it's like a
magnitude different from all the
uh industrial programming languages. So,
here is machine learning. You can also
do video and image
editing, you know, programmatically.
And machine learning, you can also, you
know,
like just have it it have it predict
what kind of category, you know,
categorization, kind of different things
in machine learning.
Okay, so that computational journalism.
Anyway, that's a new uh
like new website design from Wolfram.
This just came out like 2 days ago.
Okay, so but we
let's get back to what we were doing.
So, that's, you know, all the before is
like introduction. Um okay, so let's put
this back. Syntax correct showing
browser.
So, we covered demo of Wolfram script.
Uh download Wolfram engine. Demo of cell
Wolfram mode, yes. And show problem of
completion, okay? So, let me show you
what is a problem. That is a problem. I
want I need to do, okay? So, let's do
this again.
So, for example, if you have a um
table, you know, tape
you know, what what is tape this table
what it does is like
it's analogous to Python programming
languages
um
list comprehension, okay? So, it's
called list comprehension.
So, if you don't know
list comprehension. So, why list
comprehension is bad. That's about
programming language design, okay? I
have a article on that.
Uh and here is, you know, list
comprehension Python semantics and
syntax in the hacker idiosyncrasies.
That's another one of my rant.
Uh there it is a tutorial of what is
list comprehension in the Python
programming language. Basically, it's a
special expression special syntax to
allow you to generate any kind of nested
array, okay?
That is what it is. This comprehension
is a special syntax within a language
that what does it do? It allows you to
generate nested array.
Okay? So, if you don't have this feature
in your language, you can do the same by
nested loop.
Of course, it's more cumbersome, you
know, for for I, you know,
I equals to something, I less than
something, then for J, you know, you do
two loops or three loops if you want
three-dimensional array. But this list
comprehension make it easier, okay? It
generates nested array.
Now, in Wolfram language, you don't have
this so-called list comprehension
because it's kind of idiotic, in my
opinion.
But you got this function table. What
does it do? It does exactly what this
list comprehension do. It's It's for
generating nested array, okay? So, for
example, this this is flat array.
Uh
Okay, we Okay, we are explaining. So,
let's say just X X from 1 to 5. Press
press press press.
There is a result, flat. This is also
flat. What if you want to do
two-dimensional array, nested array? So,
let's You can say
uh F something X Y. So, X from 1 to
let's say 2,
then
Y from 1 to 3, okay? And what you want
is a F X Y, okay? So, now you run this.
Fantastic. You get that, okay? Let's
kind of like Can we clean it up? Let's
make it
uh formatted, you know? So, one of the
thing I don't have in so Wolfram Alpha
is that I don't have
the ability to format the code.
You know, so I need to code that.
That's, you know, that's one of my
to-do. So anyway, this thing
generates
this output. Okay, so that's a
two-dimensional. So you can run the
exactly the same thing in the Wolfram
notebook.
It'll be pretty. It'll be prettier. And
you can you can say you can say
slash slash is a post fix notation. You
can say tree form.
Then it shows you as a tree. So this is
like this demonstrate the power of
Wolfram language. You don't usually see
this in other languages. You know, like
they don't do things like that.
Uh so okay, so that's that. So
So so so
what I'm trying to say here is this that
this table is a function.
Okay, it's a function. Now
Now let's
But some other symbols are not
functions. So let me show you. Okay, so
Uh what is this parametric plot? Okay,
so this this is a curve. So let me show
you. So if you if you do this parametric
plot
obviously that's a helix, okay? Now I
don't want this to be that long, so
let's reduce it.
Okay, so that's that's a bit shorter.
So suppose I want it to show us tube.
Now is there a option to you know, right
now it shows us a line, but usually
in some situations you want it to be a
tube, so it's prettier.
So I don't know how to do that. I you
know, I don't remember there's like 100
options. So, so let's look.
Okay, so let's say I want for example, I
want the background black.
So, there's options. So, let's say back
b a c
c k ground. There it is.
Uh background light blue. Okay, this
automatic completion. So, shift enter.
There you have it.
Okay, so you you got uh got this.
Now,
uh okay, now I get it. So, you see
when you see when it's not true, it's
hard to see. Sometimes you you see the
flip of it. So, it's became weird. So,
anyway,
my point here is that this background is
not a function. It's a symbol, but it's
a option.
So,
when you have a function, typically it's
followed by the square brackets for the
arguments.
But, when you have a option,
it typically is followed by a right
right arrow. Okay. So, in my
example from mod,
I want to be able to say for example, I
type background
b a c k b a c k g
completion.
There it is, background. Okay, I want to
like then it automatically type a
uh
right arrow like that. So, I can say
red.
Completion red. There's a red color, you
know. So, but if if this thing is a
function, it automatically add a bracket
like that.
Okay, so that's what I want. In order to
do that in my package, I need to know,
you know, which of this name is is is
this a option or is it a is it a
function? That is the
That is like what I'm trying to do,
okay? But now
we can go back to the question of how do
you make this a um
tube? So, you can view the documentation
inside. So, okay, that that's a surface,
but um
Okay, I I don't know, but what you can
do is you can
Let me show you how So, we are
digressing, but this is a interesting
question. You You call
uh
options. That's a function. So, press it
should automatically add the brackets.
Then you give it that, then you evaluate
it.
So, there you go. So, these are all the
options that is available for the
parametric plot 3D.
So, now it's one line. Let's make it uh
multiple lines.
Okay, so let's
uh wait, let's do it again.
Okay, now it's uh okay, now it's not too
good.
Anyway, so that now it's one option per
line. So, is there
So, now let's search for tube.
Uh no, you don't see
Okay, so
you don't see tube. Let's search for
style. Plot style.
Okay, anyway, I you know, I'm I'm I was
trying to make this line to be a tube.
Um but
I don't know how
to do that offhand. I'm sure I can find
out in 10 minutes, but it takes time.
So, let's Let me just try something.
Then, if it doesn't work, we'll forget
it. Okay?
Plus style, let's add a um
I don't think it work.
Okay, no. That's not
how you do it. Anyway, so let's forget
about that.
Okay, so let's get back to our main
thing. Our main thing is the question
about
Okay, hold on a second. So, what we're
going to do uh let's put this thing back
in here.
Okay, so now put it back.
Uh
Wait, pop it out.
Let's
separate.
Separate.
Put it back. Syntax correct showing
browser.
So, we talked about all these things.
And here's our sample code.
So, now the question
is Here's a question.
Uh I asked I ask uh AI about it. So,
Grok AI, so let's see. Where can I find
uh let's not go over there.
Uh let's So, I
asked Grok about this question.
In Wolfram language, how do you
determine if a symbol is a function or a
option name?
Here's the question.
And here is Grok's answer. So, let's go
there to see the Grok's answer. Okay?
Magnify.
So, it says, "In Wolfram language, there
is no single built-in predicate like the
hypothetical function Q or option Q to
determine to definitively classify a
symbol as a the or option name." So,
it's saying there's no building function
to do that. But, however, it's you know,
it's suggesting that you can do it by,
you know, checking this or checking
that. Uh
then you So, this is a probabilistic
approach.
You know, you you might call it
probabilistic algorithm.
Meaning that it returns an answer
with a probability of correctness. Okay.
So, it
you know, in other words, it's
heuristic. So, let's look at how it
does. So, let and let's try maybe we can
um
maybe it'll work. Because what I need to
do is I need to apply this function to
the entire 7,000 building symbols. Okay,
paste it. Let's pop it out. Okay. So,
the AI chatbot is suggesting this. By
the way, I already know this, you know,
I I I want to know if there's a single
building function. It says no.
So, let's explore
uh you know, what it does.
I mean, let's explore what are the
ways in order to determine if a symbol
is a function name or is it just a
option name.
B O H N A 1
financial technology
Good morning.
Okay, so here
what Quirk is doing is writing a
function. So, you can see it's defines
this classify symbol and here is a
pattern for the argument symbol.
Uh then it it's a module. This is a
local variable
block like Lisp's let, okay? And here it
defines two local variables, usage and
name.
Uh so, the usage is
is basically that the value of usage is
that and what that means it returns the
inline documentation for the symbol.
Okay.
Uh let me show you.
Uh okay. So, so remember previously we
we were talking about the table function
which is
lets you generate nested arrays, right?
So, here's a official documentation
nested arrays.
Uh and you can see examples. Okay.
And but you but within
within the you know, you don't have to
go to the website. You can look up the
inline documentation. How you do that?
You do that by just uh wait, not that.
Uh so, you need colon uh got colon colon
usage. Okay. So, you just evaluate this.
Okay. Let's try.
There it is. So, it's kind of verbose.
Uh I mean, there's a lot. So, it's you
know,
it says that that okay, this is not
good.
This big you know, what did what this in
this is unreadable.
But what actually it is it's a formatted
it's it's using Wolfram language to
produce a formatted output. So, this
display form row box something something
that's just like markup like
the markdown you know, language or HTML.
So, that's but this is a Wolfram
Wolfram syntax to to format the display.
But if you run this in notebook,
let's go to a notebook. So, if you run
this, you know, this in notebook, you
see now it's beautiful. It shows the
inline documentation for the table
function.
Okay. So,
so what is that's what that's why what
that's what this that's highlighted.
Okay, usage and name.
You know, it it it
it assigns the inline documentation,
which is a string.
Oh, actually, here it's not a string,
but
oh, you actually it's not a string.
Oh god, so that means you need to pass
this. That's not trivial.
I thought this is string. But, you can
turn this into a string. Okay, so that's
Anyway,
so
so so so this is what this syntax means.
Okay, it's just the inline
documentation, but it's not a string.
How can we turn into a string?
Um
I think
for example, let's see what is this.
Can we Okay, so this is actually one
giant expression here.
Oh, wait. Wait, this is a string.
Uh
This whole thing is a string, but I
think
You see, so you see this
Let's see. Yeah, this whole thing
No, but
Well, here's how we can test if it's a
string or not. So, what we call
string
Q that will return true if this is a
string.
Okay, so cut that. Let's go down. Let's
go down. Put that there.
Run it.
True. So, it actually returns a string.
So, that is interesting. So, that this
thing is a string.
But, you see, normally Wolfram Language
doesn't print the quotes. So, that's why
you don't see Let's see.
Can you search for the quote? No, it
doesn't.
It's not there. So,
but let's put them into a quote, okay?
So, let's put them into a quote.
There, okay?
And now, if we
cut this and paste this here, will it
format? I don't think so.
No, it doesn't format.
So, Wolfram Language in notebook, it has
special, you know, it's doing special
magic.
Anyway,
uh
So, what is that?
By the way, you can you can get the
string from actually. You can, you know,
so
Okay, so you understand what this is,
okay? It returns a string of the
it returns a string of the um
of the inline documentation.
Okay, but
but to actually make it a string format,
um
you need to use a full syntax for that,
okay? Uh I have So, let me check my
Wolfram Language tutorial.
So, here you go to print version
building help.
That's what you want, okay? So, that is
what you want. So, you want to just say
information table.
Okay?
Cut that.
Uh let's go down here.
Paste that.
Put this into a
comment.
Run this and paste output.
Okay, it still doesn't it still doesn't
It returns this thing information box.
Uh but I'm sure text form.
And you need to get it. Okay, so let's
try this again.
Text form.
Run it.
Okay, now it's
it's now it's text form, but it's ugly.
Table and generate a list of copies of n
and then table that generate a list of
value of that uh from one to I.
Then then that, you know, it's ugly. So,
anyway, this this are the flaws
of using Wolfram script in a text
interface.
So, this is when you actually want the
notebook interface
because the notebook interface will just
return this, you know, with
sometimes with um
math type setting, you know, like a
fraction or radicals.
Okay, so
anyway.
So, let's go back to the problem uh we
have, you know, uh so we
uh
a very technical um issue.
Are you guys doing good?
And am I doing good?
Shall I continue? Is this interesting? I
don't think it's interesting to a lot of
people because it's very kind of
technical and boring. But okay, let me
just do it for myself.
Let me, you know, talk for another 10
minutes or so.
So, basically, you you get the symbols
um
documentation,
then you check.
So, obviously, this function generated
by AI is not going to work. It, you
know,
um
Yeah, I don't think so, but
but what it's trying to do is you it
uh
it gets the um
get the inline documentation of the
symbol, then check if it's a string.
If it's not, then undefined. Okay,
that's kind of that does not always work
because
you know, I I just kind of know
from experience, 30 years. Uh then, if
string start with Q, usage name is an
option. So, it basically is, you know,
it looks at the documentation.
If the documentation begin with, you
know, some function name and bracket
something something, then it's highly
likely this this thing is a function.
However, if the documentation says, for
example, let's say um
you know, we just tried the background
before. So, shift enter.
If the document says, you know,
something something is a option
something, then it's highly likely that
this
this background symbol is a option.
You know, let's So, by the way, this
question mark is a
this question mark
uh
got
table.
The question mark is kind of a
convenient syntax for this usage, okay?
So, but you can kind of see this table
something something usage.
It returns exactly the same as this, but
the question mark make it formatted.
And then you can click on here
to go to the
uh
the actual documentation, you know, with
examples and uh
scope and generalization and extensions
and applications and properties and
relations and possible issues and other
see also kind of related
uh functions.
So, anyway, so this
So, this approach
you know, you you you try to get the
inline documentation and check if the
string begin with a something symbol
name and bracket,
then it's a function. If it begin with
something is an option, then it's an
option. That's how it does it.
Okay, so
So, I need to run this over the 7,000
symbols building, okay?
You know, so I need to do this for the
over 7,000 symbols building and
preferably
I want it to be able to run this in a
text terminal in Wolfram script, not via
the Wolfram kernel, the notebook.
So, I need to I need to get this part
fixed, you know, I need to be able to
return a plain string
of this this Not
not wrapped by, you know, the display
form, the row box, the row box style
box.
That's what format that what makes this
format. You can see
You can see there's a subscript, there
is italics. You see that's that's what
this style box and box that's what those
are for.
Uh but I just wanted a text format. Um
Well, but I
um
But
Oh, yeah, we did this here. Oh, yeah,
actually
Yeah, so this will work. Okay, so we
need to So, let's remove that.
Uh remove that. Okay, so actually remove
all these box.
So, let's try it again.
text form
Okay, it actually kind of works. Now,
let's call postfix notation
string.
Uh wait.
String Q is it
a string? Is the return is a return
value a string? Oh, it's not a string.
Oh oh, wait. Uh
what?
Text form is not what you want. You want
to convert it to string. So, how do you
uh
Oh, there's no text form. What?
That's an interesting
kind of bug
because
text form is should be a valid function.
Huh.
What?
Let's run this in notebook. Okay.
Run it. So, it's not a string.
Shift enter, run it.
So, it does return text form.
And now, let's look at the
documentation.
Search result. So, actually, there is no
So, the search form
function is actually not documented.
That is what's happening.
The search That's interesting. You know,
you might consider this a bug.
The
The text form
function is actually not documented.
That which is very rare, very rare,
okay. I've You know, there's a few, but
you know, so among the 7,000 functions,
it is very rare.
Uh let's say one in one in a thousand,
you know,
that it is not documented. So, but it
suggests string form.
Okay, I think that's what we want. Where
did I find the text form?
Or did I just cook it up?
I found it somewhere, but anyway,
I think what we should use is string
form, okay? So, let's do it again.
String form, that's the one we want. Run
it.
And still false.
Uh but we So, text string, so
Wait. So, how do you convert to string?
So, now let's Let me just look. Okay, so
let me
look
um
building help.
Let's go to string section, open a new
window, new tab. Uh string
Here is everything you need to know
about string.
Then regular expression, string
expression
string template
You want to convert
an expression to string. Okay, so
string functions. Okay, so convert
string there.
Okay, two string. That's right.
Well, that's, you know, I'm not sure
that is right. So
Okay, so let's try
two string
completion
Run it.
True.
Now, let's see what it actually returns.
Okay. So, remove the post fix
of string Q. By the way, Q means
question. Okay, you see that Q?
Any function name, if it ends in Q that
means the function returns true or
false, always, either true or false. Q
stand for function.
In other programming functional
programming languages such as Lisp,
Scheme
or I or some others, they call it
predicate. Okay, so usually they end in
P. For example, in Scheme and Ruby
any function that returns true or false,
they they ends the name ends in a
question mark. Okay. But Wolfram ends in
Q
question mark is not allowed character.
Okay, so let's see what this returns.
Okay, run it.
Okay, so now this actually returns a
string. Okay, so you see
So this is a string. So So I can call
the function
So table is one of the 7,000 functions.
So do a map on each one of these symbol.
Uh
and
it returns a string
and check if the string begin with
something of the form something
something bracket. Then we know this
is a function, this table.
If doesn't, okay, so actually this is
doable.
I can do this.
Okay, so
um
shall we do it? Um
Yeah, we can. Okay, so we can actually
start to modify this, you know, whatever
this uh AI suggested solution.
Uh
We can We can start to write it.
um
Let me Let me try this quickly, okay?
Let me just try this quickly. Uh then we
shut down, okay?
Uh let me see. Let's see if I can So
here is a example.
So
So I I don't want I don't want a module,
okay? Block. Block is a a local dynamic
scope, okay?
Uh
then
to Okay, so this part is a symbol. I
want to rename sim by
Uh wait.
Sim by xsim.
Make them unique, okay?
Uh well.
Yeah.
Okay.
Not Okay. Anyway, so
So, this Yeah, so
cut that.
This you don't want You You cannot use
this, okay? Paste that there.
Okay?
So, you get
So, usage is a string.
Copy, replace
doc string, okay? Rename it doc string.
Okay? Then
Then this name
is a symbol's name. That's a string,
okay? So, let's rename it
X name, okay?
Uh
Do it. Do it. Do it, okay? Then next, if
if string Q if not string Q doc string
Okay, otherwise if string start Q doc
string name. So, this this This means
string join, okay?
Uh
That You know, that
this
This is a syntax
shortcut syntax for string join. So, it
just join the symbol's name with
something option, okay? Actually, this
works. So, let's just run it, okay?
If string contains something something,
wait. Uh
If string start is an option is a then
it's a option, otherwise
so this is if statement.
If that, then
Wait, so yeah.
So if
not dark string that, then another if
statement, okay?
Then if
string start with something is a option,
then
output option. Then another if if string
contains
uh
something something
left bracket,
then it's function. Otherwise, other.
Okay, I kind of let's just run it.
So that, then let's call it
um
table. Okay, table is actually a
function, so
Okay, let's run this. Let's see
what we get.
Function, fantastic.
So all we have to do is just change this
one line from the AI suggestion.
Okay.
So let's try again. Now let's try uh
uh background.
Back background, that's an option.
Okay. Let's run it.
Function, option, fantastic.
So it actually worked.
Okay, I think that's it for today, so
actually worked, fantastic.
Bye, guys.
Hope you guys like it.
Okay, so now let's put this back syntax
correct showing browser so that we
successfully
kind of successful. The next thing to do
is to
try to run this function on the 7,000
um
Actually, we can try that. You know, the
7,000 building functions. Uh let's let's
let's try that. Let's just see what
what we get. But okay, so but
But let me prettify this a little bit.
Oh uh
w o o l Wolfram code and let's pop this
out. Let's go to the bottom.
Let's uh let's
cut that.
Okay.
Put it back and let's put the new code.
Uh
what's
here syntax correct and showing browser.
Okay, so here's our code.
Paste it.
Classify symbol um
Okay, so let me do something else to it
to do it to it. Okay.
Clear. Let me just
We We add a clear so that every time we
rerun it we reduce problems because
sometimes previous definitions screw
things up. So
this clear is just
clear the value just to be convenient.
So we clear it and also we don't want
this part.
We just want We just want this part.
Okay?
And then we need to get all the
functions. So that would be names
that
then uh
then a bracket. I mean the then we say
that. So, that returns all functions.
Okay, so
which is a list. Okay, so we can kind of
run it. It returns the 7,000 functions.
Okay.
Uh
uh
Okay, then you what do you do? Then
you want to map. Okay, so
Let's delete it. Okay.
Delete.
Then you
map
classify all function
to
this list. Okay.
That's what.
Okay, copy that.
Let's just run it here. Paste it. Okay.
And that not so large. 150. Okay.
So, now we run it.
Uh shift control D to separate them.
Shift enter to evaluate that.
Now, shift enter.
Okay, some of them doesn't return show
more.
Uh
show more.
Okay, so for a lot of them
you see these are built-in variables.
So, when they
Okay, so when the value is a built-in
variable, you don't want to deal with
it.
You want to ignore it. And when the same
when the value is a uh
named character, you also want to ignore
it. Okay.
So, let's say show more.
Show more. Where is the true false
thing?
Show more, 7,000.
Okay, you you want to show all. Let's
say show all.
Okay, so for actually, they don't
return.
You see?
For example, let's run that.
None of these return true or false.
What's going on?
Uh let's go down. Let's go down. Let's
go down.
Yeah, none of these return true or
false. So, what is going on?
Oh, because they are not symbols, they
are strings.
So, then you need to Okay, so you need
to turn the string to symbol. Okay?
So,
So, instead of that, you'll write
a function.
Okay, then
classify
and uh you want to turn a string to
symbol. So, that is
uh
that, okay?
X
Okay, function X classify symbol and
turn the string to
X to symbol, okay?
So, copy that.
Uh in fact, let's shorten it. Uh let's
say all names starting with T.
So, we don't have to deal with 7,000 as
uh symbols. Let's just test it.
Uh, there's only what? Other.
Wait, why is just Oh, not T must be
capital. Okay, capital T. Because all
building symbols start with capital
letters.
Okay, now it's running. It takes some
time.
Wait. Uh,
I looks like
I seen I saw the result briefly.
Okay, I think that's it for today. Um,
Okay, now we got
set error, uh, set accuracy, requested
accuracy, which GIS traveled dump
kilometer greater than one something is
not a real number.
Okay, so it's running into issues. It's
not as simple as that.
Anyway, oh, there is here is a result.
Okay, so it actually most of it works.
It tell you
So we we need to modify our code so it
returns not just what type it is, but
also the name of the symbol. Like, you
know, so we know which one is which. But
from here you can see it actually works.
You know, some of them are functions,
some of them are option, some of them
are some of them doesn't
return a result because the input is not
a symbol. It's a expression.
So that means we also need to fix our
input, which is this name thing.
So, it only includes symbols.
Uh can we actually do that? Yeah, we can
you know, we can do that.
So, some of them then some of them are a
date. You can see it pops up a date
today's date.
Uh
yeah, and some of them are what is this
gray level 00 transparency. So, that is
black and transparent. That what's
That's what that represents.
Okay, but mostly it works. So,
with a a little bit more fix, then we
have it. We'll have a function that can
classify of the 7,000 building symbols
whether they are a function or an option
of Wolfram language.
Okay, that's it for today. Thank you
guys for watching. Bye.
Bye, you are late. If you watch it from
the beginning, you'll understand what
I'm doing.