hello guys I think I'm leave ya peace
and everything good morning good morning
or good afternoon or good night
whichever it is for you hey bottle
wrapped boat pet bottle pen
did I pronounce it right so this video
this is like this is a talk show and
here I am just going to talk about
random things
well actually I'm going to talk about
let's go to well I'm going to talk about
YouTube stuff okay I'm going to talk
about Oh
Iceland Jack hi how are you so you are
you are you in Iceland actually on a
second let me go to that guy that guy uh
what else
so this you know some just that's those
are just some random windows I've been
reading now I wanna I gotta be careful
you know because when you do a live
stream with a video you know you don't
want to pop up something you know that's
private you know and that's easily done
accidentally go in London that's cool
I've never been to London looks like you
know England and you know there's much
trouble there these days you know in the
past you know to two years anyway so I'm
gonna talk so you know so this this is
like this video this live stream is like
talk show you know you know I'm today on
so it's it's like random ish okay I'm
just gonna talk about random philosophy
well I'm talking about floss
you know like I kind of mentioned
philosophy a lot because I'm kind of a
philosophical person so what does it
philosophy mean it just means I think
about things a lot you know everything
everything I see I think about it and
that is philosophy that is the
definition the gist of philosophy any
any other definition is is inferior when
you think about things everything you
think about it you keep thinking about
it think about it you know try to in
whatever style that is philosophy but
usually when people say philosophy we
think of a risk total or you know Greek
philosophers you know the like classic
philosophy of philosophy problems mind
mind and body problems and you know
things like that but but anyway so again
so this is you know like Saul talk show
I'm just gonna talk about random things
and you know feel free to leave you know
if you don't find it interesting I mean
you know come and go you know maybe you
are eating breakfast or maybe it's your
sleep time you know and keep the
comments going you know so you know when
I comment on something if you have a
question or if you have a comment feel
free to you know just post it so you
know I've been you know there's so many
interesting things I started to do video
like almost like half a year now you
know well my first video is like many
years ago but you know I wasn't like
doing video but now I'm doing regularly
and also you learn things there are
several things you learn you know for
example I want to you know I'm doing
video because you know I'm writing my
program tutorial and Emacs tutorial and
there are a lot of people who wants to
learn Emacs so I can teach that and but
also I have a lot you know programming
stuff opinions about programming and and
also because you know just my
personality I always like just you know
I just have opinions and I want
talk about it I you know I want to say I
want to tell people about my opinions
but you know each person is different
some people don't like to you know they
have opinions too but they don't they
don't want to be like public they don't
want to they don't really enjoy you know
like becoming you know telling other
people's about their opinion they keep
them to themselves but me well maybe
they work I mean most people they focus
on money you know that's that's majority
actually that's a human nature most but
you're people are just focused on money
and did you know there's a saying in
Chinese that is keep quiet and make lots
of money and and a lot of people are
like that especially you know there are
a lot people like for example I mean
this is just random example there's
cameras okay you know like everyday you
see on a webpage there's cameras there's
also the guy and their focus I mean they
don't they don't like they don't feel
they don't have an urge to go online or
write blogs telling about telling other
people about what they think about
things I mean that doesn't interest them
I mean there's no entry they don't find
that interesting at all however you know
making money like just quietly like
nobody knows and it just make money and
they you know that that's that's
actually the most people so Iran Lambo a
lot you know and I learned video so you
know so I'm I'm I'm I feel like I'm
getting old you know I'm 50 years old
now although I probably don't look like
that you know Asians usually are look
younger but anyway so I was saying yeah
so you know doing videos so I'm I've
been missing out you know because when
you get older you know young people
tends to you know do they create
innovations and do new things for
example in the past ten years there's
huge number of YouTube stars you know
they are often think oh 20 something
very young and you know they a lot of
them not just like hundred
serve them like that more than a
thousands of them thousands of them they
making millions and millions like you
know it's so amazing and you know if you
look at what they do what they talk
about not much I mean it's just young
people they they talk well you know
maybe they do usually have some charisma
you know they look you know they have
pretty face and they do funny things you
know the teenage thing so game
especially gamers they just plays games
and you know put it online so they are
like hundreds of them you know thousands
of them they make huge amount of money
and you know so but anyway I think I was
you know watching viewed YouTube of
course you know just like I observe I
like to observe everything you know I
saw them but but you know things there
are so many things happening today you
know because technology and you know you
cannot see everything at all you know
that what you can actually know becomes
smaller and smaller smaller you know
because the world is growing
exponentially you know in different
countries different political events or
different technology happening you know
for example I mean the the most
interesting example is like if you have
programa
the JavaScript front-end programming you
know there you have like hundreds
frameworks you know keep happening like
you you cannot even keep up meaning that
you cannot even know you know how many
are there you know so anyway so so this
YouTube stars you know young people and
I used to you know I used to have the
mentality of actually you know knowing
who they are like how many are they what
they do you know what kind of things did
they do on YouTube you know the there
used to be I think there is series
Wikipedia article that lists so called
personality you know internet
personality you know basically YouTube
stars you know what what this guy do
what that girls do and and so on you
know I used to want to
you know like to like to know who they
are what they do but you just cannot
keep up like today I know for sure that
there are a thousand you know I don't
even never heard of I can and I cannot
possibly imagine to actually know you
know even see a list of them because so
many things are happening well actually
I haven't played games much you know
because well the most the one major
reason is because I have become poor in
the past say ten years so I don't
actually have the computer you know with
a graphics card to play games but I
would enjoy that you know and gay means
you know so so the only game I played
his second life but that is a big one I
don't know about today is kind of but
you know backing in 2007 remembered you
know second life is supposed to be you
know it's supposed to replace the
internet because the virtual reality you
know the vision is that you know you go
to Second Life it's a virtual world and
it's going to replace internet because
you go into second life and it's quite
amazing because okay for those of you
who don't know Second Life Second Life
you know it looks just like a 3d video
game you know you know today you have
the first-person shooters or whatever
you know it's just it just looks like a
3d you know computer video game but
actually you go there everything inside
Second Life is created by users and
there's no goal you know not like a
typical game you go in you have to shoot
people or wing you know take over your
enemy's fortress or whatever with your
team or whatever or you have to
adventure like Zelda you know you know
meet the princess or something like that
nothing like that there is no there's
you know no go like it's just a second
it's just a word it's just like me award
okay you you were born into this world
what you gonna do you don't know and
nobody knows nobody can tell you and you
know you just grow in
you do whatever you want so that's the
second second life situation and I was
actually I lived I kind of like in the
game almost like eight hours a day
everyday you know for like four years so
you know well second life is like a a
long story you know I can go I know it
but it's it's amazing in several ways
because this it's not just again but
it's it's also there's a social aspect
is human nature aspect because you know
maybe maybe I'll just talk about singing
life for a bit because I'd Rambo
you know that well that's my nature so
why not just talk about it now if you
want to change subject you know oh it's
just common then I'll see y'all go that
originally I was planning to talk about
YouTube you know many interesting things
happening on YouTube you know many
interesting characters in their videos
there's amazing people you know the
technology is so advanced today you have
all all sort of amazing people and they
they usually is often they are expert at
some particular area and you can watch
and there's also you know lots of random
things
but anyway second life the thing about
Second Life is actually yeah let me show
my website why not because I want to
after all you know I have a website
so you know I have a second life blog
but actually I stopped since since about
2011 you know you may see 2017 here but
that's you know that's not really
blogging I basically stopped using
second life since 2011 so the the days
I'm active is 2002 let's see intro to
second knife yeah 2007 to 2011 basically
that's the years I'm second in second
life so so in second life you have math
so these are math this this guy Henry's
C German you can see he's on YouTube
he's on Twitter and he also have a
YouTube account
he's the mathematician this guy
introduced me to a second life so why
because originally I was going to go
into a second life to build geometric
models you know like the picture you see
here it's an actual virtual world like
you go in you go into second life you
can walk you can walk on the bridge you
know just like real life
you can go into the geodesic dome you
can go into that Tower and you know so I
mean you probably you know what I mean
right yeah I mean like 3d games you go
into a church or building elaborate
Cathedral or whatever that's that's what
Second Life is you know there's no code
people do whatever you know they do and
so this is originally originally why I
mean Second Life I was going there to
build geometric models geometry stuff
using you know the Second Life
technology you know for educational
purposes for artists artistic purposes I
mean I love math there's so many things
about math but let's go but okay let me
talk about the other thing about singing
I'm you see this Newsweek cover virtual
world be your money so this girl is is
the first girl who became a medium air
by doing things
Second Life she she's she said she's she
sell real estate you know korean called
real estate in second life basically
land areas
she resell them that's how she became
rich I mean real world millionaire we
are talking about so you know not not
the fake money gaming money real wood
but today in that's no news right
because there are a lot gamers who
became you know millionaires or a
hundred millions like they just fake
games and they show on YouTube stream
that they are several of them and I
noticed and not even I mean we are not
even talking about game champions of
course gaming champions they you know
they have gaming competitions they win
international championship and they have
sponsors you know big money corporations
but not that I mean so she is the first
one who made the median who became media
here but and there are several others
and usually they have to do with sex
okay so anyway so I'm talking about the
aspect of second life so this I was
there originally to be oh geometry then
I got into the sex stuff you know so
here's the you know the different things
in second life it's amazing you know
yeah so so yeah it's amazing I'm not
sure you know this the sex stuff about
second life is actually not on this
domain so this domain is let's see sorry
dog okay wait wait let's go through
break browser sorry dog
okay that's the that's my website then
you can go to Second Life here saw Sao
dog so that's the second knife pages but
actually due to Google senses ship I
have well I have a bunch of gallery
about the sexual related things in
second life but it's not on si si org
it's on sorry dog and it's not linked
here you have to you know just search
for it such sorry Second Life strippers
let's say for example you'll find it I'm
not gonna talk about that here because
why because Google YouTube censorship
and the social justice you know
situation you know they gonna they gonna
cover me
they cannot censor me they're gonna shut
me up they're gonna put being a back and
slowly disappeared that's that's what
happening these days so anyway so so I
was in second life so let's look at the
gallery okay here's a gallery and you
see hold on a second
so it's magnified you see all sort of
things people do okay so besides you
know so there's programmers
technologists you know we go to Second
Life we try to maybe be out mathematics
or geometry then there's you know sex
sex is everywhere you know people's you
know as they say everything becomes pong
you know everything this and it's not
just my it's it's huge
you know so everyone is you know they
people just don't talk about it that's
all
and so what so so yeah but anyway so
people do a lot different things
okay let me let me you know activities
you know this politics George George
Bush remember back then you know see
this this thing act now
end the war so this is this is like 2007
you know when George Bush is there so so
you see all these these are people built
in
I mean people build this and you can go
in yeah I mean there's all kind of crazy
things you can do so this is a target
you know you shoot it and sometimes
there's and there's funny dance and
stuff you know this is pretty I mean
it's like like all these things like
like when you for example in art you
know you have classic art you have
architecture you know heart you have
street art you know graffiti graffiti
you know but the thing is in second life
because this there is no coal you know
so you you see all kind of you know
unimaginably ativ 'ti that just swim up
from anywhere that you cannot classify
you cannot say oh this is you know
something anyway so in second life so
let me show you some math Oh
architecture well yeah this is some of
them so is extremely amazing you see
here are some of the architectures again
second life is a virtual world that
means you know you are seeing a picture
here like from the bird's eye view but
actually you are inside you know for
example this these rhombus buildings you
actually go inside like you are a person
inside the building and you are looking
from the interior to the outside or you
can like come out and fly around you
know someplace you can fly someplace you
cannot then you can see the whole
building so anyway so this is the you
know like a picture of Second Life in
2007 but by today's standard you know
you probably find this picture the most
boring and ugly you know but notice but
to realize that all the things
everything you see in Second Life is
built by people
you know what was so what does it mean
Bo PI people know it's not like other
games for example what what are some
today's other games for tonight or
whatever you know shooting games so but
but in Second Life
the um so what do you mean by build you
know how do people build you build
things in a second life just like a
let's say your carpenter build things in
real life like you you take a break you
go there and you put it down something
like that okay let me show you so here's
how you build things in second or second
life here he is a good picture example
so you are a person inside this virtual
world Second Life you huge then you
click there's a user interface you just
click and you'll create a thing in front
of you other people can see as well you
know in in this case we have a cylinder
and then you can manipulate it change
the shape and create another cylinder or
brick or square or whatever shape and
you build so so let's go back to the
picture you see this building let's see
you see this building
okay let's it's good okay so all these
are different okay here's another
building this building is actually a
Telecom Italia it's like official their
official representation in Second Life
so they build this you know building but
anyway so you see all these kind of
buildings let's let's see and next one
oh so and this one is a military base
which I'm part I'm a member of you hear
you play first-person shooters it's
amazing I have a great time with these
people there and you know so back in
2007 I was forty or forty something and
most of these people are like you know
20 young people that first-person
shooters so it's like whatever today's
game you know they what's the one that's
you know what what are some of the
first-person shooter games there is one
wait what's the name and say it say it
so you know there's so many first okay
so there is a shooter game where you
have a team of like heroes they called
heroes eight eight or sixteen characters
heroes and oh god I cannot remember
names now so eight person watching say
it guys overwatch that's it thank you
thank you so much
okay so minecraft I don't like Minecraft
you know why I think minecraft can be
similar to Second Life somehow but I am
not really experienced yeah I think it's
similar I think it's very similar except
that I've never been I've never used
minecraft but I really despise minecraft
why because you know as technology
advances you know we have more realistic
graphics but minecraft is like a step
backward they use like logo Lego break
bricks like everything is made of a
square that's what the [ __ ] is that you
know what
but do you enjoy it you know what can
you do and the guy I noticed actually
that the guy who created Minecraft is
very interesting he's on Twitter you can
you can find him on Twitter so he's
interesting guy but anyway I've never
been to minecraft and I'd hate it you
know just because the very idea where
you use cubes to to you know to
represent three-dimensional things
that's the that's the most ugly hack
you know as a programmer well some
program okay we are interesting elegance
right you know elegance not necessarily
like realism like not necessarily bad
but we want and you know you know we
don't ya not chachi is great you know
you use cubes I mean what the [ __ ] is
that concept I don't care how could you
do it how come fun you know how grateful
it is a game the very concept where you
use tricks to represent 3d objects you
know that that just throws me off so
anyway so yeah so I think I never been
to minecraft but I think it's very
similar to Second Life where people just
you know do whatever they do you know
and also okay Second Life there's also a
criminal aspect you know because of the
fact that Second Life is just a virtual
world so you go in there's actually a
lot criminal act
I mean criminal activity like people are
in second life you talk to you know you
know I'm talking about real criminal I
mean serious things so I think I don't I
can't even talk about you know I don't
want to talk about but but like can stir
so you know it happens in second life so
anyway so yeah I was you know I was so
arranging oh yeah I was in second life
to be old math let me show you some math
that's truly beautiful some of the math
things okay maybe you guys are not
interesting math some of you are I know
okay this is a this is a equiangular
sparrow again remember these are real
like kind of real things in second life
so this is big I mean a human let me
show you okay here's another sculpture
so what is this haft hop band oh it's
some advanced math stuff and that's me
that was my avatar a girl okay so look
look at this picture so this the
is like a sculpture in second life so
and that's a girl I don't know who is
she but she is in Japanese kimono
traditional as a that's a traditional
Japanese dress for women and you know
including the dress the dress and the
Hobbit ah the face is also peeled by
people I mean not by the company but
just by people like you going you can
you can if you want to if you have the
talent or creativity if if that's your
thing you can build a dress and you can
sell it in second life so here's another
thing this is Lorenz attractor
it's incredible interesting because look
at this one
now I must I want to emphasize this is
like real thing I mean well it's virtual
but it's real you see that cat person in
the middle that's me so when you are
standing so this giant stars shape is in
the crowd you know you like so I'm there
in the middle you know looking at a
thing you know you get you get a
complete different perspective of things
of mathematical things of whatever
things because that's what you see you
can you know you can fly around like a
fly and you can you can look at the
thing from you know like when you are
like a fly so that's amazing and okay
this is another thing interesting that
girl the chick who Pio this one this
this star shape a better way this star
shape is is called Lorenz attractor it's
a mathematical idea from in the branch
of chaos theory okay it's a fancy name
chaos theory and chaos theory is a
branch of dynamical systems that's what
called dynamical systems does that okay
that the terminology is fancy if you had
never studied math you might get
confused you know oh my god
you know what are these terms
I don't understand math you know it just
fly by me but actually it's very simple
you take a function you're putting a
value and you get a result right you
take the result put back to the function
so we you know in programming we call
recursion so you just repeat the process
and you get a sequence of different
values right now that this activity this
is called dynamical systems so what do
you mean system what do you mean
dynamical systems basically the
interesting thing is is that you want to
observe what happens to your sequence of
numbers you know you have a function you
put a value it comes out a result you
put a result back to the function it
comes out it comes out a new number
repeat you get a sequence of numbers and
the interesting to you know
mathematicians or physicists or
engineers there's a lot applications
it's a big field of math the interesting
thing is that you want to know what
happens to the sequence of numbers so
what's you know what kind of function
will get you what kind of sequence of
numbers do they repeat like do sometimes
they form a loop like once you reach
your number then you just loop it's just
always that number you know let's say 1
3 7 2 then 1 3 7 2 again you know every
time you reach Y it becomes 1 3 7 2 for
example so so so this basically this
this thing is called dynamical systems
and when you study time dynamical
systems you come into a situation when
where you notice very interesting things
happening for some functions the result
the sequence the results sequence of
numbers become such that such that if
you change the input you know let's say
you start with 3 number 3 ok
I mean you just put in the number 3 into
the function then you have a bunch of C
conserve values as a result now if you
compare that to if you put in the number
three point zero zero zero zero zero
zero one like very very tiny difference
almost no difference then but what
happens is that you're the result
sequence of functions becomes huge
hugely different from from from if the
input is number three you know so so
what people say is that a small change
in input affect the outcome huge
completely differently so that's when
people say you know you might have heard
people say you know a butterfly
you know the butterfly's wing flaps in
Brazil that cause caused a storm in USA
or somewhere so that's that's called
chaos theory
so chaos theory is the study of the of
that okay let me read the comment a
little bit so there so there was a great
Christ maker interview he did in Second
Life check it out
quite smoker Chrismukkah is a person his
fate is he famous for something I'm now
kind of out of second life force for
many years now and right now I have a
Mac I don't have a PC and no graphics
card when you don't have a graphics card
it's hard to play so the other question
so so you can put in for me a lot
formulas and it will be Oded in 3 do do
you have to build a manually okay let me
talk about let me answer that question
so anyway I was talking about math you
know this time dynamical systems by the
way that girl the girl who Pio this one
this girl I have a picture here
somewhere she she was my girlfriend well
online girlfriend
and her story is oh my god it's it's
another long story let's see if I have
pictures of her gallery
okay math where is it Oh in this picture
you can see the Mobius strip here and
this this girl this character is
actually a character in some Japanese
anime over yuri car seven i don't know
that anime but anyway people are so
creatively somos so every character
every famous character in USA or in
japan like Superman spider-man Batman
Joker and so on every movie character or
every anime character people have
created an avatar in Second Life so you
can buy you can buy with linden linden
linden dollars which is in public
exchange with US dollars so another
aspect interesting about Second Life is
that in most games they have a income
money right but it's not you cannot
I mean it's illegal to exchange it with
US dollars okay it's not really I mean
usually they don't make it that way but
anyway the my pony is that in Second
Life
they have the income dollars called
linden linden dollars and it's
officially in exchange with US dollars a
fully sanctioned you know so so so in
essence Second Life is not it's not just
a virtual world for gamers it's actually
there's a commercial activity
you know like start stock traders they
watch you know you can trade linden you
know you can buy and sell linden dollars
you know and to make money you know as
if you are a business type of guy and
people do that there's you know okay let
me show you oh well this that's my
girlfriend this so in Second Life
I'm the cat I'm the purple cat on the
left the girl the the what they call
these character there's Nick oh yeah
they called Niko Niko is a Japanese word
for cat go or something she this Niko is
or was my girlfriend but it's a long
story
it's not simple but anyway so so let me
talk about how to well I try to keep
things interesting you know I don't want
to be you know just rambling about
myself things so so let me talk about
how so if I'm if I go astray you know
say something you know like you know so
so so what I whatever I say is some you
know in some way interesting to you to
you guys you know interesting
perspective or interesting things or
whatever so in second life you build
things there are two things about
building in second life once you build
architecture or stuff so I have a
tutorial I actually wrote a tutorial
here you can see so this is how do you
build things in second life now remember
again everything you see so far all the
picture I showed you everything it is
peeled by people like you you know that
and me you know we go in I mean you
don't have to like you can just go any
most people don't build anything they
just go in second I've have fun with
friends but everything you see is built
by somebody you know usually usually
young artistic means this so many so
much talent you don't see in real world
I mean you don't easily see it because
you know the corporations and all that
they have a structure you know make but
in second life you see all sort of
artistic creativity they're like people
you know things you cannot describe
easily anyway so this part is you know
here's how to be your things in second
life the other part is scripting now
that's interesting because that's about
programming languages so this thing you
see
LSL scripting tutorial OS l stand for
Linden mean wait now as a Linden
scripting language okay that's a name
for the language Linden scripting
language Linden is the name of the
company Linden Labs that created Second
Life
so the other aspect of Second Life
besides besides building things is
scripting so what does scripting do well
it's a programming language for example
if you have a car in second life or jet
plane or whatever or this smoke
you have to coded and the way you coded
you is you write a script so so that's
interesting so I studied that you know
for a few years it's it's also very
interesting its first of all it's the
most lousy language okay it's a worse
it's worse than JavaScript it's worse
than power it was named PHP so that's
interesting aspect the other interesting
aspect about Linda's scripting language
language is that it's different from
basically or industrial programming
languages because you know in in in the
language the languages we are familiar
with you know Perl Python Java C C++ has
cow you know is crucial list so what
they do they you know you print things
you you add numbers you know that you
know you you you write a server that's
it but linden scripting language is like
it's inside second life virtual world so
you use this language to control
vehicles like you know cars movement or
or talking interaction between objects
so it's it's quite different you know be
not because the syntax or semantics but
rather because the environment what it's
supposed to do for example let me show
you a simple example
see this one let's go through basic
concepts examples so for this for this
one this one the first this one hello
just just three lines four lines okay
you know state entry our set text I love
ya that's very funny
so what does this to this script you put
you putting an object in second life
like you can see yourself like you can
see yourself you know grab this thing
putting an object and basically you'll
just show the text I'd love yet you know
on top of the thing you're just display
it anyway it's a you have to you know
you have to be in second I have to to
kind of get it so let's go back to the
comments
so can you make can you maybe talk about
what was building stuff like he's like
to you and what and what was the
chronology of its development and do you
have any more ideas to upgrade it even
more at this point yeah sure
I want to mention iterate which produces
an infinite beast formed by iteratively
applying a function to an initial value
yeah that's that's that's what
mathematician call it iterate you know
program I usually say recurs recursion
but anyway that's you know that was the
dynamical systems stuff we were talking
about earlier so maybe today second life
will be some kind of augmented reality
in some kind of grasses yeah so you know
today you have virtual grasses I never
used it you know I never had chance to
use them and so I I don't know what's
the state of second life or the virtual
would you know I don't know so I don't
really know what's going on today we
probably missed that what do you mean
missed who what I mean what topic so
okay let me quickly touch about
Sophocles you know for just two minutes
Emacs blog so I think you know that's
kind of our topic today because most
other people are probably don't know
what that is but anyway it's a Emacs key
binding system let's see saw packages
Sophocles so you know it's a key mic key
binding for Emacs kind of like them
Vince key binding and history so if you
go bottom of this page you'll see
you'll see some history about why I
wrote it okay why I created it so you
can read it there you know I think that
answers part of your question basically
I was okay
the okay let me talk about it so
basically in 2006 I had some kind of
hanpan hand problem then in 2007 I
started to create a ago Emacs mod which
is a Emacs package that has efficient
key binding based on using the old key
as the modifier so that's 2007 and I did
that for like three four years okay
seven years then in 2013 I created
sapphire keys so what's the difference
well the difference the difference is
like is that soft like is this modal
like VI you know you have command mod
and you have insert mod if you want to
type some text you go to insert mode
then you exit the instrument you are in
command mod in command mod any single
key you type is a command so that means
you don't have to hold down control or
hold on meta odds you know so it's
actually more efficient you know less
less keystrokes so that's why I created
sapphire keys and as far as future plans
yeah I have some future plan ideas but
okay but basically right now it just
works you know it just works so there's
no strong incentive to to actually
improve you know change the architecture
or you know some other things because
right yeah you know it's almost as good
as it gets I mean I don't have a problem
I don't see
people have a problem you know it just
works so and also because you know in
order to code it I have to put a lot
energy and effort yeah you know I don't
have money
you know I need if somebody like here's
$1,000 go work on Sophocles I'll do it
so if there's anyone out there you want
to do that send me the money and I'll do
it and you know and you know I can do it
for you or I can do it for the public
like you know you you you like you put
the funding and I you know improve it so
anyway but I do have some future I have
some thoughts example one of the things
I want to do is to change the underlying
engine but because right now every time
you switch between insert mod and
command mod it actually reading for
redefines the 30 or so keys like every
time you switch mod it redefines all the
keys it does like well I mean there's no
problem with that but a better way is to
actually just swap the key map so you
know instead of redefining all the keys
each time you change mod you want to
just swap a key map like you know here's
a key map press a button it just swapped
the entire new key map into it I tried
that a little bit a few years ago it
didn't work so I'd but I didn't continue
because you know it just works right now
so so that's about Safra keys
there's a video of people watching via
phone somewhere yeah well the thing
about YouTube we said you know YouTube
is getting into heavy censorship so you
know it's it's a big problem we cannot
talk about things we fear of getting
axed and and that's besides eatin that
you know not even talking about
monetization you know right now I'm not
making anyone any money I hope I hope to
but you know right now I'm not oh yeah
looks Smith you know I first learned of
him that guy because someone I think
because when it was because oh yeah the
first video I watched someone showed it
to me I think is because he was talking
about Linux code of conduct stuff you
know so but I haven't I haven't watched
much of him his videos I think you know
I'm subscribed not here but in my Google
browser I'm subscribed I haven't watched
much because there's so many to watch
today you know like you can't you can
spend your whole day watching videos on
YouTube it's endless
you know it's okay okay anyway so how
long have I been talking 15 minutes
that's about okay so that's a lot you
know I think I think that's a good time
to stop because you know usually 15
minutes you know you know but originally
actually I was going to talk about Bray
bowser's okay I'll talk about that
eventually I was talking about the
videos I watched I mean few of them are
really like to comment
you know this amazing people and amazing
[Music]
things you know in this ex experts and
you know just incredible amount of
amazing things like her and I rode off
okay she is
okay she's beautiful first of all she's
amazing she's hot Kira because you know
why they are oh that's because the
because of the adblock it's it's got
going into my earphones so anyway let's
go back to so what is our TV see you in
TV does I mean I know what it well I
guess I know what it means figuratively
but does that actually mean some
particular streaming technology or
something anyway very browser okay let
me just tell you browser and that'll be
it for today so brave browser is this
one it's like okay great browser you can
just go to brave calm way okay but let
me tell you what it is it's basically
technology creates just a clone of
Google Chrome okay that's the technology
but it's created by the same guy who
created JavaScript Brendan Eich okay and
why is so what's the purpose of brave
why twice does he created that so very
browser you know in today's browser you
have all these ads right that's
different from JavaScript
now if you co JavaScript then you know
it's extremely bad because the
JavaScript it's they are just like
viruses almost like you know when you
want to put Google ads so with like
every website tracks you tracks you in
all ways not just in cookies there's
also fingerprinting many technologies
and and you have to use JavaScript like
every time you use some library you you
know npm npm every time you load the
library it loads 100 others
so it's it's not secure you know because
this because the browser originally the
internet is not built for that purpose I
mean it's not supposed to be
commercialized by ads especially the way
adds up then on the browser so he
created the brave browser
it's basically okay put it simply it has
ad blocker bo Dean okay so I don't I
don't have to install I mean I'm I
didn't install any had blocker but it's
built in into the engine into the brave
engine so it it just it doesn't show ads
or tracking you know eliminates all that
however the goal is that it tries to
build a modern system where people can
still survive and you know have ads so
if you don't want to you know have
support when you run a website you know
by monetization by means of either
donation or automatic kind of I don't
know what the details you can look up
but but gee is trying to build a new
system ecology for you know running in
the Internet so I I recommend it highly
supported you know so and also they are
also using crypto currency as part of
the part of the system so you know
that's that's why that's what babies
okay thank you guys for coming I think I
rambled enough I mean 30 54 minutes is
good a good period of time so I hope to
see you guys again thank you and of
course you can comment I mean you can
comment when the stream end ends you can
comment on the you know youtube comment
yeah you can let me know what you'd like
to see next or what kind of like I
talked about lots of things you can ask
me questions so you know comment on it
so thanks thanks guys for
checking in I'll see you again next time
bye