come on everyone welcome to Kentucky Oh
today is June 14th 2019 5 o clock p.m.
California time California and the sunny
state and today we have a purpose
today's topic is going to be Emacs Lisp
live coding demo first tutorial because
when I'm you know coding it I will also
explain you know something about Emacs
Lisp so you can learn it from learn
learn from it let me fix the title here
let's see I'm alive yes that is correct
so let me fix the title so Santa chokes
out talk show and today state and live
demo today ok ok let's put that here
Emacs live demo first tutorial ok copy
that over here press a key press a key
paste and o single button operation this
is the utmost efficiency good morning
one guy watching good morning say hi and
so let's get on with it
so on the Left window as you know it
lists all Emacs commands I call doesn't
matter it's by meta X or by key so so
okay so Emacs like demo that's right so
what we're gonna do is okay let's begin
the topic so I have a command called
soccer field line or region for example
suppose I want to copy this line so I
just press a key it's already copied you
can see on the left window there is you
know I just called soccer field line or
region
and the key I used is jae-hyung vorak
layout I'm using a very big layout and
as usual let me just show you you know
this is my keyboard you see this is the
Evora keyboard
it's a Canisius advant advantage too and
you know it's an economic keyboard I
have a review on my website just such
folks ollie keyboard and you are see it
and also let me let's fix up this thing
this window this this window and see we
don't want that thing okay so
okay so that's good so I have this
command soccer field I know region now
let me show you something interesting
okay so some thing interesting suppose
suppose I want to copy these three lines
okay now I I can do echo kusakabe line
or region and it moves the cursor to the
next line and I can call that command
again and call it again
now I paste you see it places all the
lines
so this is very extremely convenient and
you know this is part of the feature of
the Sacopee line or region there is
another feature that is you do not have
to make a selection first like normally
if you want to copy this line for
example you make a selection first then
you copy then you can paste but you
don't have to for example it's let's say
I want to copy this line okay I just you
know call the command you know by okey
then I can paste it here you see so no
need to make a selection
however if if you have a selection it
will copy the selection you see so
that's a feature and you can copy
multiple lines you know copy copy copy
and you know paste multiple lines so
those are the features of akkad copy
line or region now let me show you the
command so I call describe function okay
copy that
describe function so copyrino region
show it okay so it says copy current
line or text selection if there is one
when code repeatedly apply copy sub seek
a pen copy subsequent lines so you see
when universal argument is called first
copy hole buffer so for example if I
want to copy the entire buffer I press
ctrl you first okay
then I call the command now it's copied
the entire buffer now I open a new
paste you see or 700 lines it's you know
it's copied now let's close that so
those are the features of car
Shakopee Lyle region and I have the code
here so Inc you know if you want to use
it go to this URL and you know you've
got a code this this beginning 2010 you
know the first one is the command the
other one is the another command of
variation you know so you can go and use
it now there is a problem though there's
a problem which is what we are going to
do today we are trying to fix that is
when you let's say some okay when you
copy let's say when you copy these and
you know the problem is that sometimes
it will copy the same line twice let's
see if I can duplicate it yeah sometimes
it copies twice now I have to you know I
have to remember how to duplicate it it
happens you know every few days to me
but what is the condition that happens
let me see
copy okay I know so I'm going we are
going to duplicate duplicate the book
which is it copied the same thing twice
so that basically I you know let me show
you so so there's a line here I copy
okay hold on a second let me just copy
something else so in case we get mixed
up so we don't get mixed up so here we
chose us here we copy the line and
actually let's start a new window
hold on a second so let's start a new
window new buffer and we can this
another command let me show you this
command is wait this command is this
show Sascha Keil ring so now basically
when you call this command it will
create a new buffer and show all the
history of copy and paste you see so you
see we have here this is the latest item
then we have here this is the previous
item then we have some Sun then we have
this and then we have this entire buffer
but we copied copied that so this is
long then we have this is quite long
then we have other things so I copied
before so close that so that is another
command you might find useful so let me
show you what is the command describe
key and this is the command sorry ok
ring so you can get the code at this URL
it's very useful command and both of
them are part of supply keys so if you
use cross surf like is you you have
these or these so now ok now let's go
back so so what I'm going to show you is
that we are going to duplicate trying to
reproduce the bug where a line is copied
twice let me show you what that means
so I copy this line so let's try again
so ABC ok ABC I copy this line then
wait how do we how do you reproduce that
then I switch to Chrome for example okay
now I switch back to Emacs then I gone
how do you duplicate the book I paste
okay so copy the line I cannot duplicate
the bug what that problem copy the line
switch to Chrome you know do something
there then get back to Emacs then copy
the line again now let's see what we
have
paste no you know what should happen is
that I should get these this happens to
me sometimes like I would when I paste I
would get you know the line to repeat it
once okay but we have problem
reproducing the bug okay how do you read
reproduce the bug this happens usually
why want to go to white to Twitter stuff
copy the line switch to Chrome
switch back to Emacs copy again okay now
let's see what we have taste that is it
so that is the problem a b c d e f DF so
let's try it again
copy switch to Chrome
switch back to Emacs copy okay that's
not it
good morning pace good morning paste so
we're trying to duplicate the bug let's
try again so base are you using Emacs
your Emacs user right or you are you not
so let's see some things let's make this
line long okay
so sometimes I want to copy the line
copy that i Kapila the line switched to
crumbs
switch back to Emacs copy again paste
okay I don't think this is a bug then so
we actually yeah I don't think it's a
bug you see basically what happens is
that let me show you the code some
coffee Lyon region okay so let's go to
the the code stop like he's here C
source code so let's so let's look at
that coffee that caused it make a new
buffer paste and let's make saw Emacs be
smart okay so here's a code so what what
did happen what did does is that when
you copy your line okay instead of
trying to fix the bug because because
now we cannot I don't think he's a bug
you know now thinking about it it's
likely you know it's not the bug it's
just the way it works so instead of
instead of fixing the bug let's just
turn this to I'm going to give you a
walk through how these command works so
hopefully you can learn some email is
you know retaining the original purpose
where you learn some emag bees so bases
I've dabbled in the basics of Emacs but
because I mainly do dot network I'm
pretty tied to visual studio and me as
code cool okay great so I'm interested
in Emacs though so yeah PS code I heard
it's very good I really want to try it
you know you know Emacs has lots of
problems mostly mostly the community the
free software foundation they the Emacs
has a code problem so you know but I've
been
you know leaving Emax for 20 years now
and exactly basically exactly 20 years
or you know living in emacs 20 years
everyday you know many hours and you
know so I've spent huge amount of
investment in Emacs Lisp I started
coding Emacs Lisp in 2006 so you know
that's 15 years so V so Emacs has lots
of problems code and you know which
basically it ends up you know there's no
progress there's lots of inefficiencies
it's still pretty good but depending on
what you how you compare you know how
you judge but it's got lots of problems
and it's stagnating and the user base is
strengthening and grinding of course to
us you know many of us Emacs fans we
think you know we perceive emacs's oh
the greatest thing that Oh more people
are using actually no that's not true
less and less people are using you you
know it it's like steadily down here Oh
since 20 years ago yeah that's about
right you know is basically is basically
less and less people using and you know
if you are a Emacs fan if you are
typically math user you may not agree
but I don't think you know Emacs user
base the number of users is declining so
but so that but the the essence of the
Emacs idea is that essentially it's a
you know some people call it it's a list
machine environment basically what that
means is that it it's got this language
Lisp in this case Emacs this that is the
main thing basically the whole Emacs is
essentially a environment or you you
some people say operating system it's an
environment to learn Lisp and everything
you do is actually you know it's it's
you know everything you do
including moving closer is actually all
calling list commands for example I
moved kusa it's actually calling
backward and actually why I type
something here it's actually calling
insert character you don't see it
because in command log mod you know when
you call that command it's suppressed
but let me show you just the example let
me turn that back on so you can see so
the idea basically what I'm saying is
that every everything is calling a Emax
list command I'm gonna show you that
later okay so you might be so in my
Emacs is a this environment so the most
important idea about Emacs is
essentially it has a language the
programming language that that that is
the foundation that is actually the
heart the core of Emacs everything you
do including you know inserting
characters switching windows whatever
anything anything past you know if
anything happens in Emacs is is because
some eMac this function is running and
the way you interact interact with it is
that because every key you know this is
an another essential part of Emacs is
that every keystroke
is gone through it is functional say
interface every keystroke including like
when you type something something s ome
you know when you type when you type s
for example any keystroke that is feed
into Emacs then Emacs determines what
commands should run for that key so in a
case when you press s Emacs says we are
going to run the command insert
character then it inserts the character
s so everything so so let me get back to
talking about the essence of Emacs
let me say two things one fundamentally
it's a list machine you know everything
is running around the core there's a
language you know the language that's
running is the whole thing is an
environment for the language that's one
thing the second thing is that every
keystroke is the interface of two users
II is that every keystroke is
interpreted to into running a list
function or command you know so that is
a two thing about Emacs that and that is
kind of what makes it tremendously
powerful now you you might know if you
know Emacs that Emacs was originally the
name Emacs stand for at editor let's see
Emacs
so it's editors maybe not it has
something add mark well it's not editor
it's something but anyway it's something
mark was editor mark was I think that's
what it it is so let's look up Wikipedia
okay you know that will give us the
magnify magnify move it to the right so
you can see it
so the original acronym for Emacs is
let's see mark oh yeah ed editor Marcus
you know that that is the what Emacs
originally stand for editor Marcus so
you can see from this abbreviation that
you see the whole thing about Emacs is
just editor Marcos meaning that key
Marcos meaning that the essence of Emacs
is that you define what each key does
you know each key becomes a marker so so
that ties to what I'm saying so Emacs is
first of all a lisp environment the
other thing is that it's a chemical
system this you know for the entire
thing every key you press including
control something in our something it
it's a macro it runs the command you
know to do something - you know - it may
type other keys or whatever it's a
editor Marcos so that's the two things
about Emacs the nature of Emacs and and
what made it powerful but this idea this
idea is not a very complicated idea by
the way this idea came from history it
is not you know someone you know think
you know sit down and think oh what
should an editor be what should be the
you know the most powerful editor should
be like then he decided oh let's do a
language environment and keyboard mark
oh no it's not like that
things happen what most things happen we
see every day they it's from history so
Emacs became this ways because
originally it was you know editor Marco
it was you know key a set of markers
people have started to do for the editor
at a time what's the editor called tech
oh yeah Tico is the editor so it's
basically
just a collection of you know convenient
markers you know keyboard macros that
people start to collect and you know
start to collect and bigger and bigger
then people have tried to make it
consistent refi it eventually
that is what Emacs is so you know that's
the history of Emacs you know it's this
idea but okay so let's get back to so
what I'm saying is that so Emacs is
these two things a list of environment
and key markers this is a great idea but
now this idea came from history it's a
from you know for history historical
reasons this way and but this turns out
to be a great idea and this idea is not
very complex as you can see it's pretty
simple you know you had you just have
keyboard markers you have a lisp
environment then you have keyboard
markers as an interface you have a
language you know firming language and
with keyboard marco as an interface to
the language so this is a simple very
simple idea and it's a great idea so so
this idea in my opinion I think it can
be duplicated in modern environment for
example with JavaScript so I don't think
it's too hard I think it's not a hard
thing to do so you know in the past
decades we've seen Adam editor which is
a editor you know say you know it's it's
almost like Emacs because you can think
of Adam editor is written in JavaScript
pure JavaScript you know ands and then
we have vs code which is Microsoft's
version you know it's a editor written
entirely in JavaScript on top of the
Google Chrome browser engine v8 so
chromium you know be a VAD is a
JavaScript compiler
chronium is the open source part of
Google Chrome browser so Quan Quan Yin
contains the v8 corneum is like open
source okay so so browser becomes so
complicated and powerful today so it
becomes actually a it became a kind of a
desktop widget system you know GUI
system so you can write editors on top
of browser so when you start atom editor
of vyas code whatever you see is
actually just a browser you know you
know it's basically essentially a
browser but without all the you know
process specific features but it is a
you know a browser running JavaScript so
but the idea is like you know it is
basically you have JavaScript as a core
language and you know and and as far as
I know you can also define keyboard
macros of course obviously you can
create your own shortcuts so to me I
have always thought that maybe that is
the modern idea of Emacs you know so I
i-i've been wanting to look into them
but I never got to I never spent much
time into them but it looks like V s
code is very successful and you know
today extremely popular so yeah so I'm
thinking you know maybe vs code or atom
could be a you know possible replacement
but however I've you know I haven't
looked into myself but I I've seen some
people I trust you know some other Emacs
users David Capello for example you know
I you know sometimes you don't have time
to do something yourself but you can
look up people you trust you know what
they say it seems like that like that
they it's not like that you know it
seems like you know although they are
you know system based on JavaScript you
know similar idea to Emacs
they they don't really function that way
so you know it seems that they don't
have the essence you know the essential
power like like Emacs so I don't know
for sure you know you know as people as
they say you know when you want to know
something the only ways you have to do
it yourself like you like I would have
to spend days to actually see for myself
where the vs code or ad editor can
really function like Emacs if it is the
case then you know we don't really need
Emacs because everything because because
because if we assume at a meditator and
V s code has the same kind of nature's
Emacs namely a language environment plus
a key interface to it then it has the
same nature as Emacs then you don't need
Emacs it has all the powers of Emacs and
more why because we to realize that
JavaScript the JavaScript community is
like what hundred times bigger than
Emacs you know the number of libraries
the number of people the number of money
resources going into JavaScript you know
hundred times no a thousand times no ten
thousand times yeah maybe that is true
you know that the resources put into
JavaScript and the browser is ten ten
thousand times more than Emacs is not a
you know hyperbola you know it's it's
it's it's reality let's just say a
thousand times so it's so far bigger
yeah of course but that's not what Emacs
fans like to hear you know you Mac you
you want to believe whatever you you
believe but you know that's some of the
fact that JavaScript community is really
the resources in the number of libraries
the the improvements to the language is
a thousand times
larger than Emacs so so you know so I'm
thinking that is why I've been wanting
to look into a demand vs code because
you know so if they have the nature of
Emacs then Emacs is really a video
Gunnar
but but of course there are some other
minor flaws and things you know like
social social issues a for example let's
assume first of all let's assume that BS
code truly has the same nature as Emacs
namely a language core with the key
markers interface let's assume that is
true but however even even if that is
true so in a technical sense you know vs
code or atom release is superior to
Emacs by far but however there are some
other problems not related to technology
for example vs code atom the JavaScript
the chromium browser they are run by
these greedy corporations you know the
billion dot me PD billion-dollar
powerful corporations to in censorship
or whatever they can to you know get
more money even though they are open
source but you cannot ignore the
background because they they do things
and and well meanwhile Emacs is run by
this by this by this richard stallman
guy okay he's a very he's not a very
good guy today but anyway he is he he is
known to be this nerd you know he is not
greedy let's say you know ed you know he
makes he takes a lot donations you know
for himself because he was you know the
goon the free software foundation he is
comfortable you know having he doesn't
have to do anything money
come to him and he sings you know
software do you know his job is just to
sing the song of free software and to
make sure that he will have money you
know to go to his pocket
you know then he's not worried about you
or other people anyway Richard Stallman
but but in any case he's not a greedy
guy you know although he's you know he's
not you know he's not there to lie or
cheat your money he's not intentionally
or you know explicit way so he anyway
the point is that he's not you know
these giant big corporations so you can
you can trust him you know you can trust
the Richard Stallman even though he did
many things bad as leaders of Emax you
know but but still you know all things
considered compared to the you know
whatever who is running Microsoft or
Google these days you know you reach a
storm is one you can trust
much more so it matters because because
then you know who how do you know that
vs code or a tomato respecto to FBI when
you know government you know government
is another big entity you know there are
billions dollars tax money from people
so they say okay you know one day they
say Oh Microsoft you know we have
concerns about security and stings so
let let's let me give you a deal you
know AG I sponsor you you know 1 billion
dollars for some project you know to
help humanity you know let's say I talk
to Google we're gonna give you 1 million
dollar 1 billion dollars to help you
know your Google search or whatever or
make oh I'll let you help us to create a
I for military purposes so you know
you're gonna benefit because the
military AI is a billion dollar industry
you know we gonna hire you and but you
cannot to us of a favor let's you know
we want this
corneum code to change a little bit here
and so then you got back back to-- and
the con comeon you know JavaScript
engine chromium you know how do you know
do you you know few very few people
actually are able to look into this
source code you know millions of lines
you know you don't know even if you are
open source or Security phonetic these
days because it's technology grows
exponentially it's impossible for one
person to know that you know million
lines of all the things happening
plugging libraries you know so you don't
know so so back to the point the point
is that quote you know oh this atom vs
code even though if they are technically
superior than Emacs but because they are
learned by corporations you know and you
know you cannot you know you cannot
trust it trust it as much as Emacs why
our Emacs is this little kind of little
guy you know
cranky lots of code problems you know
lots of these this free software and
open source phonetics you know
they do they believe in in in in fake
news they believe that what they want to
believe which not reality you know they
have you know it's a code but still they
are not these big corporations so you
can somewhat trusted more so it will not
it would be much less likely it's not
likely that one day you know Emacs will
contain some backdoor code you know
because when government tries to talk to
Richard Stallman you I can trust Richard
Stallman to he would say no you know I
this this part and this I can trust and
lots of the you know you guys you know
free free software open-source phonetics
you will say you know you will you will
cry out loud when you when you when you
see any such thing so this aspect is is
great yeah that that is why
you know so so you can trust me Mac said
that so that is it that is why even if
you know vs code anthem editor are you
know like Emacs and technically superior
but because of the social issues they
are also still good reasons to stick
with Emacs yeah that's my point about
that yeah okay so let's go back to talk
about the so this one one thing I want
to show you before I mentioned that let
me show you command log mod so describe
function command log mod so here is the
mod that I'm running that allows the
commands to show on the Left window so
we look at this code and you can see let
me modify something here you can see you
see this this block of code okay so
that's so this block of code you see it
does theater it filters are certain
commands you don't want to show on the
on the window so for example I have
filtered out self insert command you
know I filtered it out let's comment
comment it out and give out the function
now if I type self-insert he should
possibly show for example something you
see now if I type some thing ABC on the
Left panel you can see I'm calling self
inside command 25 times so that that pax
that my point about how Emacs is a
keyboard interface you know chemical
system any character any key you type is
bound to a list function or command so
you know so even
you are inserting something or pressing
enter now when I press enter you don't
see anything here because that command
is also filled theater feel filtered out
you see this this this one new line so
if I comment that line out avow the
function now now when I press enter you
can see that new line has says you see
so this is the power of Emacs you know
everything is in in real-time and
interactive you can you can edit the
list code in real time you know you make
a change like right now you make a
change you run it and Emacs behaves
differently you know according to your
change so that that is the power of
Emacs okay so that is about that let's
let's let's leave that like that
okay so let's close this and let's see
maybe we should explain this Sacopee
lion region code let's see how long I've
been talking 40 minutes maybe that's
about it so we got five people watching
so guys you know so he said should we
stop or should we do you guys want to
listen to how you know I explained some
emag list stuff you know technically mac
based coding you know because Mike's a
talk show has been you know you know it
has been running longer and longer
you know before it's like 40 minutes it
becomes an hour day in 90 minutes two
hours
you know because every time I it becomes
non-stop it's too long for people to
watch so today we talked about the we
talked about some the nature of Emacs
you know what makes it powerful we
talked about a little bit about you know
atom editor and vs code how they are how
they compare you know what you should
P and we talked about a little you know
things about Mike saw copyrino region
command so so that I would say the main
topic the useful topic is about the
nature of Emacs you know when you do a
talk show like when I do a talk show
I consider or if you are writing a book
or blog you know there are certain
content that is everywhere for example
if I talk if I teach you about Emacs
Lisp that is not a new topic you know
everyone you know lots of people have
you know teach can teach you Emacs Lisp
or Emacs okay so in terms of human
history in terms of a humanity that that
is tried you know know if anyone can do
it but however when you write a book or
blog or you know or video some certain
content that is rather unique that that
you don't see anywhere for example today
I was talking about the nature of Emacs
now you know I was talking about how
Emacs is you know the Kois
Lisp environment then the interface is a
you know chemical system that of course
this is not a unique idea other people
has said that too but however this part
of the content is rather more unique you
know it's rare and so and and what I
want to say is that it tends to be so if
I teach eMac list or or if I teach Emacs
people love that it tends you know a lot
of people we will you know uploaded it
you know we are hearted because it's
useful it's practical
you know people come to your show or
your blog you know they know they learn
something they can use you know but on
the other hand if you talk about this
philosophical topic about nature of
Emacs few people are interested
I mean you you can tell by statistics
you know like the number of likes you
know this is where it's few so this is
interesting because this applies to
books too because the most useful common
topic that gets you cells or money you
know like when you when you when you
talk to a publisher you know you plan to
write a book the the the type of content
that sells is often often the common you
know the tutorial about JavaScript
JavaScript tutorial you know programming
language you know those kind of thing
common you sell you sell things but no
value vd of little value to with respect
to humanity on the other hand if you
want to talk about unique opinions or
ideas such as you know like for example
philosophy or programming languages
philosophy of Emax this kind of thing it
doesn't sell nobody nobody give a
you know nobody cares about you know you
know your opinions even though it's even
if it is you know lots of wisdoms you
know nobody care about those kind of
things but however if you look at
humanity like history like if you try to
read you know 50 years ago what computer
you know programmers are doing you will
see a lot of programming tutorials those
you don't care rather the the thing that
interests you is the the ideas about
what what they are doing you know what's
the philosophy you know so the this kind
of thing becomes important with respect
to human history you know that that that
is the thing so when I'm doing my talk
show I have kind of this conflict I mean
this surprise to every every author
every you know bloggers you know such as
yourself you have this kind of conflict
on my hand if you want if you want
clicks you you want you know popularity
you want you know people to like you you
know
you you write practical stuff like how
oh how do you you know how do you delete
the line how do you copy your line you
know you do that but if you want you
know something that's really substantial
to history or you know to humanity on
the whole as a whole you want to do
something more unique but you you don't
get you know nobody read it that it that
is interesting that is my you know my
thought about this this this interesting
thing this this happens to book
publishers because to you know in in in
lots of areas because I've looked you
know I've looked you know into like you
can do to you know you can start a
research you know so-called research you
you know if you are curious about you
know suppose you want to write a book
you know there are people you know in in
book publishing or author communities
they talk about books you know what to
write what happens when you talk to a
publisher you know what kind of topics
you know sells what kind of topic
doesn't sell and things like that and I
have read you know as part of my
experience you know you know looking at
all different things that you know you
know so some publishers in you know
author that's a community you know you
have to look into different community
communities to know things so they talk
about you know things about that so when
you look so so apparently a lot authors
when they write a book you know they
talk to a publisher they say they think
oh I have this idea that's new I've
never seen anywhere you know I'm gonna
write a book but the purpose you're
gonna tell you know we don't want that
get out we want we want you to write a
book that everyone is writing a book
about that like there are already ten
books about it you know we want you to
write that because that sells if you
want you to write a unique ideas about
some human history of philosophy the
political
whatever you know nah we don't want you
don't get it because they don't sell
even though but but hist
but if you look at the thing from
historical you know from human animal
point of view long-term those are
actually more valuable topics so so when
I'm doing my stuff I am conscious about
you know with you know I'm attends to
you know talk show this is my talk show
so when I talk about eMac this tutorial
that's not really important because
there's there's a lot other people can
teach you Emacs you know eMac this
coding or programming stuff but but the
part you know where my some of my weird
you know it's like people like sometimes
people say they like to see my rant when
I get into a rant things becomes
interesting so there are certain
opinions or things I've you know that
only I do because you know it's me you
know so so this is like you know this
interesting thing so much data and says
please continue okay thank you do you
may paces do you want to do I mean do
what you want to do okay so so okay so I
guess that's it for today because yeah
so you know forty minutes that's a good
time to stop so I was going to you know
explain some of these eMac lists code
but you know let me put a little plug
you know if you really want to learn em
at least this written tutorial is is
very good you know just because they
start from the beginning they start from
the beginning you know you spend an hour
or two you know start from the beginning
you read this first seven articles in
this in the
brach eMac emacs this basics that's how
you you'll get up very fast you you know
on the other hand not many people are
actually email is coders so if I is
explain this I don't think they are you
know many people are you know you
valuable to a lot of people so okay
that's it for today I yeah so that's it
for today thank you guys for watching
so I'm gonna shut down in ten more
seconds you got 10 seconds to you know
post last comment so question yeah so
then I'm going to get on with my life
for today I woke up about four hours ago
and you know then my life is about you
know just working on my website
JavaScript email please update my
websites you know that I have like by
you know 20 years of blogging I have
like seven thousand six thousand
original articles that to maintain its
huge pain you know walk everyday stuff
tree function this this is actually
interesting actually I can digress yeah
but anyway okay I have a good day guys
bye