hello good morning welcome to another
episode of exan talk
show start recording if you are here say
hi hello good morning juang and uh if
you are not here play at 1.5 speed so
today we are going to code emac LP emac
LP
nonstop emac is a great editor in the
world so for programmers and cod
and emac lisp is necessary one of the
best lisp programming
language in fact it's the best
programming language if for the task of
text processing okay so this is
generated by gu gu Ellen musk X the
artificial artificial chatbot
intelligence chatbot
G and uh you know G has a update about
two weeks ago and the image generation
engine they apparently they change it so
right now it sucks so let me show you
quickly we're going to talk about emac
LP coding today okay so it's all about
emac LP but let me just show you quickly
the difference so you can see all these
pictures are generated by
grow The Prompt is draw a beautiful
Chinese girl with a wolf something like
that or draw a hot girl with a wolf or
draw a western girl a white girl with a
wolf so you get all these
pictures and now if you ask the same
thing you get this kind of you know it's
like it's not beautiful and some of them
are even
censored uh and uh even the picture
quality I mean this it's not it's not
realistic it's some kind of fairy tale
it's almost like they are generating
images for
children's book so the gr image
generation has degraded very
badly for some reason okay so that's
about work so this image it was
generated before uh you know it's for my
uh image history so anyway so we going
to do I'm going to show you the in emac
disp you can write a command that format
programming language source code for
example in Python script goand Po and
also you can evaluate part of the code
so let me show you okay so emac this
begin hello Mark Mark Jefferson who is
that women uh who is that woman it's
just a random Chinese girl I guess it
looks very good this you know she is she
looks Chinese you see for Chinese for
Japanese we can tell the difference it's
very apparent like we can tell almost
right
away you know most of the time just like
the white man you can tell I guess
Italian sprit or German people or French
people uh but so Chinese you know we can
tell Japanese and Chinese they look very
different uh and this girl is
Chinese uh so it's very good and
beautiful you know because I asked for
it to generate a beautiful uh girl
wearing uh I think a shirt with a leis
on it so that's fantastic but today if
you ask it it's going to generate [ __ ]
you know [ __ ] like that it's like this
you know this like this is not I mean
it's not like this looks like Southern
Asian like Philippines Philippines or
Malaysia you know you know it's not like
exactly Chinese if I ask it to you know
draw a white beautiful girl then it
draws this kind of
uh you know like lousy pictures very bad
okay so anyway so let me show you okay
so um so let's emac this coding okay so
if you are using soft FL Keys good for
you fantastic thank you and so the
command is already there run current
file so this command can run
uh can run fop code Goan code JavaScript
script code PHP code Pearl pow shell
python python 2 Python 3 Ruby uh
typescript and wolam language code it's
all building in soft like
Keys uh or even hascal closure uh or cam
or camo racket code bash
code and so on so this is build in soft
keys let me do a demo okay and it can
even compile and run Java so let me do a
demo okay so you go to so but if you are
not you know so it the code is on in Sly
Keys search it you'll find it uh if you
are not using soft keys you can download
the code so the code you know on this
website run current file so I just
updated the code everything you need is
here so you can just copy it put into
your in file and you have it and here is
a bunch of test am I alive check live
and kicking good okay say hi so a bunch
of code you can test let's test them
okay so yeah so let's go to section go
to here so let's test so let's say
JavaScript this is Javascript run
it 499 correct you just you know I just
C so you can see the command name is run
current
file okay that's JavaScript now let's
try
this python run
it 441 correct uh pow shell run it 152
by the way the right output is a full
name for the name Echo okay so for
example you can also say Echo this is
Powershell so now let's run
it you see 150 to 152 print it twice now
let's change your number run it s run
current file see correct okay put it
back now uh next Pearl okay PE language
run
it correct put it back uh Ruby run
it
correct FSH F FSH is fantastic FSH is
the function of programming language
from Microsoft build on top of net and
it's all completely open source since
about three years ago and open and F is
the descendant of ok camo which is
descendant of camo which is descendant
descendant of ml meta language the very
I think that it's almost the very first
kind of very strict functional
programming language which is where
hascal is a variant from okay okay so
you got ml meta language then SML
standard
ml camel C ml or camo object C ml then
you got
fop so they are basically the same
language hascal is a bit different uh so
here is ok camo and you know I mean this
is FOP you know you can download I
downloaded and installed fop by chance
it takes five minutes like three minutes
download it test run hello world runs
perfectly meanwhile I've been trying to
download OK camo on Windows it sucks
dony ass like it takes you one hour you
can't figure out like which one is like
what do you need where to install which
website to download you know or camo
that's a story of Open Source on Linux
it it's good you know on Linux you can
download easy in fact it's uh you can
just install from package managers so
FSH you know I'm still learning FSH I
think it's the best language I'm I'm
sure I don't need to think even I before
I learned it because I've been I've been
reading and learning about functional
programming since 1990s for example in
1990s I know about hascal hascal is very
old hascal is from I believe 1989 or
something it just just so happens in the
past 10 20 20 years starting around 2008
hascar became popular you know because
CPU maxed out maxed out you started to
need
multicore and so on so that actually
boosted functional programming so anyway
so here's
FSH fantastic and you go to FSH
documentation it's
beautiful clear document documentation
everything is professional return T
concise and no no strous push for like
open source oh this is open source this
is great you need to you know that's why
we are using it or things like that or
push for like oh this is learn learn
Japanese Zen lar Zen of pythons you know
Dojo [ __ ] [ __ ] this ninja [ __ ] these
Zuma idiots like ninja zen zen Cod what
Quang you know these extreme
idiots f professional documentation well
written the other fantastic
documentation is Java okay Java although
it's a bloated language but Java
documentation is beautiful actually
goand goand documentation is also
proficient professional so goland Java
documentation FSH
documentation poh documentation is also
professional very good and in also wolm
documentation which is entirely a
different style very good so right now
I'm talking about documentation not the
programming language the whether it's
good language or not that depends on
other things but documentation is a
thing by itself so so these are great
the worst are the Unix [ __ ] the
Unix [ __ ] with their Man pages okay
the Unix [ __ ] and pearl Unix Pearl
and python python documentation is one
of the worst okay let's continue let's
not you know digress let's continue so
PHP run
it good comments question say
it aren't you running am I running are
which one you talking about running are
you talking about the JP L guy
running Juan says Microsoft doc sus no
you don't know
[ __ ] okay like you don't know
[ __ ] uh wam so here's wolam language run
it wolam script you can download it
download it free wolm engine uh most
high level language of them all by a
magnitude so next Java so Java is a bit
tricky because to run Java you can't
just run it you can't like say Java run
something you have to compile it and uh
then you run the compiled class name
without the extension so
and for Java you can't just randomly
name this random name the the file name
needs to be to be the class name of the
file okay
so so It's Tricky but you know we can
Rite so let's change a number let's say
uh uh 73 run it so it first compiles and
it runs fast fantastic okay so you know
because I took some time to code it so
anyway here's a go
Line run
it uh the first time running go line it
takes a while but after that it's fast
okay you see
557 and let's change your number let's
run it there uh Goan you don't have to
compile for Java you have to you see it
created the printme docl class but Goan
you don't have to you can just directly
run it uh but if you want to compile it
you can okay so anyway here's
scand okay that's it so we tested this
sarun current file uh you know with all
these different languages but we can
also
try uh wait where is PHP okay now we
need to syntax color it color them all
back to browser run show it refresh
fantastic so we tested all these
language but we haven't tested scheme
list racket Lis closure hascal
or turn a latex to PDF you can do that
on Linux there's a program called PDF
latex or or camo racket bash you can do
that okay but I I don't have you know
I'm not on Linux Linux right now
so okay so do I have scheme installed I
don't think so
uh racket yeah I don't think so uh
anyway
so if you are writing you know so for
example I don't have a rust I don't have
one for rust uh I don't have one for
name language or you know or and I don't
have one for Lua so you can easily
extend this program by simply adding the
file name and
extension to this Association list
then you can then you can run it if if
that's a scripting language it does not
need compile but if it's a language that
needs compile such as rust I don't know
if rust can can okay answer the question
can rust run the code directly without
creating a compiled binary file can can
you us do that so if it can do that or
you have to do is just add a rust file
name extension and the program name and
run or whatever whatever command option
then you are good to go if
rust cannot run directly you have to
compile then it's also easy you just add
a new command to uh to this SAR run
current file
dispatch so you you have to write a
command like for example s Java compile
and run uh and how do you write that
program it's also very easy for example
you can just copy the code
here you see this about 10 lines of code
uh this is for compiling Java and run it
okay that's a example for
that uh actually we uh so let's that's
that's just kind of demo okay so
actually do we still have that no delete
all backup yes close Okay um so that's a
demo of s run
file okay so now we back to our talk
show what I want to do yeah so let me
demonstrate the another feature which
allows you to reformat code on the fly
so reformat python code reformat
JavaScript code uh reform let me Demo
okay uh okay so JavaScript so you need
um JavaScript
okay so we need a big JavaScript code do
we have one yeah okay so let me go to uh
some big JavaScript code unic code
search so you type fire then you'll
see all characters with the name fire in
it so if you type Mountain you see all
characters with the word Mountain here
so that's a JavaScript
so let's go to the
page uh so let's go to talk show uh put
it back let's paste the code here I mean
the
link okay that's a unical search now go
to that file wait uh let's remove that
mountain okay go to that file showing
browser there it is go back go to the
directory uh and what we want we want to
we want a JavaScript file so actually
just search for JavaScript so you see we
got several Javascript file here okay
let's go to the last one so this is the
short one this is for highlighting you
see the you see the pink highlight on
the
panel that's what this code does you
know it's just uh 40 lines okay it does
something else too but you see the
Highlight is here background color pink
and add a shadow that's how you get
this highlight pink highlight shiny neon
highlight that lets you know which page
you are
on okay so and also it does it here so
you know
so so that's JavaScript and uh and here
what does this part do this part oh this
part adds
a this part adds this copy button okay
so anyway so that's JavaScript copy it
close it okay let's go back to um go
back to my talk show go back here and
let's add oh yeah the JavaScript
so P all so here's a code now I want
let's let's uh let's screw up the format
okay let's make it one line okay let me
show you so you see this all this nice
nice um nice lines let's just make it
one line
okay
and you know the you don't want you
cannot do that to comments because
comment in
comment the wi space are
significant you know because if you move
this into the comment you know remove a
yspace at the end you [ __ ] up your code
so common is kind of
nasty that's another issue but a good
design for common is that the common
shouldn't be based on y space y space
should not matter at all so if that's
designed that way then then you can like
make your code into one line but anyway
let's let me do it okay
so remove that okay the rest of a code
they don't have common make it one line
okay and here this comment remove okay
so you can see now let's make a backup
let's remove the comment okay
remove make this one line so it become
incomprehensible to the average normal
industrial coding idiots like the C C++
python Java Ruby you know they they are
all like that they bring because they
are condition the the the the way they
see the code they are conditioned to
only see it in
like truncated line formatted way
they've never seen code that's one
single line like that when they see that
they think oh this you are trying to do
a f station you are trying to you know
like compactify or Minify no this idiots
in wolam language every code is a single
line like that you know I talked about
wolam language and enough like you know
in Wolf language almost every code
function is a single line like that okay
so anyway so we got a code this is Val
code so you want format it okay press to
key press press you see the command is
Javascript format
buffer you see beautiful
undo redo
so in a perfect you know ideally every
language should be like that but I mean
in real world not
really because of the industrial because
of the C C++ idiots in the beginning
okay it is they created this situation
so most people don't understand they
don't understand this this kind of
phenomenon you know when you have a line
more than 80 characters they they they
cry they they got you know shocked you
shouldn't do that you are an idiot you
know this the they are the idiots they
brainwash the entire generation of
coders beginning with Unix and C okay
Unix and C they both strap each other so
anyway but lucky for
us starting in 2008 the goland started
by the Rob Pike guy great guy he he's a
Unix proponent okay he's a Unix
Advocate but but he's a very smart guy
so he started to create create goand
with this Auto format so
today we have this kind of Auto format
everywhere okay now this a critical
thing to pay attention you see it's not
about indentation of a line or two okay
so like before 2008 go format you do
have reformatting code um but they are
like in line based so they only reformat
each line they like how many space they
put in front that's it they never they
never combine lines or take lines apart
okay they can they are incapable of
doing that before 2008 all the tools
like this so-call link usually they are
called link like SE link this this
industrial coding idiots the
[ __ ] that they are the name of my
pen okay even to to this day few people
know about what I'm talking about okay
and I hope you guys see what I mean so
starting in 2008 go format Rai created
Goan with go format so it so it
automatically format your code from a
single line to to whatever is supposed
to be formatted so all you have to do is
press a button it works so beginning
with go format 2008 also that idea
started to spread to the this industry
of Unix and cc++
and Java edit idiots so today today you
know maybe you know starting seven or or
even 10 years ago you have this reformat
tool in just all just about every
language now okay so we are doing it in
JavaScript how is Javascript doing it
reformat how do you do it well actually
if you look at the code
uh you see this is this is a code that
does a Joba JavaScript reformat if you
want it it's in my JavaScript package
you have to pay me okay but it's of
course it's it's actually calling Deno
okay so Deno has it it's calling Deno
okay so let me show you so Javas
JavaScript reformat region you go there
and you can see is actually calling the
Deno F fmt so Deno does
it okay that's a demo about JavaScript
re reformat okay
so um so what are we doing so let's go
back I wanted to show and I wanted to
you can do that in Python to um you know
python okay um JavaScript goand let's
let's demo the goand okay so open the
file so here's a go Goan code Wait no
that's not go land code
uh I mean this is a emac dis command
that CA go format that does it okay but
anyway you get idea uh I'm not going to
do demo so what I want to do I want to
rewrite this these functions you see
this format code functions I want to
rewrite it so so that so that it does
not call a shell command let me explain
this
okay Mark says will you ever invite
famous guests onto your talk show uh
yeah that's possibility but I've been
thinking about that but usually
I'm just kind of lazy you know like
famous guests like for example Richard
storman yeah I mean all other other
other emac Lis
coders uh or for example there's this
Linux guy who goes by the name of you
know
he's you know he's a bold
guy he's like a bold guy is a uh kind of
handsome fellow what's his
name pru says hi hi uh you know so
what's what's his name like on for CH
people mention him often he's a YouTuber
he usually talks about Linux Vim
latch uh
Latin guys say the name uh let me think
Luke okay yeah Luke
Smith you know so so there are a few
people I
could you know like contact them and say
hey do you want
to do a YouTube together things like
that you know that will increase your
Luke Smith thank you yeah that will
increase your popularity like it's a
benefit to both people that's what
people do on you that's what YouTube us
too you know like they invite each other
so because people like to see
that yeah I can do that but
um yeah so who do you guys like to see
so type the names you
know then I have to you know I have to
like talk to them and
um you know then we can it's probably
going to
be two live streams you know like like
like two videos not not not sitting side
by side in real
life because sitting side by side that
would be more interesting that would be
not more real but that will mean you
know I have to travel or the guy has to
travel yeah that's that's going to be
more
painful but on the other hand you see
today the live streaming technology is
ubiquitous you see these kind of
interviews all the time like like you
get tired of it like any any any day
there are thousands of
it famous people interviewing another
famous people in different areas in in
in you know in all sort of areas in
politics in coding you'll see that in in
everywhere
so you
know I don't know if that's
um yeah anyway that that would be I I
can do that but you know it's not
something I
I like I uh you
know as priority or something but anyway
so let's get back to the code so what do
we have
here uh format goand code oh yeah okay
so format goand code so so I want to
change this okay hold on a second so
here's a code that format goand
uh let's do a JavaScript example okay so
because because JavaScript
is kind of more popular and
uh and you don't have to I mean Goan is
more
um I mean JavaScript is like more
scripting language so it's easier to
understand so here's a code to format
JavaScript code you have format
region then you have format buffer then
you have format
file okay and what I want to do is I
want to modify the code so that they
don't call a
shell so you see right now they are
called
shell why do you want you know so you
don't want to call Shell because when
you call Shell that means it has go go
you know it has to start shell so it's
actually
slower uh also problematic when you have
your file name or any
arguments you have to escape all those
quotes so for example if your file name
got a space in it or got a quote in it
or got backslash in it or got any like
parenthesis or square bracket or curly
braces then it's going to be hell
because when you pass when you co sh you
have to like Escape all those those
special uh symbols and that's like
sometimes
impossible
so usually it's better to not Co shell
and call a start external command
directly so let me show you what that is
okay so recently I've been updating my
tutorial so you can
see uh
start external process so here's a page
iMac this start external process
normally okay so normally you would call
Shell you know this is very simple you
can call date you know uh you know
return a date for example let's do
it okay if I evaluate this
code uh what
uh it returns one
why
well I don't know what is the you know
because pow shell you don't know what
the date
is oh yeah because you see the problem
another problem is in emac when it call
Shell on Windows when you are on in emx
Windows it calls the command. ex C so
it's not calling Powers shell so that so
if you want to call Powershell you have
to say
pwsh date okay let's try
that uh 64 no the date is not o so you
have to say
command so emx shell command is calling
command. exe then in command. exe you
call Powershell you start Powershell
this then you say command date then it
will return the date uh
well well the date is here but it
Returns value is zero so it gets comp
complicated so anyway that's some of the
issues when you call sh command because
on Windows on Mac on Linux they run
different sh commands so that affects
what you
know affect your portal ability so
instead you want to
call uh you want to call one of
these start external process core
process okay core
process you know so if you use that
there are several of them cor process
and cor process region
or start process the difference between
them is that when we wait for the
process to finish if but if you call
start process it will not wait so you
can call this then you don't have to
they don't you know it doesn't start the
shells you know you directly call the
command okay that's
why uh you it's much preferable in emac
to uh call one of the start process or
call process if you want to call
external
programs uh AO avoid shell when possible
okay so let's delete
that uh so let's demo shall we demo okay
let's demo Cod process okay so make it
emac this mod Cod process okay so
program is going to be
Powershell and uh option
infile infile is Neo that's a standard
input uh destination is a output buffer
okay destination let's say Neil
okay uh let's just try Neil Neil and uh
then argument is going to
[Music]
be that okay something like that so
actually you want to they needs to be
separate create uh actually they can be
the anyway let's try that okay
so EV evaluate it well it it did it too
so do
it yeah it it does it it returns zero
so uh let's say e Echo date okay so Echo
actually make it
return EV valuated uh zero
no
uh that's you know let's not use uh
let's say get date
okay
help get
date yeah that's a
command so now if you say that evaluate
it yeah it returns
zero oh yeah yeah that's right it
Returns the well that's because emx the
output is actually in a
buffer um so if you you want the output
to be in this destination so that would
be
here so it would be above buffer name
let's see destination is a buffer for
output okay if T is current buffer oh
okay so T is a current perer okay so now
let's evaluate this evaluate it there it
is beautiful now can you can you try
let's try the old let's
see evaluated beautiful that works
too so you see instead of shell you um
you know instead of code shell command
it's better to use start code process
okay okay okay that's what I want to
kind of explain uh now let's go back
[Music]
to talk
show okay so what I actually want to do
is actually to
rewrite uh rewrite my JavaScript
format you know reformat JavaScript code
so instead of calling a sh command you
would call Coe sh command co uh core
process am I doing good
jie
says jie are you PR J JY says what are
your thoughts on based ARA being based
what does space entail for you
that's pru pru that's a idiotic
question uh well that's a te question so
what does Bas mean base means it's a
it's a Zuma slam
it you know it's a slant from the like
the teenagers of the past 10
years so what does it mean well
originally means it's someone who does
not care about what how other thinks so
in a classic sense of the word you can
say it's a
okay let's go to definition
conformist a person who un critically or
habitually conforms to the Customs rules
or styles of a group okay so that's the
Standard English word
conformist
today the same word in zuma jargon would
be called NPC non playing character okay
like we talked about yesterday or was it
the day
before you know this character
NPC I support the current thing which is
the video uh live
stream subject matter we talked about
yesterday uh
okay we are staying from iMac you know
there I support the current thing non
playing
character the idea is borrowed from a
game so that would be a
conformist that's the kind of people who
just follow the
trend uh you know follow the trend the
group The Rules the custom the tradition
you know whatever you know the current
uh
environment so the Jon based is the
opposite of conformist so that's called
non-conformist that's what I
am so let's see if we can get the
definition well okay there it is you
know not conforming to some norms or or
Society approved pattern of behavior or
thought nonconformist okay so the Jon
based is the Zuma idiot version of
nonconformist
nonconforming so that's what it means
spaced uh but you know in the past 10
years
it's the the Zoomers you know the
teenagers they they don't know anything
they they just chant you know like oh
this is space that space that's just you
know it's
teenagers JG okay so what do I think of
it well I think you should think okay
you
should try to be a independent
thinker how do you become an independent
thinker stop watching watching
TV 20 years ago today most people don't
watch TV anymore you know so but what
does it mean is that stop following on
Twitter stop reading your Reddit stop
reading your for Chanel stop reading
your Hacker News stop like glue your
have your eyes glued to your cell phone
and have whatever you know social
network social you know website you know
stream
that eats your
brain stop doing that stop consuming any
information that comes to you
free okay so how do you get information
then get information from your friends
from your family or from from your
active participation like you really for
example you you you want to know how
let's say virus works you actively seek
out that information you can start to
check Wikipedia as a first step or check
other encyclopedias you know you know
there's quite a lot out there britanica
for example and and or check what you
know textbooks there's a lot textbooks
on biology on viruses or there's the you
can also use Reddit or or for Chan but
usually they are not useful for this
question so the point is you actively
seek whatever question the information
you want never passively consume
information like oh I'm gonna you know
I'm into emx I'm into programming I'm
GNA follow the current uh you know the
programming top 10 you know this you
know he's got 1 million followers oh I'm
going to follow this guy oh I'm I'm
going to follow Paul grham the creator
of hacker
new I'm going to follow the
HDD the guy who created Ruby on Rails
that idiot you know that's most most of
you people are doing that's why every
day you are like oh rust rust or or this
that that
brainless okay so that is my opinion so
Bas based based what does it
mean most of these Zuma idiots it basic
is just for for is just a chant it's a
slogan based like whenever you see
something you know someone like me or
you know like someone someone who is
like funny like idiotic or poor or or
[ __ ] or got some problems you know
you watch it for fun oh this guy is
space that that's what that's what most
of these these teenage idiots are
okay and Luke Smith he understand it so
Luke Smith he in fact his YouTube I
watched a few because often times my
name is mentioned together with his
name Luke Smith he's a smart guy he
understand he know what you know he
understand he he he in fact I would say
he shares a lot of opinions as me even
though he's Vim guy I'm a emac user
um but you know some technical details
we don't share like for example his love
for Linux but overall I think we we are
compatible so but Luke Smith understand
this Zuma te stuff so he's video If you
go to his
YouTube you
see Luke Smith his
thumbnails is all this Zuma crap you
see I despise these
things but
however you know he he's into you know
capturing audience so he get you know
he's got you know like 10 times more
followers than me you know he captures
you guys you guys who are into the the
the the oh based Bas or whatever
joggin he captures
that you know so that's
you know that's that's that's that's his
style
okay so that is my answer what do you
what do I think of based okay I think
you should have it's better if you have
independent thinking and I told you how
to uh try to get that okay and I think
that's it for today one
hour okay
I think that's it for today and uh I was
going to code something for myself but
instead I just explained it okay but
that's that's okay so anyway hope you
guys enjoy the video
bye
guys thank
you uh what else so we did we talk about
emx yes we talked about formatting we
demonstrated running the code uh and you
can get the code
and we talked about um yeah we talked
about calling the shell command versus
coding code process you you see it's
easy it's very easy to code a shell
command call you know all you have to do
is just give it a string just as you
would type it on a
terminal but however if you want to uh
skip shell and call the program whatever
external program directly it's a bit
more involved so you need to understand
buffer because you you need to pass it a
buffer uh you need to deal with uh for
example this's error out standard error
you know so you know you you
also have to deal with that so but I do
have a tutorial as usual that explain
the whole thing
so so if you guys you know for you
learning emac
lisp you know you can check out my
tutorial okay that's it and uh you know
so pay me okay so you go to my
homepage emac and you can buy my emac
tutorial $30 $30
plus uh so you get the whole emac
website
free uh you can use it as a reference or
you can buy my other
packages Kar emac packages you know I
have a quite a
few and uh or you can buy my JavaScript
tutorial or just directly just pay me
patreon Amazon PayPal okay thank you
guys okay shut down in one
minute so format JavaScript code close
conformist yeah let's copy the
conformist what does it mean what does
it mean
based you know those people these young
Zuma idiots that's what I call them Zuma
idiots why because they are that's and
it's not their fault they are that way
because when they were born the minute
they were
born they are in the environment of
clickbait of the trolls of the [ __ ] post
of the memes that's what they see every
day since since they were conceived in
their mom's
tummy so they don't know what the what
the [ __ ] is conformist but they know
based based based oh that's
based The Zuma idiots
Zuma
generation you see the word conformist
is from
1625 okay and I'm a non-conformist for
for uh for reasons okay I just have been
because my family was bad it's a
dysfunctional family and so on like like
many of you guys okay so there's a word
nonconformist you know you should so you
don't need the
hyphen uh and here is Luke
Smith okay looks Smith handsome
guy looks I'm not gay by the
way let's capture yeah well let's
capture his you know let's do a
screenshot of his website so actually we
have a record does he have like the
latest one year ago did he didn't he say
like he's going to stop making videos
yeah open that delete that open that
okay that's good showing browser a