Good morning. Good evening. Good
afternoon. Hello guys. Welcome to
another episode of Kxalo
show. Kxalo show.
Let's see scene one, scene two.
So, are you looking at me? Let's see.
What are you seeing? You are seeing me.
And so, let's show my desktop. There you
go. And today's talk show. So, we're
going to talk about cascading style
sheet.
That's one of the technology for the web
and it turns out over the past 30 years,
the cascading style sheet became hugely
hugely important.
They became critical because the cascade
cascading style sheet
they became the way you control user
interface of software.
You know, in the beginning it's just for
the web. You know, it's like
back in 1997,
around there, the cascading style sheet
was
offered. You know, in the beginning the
idea is Am I here? Are you guys watching
me? Say hi, okay?
If you are here, comment, okay? So, let
me pop this out.
Um pop the chat. So, we are talking
about cascading style sheet today.
Hello, Juan.
Uh I'm looking at you. Fantastic.
Okay, so cascading style sheet. So, back
in 1997,
around there,
you know, they began to start
offering cascading style sheet.
Right? If you
Well, most of you probably have
heard of it. So, you you can look at my
cascading style sheet. This is for my
website. So, my website My My website is
extremely lean. kxali.info
and kxali.org. Okay, just search for it.
You'll find it. Extremely lean.
And And so, my cascading style sheet is
only 900 lines of code. And
12 kilobytes.
If you go to Google or Wikipedia or any
other website, they they are like 500 um
like 100 kilobytes or few hundred
kilobytes.
Okay. So anyway, so so here is what
cascading style sheet
uh code looks like. CSS.
Cascade, you know. Why is it called
cascade? It's like waterfall, you know,
which is what we're going to talk about
today, okay? So any anyway, so if I can
uh seven, it began.
Uh originally, it was just for the web
so that you can have pretty things like
all these color, you know, graphics
design. You like that user interface
design, you can uh you know, actually I
I should show you some websites from
1999.
You can see there's lots of pretty
designs, okay?
Uh
anyway, so
CSS style sheet, cascading style sheet.
So originally, it was just for the web,
but
turns out after 30 years, it became
overwhelming because it became
>> [snorts]
>> very popular. It became that it became
how
other software
user interface are done. For example, if
you're going to code uh software for
Windows or for Mac or for Linux, you're
going to use CSS. A lot of them adopted
CSS.
Now, I haven't done uh user interface uh
application
software before, so I don't actually
know how do you create a software
application on Windows or Mac or on
Linux. Like you use um
you know, you you you use the Gnome, you
know, the the the dev, you know,
libraries
framework. Uh but I only know web. So, I
know web, you know, I was a web dev
since like 1999.
So, but anyway, cascading style sheet
took over. So, you know, so you write
this basically today like I think
it became critical, you know, you you
you you write this to control how your
software or website
works.
I mean, even if you are not using the
the like the
the VS code, what they call it, Atom.
Is it called Atom engine?
Anyway, CSS, okay? So,
you're looking at the CSS, you know, so
you you know, in the past month, I've
been working on CSS a lot, so updating
my website. You can check it out.
Visual CSS. Just go to my website, okay?
You see these funky things, that's
because I enlarge the font without
enlarging the uh
I enlarge my website but without
enlarging the image images. So, you may
see some this artifact there. You see?
Anyway, so
so check out, you know, xahlee.info. So,
let me go to my website. So, x a h l e e
.info. You can see all these programming
language tutorials. Got this
font
enlargement problem.
Hacker code, okay? That's what we are.
Hackers.
So, you can check out all sort of
tutorials on
CSS, HTML, these program language,
JavaScript, PowerShell, and so on, go
that.
Cheers. Today is cocktail.
Some red wine, some mar- margarita
and some red wine.
So,
Juan says, "I hate
Whenever I can, I use pre-built styles."
Mhm. Well, eventually you have to learn
it because it's it's kind of interesting
because
because if you think about about what
CSS does,
you know, it controls the layout, you
know, it controls where to put like
where to put where you can have like
layout, you know, that's what called
layout, okay?
Uh of any page, I mean any application,
any program, any website like right now
we looking at Twitter.
Uh Twitter um
or you have Discord. Discord is actually
written in Atom, so it's actually a web
page, you know, Discord. So, we looking
at Discord is actually a web page. But,
I mean any application For example, this
OBS, okay? So, you see this OBS
application for live stream.
It is
Now, I don't know how it is written,
what framework, but I would guess this
All these are CSS, okay? All these
cascading style sheets just take over. I
could be wrong, but that's my guess,
okay? Now, how do you put this back?
Uh Jesus, options.
Uh
There's no close window. Uh
Jesus, what?
Stupid uh
interface design. How do you put the
audio back? I don't know.
Okay, so anyway, that's uh some random
talk about CSS. That's how important it
became. So, you have to deal with it.
Hello, uh Minds Ethiopia.
First time catching us live.
What?
What do you think about Tailwind have
you ever tried it?
>> [laughter]
>> Are you sure this is the first time you
watch me?
Or are you like trolling?
Okay, OBS is QT Juan says OBS is QT.
It has CSS but that is
only for colors not for layout.
Okay, I didn't know.
But anyway, a lot of them, you know,
desktop apps are adopting CSS. But you
know, yeah, so here's an interesting
thing. You see, if you don't use CSS,
what what is the alternative? You see a
application design, let's let's use the
OBS for example because
it's an app, right? So you look at So
let's move this back here. Oh, you can
now you can pop it back, okay? So you
see this is OBS, right? It's a software.
Now, there's a layout, right? You can
you know, control these windows, you can
whether this
you can decide whether they they can be
dragged out or not. You can, you know,
layout, you know, you can resize, you
know,
I don't want to mess my config, but
anyway.
You see, but how do you do it? How do
you code this?
One way is CSS which we are familiar.
You know, you can like each of these is
element then you say what is the margin,
what is the padding and so and so on.
Okay, CSS is kind of complicated
actually. You know, actually it's pretty
simple to learn. You can learn it in one
day. You know, like especially like all
the color stuff, like colors, you know,
you can learn how to do all these colors
in in one day all the uh bold, you know,
font size,
uh whether you want it bold or you can
do a you know, like
But but when you start to do layout,
like actual layout, then it gets
very complex. Like you can you got this
play they they get more and more complex
over the past 30 years. Okay, you got
you got this you know, for example,
recently in the past 5 years, we got
this flex box layout, okay, which is
very nice.
Uh but it it only came out like uh 5
years ago.
Pretty new, so I only wrote this page
last month, okay. Well, I began it last
year, but you know, I basically finished
writing this
just last month.
So, when you when it comes to layout, it
become complex. But anyway, back to the
question. So, you are designing a
website, right? You one way to do it
with CSS, but but what's the other way?
Or what is the alternative?
How do you What is the programming
language
of computer language such that it allows
you to specify, you know, I want a box
here, and I want text go inside here, I
want another box over there, and I want
a button here. How do you specify all
these positions and window, you know,
pixel? How do you do it?
Okay, that is the question. You see, I
don't know I haven't coded desktop app
before, so I don't know I don't know how
you know, people do that before CSS, but
anyway.
Okay. Okay. Okay. So, let's go what we
going to talk about. I was going to um
Well, I was going to
like um give you guys a lesson of the
cascading
uh
complexity of CSS, okay? Let me just
talk random, okay? Because that's what I
do the best.
Uh delete that. Now, first of all, I
want to tell you I made a change to Xah
HTML mode of Emacs Lisp.
My most advanced package, you see.
That's what I do for life.
Uh let's see.
Press press press press press press
press. That is a key to invoke
XHTML mode, okay? Now, let's see. Let's
magnify the font a bit more.
Oh god, it only magnified tiny, okay.
Anyway, so you go to the source code.
Uh
there are 3,000 lines of code here, but
actually 1 2 3, so there you got uh
XHTML 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 eight files.
So, together
What?
Together, they are about, I think,
over 10,000 lines of code.
Okay.
Uh so, what I did, you know, I made a
change so that you can see Wait.
So, the beginning tags are in one color,
the ending tags are in different color,
you see. That's a very very interesting
uh convention that I'm trying it out. I
think I'll like it. You see, so you can
move to the end tag, you press a key, it
delete the entire
box, including all the nested inside,
okay? So, for example, if your cursor is
here, let's say if your cursor is here,
uh press a key, it removes all the white
spaces before it.
Press a key, it removes the box above
it, including all the nested ones. See,
it's amazing, beautiful. Undo. Undo.
Undo. Undo. Okay, so this is
what you're looking at is XHTML
mode. You have to pay me to get it,
okay?
Uh
go to go to go to go to go to the top
and here is the link. You can see the
home page. The home page hasn't been
aggressively updated, but
but it's like you pay me $30. I should
increase it $200, okay?
Then you get it because for 10 years
it's free and I die of hunger.
Open source
scum.
Open source is a huge scam taken over by
the deep state for in the past 20 years.
ACP
ACP, where are you from ACP? I forgot.
Are you from India and you are a
student, right? It's like you are
watching my video every day.
You don't have [snorts] nothing to do
just like me. Am I correct?
So ACP says, "Ksatria, did you cast a
vote in the primaries?" No.
Well, that looks like you are American.
Primaries, no.
I voted once in my like 20 years of
eligibility, 25.
I voted once for Trump
2 years ago
and that what the what a [ __ ] mistake
that became. Trump is became the
greatest
American criminal.
Trump, you know, and we voted for him.
Very sad because the you know, so how
could you become how
how could you fall for such a trap
because it's fairly complicated.
>> [snorts]
>> Okay, Trump became the greatest criminal
in USA history, I would say, you know,
in fact it it it you know, the things
they've done
is not tolerable. It's it's you know,
it's I could go to detail, then YouTube
is going to ban me, okay? So, these
things we cannot talk about.
Uh
>> [sighs]
>> well, enjoy life while you are still uh
Can you see me? Am I alive? Am I dead
yet? Not yet.
Uh sad story.
Okay, I I voted one time for AFD.
For funny before they got popular. What
is AFD?
Uh let's say
uh Obama, let's say Biden, let's say
before that
then you got the the Bush [ __ ] face.
So, what is AFD?
And then before that you got the
Clinton, the scum. You know, Clinton is
the one one of the greatest criminal,
okay? The especially the
Hillary Clinton.
Um
Why have you not visit China? Yeah, it
it takes money, you see? I'm I'm like
kind of a poor guy.
Oh, AFD is Alternative for Germany. Oh,
okay. Well, I don't know what's going on
in Germany and uh
Well, Germany, you see,
we starting to talk about politics, you
see?
Germany and UK, especially these two in
Europe, in the entire Europe, Eastern
Europe or Western Europe, you know, like
5 years ago, I don't even know what's
the difference, like
like I I I was creating a unicorn map
and I was trying to classify. So, which
country are Eastern Europe? Which
country are Western, you know? I was
confused.
Take took me several days. I post on
Twitter and and people Jesus, no, that's
not what you crazy, that's not Eastern
European. That's you know
So, it took me several days to correct
it. Uh, let's see. So, I was doing this
page.
This page was created 2017. That's about
Unicode flags or in other words, flags
of the world, okay? And in order to make
it easy to re- read, I want to classify
categorize the countries into like
regions, so people can easily see be-
for example,
Northern Europe, all the flags are
similar. You you got Iceland, Denmark,
Norway, Finland, Sweden.
And uh, this rare rare really known
Allen Islands, okay?
And Western Europe, you know, I need to
group them. So, but I wasn't sure like
what what how is like how do you define
exactly Western Europe, Southern Europe,
Central Europe, and Eastern?
Like obviously, UK is Western. That
everyone knows. And and Ireland, okay?
But then
then the France, for example, well,
couldn't it be Southern Europe? Like you
don't know. Like
After all, they are like all all close
together, right?
>> [snorts]
>> So, it took me several days to create
this. And and anyway, what I want to say
by the mention of your comment, Huang,
is that basically, Germany
this big [ __ ] country, Germany. Germany
is a big a very powerful uh,
group of people, okay?
Germany and the United Kingdom
these two
are what we would go what they call
white men, okay? You know, the the the
the jargon, white men has been
personally to me
you know, like
you know, they are popularized by the
social justice warriors in the past 10
years. White men. White men is white
men. White men evil, you know, white
men.
So, what?
So, I didn't know. So what like
You know, so well, white man, what does
it mean? Well, it means like people
looks white, you know, blonde and blue
eyes or not necessarily, but
but that's not the case because Russian
the Russian girls the hottest people,
you know, hot hottest girls the
Russians. They are not white.
And you
you know, the technically the this white
people the United Kingdom and the German
guys hate the word Russians, okay? The
Russians are not like white.
And there's [clears throat] another
group
which became so
widely talked about in USA because they
are doing some
uh things in Middle East, okay? This
this group of people.
And they are they are just like white
men. Like I didn't know like to me they
are like white men. I never thought
about it.
And then turns out, oh my god, Jesus,
there's a big difference, you know.
Uh yeah, but anyway, so
uh we're getting into a hot topic.
Maybe we should exit now, okay? So
because you see
So you see and one thing I learned I
learned so much about politics and you
know
is that uh by the way, the USA census
there's no special group for the
for these for these Middle East kind of
the special
uh people.
You know, they are just in uh USA census
they are considered white men, okay? So
are they white men? You know, that
depends on who you ask, okay? It's a
It turns out it's very complicated that
that that this group of people.
And uh
well, they are not doing things uh very
good things, okay?
So anyway, you got the United Kingdom
and the Germany. They
You know, in my view I learned they are
the most aggressive people.
And the what is the question? Oh, well,
you were talking about um
You know, yeah, we know it what the
group that is, but we shall not talk
about that because, you know, it's
because in in USA it's interesting that
you can criticize lots of groups, but
not that one.
Okay?
>> [laughter]
>> You got to be very careful. Um okay, so
that's unjust.
Anyway, so I was going to say Germany
and UK, they basically they are puppets
of USA, okay? Germany and and also
including France,
Ireland, you know, they are they are
nothing, you know, they like but anyway,
the the big powers is like Germany
and UK. Not not so much. They are not
powers anymore like and France. Okay,
they are not
not today, you know.
Maybe
30 years ago they are like powerful, but
not today. Anyway, they are just puppets
of USA, okay?
And USA is puppet of the other country.
Sad to know, but
anyway.
They don't check ethnicity in Germany.
They only check our nationality, of
course.
I mean, it's it you like by the white
man's culture you are not supposed to
check ethnicity. However, the ethnicity
is the most sensitive topic among
Now, the creeper guy, what are you
talking about? Like what white something
isn't real?
Like yesterday you was talking [ __ ]
about some AI is not fake news. It's
fake news or something. Anyway.
So, let's see what we going to uh
Okay, Unicode. Let's quickly can we like
quickly uh talk about Yeah. So, I was
telling you guys, you see I got the new
scheme coloring scheme where the ending
tag is colored
differently from the beginning tag.
Okay? So, it allows me to like, you
know, delete the whole header, for
example.
Uh
Okay. So, that's uh just interesting
thing. Okay. Now, go back to today's
talk show.
Uh let's talk about CSS specificity.
Can we?
Shall we?
Okay. So, uh what else you guys are
interested? Shall we you know, maybe I
should quickly actually go through this
because
every time I start the video, either I
don't start the live stream or if I
start, I start to ramble for hours
without actually talking about the
things
I'm supposed to cover.
Uh so, but that is the story of my life.
So, cascade. Okay. So, CSS, you got the
cascade.
And specificity.
Okay. And in the past few years, you got
a new thing called cascade cascade
layer, which you can customize. Okay.
So, let me give let me do actually talk
about them for like 20 minutes. Okay.
Let me see the comment. Uh
Culture is more important. Ethnicity
doesn't mean anything. Okay.
Uh
Yeah, you are right. For example, you
know, if you use uh look at the Chinese
in USA, okay? They are so-called
American-born Chinese, ABC, you know, in
our in this community. Actually, I'm not
part of that community, but in this, you
know, Chinese community, they are called
ABC.
Means American-born Chinese, okay? But
if you look at them, they are not
Chinese. They are just They are [ __ ]
white people, okay? Because they talk,
they think
like white people. They just like white
people with yellow skin, okay? That
those born in America
Chinese, okay? And I'm not
I think
I still more like, you know, I have like
I have both, but I have roots in
Chinese, okay? So
So, you know, it is true
that you are really how you, you know,
your environment, who taught you.
Like, for example, today, you got a lot
white people or Europeans who were born
in China.
You start to have more and more of that.
And you talk to them, of course, they
are not like you guys Western. They look
white, but they
they talk and think like Chinese people,
okay?
You know, they look white, but they are
not, you know, they don't think like the
way you do about oh justice, oh rape, or
whatever [ __ ]
The Roman Empire you know.
They are banana. Yeah, well, that's what
they say, something.
So, can humans ever live together
peacefully?
I don't think so, okay?
Uh
to be blunt
I don't think so.
That is like Okay, so how can I, you
know, so the question, can humans ever
live together peacefully?
That question
I don't think so, but it's not absolute,
okay? It's not like, oh, then we going
to just kill each other and die, or we
going to die. No, that's not the case,
neither. The case is similar to look at
all other animals, okay? You can look at
tigers, you can look at
I don't know, lions or whatever the
other animals. They fight. They kill.
They eat each other.
Okay? Even among monkeys.
Okay, so can they live peacefully
together? Well, yes and no.
Okay, they they probably will be around.
Uh, you know, but they not going to live
peacefully together because, you know,
if you like peacefully, peace, what does
it mean?
Well, it's a philosophical idea created
by human animals. We imagine, you know,
we imagine this this concept of peace.
But you know, biologically, basically,
well
we just need to eat.
And we need to survive.
And we need to [ __ ] But you don't get,
you know, everything. Like there's, you
know, girls, they you have to fight for
the girls because the girls, they want
the king. They don't want the losers.
Okay? So, you know, you and me
the [ __ ] you have to fight.
If you fight, there's harm, there's
injury, there's death.
Okay? Because you want to [ __ ] the girl.
The girl want the winners. The girl
don't want the losers.
They don't want, you know, the girl is
not going to say, oh, yeah, let's have a
threesome.
>> [laughter]
>> So, that's the origin
of this, uh um
not piece, okay, that is the like the
fundamental
reason, but
So, anyway.
Um
so, let me think about, okay? So, how
long have I talked about Let's see. I
talked for
30 minutes, okay? Now, let me do 20
minutes about Let's talk about cascading
style sheet.
Okay, all you guys here eight watching,
say hi, okay?
Now, let me talk about cascading style
sheet. So,
So, CSS, you have, you know, one of the
uh issue you have in CSS is that you
have the
conflict of priority.
Like, you can specify, you know, this
element should be red, but in some other
place, you also specify that element
should be blue. So, which one, you know,
is it going to be red or blue, for
example?
Um
For example, let me get uh show you. For
example, this
this you're looking at, okay? Can you
see?
Can you guys see? Is it clear? Is it big
enough? Okay. So, you got HTML element.
You got P tag, paragraph. You got ID for
that paragraph.
ID attribute. You got a class attribute.
Then, it says, "Good morning."
Okay, that's an element. HTML. Then, you
got CSS that specify the style. What
style should it be? Now, if the ID
match, then it should be green, it says.
Now, this part says, "If the
if the element is a paragraph it should
be red.
This element says if the class is this
class it should be blue.
So you can see
all of them match this element. So what
color should it be? They conflict. You
know, there's a conflict of interest.
So you need to have some sense of
priority. You know, who is who is got
you know, who is considered more
important. That's a problem.
So this is an example of
CSS rule conflict. Okay. Now how do you
resolve this? How does CSS resolve this?
It It is resolved by
what's called cascade. Okay. It's So
there actually there's several
mechanisms I'm going to explain today.
Okay. So the first the topmost uh
mechanism is called cascade. That's the
name cascading style sheet came for.
Cascade. So what does it mean? Okay. So
first is the origin of the specification
like color or style whatever origin. For
example, you have uh for example, inline
style has higher priority than page
style.
And page style has higher priority than
external style file.
And that has higher priority than the
browser style sheet. Okay. So what does
that mean? So let me show you example.
So origin, okay. The first way to
determine which rule is has priority is
the origin.
So what is what does that mean origin?
Well, so you know, for example, you can
add a style to a element like that. This
is called inline style. Because you
embed a style equals to attribute to the
HTML element. Okay. Direct direct. This
is inline style.
Another way to add style sheet is you
add a style tag to the whole page. The
style will apply to the entire page. So,
for example,
for example, let's look at today's talk
show, okay? Now, let's see I want to add
Let's go to this URL. I forgot I'm Let's
make it list make a list, you see? Now,
it's a list UL unordered list. Showing
browser,
you can see now it's a list. Now, let's
make a style, okay? So, now you see this
is the link
anchor href something target blank,
okay? Now, let's add
add a class, let's say style,
and let's say color
let's say let's say
red blue purple. Let's say brown, okay?
Now, go back to browser. You see right
now it's blue. Now, if I refresh it,
it'll be brown. Refresh, you see?
Fantastic. That is because I got this
inline style. You see it? Like inline
inside this element, you know,
direct apply to it.
And I can make it
more, let's say,
font size, let's say three REM root
element size,
three times.
Refresh.
Okay, let's let's We are doing inline
style, okay? Go back here.
Go back go back go go back go back go
Okay, wait. I'll go back to the other
page. So, we were explaining what is
inline style, okay? Now, what is page
style? Page style is if I go to the top,
and here I add
a style tag, and in this style tag I
want to say
everything that's a tag of A that should
have color. uh
What color? Gold. Golden.
Golden shower. Okay.
Now, if you go back to the browser
and refresh,
you see, oh, they all become gold. Well,
except this one, because this one,
you know, that one is got the inline
style of color,
which overrides
has higher priority than the page style.
So, you can Can you guys see?
Is it clear? Do I have clarity in this
live stream talk show?
Good morning, sir. Okay.
Are you guys still watching? Does that
make sense?
Okay.
Is that Does that make sense?
So, we talked about the page style, so
which is this thing, and we got the
inline style, which is right here. Okay.
Okay, what What are the other ways?
Well, you can have inline style, you can
have page style, and you can have
external style sheet. What you do is you
add this link
tag,
which refers to a file.
Okay, so, for example, on this page, we
can go up, go up,
go up, go up, go up, go up. And here,
you got a link
reference.
That stand for I E L stand for I forgot
what I stand for I E L. But anyway, this
means, you know, this is a style sheet.
Okay. Now, open that, so you got the
whole file.
This entire file
is all styles. Okay.
So, that is for my entire website, so
every file can link to this style. So,
9,100 900
lines of code.
Okay? Do I make sense? Do I make sense?
I make sense?
Okay? So, you got inline style. So,
So, that is so, you know, you got
several ways
adding cascading style sheet.
Now,
if you go back, the cascading rule says
origin
is how you first of all determine
priority. The first way to determine
priority, okay? Inline style has the
highest priority then
page style then external file. Okay?
Then the browser style sheet the browser
actually got a style.
Uh because, for example, if I comment
out this
my external style file
and
delete this page style, delete it,
and go to this uh also remove the inline
style,
remove it. Now, showing showing browser,
refresh what we are going to get.
Refresh. Refresh, you see?
You got like nothing.
No style. Actually, there's a style. The
style it's using is the browser's
style.
Now, how do you view the browser style?
You can.
So, the browser style actually so,
you know, I have it I discussed
somewhere. So, there is you can actually
view the browser default style sheet,
okay? It's available on GitHub.
So, you got Google Chrome style, you
know, Google Chrome browser style, and
you got Firefox, you know, and so on.
So, here is an example of Google's
browser style sheet.
So,
it lies at the bottom. So, when you
visit a page that doesn't have any
styles at all, just pure HTML, no CSS,
you still
you're still kind of formatted, you
know, for example, this is H2 header,
big font, and link are in blue and
underlined. And
if you hover, you notice the cursor
becomes
of a finger like that.
You see, a pointing finger, you see. So,
that's a browser style, okay?
So, cascading style sheet says
priority,
inline first,
page style second, then external style,
then last is the browser style sheet,
okay?
Now, what if in the same origin, for
example, in the same origin,
for example, now let's put it back
showing browser. Fantastic, beautiful.
You see, now I have my style. Now, you
see, let's do it again. Remove that,
refresh, do it. You see?
That's the browser style or no style.
Now, I want my style back.
Refresh, you see? Fantastic.
Now, if you go to a cascade, so we want
to Yeah, okay, so if you
So, if if you have a situation where
uh
where Okay, I already explained that. If
you have a situation like we talked
before, the style conflict, for example,
these three All these are in a style
sheet, a style file. They are in the
same origin.
So, according to origin,
they are all in
style sheet, so it doesn't resolve their
priority. Then, the second way to
resolve priority is called specific
specific
Okay, this is a complicated word.
Specificity.
Wait, specific specificity.
Okay, that's
How is it? How are you supposed What is
the proper
>> [gasps]
>> um
um
Wait, how do you say How do they say?
Yeah, the the browser style
They are similar, but they are not the
same.
That's why if you have a plain page, you
know, in different browser, they they
they they are
different. Okay, they are slightly
different. So, [snorts] that's why many
of the web dev when they create a style,
they
the first thing they do in in their
style sheet is clear all browser style.
So, what they do is, for example, I can
show you.
So, what they do the first first of all,
what they do is for for everything, the
root. Actually, they they do You can do
that for for all all tags, okay?
Reset.
Wait, not that.
I think they reset in it, okay?
Something, you know, anyway, so the
point is that you
you basically delete
all browser styles.
Uh actually, one of the common thing
they actually people actually do is um
is this is Let me show you, okay?
Uh
border
Yeah, so this this three lines this five
lines people actually do. So
for all HTML element, they make it
box-sizing border-box, okay?
>> [snorts]
>> Which means um which means it change the
meaning of width. So when you have
box-sizing
border-box, that means
width
counts also the border and padding,
okay?
Because if you don't if you don't say
this box-sizing border-box, then
width will only mean the content. So
when you add padding and border, it will
change your your your your goal actually
your change your element size. So if
your your layout become shifted anyway.
Am I clear on this? I don't think so,
but I'm not going to talk about this,
okay?
So you can but you can look it up, okay?
Just ask AI box-sizing border-box. This
is important. So and you So basically
these five lines will clear
um
Wait, actually the the things they
actually do is I didn't explain well,
but you you you you look it up, you'll
see it uh
What people do is that they they do
this, okay? Margin
padding
so that they clear all elements margin
and padding. Actually, they do it like
that.
Uh
that, okay? So they clear every elements
uh
margin and padding. So they set that
themselves anyway.
Look if you said this, you can ask AI.
AI will tell you all about it, okay?
So, let's see. Did I change anything to
this file?
Uh
yes, I did, but that's before, okay?
So, am I so far so good? Okay, I changed
that.
Um
Yeah, okay.
Uh
I just want to make sure I didn't [ __ ]
up anything.
So, anyways, so we talked about cascade.
Then, the next thing if the conflict uh
or within the same origin, the next
thing you consider is called specis
sp- specificities.
Specificity.
How uh what is the uh how they say this?
Um
Like where do they put the em- emphasis
on the word?
Okay.
Specificity. Okay, something like that.
Specif- specificity.
Okay, so let's ask Google, okay?
Let's see what Google says.
In a cascading style sheet, you have the
concept of specificity.
Can you say that?
>> Yeah, CSS specificity is basically how
the browser decides which style wins
when multiple rules apply.
>> repeat that?
>> Sure, CSS specificity is how the browser
decides which style wins when multiple
>> CSS specificity.
CSS specificity.
Repeat that three times, please.
>> CSS specificity. CSS specificity. CSS
specificity.
>> CSS
Wait, specificity.
This is incorrect. Specificity.
Okay, anyway. So,
so what does this mean? That means
you know, the way when
these CSS rules are all in the same
origin. So, now you have you have a
problem. You have to You have to
determine which one has priority. Okay,
the way this works is that you
you classify each of the tag matching
so-called selectors. You classify them
by, you know, you got ID selectors,
attribute selectors, you got
tag name selectors, you got class name
attribute selectors. So, you classify
them and give each type of selectors a
different score. Okay? The score are
usually three numbers written as a
triplet, ABC.
So, if it's a ID selector, you
you score it one on the first slot.
Okay? If it's a attribute selector,
including class, then it's a score on
the second slot. Okay? Or if it's a
pseudo class selector, it's also the
second slot.
Then, if you have type selector, which
is tag name, and pseudo element
selector, then you put a score of one to
the third slot.
Okay?
So, so when you whenever you have a
rule, you can check, you know, how many
ID selectors are there. Typically, just
one because it's not possible to have
two ID selectors, okay? So, if you got
if it's if it has one ID selector like
this case, you add one to the first
number, okay? Then,
check if it has class selector or
others. If there's one, add it. If not
if not, don't add it, okay? So, that's
how you
get this triplet
uh number.
Three numbers, okay? That's called
specificity score, okay? Then, you can
compare the score when you have two
selectors like one here, one here. So,
this one, you got ID selector, that's
all, that's one. And no other, so that's
1 0 0 score, okay?
Then, this one is you got a
tag name selector, so that would be the
you add a one to the last number, so so
this selector would be 0 0 1
because it got no others. Then, you
compare the score of these two, this is
1 0 0, this is 0 0 1.
The
the bigger number in front wins, okay?
So, this ID selector has higher priority
than this tag name selector, okay?
And this mechanism is called
specificity,
okay? So, this is how
CSS resolve conflicts when
the cascade is a tie. You know, they
came from the same place. The cascade is
a tie, then you go to specificity,
okay?
Okay? So, that's that resolve
a lot problem, lots of, you know,
priority issues, but you still have
other uh
unresolved conflict. For example,
so when you have, for example, like
this, for example, P color red,
but if you at the bottom you have P
color blue, which one has priority? Does
the first one,
you know, they are the same specificity
because both of them are identical P,
you know, just a tag name P, something,
but one occurs
earlier, one occurs at the bottom. So
which one come has priority? In that
case, the one that comes later has
priority, okay? That's part of the
cascade. So now, in summary, understand
the cascade concept.
You got
the CSS rule origin
that determines the priority, okay? If
it's a tie, then you check the
specificity
of the selector.
Okay? Which means you each selector is
classified,
given a score, then you compare.
Basically, ID has the highest priority.
Tag name has the lowest priority.
Attribute names like classes like
middle.
Okay?
That's how you determine
selectors, okay?
If it's tie, a tie two, for example, you
have the exactly the same selector in
the same file.
The, you know, so both have the same
score, it you know, then
you determine by the source code order,
okay? Later ones
has priority.
Okay? So this is the
this is called
cascade of cascading style sheet. That's
what That's what cascade means, okay?
Like like a waterfall, like a
like a hierarchy of rules.
Which one determines priority? Now,
there's one exception, that is the
important keyword. Whenever you say
something important that made it that
makes it highest priority. Now, the
problem is if you have two rules that
both says both claims to be important,
then what happens?
Then it's more complex complicated.
Okay? Then it's like very complicated.
Anyway, so that's the basics of
cascading
priority determination. Okay? Now, the
specificity
is a bit involved, so you have to read,
you know, you have to read a little bit
to understand.
Okay?
Uh that's it. Um
then you got other selectors that you
get complicated to determine their uh
specificity.
Okay?
Like this this new this this new has
selector is any is selector, where
selector, not selector, pseudo selector.
They they are fairly complicated, okay?
They're very advanced, that's why I'm
saying
uh
CSS requires a PhD today. So, if you
haven't done so, you should watch
um
4 days ago, 5 days ago's video
where I talked about
how CSS the complexity of CSS, okay? So,
that is
uh that would be episode
aired on
May 23rd, 2026.
You need a PhD for CSS selectors, okay?
That's got this cheap out girl
thumbnail.
So, you should watch that one, okay?
That one is like a prelude to what I'm
talking about today. So, today
uh we kind of finished talking about
this, but there's one more a
It's a new feature, fantastic, very
good.
Okay, but this is like for advanced
users. This is CSS at layer.
So, basically, what this do is it
allows you to create
a layer
like so-called layer. It allows you to
create a customized
um
um like grouping of cascade. So, for all
your CSS rules, you can you can actually
put them into several different
so-called layers or groups. Okay, let's
just say groups. So, you can have group
A, group B, group C.
And you can say that A is at most
should, you know, like C should have the
highest priority than B. B should has
higher priority than A. You can say that
yourself. You can have A, B, C, D, or
whatever name. So, you can put all your
rules into like different groups and
specify order of priority. So, that
That allows you So, that is called
CSS cas- cascade at layer. Okay, that's
optional. That's custom cascade layers,
okay? This is pretty new. This is
available
Let's see browser support few years ago.
You know, this is new.
Uh when is it widely supported? 2023,
okay, 2 years ago.
It only week became supported by all
browsers
two or three years ago, okay? So, this
is called cascade at layer.
It allows you to group all
or part of your CSS rules into like
different groups and order them by
priority.
So, this is nice, similar to how you can
in a programming language, you can um
you know, you can group code into a
function,
right? And you can group functions into
modules. So, this is similar this this
is similar like grouping them into a
function.
Okay, so you can you know,
so you can so you so
so you don't have to worry so much about
the specificity
like
because the specificity is a little bit
involved. You have to know oh, you know,
which ID selector what how what score is
it?
Because once you group them, you know,
the your group priority takes
you know, resolve the priority before it
reaches the specificity, okay? So, that
is a CSS cascade layers.
You know, so I haven't done you know, I
could go into detail how do you do this,
but um
but uh do you guys want to see it? Are
we done?
Okay, so let's see.
Are we done?
Good morning, sir. Yeah, interesting.
Okay, ask Dobao Dobao.
Ask Dobao. Okay, Dobao, what is that?
What what AI is that? I think I'm done
today, okay?
Anything else, guys?
Uh God.
Got a spammer today.
Okay, so I think that's it.
And what else? I talked for an hour,
okay?
So,
a lot of things going on, especially AI.
Oh, I forgot to talk about thumbnail.
So, the thumbnail you are seeing is
quite interesting phenomenon, okay?
The thumbnail for this video they came
from
uh they came from
amazing AI, okay? They came from AI.
It's just amazing.
Amazing AI, okay? Now, Grok, you know, I
don't want to show this because Google
is going to censor me. Here because they
are girls with
tits
showing, okay? Now, Grok.
>> [snorts]
>> If you ask question, you know, there's a
Grok images. See
you ask a question it will show girls
with tits naked. Okay? It will just
even if you didn't ask for it. If you
just ask for, you know, show me a hot
chick
you know, give me some drawings of hot
chick some of the girls will be naked
with their her tits showing.
Okay? So, you can see what is this let's
say Ksaw
art blog. So, you can go to ksawli.org
art blog, okay? So, ksawli web
ksawli.org
then there is
Ksaw arts
and art blog, okay? Now, there's a new
entry, Grok AI image showing tits. I
have documented this phenomenon.
A documentation of human history, okay?
I noticed so, for example, this one I
asked Grok draw a sexy Chinese girl
wearing a wea- wearing a top that says
Emacs.
Then
then one of the image it shows tits, you
know, like
this is like
not normal.
By that I mean like typically you don't
expect this to happen in USA, okay?
Well, but today you got chatterbate, you
got, you know, porn all over, you got
the trans porn.
You got the furry porns. So, maybe this
is not surprising.
Okay, you got the gays, you got the
[ __ ] in the ass and rampant.
So, anyway, so you see, but they show
tits.
And then I asked it to
uh
you know, the prompt is
the very interesting poem, okay? Let me
read it.
They find me fault with her where I
default never find save happily that a
speck in either eye may show.
But if her eyes have fault of fault her
form hath none.
Slim built above the waist and heavily
made below.
Okay, that is a poem from Arabian
Nights, okay? Let me show that again.
I talked about Arabian Nights quite a
few times, so you need to go to again
xali.org.
Uh then Wadi English, this is English
literature section of my blog and there
is literature classics, then Arabian
Nights and one of the story is story 70.
Abu
Aswad and his slave girl.
Okay? Then there is this poem.
Okay, so you just paste this poem to
Google and you know, ask Google to show
a illustration and
this is what you see.
Girls with tits. So, I was like taken
back. I what you know, like the first
one it just like so maybe it's a
mistake, you know, it showed half of the
tits. But this one is like just
just like naked, okay? So, I asked
Google
what's going on? Do don't you guys like
oh Jesus that
don't you guys do censorship anymore?
And Google answered, okay? So, it turns
out
here's the answer. So, basically Google
is saying
they censor pornography
but they do not censor erotica.
Okay? Now, for you young guys, for you
zoomers like you you you have no idea
what the [ __ ] that means, okay?
So, let me give you an education.
Um
so erotica, you know, like what's the
difference erotica? Erotica basically,
you know,
porn, you know, when when you see girls
like
if you just you have a girl walking on a
street, what what makes her not a porn?
Well, the thing is if if there's an
artistic element
then it's not
pure porn, okay? That's like that's
that's like the major difference.
Uh and some people would say, well,
it depends on the lighting, okay? That
is actually true.
So, if the lighting is certain certain
way, there's artistic element that is
part of humanity.
Okay? Then you consider it like erotica.
You don't say porn, okay? Because
there's artistic element. If you just
you know, it's just tits and ass,
nothing else and [ __ ] then
you know, it's like then you say it's
lewd or porn, okay?
So, basically Google is saying that if
there's artistic artistic element then
it's okay.
That's the
like the policy of Grok today. Okay.
Then Elmo's then someone showed me
Elmo's
take you know so Elmo's is saying so
where's the Elmo's
Elmo's is saying that
where did I
wait?
Okay. I asked what?
You know Twitter sucks because it's hard
to find a post inside a thread.
You see it's not showing up but it's
like right this is a reply right to the
first this this one.
You can find it. Then another guy
replied which directed me to an Elmo's
post. So Elmo's is posting about like
what what is the policy for Grok
regarding tits?
And basically Elmo's is saying that you
know if if it's in a if it's allowed in
a R-rated movie
you know the the USA concept then it's
fine.
Otherwise Grok will censor. Okay. So
that's what
Anyway, so that's one thing. The other
thing is that you know the the AI
artificial intelligence today is like
Jesus.
You know it just create this beautiful
amazing drawings
a million per second.
You know this this is
this is end of human animals. This is
impossible. You know
maybe I worry too much but
but this is not possible. You know like
you can you can just talk to it, ask it
questions, things like that.
And it generates, you know, thousands of
these
amazing pictures, okay?
Bye, guys. Bye.
Fascinating. [snorts]
So, Arabian Nights story, okay?
So, yeah, so this amazing
amazing.
And you you see, the other thing I find
amazing, like when you read literature,
you know, this Arabian Nights. So, how
old is Arabian Nights? They are like
from year 500s
or 1,000 years ago, okay?
Uh and so, they are talking about
>> [snorts]
>> They are talking about women.
Uh you know, um
slim-built above the waist and heavily
made below.
So, what does it mean? So, it means
okay, so it's not today that oh, we are
like, you know, bikinis. Oh, girl, can
you draw bikini? We find all these
thoughts online
attractive, you know, the tits and ass.
It's like 1,000 years ago, 1,000s years
ago they are saying. What what what does
it mean? Heavily made below. That means
big ass.