welcome to another episode of saw talk
show let's see if this is working okay
great now this is all okay now this this
live stream is not announced
I have not announced it usually I
announce it on Twitter but I didn't do
so today just for a change because I'm
wondering how many people you know who
are watching my talk show actually you
know using my announcements on Twitter
I'm not sure so you know so you know so
so let's see so anyway today I'm going
to talk about I'm going to show you this
keyboard I'm going to actually do a
Emacs demo walking on my keyboard
website this is a funky keyboard and
it's not really good
so anyway I'm gonna do this it's gonna
be like four minutes five minutes then
I'm going to work on my JavaScript
tutorial and with Emacs and and in the
process you are going to learn some
JavaScript so basically so there are two
things you know so basically it's a
Emacs demo plus some talk about keyboard
plus some teaching of JavaScript so
let's begin let's shall we not waste
time
so this keyboard this this is a funky
keyboard I found it on Twitter from
Japanese keyboard community so I'm not
sure this is actually of Japanese or
ancient but anyway apparently this one
is called benzine 666 keyboard and it's
got this hexagonal arrangement now this
is actually no good because it's gonna
wreck your fingers okay
so we made a copy okay hold on a second
so let's start it's a start command log
okay so you can actually see the Emacs
command I call good morning guys
so let's copy hexagonal key arrangement
looks fancy
but rank wreak havoc on your fingers
okay show embosser yeah so anyways so
what I'm so if you go to my store copy
so if I go through my keyboard prog you
can see I already have a link there but
actually let's open that again I want to
make these
I won't make thumbnail so let's do it on
this one these six now if you are
watching say something okay now I'm
gonna call this command that will make
that will create an image file like that
a small version and put the file path
here then I'm going to just going to
make it into a link you can see you see
it's a link then copy it save it close
it back to my Emacs blog paste it that
and had the dive you see here is a
problem of Emacs 26 Emacs 26 we're
sometimes like become a blank so it's
the type sharing browser you see that's
that's how I want it but actually this
one is pretty good so let's use that
image instead so let's go back to the
page here let's go let's go back here
and we want yeah we want this image so
make a small version cut close save
paste make it into a link now open this
one
daveed it we don't need it anymore and
now we have the new one so that's good
there's one more thing I want to do I
need to I want to add this to this
section to it yourself keyboards so this
one I will put it and yeah okay so copy
that open page
so copy that open page DIY okay such for
my cue okay and put it here we move the
dive showing browser page down there it
is it's right there so and give me the
keyboard the word keyboard because it's
redundant
okay that's good now what I'm going to
do is just to go to issue let's see go
to Isha sigh interactive a brief the
first one yes and enter password okay
that is done for the keyboard
good morning green deck green deck from
Russia hello from Russia so now I'm
going to okay green deck if you have any
comments just say it okay now we are
done with the keyboard or any topic any
question we are done with a keyboard
actually if you know if you have quick
kibo questions as asked okay close close
it so showing browser close it close it
refresh this page we don't need it
anymore
so oh yeah so let me talk about keyboard
is one more thing then we gonna do
JavaScript okay we are going to do
fantastic JavaScript and okay so the
keyboard so now now notice so so this
keyboard is has a hexagonal arrangement
now it's no good because you put your
fingers here then you move up you know
you kind of move to the left you know
like
JKL you know for example this is j k l
and you move up you know you kind of
move to
the towards left on the right-hand you
can do the same but you move to the
towards the right which is good but
however that movement movement you know
up is kind of too much to the left kind
of but the thing is you know on the
bottom then you have to move to the
right you know so so it's you know the
arrangement is hexagonal and hexagonal
means it's it's got these 60-degree
alignment so so your fingers you know
your fingers when you move up and down
it's gonna like oh in that way it's not
really good because because your fingers
no money you know you should just move
up down not not going you know into that
direction and back to that direction you
know so so this land is more slant than
the than a standard PC keyboard you know
there is actually more inclination there
are no more PC keyboard so it's it's
actually no good it looks fancy but it's
not good okay so let's but let me show
you another interesting thing okay there
is another keyboard that has that
hexagonal arrangement which is this one
now this keyboard you can see it's
pretty cute it's cute alright but it's
it's not good because you can you see
that it's the difference is that you see
the arrangement it has arrangement that
is it's hexagonal okay you can see for
example this suppose this is the center
you can see one two three four five six
see to their to their you know it's a
hexagon it forms a hexagon so it's
actually the same is kind it's the same
arrangement like that hexagon hexagon
one and it's just not good because the
even though it's the slant is regular
than normal keyboard but the 60 degrees
30 degrees is too much normal keyboard
are slanted in a regular way you know
like that but it's like 20 degrees or so
so it's the problem with the normal
keyboard is on the left hand because
they are all slanted in this way so the
left hand you cannot you know if you try
to move up and towards right then it's
like a big distance so it's no good the
best is the best is actually like that
called ortho linear or called grid
layout you know like like this like this
for example its keyboard IO grid layout
it's like you know regular grid so
anyway that's about keyboard so let me
walk on my JavaScript page so how long
I've been talking to me it's okay we're
gonna work on JavaScript page for maybe
20 minutes
okay javascript in-depth so that's
JavaScript in-depth tutorial and let's
go to the map page I need to work on the
map object so here is a page JavaScript
map object that's added in JavaScript
2015 and what I need to do is check
check existence
let's see okay I need to what I need to
do is to remove this code examples
because you can see the code examples
already here so remove the redundant
code examples so let's go to it back to
Emacs check existence okay delete it
first of all let's do this so that you
can see the code for example for example
go to the browser you can see I already
removed that one but here get value of a
key which is this section and we're
gonna we're gonna remove this code block
block which is it's hard to tell because
it's this block but now we're gonna call
command such tml dhtml eyes pre-code
buffer so now you can see the code shows
up you know without the span tags and so
it's easier to identify where the codes
are for example here so i'm gonna remove
it so get value of a key so yeah refresh
is it's gone so that that I'm going to
entreaty did entry so I'm gonna do the
same for size identity Liddy entry okay
delete delete delete
actually sighs showing browser
okay
good morning Duncan
okay so hold on a second so we just did
that
let's see creating map
let's qualify it then color refresh new
map
okay so parents yep let's see clear map
okay I need to remove these C brackets
so let's do that so go here you can see
that now get the URL copy that URL put
it here link of I paragraph it remove
get a URL put link of a paragraph to
remove same thing here
good that's good so now back here I need
to change the date so up to date to date
no it's good
2019 April 22nd so that's one page then
let me get to another page and let me
answer the questions in a minute so
javascript map iterate yeah so that's
good for this page let's see next
oh yeah there's some inconsistency you
see this you see on this one is a SMAP
object and over here is this map so
let's make them consistent size so we
want to change actually change all that
to clear replace that by change change
change change save back to browser now
watch over here reload that's good so
that's another thing to delete the note
a prototype parent of math objects okay
there's another thing you see the parent
of map objects the parent of any map
object is mapped out prototype but I
said this akka which is also known as
you want to remove it because it's kind
of too wordy but actually what I need to
do is to check all websites on this
phrase so search for that let's see if I
find anything
okay I forgot to show you the panel okay
let's do it again
copy that such that okay there are two
instances so open it over here okay then
open it
TV that done in browser that okay that's
good
actually I want to add a link to map
that prototypes object which is here you
can see mapped out prototypes of copy
that go back here so put it here wait
okay put it here link if I make it see
and make a paragraph which one is this
JavaScript Map painted map object
oh so you need to view in browser so
there it is here's a new link I just
added so let me read the comments and
then we'll continue to the next one
so green deck Duncan Duncan says I like
Microsoft mobile keyboard 5000 very
compact curved Microsoft mobile 5000 so
are you guys watching me from Twitter
like usually I make an announcement on
Twitter about you know usually I say you
know some talk show in the next two
hours
so are you guys following me on that or
or not you know not checking that
because I'm still trying to figure out
how do I plan you know me you know I'm
thinking of schedule looks a talk show
so what so let's see what is this
Microsoft keyboard oh I didn't copy
Microsoft 5100 Microsoft mobile 500 Oh
mobile
okay that's probably that
at Siena zone
oh okay so this well I guess it works
that's you know this one is old and it's
no longer made its free old it's almost
five years at least or 10 years so Green
Tech says what's your opinion about what
happened to the web like every like very
like very heavy browsers that takes
gigabytes of memory and walking slowly
even on good computers and I've seen
several videos about COFA it's some
Asian protocol that is older than me
like we should switch to it because
there is no hope for the web yeah you
know you know for the browsers they're
getting heavy yeah that's that that is
true and you know and they take Chicka
bytes of memory that's also true but
working slowly even good computers yeah
they load you know for sure but on the
other hand the Gopher thing you know you
know you you have to understand the
technology you know grow exponentially
so it's not realistic and it's silly to
expect you know to want something work
like the way they work 20 years ago like
gopher you know so you know the geeks
the Nerds always have a tendency to to
kind of want that you know on my hand
there they are bloat for sure you know
that's no good you know that because you
know programmers companies they they
churn out code you know they churn our
products they market you know they want
to say that they want to make money and
programmers to not spend a lot of time
you know a lot of programmers don't
knows this stuff they just chunk churn
out code quickly so you have lots of
bloat because code quality is bad and so
on and memory leaks and so on and adding
features you know adding features so
that
the company can say oh we have this new
feature and all the people who don't
know a thing about computers you know
think it's good that's why you have all
this float on the other hand many of the
Nerds they are thinking oh we want 10
texts we want its that's stupid ok you
want to go back to gopher because first
of all and just you know know that
technology grows exponentially today
today we have AI you know we you know
like it but we are still using you know
Emacs and oh okay
mod and stuff it's good but you know we
you know we have a is most of the time
like ninety ninety-five percent of time
your CPU is sitting idle you know so you
so in a sense you're not using it you
are wasting it you know so you have we
have to consider that the and there's no
hope for the web you see the Nerds you
see most I'm addressing the nerd crowd
okay I suppose you guys are you know
like me okay but also so but usually I
often criticize you know you have to
remember the world is what we make of it
you know if you just want to if you keep
you know keep saying about open source
or we want open source oh we won't go
back to 20 years ago that's no good you
know what happens today is what you guys
okay or other people made it that way
so it becomes that way because all the
push for open source that's what happens
so you have now Google Facebook you know
they are evil empires they do whatever
you know that's what happens because
when you when you push open source okay
all free software foundation whatever is
good okay original intention is good but
however you want to be realistic because
if you if you just want to push an
ideology and that's not realistic
something goes wrong
that's my opinion okay something goes
through on that like today like today
the the cell phone you know the
smartphone they they do tracking
whatever they and you cannot possibly
control it there's no way the only way
the only possible way for you to
actually know what's going on on your
phone for privacy reasons is is the only
way is if you are a professional
security expert that that is that's your
specialization for for 20 years then you
can possibly you know know what's going
on because there's the chips you know
that's beyond your control even if you
are a good program the design of the CPU
they got things you know you have no way
to know that happens because of you
because of you oh you guys pushing for
idealogy open source and whatever that's
my opinion okay I of course I like so
many ideas in open source
you know we I'm a nerd for example I
like I don't want to be tracked
I want privacy I want full control of my
data I want full you know capability I
don't want any bloat I don't want stupid
you know animations things like that
however you have to you cannot just like
push for ideology so I believe okay it's
my opinion that today's situation of
Google Facebook you know they tracking
and everything in Apple selling things
expensive and make your phone slower
every time it I have a new version and
thousands of patents by Google by
Microsoft by Apple you know thousands of
parents that's because you guys the
open-source and free software
they be they are good in the beginning
but you know it becomes anyway so what
I'm saying is as society becomes don't
blame don't blame Oh Google because
Google is Evo Microsoft's people is Evo
that's big no that's not true okay
that's it's not just them creating it
because all things happen
or together made it becomes that way
okay quick reads okay so so Duncan says
that's probably more the 4/4 of certain
web day of writing using bad code rather
than the foot of the browser vendors now
today I think today it's beyond that
it's not it's not you know one team or
one guy it's it's happening a wholesale
I mean if you are a company you cannot
even stop it
like for example the Java JavaScript the
framework thousands frame logs you know
and they are supported by Google or
whatever in corporations you know it's
not even if you want you know you if you
are trying trying to make a webpage or
an app ok and and if you are not like
the programmer and you you you you want
it to be no bloat okay you cannot do it
and you know well you can do it of
course but nobody is going to use your
app okay if you want your app to have
some at least some commercial value then
you have no choice your your app is
going to be full upload because you have
no choice other than other than using
lots of the frameworks and protocols
that's out of your choice you can now
control you have no control that's the
way they are
you know frameworks you know you might
say you know maybe you are like me okay
okay I am NOT going to use any
frameworks I'm going to choose just to
code everything go and you are because I
know JavaScript and so on but it's not
like that
because once you have an app you know I
ad for the apples phone Android phone
there are lots of things that force
force force your choices you have no
choice you have to use this framework or
this protocol or something like that you
know this
of things like that you have no choice
but to become become a bloat you know
that that's the reason and Duncan is
subscribe Prospero oh I see I see so
daniel says I have two things on my mind
I think Emacs seems to have too small a
community but this remark is just
showing maybe second I'm I'm learning
were ranked and complain complain it's
hard hard yeah so what what do you mean
Emacs has two small community that's
true that that is true but but what are
you trying to say yeah so and yeah
learning where I guess is it's very
painful for sure so let's go back to let
me just go back to working on my
JavaScript and you know keep the comment
going so creating maps okay there's one
more thing I need to do here you know as
you get old you cannot have problem
seeing things have to take like take off
my glasses to see things
okay so map so JavaScript
yes 2015 you have a map object which is
a proper hash table okay
and there's something I need to change
here you see I give a so turning people
you know you there's no literal
expression for map however you can you
can use you can convert array arrays of
array to map and I'm giving a code
example here but however what should be
done is me let me try to fix it in your
C so here is so I want to be like that
okay
he won one copy that paste too
okay back to brown so you see this is
what I want I want to add a text syntax
instead of the code example now here's a
tip about writing tutorials when you
read a tutorial you do not want just to
write the code you actually want to like
separate them out as they explicit text
like explanation and the same syntax
description instead of just using code
you know as a programmer most nerds you
know think that oh they're just right
you know like all the information is
here they just actually use a code they
are thinking that you know here's the
code that actually runs so you should be
more precise and clear but actually no
because when you read a tutorial you if
you want to it to be a good tutorial and
effective you want to you want to focus
on you know communication like you are
talking to the reader like this is what
you do like explicitly explain or say
what this does so what to do like you
are you are talking to someone like
telling them this or that you do not
want a supposed to you know just just
have a block of code and thinking that
oh look you just read the code it's
everything is there and you know you
don't want to do that if you do that you
know like like a lot of pages on github
for example you have a lot say my
tutorials you know written by
programmers you know they and you if you
go read them it's just a one page of
code with comments that's not good you
know so this is a little tip about
communication that I've learned you know
my experience because you know to you
you it may not matter to you but to vast
majority of people it is the
text and description the actual
communication that they learned from not
you know not code not the you know code
you can actually you can see these if
you for example if you are trying to
learn something that's totally new to
you for example mathematics you know
would you rather read a math book where
it tries to explain what it is in
English then shows you formulas you know
as opposed to a style where there is no
English no explain nation whatsoever
instead it's just chunks of chunks of
logical formulas you know so to a
mathematician you know some you know
some some school of mathematician they
think this is this is good this is
precise you know everything is you know
clear and precise and accurate you know
logical formulas but to you now you see
the difference you see oh my god well is
this you you know it's you cannot read
it you don't know what's going on so you
rather prefer to read you know math
tutorial where it says okay this formula
is doing this and it's because of this
that you know it it explains it it
actually tries to do you know this
emphasis somewhere that tries to explain
tell you what's going on then it shows
the formula you know you know then you
know it shows the formula or logical
seem symbolic expressions you know so
that so that's you know so I'm sure you
showing you a perspective so this is
when you see when you actually see oh
you know you actually need the
explanation you don't want to like you
know many nerds are thinking you know
just pure code stupid notes you know I
hate despise the programmers
like UNIX philosophy
okay
so so let's put it back actually I
there's something I need to do here so
so actually I need that no good
now refresh you see so and and also I'm
starting to remove the comment here so
okay let me show you the Emacs panel run
it it's good cut paste syntax color save
switch to browser refresh now it's clear
more clear remove the redundant comments
okay so let's Stanfill this page let's
see and let me read the comment
okay generous good man okay so let me
hold on a second there's another thing I
need to do on this page so what's the
difference between object and map you
know JavaScript object is technically
defined as a collection of key and value
pairs but however in JavaScript 2015 the
introduced map object so which is a
proper hash table or dictionary so
what's the difference so here are the
differences you know you can anyway I'm
just going to so I want to change all
these are paragraphs I want to change
them to two lists instead okay so remove
that in actual eh damn I forgot to show
the panel but anyway
make a list go back to browser that's
good except there's a arrow here
yep that's good make them into a list so
that's that actually a few more pages to
do okay let me do a more math object
tutorial oh there's another thing okay
so you can see here so the map object is
designed to be used as a map data
structure similar to Python dictionary
or Ruby hash table or JavaScript or Java
collection in maps so I have a tutorial
on Java language is collection in map
now there's a wording that should be
changed because it's not collection it's
just a Java mat okay so so you see
JavaScript map object is similar to
pythons dictionary Ruby's hash table or
Javas Chavez mat and on this page I also
need to change the title it should be
collection in map so let's go to that
page now I'm going to let me show you
how I do it in Emacs so this is Emacs
demo so I copy that sir find replace
text search for this text we face it by
collection in map okay do it for this
directory HTML files right change to
files fixed case fixed case yes make
backup yes so all these pages changes
you know so that's done and I'm going to
do this again repeat this command now
the here's the list code you can see I'm
gonna do it for the entire sorry you
for directory so that's like you know
ten thousand files seven thousand of
which are HTML files so that's done okay
okay so now I look at that you see the
title has changed and anything to these
pages also changed so this page is a
tutorial on the Java languages
collection in map you know it's funny
like like okay hold on a second
you know each language they have
different words for this thing like
originally it's known as hash table then
Python codes codes dictionary then Java
and JavaScript code matte closure also
calls it a map
you know the essential idea is it just
lists of key value pairs okay
and now on this page I also need to
remove the first paragraph you see on
this page I says this page teaches you
about JavaScript and map in other
languages spell over that paragraph
should be removed okay now here's
another interesting interesting thing
about dragging tutorials or writing a
web page or blog when you read a blog
you know you like I used to on every
page the first sentence will describe
what this page is about because I'm I'm
usually paranoid like you know like I go
to websites I'm confused you know what's
the context you know what's the context
of this particular page so I always like
prefer to for everything to be very
explicit and logical so my own page is
you know almost all pages will say the
first sentence will say this page is a
tutorial about something something oh
this
pages on essay about you know it's an
opinion about like you know a one
sentence description that gives the
context of what this page is about it's
like I'm doing that painstakingly I
actually if you go to if you read
Wikipedia that is actually true
Wikipedia actually does that for example
let's say vector space okay which is a
math topic you know let's go to
Wikipedia
on a second okay you know we are not
lucky because this page actually do not
do what I did just described but let's
see you cry dear makers
okay so here's an example you know
basically you go to any Wikipedia page
the first sentence will actually give
you the context for example the Ukranian
vector first of all you'll say in
mathematics physics and engineering and
Euclidean vector is something something
something okay often almost always you
it will say like in you know what
specific feel like math or you know Oh
biology or whatever you know like in
something something then this is
something something that's actually you
know that's so the the the purpose of
that is that it gives you the context
where everything you know this page is
about but usually when you go to other
random pages on the web that does not
happen usually that's not true
usually you know it will just begin to
talk about the subject but I noticed
that you know the the style of actually
you know giving the context is usually I
think it's annoying to most people it's
usually redundant and annoying to most
people so I decided you know in the in
recent years I began to remove them you
can see you can see that in lots of my
Emacs pages pages still for example
let's see practical Emacs Emacs keys
you see for example this page Emacs CSS
compressor then I say you know I first
say this page shows a Emacs command to
compress reformat CSS code so anyway let
me read the comments so daniel says
speaker community for Emacs would be
good for fixing bugs and adding new
features to Emacs seems like we have to
look at what is getting popular and get
with it so use so use video visual
studio code yeah I liked Emacs to have a
bigger community too of course and it
will help a lot but that's not happening
because in my opinion Emacs people is a
coat they refused to change some many of
the very simple things
for example I've mentioned this many
probably more than one time in my talk
is that you know if let's let me show
you example then he Emacs modernization
ok we're here
Emacs modernization the first article
simple changes Emacs Emacs should adopt
ok on this page first of all I describe
the problem ok then just a few changes
let's see simple changes one two three
four just four changes ok make the copy
cuz space on do keys have have the xcv z
keys like you know standard in Windows
Mac and Linux just do that just make
this change and and you know just make
this single one change Emacs users will
turbo I guarantee a double in in two
years okay and this are how is pretty
old 2006
so it's more than ten years old you know
it's lots of Fame flame wars anyway you
know I'm kind of already tired of the is
it's going nowhere because you know I am
well known as a trying
Emacs community and this this article
has been shown you know now and then and
you know people don't like and and and
the Emacs community and code they they
suppress information basically these
people you know this article is pretty
odd but very few people read it and and
the issue about how to improve Emacs
comes up every you know repeatedly you
know again you know it's just going
nowhere because why because the Emacs
code the Emacs people the Emacs
mentality it's how its kind of helpless
so Duncan says Duncan says insisting
everything runs inside the terminal is a
good example of a regressive ideology
yeah I agree
terminal applications are emulators of
70s and 80s hardware hardware that is
the that is in the scrap heap yes that's
true you know one thing funny about
terminal as I learned you know in you
know like when you press control-d mag
if I press control-d here you know it
exits the terminal right but the
interesting thing is that when you press
control-d
it's a no it's not actually a shortcut
like you in like like in terminal like
control for example right now I just
pressed ctrl command in okay to give me
a new window or I can press command T to
give me a new tab okay now usually you
think of these as keyboard shortcuts
right you know for example I want to
close this tab I press command W you
know I'm a Mac so I'm using command but
but on Windows or Linux
you usually control okay you know so
these are shortcuts but actually when
you do ctrl D to close the terminal
that's not a shortcut you know that's
actually sending the ctrl T key signal
well it's not actually a key it's a
character it's a character he's one of
the ASCII character okay
unicode characters so you can see I have
a page discuss ASCII characters here so
the ctrl T is actually one of the
control DS is one of the ASCII character
it means end of transmission you know so
so I mean this is just something
interesting because back then you know
let's you know in terminal days you
don't have you don't have the concept
concept of shortcuts but you do have you
know ASCII you know everything is input
and output so you have these ASCII
characters so when you press control D
that sends you no sense of you know it's
a sequence of bits signals to the to the
machine you know that's how then it
tells it to exit you know so so it's you
know so that's the interesting thing
so if you think about this I mean the
point you know I don't really have a
point but if there's a point is that you
see that technology changes you know so
what we normally would think of say as a
keyboard shortcut but these are not
actually keyboard shortcut so you know
then because of this actually there are
many confusing phenomenons like
confusing to today's people for example
ok control you know so ctrl T is
actually not a keyboard shortcut but
however however some others are for
example ctrl L ok ctrl L you know which
is like clear clear out the screen I
think originally it is actually a
control our let's see where is it foam
feed okay
I think it's Oh control K I think
control K let's try control K yeah it's
it's kind of similar you know so at one
point they are they are signals ASCII
characters you know in terminal is since
the ASCII control characters to clear
the screen but then later on it becomes
a keyboard shortcut that the terminal
application clears your screen locally I
think you know yeah so I mean what I'm
saying is that so you can see a lot of
history here you know take technology
changes and terminals you know today we
call terminals actually terminal
emulators and they are X they are very
extremely complex actually so because we
have like basically three decades you
know 30 years of computer technology
evolution and in each generation we try
to be compatible with a you know with
because we don't want to change habit
even though the design is extremely bad
but we don't want to change the habit
therefore you have the UNIX fax and
Linux so anyway so you think you have
the terminals term you know it it's
called terminal emulators okay and
actually you can see in the settings you
have you have bunch of you know old
terminal names you don't see that much
in Mac but you see it much more on Linux
for example
yeah the Mac pretty much kind of just
removed them you know the Mac is pretty
pretty aggressive about
advanced okay there there is you see
those VT 52 vt100 B t10 - those are
actually actual terminals like hardware
let's see you can see that ultimate
hacking keyboard so if we go to keyboard
history here you see these are actual
terminals what some of them are very
popular for example this one is the
father father vim VI this one bt-50 -
1975 this one vt100 1978 these are very
popular terminals so so they went away
you know because technology changes
computer changes they went away
however they became what we have instead
we have terminal emulators which is like
software that emulates you know cut like
connecting to them you know emulate
their screen why because we don't want
to change habit you know partly because
of backward compatibility you know they
are still some systems using that things
like that but but but the other more
than fifty percent of the reason is
habit people don't want to learn new
things you know that's why everything is
like the way including keybinding
including e-max stuff including lots of
things including you know the terminal
stuff people including also including
many programming language features
people don't want to change you know
that that's why that's why functional
programming takes decades - part of the
reason functional programming is not
popular because people are used to see
you know
they don't want they don't want to
change that's that's how it is when you
actually dig into history because I have
done you know in many aspects of history
not just keyboard history keyboard
history programming language history
this history UNIX history but not just
technology I've you know I've also seen
you know typewriter history and credit
card history okay like when something is
invented when the first time something
is remain invented almost always people
refuse it you know so when credit card
is invented people think I don't want it
I don't want it no thanks I'm you know I
have I have banks I have money in my
banks and I can I know how to write a
check you know I'm a you know I'm a I'm
someone who is trustworthy I don't need
this
you know this credit card you know
scan you know the the credit card the
scam or something like that that's how
people consider it you know when
something new happens
same thing with programming languages
you know when you have a higher level
languages people think no thank you
I can't go to assembly thank you it's
like insulting insulting to them when
when you have something new tech that's
easy you know that's everyone can use
it's insulting to them and this this
this train of thought happens of course
in Emacs and UNIX people to you know
this elite nerds you know so we
constantly laugh at you know Microsoft
Visual Studio you know like these people
studio people they need to use the mouse
like you know but actually subs okay so
you know the point is okay some of the
criticism is valid some some of them are
not you know usually you know so yes you
know you want to consider efficiency you
know
you're you always want to look at the
things you know in a scientific way you
know as a human animal most most of our
judgments are just by us you know by us
and habit you know personal habit so
anyway so so that's back to ASCII backs
through terminal you know so we have
this weird all these weird things it's
cause that because I cuz cross cross
okay cuz cuz knew okay I think it's good
my terminal back and let me read the
comments again so I think we are almost
it's like our okay so so yeah definitely
I want Emacs but you know we need Emacs
to have a bigger community go community
but it's very hard you know because
something is Emacs really should adopt
but people you know they the Nerds the
Emacs people we are not do it for
example in my opinion okay you just to
you know just make the copy cut and do
keys to be you know control X control
see that we are turbo Emacs users in in
a year or two okay I can guarantee that
but as you know you know you probably
know and you probably think you know
that's stupid idea you know this will
never happen so there we go you know
this is a controversial you know topic
you know so you know so Emacs is not
likely to ever grow you know like on
reddit or Emacs community people think
Oh eMac this coin you know because we
see so many people chanting a good
things about emacs org-mode
stuff stuff it's not going it's actually
I would say relatively to the whole
program of population the Emacs users
are declining declining and declining
and declining you know nobody has the
actual data you know for this thing but
you can but there are many ways to to to
make a good guess you know for example
search results you know over the years
you know like I've written about this
like all the hundreds articles it's not
going anywhere
so George says George says don't
understand sauce coming about website
blocked you can still create low bloat
websites like 15 years ago
that's pretty useful yes that's true
such as my website yeah but you see no
you see okay you see my website yeah
yeah you can do that as I said before
you can do that if you are not trying to
be popular and if you are not trying to
make money now the moment you try to
make money you know try to feed your
children feed your family feed yourself
you cannot do it because there's so many
things that again for example for
example I'm running ads on my website
that immediately make it a lot slower
than it should be because because then
you have a bunch of JavaScript from
Google you know they do things and then
and that's just my website then anyway
that's another topic so the new says
accepted practice today is for the
actual ads along with all their
JavaScript surveillance infrastructures
to be poured in by the browser after the
content elements are in place what do
you mean
so anyway third-party trunking it does
something like in the fly yeah
in pants Inc no that's yeah in band
signal so anyway so Daniel says the
difficult part of using control
sequences remember remembering which
does what
yeah that's interesting idea - yeah
because okay so here is one thing that's
interesting topic you know so so you
have a bunch of keyboard shortcuts okay
they are there are two things I want to
say about that topics one is when you
design your key binding system for
example in my Emacs of like it when you
design a key binding system it's good
it's go to my keyboard block okay when
you design your key binding system
there's a question of should should your
key binding or keyboard shortcuts
should they be put more emphasis
emphasis on new mnemonics that is make
them easy to remember or should you put
more emphasize on how easy the key is to
press the key for example for example
let's say move kusa forward forward word
in Emacs you know in Emacs forward what
is what can meet our F okay let's try
meet our f you see meet our F forward
word now that's a pneumonic paste that
makes you make it easy to remember
because you see it's using the key F
which is like forward you know so
backward is P metope you know move
backward you
so and same thing for previous/next with
P and n okay so so so that choice is of
the keys are based on easy to remember
however however it's it's it's no good
for it's not based on ease of keepers
because I'm a keyboard you know the easy
keys are for example the easy keys are
you know you want i j k l for example
that that would be easy for the fingers
you know not you know the the forward
the f and backward P you know FB and PN
that scattered scattered over the place
so you so you have the situation you
know either it's easy to remember
Oh either you want it to be easy keys
for the finger so I have studied this
issue and my final decision is it should
be like 100% almost hundred-percent
99.99% of effort should you should you
should make the choice of the keys based
on how easy it is to press the key and
that's key Bonnie okay so I have an
article about that it's somewhere here
so actually right now it's 4:30 4:30 in
the morning I think my my neighbors I'm
waking up I'm waking up my neighbors I
think so where's article so so anyway
this section this this page is a index
of articles that's related to key
binding design
so yeah so I have our core somewhere
here about about that issue now the
other issue the other issue about key
shortcut not easy to remember okay there
is a way a user interface that can make
whole keyboard shortcut easy to remember
let me show you lark oh sorry Linux GUI
design so
okay come on such sorry Enix chill
I versus command hi okay so here's a
hotter coat
gu hai versus command by a unified
design the problem with command line is
that you cannot remember I mean for for
someone who did not study the system you
know you don't know what to do
the problem with the GUI is that it's
less efficient because you cannot just
you know type it you have to pull the
menus and so on but there's a way to
unify them into one so you have
advantage of both so in this Holika i'll
discuss about it actually I think I
should you know I should stop like how
long I've been talking for over 100 or
now so so yeah I'm waking up my
neighbors so I should stop now so thank
you guys for coming
maybe I'll do another one later on today
make in a de or something like that
okay so that's it for today for this one
episode see you guys