good morning welcome to another episode
of South Park show
let me get prepared start my machines
the applications so what do it's the
topic today well if you know if you are
new here go to this link and type a
question type a topic then we're gonna
talk about that topic and meanwhile let
me just begin to talk about some topic
Sal talk show that's right the great and
wonderful talk show we are going to talk
up talk about the very 8 variegation of
the word all the colors of the world
let's see how many people are watching
zero that's fantastic ok today's topic
is going to be let's begin with
JavaScript Yes No
ok so let's begin with this thing ok
let's see I'm gonna tell you issue about
programming idioms ok programming style
and the meaning of elegance ok and let's
look at this image PNG ok let's let's
first of all put this into a command log
mod you know when people while people
are coming on let me adjust these things
so there it is
you know the efficient use of time so on
the left you can see all the Emacs
command I call and now let's go to the
PNG image is this one yes
okay okay this issue
let's see type of undefined' typeof okay
so let's go to JavaScript okay
javascript my JavaScript tutorial and
you go to JavaScript in-depth and you go
to value types know JavaScript variables
do not have types are not associated
with type but values has types which is
almost always the case for any computer
language except well anyway yeah that
that is almost always the case for
computer languages now if you so this is
JavaScript types now let's go to the
type of operator and here's the code
here is a code let's do a live demo why
not instead of talking you know instead
of just talking with this hold on second
close showing browser instead of talking
with this picture image so let's section
okay section such next okay let's let's
go over here and create a new javascript
code block you see like that and paste
it here that's where we copied from our
website previously from here yeah and
press the button okay let me show you
press a button and you get into here
magnifier a little bit and run it now
I'm using not JSI my rendered because
why I called a command
sarvam current file and that's a Emacs
command you can use go to my website
just such folks are on current file
you'll find it you can run javascript
perl python you will be and bunch of
others so i run this it's so true now
you see on this code is showing you is
trying to illustrate the values of
javascript values the type of the values
for example the value undefined the
literal undefined there is a you know
literal keyword and that is a value and
that value is type is is space is just
the string undefined so undefined the
type undefined happens to be in
javascript to be the only value of that
type so undefined is a value and the
value the type of that of this undefined
value is the undefined type so in other
words let's go back to javascript types
so javascript has these types and one of
the type is undefined and the only value
of that type is the keyword literal
undefined so so anyway so this you know
this code shows you all these values you
can read and it return so true
but now you may think that this is you
know there's a lot repetitions so
instead you want to code it like this
let's let me show you
so only find type of you see okay so let
me show you how how this might work so
you might think the code is not arrogant
right so what what do you want to do
okay ha replace that by
all and we face that by Mt
Oh and replace that by actually we don't
need to that okay then
basically what we want to do is have a
replace type of as well then we want to
ok replace the dead by a coma okay then
for each one of these had a parenthesis
code to use okay that's wrong
that's good so now we have a kind of
array you see now we have turned these
things to away we want to check the left
side is equal to the right side so
there's an operation array is a method
called every which applies the function
and if this function returns true on all
items then the result is true so now we
want to give it a function arrow
function okay
error function takes one argument which
is an array element okay and over here
we don't want the traces because we want
an expression right here and so the
expression will be X the first item
equals to the second item so that is our
code okay now we can run it it runs but
however it does not print because there
is no print statement here so let's
comment out all the things above okay
and now this part let's do a console log
okay so now we can print it now when it
Oh force this is wrong something is
wrong here
oh yeah I forgot typer obviously you
have to have a type of here you see so
that means the type of the first item
such as this one is equals to you know
the second item which is this one so
let's run it true you see so now the the
issue now is compare these two sections
of code you know this one versus this
one which one do you think should you do
let's see how many people are watching
one watching my mind my god Sunday okay
so which one of these style should you
do when you code you know unpacking 20
years ago in the 1990s I will I would
always pursue this this style this this
is kind of more elegant because it's
less code less repetition
I would strive to code in this style in
Mathematica and later on other languages
Perl or you know Python but not today
because let me try to indent them let me
show you
JavaScript mod okay intended what there
was good mod okay indented now this is
the for JavaScript mod which is not very
good because it's not as good as sass
JavaScript mod because you see the
console.log is not syntax colored and
every you see Jason is also a keyword
building it's not syntax colored math is
also building is not colored every is
not colored you know so instead you
switch to such other squid mod now you
get the proper color because when
something is not colored then you are
sure that either you have a typo or it's
not building so this gives you a visual
crew you know when you code the you know
visually a visual feedback so you run
this you know it's so true so there are
two styles this one was as this one so I
was saying so most people I mean if you
ask most programmers you know who who
talk a lot you know the hacker types of
program
they will obviously say this is better
but but actually if you compare these
two you can do a survey you know you ask
programmers who may not who may or may
not know JavaScript okay you you can ask
any programmers suppose you do a survey
on ten thousand programmers you show
them this code now this one they will
understand immediately they will have
some sense even if they do not code
JavaScript but this one you got a lot
less people who will understand it
probably less than fifty percent
depending on who you ask you know so the
the the so so we have so this shows that
this the first version is actually
easier to understand
now that's one thing also the first
version is actually simpler I mean
although it you know simpler depending
on what how you judge how do you judge
something is simpler because the the
first one is simpler in the sense that
everything is basic you know the second
one is not as simple because it involves
you okay you see as far as programming
semantics goes it involves quite a lot
of things
it involves a nested array then it
involves a array method you know then it
involves a function and in this case
arrow function so you see comparatively
the second this style the second style
that suppose the more elegant style is
actually semantically more complex
there's no question about that you know
it's actually semantically more complex
so we have established that this this
version is easier to understand now it
is also simpler in fact now if you judge
simplicity by another method for example
you can judge by
how much repetition some code has then
in in that case the second one is
simpler okay so so let's say that's a
contention you know so you know maybe
you think you know the second one is a
better way to do so you may argue that
we should use the criteria of simplicity
by how much duplication there is you
know if you really want to push the
second one was the better way but do
know that the first one is simpler in
the sense of semantics so so there's an
issue you know we can think about it
later
which simplicity criteria is more proper
proper I mean again then it again
depends on what course you have you want
I mean is it is this some code like some
project you are just doing for yourself
or is it in a company or is it oh what
kind of programmers are is the target
for example new programmers or in
experienced programmers senior
programmers for example and also there's
also other considerations for example
how many lines of code in this project
now if it's 1,000 you know then maybe
you want to prefer to use the simplicity
criteria based on you know simplicity of
semantics because it doesn't really
matter it's you know but if you have a
million lines then possibly the second
one you know is better you know so it so
that's the issue okay so but anyway it's
let's get to the point so my point is
you know in the beginning in the 1990s
Oh mm I always strive for this the
second style which is you know it's
considered more elegant and it happens
to be actually more difficult to
understand but today the I think that
those kind of idea is just wrong okay
it's not it's wrong the arrogance the
you want to stick with the first one
this this one it's easier to understand
and it's in fact simpler and when you
want to debug when you want to you know
think two things this one is is it's
just better it's it's almost better in a
mode let's say in most ways so that's
that's the thing I want to say that
that's the thing I want to say so this
is kind of you know so you programmers
out there you know especially you know
if you are following me you are probably
into programming languages or you know
the elegance of programming languages or
the elegance of coding styles and
typically we would think that you know
this one is the the superior one but I
don't think so
good morning Isaac
so as access I bought a Libra booted
ThinkPad X 200 T the other day I thought
it would be fun to try libra booted
ThinkPad so so what does that signify
think fact think fat X 200 T okay so
it's just a Levin I think pad okay
and it's Libra booted so you mean like
free software like free software
foundations concept of three right like
no proprietary code and deciding this
account the firmware because those are
not you know you don't find those you
know if if you want everything to be to
be a free software free you know
computer device basically it's
impossible to find it today there's it
doesn't exist
there exists however you know look at
Richard Stallman the computer he uses
you cannot buy it you know what you are
you can but you have to basically you
cannot buy it it's not a consumers
consumer product if you really as you
know I want everything to be free
software free yup
free liberal bias okay yeah okay so and
so you're gonna install Linux on it I
suppose you know it's so think ThinkPad
you know it used to it it was created by
IBM you know in the u.s. you know it's
one of the highest quality notebook
computer as compared to Apple you know
Apple is the other one basically Apple
and then you have think pad in the 1990s
but however you know sometime around mm
they are all owned by China it is just
incredible to me you know it's like yeah
you know is starting some sometimes
around 2000 everything is China did you
know that the fast fastest
supercomputers China you know like you
don't hear these new as much you know
but I discovered them you know just one
by one it's like the fastest
supercomputers has been in China you
know built by China I'm not sure
everything beyond about you know the but
it's been you know it's been in China
for like many years now let's see
fastest super computer
top500 okay you know I've been looking
at this article now and then like in the
past few years I've been looking at it
so they show you know the fastest
supercomputers let's magnify
oh wait table top ten positions of the
fifty to fifty second top 500 November
Oh
so the US has taken over
Tesla what made by IBM okay
oh yeah so now the fastest
supercomputers are now us actually two
of them that's interesting
so useful nowadays I have a very central
so I guess you guys are all heavy open
source of free software fans right are
you guys so on Linux I was on Linux you
know in the past few years but you know
I got a Mac so you know my Linux machine
is owed so a professor gave me a Mac so
I you know is a mono man like if you are
Linux you know I have to spend how you
know a few hours every week to deal with
things but I mean any anyway let me
finish this
yeah so Isaac so you are are you you you
are seriously heavily into open source
that's why you you know you bought that
software I mean that that computer okay
Ubuntu is pretty good I don't really
have any issues with it so that's how
well how well says okay that we're gonna
get into a topic unless the topic is
about you know Linux computers or
something we have to like I think after
I need to do a talk show I need to keep
talking instead of I mean the other the
opposite is to be just become chat like
I'm just going to be here like chatting
to you guys I don't think that's good
well I mean we can do that sometimes but
you know that's that you know that don't
get you much people you know I mean if
we want to do chat the best ways to
actually we let's do a Google hangout so
we can actually see each other face and
talk about things you know I can show
you things and you can show your screen
you know tells me interesting things and
so on so Isaac says Stoneman inspired me
okay but I get that it is impossible to
make everything free yeah you know as
you know I'm not a fan of Stoneman
actually you know I was I don't know if
you are I don't know if you have
listened to my talk show like a month or
two ago where I talked about storm and I
talked about him quite a lot you know
but a few videos I've talked about him
in depth and my history of you know open
source or free software philosophy and
you know free software foundation
history so you know back in 1990 1998
okay I was a up to up to like even 2000
early 2000 I
say fan of Richard Stallman and I got
banned you know people call me a Richard
Stallman fanboy you know I got I got
Benny Mac OS forums and you okay that's
a good actually maybe we can talk about
that you know the well yeah you know I
have like so I have like tens of
articles about that you know the free
software foundation history and open
source the history there are issues and
you know anyway so I was you know a big
fan of Richard Stallman but not today I
think yeah I think well it's put it in
one sentence you know Richard Stallman
has become irrelevant in society
I mean seriously irrelevant I mean it it
might be relevant to you but because we
are in a niche you know because after
all you know like but if you look at the
whole world including especially in a
computing world which erst Roman has
become basically irrelevant and part of
the reason is also is because he has
become he has become out of touch like
he's like good you know have no idea
what see what is going on in a world you
know he doesn't you know he like
completely out of touch he's saying
totally again things you know about you
know and he don't know the news he don't
know what's happening he don't know what
he's imagined you know he don't know
what he's a github you know he does he
doesn't know what is a you know the male
part you know yeah it's like he I talked
about it many times but I'm not sure I
want to you know you know yeah yeah I'm
not gonna show the details but anyway so
he so you know in summary he has been
out of touch and also he has become
irrelevant like no no nobody no-nobody
of importance give you know pay
attention to him also he has become such
that he has no power at all you know
back in 2000 year 2000 he has great
power
you know people listen to him that
because that was when the open source
began you know that you have Linux you
have pearl you have Apache then the
first cooperation that went into open
source released their software in from a
commercial you know software to become
open source is the cause you know that
is the nest
Mozilla you know netscape browser
basically and actually the reason they
become open source is because they
already lost commercial value because
they lost the browser war to Microsoft
so so they are struggling you know the
company is like going bankrupt you know
is it Stanfill they failed and so so
they so the open source where the open
source is becoming you know huge linux
apache and we are thinking oh Microsoft
is going to cease to exist in 10 years
you know that's a fast you know look
look at what happens happen today anyway
so we are thinking that you know
Microsoft is gonna go away and we have
Google with a great ethical company
Google Wow the Google you know do no
evil you know so those things are
happening and and Netscape is you know
bankrupt you know so they they try the
open source way so
and it's a huge news you know they
release their or their software to as an
open source you know open source license
I forgot what license they used but
anyway it's a open source license so
it's a big news among industry like you
know like today's news you know you it's
everywhere you know and
you know you you can still find the news
you know actually I have so many
articles about it - okay so it's yeah so
let's look at savvy okay Netscape so I'm
kind of like talking history you know
I'm you know is it the oh these are
history and you don't see it because all
the news today they bury it all the
organizations and news organizations and
corporations they they spew out and
Twitter and you know Facebook they spew
out all the garbage and click baits and
they actually actively try to bury
history they don't want you to know so
here's my one of my essay this is
written rather late 2011 internet
history netscape dot-com called rush you
know I was there you know okay Netscape
is just down you know down I walk I walk
for 20 minutes Netscape walk you know
walk for 20 minutes in a skate
of course they moved but back in 1990
you know 1998 1997 is I'm still you know
I still live in this around this area
and they are just you know across the
street
Netscape PayPal is down there you know
downtown Mountain View you know Google
is of course just slowly here walk 30
minutes but you know but Nick Benecke
you know he's just right there and they
are but you know so I was there you know
I was you know back tense
I was in a startup company so I was
right in a web the first bubble you know
take bubble
they were they a dot-com disco dot-com
bubble okay and here's an article this
is this article is from 2000 2002
Netscape crap okay Netscape you know as
you know as
you may or may not know I sag I don't
know you probably don't know because I
think you are young younger so you know
in this skate back in 2000
so Netscape back in 1995 you know when
when the web is beginning they are
basically the the only browser you know
they they they run the market like
nineteen ninety percent of the market
everyone is using Netscape they
Microsoft began you know they saw that
they start slate they didn't join the
web web as early so they saw that and as
you know as a threat you know you keep
you could say that any any company you
know always monitors the situation and
do what they can because if you don't
the tech industry changes very fast the
situations the thinking the thought they
change very fast so if you don't you
know if you don't change you disappear
basically you you know that's that's how
corporations capitalism works you know
like for example when you know I'm not
going to go to economics okay
and history of the corporations you know
but I've but anyway so Netscape back in
1995 so they they have the Netscape
Browser it's used by everyone eBay they
are hugely popular and they went you
know so back then this is dot-com era so
they they they went IPO and oh my god
the stocks just jumped you know
historical records you know or they come
all these companies is like that so
Microsoft sodas so Microsoft began the
Internet Explorer browser you know free
and so you know they want to get into
they want to do what they can you know
to to get you off to - to fight their
competitors so so this they began the
Internet Explorer browser now they have
a version dedicated for Mac ok back then
so and back then in throughout 1990s I
was on a Mac but I was doing his
assistant me on Solaris ok but anyway I
was my home computer is as always being
a Mac throughout 1990s so they so
Internet Explorer oh they have it's a
dedicated version on the Mac developed
just for the Mac it's not a port of
anything so I have used you know I
because I do web them you know I that's
my job you know so I have you know I
know these details I use all the
browser's you know every version ok
Internet Explorer ie versus Netscape
every version the IE is better gets
better and better the Netscape gets
worse and worse ok in terms of a speed
ie is faster in terms of memory
consumption ie uses less okay in terms
of crashing the nest egg netscape crash
is small okay that's my experience so
you know I wrote you know anyway so this
essay you can it's you can you might
consider it as a kind of documentation
okay I have like some these articles are
pretty old like you know so this one is
from 2002 and back then there's a huge
amount of Microsoft hatred okay like
huge yeah all these articles are you
know kind of odd and by the way Netscape
you know when you talk about Netscape
one of the person you must mention is
jwz jamie zawinski he is famous as the
guy who created who wrote the UNIX
version of Netscape 4 for Unix
you know average systems for Solaris you
know basically he put he his job is put
in escape to run in X 11 X
Levin is the you know the the windowing
system on UNIX is you know back then
there's Linux but it's not it's not
popular yet ok the server's used by big
corporations are solaris solaris was the
from semanko systems and you know Samara
systems is the guy who runs who created
Java you know back then some micro
system is this huge big giant you know
corporation like the other king so they
do they do all things they can to
prevent Java running on Linux okay I
despise you know some Microsystems they
they do all everything they can to
meanwhile you know they are saying you
know we are or we are I forgot exactly
what they is theirs but anyway they they
just like today's companies they always
say pleasing things you know like oh we
support open source or whatnot we help
humanity what whatnot but my so
Microsystems they do you know all
tactical methods all ways to prevent
people you know to prevent prevent a
situation where people do not use arrows
they just stick with Linux and run Java
okay
so their java version they do everything
they can to make java not run on Linux
so make it you know release half a year
later or a year later things like that
so that's some Microsystems
you know the you know impacting a lot
people these spices Microsoft but but to
me to me Sun Microsystems see stuff is
the most evil company you know back back
then so jamie zawinski jwz yeah so he's
he has been on a show called rush you
know actually i haven't watched the show
you know I lived through the era so he's
well known for the you know as the guy
who create who writes Netscape
but also he's even well-known even more
in emacs community community he's the
one he's the lead programmer who write X
Emacs well if you are young today ok you
probably don't know you XE max it's kind
of also old thing but in Emacs community
back then X Emacs is this huge thing XE
max versus Emacs because you know it's a
big thing so so jwz is a bit basically
richard stallman okay this is the X
Emacs versus Emacs it's a big issue in
Emacs community like every Emacs user
knows and talks about it every day you
know it's like it's like that for like
10 years over for more than 10 years for
15 years from I would say from 1990 to
2002 even 2008 okay let's say 2010 from
1990 to 2010 every Emacs users I mean if
you are the type who read blogs and you
know go online you know supposed to a
lot Emacs users actually you don't see
them online you know they never talk
about anything but about it anyway so
every Emacs users know from 1990s to
about 2010 there's this XE XE max versus
Emacs because they are they are of fork
they are the first big well-known folk
in open source community okay you know
back then forking or software of
open-source software is not considered a
good thing not like today today like
everyone like on github they tell you
please me you know that that kind
of mentality began with github around
2008 you know so before that
open source software is is from
pound you know nobody wants you know if
you folk
you better have really good reasons
because every programmer will hate you
every open source programmer will hate
you okay that was the situation so you
don't folk mean you rather the
mentalities like that you know it's open
source you collaborate you contribute
you do not folk okay but anyway the X
Emacs is the one of the first none
unfriendly folk you know they became
enemies X Emacs and Emacs so every
programmer every year you know program
Emacs users are talking about you know
can we merge them you know what are ways
what are issues I mean it's a big
controversy controversy okay so anyway
so and and Richard Stallman he points
finger at at jwz jamie zawinski okay
directly you know he published he buy
his essays you know he says you know jwe
Z is a guy who who is a it's like a
okay he didn't say that word
but basically that's what he means
you know jwz is a guy who who who began
the you know who began the situation
where they do not cooperate with GUI max
I mean he's talking about XE max he so
he blames jwz so Jake jwz is famous for
that reason I think I got some oranges
you know I was eating oranges before
anyway yeah so so there is jwz you know
and you can see this article is from jwz
this is when he resigned at Netscape
because there are a lot of problems you
know there's a lot politics they are
sought issues you know people you know
people hide it you know you don't hear
much about any of you know much of this
because all the corporations they they
don't you know they hide things and they
you know and politicians and so on sub
anyway this is the arc of um jwz you
might try to read it because when you
read this you see history you see I mean
it's not history is such a thing it's
not practical
okay it doesn't bring you food I mean
you can read a lot history you can be a
history historian you can study history
for 10 years maybe maybe technology
history or American history or what
history or you know politicians history
it doesn't get you anywhere anyway it
doesn't bring you food that's what
history historians is it's like
philosophy or mathematicians okay but
however I mean it is obvious you know of
course it's very important and also in
general as a person or as a nation as a
country you have to know history because
that's that's how you see things that's
like it's your past okay what's a person
you can learn you know you have your own
history maybe you write Diaries or maybe
you can maybe you don't write Diaries or
blogs but but memory is important you
know of course to you to you your
childhood what have you done your high
school or all in terms of computing you
know that's memory or the places you
walk that's important to you if if if
for example if you lost your memory
that's gonna be a problem
you know you became you know you are not
gonna be doing well you know so memory
is like is part of history and in a
broader sense you want to know you know
your dad or your family your countries
you know history and world history human
history you know so so so so the here's
a you know
essay by jamie zawinski you might try
you can read it it's you know you get a
sense of what's going on some of the
stories back then
and of course I have lots of essays this
one is about GUI Max and XC max schism
from my point of view okay so this is my
personal account of the situation
actually
okay this Arco is actually written by
penguin now penguin is a lead programmer
for exe max after jwz okay and he's got
severe he developed severe is I to the
degree that he no longer cold I mean he
has to exit program exit the programming
career so he stopped being a programmer
yeah that's it's that serious he went to
see doctors and so on so he you know and
also jwz is also well known for his
eyesight problems okay
he's also got severe eyesight problems
because you know you can imagine in this
not calm days you code day and night you
know you don't sleep you have to code
and back then
ergonomics is not as well-known as today
you know this is back in 1990s so so you
know you know you have to see doctors
and doctors doctors don't know what to
do because the eyes I use typically
cannot be fixed by doctors I mean we do
not fully understand what happens and
you know basically even doctors cannot
do nothing you had to help you so anyway
he j ee j jamie zawinski has also
written blogs about his is i so you can
search you know jwz RSI you know you
will find his asian blogs written around
1999 something like that i also have
links to his blog i mean i mean you can
you can find it for my writings about
RSI too but anyway so so this is article
guru guru he max was a sexy max
for liberation about computer languages
we don't care about that when yeah and
this one is language code perception
deception you know the back then is it's
a this this article is a story about
scheme this the language ok scheme this
was considered one of the most elegant
programming language back then
throughout 1990s up to let's say 2010 so
up to let's say 2005 okay so from 1990s
I mean even before to 2005 scheme least
today is known as racket you know the
name change changes it's considered that
considered the most arrogant language
but that's another topic about language
so I'm not gonna talk about that I'm
going to try to focus on the dot-com era
the politics open source issues free
software foundation you know related
topics and this one article is written
in 2005 the Microsoft hatred it
describes the situation how people hate
Microsoft you know it's my it's kind of
my rant and Microsoft you know a lot
corporations are suing Microsoft you
know because they because they are ie
browser they warn the browser war and
lots of other things you know so some
Microsystems that's a company I despise
okay so Microsystems the company who
created Java and the most evil company
they so they are suing Microsoft and AOL
is joining to see you Microsoft Netscape
is also suing Microsoft yeah me they
hopped onto the bandwagon because
Microsoft is the powerful they are enemy
they all failed they all you know
Netscape failed when it when it scape
fight failed you know a lot a lot UNIX
geeks you know at the time they want to
say Oh Microsoft they did you know
tactics you know like when doing browser
for free no the reason Microsoft IE
browser wound
browser war is because Netscape has
become crap crap and crap every year was
them ie every aspect in every way in
speed in how it crashes robustness
every way and including in how they
support standards such as CSS ok CSS was
not you know it just began around 1999
ok and HTML standard you know it also
just just begin you know HTML to HTML 3
okay
and back then Netscape is busy creating
non-standard tags like blink you know so
you have all these evil stories you
don't hear much anymore
the this tag blink so what what is tag
do is that you have something you blink
the text when you show in browser now
it's all dead they remove that you know
browsers remove this but yeah they
removed like five years ago or six years
ago maybe seven years ago so but back
then Netscape you know blink is a tag
Netscape invented and back then so every
every company browser especially they
are busy inventing new tags because once
you have a new tag programmers start to
use it you know if they like it then
your browser grows you know so they do
all basically just like today every
cooperations they do all possible ways
to maximize their profit you know
including unethical ways you know they
don't care that you know that's what
they want to do so blink is non-standard
okay so Netscape is busily inventing or
you know a lot including cookies don't
you hate cookies you know the privacy
invasion cookies
Netscape invented that Netscape invented
JavaScript okay what is an escape which
became the you know the open source
Mozilla and you know so blink tag so
what was what
anyway so what was I going to say so
Netscape yeah so every version of ie you
know Netscape is was so finally ie you
know Internet Explorer they won the
browser war then they then they stopped
doing anything okay so you start with
the you know a version I mean it miss
gave his gun is blown away so you just
have a II and they stopped updating
anymore because Microsoft is not in a
business of running websites you know
that's not in their interest they are
they are in the business of making
operating systems to sell that and game
game games and keyboards you know gaming
keyboards to back then they stopped
making gaming keyboards but anyway so
they so they created the IE which is the
best browser at a time you know Pete's
you know Netscape and Miss KP in 2000
year 2k they come Kim we came up with a
version called Netscape communicator my
god it's a large history with the
Netscape communicator is the one of the
most bloated crap okay yeah this you can
see there's a Wikipedia article but let
me show you some images you know so
these are what Netscape looks like you
have the nessip communicator which is
which is a huge deep loaded thing that
includes a browser includes a calendar I
think includes a email application not
not web site by the way web site emailed
like Google Gmail is not there yet okay
that's kind of actually a new thing we
don't have a website email in fact at
that time you know any programmer we
think website based email is like stupid
you know
so when you read email it's a with an
application like a desktop
occasion email application so so
Netscape communicator you include you
know schedule you know a browser email
and it's basically a bunch of things
like like you know and it's hugely
bloated and slow sucks huge amount of
memory and of course it failed you know
nobody nobody really liked it so you
know back then so Microsoft you know I
really you know warned the browser war
and and Microsoft stopped you know doing
things to it because you know it's not
it's not there interest you until until
the Firefox came up so Netscape failed
so Netscape generate you know release
their software it becomes open source
and basically not many people you know
it nope nobody contributes and until
they they become an organization called
Mozilla okay
the Mozilla tried to work on it and they
scratched everything they instead I
think they'd be right everything they so
they came up with Firefox then Firefox
began to eat the browser browser market
from the IE so Firefox throughout year
2000 they become smoke more and more
popular so ie becomes less popular but
still dominant but Firefox is like you
know you can go to Wikipedia and you can
see the historical chart of browser
popularity but anyway in 2000 year 2000
Firefox becomes more and more popular
until Google came Google Chrome ok and
you know so so I'm not sure what we
gonna I'm where I'm going you know so
I've been talking for an hour now and
you know so so to me it's all just like
it so push it it's all eyes and I don't
believe me
oh man sauce I don't today okay i back
then remember back then I was a fanatic
of vicious Tolman I was a deep you know
I'm a fan you know in fact I can show
you a lot articles that you know you can
see that it can prove you know and I
have been banned from people people has
been calling me Richard Stallman fan boy
I'm not gonna do that you know I'm gonna
prove it because I talked about it I
showed it you know a few a month or two
months ago in video so I'm just gonna
talk about something anyway so today I
don't think you know I I think the open
source including a free software
foundation both of them they are enemies
by the way but both of them they are
actually they are not good because they
has become an ideology anyway yeah I'm
not gonna talk about that even so anyway
so here are some histories about large
histories so there is celebrity
programmers with is I you can see this
article is also getting old
this Argo is from 2010 famous
programmers with repetitive strain
injury
Richard Stallman is one of the guy who
has CBS is I and then we have jamie
zawinski the Netscape guy and here is
his blog you know he owes he set up his
kick back this this photo is back in
2005 yeah but he has blogged about it
back in 1999 here okay we look at this
one
my wrists and welcome to them 1999 by
jamie zawinski okay it's interesting
because he's talking about how he's got
pain and he's about to be done for like
goodbye goodbye programming
1999 when he was at Netscape and he
talked about he tried out touch
acupuncture chiropractor the loser by
the way those are Voodoo's get a
keyboard timer get a chair you know and
stuff get better chair get out of the
chair you know he's talking about his
solutions yeah it's it's horrible to
read though because you know you see you
know you might think oh no it never
happened to me that's what I thought you
know I was I've been typing since 1990
1987 not until 2005 I start to have
issues you know I was young guy I was
healthy I don't have you know I am I'm
using of Iraq and I'm not using
ergonomic keyboard I'm using the plain
old flat PC keyboard you know throughout
you know from 1990 to 2005 I don't have
a problem but in 2005 it's not to have a
problem with because because I was using
a laptop for it for a year you know
exclusively anyway so so here are some
articles so penguin you know the X mod X
Emacs developer and Jong austere heart
he is the creator of the tickle tkl
programming language TCL programming
language and he's also got severe RSI I
mean these are cases okay these are
cases where they are disabled like they
can no longer type it's a serious I mean
they have seen doctors you know they can
no longer take for example Richard
Stallman at one point back in 1990s he
he had he hires a secretary who he know
he dictates and the secretary types for
him
you know so all these are serious issues
serious incidents so the this junk
Oosterhouse the inventor of TCL also got
severe ISI and he he is a VI user okay
and by the way I want to mention another
guy this guy Richard Feynman Richard
Feynman is also well known this program
he is actually considered one of the
king of you know a master of common lisp
okay he has done a lot of things easy
and he's also a computer algebra expert
like Mathematica you know you you write
code to solve equations you know you
want to do ink integrals derivatives you
know it's called computer algebra system
he's a major contributor to the maxima
computer algebra system okay so he's a
big you know Common Lisp ER and he wrote
you know I kind of know him a little bit
we have exchanged emails you know yeah
and he told me that he told me Jeong
Jeong Oosterhouse is not a Emacs user
he's a mostly a VI user anyway so that's
Emacs okay that's I Sai and Emacs
history so so what else are you guys
still here fight people yeah what else I
think maybe that's it for today then so
Oh Isaac Isaac asked can anyone link me
to the video where he talked about
stolen F free software foundation
jwz you can just you can just search it
I mean do realize they are like turns of
it okay so some of them you know jwz
okay jwz he runs a website you know for
example this you know this is one of his
page and you can go to his main website
you know he's a he's got a condo section
you know he's like he's got this guy's
got hundreds of articles not this he's
one of the guy who talked a lot one of
the pro
you can see that his articles are back
to 1995
now the word blog blogging does not
became a word until early 2000s okay so
there's no word for blogging yet so he
but he has you know began to write in
back in 1995 you can see his articles
stupid background by anyway by the way
this logo there was a Netscape logo okay
I was you know used by Netscape so so
he's one of the guy programmers who
talks a lot and also who write a lot you
know write a lot and also offering a
controversial way that's his style he
likes to offend people you know that's
one of the reason he became popular
famous you know he always he liked to
say controversial controversial things
and and I think I do remember one you
know in some of the Asian articles he
just like says schools which are stolen
yeah so system and you know obviously
they don't like they have issues with it
with each other well anyway so he's got
a huge amount of articles on his website
I mean and this is only a one section
this is not his homepage you know you
can go to his home page then you got you
know then you got these
you know this idiotic thing you know he
like this type of thing he's a so he's a
hacker type ok he's one you know like
the matrix by the way these this thing
this his homepage this is before the
Matrix movie screen you know those
flowing characters it's before that so
so maybe if you are familiar with that
no he didn't copy matrix
he'd rather matrix copied him so he's
got this is got his home page so so he's
got tons of articles on his website but
also a lot of his writings are not on
his website because back then you have
new scoops you want to go to the new
scoops like com dot landed yeah come dot
E max so contact you know they are civil
you have to dig history where while
mailing lists you know you have to take
where the discussion between kanui max
and XC max were happening okay so so you
want you know and by the way if you are
you know interested in this kind of
history this just like actually there
are huge amount of things
tons of stuff you're gonna spend years
like I have myself been reading this
history for more than let's say more
than twenty years but not every day of
course but I do spend I mean I do spend
significant of time to read them you
know every every almost every week okay
well at least every month for 20 years
you read history so when you read this
kind of history you have the UNIX
history it's a huge topic okay the X
Emacs and Emacs history then it gets
into keyboards and terminals like order
order all terminals you see they are
related you know they are all tied
together so keyboard for example this is
this is Commodore okay Commodore is not
relevant here but but if you go to
history
you can see a lot of these terminals
this cell keyboard is huge it's one of
the granddaddy of list machines Emacs
Lisp machines Lisp language you know
it's you know it's artificial
intelligence huge history with with just
this keyboard itself then you have to
find out you know what operating system
this keyboard is used on you know so you
start to study PDF pdp-10 you know what
they are you know they like they are
operating systems back in 1970s so I
mean I don't I don't even know what how
they walk you know how they are like but
which in turn the PD PDP I think it's
pdp-10 is the hardware where C
programming language is based on ok
pdp-10 yeah and there are other
operating systems w AI TS and itcs and
cell and you know so you start to get
into all these things and you know you
know it was it's his history it's all
interconnected Emacs history unix
history mo Tikes history which is a
genious Emacs by the way artificial
intelligence you know they are burning
systems night keyboard you know the list
kibo history and an Emacs history and
Emacs keybinding and other Emacs
versions such as the XE max history and
and all the people associated with them
actually you know actually I can
actually give a lecture about the
history but not today because having
already talking for an hour because
again some of the people died you know
the some of the pioneers in Lisp in
Emacs you know many of the earlier users
they died and you know yeah
it's there's a lot history and you know
a lot to talk about so if you're gonna
dig into this topic it's just gonna is
it's endless like because every time I
started to for example for examples
today I saw some new pictures about this
keyboard so I start to plug it then
based on what I already know there are
so many things I still don't know like I
have questions about about what is the W
AIT operating system for example a cell
you know what is a cell you know machine
exactly you know so there are still many
questions so every time when I try to
when I got some Twitter you know some
some new things happen I start to again
you know to read or dig into it then of
often it's like things like hour after
hour you know things like a period of
days I spend hours every day you know
just to read the so many details you
know then I got tired you know because I
know it's in the endless history is
endless you know then I got tired I
stopped until until you know I saw some
other news next time about these
machines about Emacs this piece three or
whatever you know so you know history is
such a topic it's literally endless I
mean it's not just in this inverse is
like ten thousand a billion times more
than you have a lifetime for because
literally literally history is like
these speedy ins of billions of people
each one has a lifetime history and
there they have their dad we each one
has a lifetime history and so on
backwards you have you know you have at
least written history of 1,000 years of
that of these speedy ins of people and
when we usually speak of history we are
talking about some sort of immensely
condensed you know not yet that that we
see as history you know like today we
talk about this history we just say oh
this is
you know you have common list and before
you have just these few days but that's
just that's kind of like superficial you
know anyway so that's the history and
also the other thing about history is
that it's it's critically important in
some kind of long term sense but it does
not bring you food or any immediate
value you know you just read history for
the sake of you know and also once you
know history you are kind of it's a sad
situation you are kind of helpless and
useless because once you know history
once you know this history about you
know Emacs or corporations then you go
on Twitter okay today you maybe you talk
to some programmers at Google or
Facebook or whatever they say something
okay this is something and you and you
know to yourself immediately that's
force that's let's plate and see force
you maybe you can't maybe he's your
friend you say oh that's not true and
you start to talk about it and but he
doesn't you know he may not believe you
because why because well because every
other programmers don't know what do you
know you know because then you got an
issue of convincing them because then
you have to you can't basically because
there are so many forces powerful forces
that trying to say another situation of
history they you know what you know is
you have you know it's a issue you
cannot you know it's like that you know
it's it's like that
okay so I think so I can find it I mean
you cannot okay so
Isaac I think you are tried I'm guessing
okay excuse me if I'm being direct I'm
guessing you are just you you want to
try to find this like one article where
it contains you know jwz flaming flaming
RMS you see a snowman oh I am as flaming
jwz you want you are thinking maybe you
want you can find this one post so you
can get it oh no you have it's like
buried and you know turns of thread I
don't mean I don't mean that as a put
off okay but but yeah yeah I mean you
you may not find one article where it
contains them fighting you know jwz yeah
I'm thinking like I might search it you
know you know take hours to actually
find takes hours of reading to find me
one article that's somewhat dramatic you
know that's most people will look for it
you know they want to see this condensed
dramatic versions of them fighting you
know oh so what are you trying to find
Isaac
yeah so I like
so yeah I'm not sure what are you trying
to find but I think that's it for me to
vote today talk what I meant doing is
how do I spend my time these days well
I'm just coating my website basically
okay so - that'll be it for today mean
talking yeah so thank you guys for
coming oh the livestream when I talk
about Richard Stallman okay let's see
let's try to find that and albeit
YouTube let's see YouTube sorry okay
YouTube sorry IMS let's see okay maybe
maybe Dow P it
so I think maybe this one I talked up a
lot about it let's go to YouTube hanky
yeah let me find that thing weird that
there be it for today it's still loading
hold on top show
not that one
okay this one maybe try this one okay
try this one at times 53 minutes I'm not
sure this is actually the one I'm
talking about because
it's too so
yeah now I want to find this actually
one specific video where I talk about
you know I talked about Heavy D about
[Music]
I'm thinking maybe should I spend the
time to find it or should I just you
know it's just me talking anyway because
you've you know because on the open
source issue you know it's just my
opinion it's a controversial issue right
it's it's such okay yeah
alright so okay thank thank you guys for
watching house I hope to see you next
time bye