good morning everyone welcome to another
casaya talk show today is June 7th 2019
I'm sorry I'm late
14 minutes late that's super late and
I'm tired so I'm coming up one of my
eyes because I have you know what I'm
tired my eyes closed cross actually I
can't I can do fine here so today I'm
going to talk about understanding
JavaScript object like a mathematician
okay so after listening to this talk
shop you will understand JavaScript
objects like a mathematician okay so
let's go to my JavaScript blog and show
okay I haven't okay so anyway so it's
not help show yeah we're gonna talk
about JavaScript object and let's see
what what do we have here new your time
update showing results yeah so this is
my JavaScript blog so I have JavaScript
in depth we're gonna talk with this my
tutorial today of course so let me show
that here and get prepared here so I
make sure you can see my screen I'm
sorry I wasn't prepared before and this
screen it's movie here so okay so I
think that's we are set
game critic imp save memory we are said
so yeah so we're gonna talk about
JavaScript is it talk show JavaScript
JavaScript object the way a
mathematician understand it you know
because I'm gonna talk teaching a
special way so that you understand the
kind of logical into relations and stuff
I guarantee you you will have not heard
of that style of teaching JavaScript
object people and so so let me actually
write it out javascript understand
JavaScript object like a mathematician
okay copy that
talk show okay copy that
switch back here and paste it here so
app so after that maybe we talk about
something else you know so if you have a
questions just ask any questions
comments I'd love to see that so let's
begin let's go to my JavaScript tutorial
well let me talk about yeah so talk-show
understand JavaScript object like my
mathematician that's right and let's
begin so let me begin by starting with a
section and since we are using a Emacs
which is my my editor of choice
let me start sauce start command mod
command log so in this window you can
see all the Emacs commands I call so
we're gonna do a JavaScript and so this
is a JavaScript file let's say
console.log 3 + 4 ok vennett 7 that's
good a good morning runs
ran six hello Chris I am I'm Gabriel
from Brazil
oh hi Gabriel I think I know which one
who you are thank you thank you
so I'm going to cover one of my ice
because I'm tired I have a little
cross-eyed so I'm gonna talk like that
so anyway that starts with the on with
the job understanding JavaScript object
like a mathematician okay so first of
all what's the object okay okay let me
tell you what is is a syntax so we
create a constant object
it's okay hold on a second okay here we
create a constant thing object is
basically a key value pairs so here we
say my object and let's say a is a is
one let's say that B 3 C is 3 B's - okay
it's magnified okay so so let's run this
oh and it works but however we have to
print it so print my object
it's just shortening it to object the
net you can see it's printed you can see
it's printed here so we have this object
of three keys the keys are a and B and C
and the values are 1 2 3 so a object is
mostly a key and value pairs and each
key and value we call it a property so a
object is a collection of properties a
property is two things key and value
pairs actually let me write it down so
that as we go along we have a bunch of
notes Gabriel from Brazil you have a
Russian name that just occurred to me
wait I'm not sure which one you are you
are not for me
sico right so anyway so object object is
a collection of properties not ordered
okay they are not ordered collection
let me read an object is foremost a
collection properties each property is a
key and a value
okay so object is a collection of
key-value pairs the key now next thing
important to know the key must be of two
data types one string two symbol okay
now symbol is a new thing in JavaScript
2015 you know the language and the
symbol key is is basically it's not even
readable it's just like something
internal it functioned the purpose of
symbol key is just as a ID you know
identification ID you know just like
almost like a random stream stream you
cannot even see it you cannot you know
even see what you know actually show the
symbol it's just you know a random thing
it's an ID used for keys so that the
purpose is so that you can create an
object with a symbol key that nobody
will be able to override it because you
know you know it almost impossible
because you cannot retrieve the symbol
key since you don't know what you know
what number or ID it is unless you know
the ID you know as so the purpose of
symbol key is just to to create unique
key unique unique keys that other people
may not not likely to be overweight
written so let me write it down the
purpose of the symbol of the let me
rephrase it so so it's more accurate
purpose of a key that's a symbol type is
so that so that's such properties to not
do not easily get overwritten okay so
you know you cannot stand on each
other's keys so again let me let me so a
property is a collection of key and
value pairs now the keys are of two
possible value types string or symbol
now we can see here we have three keys
ABC and you see the a and B and C are
actually strings you know they are
actually strings because you know for
example we can actually put a string
like that and let's print it and the
result is your sentence still the same
you know what actually happened is that
when you don't have a stream the
JavaScript automatically convert that
that B into a stream okay so now let's
say the the type of a Keys value can be
any JavaScript data type okay so the
match so the key must be of two types
string or symbol okay
simple we we are not going to talk about
we barely use okay it's new in 2015 so
the key must be either string or symbol
if it's not strange our script
automatically converted to stream so so
you know this C with or without code is
actually the same now the value can be
any JavaScript type so let's so what are
the JavaScript value types let's have a
look so we have here JavaScript
JavaScript variable JavaScript value
types now
variable do not have a type but but any
JavaScript value is associated with the
thing called type you know the type of
the thing so you have undefined is a
type new is the type pooling is a type
pooling has two possible values true and
false or building building keywords so
then you have string type you have
number type you have symbol type then
you have the object type so if every
value in javascript is one of these type
so so let me summarize one more time
object is a collection of keys and
values you know key and value is a pair
key values collection key and values the
one key and value together is called a
property so you know you got a bunch of
properties now the key must be of two
possible types string or symbol almost
always it's a stream you know unless you
are you know you know like before 2015
keys are always just strings so key can
be two types string or symbol the value
of a key can be any type that means it
can be any of these undefined no
true/false or can be a string which is
typical very common or can be a number
very common it can also be a symbol and
it can be a object again like you know
like what is object the collection of
key value pairs so the value of a key
can also be another object and of course
that object in turn you know has its own
key value key value pair properties so
the interesting thing about the key when
a value is object is that so what is
Java JavaScript object JavaScript object
is anything that basically anything not
one of these undefined no
Stream number symbol if it's not one of
those then it's object so what does that
mean it basically practically includes
any function any array data object
regular expression object JSON object
you know it just can be anything so so
we covered let me let me write that down
so object is one foremost
okay then then to each object we each
object has a link to another object we
call it the parent object we call it a
parent or the prototype object
now remember Java JavaScript object is a
key value pairs so it is just like
exactly like a hash table in Ruby pearl
or a dictionary in Python so you can
kind of think of it exactly like a
dictionary in Python now that's one
thing correction of key value pairs but
that's not all
to object they object each object also
by definition has a link may may have a
link may have a link to another object
and we call that object its parent so
it's a directed arrow you know with an
arrow link so so a essentially a object
may have a parent it may not may or may
not you know so in general all the
building objects you know all the
JavaScript peony objects they they they
all have a parent they are all connected
in forming a tree the object can have
only one parent you can never have two
parents and also a objects parents
that the parents will never be circular
so you cannot have a spare anis peepees
parent is CeCe's parent is a that can
never happen that's impossible
you also cannot have you know peace
parent is a a spirit is P you know so
that doesn't exist object always have a
parent one parent and you know and it
may or may not have so you you always
have like a line or lineage so so this
this is called the parent of parent act
of a object is called the prototype
chain so you might have heard that you
know prototype chain so that's that just
means you know object always have a
parent know okay so but what what is the
purpose let's talk about what is the
purpose of this parent chain you know
what does it actually do what you know
so the purpose is that okay the the
purpose of the prototype chain you know
the purpose of parent itself I mean
what's the point of something having a
parent the purpose of all these is only
for one thing that is when JavaScript
look up a property like when you say
let's say for example when you say
object dot a you know suppose you want
to print that we can print it and the
result is what you can see here you know
we are accessing the the key the
property key a we want the property key
a value so the result is one you know
because we defined it that way so when
you access a object when you try to read
a object e of a object-- JavaScript will
try to find that to see if this object
has has that key in this case it
so the result is one however if this
object does not have a key of that name
you know by that string or symbol in
this case it's a a is a stream so if the
if the object does not have that key
then JavaScript we all look up try to
check the parent object has that key if
not it will try to look up that object's
parent to see if that object has a key
and so on until a key is found by that
name a oh you know the object has no
more parent you know and no key is found
then in that case it actually returns
undefined so so this behavior you know
this you know trying to find a key then
try to check the parent and try to check
that parent you know so this behavior is
called inheritance now this is important
because inheritance this is what it
means and only mean these nothing else
nothing absolutely nothing else
inheritance in JavaScript just means
when JavaScript checks our object we
will try to keep checking the parent
until a key is found or normal parent is
found you know so this is called
inheritance and this is the only yes
this is the only purpose of the whole
parent thing you know we said before
object may have a parent you know and
you know therefore that object may also
have a parent you know you have a parent
chain you had you know called prototype
chain what what's the point about this
parent for I mean what's this useful the
only purpose is when when you try to
look at lookup a try to read a objects
key you know you'll just look keep
looking up the parent so that that is
the only your purpose so we talk about
okay let's write this down the whole
point a parent or parent n is just
when JavaScript looks up a key a objects
key it will try to check the parent
until a key is found or normal parent
object okay this is called inheritance
in JavaScript let's just say in
inheritance okay in JavaScript and this
is the only whole purpose parent or
parent chain okay there's no no other
use parent this is only purpose now I'm
I'm not doing good
am I like so rot glass six am I like
being too verbose or too repetitive or
I'm doing okay
so you know let me know so any guys
watching let me know give me your
comments any comment you know don't need
needs not to be a question let me just
you know give me some feedback so I know
so we cover we are trying to define what
is a JavaScript mathematically you know
because I'm trying to teach this great
thank you so I'm trying to teach this in
a math you know logical way so we are
trying to define what is the object
mathematically mathematically so first
of all we know it's a collection of key
and value pairs okay and key must be
string or symbol and value can be any
any other type and we also know by
definition a object has this kind of
link called parent pink or prototype you
know links to another object we call its
parent okay we also know that so these
two things so far these two things are
not all yet they are part of the
definition of object the you know the
meaning the practical meaning of object
in JavaScript and we also discussed you
know the point the the purpose of the
parent thing you know it's so that
object access wheel you know so you know
ensured its inheritance inheritance ok
javascript is these two things now there
is there are one or more two things
about it yeah let me talk about it
one more thing one more thing we
mentioned okay let me take the match I
patch up okay we mentioned javascript
object you know two things key value
pairs and there's a parent possible that
possibly there's a parent linked to a
parent one more thing javascript object
you know that the definition of object
is that some objects may okay some
object may have a special behavior or
spatial data internal data that are not
key and values now this is getting a bit
complex because it's kind of
inconsistent you know because what what
we are saying is a javascript object
some object may have a special property
or special behavior not special behavior
or special internal data okay
let me give you some quick examples what
I'm talking about for example array
JavaScript array is a object
you know because remember we talked
about JavaScript value types you know
arrays is not undefined arrays not
normal arrays not number arrays not
bullying you know it's not any of those
things so array so what is array it's
not string either it's not a symbol so
it is a object you know so so array is a
object
arrays object that means it has key
value pairs and
we mentioned it may have special
behavior that is true because array has
a property key named links for example
let's let's create a way create a array
example okay so let's say constant AR
let's say 3 4 - okay
and let's print printer array so we see
that we get that and by the way to find
the type of object use the type of
operator so we can you know we can print
here console.log type of a or object so
and we can also do it for the array here
so we are trying to type we are trying
to print the type of array or object
you'll see that you know both of them
return just object meaning that they are
objects and so here we have array and
array has the length let me show you
console.log a r dot a r dot length
okay now length is a property key so
when you say a r dot length it returns a
value let's see so you see is it returns
three because we have three elements in
the array so what is this length
remember we talked before now don't
become don't get confused with other
languages because with other languages
you automatically think oh of course
I'll rake out the length but remember we
are trying to do this in a mathematical
logic foundation way so we we said
before arrays a object is
a Correctional properties you know kyun
values and it may have a parent now we
never mentioned there is a property
length where does it came from you know
we didn't define a property length year
no you know you know for example this
array three four two three things where
are the keys
what are these people to you know we we
are not seeing key value pairs because
we because we mentioned that object is
always key value pairs that's one of the
thing so but remember we also mentioned
a object may have like special behaviors
special behaviors and special internal
properties arrays one example and this
is part of the reason why javascript
language is pretty bad is fairly fairly
complex so array so arrays object so you
have length length is a building
property like you don't have to define
it it's already there it's just there
why well it's useful but but it's not
logical well that's just the way that it
is you know it just has a magical
property already big building named
length and when you change the array
push for example when I add a more let's
say add five here then we try to print
it then we try to print length you can
see the length was three then we added a
element the lengths becomes four you see
that the length automatically get
updated even we didn't change it so
that's magic there is no other mechanism
in JavaScript entirety of JavaScript
spec to explain this other other than
just magic that's just that's just the
way JavaScript is that is why there are
many complexities in JavaScript now also
remember javascript array is actually
you know it is a object there is no such
thing as
just a object it just so happens that it
has this kind of magical thing like
links and you know it's actually just a
property because if you print the if you
print all the properties of the array
you will see the property keys let's try
that so let's go to JavaScript in-depth
and let's go to JavaScript these
properties so we want to be able to show
Oh a objects keys so we can do this
object keys include string key yeah
let's do that
so console.log object a our object keys
object keys okay on the object AR it
will print all the keys of the object AR
run it and here is the result you can
see that it's fully let's put the result
here let's just put some of them result
okay down second almost done vennett
good so you can see the result of
running this is that you know it returns
these AR objects all the keys of this AR
AR
object and you see we got zero one two
three
each one is a string now it's a stream
because remember Oh a key must be either
string or symbol so in this case a
string but where do they came from I
mean we didn't ever add a property key
you know zero there where'd it came from
it's just magic
so array in JavaScript it's object
that's pretending to be your ways so all
the keys came from the index of the
array 2 3 you know 0 1 2 3 because we
have 4 4 things so that that is why so
you know that's some that's that's some
of the complexities of java javascript
so let me so let's go on to mention the
the third property of the I mean the
third thing that defines a a object so a
object may have special behavior or
internal data okay for example for
example JavaScript array or function or
map or set objects or even date state
like when you get when you create a date
like equals some x equals to new date
you get you know you get a date but
where does that date came from you know
it's not a property key it's not key
value pairs where does the date came
from it is it came from a internal kind
of internal data you cannot access I
mean you can access but
but it's just internal you know it just
magically has a date so that's for the
date object and and similarly for each
you know for a function for example it's
let's define a function function FF
takes X as value and return X plus 1
let's for let's say for example okay and
let's call FF 5 and the research is
gonna be six let's run it
six indeed so you can see that so here's
a function but a function a game
function is a object two because you can
add key value pairs or properties you
can add properties to it for example
let's let's let's add some properties to
it let's say f f/a okay wait F if a
equals to let's say F F F F X okay
equals to three okay let's just say for
example and M equals to that okay then
we console.log F X dot X let's see what
we get three there it is you can see
that good morning Paul why does
JavaScript even have array then why not
have only object okay let me talk about
that let me finish about the function so
you see a function is also a object
because you know it's it's not undefined
you know like we mentioned before it's
not strange it's not any of those basic
let's go there Java scream dead
leave the window open so we can easily
refer to it you know so these are the
value types so JavaScript function is
also an object because it's not any one
of those other things a function is an
object that means you know like we
mentioned before object always can have
key value pairs so therefore we can add
you know let's say F F dot X equals to 3
you know or anything then we can name it
shows and in fact we can now print the
keys of it for example let's print
object Archies we want to see all keys
of the FF so there we go
and we see here is a result X and M
which is you know correct so you know
function so you know this this is a bit
strange you know function is also a
object but it has this kind of special
behavior because you can call it like a
function you know you can it's like you
know a thing that does something but
technically they are all just JavaScript
objects you know JavaScript does not
give a function as special you know
technically it doesn't but in practice
we all know function is you know it's a
function you use it as a function you
don't usually use use it like you know a
object or dictionary
you know same thing with array when you
have array you you you you use it as a
array you don't try to use it as a
object but however you can and a lot of
people when people do that it's a
mistake so you get confused and
therefore you have lots of bugs so why
is array you know so what's the point of
array then why do you have this strange
kind of strange behavior well the basic
answer is that JavaScript sucks you know
because it was created it was designed
created written implemented all together
in 10 days by this Brendan Eich guy from
Netscape you know he's
he's now running the company brave
browser today so anyways yeah so it is
really it's truly you know if you look
up JavaScript history from him he has
plants and other places you can verify
you know it's just written in tender is
designed the whole thing designed and
implemented the you know compiler
written you know in ten days so and in
the beginning it was designed to be a
easy language for non-programmers you
know for HTML designers who can so they
can maybe add a little code to make
their page interactive it's not it's
nothing like today you know where you
have whole applications written in
JavaScript all his servers that's you
know that was not in 1995 he was just
designed to be a a language for you know
non-programmers almost like in for
beginners you know so it's kind of
rushed and also they tried to make you
know JavaScript the language is based on
the scheme Lisp the function of foreign
language and self the language named
self there's a language named self where
the JavaScript prototype inheritance the
prototype object system came from the
functional aspect features of JavaScript
came from the scheme disp language which
is great language you know I think I
heard that self you know a lot of people
also like self but I don't know self so
anyway javascript is based on these
great languages but however it has to be
made to be like Java because there is a
commercial deal
Netscape with the Java some ecosystems
at a time so they try to have the Java
syntax and they try to fit in like you
know to behave like kind of like Java
the language you know the Sun
Microsystems Java so so for marketing
reasons and because the big rush so it
becomes it's rather very calm
kaydee language complicated in not in a
good way it's just sucks
so that is why today we have this you
know we already mentioned few like white
why do you if I raise a object why do
you know what's the point of it right
the thing about that is when when when
browsers implement there's a difference
when browsers when you create array and
you don't try to use it like a object
you know for example you don't delete a
key you know in the middle if you do not
do that if you do that then then
something happens so get out I'll tell
you but if you do not if you just use it
like a way like a normal way then the
implementation maintains maintains it
internally like AC array so it's very
efficient you know you can loop you can
access random access you know in
constant time but however here's the
thing if you have array let's say 1,000
element let's say 0 to 1000 then if you
try to use the delete operator to delete
some of the element you know what
happened is that if let's say if you
delete 300 random elements in our array
that has 1,000 elements what happened is
that we that array is technically now
called a sparse array in JavaScript and
essentially the effect is that it
becomes a normal object it losses all
the efficiency poverty of array it
becames you know hash table or
dictionary so so this is all internal I
mean on this language level you're not
supposed to know but yeah so that's why
it's part of reason it's very complex so
does that make sense there's a lot of
complex complexities but let me finish
yet so if he
there's something unclear let me know
let me mention another complexity which
is very useful to know that is that the
type of operator so how do you find
something a values type you use the type
of operator but here's an important
thing another complexity when you use
type of are know for example like that
you you get the return is a object he
says it's an object that is wrong you
know that that's just you know one
another problem of JavaScript it's not
know is not a object like we talked
before another let me go back to that
page again the JavaScript values are
just you know one two three four five
six seven seven of them undefined no
true string number symbol object there
is no type called know well I mean no
that the type of know is the literals
keyword know itself and the only value
for the of the type know is just that
value there's nothing else possibly can
be can be no so when you say type of
know you should get no but but that's
not what happens you you it returns a
object you know it says it's an object
and the reason this happens is because
there was a see bug in the JavaScript
language you can you know you can go
through list this link this this is
written by a famous JavaScript expert he
dug into the C code you know back in
1999 not 1995 you know and it's just a
bug in C so that is why when you when
you do type of nor you get you know
JavaScript says it's object so so you
know this is another complexity but also
there's also interesting things
let me type this so you should read that
later you know this this URL also when
you say type of a function let's try the
console log okay type of no let's see
what we get you know we you we get
object we says object now let's let's
try type of FF great thank you so if we
try type of FF what do you think will
happen anyone let's also try type of AR
what would happen you okay I'll give you
five seconds to say and I'm gonna show
run it so you know so there are two
questions type of FF what does it return
f F is a function and AI is a way
well what would type of return okay I'm
gonna run it let's see
so it says function here okay
so for a function he says function for
object
it says object okay so you say it's
object and object you got one of them
wrong so when you say type type F F type
type of FF or function it actually
returns a strange function you know it
says it's a function so here is another
complexity now you know that's why I'm
you know JavaScript many people hates it
you know remember here are the you know
value possible value types of JavaScript
there is no type code function okay but
however when you say type of and use of
function it just return function now
this is actually extremely useful
because
you need to distinguish object you know
a function is you know not normally a
object you know it's a function so you
need that distinction but but by the
JavaScript spec there is no such thing
as a function type you know it's just
object so so you have this you know you
have all these weird situations so just
remember you know when you use type of
type of there are kind of two special
cases one is function and one is the new
so when you say type of know it actually
say object when you say type of function
it says function not object you know and
and also when you say type of array
it doesn't say already says object so
this is you know it's just really bad
but however you know people get you know
what can you do people just use it you
know like if you consider computing
history let's say C programming language
in Unix
oh my god and there's lots of problems
there in C press first but you know
people just get on you know you just
have to you know get on with it use it
so I think I almost covered everything
about object but there is I think there
is possibly one more so but but let me
do a summary first okay three things
about object one is a collection of
properties key value pairs
that's what object is - it may have
another object called its parent there's
a link you know so so a object may have
a parent and the purpose of this parent
thing parent chain is just so that when
you look up a property javascript will
look up its parent try to see if there
and repeat then this is called
inheritance so okay so that's the second
thing about object it may have a parent
for the inheritance purposes when
looking up properties
3a object some objects may have a kind
of special behavior or special internal
data you know you cannot it's not it's
not like he value pairs you can readily
you know manipulate it's just internal
so example of such objects are function
array there's a map type which is new in
let me show you JavaScript in depth so
you go to in depth and you go down you
can see JavaScript iterables okay set
object and map object well actually
let's go to JavaScript reference so you
can see you have this set object a set
object is just a mathematical set it's
just like it's like on a way except that
no item can be Pete every item must be
unique so that's what set is and you
have this map object map object is a
proper hash table or dictionary like
dictionary in Python or hash table in in
Ruby so both set and map objects are new
in 2015
okay they just added that so why do you
need map object because I mean you you
say you say it's just like a dictionary
but a object is already your dictionary
you know because it's got key value
pairs why do you need map again that's
another complexity because the object
data type we created here it's got a lot
of problems for example there is no way
to find how many keys are there well you
can but you first of all you have to get
all the keys then count the keys you
know you know tell me you know when you
get the keys it's a race then you use
the length property but that's not you
that's too English and you know you this
but there's no direct way to to know how
many keys you have so you have these
kind of problems so so that is why
javascript in 2015
properly added the dictionary or also
known as hash table thing which which is
a object you know another object so you
have the map object so let me so let me
mentioned so that number three things
some object may have special behavior or
internal data for example array function
map or set objects or date or all
rejects or rejects or you know not kind
of you you know but to JavaScript
technically speaking they are all just
objects like like a coding PI you know
if you go by the JavaScript spec
specification for example I have several
links to them you you know they they
just define it that way though all these
are objects there is no to us you know
we might say okay function array map set
you know these things are kind of like
subtype of the object type that makes
sense right because you know you have
this object but you have you know you
have array function no more object you
have map you know this date you know
these things behaves differently because
they have special purposes so we might
think you know it's logical to us we say
oh those are subtype you know of the
object type but however JavaScript spec
has no such notion yeah so that's too
bad
otherwise we we could you know maybe we
can have a function or you know like
subtype of then you will properly tell
us you know when you when we have array
you'll say array you know when we have
you know a functions
it says function when we have a normal
check you will say like data object you
know for example but there's no such
there's no actual subtype concept but
however there's a trick you if you
really want to find the the subtype you
know so-called subtype of a object type
you can and but that's considered like a
trick so you can find it you can find it
by object and inheritance object type
okay fine objects type for example here
I show you how to find the various types
how do you actually determine you know
whether this is array or is it's not a
way you know it's just another data
object you know oh this so you can check
you know the the special way the trick
is this reflect on apply object our
prototype to string then object then oh
you can say object a prototype dot to
string Col then object and you it will
return a string like one of these it so
so in other words it tells us the
subtype of the object value type and you
know this is sometimes useful but it's
it's tricky again it's tricky because
javascript language does not define no
such concept of sub sub type i mean if
there is then you could have easy you
have a function that precisely tell us
you know what subtype it is but
javascript doesn't have that the the
reason that the the technique we are
doing is actually from a kind of
convoluted thing it's it's it's it's not
easy to explain it's not simple to
explain but but anyway that's how you
how you can find the the subtype of a
object type
so I think that is so we covered so far
we defined object to be these three kind
of having these three aspects you know a
collection of properties may have a
parent and may have special behavior
that's a three thing but there is like
one more thing then we'll be done today
54 minutes great one more thing and
about object so let's go to here I'll
check overview so let's read it let's
see if I missed something so javascript
summary of javascript object object is a
collection of key-value pairs okay each
key/value pair is called poverty okay
most objects have special purpose in
internal data for example function
objects is a function array object has a
magical length property bigger
expression object is used to match
stream pattern state object holds
date/time data and so on the one object
that does not have any special purpose
is what we call the data object you know
which one way to create it is you know
with this notation you know curly
bracket in
okay so we cover so and and and let me
continue each object has zero or one
parent object okay called its prototype
when a object is obsessed where poverty
is exist JavaScript will go of the
parent chain koko of the parent object
or parent a parent at to look for the
poverty this is called inheritance okay
so that's that's a the third thing about
object you know her parents may have
parents now for the the fourth thing
about object is that each object has a
special info attached called the is
extensible internal slot it specifies
where the new properties can be added to
the object okay that's the that's the
other thing I want to mention so so be
so so we we are trying to define the
object there's one more requirement the
the so called you know the object thing
has a special info attached to date
attached to it that that is called
is extensible you know technically in
JavaScript SPECT they say they call it
the X deco it is extensible internal
slot they used the word internal start
to describe this special info sometimes
you know in I think in previous spec
it's called attribute but you know the
terms change anyway so anyway the point
about this is that each object remember
each object may have a parent meaning it
has a link to another object we call it
its parent but it also have another kind
of special info that is is extensible
meaning that the the the kind of value
of this is either true or false so if it
is extensible that means you can add
more properties to the object if not
that means you cannot
so you have this is extensible thing you
know it's called internal start by the
way it's not a property okay it's not a
key it's not like you just say that is
extensible equals true you know true or
false you cannot do it like that it's
not it's not a property it's not a key
value thing it's just a special internal
information but if you want to you know
change this is extensible or thing you
can there are methods to do that so
actually I have written all these out
for example if you just go to JavaScript
in depth and go back to the object
section object and inheritance you
already know what inheritance means we
covered so you go this section there are
ways to find out which is a objects
parents you know sometimes you want to
know you know find the average
experience you can which is very easy by
the way you can find the objects type
you can find the prototype chain you can
for example set parent or get parent
almost anytime you want and here is how
do you hear the explanation of the
prototype chain and you can you can show
prototype chain you can prevent adding
property okay sometimes you want to
prevent people or yourself from adding
another property so all you have to do
is you want to set set this is
extensible to force but because it's
internal thing you cannot do it directly
you do it by by calling the method
object are preventing extension then the
object name so you know so and you can
also check if an object is is extensible
so okay so I think that's the the main
thing is I want to cover about
JavaScript object the let's see okay sit
and get prototypes that that's set and
get parent okay let's go to let's go
back to JavaScript in-depth house okay
yeah so that's basically what I want to
cover today yeah we are trying to cover
what is javascript object in a kind of
mathematicians way which means you know
you abstract me you identify things you
know by the way know that we didn't
mention anything about class you know
like in Java or Python or Ruby you
created you know you defined classes
then you instantiate a object you know
from where class class has inheritance
like parent you know a tree you know
then you create objects then you can you
can also extend a class you know
JavaScript does not have that okay this
is important javascript object is this
is nothing like that like you know you
saw it's nothing you know Java scripts
object system the OB system it's called
prototype based object system it's
modeled from the self language it is
absolutely totally nothing like the way
OB is in Ruby Python or Java because in
there typically you define classes and
classes can can have a children so
classes in helping the they say inherit
each other you know then you create an
object of the particular class the
object will have you know the same kind
you know it's like a type but again but
we have covered we have talked about
JavaScript object for one hour did we
ever mention classes no because it's
nothing like that
but javascript you know so you know like
all the things we talked about
javascript object you know like
correction of key value pairs may have a
parent may have special behavior and
have this is extensible thing attached
that's the four things about javascript
object and that is it that
mathematically defines it there is no
class in object creation there is
nothing like that
but however javascript do have the
keyword class and that is from
javascript 2015 which you can read about
it here which function was some kind of
a syntax sugar in other words you you
you do not need this class whatsoever
because it does not add anything new to
JavaScript object remains the way we you
know the four things we talked about
that is the definition of object in
JavaScript script mathematically there
is no such thing as you know class
really but there is you know in 2015
they added a class keyword which is very
convenient to allow you to create
automatic helps in in in a sense that it
automatically creates several objects
and several properties by a wine single
definition with a keyword class so when
you say class something you are actually
javascript wheel behind you know will
take your code and create several
objects the way we defined it you know
several object with with proper linkage
of parents and also create several
properties whose values are the
functions you
in your class keyword so that that kind
of so the cast keyword of 2015 kind of
helps it's kind of convenient to make
you know it's kind of convenient if you
do Opie canned of thing but again it's
important to know JavaScript object is
nothing absolutely no similarity yeah
you could say absolutely no similarity
to the class or object you know systems
in Java or Python oh so why is
JavaScript so why do we use that's
that's not difficult to answer because
because you know so it began in 1995 it
didn't really go anywhere it's kind of a
it's almost like a failure
there's nobody using using it not not
really not not really not industry
heavyweight you know it's like anyone
can miss it no problem but so back then
let's say in the 1990s or early 2000s
the only other thing that can run in a
browser is Java you know Java is not
just for servers but it can you can run
any browser called applet you have this
kind of special plugin by the way Google
Keo did so it you know you cannot even
Java high anymore
so anyway so Java you can in a browser
you run this per game to run Java
applets so-called applet ever just means
Java code running inside browser we are
this kind of plugging a foundation in a
browser but that is removed few years
ago in all browsers basically so anyway
so so to run code in championing a
browser you have two options either
JavaScript which is a very extremely
lousy language designed for
non-programmers okay we have already
seen several examples how it is you know
a lot of quacks yeah so you have in
browser you have Java for design for
non-programmers very lousy on the other
hand you have Java okay you have
JavaScript on the other hand you have
Java which is the languages for rather
professional programmers and it's rather
lower level much lower level than in
JavaScript because one javascript is
kind of equivalent to five or ten lines
of Java so Java it's very hard to do you
know is more difficult especially most
people are program are beginners you
know and also Java is very clunky
because it has to start the virtual
machine and so on anyway the the end
story is that Java kind of failed
you know only maybe amateur programmers
use Java to create you know some fun
applications educational applications in
Java but the industry doesn't really
have any use for it Java him in browser
okay this is in browser on the other
hand JavaScript start to have more and
more users because because partly
because for e-commerce you know for
e-commerce when you want to buy and
update things you usually you don't want
to reload the entire HTML page usually
like you just update you just want to
update a section of your page so if you
can use JavaScript just to update a tiny
section like one item in basket you just
click you know put one item in basket
then the basket changes to what you
don't want to you know because reloading
a whole page back to the server you know
back to the browser takes a long time
it's too slow so you want just to be
able to update parts of the screen and
that is super useful so gradually people
developed what's so-called
ajax a
JX kind of hack no because javascript is
pretty bad and but people do really want
to update you know just small part of
the scream all the time like for example
when you are chatting you know you just
type a message you just want to update a
message you like meanwhile can talk to
the server you know I keep the
connection but you cannot do that before
you know be lets say 2005 it's not easy
because the the the browser works at
that time the the idea is that you just
reload the whole page like every time
you type something you send it to the
server I mean I typed something I press
enter my browser send it to the server
the server sees takes my message and
send the whole page back so my browser
update does host rinse screen you know
but it's so it's very wasteful you know
when you have a chat you know things
like that but actually what people
really want is everything stayed the
same just you know change the part
that's the new incoming text and so on
so eventually javascript has you know
slow javascript has this critical use
and people's needed especially
commercial organizations they really
need it so it just kind of grow and grow
and so you start with ajax then you
started to have yeah ajax then you then
eventually html5 kim because apple and
that has a they are kicking out the
flash extremely popular flash because
flash is not friendly on apple you know
fascist run by Adobe was Macromedia
Adobe bought it so it became fresh and
fresh it's very slow on Apple computers
because no market you know and so I
don't like it but Apple do need you know
interactivity drawing and stuff so Apple
invented canvas technology that
eventually became part of html5 so html5
pushed the whole thing and then
in 2008 or 2009 the not Jas came up you
know that's the whole history about not
J's because but basically it's
JavaScript as a server and that
that kind of changed the whole industry
a lot it's rather it's even it's
technically not that good but the reason
you change the industry because it's it
it allows you know it it further rather
run away the old kind of thinking of
doing servers like you see in the
homepage it throw that away
so instead everything is like we so you
started to have what's called a single
page application you know basically
you're a single web page you'd load it
one time then everything you know you're
no longer like reload the whole page you
just have you know services running
behind it talking to the server update
to the part of the screen like a game or
whatever you know single page
application
so anyway not jeaious became you know
extremely popular so that further and
also with html5
on the scene that began to update the
entire JavaScript so so we eventually we
have Java JavaScript 2015 which is
actually like a complete overhaul not
overhaul but it's like a complete new
language with huge amount of features
that Pete's any any advanced feature in
Ruby or Java or Python so you can look
at JavaScript 2015 features you have
lips which is good you have constant you
have arrow functions you have function
argument default values you have rest
parameters you have destructuring
assignment you have object you have you
you can you know now property keys can
be computed meaning a variable can be
property keys
you know whatever its value will be the
real poverty key you know so you have a
bunch of features in 2015 they also
importantly you have you begin to have
iterators this kind of thing iterators
and generators and interface so the
language becomes more complex you know
already
before it's kind of a small very small
language designed for beginners you know
but now but it's very badly done because
you know it's in Russia and all that but
now it's like the language becomes
sizable sizable okay with all the
features you can find in Python whatever
Python Perl all these you have in
JavaScript you know possibly even better
than but however they try to maintain
backward compatible meaning that all the
bad things in JavaScript remains so you
have this rather even more complexity
you know if you are not careful it's
very complex language okay I talked a
lot okay any questions I'm gonna react
any any questions yeah so so because
these reasons JavaScript became you know
it's like one thing leads to another you
know so after not jeaious becomes
extremely successful Oh before not J's
there's a jQuery you know remember
jQuery charity queries
one of the fundamental help in spreading
Java because because this language
helped you know making all the browser's
kind of compatible they'll commit you
know because it's very useful like Dom
is very complex itself but jQuery helped
a lot and also JavaScript spread
functional programming actually I would
say even more than Haskell practically
speaking because JavaScript language
they support functional programming it
came from the scheme Lisp you know where
JavaScript is based on so function can
read
a function it is a function it's a value
function can also take functions as
argument this idea is extremely powerful
so that is why sometimes you hear you
know functional programming in
JavaScript and that is actually I would
say in my opinion okay javascript has
helped spread the functional programming
idea more than any functional
programming language more than a scow
okay it is JavaScript that helped help
the idea to the masses to that you know
to the beginner programmers who don't
know what they are doing you know like
you know HTML designers you know a lot
of people who just you know you know
they are not programmers but they know
some HTML they design a web page so in
in 2000 a lot of people these people
learned you know start to program you
know begin with you know maybe your
little JavaScript it became and many
many of them are today experts you know
so yeah ok that's it about maybe that is
it about understanding javascript object
like a mathematician okay am i okay so
is that does that make sense
let's see let's see if I anything else
em cover so if you have any questions
any comments about my videos my anything
type it you have like 10 seconds then
then we're gonna shut down and say
goodbye math object said type okay by
the way so I'm sending my tutorial so if
you are intrigued about JavaScript this
is the best tutorial okay give you a
give it a shot
so I'm sitting it you get the whole page
fast loading and also serve as a
reference and also Tom scripting don't
scripting is where things gets start to
get interesting because you start to
program actual you know programming the
browser I have several examples I mean
yeah let me show one example and that's
it for today okay
actually I showed this before yeah six
takes ah could you talk about some of
your favorite JavaScript libraries okay
actually I don't use any cuz because I'm
kind of old-fashioned and I'm kind of
I'm like you could say I have trouble
any new stuff yeah I have 50 years old I
so for mixed reasons I don't like I
don't I try not to use I don't actually
I don't use any of the frameworks
alright first okay let me give you a
practical advice first of all don't use
jQuery jQuery because jQuery it was
invented around 2005 okay anything
jQuery can do is already in the
JavaScript language 2015 actually a
little bit more lines you know sometimes
you need to line since they've won but
you don't need jQuery at all so if you
are not working with legacy code you
know a jar a job or something
any new project you don't need jQuery
don't use it okay life is much simpler
and better not using it because what it
does everything JavaScript building can
do so don't use jQuery but I would
recommend you know I would recommend
I've studied react.js I only studied it
because I've been thinking maybe I
should use it you know because but for
my for my personal projects I don't
really need it so I yeah so I would say
so if you are you know just known in
JavaScript try to not use any library in
fact there's a movement right now I
think called JavaScript 30 you know
hashtag JavaScript 30 meaning like
something like write a JavaScript
application in 30 days or something like
creating 30 applications I forgot which
which but they they say one of the rule
is no library whatever just use plain
JavaScript like JavaScript language you
know it's JavaScript in browser that's
all you need so they are I guess they
are trying to push you know they are
trying to tell people guys you don't
really need all these fancy libraries
which is good you know so if you are
learning if you just I recommend you
know if you are starting out don't use
any of the libraries of course at work
you probably have to you know depending
on what they use and never use jQuery
never like for whatsoever reason never
if your company's is using it try to get
rid of it like it's it's time it's you
know you can like try to remove it react
I think it's pretty good there's another
thing view touches I haven't tried but I
heard it's like Chinese people Chinese
programmer at Google wrote that and it's
also very popular food rjs this
angularjs I looked up anger a little bit
I don't like its history I think it
because angular just like JavaScript and
PHP they were born humbly angular was
spawned because some programmer tried to
make money they are trying to create
like they are trying to create a
language so that any terming can use
like non-programmers like you know bees
knew your mom your dad it was you know
your granddad or someone trying to
create a web store or something you know
they they have a small business you know
they try to create their website but oh
my god you know what is javascript like
they don't know so there you have this
angular that's original purpose you know
the guys are thinking we are just
creating this product so anyone can
click and make a website no time dynamic
website that is the history that is or
engine of angular you know then Google
bought it then you know they try to
change it you know they try to erase the
history you know they they try to erase
this this humble history just like you
know just like PHP has done Phe P began
as teenagers pretty homepage you know
and and you know ten years ago it became
the most popular language and it was
named like post you know it's named like
hyper let's see PHP what does they say
PHP Istanbul something hyper for God you
know this they are basically they are
they are kind of lies you know they are
anyway so yeah so and I also look at t3
the the plotting library which is I'm
what I'm doing now that's my main
project to create mathematical
visualizations and I really hate
chiefly okay let me show you some
articles so here's the article about
history of angular saw the d3 okay then
I explained something I really dislike
about d3 by the way I tried to write a
tutorial but that if this tutorial is
incomplete and and no good so it ignore
it so don't you know you can know of my
d3 tutorial but anyway I wrote this
essay because I try to study it in depth
and d3 I find it to be it's almost like
a religion it's a voodoo okay I don't
like it at all they try they are trying
to create like a new way a new way for
writing visual visualization of data
like a new paradigm you know they are
trying to change you know the the the
the Nommo that the the practical way of
writing you know visual application they
are trying to create some kind of new
you know like patterns and extreme
programming so I don't you know I don't
like it I don't find you know oh yeah
PHP hypertext preprocessor where does a
yeah so but we did the first P went
professional hypertext free process
yeah libraries yeah so that's what I
have to say about libraries you know I
hope I'm not using them because mostly
because I actually don't know them well
and also that is because I I don't
really want to you know because so what
I'm trying to say is that I don't really
have a solid reason you know because you
know part of the reason because I don't
know I just have a lot of opinions about
libraries but I don't actually know
this stuff so you know take take it as
what if I'm trying to you know part of
the reason I study JavaScript and I
don't use any libraries and that's why I
study JavaScript in depth so I wanted to
you know you will be able to write those
libraries if you want to but however if
you like a lot JavaScript programmers
they use these libraries they know how
of course in some sense it's actually
easier of course because see so then you
know you just want some commands but
then once you get used to you don't
really know how to how to do things you
know you don't understand the underlying
dome-like you know in jQuery you have to
select something you know this is just a
dollar sign dollar sign which is say 80s
by the way it's a it's it's just a
function name dollar sign
it's a 80s for jQuery the function name
so you can select something right but
but a lot of people you they wouldn't
know how to do that without jQuery and
same thing with react you know
especially things like we react which is
very you know the it's actually a layer
on top of JavaScript trying to make
things easier yeah okay okay thank you
guys for watching hope you like it bye