hello welcome to another episode of the
S Talk Show today we are going to I'm
going to give you my first impression of
this fantastic
thing SVA board s data hand SW board
data hand okay truly fantastic now after
you know having it you know the guy
showed me Moran Morgan Venable the guy
showed me I think this is the best form
of input device let me talk about that
so I'm going to talk about this keyboard
my first impression that's today and uh
and I'm going to try to be short in 20
minutes 20 minutes for this video that's
it usually my videos are long okay so so
so here are my favorite keyboards okay
all of them these are you know my
favorite keyboards so this is glove
80 this is my wal glove 80 fantastic
okay glove 80 if you search for S
keyboard blog you'll find full review
for all of
them this is Expo night okay
fantastic Expo
night okay and uh this is kesis 360
wired okay it's also great I recommend
fantastic this is Ultimate hacking
keyboard okay I use it for as a keyboard
markco it's also fantastic okay let's
see what's the YouTube uh complaining
uh stream status pool am I doing okay so
how are you guys if you are here say hi
okay so that covers all my my favorite
keyboards uh now let me let me talk
about um the SW v data
hand okay so if you have a questions ask
it okay I got the Kinesis 360 a while
back and I can't get the glove 0 out my
brain I'd love to mess with the data
hand but I don't think I can adjust oh
this data hand you know I just got it
the first day and I'm going to try to
learn it it's very simple okay I'm so so
many things let me let me start to tell
you
okay uh let me start to tell you so so
first so this guy you know the guy who
created this is uh more Venable so
apparently he is a
he's a
industrial design professional you know
so his job for the past I don't know his
life 10 20 years is to design input
devices and maybe others you know so
anyway
so um so meanwhile let me so so he he
worked at all the big tech companies you
know like all all the big the top three
uh big tech companies so this is
actually so he's a professional in this
kind of things so he designed it so so
so now let me tell you about what is
this uh this SW board for those of you
who don't know it yet okay I have
written a review kind of already so can
you see my screen yeah so Smartboard so
originally it's based on I mean it's
based on data hand so this is data hand
this is a device that came out around
1995 and it cost like $1,200 back then
um and uh 1,200 or more you know and but
this device stopped producing since
about 2009 so there's no more data hand
okay so this data hand then you know and
you know I I was aware of the data hand
but I never looked into you know to me
it just like oh this is fancy you know
like probably coding but it's actually
not coding okay but you know the
creation if you haven't looked into you
think it's a fancy oh it's going to take
you a long time to learn and stuff
actually it's so
simple so I'm very greatly impressed by
the SW board okay so anyway the data
hand is the first uh device this is
created by uh created by by by this guy
uh Dale J R okay he's still around you
can see him in in swb board's Discord we
are talk talk about that okay so anyway
this is the first invention and in 2009
they stopped
producing and then okay so this is you
know photos I collected I don't have it
and uh and
then then someone you know in today's
age you know 3D printing someone created
laboard so this is do it yourself you
can print it you know the guy what's his
guy he's a kind of Anonymous you know he
used Anonymous name so anyway someone
created this back in
2019 okay
then then came the SW board uh Morgan
Venable so he he has been using data
hand for like 20 years and he his data
hand broke you know so he need a new one
but it they they don't make it anymore
and so he saw the saw the law board and
then he you know he's a professional in
this thing so he created this Smartboard
basically uh remake of the data hand and
now you can buy okay you can buy so this
can be mass produced and he's you know
planning to so and so he showed me this
yesterday and uh I was just extremely
impressed because I thought um so let me
show you some photos so I so you can go
to my website you can see all the
details photos uh I was truly impressed
because I thought the the optimal input
Hardware shape and Method how you how
you move your fingers and so on is piano
keyboard okay that that's a long story
but anyway let let me show you let let
me start to talk about that later so
anyway this is so this is spab Bo you
can buy okay uh in fact I can I highly
recommend it now like even I haven't
actually learned to be proficient on
this thing proficient but I can actually
recommend it if you are into this kind
of thing okay let me explain so let me
get into the details okay uh so SW board
okay and uh then uh so that's orine
that's kind of the orine where it came
from you know this this thing weird
looking
thing so the Creator uh mgan we talked
about uh the magnetic switch extremely
fantastic okay let me start to show you
the screen okay so this switches okay
let me let me show you oh God my camera
is so bad so in each finger let's see if
I can put on more light so in each
finger you have north
south west east you have four kind of WS
they they function as a but buttons
right then you can also press it down
you know in the middle press it down and
so 1 two 3 four five five buttons for
each finger but for the thumb actually
also five so you so one for your
fingertip your thumb tip one for your
knuckle and one for inward press and one
for if you move your thumb up let's see
you know like one two 3 one two three
four and you can also press this button
down and this extra so if you press it
down and if you press push it further
there's like a mouse click action so for
the thumb there's actually six
buttons okay but the thing is you know
they they are
magnetic uh switches so I didn't you
know I heard of the magnetic switch
before and uh it seems nice but I never
looked into how exactly it works so it's
like so it's like a piece of magnet
magnet okay so let let me try to explain
this so um so you have a magnet you know
attached to something so when you press
it you dislodge the magnet from whatever
iron or whatever it's attached you
dislodge it so once you dislar it
there's no res resistance at all so
there's only
initial uh resistance you know you you
you press the magnet once you it
detached from whatever in fact it
doesn't needs to be attached but anyway
once you press it you know just for
millet there's no res resistance at all
unlike a spring you know in this Cherry
MX or whatever mechanical keyboard
switch there's a spring inside there's
always
resistance but the magnetic switch is
like there's no resistance
so I never thought of it and now I you
know actually have it and use it it's
just fantastic okay like no resistances
at all so that's about the you know I'm
highly impressed by the magnetic
switch uh and the and uh okay so the key
feel you know when you talk about
mechanical key switches you know usually
they talk about key field so the key
field you know um let's see if I can H
let's let's just show you video instead
so the key field is by this mag mag
magne
uh mechanism
magnetic but the actual electronic
switch is
Optical uh what they call Optical
electric so there's kind of a lead laser
it's not a laser but it's kind of lead a
light so once you press it down it
blocks it so then the key is activated
so that's the
electronic uh switch
mechanism but the key feeli is the
magnetic fantastic okay so let me go
over so you know at first when I see
data hand you know it's like oh funky
device how long am I going to learn this
but actually that's not so because you
know if you can type on a normal
keyboard quy you can type on this
because on the quy you see you have the
home row which is like this these four
fingers you know by the way they have
Ting so you can see you know the index
the you know it's higher in
side uh yeah you can see it that
way okay so anyway
so so when you type on a normal keyboard
you have the home row then you have the
upper row you and then you have the the
bottom row on this is exactly the same
so the north wall so they call these
four things uh north south west east I
call them WS so if you want to type the
upper row you simply you know nudge the
upper the
north um let's see if I can show it
clearly you simply nudge it up so that's
like the equivalent to upper row
letters uh and similarly for the bottom
row you see 1 2 3
4 let me show maybe in a different angle
or something so so it's like it's just
like quy or you can use vac or different
layout but that but but it's not
necessarily good if you use other layout
so anyways you can stick with quy okay
so the rul you know so it's actually not
coding keyboard you know at first I
thought this is going to be coding so
you have to do this combination like
combination or or or or TR or you know
squeeze squeeze these two actually this
there's no such thing so this device is
not a coding keyboard it's just like a
normal keyboard okay uh but if you want
to do coding if you want to do sto I'm
going to explain you know in my screen
later if you want to do sto this is the
best thing okay you know today you have
the sto you have the uh what they call
sto sto machine and then you have the
project that uses the um let's see let's
see if I can
quickly
sto with computer keyboard okay so it's
um Plover you know this a project so it
allows you to use a normal computer
keyboard to do sto okay I'm going to
show you pictures later so for sto you
need a code keyboard you need to press
multiple keys at the same time and this
this device is actually best for it okay
it's it beats all these other you know
there's so many keyboard uh trying to do
that uh let me show you let me see
um but anyway so I think this this is
actually best for sto if you want to do
that Co coding keyboard okay so let me
go on to the next point you know so
before I thought so let me show you my
screen okay so here is what standal
machine looks like so this is one form
of physical device uh
and uh you know so there's another sto
machine uh then she she's a creator of
the staino the Plover system so she gave
a talk here uh marab by night um and she
types 240 wat per minute very fast and
uh then you know so I thought I I didn't
really like the keyboard based sto so if
you really want code you need a keyboard
a physical sto machine like that and I
thought a piano keyboard is the best
alternative you know so I thought I was
thinking you know maybe I should buy one
of these piano can you see it you know
piano keyboard so I can program it so to
type keyboard in fact there are people
researchers who has done that using
piano to type text so you can read this
this researcher uh she did research on
this using piano and I thought you know
piano is actually the best physical
input uh
device but now now I've seen this I've
seen this uh data hand SL board I think
actually this is the best as far as
input goes okay you know because when
you move up you know so you no longer on
a normal keyboard you move to the upper
row then you press or you move to the
bottom row then you press but on this
thing you just simply move up you don't
press anymore like you just move up so
it
simplifies uh these hand
motions okay let me go to the next point
I want to talk about uh if you have
questions ask okay so but but I need to
let me finish uh because we have a lot
of things to do