hello guys hello guys welcome to another
episode of South Park show today is 2019
November 21st Thursday
3 o clock 35 minutes San Francisco time
in the afternoon and we've got a lot of
things to talk about we are going to
play footsie and we got a lot of things
to talk about
good morning Emily just Emily here who
else we got six people okay
people say hi come up and so let's see
what is today's topic key Mouse okay
this page I need to fix oh maybe not
okay so let me show star talk show there
it is today's page and we are going to
talk about Kensington scratchy feel and
the Canisius foot pedals
I have there prepared to show you and
I'm going to show a bow on a foot
massage
foot foot see in the office okay I'm
going to show you guys how to play that
and and where to buy juggling ball
square to buy the stuff and so that that
is the today's topic and we might be
coding some eMac B's maybe yet near the
end then then that's it I was I was
thinking we're gonna do JavaScript but I
think that's enough for today
come on in pork mornings in way zoom way
out morning Kathy sorry you have sold me
on the Canisius advantage wait time to
put a dent in my wallet
yes indeed so buy from my website okay
if you are in USA or if you are buying
from buying from Amazon buy for my
website and okay so let's go into show
let me go to the my keyboard blog there
is quite a few things interests
yes when is that he's got okay so I'm
going to show you okay okay let's start
with the Kensington expert mouse well
it's not it's not actually a mouse it's
a trackball okay and there's more
interesting things okay so first of all
let me show you let's post the keyboard
blog so you guys can go by it
okay make the economy great again paste
I like the happy hacking keyboard who
doesn't
now if you are a hacker you have to have
a happy hacking keyboard okay otherwise
you don't qualify okay so okay so should
we start properly now stop this video
stop these there and ten people watching
which is great now I have to look at
myself do I look good okay I look I look
okay I'm okay I'm not too old yet oh God
next what is the next thing next thing
is discord okay if you guys have not
joined yet join well but party is not
here or not yet because I screwed up my
schedule and sow discord you can find
the discord link over okay just sorry
discord you'll find my discord he's on
my website he's on my youtube link to it
too
okay so we're not talking about the
Kinesis expert mouse I mean I'm not
kinases but the Kensington X expert
mouse now Emily who is right here and in
a chat and she's got this mouse and she
said this is her video she's got you
know hackers programming books now
listen listen to that
so Kensington Mouse is got this
well-known problem of the scratchy wheel
if you scratch if you rotate it that's
that's that wheel is like a functions
like a scroll wheel and it makes this
hideous noise you own that as well so
can you guys hear it let me see if I can
turn up the volume or something
can you guys hear
lovely books can you guys hear it or not
okay yeah okay so this is no good
wait headphones there
now I've been listening to that all this
morning okay let me turn back my
headphones are GTECH headset okay I've
been this listening to the hypothesis
does this money so this is a known
problem and if if you go online there
are some nerds you know who tries to fix
this they open it up and I don't
remember what's the problem but it's a
bad design you know there's there's
something inside that makes that no it's
so bad so you know because of this and I
don't want to buy this this one because
because that is really annoying that
when you do that why have you been
listening to it so much it's just
filling in the background that's all
this it's it's it's a me exaggerating
you know so so there is there it is the
Kensington and it doesn't look like it's
well peeled so when you when you buy
this device look look at the look at the
corner okay wait hold on a second it
doesn't look like it's well peeled right
look at look here you know so it doesn't
look like it's way opiod so when you
when you bought this was it after
careful consideration or he just happens
to buy it so anyway I don't think so you
know I wouldn't know not this one
you know I would pick something else so
yesterday we were talking about
trackballs for like 40 minutes in my in
the stream so so there it is that okay
and she Emily is talking playing footsie
with Jack Bosch so she is going to she
is using this trackball in her office
and and put it on the floor and you know
mess with it and see she doesn't she
didn't she she didn't actually show a
photo of her feet on this thing but but
she said she well she was she is doing
this oh look someone else has this
footrest and I'm going to show you saw
system okay so what what else comments
comments lovely books I used to have a
CST I'll track yes that's a that is a
well-known trackball one of the highest
quality trackball so let me show you
okay so did I hide my windows no okay so
let me position it correctly so so you
guys can see it so the so we are talking
about this one
the L track and I have some of my
friends who bought it this one
unfortunately they they they the
business shut down about few months ago
because the guy you know apparently so
thanks to George who always give us
interesting informations so George
posted some information about this this
L track with basically apparently the
company shut down because the owner is
getting old is he's retiring so and they
sold it to another company so apparently
this trackball will still be going we
all have to wait and see you know until
the new company makes name of it so this
is this is rather high you know one of
the highest quality trackball but you
know I read all the reviews I have not I
have never actually touched it because
this is you buy it online usually it's
not through via retail you can so you
can I cannot go to the you know the
price electronics and try it they don't
they don't have it so this one
I never touched it but for my reviews
you know I read all the reviews I
wouldn't get it because well it's high
quality and many people like it but a
design you see they got this squawk
wheel on top which is kind of a awkward
position you know a lot of people
complain about that and also that is a
middle button so the design is kind of
not that good okay you know the what's
the best design for trackball let me
show you the the best design for trap oh
it would be something like this okay
this this this Kensington slim blade
okay but again like I mentioned
yesterday this one's doesn't have a
wheel so if you want to rot if you want
to scroll up and down you have to rotate
it like that which is not good okay it's
not good you you want physical devices
like like like I'm going to show you you
know what what you want is like you know
like knobs in wheels you want a whole
bunch of knobs in wheels like in the
cockpit cockpit of some airplane you
know you know or they're not saying we
also because that way you establish
muscle memory you know that that is
natural like in in nature you don't have
you don't have like virtual keys or
virtual trees or virtual you know you
you you touch this tree then you have to
touch that tree then you touch this tree
then it does something yeah that doesn't
exist you want physical things you touch
you don't want touch screens okay
and Navy there's an article about this
Navy who who has who had an accident you
know some because because the user
interface interface them up they
ran into you know another ship cargo
ship train ran into the the the
destroyer how do they call that the
ships you know the worship there are
several types I cannot remember the
names of anything when I'm talking but
anyway I have Arco is somewhere here so
well should I show it or not no sure
so okay so Navy okay so go to keyboard
blog and Navy okay the Navy touchscreen
there it is this is a warship this this
one is what's a specific type of the
warship I didn't say destroy you
yeah so it's a destroyer destroyer means
it any kind of where anyway it's a
destroyer okay so it is a big hole and I
think four people died in the ship for
four sailors died because some merchant
commercial cargo ship learned into it
why because this warship is TV deviated
from it the plant route you know it big
and it's too late to change then then
then a cargo ship put a dent on it so
and you know they were using because why
because one they found out so they were
using this touchscreen you know the
modern touch swing thank you touchscreen
that is why okay so well that's part of
the reason they are using this modern
touchscreen that that factor things up
so after study they did they want this
old old-fashioned style
everything is physical you you know
knobs in wheels that's what you want and
in the same way it is actually good in
the same way you want
you are not knobs in wheels okay for
your keyboard or for your mouse let me
go here okay let me show you yeah you
want you know you want trackball you
want keyboard keys you want you want
this you know knobs and wheels lots of
it this device is new on Amazon you can
buy this is designed for Photoshop users
so one hand you look at look at this car
one hand for drawing
I possess this too you know I possess I
possess things so one hand is gonna be
for drawing you draw you draw dududududu
and the other hand is trysting and
tricking and pushing and rolling you
know means like that and next stop next
stop let's let's show this to the
footsie footsie 101 let me see the
comments okay so it's not at first
though not at first foot dexterity zoom
words where are you from again zoom welt
I forgot
I lost it when moving and I will never
forget it because soon after I realized
they shut down okay how long I've been
talking I have to adjust my timing eight
people not many today okay so go
back here so three buttons on UNIX
okay so let's show the foot see okay so
I have cut Kinesis pedo
first of all if you just bring it up
this okay this one very good point in a
user interface let's go back here so
there you have it you can see it let me
show you okay so that that this is the
Kinesis okay II did you know now now I
have programmed the keys I mean I have
programmed the pedal so so this one on
the right is for switch to last app or
window so you can see I press it you see
let me show you okay so what's a good
angle anyway so so the right one is this
one you can this this one okay so I
press it it will switch to the last
window okay
and so that is the right one this is the
right ones and the left one the left one
is for its for I forgot it's for but the
middle one is full screen wait is it
full screen or not I forgot you know
yeah full screen there it is you see
this middle one is full screen so there
it is Kinesis elite what is is savant
elight to Kinesis cooperation so you go
you guys go there and buy it okay so on
the back yes so let me show you this on
the back they have they have these
schools okay let me show you weird
net there so the you know each foot
pedal you have a school that's cool we
are tightened or loosened the pressure I
mean how much so you is adjustable you
can adjust resistance how much you have
to you know the the resistance of the of
the thing yeah okay
so thank you so let me press this one so
you can see so it's it's just like three
pedals attached to a metal plate okay
it's three pedals attached to a metal
metal plate basically scoot scoot up
scoot on to the metal plate and then
they so you can see the wires coming out
then they connect to the middle to the
center then so you can program them and
I don't I forgot how it is program I
don't you see because I don't actually
use foot pedal much so it did
let's see what it does okay so let's put
it back so what is you know because I
don't use it so I forgot what the keys I
programmed so the left one the left one
is switched to last app okay for example
now I'm Emacs press it yeah
so switch to last half now the middle
one is okay it's a max screen so middle
one is max screen so you can see toggle
max screen and what is the right one
oh the right one is reload I didn't
want to reload right one is reload
browser okay okay so reload browser yeah
so so okay so so let's go back let me
show you the footsie thing so copy that
close that show that okay close the
keyboard and paste that okay okay
so that looks really satisfying to click
its program with an app on Windows or
Mac ok so yeah let me show you hold on a
second let me show you where you cannot
well i'm bare feet okay so you know
because well i had i don't wear socks I
don't like to wear socks so this is kind
of okay Matt you know this is okay yeah
I wasn't sure whether I should show it
that's my trashcan that's my this very
old PC it's all dust you know actually I
did some cleanup here so this this one I
don't want to show my feet too much so
that one is too named guy like stamp its
template stamp it that one is switched
to last window and this one is max
maximized okay maximized you know it's
actually doing command ctrl F on the Mac
and I don't think it's working in this
app you know so that's another thing
annoying big because when your app
doesn't have the same doesn't have the
same shortcuts so that is annoying then
this one is anyway so I have this poor
let me show you this boy this boy is
fascinating now I need to turn on
torchlight to demonstrate this properly
so I have this ball this boy is a
juggling ball in fact I have quite a few
of them there so let's draw them over
show them over now you can do foot
juggling with this with this this this
pause now push that aside this is heavy
actually you have to
you know it's it's solid it's got rubber
feet feet so it won't move then so there
it is the the boss I'm going to so that
that that is the footsie game so this is
actually great so this is a solid port
port okay it's a it's a it's a you know
I
someone threw it away my neighbor's so
and you you have this pole here and when
you see it you just put your feet there
so it can function like a massage you
know you put both your feet there and
like a massage you know so I guess
that's that's about that takes some
trouble to show that and they come with
giant key caps
I was kind of thinking buying some kind
of oh yeah so about the about the I need
to now I need to sit back properly and
you see I don't you see I have a small
body frame so I have a small body frame
so I usually I usually sit up with my
legs on the chair like that so that is
why I do not often use the foot pedals
you know I find it now because I need to
hop around all the time so let's go back
to
the
Oh because I thought I'd quit by mistake
he might still alive chick okay I must
see your life but why is okay so okay I
need to stop I need to show my screen
okay I should be showing you my screen
oh this party's dead
okay so close that let me open that's
why I don't see the comments and okay so
about the food petals so what what is
the software I forgot so let's go to my
keyboard page to see yeah let's go to
the Canisius footbed oh I have it
somewhere here there it is so they have
a version that's just two petals and a
version with three you know usually
these kind of thing they sell such that
they are very very expensive they differ
by just $10 so if you're gonna buy one
you might as well get the three three
pedals one okay but the Canisius one is
very expensive I mean it's way expensive
you can go check out our Amazon so on
this page I didn't actually do a pop-up
review because I wrote this page before
I got it well they send me a copy you
know they send me a copy so I can review
it for them I did I did you know so I
actually never did because I actually
never used it much so today is some kind
of some sort of review so it's very well
built but what is the software use you
use to program it I forgot and then you
have this kind of thing wait let me
focus okay what is the software
I forgot you you have to you know just
go to their website Canisius food fellow
you'll find it and they have food
description they also have manuals you
can download so I forgot what is the
software so that is that is that you
know about the food thing you know when
you row a bow on it what so what do you
want is you want a one second
so you want a let me show you so the bow
I'm using is this juggling boss okay I
had them for like four five six seven
years now so it doesn't look pretty it
looks kind of how do you it looks kind
of nasty you know because it's it it age
with you you know the color goes become
strapped before it's all shiny like neon
neon color but now it's very dirty and
and so let me show you juggling okay I
haven't been choked a heaven showgirl
for like ten years
so Amy
Oh God muted ha
I've been muted under my video how long
have I been muted impossible this must
be done' go I must be talking muted for
like 10 minutes or 20 minutes oh my god
this is so bad
taco timestamps mute 4:05 p.m. so I've
been talking seven minutes muted it's so
bad now I don't know what to do now yeah
it's really bad so seven minutes I don't
remember
oh god this is so bad
ten minutes okay so I don't remember
what I talked about 10 minutes before
okay let me just repeat something
important on foot pedal so foot fellow
so let me write it down okay foot pedal
let me write down some people like to
press them use them as a control by
default like you you hold this pedal for
control or odd things like that so if
you are Emacs user you can press down
for control and you press keys with your
hand on keyboard I don't like that okay
I prefer I prefer single key okay we I
prefer single you know make the pedals
to single key so you for example like
what I've done one pedal is for last
application last window the other ones
toggle fullscreen things like that oh
you can do you can have them zoom in
zoom out refresh browser something like
that you know make them single key
functions I don't like I do not
recommend using them as modifiers so
that's one thing
that's one thing okay foot pedal using
us modifiers no recommend using us
modifiers I recommend using them a
single function keys such as Targo max
screen switch to last app back next
window tab workspace things like that
okay that's that's that's one thing one
point the other point is I read from a
story some Gemma
he bought a foot pedal and he used it to
push to talk in cami so he he he stamp
on a fellow and he can talk and one day
he's driving and he's talking to his mom
so he pushed to talk and the result is
not too good so if you get foot pedal
beware of that okay you want you don't
want to get confused
the story of a gamer who used foot pedal
as p de l da l as push-to-talk one day
he is driving and and and pushed to talk
to his mom okay that's the thing and
about the software is it Windows or Mac
I forgot so you just go to their website
and you can see it's Windows or Mac I
mean yeah check their website I don't
remember I don't I don't have the
information here and also on this page I
wrote this page before I actually have
it so on this page my information is not
too good okay I I don't know so I'm
going to update it today a little bit
so they sent me this one Kinesis they
send it to me so you know I because I
don't use it so that's why I haven't
done review but today is some sort of
review so that's the some of the
important things so what did I talk
about that you guys all missed that's so
bad what I don't know what am i
doing so so we did show Kinesis photos
we did Emily footsie okay so and we show
pour on the board so we I was I was
talking about the juggling balls okay
the juggling balls the one I have are
the others so Sasha
okay so Sasha is she has peeled a she
has a blog about creating a USB foot
pedal yourself so you can read her blog
and see how to do it
the Canisius one is kind of very
expensive very expensive and okay yeah
so that's about that
so did I talk about this when I was
muted so I was saying you know there is
a ship this is a u.s. Navy warship and a
merchant ship ran into them
okay so and so why because of the oh the
touchscreen GUI that's bad so what you
want is the classic you know knobs and
wheels that's what you want you know so
the Navy decided they are going to
switch to all command centers into you
know from the GUI
back to the knobs and wheels that's
that's what you want and and yeah that
so I think that's it for today yeah it's
so bad I talking for 10 minutes without
audio so anyway so anything else any
questions questions and comments okay
questions about the foot pedal or
something else and maybe that's it for
today let's see I've been talking night
people 40 minutes and we do Emacs
tomorrow or next state so wait so this
let's see what the keys let's press the
foot pedal let's see I need to turn on
event viewer so let's see what my foot
fell oh so right foot is refresh browser
okay so right foot refresh browser
that's right then middle is left ctrl F
right UI yeah so middle is toggle max
window okay and the left is last app
switch to last lap anything else any
questions can you program different
functions if you press the two pedals at
once oh that's interesting I don't I
don't know I haven't I
I've you know because I had this I
haven't really used it
you know maybe for one hour that's it so
I don't remember and I don't remember I
don't even remember what software is
used
I mean what's their software to do it so
you know just go to their website they
have manuals and full information and I
think I'm going to update this page my
review of it so so you get that
information yeah okay that that that
that that's it for today I mean I guess
that two minutes three minutes five
minutes Cole keys and mouse yeah
anything else otherwise no comments or
we shut down in in one minute
any comments
oh but but we missed you so I looked all
day long for your schedule and now you
scream right after I stopped looking no
it's you know I just don't have a good
schedule and but that's it I think
that's it core keyboard
what about Cokie ward yeah that cookie
board you know code keyboard so you have
this you know this is a famous you know
so-called mother of all demos this guy
who who kind I think he's the first he
invented the mouse and so this is back
in 1950s or 1960s Engelbert his name is
Engelbert and he died I think five years
ago and and in the beginning he came up
with the code keyboard idea and we do
have several Cole keyboard you know like
I mentioned yesterday we do have stay no
piano texts Mitchell or my color-coded
keyboard okay but we also have things
like that the pad keyboard and if you
look at so here is the cheat sheet for
the bad keyboard so it you know it will
take a lot of time to learn so basic my
opinion about coded keyboard is that if
you have that okay I don't like it okay
don't do this by the way I don't you
know it's not hard I don't think it's
very difficult I talked about this
yesterday I don't think it's it it may
in fact be easier to learn then touch
typing to achieve the same speed okay
that's my point
so what I'm saying is that in fact if
you can't
number of hours spent to achieve let's
say 80 watt per minute the court
keyboard may be easier any any one of
these you know chord or piano or steno
may be in fact easier because I talked
about it yesterday so anyway about code
keyboard you want you want proper
properly designed physical keyboard such
as any one of these okay you don't want
the you know you don't want to use the
computer keyboard keys for that that's
that's that's actually not good
and also there's another device called
what's the name do you guys remember I
don't have a picture I think I have it
somewhere but I don't remember what's
the name so you so it's very expensive
so it's a it's a keyboard it's got holes
for your fingered fingers to thinking
then it for each finger it got like four
kind of keys on each side
so you stuck your finger in and you push
it up down and left right
that's how you create input with that
device it's not good I mean it's it's
one it's one of the rare device anyway
that's it I think that's it bye guys
data hand that's right Dana Han hello
hello knobby young theta and let's look
at that data hand I need I need pictures
okay let's just see look at that
Wikipedia
you know usually they don't have you
know I want to see your art pictures
okay so
there we have it lots of pictures so
yeah it looks like that I don't think
this is good device you see the way you
use it you know you sync your finger in
there you got it
it got four things its first of all it's
not economic because I don't think your
finger is designed to nudge the fan
right like that and it's overly complex
you know I don't it's a it's not a good
design so rather you go with any of
these piano you know you go with this
any piano key design or the steno design
it's better than this
okay let's see okay my guys
check okay good