good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show today's today
is August 1st oh wow
August August 1st 2019 6 o'clock and six
minutes in the afternoon San Francisco
time and actually I'm going to I'm not
ready yet so I'll be back in let's say
five minutes five minutes
oh okay five minutes I'll be back
yourself be right back in five minutes
okay let's type it be right back in five
minutes
start at 6:15 okay sorry about that yeah
so you know nothing wrong with that
yes
hello guys welcome back welcome back
welcome yourself back so today's topic
is random I don't have a fixed topic at
Mon time so today's topic is random okay
so so guys what should we talk about you
know usually you know this math you know
there's a lot of things like usually
when I don't have a topic like I just
clicked some way on my website and I
started to talk about that and usually
it's going to be half an hour or more
like usually just you know gonna take
the whole hour so you know this is math
so we can you know I we can talk about
math I can teach you a little bit you
know something about math interesting
stuff you know not the typical you know
calculus you know you're learning in
colleges but these are serious you know
mathematics you know interesting things
math the shape of space that's very
interesting geometry you know is a shape
of space and I can talk about you know
random stuff you know these magic
polyhedrons and by the way it's okay
okay so this one is a virtual what you
can you know it's a software you can go
there it's written in JavaScript and you
can you know it's I love these kind of
puzzles let me adjust the window okay
this is too big and this is not good
okay so of those you here type okay if
you like to see Emacs lists you know
programming languages you know just you
know let me know because I usually my
topics are good morning guys my topics
are usually
okay math is one of the topic math
programming programming languages or
live coding you know I can do like
coding typically Emacs Lisp JavaScript
or : okay you know it seems Python is
very popular a lot of people ask me if I
want to do Python but you know I haven't
coded Python in the past few months so
you know is usually in order to do a
live coding you know you have to kind of
you know warm up if you haven't coded
the language for a few months that's not
good so yeah so math programming and
live coding eMac beats JavaScript PI you
know ghola and usually and also I can
talk about programming languages
programming language design oh my god
that's like that's a huge topic
you know that's mountain a mountain in
the sea of topics you get to see the
mountain and heels in the programming
language designs you know I have because
usually I have quite a lot esoteric
things you know these are usually these
are not the things you see online like
you know like if you go to if you are a
programmer you must be familiar with
hacker news or Stack Overflow those
questions you know they they don't you
know like you could say it's mainstream
but it's there's a lot of things
interesting that the other nando's some
for some reason they just you know these
topics you know they don't come up
semantic noodle you know syntax soup on
least oh yeah
the other day I was trying to show you
this picture okay I'm gonna read the
comments in answer them so the other day
I was going to show you this picture
which I you know didn't find you know
this is a
by byte magazine bad magazine this is
1979 this is very funny and byte
magazines 1979 Lisp you know their cover
is Lisp with this monolithic slab and
with Lisp code on it and you know you
know what this refers to anyone you guys
know what this refer to like type it
okay I'm gonna tell you what it refers
to you know in a minute like type it so
this you know language design issues you
know I haven't written a compiler myself
I haven't created language maybe
possibly down the road I hope to but
still you know there are many
interesting for me language design
issues in fact I don't think there is
actually a book that teach that that
that talks about programming language
design you know all aspects of
programming language design there is now
there is one you know by the scheme
racket group code and you know you guys
it's very famous you guys know that type
it okay type it then I have to you know
then I know you know like yeah there is
a book about programming language design
but I looked into it a little bit you
know I don't think that's the book so
there is actually no book that covers
comprehensively what are the or what are
all the issues about programming
language design okay there is I don't
think there is one by the way
Donald Knuth in his other programming
series of books okay I guess I need to
show it r programming okay Donald Knuth
most of you know you know he's
and you know this is supposed to be
ambitious project out of programming
what the heck is that other programming
so it's supposed to be like eight
volumes on AI but it turns out and what
what the [ __ ] is this wait how is this
now I'm out DuckDuckGo how is it
possible we start to show maps where did
I click that's interesting okay so
anyway this open a new window other
programming okay so Donald knows he you
know he wrote these series books
supposed to be eight volumes also but
right now it's only four volumes are
published
I thought he can finish it you know he
is going to I mean he's like 80 years or
something like that but you know but one
of the volume like I think Miriam eight
is supposed to be programming language
design you know so anyway yeah so I
don't think there is a book for
programming language design but however
there is one let me mention that
amazon.com but I don't think that's
actually that that's kind of you know
half of it is for beginning you know it
serves as a textbook for programmers for
beginning programmers so what is that
book okay so I know how to find it you
can find it by first find the book the
okay sicp okay sicp structure and
interpretation of of computer programs
this is a great book I read this book in
1998 or 1999 and this book is online
free by the way
yeah okay this has just starts to talk
about things sick and that book has four
chapters the you know it's known as the
wizard book it has four chapters I read
three chapters of it the last chapter I
didn't read and this is back in 1998 or
1999 so and this is this is free online
it uses scheme lists to teach you some
principles about how to write programs
okay so so there is that book and but
that there is another one you see we are
talking about a book that talks about
programming language design designer
programming languages so in order to
find that book I just use the related
Bing
okay here I which one is it
I think it's
I think that's that's that's this one
concepts techniques and models of
computer programming no it's not this
one does anyone know what what's that
book
okay so let's read the comments just to
say hello I watch the relay tomorrow
okay good night
info Matic high date Dec ways Hajduk
ways haven't seen you for a while what's
a good alternative to Python that's an
easy question now the common popular
answer to that is Ruby Ruby is a
alternative to Python okay
now Ruby Python and Perl they are kind
of in the same class so I have a
tutorial for each Ruby Python and Perl
okay i coded Perl from 98 1998 to 2002
every day eight hours a day you know so
but but my perche Dory oh I only started
to write it like five years ago
seriously
oh okay so well I it's complicated story
actually I started this Perl tutorial in
2005 but back then it was Perl and
Python together like on each page for
example how to do a loop then I have a
page you know on loop then you know half
of the half of the pages Perl the other
half is Python but a few years ago I
started about five years ago I started
to separate them because because you
know in general people are not
interested you know when you have
comparative study of Perl Python you
know like that your main audience will
be you know those who are interested in
programming languages now this group of
people is very very few okay for each
such person interested in programming
languages they are 1,000
for crimeless okay so in general people
you know those who wants to study Python
they just want to study Python they
don't care about you know Perl whatever
they are not interested in comparative
study of foreign language design you
know vast majority of people they just
interested in you know how to find a job
you know make money and so back then my
tutorial was you know probably and
Python side by side then I separated so
I got a pro tutorial Ruby Python : okay
Python Ruby pearl this three are
considered in the like almost the same
thing like me in the same class they
have the same they are you know they are
designed basically for the same kind of
the task and same speed same speeds as
you know you know almost the same okay
per Python Ruby I I never actually coded
Ruby but I spent like two months to
study Ruby because I was planning you
know I was planning to to use Ruby as my
main programming language you know I
started in Perl right for four years
back in 2000 yeah you know 1998 then I
got tired of Perl you know that get back
like there's more than one way to do it
just idiotic you know the code Perl
Larry walk okay I'm gonna show you you
know I have Larry was signed signed one
of my book Larry Warren codes laziness /
Larry Ward
you know these are this is written in
2002 there are several essays about you
know if you are interested in history
now this is like 20 years ago
his history is such that when you live
at the time you know the situation like
you you have the feeling you know the
environment you know how everyone is
talking about something you know there's
a main tab
you know there's a word for that
zeitgeist you know describing the
thinking of the time but as long as time
goes on if you don't live in that
community in that period you read
history book this kind of mindset thing
is lost but instead so what you have
instead is mostly like statistics Oh
power was invented at this year then you
know this that you know you don't get
the you know the the the sense of the
what's going on in a situation so but if
but they are books that that that you
can learn from for example great novels
are typically of that example you can
you can you know dive into let's let's
say 200 years ago from reading a great
novel war and peace and you know things
like that you can get into the mindset
of the you know particular region what
they are thinking what they do every day
so if you are interested in that so you
can read you know this is pearl 2002 the
and in this one Larry Warren Coates
this is returning year 2000 you get to
realize you know what
you know like indirectly from my
tutorial you know I mean from my essay
you know I was I'm ranting about certain
things but indirectly when you read this
essay you can see oh so you know people
are thinking like that you know you can
get those kind of things so I was saying
you know so I program pearl for four
years in 1998 to 2002 you know
professionally then after that of course
I do my own scripts but but but then
around 2005 I learned Python okay
because I wanted to you know I'm tired
of the Perl
let me show you the I'm tired of the
pearl coat you know that it's like the
UNIX philosophy code like there's more
than one way to do it and you know lots
of those silly quotes you know the power
people and Larry woe is found of
now they make it they make tons of a
city you know this this this studio
science this code like snake or your
things the most famous is being you know
that they are more than one way to do it
yeah I'm trying to show you the picture
actually I mean because I have let me
find it okay theory and practice back to
Pearl okay so let's see there it is you
know this is this picture is taken in 19
2001 oh yeah okay yeah this photo is
taken 2001 in San Jose Larry was signed
it you know I went there to to the Linux
conference in Linux Expo 2000 what you
know back then wait that's that's when
the open source is thriving you know
like anyway so I so you know I'm tired
of Pro that's why I began to study
Python I want Python to be my main
language like you don't want Pro anymore
then after five years after 10 years
it's a mistake okay it's a mistake title
is a Scottie or spell okay Python you
know how do you describe Python
community Python people in one sentence
you know so the way you describe it okay
it is this Python people they like to
think let me write it out because it's
more fun okay here's what Python think
people thinks comp
comp comp sigh ah [ __ ] okay that's what
Python people thinks this are should be
reversed are you know that's Russian
alphabet savile ik unicode let's see so
we go to único let's find the Russian
alphabet
okay so comments up hiding
I need to read them because otherwise
they let me read it
you know just in a minute so Cyrillic so
in Cyrillic which is the Russian
alphabet you have these are reversed are
okay so this is what in one sentence
this is what Python think python people
think of themselves
pythons you know Python people they may
think that oh this is the only way
Python you know it's a mistake
you know Python is different from Pearl
culturally you know pearl is is kind of
inherited from this UNIX philosophy like
they are they are all about slants you
know jargons slogans pearl mongers you
know you know probably public you know
the state of the onion those kind of a
crap you know that you know this is this
this this idiots pearl you know they
love that you know there's more than one
way to do it
only laziness is the great virtual
programmers you know the link you know
the three virtues of programmers at
least laziness something something and
you have to you know today you don't
hear that anymore but you have to
understand back then
almost every programmer you know online
they they have signatures or coding that
like like they deeply believe in that
like again like every everyday you're
here oh but you know if you are
discussing some programming issues then
someone will pop up say oh this is
should be this way because lazy
laziness is a great virtual programmers
the [ __ ] is computer [ __ ] you know
the the UNIX philosophy is beginning of
this the beginning of that name for
people is like like they inherited they
are kind of the same type of people you
know the probe coat then Python came
along so Python is supposed to be you
know the guy to van rossum okay
so poor people they are sloppy you know
the yeah
you know they are not bad people okay
you know this is just their culture you
know they are like
you know these sloppy things you know
and thinking and they think they are
doing great they think they are creating
art you know remember you know for
example you have the canoe license you
know GPL you have you know MIT license
you have apache license and you know
many others Perl has its own license
it's called artistic license okay
artistic license you know the point is
that you see the Perl people the
community they like this kind of you
know you might say wordplay you know
they enjoy that okay name Python came
along now Python is very kind of in
sharp contrast with Perl people Python
people they think they are you know it's
it's mostly because of the Kaido van
rossum you know in general a programming
languages community what they are like
mostly depends on came from the Creator
you know whoever created language he you
know he get followers basically the
community becomes you know a broader
view of his personality okay it's kind
of like that so that's why you know
Larry was you know you know that you
have the pearl Larry war community then
Python keidel van rossum I did a video
like three months ago two months ago
that I talked about Godot van Rossum
he's personality he's he's this kind of
passive-aggressive guy okay he doesn't
you know not like Larry war you know who
just freely you know what I call
happy-go-lucky okay this that's he's you
know those type of people they don't
care about nothing you know there's just
two things happy-go-lucky they don't
care about correctness oh yeah you know
like in Perot days you know another
quote very popular is is theory versus
practice there's a famous quote you know
one of the famous crap from the pro
people is he reverses pack
you know the way they say is that you
see Randall Schwartz you know very
famous guy you know he said you know
this this quote the difference between
theory and practice in theory is much
less than difference between theory and
practicing practice you know that's a
core very famous you know you see it
every other day okay and you know and so
so but if you look at that truly that's
that's that's the epitome of
pseudoscience you know that's the
epitome of pseudoscience it sounds it
sounds so true you know the difference
between theory and practice in theory is
much less than difference between theory
and practice in practice yeah this is
this these [ __ ]
you know they UNIX philosophy is one of
them they they like this they love this
you know they they they so Python is
very different community from Pro
because the guide around Rossum he's
kind of this passive aggressive he has
this mannerism you know he's kind of
passive aggressive type of person you
know and why he doesn't go around you
know tell you that that his idea is the
best oh you know things like that but
however he thinks that you know he think
that his idea he's his design is the
best he does but he doesn't say but
however he can stand me like he has a
need he has a obsession to express that
in a indirect way you can see that in
many of his essays you know like I have
essays about that like you can see as
you know so so two months ago I did a
video talking about Godot van Rossum so
he you know so he's passive-aggressive
and he think he's his design is the best
everything is no good
that is the Python community you know
that they you know empower community for
example if there is a mailing list of
online forum
per community is such that they will
come everyone you know they welcome
maybe everyone but Python community you
tend to have like this hierarchy and and
also they they they they constantly you
know they are active you know abandoned
rows you know it's somewhere they
considers a true they bad you know they
and they you know anyway that's the
Python community okay
and the language is it sucks okay the
the Python language is no good you know
I thought you know I'm moving from pro
to Python I thought you know I'm tired
of the Perl crap you know these autistic
or sloppy things I thought you know it
looks like the Python suits me you know
Python is like okay try to do it one way
you know this just what one way to do it
you know but python is no good Python
the language you know the many details
okay my roommates back so let me close
the door and let me talk about then you
know let me talk about Ruby so Python
Perl Ruby they are you know same type of
languages let me invite to talk about
Ruby then let me tell you actually colon
is the best language to learn today as a
alternative to Python okay so let me
close the door
okay so I should read the comments
because it's piling up keep the comments
coming guys
so thick ways says I wonder so what's
the alternative good alternative to
Python okay you can do Ruby now Ruby is
popular because beginning in 2008 also
because of the Ruby on Rails but today
for some reason
Ruby kind of fell to the side you know
by the way Ruby Python Perl among these
three languages Ruby is the best by far
Ruby is simpler semantically simpler
than Python or Perl the model of the
Ruby language or gates it's simpler
the syntax of Ruby is also simpler it's
easier to learn than Perl Python okay
and okay so it's simpler easier to learn
the documentation is is much better than
Python or Perl okay Ruby and the
language design of Ruby is also better
than Python or Perl okay so Ruby is the
best Ruby came Ruby's invented by this
Japanese guy
Noah's madman ma TZ okay he's known as
ma tizzy now in Japan Japanese you know
Japanese names they they are like
Chinese names you have first name you
know you have first name and last name
but but the last name comes first so for
example my name is Sally Lee's my family
name but in Chinese you would say leaks
are always and usually when you meet
people you you never say their first
name you always address the person by
the family name you know that's the part
of the culture anyway so then but the so
so in Japan especially in Japan you know
you don't you never address someone by
their first name that's that's rude
okay so so he's a Japanese guy but but
but in America in European countries you
always address you know the person by
first name usually so this is like so
this is situation you see because if you
address him by his first name
I mean even he knows you are not
Japanese but it's kind of you know when
it's written and you know it's kind of
odd you know so so he goes by you know
just by Matt's you you know that's how
Westerners call him so anyway he so he's
a Japanese guy he created Ruby Ruby the
language is based on two languages it's
based on Lisp and Perl okay it's based
on pearl and least these two almost
that's all so it's very good so Ruby is
much more elegant it's simpler easier to
learn same speed as Python Perl they are
the same speed it's better designed it's
better documentation okay Ruby came to
fame because of the Ruby on Rails this
this guy american guy who invented you
know he created Ruby on Rails so he
become very popular
that guy's a scumbag okay he's a bad
person what's his name who who's the guy
who invented Ruby on Rails you know that
guys has come back anyway
so do we become very popular but however
if is today it's not you know seems to
fail you know it's you don't you know
it's you you know use everywhere
especially in startups for web dev but
you don't hear you know it as much
Python on the other hand is like
everywhere because Google you know
because Google create created this
machine learning stuff and Google Python
is Google's language so so intern Python
becomes you know very popular and
associated with machine learning
so that's a situation but you know I'm
going to tell you that : is better than
them okay Golan Golan you know I love
Golan I learned going on about a year or
two ago I seriously started to you know
code goal and you know actually I'm
going to show you : you know some code
and stuff maybe today so Golan is great
you know I wrote this great tutorial
okay you should check out check out my
tutorial my tutorials are different from
others because my tutorial I try okay
the style is that is a math perspective
okay when you hear that you you might
think oh no I don't want I don't want
math you know style tutorial that I
wouldn't understand that's not not like
that I read my tutorial seeing a math
style so what does it mean it means you
know you might think of math jargon so
not no nothing like that it just means I
treat the language as a as simple as
possible you know each each idea is
independent as possible from others and
each idea with lots of examples so so
you know I'm telling you what it is you
know exactly this this this and once you
read them you can understand how they
connect how they relate to each other so
that is my style of tutorial you know I
you know usually I say math oriented
math style but usually that's not a good
phrase for marketing because when people
hear math style oh no I don't want mad
you know that's seedy but yeah so anyway
so okay lots of comments let me read
them yeah so I recommend Golan because
coline is is like six times faster than
any of Ruby Python Perl and it's it's
simpler it's actually even simpler than
Ruby okay the language model is simpler
than
even Ruby six times faster great
documentation okay the greatest
documentation industry I've read
thousands of you know man pages Apache
dog you know III read covered I tend to
read them like cover to cover
I read you know I read entirety of proto
completions in fact in fact Perl Kasab
Perl book survey ok I read you know
backing there are seven books I'd read
them all every every every page every
word okay so this is around 2000 year
1999 okay there are these pearl books
you know advanced programming effective
Perl pearl cookbook and pearl this is
Valerie war and the Pearl man pages I
read them you know oh and I read you
know most of the main pages and you know
I read entirety of PHP documentation
okay
I read the entirety of Mathematica
documentation that's a book this thick
okay you know this this thick it's a
doorstop you know that I read it like
three times from separate years
Mathematica you know a PHP entire PHP
documentation almost every crucial essay
by the way which heck guy yeah that
there are only like ten of them you know
the rich hickies that's you know then
then Ruby talk I haven't so I only have
encoded Ruby I only tried you know to
learn it for two months and the result
is my tutorial it's not complete
you know it's just simple introduction
for beginners that's what it's good for
so I don't know Ruby that much I don't
know Ruby well so back then you around
to around 2012 that's why
2012 yeah that's when I started to learn
Ruby I was thinking you know so I'm
moving away from pearl and I'm moving
away from Python I'm thinking Ruby will
be my main language that didn't happen
but today that didn't happen you know
for reasons you know I started to do
things but today : would be is my kind
of my main language for industrial
purposes : okay
so Ruby pearl so we're talking about
documentation Ruby's : is great
documentation the most important thing
about : is that why is so good because
besides all these you know good
documentation good language simple to
learn fast you know as five times six
times faster than Python Ruby pearl but
there's one thing more critical than oh
very important that is : is in the
industry standard you know standard is
one of the most popular language meaning
that if you learn :
you can find job everywhere now
for those of you interesting language
design you know many of you are
interested in closure ok I want to learn
culture or I want to learn Haskell you
know Haskell is this cool language you
know oh I want to learn scheme you know
at least racket you know this cool
language but there's a problem
serious problem you know these these
languages there's no no industry or the
option ok well yeah did you know you
could find a job you know once in a
while there's a job you know here there
Haskell closure you know but literally
speaking I mean practically speaking you
you will not find this know this very
little job opportunity okay so you want
to take that into consideration I mean
if you are such a guy you know you don't
worry about money you have you know you
have all the money you need then okay
you don't care about that then you just
pick language whatever you know is cool
or whatever but for most people you know
you you want to pick of language
that you like and you know it's nice and
also a very good thing is that it's you
know industrials you know it's it's very
popular
so today : Python Ruby you know they are
all actually they are oh okay so well
culture when you when it gets to closure
or camel has cow you you are getting
into the fringe okay you will not find a
job okay you be yeah you know because
for every job enclosure there will be
like ten thousands and chopped seen in
Golan or Python or Ruby okay that's the
situation
so I recommend : okay it's because it's
very popular
it's and also it's : is kind of a low
level it's like in between high-level
and low-level so when you learn :
you know : is designed to replace
tsipras first you know it's in that
class so it could you know so it's very
fast it's compiled or you can just run
it you know without cam polish
compilation like Python so I like you
know so that's that is why I like Golan
so much you know I know a lot of my
followers I know that they tend to a lot
people like to criticize Golan because
you you're see people criticize so : is
just this you know oh technology they
they don't you know they don't have this
or that features you know they come fin
you know you know yeah but you can
complain all you want you know go you
know go study Haskell go go study
Mathematica you know they you know the
the thing is that what's what's my point
anyway anyway yeah so anyway I highly
recommend : okay I you know yeah so okay
let me so that kind of finishes that
kind of so let me read the comments so
for now saying
so yeah alternative to Python : Ruby
is good choices so dick ways I wonder
because people always say it's good
language for he knows but I think it's
isn't a very good language you know D
yeah I don't like Python so what should
I recommend a friend of mine to start
learning well that depends you know you
see never programmed before you know
things like that you know if you I mean
:
I mean Python is still good you know
it's you know aside from my personal
opinions I mean going it just walks okay
it's like many of the programming
programming language debate you know we
each of us has you know very you know
strong opinions but in general you know
you know it's a tool you know you can
you know get on with it you know you
remember that we went to the moon back
in 1960s was in 1960 or 50s you know
this back then you know today your cell
phone has you know 16 you know eight
chigi bytes of memory back then it's
like 100 tip 8 bytes of memory you know
you don't have even calculators but you
got you went to the moon so what do you
do but does that mean people don't need
to compute no there's like tons of
computation you need to do calculus you
know differential geometry you know you
going to the moon you don't have
computers you have you know you know you
don't have like a memory you know one
kilobyte is it sits on the Space Shuttle
so so what people do people you know
people are very flexible we human
animals I mean we you know we we can
craft things know before technology we
craft you know lots of you know things
we you know as long as as long as
there's a need and as long as there's an
wheel
you know usually a need first a need to
something the wheel you then you can do
it you know you don't there's like
different you know the difference
between you know - Ruby it's like baby
small okay yeah so next let's read
comments in formatic go arrest go or
roast yeah so yeah a lot of people like
roast not for me because I don't like
languages that's you know very low level
and you know you know with memory stuff
I don't like
so yeah a lot of talks that's about
programming languages today let's see
how long I've been talking 15 minutes
okay so no cause something disp
so George Phillips says George George
Phillips erase says oh yeah so so we
were talking about this image this this
is a fantastic image let's see where is
it
did I just cut where is it
okay so let me show you that okay so let
me show you that so pro Python so so
long list so yeah so this cover right
magazine 19 1979 is in reference to the
movie 2001 you know that's a great
movies so no cause something list
what does I mean no cause something this
so Bethel la miel Bethel um UJS
greetings privet what does that refer to
so Z Tron crazy says privet what does I
mean methylome uses it can do methanol
muses it can do everything what Python
can but better first it can do more has
flexibility and is more clear in
implementation so you are talking about
: right okay I lost the context okay so
okay so hold on a second so yeah yeah
actually let me expand the window
magnify my I saw going I'm going blind
so so but what is something easy to
learn Ruby :
okay Ruby is very complicated so that
way says Ruby is very complicated it has
like ten ways to do the same thing and
the operators are very confusing you
could be right I mean I guess depends on
you know exactly what you mean I guess
you see one of the issue about flexible
programming languages
this would include yeah this is an
interesting issue okay this include
JavaScript Ruby JavaScript Ruby pearl
Mathematica okay let's say this for
these four languages their syntax is
such that you can you know like one
algorithm you can write it in so many
different ways okay
each one is totally different from the
other but actually they all means the
same thing you know they they all follow
the same algorithm Python not so much
right on you well you know but mostly
mostly JavaScript Ruby Mathematica
what's the other let's see yeah so so
Ruby pearl JavaScript Mathematica okay
let's say these four languages you know
to implement the same algorithm you can
write it in so many different ways and
it's very flexible one of the reason
they can do that is you know function is
a value so you can you can assign a
function to a variable you a function
can take your function can return a
function not just that but but other
syntactic of things you know
so you can write it in many ways and
it's very flexible powerful it's this is
great
Express ability for programmers you know
if you are a geek another hacker you are
keeping interesting languages you tend
to like these kind of languages on the
other hand Java is the opposite extreme
okay Java I guess see tsipras first also
count you know I don't know Cece purse
purse but anyway Java is the opposite
extreme extremely inflexible you know
basically they say template coding
everything is just you know looks that
you know just type template now this is
a very interesting issue going on here
because if you want a programming
language to be popular such that you
know used by Google by you know
Microsoft Facebook you know who in a
large team you know let's say hundred
people for a large project you know AI
or whatever large project when that in
that situation you tend to want a
language that's not very flexible you
don't want you know you don't want
things like you know pearl pose the
extreme you know on the right side so
Perl JavaScript Mathematica Ruby okay
and Poe is on the extreme side on the
other side is Java okay so when you want
when you have lots of programmers in a
big project you don't you tend not to
want you know the flexibility in in
writing the same code because then
everyone is different I mean even style
guide does cannot do it style guide
cannot enforce it because you have so
many ways to write the same thing so
that's a that's kind of that's that's an
interesting issue it's kind of like a
conflict you know on the other hand if
you your team use uses Java everyone's
code is the same like every other you
know every piece of code it looks like
the same now so in that's perspective so
so this is
interesting things so you know
cooperation when you have a large team
you want you don't want flexibility and
:
when colon is designed they specifically
also have that call you know : you know
they want to make it so that you cannot
just like write the same thing is in ten
different ways you are kind of fixed
into one way to write the same thing you
know and and that's they specifically
designed that you know this is part of
their core because when you have like a
flexible language you you have that kind
of problems you know everyone's code is
different you know it's so that's a
issue yeah so that's the interesting
issue
how about Pico Lisp I don't know if you
call this it's an old Lisp I suppose I
don't know why are you interested in
pickle is so methylome uses somehow the
cast somehow the chat swallowed part of
my messages I will repeat them you can
post links you can usually you're just
pop up and you know
okay Julie our land yeah I heard great
things about Judy our land so you know
I'm you know I'm thinking of learning
Julia possibly I don't know because
there are so many things I knew I want
to study you know in math you know proof
systems you know this I like but but
Julia Allen's got a problem okay which
is Judy Allen is not popular meaning
that it's like you know Haskell or
camera mathematical Crozier you know
yeah you can learn in this grade but
your opportunities in job market is
severely limited you know that's a you
know that's a thing to consider you know
that's one thing that's kind of the
thing I hated hate about you know the
situation like sometimes you have this
language great language but nobody use
it you know do you don't have you you
cannot use it to learn a living weeaboo
hold on a second so let's see
I would sabatham you says I agree with
what you said about communities around
programming language and its creators
okay we beauchamp all champloo says add
me to your test mode no no I think your
website and tutorials are great thank
you
but that's not enough well I haven't
well yeah yeah big you know so you you
have to say something more like more
powerful or if you are famous person
then that has weight to my readers but
yeah so so they David him Hanson DHH oh
yeah that's a guy so that's the guy who
created Ruby on Rails I think you know
he's okay first of all he's a [ __ ]
this is you
this is you know this is the consensus
okay universally agreed he's a [ __ ]
kind of a guy but besides that I think
he's a scumbag he's a human scum back
okay he's he's not a good person okay
with his respect through morality you
know I don't think he's a good person
he's a scumbag you know I criticize a
lot people you know programmers
computers you know we're non-programmers
reberty's larry war for example you know
some you know i criticized a lot people
Python it's kind of an awesome
Kaido you know the Python guy but I
don't have you know I think they are
good person yeah I mean they are fine
person you know guide Oh Larry war you
know yeah you know I just don't like
their their design their thoughts and
the way they talk you know criticize but
you know this is it's I don't think they
are bad person I think they are you know
good but this person for some
programmers I make a difference that
th-th guy the guy created you know Ruby
on Rails I think he's a scum okay not
not in a good way he sees a you know you
know hey you know I'm not a good person
you know and and also also the guy who
created MPM you know he's a scumbag the
MPM guy you know I read you know I
haven't really studied them in detail
but you know in the past years you know
they are news and incident incidents
happening you know in informing
communities you know you you see them
once in a while you know you see their
behaviors you see what they say you see
the kind of things they say their style
I think they are scumbags okay they they
they are not good person this dear you
know that this Ruby on where DHH guy and
that MPM the guy who created npm you
know the Java Script library guy on the
other hand
the not jaya sky the not J sky what's
his name
let's see dome he's a great guy okay
he's a great person great ethics quick
morality he said you know and he's and
he's a great note and he's also a
mathematician not jazz guy what's his
name
Ryan Dow okay yeah he's a mathematician
he's act you know true mathematician
actually lots of this program lots of
these programming language creators are
mathematicians Kaido van Rossum is a
mathematician you know but I don't like
his idea okay he's you know I mean even
I'm a mathematicians there are different
styles and different schools of thought
and different factions sometimes so bad
that just like programming community
they fight each other you know calling
each other's eyes out this you can see
in history you know there's lots of
stories not just verbally but actually
you know I want you to go you know I you
know I want you to get fired you know
things like that among mathematicians so
so guy know van Rossum is a
mathematician who else let's see
Mathematica Stefan Wolfram he's a you
know he's a certified genius he won my
author award when he youngest guy to one
to one that a word and he had PhD since
he was 15 or something he publishes you
know physicist
his physics in physics research journals
where when he is a team you know that's
Stefan Wolfram he created Mathematica
richest tome and he's not
Oh Richard Stallman actually I think he
I think he's a drop out if I recall
correctly college you
the dropout and he is he also has a math
background yeah I think yeah I'm pretty
sure
he was studying some math something
let's see PHP the guy who invented PHP
is a ting ting boy you know he was just
making a pretty homepage script written
in Perl and that so happens PHP became
popular we are they are quite a few you
know they are mathematicians so that's
about it today let me finish reading the
comments so George Philip okay and
Bethlem you say is thh extracted Ruby on
Rails from his work on the project
management tool base camp at the web
application company also called base
camp apparently this guy made Ruby on
Rails yeah I don't know his background
detail so George Phillips George
Phillips says I think that magazine was
talking about no colas oh this path
despite magazine is talking about no
colas oh I see ah let's see
SiC you frog define how do you know it's
know called Lisp okay so that's
interesting
yeah I I don't know I couldn't tell ya
so this is 1979 so yeah so put into that
time frame that may be that yeah that's
that maybe that's it so what
Oh
privet is Russian for high that's
Russian right sing - oh good morning sin
- so bathroom immune says basically I
think Julia is way better than Python in
every way yeah III think I agree even
like actually I don't know Julia
actually yet so Ruby Python are very
complicated in my opinion George says
but they have a superficial impression
of being simple okay go and Java are
simple hmm go is simple I can agree I
think will be simple but you are saying
Java is simple I think Java is very
complicated so you know to discuss this
further we really need to go into detail
like what is your you know sins of
simple you know how do you like define
it you know we need to get into details
so you know this is why so many
programming arguments you know because
in your mind you are thinking you know
this or that and you think so therefore
it is simple but in my mind you know
it's some other thing see is also simple
and difficult for other reasons ok so
Jude so George says and bathroom uses
julia is partly focusing on machine
learning data science is act isn't that
great for current and future job market
no I'm not sure no I wouldn't say so
because if you are thinking the future
is machine learning and data science
definitely not
they are did they did they just happen
to be the current fad okay now I'm
saying this from consideration of all
things okay the history you know the was
you know as far as I know all the
mathematics I know of you know the
research math
systems all the programming technology
you know AI different branches of AI
machine learning neural networks you
know genetic change you know genetic
programming you know many different
techniques if you consider all things
you know humanity you know the whole
things do you think do you think the
next you know let's say next 20 years or
10 years in programming will be machine
learning and their science I don't think
so okay I don't think so yeah in my
opinion I think they are they will get
deadly we of you know come and go you
know they are not in in no way in no way
the field you know the scientific field
of machine learning and data science you
know they have data science is very
broad you know like what you mean but in
no way I mean even if you say data
science in no way machine learning and
data science in my opinion is is you
know occupying some kind of large chunk
of progress in Sciences I don't think
not at all I think they are just you
know maybe you know for now you know for
maybe even more few more years so even
though hey good morning Erin Oh haven't
seen you for a while yeah I think I'm
about to end I've been talking you know
today I've been talking like non-stop
for programming languages and stuff how
are you going so Erin ho I know who is a
Python expert so we both camp who says
can i you seem actually to do sick
exercises or should I get racket
you should get racket actually you know
the sick sick the that book they are
known for a you know they are heavily
criticized because I mean let me show
you what sick okay where is it
yeah they there's one criticize you know
the structure and interpretation of
computer programs this book it uses I
think it uses a variant of MIT scheme
you know scheme is to teach many
phenomena programming concepts okay
but however their scheme is not I think
it's MIT scheme or variant of it so so
so scheme you know list is kind of like
a family there are many variations
income incompatible so there are many
people with common criticism is that
it's you know when you try to do the
homework you know it's it's not exactly
the same you have to either get you know
that scheme list you know that
particular version or you have to kind
of you know you know the the code is not
exactly assembler so that's a common
criticism but I've seen I think people
have tried to translate not translate
but the same book but however they
defaced a code snippet into I think
there's a eMac I think there's a Emacs
Lisp version there's a Python version I
think there's a closure version and
there's also a racket you know scheme
disk version so you might look you know
such search for it but I wouldn't I
would not use email is okay because I
wouldn't use him at least because well
you make this Mystery's but in general
you you want a general-purpose language
eMac this is kind of just in Emacs you
rather you want to you know go and you
know use try try study that
general-purpose Lisp so I smell
something burnt let me check if there is
something burned sorry
I guess my roommates are cooking so so
few more comments and we are done for
today
so the Ruby has a chance so so ruby has
tries as much stuff to learn or spite
down to really know the language I don't
agree
Oh Aaron oh yeah Aaron I know you like
Python better than Ruby like you study
them both and you prefer Python well fed
well I get yes but you know everyone is
different so I guess to you
Panama is simpler but yeah actually so
actually that you know you make a good
point okay actually I because I actually
never really learned Ruby you know I
only learned it for three months and
from that for my impression of this you
know two months I think will be simpler
but maybe if I actually started to curl
maybe the story will be different but
but I still think yeah so yeah so okay
so that's you know maybe maybe you are
right again I mean of course it depends
on exactly what we mean by simple we
have to kind of you know each of us you
know give a sense of what what's your
definition of simple so Alan W what's up
hey Alan Alan says machine learning
process data science invites people
think because they can count a bunch of
stuff that they can socially engineer
utopia yeah that's a lot of Google
people and tech heads are thinking that
they think you know a lot programmers
okay I know and especially in Silicon
Valley you know the this is this Google
or maybe today Facebook people they they
like to think that you know you know
they are creating they are going to
create a utopia you know you know
technology will solve everything
not really actually actually programmers
you know I regard programmers as the
worst
beador of society for example right now
in u.s. presidential election there's
this Chinese guy I think he's Chinese
Andrew Young okay he is a tech head he's
a nerd okay he do he does bi research
and you know his campaign often the
slogan is math you know man like you
know the stuff I like math so a man take
people usually there's you know take
people I think actually I think
engineers the programmers type ok the
nerds they are the most econ ignorant
about society about how society works
how society or history evolves what what
should be good what should not be good
ok I think the program was you know if
you if they rule you know if you favor
the world the role whether were the
world will collapse okay into
nothingness and we can kind of see it
you know in part you know that you see
how you know the censorship started you
know the riots violence in USA you know
the what kind of things you know the
Google beginning with you know to know
Evo and look at them today
it's like Evo everything like to evil
its to evil everywhere that's what
Google has you know it's no it's not
opinion anymore it's like you see it
every day you you know this you know
it's not like it's not like debate
debate about any anymore so you see how
programmers you know you know you know a
lot of you are open-source fans I'm not
okay I used to be free software fanatics
I talked about this many times but you
know so part of the blame I also blame
the open source people the open source
you know they are part of the root of
the social justice you know warrior
because you know why because you start
with the ideology you know that utopian
you know like we're gonna help everyone
we're gonna share that
that's part of them you know that's the
heart of the open source we're gonna
share everything Oh every the word is
gonna be beautiful you know anyway you
know today we have you know if we
consider the whole earth we had our
technology is sufficient to such a
degree that everyone can be happy and I
have money you know there's no more
hunger we can't you know it can be done
I mean you can accept you know
technically it's we can do that except
the relation you know the politics
situation you know you know like you
know for example if you are rich you
know give me your money are you going to
give me your money like you just give me
why not you know it's good for everybody
but you are not going to you know it's a
power struggle you know the rich gets
richer they want to be richer they think
they are doing good they think they are
oh we are you know anti-trump you know
we are you know just they think they are
doing good but they get more richer and
they're talking about equality
you know the equality is very easy just
give all your money out no one is good
doing you know doing that so you know so
anyway not to get into to Politico but
basically our technology our kind you
know technology and resources we could
you know what in one you know in peace
like imagine what there's no religion
that's idiotic song okay that John
Lennon it that's most harmful so because
it's it's a impractical you know this
ideology if they think people think like
to think if you don't study anything you
that's all sounds good to you but why
not because why not everyone is in peace
why not but in reality you know you
can't you can see why it won't work by
just thinking yourself your family you
know everyone is equal you know nobody
owns anything you don't own your car you
know your car is shared by your
roommates or your family whatever you
nobody owns any money when you make some
money put it on the table like everyone
put their your money in your family you
know put put it into a pocket you see
how it works you know it's not going to
work
so okay I think I'm gonna stop like
because the comments I'm gonna just keep
reading and you'll never stop yeah so
because I've been talking for like okay
a few more comments so you know you know
I have some opinions so that just my
opinions you know you can always you
know judge for yourself hey hegemony
interesting just thing I know you for
for four years I guess online so Ruby
so ruby jobs has to advertise small okay
it is you know like few years ago three
three years ago I was looking for jobs
it's almost like every startup they use
Ruby yeah every every startup I think
it's probably still true now but anyway
at least three years ago or more you
know they like it like you know for for
several years every job every startup
job in Silicon Valley you know in San
Francisco Bay Area it so Ruby I can tell
you that
so Bethan well so Alan W says it's true
no sense is being smash together every
field so yeah we were talking about
Andrew Young you know he's not you know
his idea
you know he's his political his speech
is that he is going to create a you know
he's going to give everyone $1,000 a
month and he speak thing is about AI is
going to take away jobs I don't think so
you know you you know he's a nerd I came
you know as a nerd I can kind of see
exactly what you know what what he's
thinking what he's you know I think
that's just I don't think he's you know
that you know he
in a sense he's like he's pushing
fear-mongering of the artificial
intelligence I don't think that's that's
an issue
okay that's yeah you might think you
know AI is going to be a disaster or
something but I don't think that's
that's like I don't think that's
critical as far as politic politics goes
in my opinion the most critical things
okay doesn't matter what's your opinion
on guns oh okay on any of these hot
topics I think the most important thing
is to read of corruption like no lying
no corruption okay meaning that if you
break the law you go to jail oh you you
know you go to death penalty you lie to
the public you go to death penalty okay
you you know you you death death for you
you know no corruption you take bribes
if we found out death that's what I
think that's the most important of any
region any political any religion that's
that's what I think okay you rid of that
then whatever is your opinion or what
what's your philosophy what's your
school of thought it we are all become
good you know they they will hit in the
right direction doesn't matter what's
your you know philosophy communism you
know capitalism whatever but I think the
most in my opinion most important is is
rid of the you know eliminate corruption
you know that's the most important thing
that's just my thing that's just my
thought of course you know maybe if you
dig deeper you know it becomes hard to
define then it becomes you know
something else maybe young and young
again yeah that's his slogan young
so okay I gotta stop because I'm gonna
talk and then stop I mean what kind of a
ruby right now just means I'm working on
movie right now
not my choice but the best jobs in
FinTech around Vancouver oh okay
Ruby and this Ruby has some roots in
this yes exactly
yeah well I was just talking about that
Ruby's based on this being the pearl
I think young is overestimating how fast
jobs will be automated in the future for
example that or truck drivers okay okay
full staff you know that's a United
Kingdom the the British Empire they they
say the period in America its period
they say full stop okay full stop thank
you guys for coming by thank you guys
yeah I'll see you next time