hello welcome everyone to another cound
talk show today we are going to code
wolam language wolam language fantastic
let's get
started okay so wolam language we're
going to code wolam language and doing
the Advent of code
2023 day night uh okay let's begin we
did you know we did day one to day eight
so today is day Night Live I haven't
read a problem yet okay let's
begin so let's uh let's move this here
so you can
see uh can you see
it yes okay so it needs to move
more okay day night you write the camo
through the Cent storm and stop where
the ghost Maps told you to stop the
sandstorm
subsequently subsides somehow seeing you
standing at an oasis the cam goes to get
water and you stretch your neck as you
look up you discover that you must be
yet another Giant floating island what
must be another yet Giant floating
island this one made of metal that must
be where the parts to fix the sand
machines come from
there's even a huge there's there's even
a hand glider partially buried in the
sand here once the sun rise Rises and
heats up the sand you might be able to
see the glider and the hot air to get
all the way up to the metal Island while
you wait for the sun to rise you admire
the Oasis hidden here in the middle of
desert island it must have
a deic
ecosystem you might as well take some
ecological
readings while you wait maybe you can
report any environmental instabilities
you find to someone so the Oasis can be
around for the next Sandstorm War
Sandstorm War traveler okay you pull out
your handy ois and sand instability
sensor and analyze your surroundings the
is produces a report of many values and
how they are changing over time your
personal input okay each line in the in
the report contains the history of a
single
value okay each line in the report
contains the history of a single value
all the above is preluded uh that
doesn't make sense but here is the input
so you got several lines each line is
the input history of a value okay a
bunch of numbers to best protect the
Oasis your environmental report should
include a prediction of the next value
okay that's basically what you have to
do in each history to do this start by
making a new sequence from the
difference at each step of your history
if that sequence is not or
zero repeat this process okay make a
difference between between uh between
the lines or between numbers so I'm
making a new sequence from the
difference at each step between the
lines I
suppose uh I'm not
sure yeah between the lines so if that
sequence is not all zero repeat this
process using the sequence you just
generated as the input sequence
okay once all of the values in your
latest sequence zeros you can
extrapolate what the next value of the
original history should
be okay so we got this input let's start
to work on it let's get the input so the
input is um so paste the input here's
today's talk show and let's
begin let's start a wolam language paste
it okay so that's the input kind of so
here is a wolam language
Mathematica uh and if you don't know
wolam language you go
to just search for wolam language in
depth and you can get the download on
the official wfm.com website you can
download the wolam engine for free uh
and you can read my tutorial or guide
about what's a wolam engine what's
Mathematica W wolam language wam script
script what's the difference or you can
buy a Raspberry Pi and it comes with wam
language uh it comes with Mathematica I
believe okay so that's about wam
language so let's start coding so here's
the input you make the difference
between the lines so for example
here okay you make you make a difference
and you got the same number
of
numbers and if that's not all
zero then
[Music]
you you make a difference again but with
respect to which line I don't
know so let's see in the above data set
the first history is 0 three something
because the value increases by three in
each step the first sequence of
differences that you generate will be oh
okay so it's not between lines it's a
difference between the numbers
okay so the difference the difference
values sequence is 333 33 not that this
sequence has one fewer value than the
input sequence right okay since this
values aren't all zero repeat the
process okay do it again the values
differ by zero at each step so the next
sequence is z z0 z this means you have
enough information to extrapolate the
history visually this sequence can be
arranged like this okay yeah yeah yeah
yeah okay this is called uh uh
difference SE uh difference sequence
wait this's a mathematical term for this
I forgot what it is but anyway so to
extrapolate start by adding a new zero
to end of your list of zeros okay
because the zeros represents differences
between the two values is above
them
uh
what so you add a
zero to your all zeros
then then you also add a variable to the
end of the previous difference
lines then you can start filling in
place holders from the bottom up a needs
to be the result of increasing
[Music]
three
okay so difference do they come count
what does the old count are they the
difference of absolute values or not we
don't know yet but so far the sequence
is
increasing so you take the second number
minus the previous number okay then you
get the
positive number if the second number is
larger right so you can start feeding
the in the placeholders from the bottom
up a needs to be the result of increase
in
three okay a is
six wait
what wait a is three uh the value two is
left by zero the value below means a
must be three oh yeah that makes sense
because the difference between a and
three should be zero so uh and then you
need to find out
b b is 15 + 3
18 okay you know uh you can kind of feel
what is a problem asking without reading
the
details okay so the next value of the
first history is 18
okay you find
the difference sequence and you
then until it's all
zero
then I don't quite get it so so far you
don't need all the differences before
you just need
the you just need the difference of last
two numbers okay you need the you need
the all the differences before because
you need to get it to
zero okay it seems to be so find all
zero differences for the second history
required an additional sequence okay we
go on to the next line so 136 10
1521 so the input 136 10 1521 that's
correct
okay then here is the result you get so
you need to first of all do this until
your order numbers is zero then
and then you go one step up so 1 + 0 is
1 6 +
1 is 7 and 21 + 7 is 28 so 28 is the
answer so you basically you do
this uh sequence difference you know
different
sequences until you get all zero then
you then you start with the line before
it you take the last number then you add
that number to the line before it then
you get a new number then you add that
number to the line before it okay so you
just
add until so you do this different
sequences until you get a line it's all
zero then you just drop the last line
you go to the previous line take the
last number you add that last number to
the previous line and
repeat that's right so you get that's
how you get 28 okay so the next value so
let's see the next one so this
one so you see 0 0 0 so you get two last
item 2+ 6 is 8 8 + 15 is 23 23 + 45 is
68 that's
correct okay so you got a bunch of
these numbers so if you find the next
value for each history in this example
and add them up you got 114 okay so that
is that is 68
28 that's 68 28 and
uh and
18 so so what is
it 2 6 7 8 9 9 + 2 is 11
118 oh 114 that's
right okay so now analyze your osis
report and extrapolate the next value
for each history what is the sum of
these extrapolated values okay let's
begin to write this
okay so first of all do we need to pass
the inputs do we assume this input is a
text is a string or not uh let's get our
person input let's see how large is
large is it okay easy so copy
that so create a new
file create a new file okay uh and uh
okay and uh this will be we'll name it
uh let's see what how
[Applause]
to okay so we have already a names
something like that so let's go back
here let's a d of code
day8 okay so open it oh okay so wait
today is day nine right yeah so Day N so
we day night open it switch switch
switch cut cudle close go back say Okay
paste it so here is a personz
input okay
now it's very trivial to pass because
it's just the line uh separated by space
okay save it close
it
uh close it let's go back so make a link
showing browser so we got the Advent of
code
2023 day night input okay but first of
all let's try the toy problem I mean the
toy input so once you get the okay
so uh input equals to uh input equals to
that can you see it yes okay so we got
the input
then string split input split by uh
split
by okay so there's a question is each of
these are they always same number of
items we don't know so we want to know
if if there are same number of same kind
of numbers in each line and also notice
they do have NE negative numbers so it's
gets tricky
so how
many uh so let's
count how many
space 20 okay now let's go to this line
how many space 20 okay now are all these
lines of the
same how many space 20 it seems all of
them have the 20 21
uh numbers 20 space 21 numbers okay it
seems but let's we need to verify okay
go back to wam code so string input by
new line
then string input by a
space so
something like that we map it
okay
so in new input okay
okay so let's just try
this minut it let's see what
happens okay we got that that's what we
want is that correct
yes Henrik hello
Henrik good evening hi hi I don't know
would a hash map map be a good approach
for this
problem I don't know but I I don't think
we need to use it this is this problem
seems trivial very extremely trivial
easier than the previous days it seems
to
me okay so we got we got this is the
input we want that's fantastic uh what's
the next next need to do so you just
take the difference okay
you need to take the difference so let's
uh put it here so that we can see the
output okay so all you have to do is to
take take take the difference um okay
let me show you guys running it in
wolarm Notebook
okay okay let's go back here and uh
let's continue on the problem
so you want to take the difference
now this is going to be one single line
uh actually I think I can do it one shot
one single line to solve this
problem so you see you got each of these
line you need to take the
difference oh god
so let's look at
how oh okay so you process each
line by itself so for each line let's do
a toy uh example so for example that's a
input so you what you you're going to
um you're going to take the difference
between the numbers so what's the best
way to do it of course in C Java Pearl
python you do a
loop with the index but we don't do that
in functional programming
okay so what is the best way to do this
you
can in fact I think there's a buildin
function okay
so let's see so
differences okay so there's a function
differences I don't know what that is
let's look
up
uh wait so look up W and
documentation turn on JavaScript
magnify gives the successive differences
okay that's that is the that is it it's
so trivial run
it you see that is the function we want
okay so the difference is Returns the
differences in a list you know this is
one of
the nature of wolam language basic you
know you have 8,000 functions build
in commonly you know any common
algorithm you know you have it built in
so you don't even have to do code
anything so anyway so this Returns the
differences between the elements okay
then you need to repeat this
until all the until all items are
zero okay in other words you repeat this
until you reach a zero basically
so that's right so what you can do in
that in this Loop we can just
call fixed Point okay p i n t fixed
point is a function that takes a
function and takes a value it will
repeat the code function on a value and
call the function on a result and repeat
like recursion
until the result is the same so that's
what we need
okay so we do this so this here you need
to be a function so let's write one okay
function and uh the input is X so here
is X so you do that okay
until and the
input well what so what's the original
input okay the orang I mean the first
input is
that okay that's basically what you
need let's run
it okay it returns empty yeah
okay uh okay so let let's do this you
need uh it returns empty that's correct
because then eventually you reach 0 0 0
for example then the difference between
them is 0 0 and then the difference
between them is zero then the difference
between a list that's just zero itself
is just empty list I believe that you
know that's
what for example we can and try fix
Point uh actually you don't need fix
point for example let's say uh one two
for example we can try that uh actually
we can run this
line you see one so what if you have
just one what happens you see empty list
right so what what if you run empty list
okay run
it you see that's empty so so you know
that's how that works okay so actually
let's common this out so that other
people can
see kind of okay so what we need here is
uh fix Point list
okay so remove that okay now run it so
you can you can see uh
okay oh yeah okay I mean the syntax eror
there run
it uh new okay new is not we want yeah
okay so because you yeah okay let's put
it here run
it there it is so here is the
output uh let's clean them up so you can
see you see that is a
result okay
so you got this so this is what you want
right so
now now you need to
take the last number so 0 0 Z you need
to take this
[Music]
um wait what what does it wants you to
do
you take okay you start with a
line you start with a line that's right
before the or zero okay so you start
with this line you take the last
number then you add it to the um
previous number I mean you add it to the
last number of the previous
line and you repeat until there's no
there is no previous line okay very easy
so yeah so I mean the whole problem is
just one single Short Short Line
solution okay so we
um okay so what uh so what do you do so
let's
try let's
uh okay let's try a different input that
has more lines to work with
so we can kind of
see how it works out
okay okay so now this one is got more
lines to work
with uh okay so this one you start with
this
line the line before the all zero okay
so you take
2 plus
6 then plus 15 then plus 45 let's try uh
so 45 15 6
2 add them together
right yeah I think so
so okay
so what is the result 68 so 68 for this
indeed
okay that's it so now we know what to do
so this is
processing of a line so you just write a
function
that that takes this line and return
this number 68 okay so let's proceed to
do
that so here you got the fix Point list
then okay so you need to start with um
okay
so what's the difference between fix
Point list and other list okay they are
the same thing okay so one is
just uh I mean one is just
okay so one is just fix point and one is
fix Point list so fix point will just
return the end result fix point this
will return each
step okay so is that clear does that
make sense for example okay it's easy to
show example so f is a
function okay you apply a function to a
number three for example uh actually
that doesn't work because
it because it it will stop right away
because because it doesn't um
it doesn't change whenever you run it uh
okay
so so if you know what I
mean uh use a new buffer no okay so
actually I think I went into infinite
recursion yeah we we went into a
infinite recursion because this never
stops you know it just F at three then F
at that then F at that it never stops so
fix Point never stops fix Point stops
only when the result is the
same
uh it's not map and it's not scan okay
so you know map is when you your input
is a list the fix point the input is
just one single value it doesn't take a
least well it can but it doesn't it just
single value it's just um okay so let me
show you so I believe it takes a
optional argument to say how many times
it
recurses okay so yeah so it can take a
step so let's say four okay so maximum
of four times so you do it uh actually
it's easier if you do it here okay so
you run this
so you see you get
that okay you see it fix point is just
an uh Nest okay nesting a function you
start with three then F3 then ff3 then F
ff3 repeat until the result is the same
so in this case since our F doesn't do
anything every time you call it it just
Nest so the result will never be the
same it just continue nesting
so fix point will not stop but you can
add option for so it tells it you know a
maximum of four times so that's when
that's why it stops okay so this is a
fix Point
list now fix point is exactly the same
as fix Point list except it only returns
just the last element okay uh for
example we if we run
that for example we run it it'll paste
the result here no it doesn't okay let's
Okay so uh run it
and okay so yeah there it is
close run
it uh there it is okay
uh you see so these two function are
actually the the same it just this one
returns all the intermediate
steps
uh this function I don't think I
wouldn't say I don't think it's
available in other languages
uh possibly hasar but I don't think they
comes in this form anyway let's let's
finish the problem so I've been doing
I've been coding 36 minutes
already Okay so this does one step
now now you need to start with a non
zero in fact you can just take the last
element of each each line and you take
the last element of each line and you
just sum them up that's right you don't
even have to worry about special cases
like that okay so you so you take so let
me try this
okay
uh let's see let's see what that
returns when okay so last returns a
error okay when the list is empty so
what if
we use the part
syntax okay so it also return zero so
you need to treat the special cases
differently okay so you need so you can
check the length so what we going to do
is we map through the whole list we just
take the last element of each
until until the length and you know
unless it's empty list okay so so let's
do it here so we write the
function okay Y is the
input okay
if YY equals to empty list then return
zero otherwise last
y y okay that's a
function now we just need to map the
function
to this okay let's do it so we map so we
map this is the
[Music]
function okay and what's the list the
list is going to be
[Music]
this okay so
uh does that make
sense uh we don't have pry here but
anyway that's
it so now let's clean up a little bit
let's clean up our
um let's
remove the T tutorial things into
here okay
then delete that then
we fix Point list so
here remove that so what's the
difference between these
two it's the
same
okay so remove that remove that okay
remove that okay so let's put some of
that
here okay so now we got the fix point so
we pass the input the fix Point okay
so actually we can just run it
now I'm pretty sure it's
68 oh you forgot to sum okay now you got
that you see you need to
Summit
so total
okay total
at okay R it
again
fantastic okay
so and now all we have to do is map this
into all the lines so you see each so
this part process one
line right this part process one line
now you want to make this a function and
just map it to all the lines
okay uh okay so the code will become
complicated uh but no
worry
function okay so here function let's
say the input is line okay so and what
the function do is this
thing that's a body of the function and
uh but what is the line well the line is
here okay so the line goes
here so this is now a function and we
all we have to do is apply this function
to for example that a line let's run it
68 beautiful now all we have to do is to
map this function to the input
okay so now you write
map okay map a function to a list we
don't care about the level the list is
going well uh the function is going to
be that okay the function that's a
function and what's the list the list is
the new
input uh let's say input two
okay there it
is okay uh clean it a little bit so we
don't actually we don't need that
anymore we don't need uh we don't need
that anymore R
it oh okay no
wait okay something is wrong
uh something is
wrong oh the input wait did we get the
input okay something is wrong let's
now so here is a
function here is the
function right that's a function and
MapIt to input to so why is it
wrong
um hello smart man hello Ste
almost done
okay uh but some problem
so what is a problem
what is the
problems why is
it okay
what let's see what does this return
return so the input is correct something
wrong with our function
then uh something I thought we just
tried it out and it worked so there is a
function and let's take
the
yeah let's take these lines
so what
so this is a
function okay and the
function map it to this line
no okay you can't have
that so
68 okay
so it works for this line so is
it is it possible maybe if there's uh
what about
that okay
error
18 so so that was also correct for the
first line and what about this
line it shouldn't
be
wrong
28 68 28 and 18 you know they all ends
in eight
interesting maybe there's a trick
there okay so but it works for all the
lines but why is
it why is it when you
map you got the funky
thing you see this the same thing
so so it all works but when you map
it oh because H God because this you
didn't comment it out so wolam language
is trying to multiply that with
that okay so let's comment
out yeah correct yeah and uh and also
this part you don't need
anymore uh
let's let's put it to the tutorial here
okay
uh something like that okay okay so now
let's
run
it is it
uh is it a syntax issue
where does the multiplication come
from oh okay maybe you
you need the semicolon
there try
again when is
the let's see the pattern 6 15
20 15
6 okay 45 30
21 so for so there you have 45 30 21 now
what about
6520 where that came
from something something okay something
is wrong so you
map let's let's put the syntax here
maybe
I don't know so let's copy
all new
paste
magnify select or run it
gives you the same
thing don't
understand input
two and what's odd is that it
doesn't you see all these arithmetics
they don't actually evaluate for some
reason
oh because they are
strings that's that's
why because the input two are
strings
yeah the input
two you know the reason is because the
input to let's say take the first
element the first
element
okay that's actually a string
postfix
notation okay run it so it's a string so
you need to convert string to number
okay so here we just need
to uh string split okay and uh two
expression okay
[Music]
uh let's
see
44 okay let's see if that does that
work okay let's do
that okay that works so you just need
need to put this whole
thing into
here okay run
it fantastic that's correct now all you
have to do is total them together so you
can do a
[Music]
total there that's the prefix notation
the S sign so
the answer is
114 that is correct 114 okay now let's
try our uh I mean that's
correct okay we got the solution now we
need to try the let's put it back syntax
CCT showing browser so that is today's
code that's today's solution basically
this line uh and now we we need to try
our code
so I mean this input text okay so let's
see okay copy the file
path now make a backup pop this out now
let's let's read input
so
read uh uh now is it read line so
check read line file reads a line of
text no I want read lines
okay
so read string
uh okay yeah read string so read string
R string of this file then that is the
input okay so the input is going to
be okay then we convert it that's right
so let's try it and that will be our
answer do
it no so we got a problem well that's
because of that do it
again that's a number are you sure yes
I'm sure with my eyes
closed so here's a
solution here's the
answer answer there
submit that's the right answer thank you
guys for watching
[Laughter]
okay any questions we gonna close in
five
minutes so now let's clean up and and
maybe clarify for users so I mean so you
know this is how you so you got a bunch
of input which is a list of lines each
line is a bunch of
numbers then you pass it so that you
turn this number
pass input string
turn them into a list of list of numbers
okay that's this
part and that's that's what you get
then then what you do
is then then then then it's just this
okay uh we explained how that work
okay so for now uh this part
let's remove it and let's put it back to
the explanation code here
somewhere yeah so that will
show for example you can call the
differences function and that will
return
that okay and
you know so and this will
return so this is the explanation
part that and and the special case a
difference of just one single number
what you get is is that okay and uh same
thing for
that okay so
you apply so now we
apply
differences
recursively that's this part you apply
the differences
recursively and and the result is like
that okay so yeah so we don't so and uh
here is example of what fixed
point do okay okay so this is uh kind of
the tutorial part put it back syntax CCT
showing
browser and
now the real code part is just
this okay so yeah so this is a sample
output and here's a
solution okay good good let's see let's
say solution
okay uh
so this
is part one Advent of code 2023 part one
okay now put it
back uh
wait
what
what uh wait what is
this yeah for some reason I up oh
yeah
because talk
show
pre yeah so this part is
yeah now you can put it
back
now cut that part tutorial part to here
then syntax color the whole thing
showing
browser so this is a solution oh let's
magnify so now you can
see and now let's show the solution okay
so now let's let's shorten it because it
can be made much
shorter
um okay let's just use that default
input okay uh we don't need that and
let's shorten this line so how do you
shorten this line so you can just
wait let's try it again oh the two lines
okay so try it again put it
here
[Music]
so that
okay then you don't need
that okay
[Music]
so and the function X okay function
X you don't need that so the function X
is actually you don't even need that so
just
that just that and the map you don't
need map so
there it is so you map this function
to this
expression okay you don't need that and
the whole
thing two
expression okay so this line is
equivalent to this line 100%
syntactically you know this so this is
using W from shortcut
syntax and uh in lisp it's called meta
expression but Lis never get far never
went far to for that so so this line is
so the wolam language will whenever it
start to evaluate the code it will first
turn any shortcut notation to this fully
nested notation okay so that is why they
are 100%
equivalent okay so in fact since we are
doing the short version we remove all
the comments okay and here is very
similar okay so we can
um okay so let's let me uh clean up this
code so to make them uh extremely
short so yeah this is so redundant okay
so fix Point yes we need that fix Point
list okay
then okay so then here is a function
yeah function you can just
um okay so it's just that
okay the function so here so these two
lines are exactly identical
okay so you don't need that and map
again map can be written by like that
uh okay so map this function
to to this
thing okay so you don't need this map
and uh then total it yes and then the
whole thing is a function again
we um
change that to so the whole thing is a
function okay so grab
okay
well so
the so you that
okay so it becomes less it's become
harder to understand if you don't know W
from
language but we can write
it this
way that's right so that's right and you
don't need
this now
[Music]
we so you need to map it to input to
that's right
so in fact the whole thing is a
function we got so many so many nested
function now it's another one okay so
you need
to um
wait yeah so that is a
function wait we lost track of
wait
we okay we don't need this so here is a
this is a function we map this function
to oh God
that
okay uh remove that so now this is a
function okay now you just map this
function
to input
two okay so you don't need that and then
you just total
it okay that's it R
it okay that's
it let's try it here run it 114 that's
correct bye guys if you like my stuff
donate
okay do you have any thoughts on go what
go the you mean the go board
game uh yeah I had lots of thoughts on
go so wait let's put are you are you
talking about the go language or the Go
game and where can you find the emac
theme okay so let me tell you but here
but anyway for but here is the uh
today's talk show on the Advent of code
so the solution is just this single line
and in fact we can make it even
shorter yeah we
can uh but you know but that's that okay
if you want to know my emx theme just go
to emac
searcha theme okay there's noar theme
just search for
theme uh set color
theme uh theme Gallery so how to create
your own theme how to set color
theme and the theme Gallery so you can
see there it is my theme sanom theme
create the following file save it as
sanom theme. and you'll have my theme
but my theme is basically no theme it's
just background color that's all so I
don't I don't use this all I do is just
this okay Set uh let me show you my init
okay so init uh not that
init so emx in it go to the top okay so
go to the
settings uh go to the top background
color there it is that's all I do just
background color honey Drew no theme no
nothing
but if you really want to do the same
thing with the theme then you create
this file you know but it's problematic
because when you move around
computers you need to have this extra
file you know if this file does not
exist and you set the SAR theme emac
will error out so it's much easier if
you just like set background color
uh and yeah so here is all the themes
theme Gallery theme tutorial you can
read uh and
uh
AIS Crystal I think thank
you uh will will you ever use the Acme
editor no I don't think so because
that's on
plan9 uh is there a version for Windows
maybe there is but I'm not likely to use
it because I'm getting old I don't have
time to play with all the different
things okay it's on Windows and Mac OS
yeah but I got you know I got
mathematics to learn functional
programming prove Theory type Theory
there's
way lots of things to study
than uh you know then playing with
editor if you are young that's fun you
can explore you know and get experience
about editors but for me I'm too old for
that okay bye guys that's
it we shut down in one minute yeah okay
we already okay so Clos set Clos set CL
set
Closet close
set beautiful uh that's it