good morning ladies and gentlemen
welcome to another episode of Zatoichi
Oh today is 2019 September twenty-second
Sunday 8 o clock a.m. San Francisco time
and good morning Bartholomew and good
morning joe strong well from netherlands
good morning guys so guys pick a topic
so yesterday we talked about Richard
Stallman Richard Stallman quit free
software foundation he's resigned
involuntarily most likely and wait wait
in my life check check does YouTube say
I'm alive ok YouTube now if YouTube says
some I'm alive then I'm alive check 0
watching now it's time to refresh
refresh ok great I'm alive that's good
confirmed confirmed sorry he's alive so
just pick a topic ok pick a topic and so
yesterday we talked about Richard
Stallman and he is he is being kicked
out basically from free software
foundation and typically dingo good
morning dingo dingo were you from
typically richard stallman you know we
associate we you know richard stallman
and free software foundation they are
the same thing they are the one and the
same thing you cannot have one without
the other but now he's gone
therefore practically speaking
effectively there is no more free
software foundation you know three free
software foundation is now a puppet
state so bartholomew bartholomew says i
thought yesterday stream title was a
joke about richard was it a joke you did
you he did you watch it you didn't watch
it or did I made a Mis
take about a title did I did I use
imperfect English something like that
about the title let's see let's double
check Richard Stallman resign okay yeah
so he's kind of ungrammatical supposedly
Richard Stallman resign if s f you know
the thing about this is that on YouTube
you know video title you can only have
hundred characters so but I talked about
a lot of topics often in a video you
know there are diverse topics diversity
we we need diversity okay guys so hey I
talked about a lot of topics but you
cannot you know shrink them into 100
words so I have to make do you know
usually I pick you know some particular
particularly outstanding subject matter
that I talked about at length then I
have to Uncle mattify it you know so
make it so it's almost like just just a
sequence of keywords so just long wale
says can you tell something about oak
mud well no not really because you know
I actually so you know that's a
frequently asked question I I kind of
answered many times because let me tell
you what's the story okay so oak mud
yeah so if you actually yeah so a lot of
people ask me that because you know oak
mod is the big thing
Emacs but I don't actually use oak ma
much okay I have basic tutorials but I
don't really use it much so the last
time I talked about it quite a lot is
2000 19th September 12 so this is about
like 10 days ago so I would recommend if
you you know you can watch this one in
this video I talk
about I talk about my experiences of
using oak mud and basically I give you a
walkthrough of the basics and the
advanced the Babel oak bought Babel you
know language feature so you might check
that video out so Sabathia Romeo says
you know why does why does YouTube
sensor that would FSF you know uh yeah
that's a frequently asked question why
do not I use oak mud I talked about it
at length because I've been using I
being manually coding HTML since 1997
okay so I'm through already familiar
with HTML so my hTML is equivalent to
you know you guys using oak mud
everything is about the same except you
use Oakmont syntax I use the HTML syntax
that's why I don't use you know yeah
yeah anyway you know anyway so I did
talk about that what why do I not use it
and a lot of people of course they want
me to use it you know you know you have
to use oak mud and and yeah so I I don't
use it because you know I already know
HTML so well you know for for 20 years
so so the morning cream and 1990 cream
and 99p okay you know why does the
Google you know sense of that offensive
words this is incredible
you know this I want to swear but I want
to swear you know that Google okay so
from Michigan dingo is from Michigan Oh
dingo is from Richmond good
Michigan is kind of Michigan where is
Michigan Michigan is kind of in the
middle somewhere
I think so Bartholomew says no I mean I
did not believe that Richard would have
a reason no you did not no don't tell me
you did not know you haven't heard of
the news oh my god Bartholomew you've
been out of the loop you've been like
out of Dodge yes Richard Stallman
resigned from free software foundation
that space is a big news you know it's
the end of free software foundation as
far as I'm concerned and most of you
guys too I think
by the way so just if so I don't use
Olga mod and so if you have any MX
questions feel free to you know just
shoot then we can we can talk about I
don't use joke mod much yeah every time
I try to use it so Bartholomew says I
don't watch news because all news is
some type of propaganda
not exactly of course I know what you
mean but of course that's not exactly
that's not well put I'd rather hear news
from you and my friends okay yeah but
that but but in that case you get
limited news I mean yeah so green deck
good morning to Russia green deck now
green deck is in this city I constantly
forget let's see because he excuse me
pin calm oh I want to go to maps so
let's go to maps and let's look at oh
look at the map now this is near my
sleeping time I'm going to sleep after
the video you see ran out here is 8 o
clock in the morning what's going on
it's 4 P froze right now it's 8 o clock
in morning and in about 2 hours I'm
going to sleep
wait why is did B map just froze muses
Oh incredible waiting for being.com or
it's waiting yeah I suppose that's why
google map is better it's your what it's
waiting for being.com okay so green deck
says we have exactly 12 hours difference
Oh 12 hours so let's see 9 10 11 wait no
ohh exactly 12 hour difference so you
are 8 o clock in the evening Oh
so we we are boo good morning
hi again we are boo the Japanese fan
weeaboo champ champ low GPA violation
are more often than not brought to court
more often than not do you think Stormin
being ousted is an insurance policy so
that companies never do I move often not
not brought to court so do you think so
man being ousted is an insurance policy
so that companies never do okay I see
what you mean so you are saying you know
because Richard Stallman is gone from
free software foundation you are saying
you are possibly implying or suggesting
suggesting that these companies you know
Google maybe maybe not Google but many
companies commercial companies they they
pushed to have Richard Stallman kicked
out so that so that you know when they
violate GPL you know they use you know
GPL software they will not be sued I
don't think that's the case no I don't
think that's the case you know because
chief
yeah I mean free software foundation is
still there you know
yeah it's an organization you know they
sell from legal point of view it's still
there but to us to me at least I think
most to you guys as well to to me to me
free software foundation is good it
doesn't exist without Richard Stallman
you know we'll see what happens
you know that Grisha Stallman so he is
officially he's not the president of
free software foundation anymore now I'm
not sure there is any official of
affiliation at all at this point you
know so so it at this point he may not
have any official you know ties to free
software foundation and so the next
question is what's you know what what is
he going to be what what is his status
what what is he you know but basically
you know basically if you don't have any
official you know legal association with
free software foundation basically you
are not you know you don't have power
anymore you are not you know you are you
are just nobody even though to us you
know he's some some somebody but you
know legally speaking you know so foul
or the companies are concerned he is not
he
we just so many is just nobody now so as
as to the GPL violation stuff I think
that I'll still be handled you know by
free software foundation but the thing
is you know now the free software
foundation basically I you know in my
opinion is it's just a perfect state now
so what will happen we don't know the I
mean as far as I'm concerned without
Richard Stallman Free Software
Foundation whoever takes over whoever I
don't care whoever if it's not Richard
Stallman to me it's a perfect State
okay it's it's whatever it's yeah and
and I would guess
my guess is that whoever takes over is
coach is just someone who is a puppet
you know who is going to benefit to
whoever is rich you know rich people
powerful people that's that's what free
software foundation is gonna do that's
my opinion and also there they are right
now in free software foundation there is
a there's a second leader you know
before there's a Richard Stallman at the
top below him there is another guy
okay I'm that guy is very questionable
to me you know I'd rather I don't want
to mention the names okay but he's a
second guy you know officially fellows
Richard Stallman now Richard Stallman is
gone so now he is I suppose he's now
interim leader something like that you
know we don't know what will happen but
anyway that guy I don't trust okay I
don't think he's a good person I don't
know for sure but I had some experience
with him I don't think he's a good
person
so bartholomew says sorry what if some
hardcore fan of Stallman takes over and
he is even more hardcore about the storm
and opinions who like i don't think they
are we there I don't think they're as
far as I know no that's I don't think
that's going to be the case it's
possible but you know so far seeing F
says what was your experience about what
so KB map is back now let's go to let's
go to Russia
so green deck is in now Shinobu is
somewhere here cocoon deck kindig is in
[Music]
somewhere here okay cousin no penza no I
remember the name is a bit complicated
yeah yes this place yeah Custer ring bug
yeah Custer in bug
Farzin says you said you had some
experience with the second in line at
the free software foundation
yes so that guy you know back in 2000
okay I can show you I don't want sure
actually actually I just tell you the
guy who he is
okay I don't I don't think he's a good
person I think he's very you know I
don't know for sure
okay so this is my just my speculation
okay I don't know I don't know for sure
his character but let me show you let me
find let me find it find find there okay
okay so here's article this is written
in 2008 the title is free not IRC Emacs
channel been on cassabi am banned on
free nods ILC Emacs channel since about
2006 ok this happened in 2006 october
and the ban was never lifted as of 2009
I'm not sure it's lifted now I haven't
haven't checked you know haven't been to
IRC for 10 years anyway so 2006 to 2009
the ban is primarily and single-handedly
single-handedly executed by John
Sullivan ok his handle is also known as
John Jones through or what John Sullivan
okay this is back in 2006 to 2009
ok then later I realized he became you
know he he became you know the officer
whatever you know the he climbed the
ladder so it is him almost basically
know basically single-handedly banned me
and you know I have my story to tell you
can read this article this is on my
website you know this is a local URL but
basically Emacs ago you max thought oh
you know just such focus on if we not
IRC pen you'll find this and I have
locked I have loved you have a zip file
ok you have a zip file that loves
everything and you know I have to lock
the record because you know this this
page I'm showing you right now this page
was on Emacs wiki okay but after I'm
banned you know this this page they are
talking about whether I should be banned
okay it's drama okay you know just like
all the dramas are there you know you
have drama in every community anyways
this page is some Emacs wiki a bunch of
people they are talking about weather
- Bam Bam me okay some people give you
know yeah Casali should be bad and some
people say no I don't think so he's okay
you know most people say I should be
banned and they give their reasons okay
they give you their reasons and and most
of these reasons are just untrue yeah in
some you know some of them are just lies
untrue anyway so this is some Emacs wiki
back then and then I also you know
because it's on Emacs wiki I also wrote
you know comment my opinion I you know I
say you you guys are lying you know such
things like that so it's a long you know
you can read it if you want to here's
the comics someone is making a joke
about me so this is supposed to be me so
he says if if it's really a circular
list then why is it drawn with square
okay that's supposed to be me okay I
never said that but you know people put
that there and this guy Oh for the
wonderful toast and oh can someone throw
these and there's a table here
shut the [ __ ] up weathertron - okay -
drew these I don't know who that is
okay and I responded so anyway this is a
page a week on Emacs wiki people are
discussing whether I should bend should
be banned after they banned me okay then
after a month after a few months they
this page disappeared they deleted this
entire page okay these people these
people you know i should i i'd you know
i anyway that's that's dramatic okay i
you know i'm not going to claim that
100% pure and good okay I'm not okay I
swear and but but overall if you ask my
own opinion I would say
I'm not wrong okay they are the
[ __ ] okay anyway so you can read it
yourself
search for yourself so let's go back to
Reed green deck says well you are a very
controversial person yeah
of course you don't you didn't know this
is not the only place they banned me
I've been banned in quite a few places
so Bartholomew says if someone wants
somebody banned there is force there is
for sure something about about that
somebody that you are right something
good about that somebody good or bad
well certainly something with that
somebody for sure either good or bad
okay so so what is today's topic no
topic so I guess is just random chat you
know we already been talking about we
already been talking about for 20
minutes so I guess just random chat I
guess so anyway so yeah you know I so
you know I've been banned you know
that's that's that's that's humanity you
know this is called humanity you know
you read the news you see the politics
you know this spanning is small thing
you know it's just a little small thing
you see wars are going on you know they
are shooting rockets rockets in Middle
East in you know Vietnam War you know
Korean War Syria war whatever whoa you
know it's going on it's going on right
now so this is this is called humanity a
big part of humanity
uh AIC have many sick people so Farzin
says fuzzing way from fuzzing F Farzin
says so you don't support John Sullivan
because he banned you know that's not
wait hold on second okay
let me just read what you say so you
don't support John Sullivan because he
banned you it may turn out he's a good
leader of the free software foundation
despite he's incorrect decision to ban
you yeah you are right but you see like
I said before I don't fully know his
character okay and have not met him I do
not fully know his character but for my
judgment now for my judgment I think so
far okay this is my kind of guess my I
think he's a person you have to watch
out he is someone you know I don't know
for sure but I'm guessing he could be he
could be he's this person who when he
have power he will be a bad dictator
that's what I think okay but let me say
again this is I don't have solid you
know true for you know is this this you
know I don't know him too much and why
do I make this judgment because it's not
because he banned me okay they are a lot
of people who have banned me some you
know like you you can buy me you know I
don't think you are a bad guy you know
so so my you see my opinion is not just
base because he banned me actually
nothing to do you could say nothing to
do with that I judge you know I talked
about this before I just shall look at
his behavior his characteristics you
know yeah so in anyway so I you know
this yeah it's it's no big deal you know
you know he banned me I don't like him
but if you ask me it's not because he
banned me
so I'm just right now this is Mike's our
talk show this is my video so I'm just
you know I just want to tell you my
opinions you know so yeah so fasting
says I was born in Iran oh my god Iran
but I grew up in Canada since I was a
baby
Wow well I have people over the world
even and in Canada well I lived in
Canada in from 1990 1985 to 1986 to 1989
in Montreal Canada okay so what else
what else guys we need a topic we need a
topic ok so let's so anyway that's just
my opinion about that guy ok you know
it's not it's not it's just my guess you
know if you you know yeah you can you
can read these details you know you can
read the details so anyway so if no
topics then let me show you this d3.js
visualization a quasi science ok
this is an essay I wrote in 2018 because
I'm studying d3.js do you guys know
about d3.js do you know what it is
teacher says you still familiar with
Chinese yes of course let me show you
time in Chinese right now Xi'an zai ok
whoa ah ah
someone okay wait did it enter oh I
missed uh oh my god I missed comments so
that means right now I'm typing Chinese
Shenzhen without Zone one that's how it
sounds
shinza what that's on one shin side
without someone okay that's how it
sounds so I was going in Taiwan okay let
me read the comments beginning from the
top so it's somebody I honestly have so
teacher teacher away are you from I have
not seen you before and hold on second
are you using a profile photo that is
geometry looks like that looks like good
geometry you know oh yeah geometry
that's another big topic let's go to
let's go to Mass saw math block the
wonders of geometry so let me show you
some of these this is my saw math block
if you just search saw math block you
will find it okay we click the link then
we go to this fantastic collection of
great software for plain geometry these
are written in JavaScript this one you
probably have seen this before this is
called spirograph spirograph yeah it's a
toy you can draw these pretty graphs and
these curves in math they are called
hypo chocolate okay let me show you
hypothyroid let's it's okay so a lot I'm
going to show well once I talk about
something it's gonna have a bean and
stop you know non stop because too much
to talk about so this this is a visual
dictionary of special crank playing
curves and you can go down to cycloidal
curves
these curves are called cyclo Edo curves
these lists these these these okay one
second and actually in this this this is
two so this is math subject this is a
black hole
this the this is a subject without
bottom so cyclo Ito curves you see you
see these images these are called this
the technical name for this collection
of curves are called epic record okay
and basically that is what this spiral
graph you know these two draws
so April you have a port record and here
you can see how they are generated by
roll in circles on another and then you
also have okay APIs they are so loud so
many so I can you know I can talk about
this for one one hour actually we have
not had an opportunity to talk about
this topic for one hour yeah one day
next day I should if some some of you
guys are interested in math next time
you know pick a math topic you know when
I asked you know like say you wanna know
about this thing we can go into detail
this is not these are fascinating you
see you are here you have the case of
running a circle inside another circle
and you generate this pretty graph and
you look at this special case you see
this running a circle inside another
circle is also a mechanism for for
for translating rotational motion to
rectilinear motion you know you need to
use these you need to have this
mechanism in robotics for example in
train for example you know the train you
know the trains wheel you know the old
clunky steampunk train you know you need
to you need the wheels to that you have
a motor that that turns you need to
change that into well actually in a
steam engine steam engine you don't have
something that turns instead you have a
piston you have a piston like that goes
like that okay so you need to transfer
tranced you need to how do you say
convert that motion into a rotational
motion so the wheel can turn so this is
one of the way okay so anyway that's
that's about hi pod spirograph in the
hypothyroid effort record hypo truckroid
epicyclic hypo cycroid when they are
when they are inside the circle when the
rolling circle is inside it's called
hypo okay hypo chocolate when those
rolling circle is let me show you when
the rolling circle is outside you get
these kind of curves it's called it's
called a pepper
chacoly okay hypo is inside Apple is
outside and when the when the when the
point is exactly on the wheel those are
called cycloid so for example anyways if
you guys are interested in that we
talked about that for one hour next day
but but but that's not the main topic I
wanted to show you some of the geometric
applications you see this geometry
algebra
so anyway this okay let's go back to the
comics to the comments teacher you
haven't answered my question
oh did you see no you have an answer
anyway so Farzin says okay green deck
says do you have an opinion on Buddhism
I think you asked that before is that
right read he says come on in red cheeks
now what do you think is the best
programming language for a beginner to
become a good programmer that is another
frequently asked question I talked about
that a few times in the past videos you
might be interested you know just such
for YouTube sorry and such for you know
such for Python or JavaScript or
programming language I mean you look at
the collection of videos you are sees
you know I talked about that basically
so the question is what do you think
what is the best programming language
for a beginner to become a good
programmer okay now those are separate
things
okay what is the best programming
language for beginner that's a good
question okay now it has nothing what
you know it really have nothing to do
with to become a good programmer you
know how to become a good programmer you
need to work hard study hard be smart be
you know be smart actually is part of it
you know today people today the
Millennial so the social just just is
they say oh you cannot say that everyone
is you know good at everything
no actually you did this matter a little
bit you know you you have to you know
anyway so that'sthat's not important how
smart you are is not important you you
have to work hard okay so to be a good
actually required talent ok I'm not I'm
not
a great programmer for example for
example one one example is this there is
this famous skin programmer does anyone
know the name mention it you know the
most famous game programmer who who
coded the doom who coded yeah I think it
doom what's his name I you know I don't
follow him too much
so anyone type it the most famous game
programmer and also there's this guy who
wrote Minecraft what's his name
John Carmack yeah John John calm Mac
he's a guy who created don't you know
he's a great programmer you know you
know he's a you know one one of the top
program he's a genius for programming
okay he for math he probably don't know
[ __ ] and he probably cannot do math okay
different people have different you know
talents what you are good for so some
people are very good at programming you
know some people are logicians
mathematicians you know and they don't
know [ __ ] about programming they can't
they can't okay many mathematic my
almost all mathematicians most
mathematicians are like that they can't
code okay some people are good at poetry
for example you know so anyway so to
become a good programmer you work hard
and and also depends on you you know if
you are really do you have that interest
do you really you know once of course
you you start to learn programming then
after year let's see if you really this
is something you are really interested
you know if you typically you are good
when you are really interested in it
okay because you are eager to learn you
you want to know you know there's no
incentive no outside instant incentive
you just want to know how this works you
know how how Python works how you you
want know everything the detail to see
every day you know it's just like you
know it's in you so that way usually you
will become very good if you are kind of
if you are into something you know they
say something you love okay so that's
how to become a program become a good
programmer you know you love it you you
you you spend a lot of time with it
that's how you become a good program now
now the other question is what's the
best programming language for a beginner
okay this is actually not such a thing
as the best okay but there there is
there is some languages that's good for
beginner to learn some are not for
beginners okay for example Haskell is
not for beginners okay it's not good
language for beginners to learn C++ is
not a good language for beginners to
learn Java is not a good language for
beginners to learn okay so what's a good
language for beginners to learn I would
say you can go with Python you can go
with Ruby Python Ruby okay you I you
know you could also go with a scheme
list okay but scheme biz is kind of the
niche you will not find a job in it on
the other hand if you start with Python
or Ruby you can find a job after you
know if you really study hard for a year
you can run a job so I'll just suggest
Python and Ruby okay and Golan
okay go line is another one I would say
it's very good for being beginner : so
let me show you so every time I need to
show you my website because otherwise
that's what I'm here for
you know to market my stuff so does that
make sense
the dot I got the top no no dot that is
kind of dead language ray so
ray does that answer your question you
know this is you know say say yes or
give me you know give me some feedback
for my feedback so you give me feedback
for my feedback to your feedback so you
go to my language tutorials okay so I
have tutorials for my Python tutorial
about 50 pages it's very good it's
excellent for beginners okay
in fact I have Python three basics this
single page you read this single page
for for half an hour you'll get an
overview of the entire Python language
okay that's about 15 pages then you can
go into details many details if then you
know if else loop list basics you know
so on or you can learn Python - so
that's my Python tutorial it's pretty
good for beginners my goal and tutorial
is also excellent for beginners okay
because I love : so as you know yeah so
so you guys okay if you like it try out
try out my tutorial okay if you like it
and share it with your friends now my
Ruby tutorial is not so good okay I'll
be honest my Ruby tutorial I've spent
two months studying Ruby but I never
actually coded much Ruby I never
actually coded Ruby so I only take me
like three months to study it and wrote
a basic tutorial so it's not so good but
it's okay I mean well beginners you know
for beginners Ruby so my pattern is good
my colon is good
my JavaScript is tutorial is fantastic
it's in depth so rate he are you still
here right he say something because this
this answer
is for you anyway my so I have my
JavaScript tutorial it's in depth but
javascript is not really a good language
for beginners okay so I recommend you
know just go with : Python Ruby that's
not good for beginner
yeah okay let's let's go next comments
then Farzin says python is great for
beginners MIT has a free online course
which helps you think like a software
software engineer okay yeah
markus persson was the lead dev for
minecraft oh you mean right now
no he has a nickname he has a online
nickname I don't remember it at moment I
have to think then I remember minecraft
he's got a nickname maybe Markus is his
full name knotch yes not yeah not so so
he's not just full name Markus Persson I
guess
I've seen notches code you know one of
notch that puzzled me my god let me show
you okay let me show you one of the this
this is this is this this one has gone
viral like ten years ago and I looked at
it I cannot understand its where would I
find it
so teacher says I learned racket but I
think it can't find any job that yeah
yes that's true
racket this is a great language but it's
academic so if you learn that as a hobby
that's good or if you are a university
student or if you are a graduate student
you are going to do your pH PhD you know
in language research things like that
racket is good but outside of academia
racket is it's kind of like going
nowhere it's it's been going nowhere for
like 20 years it's kind of a sad sad
story you know the market
so I want to find the how can I find it
okay so let me let me try this okay so
let's go to JavaScript let's quick SVG
let's go to the bottom there it is wait
ray Kasten no it's not there okay let me
show you this anyway so you have this
ray cast which is you know you can this
is like a tomb you can walk you know I'm
pressing arrow keys okay wait you know
you can walk
you see you press the arrow keys to move
around and the code is very complicated
by anyway that's not the one I'm
thinking I'm the notch guy he has a
JavaScript thing I have it somewhere I
don't remember where I said let's see
d3 react
cameras versus SVG canvas sucks donkey
ass okay don't use canvas use SVG
actually there's some applications you
have to use canvas but in general I'm
not a canvas fan anyway I cannot
remember where I have that good morning
Israel Israel good morning to Israel
donkey ass is a bit redundant funds
pausing were you surprised not to find a
job for right for were you surprised not
to find a job for for writing racket
code me Oh teacher says I learned racket
but I think it can find any job okay a
mix fine name tired
and what
okay so yeah we let's see so I kind of
lost track dart is dead
Google flutter uses start and Google
flutter could soon be the best mobile
application development framework oh I
didn't know that
but nobody uses dot dot is kind of to
the industry it's kind of it's dead but
I don't know about Google I didn't know
about Google flutter so what is what is
flutter flutter beautiful native
application in record time I don't I
don't trust you know I don't like I
don't know you know these days it's like
anything by Google it makes you of you
know averse versiv a version you know
you developed a version towards when you
hear the name Google because they are
[ __ ] everything they are censoring
and whatever flutter you know what I do
don't use this yeah you know what they
do
yeah they you know they become so evil
so now they have this flutter whatever
it is flutter flutter is Google's UI
toolkit for building beautiful
mobile web and desktop from a single
codebase go [ __ ] yourself you know
they're gonna manipulate you know yeah
it's gonna be popular they're gonna
manipulate they're gonna control tight
control things and you know that's what
Google is today okay so it's okay let's
try not to swear it's not it's try not
to get into a rant
ok so I tried to look into dot but
flutter page was down so I went to react
native go line is by Google I thought
you love Google I don't know of Google
but Golan well I love Golan
yeah well like what can you do you know
and this score line is open source I
mean they have the license out there
it's it's totally open source so so
anything so anyway so anything else so
let's see how long we've been talking 15
minutes okay we can talk a bit more
let's see
green deck so fasting fasting is in
Canada Oh cannot uh and and and and I
still remember the Canadian Athan you
know I have a thing about a thumbs and
the American and a thumb is also very
good oh my god I got 18 people watching
so who are you guys who are you come out
and say hi twenty people now okay so
what is the next topic okay let me just
miss this let me just continue random
then I cannot find I cannot find not
JavaScript code let me give it another
try
okay what would be the name of notch you
know it's like notch wrote this
JavaScript you know it's just it's very
little like hundred lines of code but
but then it's an infinite you know it's
like going into a whole 3d it's 3d you
have punch it's like my minecraft okay
you have these boxes you know flying
flying by like you are timing type your
you are fire flying through a whole kind
of you know and it's a loop so the same
thing you know the same image fries -
it's on a it's on the web I have a copy
I have a local copy but I forgot what's
the name
what somewhere here if you know if I
think about it I'm pretty sure I can
find it for you for example first first
of all you just search for JavaScript
you know such for all backslash dot j s
okay then here is all javascript files
then if I see the name I will remember
it okay insert content molecule demo
molecule demo is another interesting one
moving clocks stopwatch view dimension
fade-out detect fresh QuickTime they're
more terrible crock cross you know yeah
some of them some of these are very
interesting they are there it is
JavaScript minecraft okay so they are
several I want to show you actually
JavaScript minecraft okay copy the file
path let's go to chrome new tab paste
enter there it is you see that
now it doesn't look smooth here now this
is not right maybe you know the
JavaScript update over the years screwed
it up or maybe because my CPU maxed out
but that doesn't look smooth but anyway
that's that's not just code
yeah Markus Persson so let's look at the
code the code is not jeaious okay dot j
s basically it's a giant hack it's
incomprehensible by the way okay so so a
total of 200 lines you know you see this
thing you know it's like you are flying
through a bunch of boxes anyways close
it it's because it's taking memory ok
close it so so it's 200 lines and it's
it's incomprehensible hack but let me
tell you whenever you read code you
cannot understand that's okay because
code by the nature it's very easy
trivial to create a code that that it is
extremely difficult to understand this
is a nature of written algorithms that
that is a nature you know the very
nature of algorithm written down it
takes tremendous time to figure out what
what it what is going on that's a that
this is a mathematical truth okay so
don't worry
you know if you are new to programming
if you read someone's code you know if
there's no documentation it is it is
true that you take tremendous time just
to figure out what what it is doing
so anyway not sure these 200 lines you
know it's impossible to read and
basically a lot of it is trigonometry
you know Jake yeah and especially when
you
Smith then it's more more
incomprehensible and look at I hate
these people doing this kind of thing
look at this look at this this thing
this double double angle bracket you
know you know what those are those are
kind of beat beat momentum manipulation
the bit operators I think that's shift
what shift right and whenever you see
that that's hack that's a [ __ ]
garbage code why I hate those people
you know this C programmers see first
first programmers this clever type of
people you know they like to write
clever code [ __ ] him you know that so I
don't like that that's not that's not
good okay you know so this is this is
about programming style so the style I
like is logic you know a lot of symbolic
logic you know so we can have a
competition where one side is pure pure
symbolic logic on the other side is this
kind of [ __ ] up first occasion see
you know golf code and let's see who is
more difficult to read okay anyway so so
far seen says I have lived in Canada
since age of two point Iran you bet make
it was it did you live in us a prior
culture so you better drop Quran what so
so many comments is coming on now
so bartholomew says and i thought i'm
the only one that finds spit
manipulation only necessary where it is
actually needed it often just makes the
code harder to read and in all honesty
just is not needed exactly that's as
well said I totally agree you know you
know I can tell you right away you see
you see I see this bit operator I can
tell you it's it's a hack you don't need
you know you
modern programming you never need it
when do you need bit bit manipulation
bit operators when you actually are
dealing with like assembly code or C
code C code when you need to manipulate
the memory address or something you know
you need to be extremely fast yeah
basically wherever you see that you know
they are doing hack you know they are
doing extremely hack they the and most
most of the time when you see pit
operators is because they want to make
it fast you know they are you know
that's that's how it is anyway that that
is this is a notched code but anyway I
also found quite a few others that's
very interesting interesting to look at
so let me show you some of them so this
one for example I'm sure you have seen
actually you may not have seen it
because you see this one guys you see
this is this is so-called physics
physics engine this is all written in
JavaScript by by the way you see you can
tear it if you drag it too fast then you
get horse you see this is amazing I
don't know how it's done well I have
some ideas but actually I to be honest I
don't know how exactly it is done and
I've been wanting to study this code but
it's not easy so let's see 230 lines my
god only 230 dies okay and it's written
it's using canvas technology
I don't like canvas but it's amazing
though you know look at that it's very
fast and that's all JavaScript so so
bathroom you
you need to study JavaScript ok so let
me show you another one actually let's
go to our talk show
ok we need to we need to add a topic to
here so minecraft ok we need to add it
here ok so actually actually Sontag show
today's date it's a new page add a li
cut put it here cut open it
paste showing browser so that is the
note the index of things we've talked
about so later on I'm going to you know
create you know go through my video and
this is a I'm gonna put it on my YouTube
you know a lot walk so let's go back to
the JavaScript directory there is
something else I want to show you fun
JavaScript code but before we do that
let me read the comments to get feedback
green deck
pausing you're not Mullen okay so if you
have a question put put put my name okay
like the red orange like that so I can
read it
in answer it so cool for school says to
others how do you know when sorry starts
live broadcast when the time okay
usually usually like and I try you know
in the past week usually I I scheduled 8
hours in advance so if you just go to my
YouTube website you will see you know
upcoming
live stream you know and there's there
will be your time there will be a
countdown clock they are usually so
usually I do that eight hours in advance
you know like when I go to sleep you
know set up tomorrow's time but not
guaranteed okay it's like sometimes I
don't you know sometimes I think Oh
today out I'll just skip video because
video actually it takes energy you know
like every day I you know I talk for one
one hour but he actually kind he's kind
of its zaps your energy for half a day
almost so anyways so let me so so what
else
maybe that's it for today I'm thinking
there are many cool oh yeah already over
an hour so let me show you another one
so if you have questions to me you know
answer it okay
I mean type it let me show you another
one fun JavaScript all these are written
in pure JavaScript nothing else make a
stand tutorial terrible cross validation
molecule demo okay this one so copy the
file path go here new tab paste enter
you see this is pretty and you can also
create a new one create a lot more can
you drag it I don't think you can track
it but every time you click you create a
new one
you see they kind of interact so this is
another you know written in JavaScript
and in fact you can look at the code
let's look at the code so go back to
here saw talk show today's page paste
here link of I and open the page search
for JavaScript and there is a code it
uses two JavaScript files one of the
file is the GUI here so you can control
control the attraction between dots and
you can adjust the friction parameter
you know things like that what is this
light oh you can actually create light
okay so let's so it uses two JavaScript
file one of them is a library that's the
user interface you see here and the
other one is the actual molecule file
this file is o again 230 lines so you
actually you know - so if we remove the
comment it's only 200 lines 220 lines so
it does not take much lines to write
them and this is written in JavaScript
before 2015 so it's written in old
JavaScript you see when you have a
JavaScript you have funky things like
that you know you wrap the whole
function like that anyways it's
fascinating so it's only 200 lines oh my
god I really need to study it and figure
out how it works so anyway so that's
another interesting one so anything else
guys okay type it okay
type it and maybe that's it for today
close close close close Java screaming
depth close terrible cross this I need
close go through the talk page today oh
it's already there so okay so let's see
what what more comments so Israel says
watch the I me I'm his video pretty good
why don't you use MX browse URL of fire
yeah I have that but you see that won't
work because my default browser is
Firefox so if I call that command you
will just go to Firefox but I don't have
script in Firefox so whenever I need
JavaScript I need to go to Chrome or
Safari or brave but I don't have those
you know I don't want to launch those
browsers for example I can for example
start command log Mart okay on the Left
window you can see all my commands now I
have a command now if I want to launch
this link in brave so I call meter X
open link in brave enter you launch the
brave browser and then there is my
Twitter
oh yeah it launched over here so you see
curse that you know and I also have a
command for example I call open link in
Safari then your launch safari terrible
cloth okay so I think that's it for
today let's see why so much on
javascript because javascript is my
livelihood well because I run websites
I have ads you know I make you know how
I survived I survived on my websites
that's all I do
you know creating writing stuff so I
need to know JavaScript well because you
know it's part of the web so okay that's
it for today thank you guys for coming
thank you
all of you guys lots of you guys today
and if you like my tutorials you know I
have tons of tutorials language
tutorials you can buy my entire web site
for only $100 truly and also I have you
know paypal mastered on patreon Amazon
gift card gift gift and Bitcoin yes of
course
so if you like my stuff support me so
thank you guys bye for today see you
Monday next tomorrow Monday Monday is
the work day
what it's we've been talking for well
one hour I gotta go I'm going to sleep
by Israel