good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh
today is July 27th 2019 in the Lord 2018
and 6 o clock p.m. California time and
today I do not have a topic so we are
just going to do random you know I'm
wondering is this talk is going to be
technical or you know perhaps includes
you know or non-technical and take it
you know technical meaning programming
languages you know math stuff like that
none technical means YouTube politics
and stuff you know the general life and
stuff so technical and non-technical you
know every time I do a video let's do
that ok so let's get ready okay so let
me get ready so you need this window
over here so you can see and I need for
hemming blog because I'm going I need
you know I'm going to go over my blogs
and talk about interesting things things
are interesting there's so many
interesting things 1000 millions of
interesting things
pop pop out the charts the chat and
let's verify if I'm alive actually I
know I am because I can move you see no
it's okay so
so talked on let's talk you know like
often when I do a video I have actually
I mean let me tell you about this okay
so yesterday I did
let's go to YouTube yesterday I did
yesterday and the day before yesterday I
did a great video talk show lecture
you know let's you know the end that's
about okay here is a combinatorial
exploration of possible algebraic
structures that's yesterday and and okay
this one Emacs livestream you know Emacs
Lisp for beginner this one so this is
this one is very popular you know two
thousand views that's popular for me and
you know usually when you do videos
usually when you do practical stuff you
know a lot of people watch you but
anyway I was going to say so let's go to
my channel okay so the channel the
channel of Saudi so if you are here say
hi
type type your comments and opinions
okay so here is my YouTube channel and
we and yes okay okay and there are a few
very interesting videos I did I I think
it's fairly good you know so one of them
is this one Santosh show July 19th this
syntax symbolic expression meta
expression and mathematical expression
okay this one sulphides called 600 views
okay
so check this out this is good this is
about least syntax you know this is like
this is like you know my 15 years of
experience my 15 years of ranting again
is the
syntax again is the least phonetics
especially the Common Lisp fax those
idiots you know online when you talk
about things among programmers like
often it happens often okay actually I
can I can tell you why this happens it
it it happens often that when you say
you know one plus one equals to two but
in a community they they do not they
think you know they do not believe it
they think one plus one equals three
three
this happens in you know programming
community you know so anyway so this
video is about this syntax the issues
you know some of the issues details if
you code this you know so that's one
video and let me explain why that such
thing happened okay so anyway it so
that's why I'm video and the other video
very interesting is this one Lisp
Mathematica term rewriting pattern
matching okay Tom rewriting pattern
matching basically this video is about
the meaning of symbolic languages you
know what's the significance of symbols
in a programming language this in
Mathematica has symbols not other
languages so you you know if you are
Emacs fan or Lisp and programming
language fan check check out these two
videos so that's pretty good they are
also a Python video that's you know
where it's this in anyway so so that's
what I did yesterday and okay so you
know why so so so I was mentioning
before you know the programming language
communities sometimes they they believe
in false patently false
things you know so why does that happen
I mean you know you think these are
programmers you know or engineers you
know they have scientific training well
a lot of them have at least you know but
it's easy to understand the situation
when you look at religion you know
actually
so this is some kind of it's kind of
like the condition of humanity you can
look at religion or you can look
actually the gist of it is tribal tribal
you know the from a academic point of
view you call these kind of behavior
tribalism basically each of us you know
are biased you know even you know
something like when you have a fact you
don't see you know you always see only
your side of it
you know you don't see other side of it
so you know one easy way to see that is
in religion you know you have you know
many religions in these days you know
since the past 20 years you have a
theism atheism it's and it's becoming
something and then you have today you
have you know the social justice warrior
ISM okay that's that's you know kind of
become a religion of its own irrational
stuff you know so you know so why did
this happen you know it's because
grouping and community you know so Lisp
programmers for example they are you
know they want to uphold their community
Emacs people they want to uphold their
community Python you know in Perl and
you know so on and Haskell of course and
you so easy easy so you want to so there
is you know it's see you can understand
that also by thinking about your own
family like many things in society you
can like politics complicated you know
you can reduce it you can you know try
to get an understanding by by reducing
the number of people for example
economics you know capitalism communism
you know that involves billions of
people it's about a system you know it
very complex complicated but often you
can get some understanding and insight
by reducing a number of the people -
let's just say 10 you know your family
or your neighborhood you know so
you know so for example in your
neighborhood of let's say ten people or
you know you're among your schoolmates
or work co-workers let's say ten people
and you think let's say if your family
member let's say your brother okay so if
he did something wrong that you know it
is wrong you know and you know other
people are attacked you know fighting
with him you know other family other
members you know outside the view of
family also the bureau community so they
are fighting with your brother because
you know there's certain issues you know
and to you
maybe it's create you know everyone says
your brother did this very bad things
and to you maybe you think that's
actually true
your brother actually did something very
bad but the question is what are you
going to do you know are you going to
protect him are you going to you know
lie for him you know you know we didn't
do anything because this is this is the
you know the meaning of tribalism you
know often it has to do with your
bloodline kinship you know you know how
like how close a means to you you tend
to support that person you know the
closest the the smallest group of people
is yourself then you're you know
immediate / align things family your
your dad your you know your parents or
your children and then then your
brothers then your relatives then your
neighborhood your community your country
then you know earthlings
you know human animals as opposed to
aliens you know so like every time we
see what you know sci-fi movies we have
alien invasion
why idea because why we why there is the
oldest conflict because there are aliens
you know they are outside of your group
so in the same way if your brother did
something wrong there's a question jar
you going to support him or not
on one hand you know he did something
wrong you know it's bad for you
manatee in general because he stole he's
still think so he you know he you know
something he took bribes or something
like that there was something it's bad
for the whole group of people but
however within your group your family
you know if you support him like you you
protect him it's good for you you see so
the I mean so this is a eternal conflict
so anyway so you know so that's it's a
general behavior of you know problems
issues of humanity you know shall we say
you know sometimes many issues in
society it's you know as a man of saying
it's not too complicated but you don't
hear these kind of things every day
although sometimes it's apparent because
a good morning George what's up so
anyway that's about that topic about you
know so today I'm going just going to
talk random random stuff so George you
are from Southern California am I
correct
if I didn't remember incorrectly and
okay so what shall we talk about just so
George give us a topic give me a topic
like a direction so anyway I was saying
there are these two programming language
list videos I did yesterday that's I
think it's pretty good so you know check
it out and okay Oh Perth Australia Perth
yes Perth Perth Australia by the way are
you are master done are you the guy on
master then that heavies the question
because there's a similar master then
and you know I was wondering okay so
it's
so shall I shall we so let's talk about
let's go through my website and let's
give some random updates oh you used to
be a master then okay paint someone else
I think he's also from Perth Australia
Perth so you know so it's interesting I
started to know people I mean online
people from Perth you know which is I
learned it's a western part of Australia
google map ok let's go to Google map
yeah okay oh okay so you introduced me
to the No Agenda show I see now that was
on Twitter right that was on Twitter you
know I actually I don't remember exactly
like which account you are I'm sorry
about that because that's part of you
know I'm not very famous but you know I
do have you know write blog so I don't
remember but I do yeah I don't remember
exactly the names and you know but I do
remember yes it was on Twitter I think
you showed me then I joined the master
then because master then you must
remember two years ago you know the
social justice saying the social justice
can are saying that oh we have a new
social network that is going to you know
gonna not have nazies you know which is
untrue you know that's not our engine of
master then but anyway oh you deleted
all social media yeah okay that that's a
good thing
you know that's yeah we yeah it so what
are we going to talk about I was going
to look at the map Perth in Australia so
you know I always wanted to like every
time I do that
I want to look at the street photos
street view this is where I live
you know this is San Jose California San
Francisco so for for those of you don't
know let me give you like a introduction
to the Silicon Valley okay
an introduction to Silicon Valley first
of all let me show you
okay there it is the United States map
then United States the Hong Kong
situation yeah I can talk about that but
actually I don't know much about that so
I was born in Taiwan
I've never been to Hong Kong I've never
been into China you know I don't want
you know like the Hong Kong people I
think they have issues okay now this is
a political thing so that you know
things I say especially you know like
the typical you know when I say
something it's gonna offend people you
know look like like you know like China
in China in Chinese people you know they
are Chinese people over the world but
mostly in China Taiwan and Hong Kong
these are you know three of the like
well-known especially among Westerners
but even this regard Westerners
Westerners you know there is a political
tension among us you know let's say
among the Chinese people and you know so
Hong Kong people I don't think they are
I mean they have issues I'm going to
tell you what okay but you know of
course then Hong Kong my I have
followers from Hong Kong and Taiwan and
China yeah like sometimes there are
things you'd rather not say because you
say it people you know doesn't like you
and you know that's kind of that's
that's what happens like like but I do
criticize Emax in this all the time even
though that's that is my community but
when is you know like is it's not
something you want to you know keep
talking about like okay Hong Kong what's
the problem you know the way I see you
know Hong Kong people they are
especially with Western influence you
know American the white people okay I'm
sorry you know that that's you know
they'd Hong Kong okay so the situation
is you know honk about 200 years ago or
150 years ago you know when UK United
Kingdom you know they invaded in the day
they abuse because they have more
powerful ships you know cannons and you
know sparkling ships so about 200 years
ago they you know the the key or Chinese
people whatever you know burn burn the
audience and day so China lost you know
because you know China was in a
situation for reasons that you know the
Western you know has the well-developed
you know science and technology more
advanced in China so they have you know
guns and ships so anyway China lost so
that Hong Kong you know they sign you
know agreement okay Hong Kong now
belongs to me
the UK the United Kingdom's is now Hong
Kong belongs to me
there you say no you say no I gonna kill
you no 1 billion you know two more
million of your people that's what
happens in war you know that's why you
sign these agreements you know it's not
it's not like you agree or not agree
so Hong Kong belongs to United Kingdom
you know so you know today's social
justice facts you know they hate America
they it's like you know so that's that's
that's kind of their thing to say you
know because oh the white people
colonies them nobody but but the thing
is you know human human animals
throughout history it's like that it's
not just white people it's not just you
know Chinese people Japanese Japanese
people or German people you know it's
like it just happens okay it just
happens the powerful you know take
advantage of the less and today like
today in USA the powerful are taking a
each of the less powerful who are these
powerful people they are the social
justice [ __ ] Google people you know
that the sea or whatever Google Facebook
you know and the Democratic Party that's
what that's that's what happened that's
that's you know that's what they are
doing the social and they seen the some
of just this they they they they are the
Nazis you know this is how nasty arise
you know they you know it's not like
nobody thought about nobody doesn't like
Evo you know everyone knows you know
what is evil but how did evil arise
throughout history you know how did evil
arise well they begin with singing the
good songs of helping people we are
helping we need to do this so so so that
you know everyone gets better that
that's you know they go by the songs of
morality that's what the social justice
can are doing today
so anyway Hong Kong you know you you
United Kingdom you know they took Hong
Kong and China is in a civil war very
bad you know the mobility then you know
one of the most popular didn't in the
American Civil War for example far more
bloody you know eating a Sybil so they
are in chaos so in you know let's say
around 1950s the white you know the UK
the phosphorus you know they they are
they like they own their own places
around the globe you know the you know
like like you know you wonder like let
me show you this okay I'm gonna just
talk about random things okay so what am
i doing okay I'm doing six people
watching guys say hi okay type it type
the stuff type it so let me show you
this this story I have okay sorry you
know code I'm kind of rambling over but
I'll get back to the topic about Hong
Kong Unicode Unicode stars okay let's go
to Saudi Unicode
click
am i doing okay like sometimes I you
know you you know a might you know poof
hi poof who can who can sue who can sue
typed hi hi who can sue that's is that a
Japanese name or Chinese name okay so
that's usually a Japanese name so let me
show you the you know there are flags of
the world let me show you the flags of
the world you know when I was young you
know any young people when you look at
you know sometimes like you like usually
you know when you are young you you look
at other flags of the world and when you
look at you know oh you know it's
colorful and you know very different and
you learn you know as teachers say you
learn geography oh you know education
you learn about the world but as a child
you look at the word you look at all the
flags you will notice you see many of
them share similar similar patterns okay
for example this not known to Northern
Europe they are all like that you know
cross yeah you can display Unicode in
Emacs sure you know linear for example
Unicode okay is my unicode page and
emoticons go to the emoticon page why is
it taking so long
okay so here is my emoticon page you can
view in browser so and you can and go
back to Emacs and you can see all the
emoticons you see so they are showing
inside Emacs yeah so let's go back to
the flags so when you look at the facts
you you notice that many of the flags
has this Union Jack you know this this
pattern of the United Kingdom flag is a
Union Jack you you notice
as a child okay you don't know anything
about politics politics but as a child
you know this many flags has these Union
Jack patterns let me show you you know
especially in was you know Oceana
you know countries like Australia and
Canada to actually who is it okay United
Kingdom related flags you know so so you
wonder you know like with like when you
are child obviously you'll notice this
what you know all these have a union
jacking it
why of course when you are adult you
know why because the United Kingdom they
go around they take places you know
that's what they that's what happens so
so back to the Hong Kong stuff you know
so United Kingdom they you know back in
the you know so-called imperialism
whether you know you know they took over
Hong Kong when China okay and China is
poor he is Hong Kong here's Taiwan China
was poor Hong Kong is living in comfort
I mean Hong Kong is rich you know United
Kingdom you know they they are you know
they are you know Hong Kong is an
important port you know a very critical
geographic location because you know
it's in other words it's critical you
know if military or for commercial you
know makes money for Hong United Kingdom
so anyway in United Kingdom is you know
has they got money they are comfortable
so so the people the Chinese people in
Hong Kong you know they are not citizens
by the way you know you you think oh you
know Hong Kong the you know democracy oh
the white people the democracy are great
you know we you know so Hong Kong people
are you you know have United Kingdom
citizens ship no not really
you are kind you're kind of second-rate
citizens
okay you are not you are still Chinese
you just have you live in Hong Kong but
anyway but but this is a good thing I
must say you know they the the the UK
people they did not you you are not
slaves okay you are not slaves in Hong
Kong so Chang
if you are Chinese in Hong Kong you are
not slaves but in fact you live in
comfort you know the Hong Kong speared
by UK you know you live in the comfort
of the Western prosperity you know
essentially pretty much means
materialistically you know you have
fancy cars so BMW the [ __ ] Hong Kong
people they love that you know there is
particularly love the status anything
that should show of status like like
Rolex watches you know Hong Kong people
love that you know big diamonds and they
love cruelty you know that is basically
any phenomenon that that contrasts or
shows the superior you know the the
superior you know the status the class
of above others Hong Kong people love
that not so much in America Americans
don't usually care about status they
mean I mean you have like billionaires
they you you can even tell you cannot
tell he's a beer here he just dressed
like you especially he tech nerds you
know this depends on the region some
regions some some countries they are
culture some country are highly status
conscious and one of the most high
status conscious people culture is
Chinese okay we Chinese you know very
status conscious so of Chinese people
you will often see them you know where
those you know very expensive watches
you know the reach you know very
expensive watch cars and so on and Hong
Kong is particularly Hong Kong so anyway
I was saying you know so UK took over
Hong Kong and Hong Kong people lives in
you know enjoys the Western
materialistic prosperity
okay so but why do I not like you know
Hong Kong people in general why do I
have a negative view here is why okay
you see it's like suppose you are you
you were born poor okay I'm gonna read a
comment sing a bit I can so you know
suppose you were born in a poor family
but then your brother lets you know then
let's say your brother got a adapted now
let's say you okay so suppose you you
were born in a very poor family you know
poverty you have to struggle to to to
eat you know hunger then you got adopted
you know let's say when when you are
five years old you got adopted by a rich
family so you are separated from your
family you are you know taking over you
know live in these rich family mansions
and houses you know spoons are made of
made of silver and gold you know silver
spoon so then when you are you know ten
you got a BMW you know you got fifteen
year you try fancy car you are very rich
the it that creates a psychological
situation in you okay because now your
parents is very rich you know your
adopted parents but they are not your
biological parents meanwhile you have
you still have your biological parents
but they are very poor so would you so
there's this is psychological conflict
when it comes to loyalty you know it
happened you know it happens suppose
your family or your adopted parents
doesn't like your biological parents
they got into a fight over something
let's say the question to you is who you
cannot support you know are you gonna
support your rich adopted family where
you you know who you see every day you
know you live in you know mansions and
you know
can have anything you want or are you
going to support your biological parents
who you haven't seen for you know four
years and you know that that's a
psychological conflict created in this
in such a situation and that is the
situation of the Chinese people in Hong
Kong okay I don't like them they they
are the the you know the you know you
cannot blame them totally I mean this is
just a situation it so happens so every
day they live under you know the UK rule
as the second rates you know the
second-class citizens you cannot you
cannot get a you cannot become a UK
citizen you know but however you have
you know you enjoy you know
materialistic prosperity and in general
the Hong Kong people they look down on
Chinese people back then not not today
is something different because China
becomes this huge you know prosperous
global economy you know sending people
to the you know space stations that's
you know China doing that now since like
2005 okay but back then let's say 1990s
you know 1980s even China is poor you
know like very poor but Hong Kong people
are very wealthy so they look down on
the change you know to the Chinese
people in China because you know they
are like you know did you just look down
on them and but also everyday newspapers
and you hear what you hear every day
since you were born the Hong Kong people
is the Western media you know the United
Kingdom they tell you what should be
what the word is how history are that's
what Hong Kong people had you know
that's what they are that's their
situation so I don't so you know so what
do you what you what can you do this is
what happens when you have this
situation you know can you blame you
know it's can you blame you know so I
don't like the in general the Hong Kong
people has this issue
okay I don't like them and then you know
so so it's like you have this kind of
identity crisis you know like the rich
parent analogy you know on one hand you
you you know you were born by these
parents who are very poor but but now
you live under these rich people you
know rich parent the rule you know who
are you going to be low your to that's
the problem you don't have the white
skin you know you don't have blue eyes
[ __ ] Hong Kong people you know I'm sorry
you know I have a lot of Chinese
followers who support me mostly it so
happens on mainland China I don't even
know them but you know and there are
some people like you know follow me on
for Emacs and stuff you know ongoing in
Taiwan so this is not something you know
when you say opinions like that you know
they don't like you anymore but but we
have to realize you know I'd that's just
people I mean that everyone is you know
this so what I'm saying okay so so
here's the thing so the thing so what
can you do about like in society in
living in life often there is a
situation where let's say you see
injustice you see some injustice going
on the question is are you going to
discuss it you know because if you
discuss it if this injustice happens on
someone else like outside of your circle
then sure you can you know you can you
know criticize it attack it no problem
but when this injustice happens to in
your community your brothers your family
your your your parents or whatever what
are you gonna do can you are you going
to expose it that's the problem so I
mean and and this is not just one of
problem this happens every day
everywhere
throughout history so the Hong Kong
situation is like what am I going to do
I mean am I going to you know stuff you
know oh shut up about that
you know that's you know that's not
really good thing you know you don't
that's not a good thing to do but also
you don't want to like you know like
make it a habit habit to to to tell
everyone know Hong Kong people is this
situation you know [ __ ] there [ __ ]
racist you know that so anyway so for
those of you who come people following
me you know that's just my opinion you
know that that's that's all okay so okay
George has to go so um difficult topic
for example how about all the immigrants
moved to the US yes yeah okay yeah so
actually so what else I'm gonna talk
about actually I think I already talked
about for 40 minutes okay we we still
have some time we can talk more talk
talk more okay so guys seven people
watching whoever you are say something
it will increase the colour of this talk
show and I'm going to drink this massive
may curtain one Megaton of juice what
what use is this I don't know what juice
orange orange juice no this is orange
plus purple
so Hong Kong people you know
and of course with the nameless brand of
Red Bull essentially concentrated
caffeine so Hong Kong people oh yeah
that's that's Hong Kong but I was going
to give you a introduction to the
Silicon Valley for those of you outside
so are you guys in USA or ken are you a
USA good morning bathroom you bathroom
you you missed how appointment last time
okay so you were not feeling well okay
[Laughter]
so bathroom you actually so on the day
on that day I talked about the meaning
of symbolic languages and it turns out
it turned out well so you might check it
out two videos one is you know so like
two days ago two videos you know one day
and the next day so that's about the
meaning of symbolic languages and the
and about this syntax so I think you
might check it out but I didn't get
exactly what are you interested like
what are you what kind of programming
you are programmer right what kind of
programming you do and what kind of you
know type it you know let me know
because I'm a probably will forget but I
mean that the point is just you know I
will remember you know at least some of
it you know like type opinions topics so
we can talk about things so anyway so
here's USA and USA okay I'm going to do
a introduction to the geography of USA
something like that but sabbatical meal
you are in Germany Germany right yeah
okay so you are in Germany and
ken are you in u.s. or not because if
you guys are in u.s. then you know it
does is not worthwhile to talk about us
but but usually farming countries like
whoever you are the the places you you
know outside you don't know you don't
know like a lot of people for example
Chinese people they wouldn't know you
know like often they wouldn't know where
is our a or where San Francisco they
just know you know it's USA so anyway on
the on the west you know you have East
Coast here west coast this interesting
you know okay East Coast West Coast and
you have what's called Midwest this is
like you know actually over here it's
called Midwest and this is a southern
USA you are interested in California so
um so let me give you the comments
okay oh you you are in pa pa is
Pennsylvania right you know like around
2005 a friend a white guy you know he's
like 10 years older than me
mm 50 so he's a philosopher he century a
philosopher with the you know certified
philosopher and he so he took me right
we ride we rode from Sacramento you know
West Coast here all the way to
Pennsylvania because he is moving there
so it's a five days right
actually it's a good thing to do you
know if you are American you know if you
live in USA it's good thing to do it you
know like once so you get to see you
know it takes about five days to drive
from east coast to coast to coast
and then you get to see you know you you
drive for like 16 hours and you you stop
at a hotel motel you know you sleep over
then you drive again you know lunch
dinner you eat you know along the road
so it's a good thing to do so you get to
see you know over the you know places
you know earth not just USA but earth
part of the earth but USA in general USA
the culture of USA is not very basically
you have the coast you know you have the
west coast you have the east coast then
you have the kind of certain which is
kind of this area you know the
north-south area so what I am is saying
what's my point
so anyway so it's interesting to go
through anyway here over here is Silicon
Valley is so called Silicon Valley you
know so here's San Francisco all these
areas here are where
basta that's called San Francisco Bay
Area's so this area is called San
Francisco Bay area and you see all those
you see all these yellow roads very busy
so so this is Silicon Valley all the
companies school goes here
Google PayPal Facebook uber Amazon
Amazon is actually not here headquarter
is not here but IBM Apple is all here so
that's why it's called you know
basically 90% of all the online
companies they began here and mostly are
still here it's called silly Silicon
Valley so I'm here martin view so let me
show you
so Palo Alto Mountain View Google is
right here Google is here you see the
Googleplex
so Googleplex is like 30 minutes 40
minutes walk from my house so all the me
it's like like all over me if I go
outside or me it's Google buildings you
know they have buildings over all over
the place and Google employees you know
when I see a Google programmer like oh
he will get the Google expect like you
know [ __ ] idiot you know this today you
know not not so not so let's say back in
let's say 2000 to 2010
so better path Romeo says what makes you
one of the most interesting streamers is
that you talk about a lot of different
topics but you don't repeat the
mainstream [ __ ] everyone else is saying
yeah you have your own opinions which
are interesting too okay
hello Abdo so Ken so have you ever been
to California so today is very hard
California is a sunny state you know
because because it doesn't rain here
like it like every in a year it rain
rains only like three times
seriously it's always sunny and good
weather no rain can you tell us some
interesting places you visit in SV
Silicon Valley
oh I mean interesting for a computer
geek well that depends on what you mean
because actually as far as I'm concerned
this nothing interesting you know I've
been living here for like 30 years since
well 19 in 1989 I came to where I am
right now the base Mountain View ok so
in 1989 I came from here Montreal Canada
here you see so I I flew here in 1989 I
arrived at you know Sunnyvale actually
and basically since I lived around this
area I also lived actually I lived in
illinois's in 1995 for half a year I
don't know here champagne Obama
Champaign Illinois
that's where wolfen research is a
it's somewhere here okay Nashville
Memphis st. Louis okay Indy Indiana
Indianapolis
so where is the champagne it's a small
college town where University of
Illinois is at but anyway is somewhere
here so champagne here you know it was
so I lived there for half a year in 1995
yes and I also lived in Maryland for
like four months
because this is because I had a
girlfriend interesting story in the
2000s Maryland so can you tell us
something interesting to visit in
California that that really depends on
what like like are you looking for place
for fun to visit for or not yeah again I
cannot like I actually III I cannot
think of anything because actually you
know where I live there is a very famous
computer Museum Mountain View here
computer museum right here so I you know
so a lot of people visit there and I
went there a couple of times and
sometimes on Twitter or social network
you can see people you know posting
photos like come you know just search
for computer museum Mountain View but
so I go there I didn't really actually
find it interesting you know because
usually these kind of museum places you
know they they are designed to attract
the masses you know the average people
the people who don't know anything about
computers who doesn't know anything
about computer science engineering that
that kind of people
so this museum you know for children you
know children which is a popular you
know audience of these museums so one
consequence of that is the museum you
know the way they exhibit things is
usually like it's like water that
watered down and or made it more
dramatic you know usually usually not
interesting although but the old
computers you can still see so for us
you know programmers we go there you
know we want to see you know there are
see storico computers right so you go
there you want to see them all but
usually it's like it's not there like
only only one of the thing is there then
and you cannot see details and they have
all these explanations you know for for
for the common people like incorrect
explanations or things like that you
know you know it's like a tourist place
you know it's almost like a you know so
I don't really enjoy this
you know museum kind of thing oh there's
a intell museum here I didn't know so
Intel is here and you know you know
Netscape was is here
you know Nestle Mozilla is also here
anyway so so interesting places to visit
you know and also I don't go out much
almost not at all so
you know in my life the number of times
I've visited you know Paso dance club
maybe once once in ten years that's
probably about right yeah I visited
clubs or bars you know maybe five times
in my life I'm 50 years old and when I
go to you know about I get extremely
nervous you know you know like I don't
know what to do so but the bars and you
know dance clubs a lot of people most
you know no more people enjoy so you
have to ask them you know dance clubs
you know they tell you things like that
oh and by the way San Francisco of
course is known for strip clubs that is
girls taking off their clothes naked and
spread their legs in front of your face
like like two inches you know and in San
Francisco you know the you know the the
heart of the social justice can and it's
on this O'Hara's streets you know
Broadway I think Broadway yeah that's
you know you can go there everyone goes
you know that's the as you know as a
traveler or you know it's a local you
know you go there so I'm interesting for
computer geek yeah so I don't know I
don't be so well I there's one thing I
know I mean if you are a computer
programmer and you haven't been to here
before of course one thing you want to
do is you want to look at the buildings
of headquarters of all the famous
corporations like Google Facebook ok
Google is here I can tell you like
Facebook is somewhere here in Mill River
City uber is in San Francisco lots of
them
Apple is down here IBM is also here so
they are Maps you know they say oh there
you have pictures or the oh these
companies you can you will be
interesting to me if I you know he if
I'm here the first time I would look at
these companies just just look at you
know what their building looks like you
know that that that would be interesting
to me
are they are many meetup in for promise
in Silicon Valley yeah of course
thousands actually yesterday two days
ago we just went to a meet-up Emax
meetup in Mountain View thanks to the
Jeff guy and I met John Wiggly who is
the current maintainer or leader of the
Emacs goona Emacs so if you just search
for Emacs meet a San Francisco
they are meet up every day meet up every
day around this area every day thousands
like Ruby Ruby meetups python-based
Crowe show you know whatever technology
it is programming languages every
everyday
Oh essentially every day and you can
start one yourself
so Emacs meet up San Francisco
so you guys a lot you know you know
check it out so he you know it's good it
started by this Jeff guy Jeff troll guy
and he I met him several times by now I
met in your four or five times and he's
he's very nice guy there is you know
smooth and you know kind guy so you know
so check check check it out you know
Emax meet up so Jeff yeah so he's the
he's a guy who began yet I I think so
anyway you know just search for Emacs
meetup San Francisco they have they have
meet up every month I think at least
every month sometimes in San Francisco
sometimes in in Mountain View you know
so anything else
type type types of Abdo Abdo wait where
you from
so I've been talking for yeah okay so
I've been talking for an hour so we are
going to I think that's about it
Silicon Valley so the word is a big
phrase you know and today we are in this
AI era you know so what is a proper term
for our era you know you used to be info
era in the 90s you know info era or you
call it digital era there's no fixed
term by the way this this you know how
these terms arouse this so usually it's
due to how people use it you know it
anyway so or you can call it today we
have a basically I think it's a proper
to call it AI era today because
specifically in the past 10 years you
know let's say starting from 2010 this
artificial intelligence thing or mostly
machine learning data mining machine
learning it it there's an exponential
growth in since 2010 and there are
significant impact to the world I mean
we cannot actually see it right now but
I you know it's it's it's it's pretty
big and you know I don't know it's going
to be good or bad you know that's a big
question you know
so okay so I think that's maybe that's
it what what else
greetings from Ozzie have a great day
sir
cat 44 where is Ozzie Wizard of Oz what
else so you know code okay so yeah
that's so that's it for today so Sheen
to Australia Oh Ozzie is from Australia
let's see
Ozzie well I it seems that there are a
lot people coming from Australia you
know I didn't know anything about
Australia before it's like you know
before let's say 2016 okay it's like
okay well yeah this Australia where you
have these animals must move Oh kangaroo
you know and you have kiwi fruit that's
almost like oh I know about Australia
but since 2016 oh oh see oh see is a
slang for Australia oh I didn't know
but since since 2016 the social justice
you know stuff is on the news every day
you know like every day oh this is a
feminism oh you know trans rights you
know every day and riots you know that's
but that is where I learned about
Australia a lot more because they are
real then you know on the news like
feminism
yeah feminism stuff everyday feminism
this this this that they they I heard I
learned a lot about Australia for
example there is this girl a woman who
began the rillette
website which is which is a perk you
know but he they publish articles
usually you know trying to fight the
social justice people
she is from Australia you know so you
see since 2016 you know it's like all of
a sudden I read news then I learned I
learned a lot of things about Australia
you know then and then may I realize you
know feminism stuff it's pretty bad you
know the social justice scan is very bad
in Australia you know like even more so
than USA and also in Canada it's pretty
bad you know like they they also do
censorship and stuff you know that
that's that I guess that's a negative
thing about Australia then you know
that's that's that's how you know that's
just the that's just the fact you know
that's how I've heard a lot about
Australia since 2016 day and then a lot
of you guys it it turns out a lot for
some reason I don't know you know
watching my youtube are from Australia
and many of them are from Perth I didn't
know that Perth so Perth is apparently a
big city and also I made this girl she
is amazing she is also in Perth not in
person but Hawaii so yeah
Australia so it's a it's pretty big you
know it's a big country you know of you
guys who are in Australia you are
probably you know whatever what I'm
saying is probably city to you like hey
all wrong what's that
hold on a second let me show you then
then there is this country's Papa New
Guinea and then there is this New
Zealand you know through the news you
learn this places like the New Zealand
is known for this king.com guy who is a
scumbag I believe you know in my opinion
I think he's pretty much just come back
he's a billionaire but he become rich by
basically by pirate pirating you know on
the surface they say you know he say Oh