good morning
good morning guys
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
so today i'm going to do a wolfram
language tutorial on wolfram language
graphics system so it's a full
introduction
and no random chat so if you have any
questions about wufam language ask me
okay hello guys hello dion and sv jack
and so
so wolfram language graphics system so
let me show you what they are okay so
introduction to
um
so wufam language graphics system so let
me show you a you know just uh example
of graphics so for example these are
wolfram language you know these graphics
are created in language that's a wolfram
language logo actually and graphics like
that uh let me see i want to just
quickly show some images
geometric inversion wu from language
code
okay so yeah i did a video about this so
here are some examples of wolfram
language graphics and let me just show
show you one of them okay for so for
example this one
then i'm going to give you an
introduction
let's start with
introduction to all the basically
introduction to the woofing graph
graphics how do you plot pie chart
function plots and so on so
so we have a wolfram language uh
launched so let's evaluate it so you can
see now that let's magnify 150
okay so you can see that's a
two-dimensional graphics this is a
graphics you program
uh
uh you know so here is the source code
you can see
let's make it into uh
you know control
uh let's make that let's render them
into the you know two-dimensional uh
uh math formula so you can see so this i
will find graphics and uh
okay let's evaluate it again so
two-dimensional graphics these are the
things you program
and uh
oh let's let's show a 3d version okay so
3d version is here
so two two-dimensional graphics and now
three-dimensional graphics
so you can see we generated this thing
this is a kind of inversion and also
shrink them okay so that's an example
and
and i want to rip the hoodie comfy no
more okay so i want to um
so wu from
ufam language
and wufong language is now free
you can just get it by
just search for wufam language you know
free will from language engine or you
can
go to um
sas talk show
and i have article just search for study
wolfram language free so you can
download it free and i have explanations
on what's ruffian language what's
mathematica what's the wolfram engine
what's the wolfram script their
differences and so on
so you can read about them and then i
also have tutorials on uh language you
can read them
later so today uh it's going to be uufam
language graphics okay
so the topics i'm we i want to uh talk
about so introduction you know from
language get it for free
then jupiter okay so once you download
wufang language uh for free the wolfram
engine
you do not have this interactive the
notebook okay so but you can also get
that free by going into the wufang
language uh
let me magnify the wolfram language is
github so you have a notebook for
jupyter so you can download that
then with wolfram engine you can plot
woofam graphics in the uh jupiter
notebook it's all free okay
so that's about that so now the next
topic so okay so now i'm going to
introduce you uh the wolfram language
graphics so first of all ufam language
has like 7 000 functions building so for
example you can list all the um
functions just by typing that
then you get you know a very long list
of 7000 functions building no need to
load any libraries you know whenever you
need to do something you know so this is
an endless scroll seven thousand of them
and for example if you want to know if
you want to plot something you just type
question mark star plot question mark
uh shift enter so you got all
basically all functions that contains
the word plot so all these are building
functions that
lets you plot something
uh absolute arc plot you can click on
that
and it gives you the documentation text
and you click on that
then you can see examples and so on so
this is a plotting absolute value
functions for example
uh so you have let's let's show some
interesting ones okay region plot probab
probability plot that's probably what
you are interested
um
dion
so
so this is probability plot uh let's
magnify okay
uh and uh i mean i want to show you
something 3d okay so plot 3d
plot parametric plot 3d okay let's try
that let's just say let's just show
something fancy okay that's okay okay
okay let's try this one so we have a
linked torus
so you paste the code here
press ctrl shift
s i believe to get into standard
standard form okay that doesn't that
doesn't
do much anyway so evaluate it so you got
a linked torus so you can see
this is a parametric plot so you give it
the first argument is a vector
the second the vector of three
components
so actually you got more than one
equations i mean you got more than
you got nested vectors so this is a
vector this is
so this part
this part is x the function for x value
x this part is function for y
this part is function for z
so this
so let me let me let me just show you
okay so
so you want to cut that
and paste it
okay so wait
so let's just cut
copy that
and put it here so we just only plot one
of them so you see
that's a formula for taurus
so parametric plot 3d this function
allows you to plot multiple parametric
formulas in one shot so in this image
essentially you are seeing
yeah you are seeing two parametric
formulas so let's
so you can see
this is the first parametric formula
this is the second parametric formula
they are actually the same they are just
the taurus but oriented in a different
way so the third argument is a you know
the variables the range u from 0 to 2 pi
and v from 0 to two pi so if we adjust
that we're gonna see a gap so for
example zero two six you see a gap there
so that's so parametric plot so all
these are building functions
that you know that that contains the
word plot
so if you want to plot a function in 2d
in 3d let's say plot sign okay let me
show you some quick examples
so i'm
so after this then i'm going to tell you
how about a tutorial about woofing
graphics primitives that is how are
these made so you can actually
you know as a programmer you may want to
plot turtle graphics or whatever
uh you know let's say a lot rectangles
oriented in certain way forming a spiral
or whatever so that's you know
programming graphics so you can do that
but you don't have a function for it i
mean that's not mathematics you know so
so
all these are building functions usually
to do uh some sort of standard
mathematical graphics including pie
chart
but then i'm gonna talk about how do
these graphics actually work so you can
actually write programs to plot
arbitrary anything so let me show a
demonstration of plot and let me
demonstrate a pie chart okay
very common
pie chart okay so let's do that and
let's also do pie chart 3d
okay so plot
for example sine
x
x from 1 to 10 okay
so that's a basic uh
plot okay
and
let's say
plot
um okay let's say pie chart then
pie chart
now pie chart all you have to do i
believe just give a bunch of values
let's say 3
1 okay let's do it you see
pie chart you know how high level it is
because you have three things three ten
one and it just shows that and then you
can add labels okay then you can add
labels like option
like uh label
label style label size labeled label you
know and uh you know
then you look up for the documentation
for the label and how do you um
anyway i'm not going to go into it so
i'm going to talk about it later how do
you add options to plot so each one of
these building you know these
few hundred building functions to plot
they have a they have lots of options
that lets you control the lighting the
orientation the viewpoint the color on
the surface
uh the
parameters the the lines the great lines
whether you want them or you don't want
them or the color of the grid lines or
lots of things or clips you know
like you don't want you don't want to
show the whole toast you only only want
to show half of it
you know so each one of these hundreds
building functions they have lots of
options and the the way you find the
option is actually
just type this function options then
give it uh
let's say pipe let's say pie chart okay
yeah so let's try to add the labels so
options pie chart so that gives you uh
am i doing okay so video check voice
check yes
so that so options then pie chart that
give you gives you all the options for
the pie chart okay so for example
uh let's say chart labels
okay um
well actually the best way is simply
just go to uh pie charts documentations
there you will see so you know you are
looking at pie chart documentation
then you'll see a lot of um
you know we want labels so there it is
okay
so that's one of the ways you can do
labels
so pie chart so what is this okay this
is
this is actually
a bit complex nested pie charts okay i
don't want that i just want one simple
one pycharm okay so actually
cut that
let's put the label here
delete that okay
there there you have it abc pie chart
so
options okay so you type options and the
function name it will it will give you
return order options for the function
then for each one of them you can just
look it up you know you can just
move your mouse there and you can see
the you know how to use the option like
what does it do so this one is base
style yeah okay base style is new but um
anyway options okay
so next let's move on to next thing so
plot 3d so did we so we showed pie chart
we showed uh what about pie chart 3d
okay so let's let's show example of pie
chart 3d
uh it's
it's probably going to be similar to the
pie chart okay so let's just
do that
and instead of pie chart let's just say
3d okay
evaluate okay you got fantastic you
could you got a 3d version of pie chart
fantastic this is much that
python or javascript you got 100 lines
you know trying to figure out how to do
things
you know this is
extremely um high level because pie
chart you know
let's say bar chart okay let me explain
how because i tried you know i've been i
have
wrote graphics for this kind of thing
and it's not
you know it seems so simple the concept
is very simple pie chart so you have
several like distributions you know
several
values so
when you actually want if you want to
create a graphics for this manually you
you you know of course it involves sine
cosine parametric you know sine cosine
functions you want to figure out how
much of a pie it is
then you have two
lots of problems then the font size it's
the font size it's in svg for example
that's a huge headache so you spend uh
you know
tens of hours to figure out how how to
you know the point is to show them
nicely that's the that is the
non-trivial part you know you can any
high school student or if you are
college computer science you can create
a pie chart easily but to create some
plot such that the size the viewpoint
the range is all figured out for you
that takes several years of coding to
get it to work
so anyway so let's uh let's move on to
the next thing so because i got lots of
things to explain
okay plot 3d is an example that's a good
to show so let me show you another
building function okay
plot 3d sine cosine okay let's let's say
sine
uh let's get let's show something fancy
okay
uh let's
it's not
okay so we got
let's say six two six
this uh fancy graphics okay i did this i
did this like back in 1990s 1992 is when
i started to use wufam language in code
uh wufang language
so let me summarize so out of the box
you have few hundred plotting functions
now this
the functions whose name contains the
word plot they are typically
they are typically plotting mathematical
functions
so all these for example complex array
plot you know they are related to
mathematics okay but oftentimes you
don't have a function such as pie chart
such as uh you know pie chart such as
bar chart
you know bar chart which is not a
function you just have a list of numbers
such as uh
let's say bar chart 3d
uh
you know and uh
sector chart i'm not sure what is sector
okay sector chart
uh
you know so my point is many many
some often times you want to plot that's
not a function you don't have a function
so what you do for example in data
science in artificial intelligence
research in neural networks you want to
plot something that's not a function
so
so let me show you so you can so let me
show you some of those building
functions so you you just search for
wufam language documentation you'll find
there's a section on
[Music]
let's turn on javascript
okay so there's a section there are many
sections you know what
one of the sections visualization and
graphics okay so that's one of them
and
that's all about graphics okay so
and then
there's a section on geometry that's
kind of related
there's a section on graphs and networks
graphs here means like
networks like nodes and lines you know
um
stefan wolfham's block they have tons of
graphs involving thousands of knots you
know because he's trying to come up with
a theory that models the universe
so anyway wufang language
has
hundreds of building functions so part
of them is just mathematical functions
so you click on you go to the wolfram
language website you click on functional
function visualization under the
visualization and graphics section so
you click on that function visualization
so you see here
all these functions are about
plotting basically mathematical
functions parametric plot plot
parametric formula
complex
functions
discrete functions discrete plot 3d
they are very fun to use okay and stream
plot vector plot for example when you
see
when you have uh graphics for weather
this usually comes up
okay so for example you can just copy
the code and
paste it right here
uh
plot layout rule so that's unknown
okay we found a bug
yep we found a bug in wolfram
documentation so the plot layout
is apparently obsolete or something so
let's let's see what's going on
yeah plot layout wait plot layout is
there
layout is an option for plotting
functions okay so why is it not
maybe it doesn't support raw okay so
let's remove that
okay so you got a
you know wolfram calls this stream plot
okay which is somewhat different from
the more
well-known vector plot okay so for
example you can see vector plot here
this is more where we're uh kind of more
uh understood you know more well-known
vector plot
so
okay so the point is you know
hundreds of
building functions
some of them
do
plot mathematical functions it's math
oriented now what about the other parts
so the other part for example you can
have you know such as pie chart and so
on so you go to data visualizations so
here you got list plot
you got list step plot
you got stacked list plot
let's see so that's a stacked list plot
let's go back
so
list plot 3d
so this one is similar to a surface
plotting a surface but instead of a
function like normally in programming or
data science you don't have a nice
function
unless you do linear regression or
something
so you don't have functions but you just
have like
tens of thousands of data so in that
case you use you know things like list
plot 3d
so
so all these functions are for
you know kind of you know just plotting
data
okay then okay so then there's a graph
we mentioned about so there's a graph
plot for example these are very fun to
look at graph
so regular so these are um so what are
these graphs these are i've
i don't remember what they are called
this is a tree actually okay so anyway
so
let's show some examples okay
uh let's show some do they have uh fancy
examples and
now they don't i want to show something
really interesting okay maybe that
i mean i want to show something fancy
uh got example data so this means it's
it's downloading from the net i don't
like that
okay but it's it's a fun result so
wolfram language is
you know many
several functions they for example this
example data they actually go through
the woofam cloud you know
somewhat like the wolfram alpha they go
to the wolfram cloud they grab the data
because there are tons of data like
geographic data statistical data about
population
you cannot have them all in language you
know so you need to get you know go to a
database to get the
demographic info or statistical info
about countries or what about atoms
about chemistry you know so on so this
example data gets that data then you
just
use graph plot to do it so graph plot
you can see
it's fairly general uh
let's try it again let's go to the help
the documentation
so graph plot generates a plot of the
graph g oh okay so it you feed it a
graph you know graph as a network then
it plots the graph
yeah okay so okay so that's graph plot
and uh can you
you cannot rotate it but
but there's a graph plot 3d
okay so let's try that
you know so we are experimenting
let's say graph plot 3d
so let's see what you get oh
fantastic now it's this is beautiful
fantastic
beautiful lovely
okay so
so we were talking about building
functions uh so they are so you
go to wufang language documentation
center then there's a section
visualization and graphics and you'll
see all about it so you know we only
covered like the top two of them so
there's also
visualization related to
geographics for example plotting earth
so let's try one of them a vector earth
plot okay so these are
these kind of functions are
happened in the last 15 years
which i wasn't
using from
much at that time
so anyway
so this is about plotting you know uh
earth geographic related plot
then there's a dynamic visualization
which allows you to manipulate
such as like animation you know like
animation for you can create a slider
and you can adjust the slider in real
time the graph will change so such as uh
useful for for example parameters
polynomials and so on
so okay so but
i want to get on to uh onto how to how
they work okay how do you program them
so
so i think i just finished the basic
introduction so
so if you want to help know
how these graphics will from language
work you go to this section symbolic
graphics language okay that's what they
call it
symbolic graphics language so this is
actually what i'm going to uh talk about
i'm going to show you
two for example in svg so for example in
svg so let me show you
you know you if you are a programmer you
javascript you probably know about svg
svg is very simple for example if you
want to um
oh
wait i need to turn on javascript
what
uh there is something wrong oh my svg
doesn't work anymore
what
because for example here is supposed to
show a circle what's going on
uh i'm going to read the comments in a
bit okay
so let's see
okay something wrong with my code
what's going on because my svg
for some reason anyway so svg you know
you probably know about svg for example
you can write a clock
you can write a clock in svg and here's
a code so basically all you have to say
is where do you want to draw a circle
where do you want to draw a line what
color it should be how thick it is you
know that's
so you basically put together a bunch of
suv svg graphics primitives you know
like the primitives specify their
position color and then you have it so
wufam language is pretty similar so you
have a bunch of graphics primitives and
it applies to all of these you you have
seen so behind them for example this one
you just have uh
thousands of
points
they say you know lines connect
connect lines through points
and the position where you place them in
the arrowhead and things like that
so it's programming graphics
okay so let's move on to the next thing
so we talked about 36 minutes already
okay so
uh let's move on to uh next thing
so
okay so i need to work on that let's go
back to talk show
let's see what's the next thing i need
to talk about yeah so explain graphics
primitives in 2d
and in 3d okay
okay so so now the you know the
beginning of the new section i'm going
to show you how how the graphics works
okay so
the
so there are two type of uh graphics
primitives primitives one is 2d
two-dimensional one is 3d let's do 2d
first so you have a circle for example
okay
let's magnify
okay so you have a circle and circle uh
basically it works like this okay so you
you want to give it a center and the
radius so centered at one and one
and radius two okay that's a graphics
primitive so you can look at the
documentation
oh i mean i misspelled it
c-a-r-c-l-e
okay yeah circle okay there it is
now you can look at the documentation
there's a documentation
so circle is one of the
graphics primitives so if you want
actually
if you want it to be drawn what you say
is you say graphics
okay you you wrap the graphics function
around it so inside it you give it a
list
then just say circle
okay there you have a circle then we can
add the axis let's say
x is true okay
so you cannot see the axis
uh let me show you some of the options
for example grid
lines okay gridlines
automatic so now it will draw grid
okay
so
the point here is about graphics
primitives so now let's say let's let's
add another circle okay
so this one will be centered
will be radius one okay
do it
there you have it
now let's say this one is centered at
zero zero
okay so you got it now let's remove the
grid lines because they are confusing
okay so you got circles then you can
have lots of circles so for example
let's say
um
let's do a table okay let's let me show
you okay
table
table is similar to python's
list comprehension
okay
that's
in language that's table this function
table it allows you to build
any sort of list or nested list okay the
way you do it is you give it uh let me
show you okay
table x x from 1 to
okay so you got 1 to 20. now you can say
x squared
okay you got squared 1 220 and this can
be any expression so you can be x
squared plus y for example
okay so you got you know it can be any
expression and in in this case let's put
we want a circle we we want lots of
circles okay
so let's do
circle
centered around
uh let's say
x x okay
let's make it into a line well let's
make it into
x increase y remains on zero okay so
radius one
okay
so you got one bunch of circles
now you say
my
graphics okay equals to
that okay
now you just say graphics
okay you got a lot of circles
now let's add axes
x is true
okay so you got
okay now let's let's reduce these one
two five one one two three
in steps of
0.5
okay
okay instead of 0.1
now
evaluate this again so you got lots of
circles
uh we can make the circle go around so
and let's uh shall we try it yeah we can
try it but um
[Music]
okay let's try it
it wouldn't involve too much code
so i'm showing you some of the power of
wolfram language so let's circle so we
want circle
x and y
of radius one and x goes from
x goes uh we want it to go around um
yeah that's
yeah we can do it but let's not do it
because i want to cover other things
okay so the point here the main point is
about graphics primitives this is how
you do them so circle is one graphics
primitives
a primitive so you give it it takes two
arguments
center and a radius
if they are omitted
basically ufam will pick a smart choice
you know if you omit the center or if
you emit the radius the center will be
zero zero on our engine and the radius
will be one okay
so circle is a primitive
primitive graphics primitive and if you
want to show it all you have to do is
wrap the graphics
function
you know so the graphics the graphics is
a function
that takes
arguments the arguments are graphics
primitives so here's the documentation
for graphics
you can see they show you several
examples
okay now what are the other graphics
primitives for example lying okay
so uh so so
so okay let's so let's do let's do it
let's do it
so line
so let's say so line takes uh
arguments let's say
from zero zero or engine to
one one
let's say
let's say two one okay
so from zero zero to one two one so it's
kind of like that
okay so show it
oh you need it takes one argument you
need to put the whole thing inside the
list
okay so you got a
line is another primitive
graphics primitive and now let's add
axis
okay so you can see your line and
similar you know you can have lots of
lines so this so this is how graphics
are made up
at least for the two-dimensional
graphics you have lots of graphics
primitives so now let me show you so
where do you see the list of all
primitives
so you go to um
[Music]
let's go to the website let's go back to
the website
let me show you where the
the graphics primitives are
so you go to the visualization section
symbolics graphics language
then
okay so now they call it object
instead of primitives you know early you
know from 1990s to 2000s the proper name
for these are called 2d and 3d graphics
primitives
but now
you know for example we have shown a
circle you know we have shown point and
line for ex we have shown circle and
line for example this is line
um
it was called yeah so this is still
called graphic experiment
so okay so here is a list of 2d and 3d
objects okay yeah some of them can also
be used for 3d okay so you also for 3d
you also have sphere cube so let me show
some 3d and let's move on i wanna you
know let's move on to other uh
let's show sphere okay so wait
um
let's show cuboid okay cuboid is classic
okay cuboid
cuboid is just a cube basically a
rectangle a rectangle shape in 3d
so
you need to specify two corners
i'm pretty sure so let's do
zero zero zero the other corner is let's
say zero two one okay
okay so now let's
graphic graphics 3
graphics 3d and
put down that
okay so you got a cube but this is a
degenerate case because we got
oh you need to specify three corners
that's right
so let's say another corner
uh
three two one
oh wait not three
okay i
it's probably
like that let's
okay
yeah
three two
four so
you need three
corners to specify a cuboid nah
okay let's look at the documentation
p mean p max uh
okay p mean p max two arguments okay
so
we got two arguments here oh yeah so
that's a proper one we got a degenerate
case before so there it is so cuboid is
one of the graphics primitives a
three-dimensional
type
okay now let's go back so
so that's about graphics so remember now
here's an important thing to remember
all wolfram language all the graphics
you see in mathematica
all of them any any and all fancy of uh
whatever you have seen
uh where is my wolfram notebook
let's see
okay so any any of these two-dimensional
or three-dimensional any graphics they
are made up of graphics primitives just
like
what we have shown you know like
thousands thousands of them
and they are either they either have a
head graphics or graphics 3d okay
graphics is a representation for
two-dimensional graphics and the 3d
graphics 3d is a function to represent
any three-dimensional so all any woofah
language graphics is made of that
internally
so
when you use a building function for
example let's say you know for example
this
uh um example let's say three two three
okay let's make
so plot 3d you know
any build in function when they plot a
graph
what they are doing is internally is
that they are just generating lots of
these graphics primitives for you
you know then it shows the result so
this plot 3d
is a building function to do graphics
okay but however you can write this
yourself you can
because that's what
it does okay
now the next thing okay that's that
completes my coverage for
how the woofing graphics works so you
got you got graphics primitives and you
got graphics and graphics
uh 3d to show them
okay now let's move on let me move on to
the next topic
which is about how
kind of how some of these building
functions actually generate the graphics
like how does it actually do it
okay so that's the next topic so let me
read the um comments a bit
and uh and so we talked about 15 minutes
yeah so another
another 15 minutes uh
should finish okay so
we covered a lot
yeah so the next thing i want to explain
how building 2d part works
then that's about it okay
do you have a direct comparison of
mathematica versus python you mean the
language or you mean the whole
mathematical package you know if you are
talking about i mean in either case
there's no comparison i mean python it
is no nothing no language
can compare
with language
now if you wanna it's possible okay
so if you want to compare okay i'm
starting to digress but
let me do it for one minute
so if if you want to compare one
programming language to firm language
there's nothing nothing whatsoever comes
even close
in terms with respect to how high level
it is
so wufang language is one line of code
in python it's ten to a hundred or two
to a million literally because when you
do
when you do some of these
you know for example this one even this
one
you know you all you have to do is just
say graphics 3d
graph plot 3d that's one single function
what does what does it take
when you have a bunch you know this data
is just a bunch of list of numbers what
does it take to
to implement this well i mean if you are
experienced it'll take you a year you
know how many how many lines of code is
that
in python
i mean in python you can't even do it
without a graphics library so you you
know you you load some you know graphics
library but how many lines of code in
python for this
what do you think
a thousand two you know a thousand we a
thousand lines of python code we are not
you know the thing is you have to know
it figures out lots of things for you
you know like do they include the color
here i mean how do i know if you know
you want this blue i don't think the
example data includes color okay so
let's show let's see what is this
example data
okay so it's got
2480 elements okay so it's a smart array
so it's basically a matrix okay
uh
let's let's normalize okay
uh let's i'm gonna do it quickly without
explanation
uh
yeah okay anyway
so
in order to have this single function in
python it would be two thousand three
thousand lines okay now so what i'm
saying is that there's no language one
single language any of haskell or
whatever fancy closure whatever fancy
language that
that is comparable to wufang language in
terms of high levelness okay
in other words in other words one wolf
in language is equals to 10 or 100 or a
thousand or a million of these
you know other languages so that's one
part now the other part so no language
comes close that's why you have to pay
you know you have to pay woofam to buy
it
uh but it's free it's free the woofen
language engine is free
on the other hand you know today with
the open source
community it's very big right google is
pushing for open source google is
releasing you know neural networking
neural network open source you know
machine learning open source libraries
in python in c plus plus you know with
python front end you know
interface so
open source community is very big they
they also have millions millions of
lines so in that case you compare for
example the
you know there's a python package called
um
yeah let me talk about this because a
lot of people are interested
so i know a friend told me about a
python anacondra package you know this
package
this thing you know you download this
thing this thing is like two gigabytes
okay so it's it's python plus plus
tens of all the libraries you need for
for machine learning for data science
for everything like everything together
comes in two gigabytes you download it
preview for you you know that's this is
open source project okay
so including i believe they include
graphics you know include data science
numpy or whatever
i i don't use it much i haven't used it
much okay so you can download this
then this thing
i suppose you can compare to wufang
language but i would say i mean
yeah yeah i would say wufang language is
just much superior okay so but i don't
actually have experience with it i know
you know i don't ever actually have
experience with this so
i can say for sure but from my
experience with you know in in the past
20 years coding
i wouldn't say it's
close to comparison okay
okay so what are your computer spec uh
you know to pay chat okay so uh what
wi-fi plan like what
i'm gonna only talk about wufam language
related things okay
only used for math and such it's used in
engineering okay
engineering by scientists by
mathematicians by physicists
and by data scientists okay so today
since 10 years ago you know the machine
learning stuff
a lot of programming involves now
mathematics statistics probability
theory so that's
so
so the programmers start to need to use
you know things like wolfram language at
google you know google nasa
they are other uh
big users
and basically researchers not the
typical industrial programmers but
researchers and engineers you want to
you want to build a jet you want to
build a new
engine for a car you know design a car
engine you want to build a bridge you
want to do analysis you know stress
analysis you know that's when you
need to solve lots of equations and
visualizations and so on
okay let me do 10 more minutes okay
10 more minutes i'm going to um
let me get into the heart of the plot
okay so let yeah so let's let's just do
it now okay so plot so we have seen this
is how you plot a sine function
uh so we want to plot sine trigonometry
x from one to six okay
so you got that but how does it work so
let me let me do a little bit more okay
so one two ten okay
how does it know
um
let me let me show you a different way
okay so
table
sign
x
form
1 to 10
right you got bunch of values okay so
well you need you know we
you want the result to be numerical so
all you have to do is slash slash n so
that gives you numerical result
otherwise it's symbolic okay so you got
a bunch of values for sine
now
you know sine 1 to 1 to 10 right um
let's say in increment of 0.3
okay so you got like tens of let's say
you know lots of data for sign and you
want to plot that so you can do that by
this plot okay
so you just say list plot and that okay
then you got a bunch of uh sign okay so
my point here is i want to show you okay
so let's let's instead of this part
let's say line plot so to con to connect
them together
oh there's no line plot okay so
um
but how do you connect connect the lines
okay
let's go to the documentation
so this plot how do you connect the
lines
uh
this line plot yeah the naming
who find wolfram is very particular
about naming because line plot
can be ambiguous so yeah so there it is
least line plot so we got you know so
what we did here is we got bunch of
values of sign
then we
you know like we are trying to we are
trying to create this plot function
okay that's what we are
kind of what we are trying to do we are
trying to recreate the wolfram plot
function
how do you do you know given a function
you just evaluate that function at the
range you know you got lots of data
points
then you just
connect the lines okay
let me show you how to how to do it
without any building function okay so we
are going to use
pure graphics primitives
okay yeah let me show you that
so
so first of all you want to build a
table of values okay
so there is a table of values
uh let's say
0.5 let's get fewer number of values
okay now you want to
okay let's say
data equals true okay so we got our data
okay now we want to use
graphics primitives so you have to do is
you
line remember
which we demonstrate a graphics
primitive of line you know like that
so that's what we're gonna use we want
to
put line to connect these uh numbers
okay so line in this case it's very
simple okay that's that's all it does
uh no actually
wait actually you know this bunch of
numbers are the height of the sign so
you need a zero in front so let's change
the data
so
let's do it again so instead of sign you
want a bracket
the first part is
is
x
x is x okay the second part is sine x
okay
so now you got a list of points
okay now
okay now you just wrap line to it
okay that's that's good
uh actually you don't want you know
there's an extra nesting so you don't
want that so we what we can do is um
you know i'm using fancy constructions
but
i'm not going to talk about it don't
worry about it you know i i just want to
focus on the graphics primitives so you
got you so you got this now all you have
to do is just say graphics
okay so
for example
that
ah okay wrong
uh
okay so you need you do need the
okay
there it is okay so there it is
so you see this is how um we build
graphics
kind of manually you know but but you
see probably you started to see problems
you see
you see these kinks that's not what you
want you see
the
the plot
you know the building function there's
no pink
you know it's very smooth
okay so what what so what we're gonna do
so uh let me do let me try to do this
again so
put the whole thing together so you can
see how it's
done
okay so
uh wait uh
so you want the line
yeah
yeah so we
delete that let's redo
okay so
this this single line draws that okay
now you want let's say because of this
kinks so you decrease the number of
increments so now you have
now it's much smoother
okay now it's much smoother
but in general this is not a good
approach because sometimes you because
over here it's pretty straight so
if you do it this way it's very
inefficient so because you are creating
thousands of thousands
point points
that is not needed
um this is critical when you have a 3d
graphics you know when you have a
when you have 3d graphics graphics like
that because that involves
you know
hundred thousands of uh points
so
so what you want to do is you want some
kind of smart algorithm you want
you want the algorithm you know you you
don't want to just uh evaluate the
function at you know very small
increments you want to evaluate them so
that when you need
when when the value changes a lot
you you want more points over there when
the value doesn't change a lot from the
previous neighbors you don't want you
know
that many points
so this is about you know this is very
basic you know all we are doing this is
high school function high school
function of you know function a part of
a function
and you can see how
it starts to get complex
so
so let me talk about the building plot
so it has some features that
lets you um
do this for example if you just plot it
it's everything is nice smooth but you
can also say
options okay let's see options
so we got all these options there are
few options we want okay
uh one of them is plot points okay so
let's just do it
okay so plot points
uh let's say
three
okay so we we are telling mathematica
don't plot so many just only three
points and another thing we want to say
is um
let me find it
you know i know this
by heart because i've been
coding wufang language
for 15 years
almost every day starting in 1992 okay
so the other one i want to
um
it's called maximum recursion or
something like that so let me i have to
actually look at them
yeah max recursion okay so there it is
so
let's say max recursion okay
let's say one okay so this is very
interesting okay watch it let's say plot
point five okay you do so
you see there are only five plot points
so one you know more or less one two
three four
five six seven eight well it went to
eight so max recursion zero
yeah there it is so one two three four
five exactly five points
so so behind the scenes what the
function does
that's exposed to the user is that you
know it uses
a kind of um
algorithm to determine how many points
to plot
so basically the algorithm will detect
the kink so if there's a sharp end
you'll put more points there
and
how do you control how smooth is this
is by plot points
combined with max recursion
so plot points is the beginning
number of points to plot for example we
we can say you know let's say let's say
uh here
let's say plot point 10
okay recursion zero recursion zero just
means don't
don't
don't smooth this out smooth it out you
know just do the plot point and that's
it okay so 10 looks better
then um let's do another
okay now it's better
now let's say 200
now it's perfect
now the other way to to do this let me
show you the progression okay so plot
point let's let's put it here
okay
now instead of increasing the plot point
we
we increase the recursion let's say one
okay
let's say two
now let's say three
okay so recursion it is
how
you know each time movement plots it use
recursion to increase the smoothness
but there's a limit because some some
some
some graph that goes infinitely kinky so
for example
i think uh
if if my math is
correct
let me try okay
something like that
no
yeah no
no what
what am i doing
uh sign you won't go sign you don't want
to sign
no
and no so what
do you guys know because it's a common
okay so i i got it
one of x
okay so
there are things like that okay
so this graph doesn't matter how much
you try to smooth out it won't because
it you know the more closer to the zero
it gets more kinky
so that's why there's a recursion minute
a
max recursion limit when when wolfen
language language reaches that usa
okay so that's
so um
okay so
okay that's that that's one thing i'm
trying to explain now the one more thing
okay i'm gonna
five more minutes the last thing i'm
going to explain
is how do you extract the extract the
graphics primitives of any building
function okay so
the way you do that is um
okay let's try that okay let's try a new
one
let's say my g equals true okay so
that's your graphics
now what is my g
uh
[Music]
my g and you can say
length okay
so length two so there are two
so this so ufon language graphs any
graphics function they return
uh essentially a list okay so
there's a length of two okay so let's
see
uh and you can see the head of the func
it returns a graph function okay so for
example let's say head
my g okay so the head is graphics just
like
just like we did the graphics primitives
where is it
uh where is the example where we show
the graphics primitives yeah here so you
remember the graph this is the
this is the function of graphics for 2d
graphics that's why
the head just means the function name so
so basically the plot
returns a thing
that begins with graphics then square
brackets then two things inside okay
so
let's extract that that's what we want
to do so
so you can just say first
that returns the first element
of
my g
okay
there it is
so you can see
the first element of the result of the
plot
is just a list
and you know at least
and the heart of the list is just this
part a line you know a line of with five
points
so this is this is so this is how you
extract
the graphics primitives from a built-in
function that plots something in
language
and this is extremely useful
because if you are you know if
fulfilling language created something
very fancy like that
sometimes you know if you are a graphics
programmer you want to know
exactly how you know you want to get the
data you know you
you don't want just the image you want
to get the data so this is how you get
it so you typically you can just say
first
then whatever the result of that
return value
and you typically you'll get
a list of tens of thousands
values
okay so that
that's it so let me show you one more
one one last thing okay so for example
one last thing so this time
let's just say plot
okay so very smooth
and
my g equals to that okay
then let's just say first element of
my g
okay so you here is you can see
a huge amount of data
now if it's a 3d graphics typically the
result is
you know tens of thousands of data
we can try that here okay so let's try
that
and that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
um
you know so now we have that and let's
try evaluate you know so it tells you
large output it automatically kind of
only shows some of it
you can say show more
show more show more show
more show more
it's it's kind of too large it doesn't
you know you can say sure or
sure
yeah so this will you know
takes
pages okay that's it for today
can you do infinite resumable plots
yes you can but not really not
not really
well
you you ca you can do infinite zoomable
plot but at each time you zoom you have
to eat wufang language will do
computation
um
uh basically what you want is
i'm uh i'm not gonna go over that today
so that's it okay thank you guys for
watching
yes it has full form expression
everything's got full form expression
um
you know like
uh you know if you are interested in
that i did a video full video on that
um you can watch but
yeah because if i'm gonna show you now
it doesn't
too much but you know i did a full video
on that
uh let me show the variance okay
mathematica installer is only one
gigabyte did you ever use emacs tab
feature no
well yes i did i did a video on that
actually
uh
okay bye guys if you like my stuff
donate okay
pay me buy me a drink