hi everyone welcome to another session
of Emacs workflow so this one I'm just
going to yeah basically I'm just going
to work on my my website my Emacs
tutorial and this is just a recording of
my workflow so I'm just going to show
you how I do things
see in Emacs you know some people there
are a lot of tutorials on various things
in Emacs but they are few showing a
workflow so anyway I'm just going to
show you show you my workflow so yeah
first of all let's turn the key log key
caster this this is a great this is a
great application if you want to
reassure your keys on the bottom when
you do a when you are doing a
presentation or something and also let
me turn on Emacs keylock so go to that
ALPA command log mod that's right that's
the one we want and command not much dot
yeah this is um alpha so you can use it
now the documentation these packages
I've talked about this before this
package is not it can be improved you
know so I added this section this is
instruction on how to turn it on so
first of all call command log mod that
turns the model then call global command
my lord global command log mod that
means doesn't matter what buffer you are
in it will it will make a record of it
record it then code the command CRM open
command log buffer okay let's call that
then you can see a new buffer here and
on the right side and whatever I type
whatever command I type your show there
so I added this section here but you can
you can
um you know it sounded it's not on their
website you can make a contribution you
know add those sections better
documentation because otherwise it's a
bit confusing so anyway I have the
perfect it's switch the buffer come and
knock oh yeah I remember you can it's
this buffer is actually not a normal
buffer so you cannot just switch to hit
no so you you actually have to call the
CRM open command log to show it so
that's you know a little tricky so
anyway so let's go back to my Emacs
tutorial so I'm just going to show you
what I'm gonna do here so solar now it's
601 so let's do it for 10 to 15 minutes
yeah so okay what I want to do is that
okay so this is my tutorial let's go to
eMac B's hang on a sec
okay let's go to eMac these you know my
media recording skill sucks so and
yesterday someone told me there is a
program you can use to record videos
with you know corner screen so that's
one this one good good video recording
software OBS so it looks like it's
available for Windows Mac and Linux so
you know I might try it next time
thank you this guy green dagger okay so
back to Emacs so what I want to do is
let's look at so this is my eMac this
tutorial you can see each one has these
boxes what that box is this this is this
boxes on navigation boxes so eMac this
basics so what that means that each page
each link in the Box each page will also
contain the same box so you can just
keep navigated to the second overview of
text processing in my crisp then you can
go to the bottom then continue to the
next 100 eMac these examples or the
other topics so let's go back to
practical Emacs so I want to do the same
thing for the Emacs for the you know for
these topics had a topic box so let's
just do it so let's so this window I'm
going to be down second make it smaller
and put it here okay 603 I like like I'm
on a time burner I have to remember the
time so let's do this quickly
again this is just my showing my Emacs
workflow so what you can what do you get
out of it yeah you know what you can
learn is that you can see how I navigate
pages how I go to diet and pain what
command I call every every command is
gonna echo in Emacs he's going to show
here you see remember that ever
everything in Emacs is a comments and
some commands are bound to keys so every
key I type is correlated to a command
it's a command call and it's all gonna
be showing on this panel so you can you
can freeze the screen and study of the
commands you know many of the commands
on my personal commands they start with
a name I saw something and usually it's
on my website so you can you can find
find the code and used for yourself so
okay so let's start so I have a topic
catch so this so you see that's
abbreviation so what you get is key you
see I got this box that just adds that
automatically so so this is Emacs
QuickStart topic and remove that and
basically I want to copy the whole thing
you paste it here and showing browser
that looks good that's what I want okay
so go back here copy and go through each
link go to the bottom so basically there
are many ways many ways to do these you
know I have a script that automate this
but let's just show you some manual
examples so this is the first page go to
the bottom you see it's there now the
second one
fun with Emacs Tetris go to the bottom
it's not there you see so we're gonna
add these to every one of them copy cuz
bye
so I'm gonna search this okay so next
time I can there it is so I'm just gonna
do this for every one of them for the
next one I'm going to do a
semi-automatic so so you don't you know
just show a different way so but for now
I'm going to do this manually close
next search paste cuz save next open
such paste close save next open such
next paste close open and now let's go
back to browse to the browser you can
see go down all the way down the box is
there so firm with Emacs
all the way down Emacs first day all the
way down Emacs keys these are emails
emails basic keys so this they're basic
tips it's there so it's done so that's
great so go back to practical Emacs so
you see this this is great so now remove
that we don't want that so okay yeah
good so let's do the next one so but
before we do that I want to make a
backup because you know just in case you
know I'm going to try to run some
scripts probably and and that will make
a lot changes so I'm going to first of
all to a backup so just in case we can
like revert everything so I'm using it
so keep status
okay that's the files I've changed so
far since the last commit I mean I shall
right now by the way so it's now git had
had everything get commit okay I have
like seven seven more minutes maybe wait
yeah save a moment okay
git commit that's done then usually I do
wait
usually I do
remove Emacs backup so whenever I commit
I do remove or Emacs backup so it's done
you can see in the line below there
so okay that's done so let's go back
here now files you see some of these are
not so nice like the other one you know
because each page you know they are
interrelated interrelated the topics
like some topic for example split window
this page is about split windows in
Emacs it doesn't really belong to files
I mean you know but however well you're
gonna put it so you know the category
categorization is an issue I mean it's a
general issue in any in any topic you
know there's a duodecimal system there's
a Library of Congress system there's
Encyclopedia Britannica
they they have a system you know people
like all the subjects in a world you
want to try to find a way because
sometimes it's necessary to categorize
them you know sometimes they called
taxonomy so anyway so back to my Emacs
tutorial it's the same thing you know
it's hard to category categorize these
topic topics I mean like put everything
in a tree so let's look at spirit
windows you see at the bottom I already
have a box for spirit windows so
this fax is related to all subjects
subjects related to manage windows
windows topic ok spirit windows but but
this box let's go back hello so let's go
here so the spring windows you see this
box is actually the topics the topics
are different from from this box from
these you know list of topics for files
and actually if you go to list buffers
all the way down and then he has a
different box you know one is open fire
on topics one is perfect optics so
because I wrote my Emacs tutorial
piecemeal like piecemeal over the year
years it's been since 2006
so it's 15 years or something so the
topic you know it's so there's lots of
things to go through maintaining
maintaining them is quite very
time-consuming you know like like right
now what I want to do now is like I have
to actually at some point I have to
actually eventually read every one of
them and think you know which one should
go where and so that I can have a good
categorization you know when I begin is
just blocks you know block blogs you
know okay here's something interesting
okay so this is this is my eMac eMac
Spock and Emacs blog archive you know
they went back to 2009 but actually I
started Emacs blog since 2006 you know
started writing but it's not here
because because it was on another domain
so you know things change and things
evolved so in the beginning is just few
tips my personal notes about Emacs how
to do things and I remember the first
one is about Unicode like some of the
very first page are still here it's a
Unicode of course over the years they
you see this Unicode page is two tower
six you know because I need to insert
math symbols you know so I started to
learn how to do that in Emacs and back
them it's not as good as today you know
today Unicode is so popular but back
then it's still you know you have to try
these or that or different you know bugs
or whatever so anyway so these pages
2006 in over the years you know I change
you know improved and I tried to put
them more in to categorize organize them
into more like a book format so you have
like the topics to start Emacs to
download Emacs the topics to file
related topics opening file
this buffer switch buffer and the topic
for find/replace and you know I started
to try to organize them so today what
I'm doing you know with these navigation
boxes again it's just another
improvement you know trying to do that
so so let's go back to working on on it
so files okay so so as we have seen the
file section is a bit chaotic you know
there's different boxes so anyway let's
go here the grab it copy and paste back
and let's put it here make a backup of
this page okay and then go here go to
the bottom copy that closed copy and
paste closed home up here paste now
let's look in the browser you see I just
added these two boxes here so together
so this way I can see you know which
items are where maybe some some of them
are duplicated you know spirit window is
here and it's also here of course this
this section is going to be removed
let's just remove it now
but first of all I have to make sure all
the links exist so in any other topic so
that exists oops
but oh god what did I do
no no I mean Emacs and do hell I don't
know which okay and do and do and do and
do okay that's good
stop and do because in accident do is
that it's and do roller coaster and do
and do and do and we do once you made a
mistake you have to undo your induce
comeback
that's why I made the backup so if I can
like I go to tie it now you can see I'm
a backup here just in case I need to you
know look at my backup and there are
many Emacs and do packages like unto
tree we do package and over the years
you know I tried them all and
unfortunately it's sad to say they all
have one problem very serious problem
they corrupt your undo buffered history
there's you know it's very bad because
once that happened like when you are
working on a file you know you do things
you you expect this always and do you
know you know like if you want to delete
this you know and save and you don't
worry about it because how you know if
you made a mistake you just undo it like
and do and do you know you just don't do
it but then when you are trying to undo
them it's a spam no more and do but you
know there's and do but it says no no
one do because but corruption of the
undo record for some reason they all
have the problem and it's a it's a it's
a nasty subtle problem you can it's not
easily reproducible so there are people
reporting at you know
every every few years let's see
Casali Emax and do so I I usually write
down whatever happens you know based on
do so so this this other code base and
do we do packages and what okay that's
not that's something else okay that's a
song that's a boo-boo song okay so yeah
undo we do corruption problem you can
read in details actually I have another
page that documented the detail document
documents the problems in detail
something another page to make too many
essays sometimes it's hard to find but
anyway let's go back to these so so now
my my task is to remove this and make it
fit but first of all make sure how the
links are exist somewhere okay that
exists that exists but for management
before switching it's just look tired
basics bookmarks and die basics
bookmarks okay you get the gist you know
I you know I don't want to
well this one is not there okay that's
new copy you put it here this one is not
there either
and oh yeah so but the other ones are
okay so drop that drop that look at mean
browser so there's this this tool I need
to put them somewhere so okay that's it
for that 618 yeah okay we are over time
so maybe that's it for today two more
minutes so that's it for today I think
you know so I'm just going to go go go
off and walk on these okay I'm gonna
show you one more thing so right now I'm
done I'm going to upload to my website
actually I don't want to do it here yeah
it's not doing so okay let's see let's
see is there something else I want to
since I'm doing a video now
so I need to do that play us find repays
the find repays party is easy
yeah it's let's do that then you can you
know you can skip the video or drop it
you know stop watching so they let me
just do two moments
find your pace so go to the bottom let's
go back here
copy paste remove finery paste paste
here showing browser finally paste okay
so I got dropped that DD that that is
there that is there it's it's there
let me say okay so drop
okay well let's show you one more step
the other subtle yeah I'm going to show
you so go to Isha go to each other then
I think that's going to sink to my
website type of password
so he'll take you know then so it's done
so go back to here then sorry max
practically max tutorial yes you see so
I've added those good that's good thing
so you know I have to ask you I have to
walk on you know combined part of these
or separate into two groups like these
two I want to separate into two boxes
and and and and the other thing is that
on this page you know base is for Emacs
basic it's you know for beginners so you
don't you know it's how to organize the
page because you know like for example
manage windows topic you have split
windows then you have more advanced
things like we stole up and fire like
effective window management that that
page is basically a workflow that show
you know I talked about my workflow but
for beginners they don't need to see
that so it's confusing to them so I'm
not sure actually this is a good
approach so I've been you know it's hard
to it's hard to actually find a right
way so anyway thank you for watching if
you have comments you know I have you
know questions or comments you know do
comment and stamp up my week video
thanks bye