good morning guys
welcome to another episode of talk-show
today's 2018-2019 yes it is
stop that and today is December 15th
Sunday two o'clock in the afternoon San
Francisco time so today we have a lot of
people hello guys emily alyn and a o EU
now that is a vorak left-hand home row
keys and we're gonna talk about you know
i'm thinking i'm gonna talk about
JavaScript you know I'm going to coach
JavaScript vectors mathematics okay you
can see on the left window this is math
this is all vector functions we're gonna
code that for 20 minutes and oh we're
gonna talk about we're gonna talk about
languages look at these fantastic
languages look at these characters it's
magnified giant fun okay so this this so
we have English Latin alphabet we have
German omelette and also using other
languages and and so I'm thinking let's
just talk about languages because you
know that's a fun topic the languages of
the world and the Aaron says how which
means Chinese is good
Alan is multilingual and Alan is Alan is
English Chinese Korean and in Japanese
and in others and emily is also english
and japanese and los bong so we have
fantastic people so you see we have
english and omelette and nina the
spanish nina that's what I that's a word
that's a character I remember Nino and
Nene Nene oh is for boy and Nene eyes
girls sweet and we have this Russian
character so let's talk about random
let's do random then I guess unless you
guys are here for my JavaScript thing
for my for my mathematics and geometry
okay so Emily shows a purple heart if
emily is found of the Purple Heart okay
so let's so we have Russian okay let's
go to Unicode okay Unicode fantastic
Unicode sup let's go to Chrome open
browser in Chrome and of course we are
using Emacs the best editor in the
universe and on this window you can see
all my oh my command names okay so so
let's see so we opened we opened Chrome
and it's it's okay so but we have to
have like go or like we have to do some
some thing otherwise otherwise I'm gonna
be dependent on you guys chat so we
gonna do something so first of all pop
this out as usual and move this window
to the right okay so we need to do
something so so what is that something I
don't know actually I don't know what he
says something so I'm thinking so let's
look at first of all let's look at the
Unicode okay so this is my website if
you like my stuff and you you want to
support me then thread my website okay
so let's knit scores close that so let's
go to our talk show
Emacs bookmarks fantastic
and today's talk show and let's face it
here there so unicode oh yeah we already
already pasted that so delete that go
back go back go back great and refresh
and also join my discord okay so you see
we have so open so go to a talk show go
to the top search for discord and there
is the link this is my talk show page
and yeah so go to discord we're so so
over here so those of you new here and
today we have so much discussion got
discussions so many things ancient
astronomy and astrology good morning
George to Australia and we have people
all around the world we have lunara's
which is from Halifax Nova Scotia on the
which is on the east side of Canada and
we have Ripper is from Colorado and
crash hacker is from India and country
in Japan and Alan is from the great
California the you know you guys know
the California flag which is the bear
okay actually some of you do not know so
let's show it California flag you know
cap you know USA each state has a flag
and California has you know so this is
the California's flag okay which side
should it be I don't know which is which
side so anyway that's the California
pair why is California using a bear as
the I guess in the past there's lots of
bears but we don't have much bears today
not in California I'm wondering why is
California using payers its fact because
California is not code Oh grab a drink
oh yeah we must that might we must do so
my drink of today is the grape juice
hundred percent grape juice you know you
wonder
fantastic you know how much you walk it
does to make this like juice tremendous
toyou and Moyo or Emily has to walk
tomorrow's you know that's Toyo and more
guys toyou and more you that word I
learned from Arabian Nights from this
guy so anyway we have wait that's the
quarantine zone so we have languages we
have the very interesting and and
fantastic keyboard or I must mention I
must show a little keyboard here and we
have other people you know who know this
keyboard Japanese keyboard who are
enthusiastic with this keyboard and zoom
way out there you are somewhere and zoom
well showed us today
this keyboard okay and there's also a
video he's typing it showing us how it
sounds mechanical keys of course and you
can see the key right here okay it's a
it's one of the rare key of mechanical
off Spruce over something like that and
that's actually new to me because you
know I don't know much about off key you
know you guys know okay so all the
people here knows a lot about key words
but one thing interesting is that you
see apparently the Japanese company NEC
created this keyboard so it just looks
like a IBM PC keyboard but actually it
is from it was it NEC or Fujitsu so
because you can tell you can see on the
back they have you know so let's let's
all go at this keyboard so it just looks
like a American you know PC keyboard IBM
PC keyboard but it is made in Japan
look look at that you see so this is NEC
cooperation a nice EAP ch4 112 so I have
no idea but that's very interesting so
anyway let's get back to ya a nice NEC
so let's talk about Unicode so so we
have this Canadian Aboriginal syllabus
syllabus
okay so canadian aboriginal syllabics so
actually what I'm thinking I'm going to
do is that I'm going to create a page on
the fly I don't know if that's
interesting to you guys but you know the
you chat you guys chat random so I'll
read it and and so let's yeah so but
before we do that let me show you some
of the interesting things so you go to
my website so actually let's go to Solly
Unicode search for it and there it is
and we have we have several JavaScript
ongoing so let's look at that one this
is my math font okay this let's shrink a
little bit so you type here type here
and see them change in real time in this
Gothic style font this is actually not a
font per se now per se is Latin and that
this is not actually a font but but it's
it is actually a Unicode characters so
these are Unicode characters and you can
change them to double stroke and
mathematical mode so so you see the
interesting thing about this is that
it's actually not bowed but it's
actually stream huh but it's actually
you know unicode characters so these
characters are both by themselves you
know you are not actually boating it so
so what's what's the use of these you
know many people on Twitter they would
use these for example I have a great day
today for example I type that okay I
copy this thing I copy this line go to
go to Emacs editor and I let's say I
pasted it here
okay shrink a little bit and I say I
have a let's magnify okay that's not
actually great day so you see you post
this on Twitter now actually let's
change it to text mod so that there is
no highlight so you post this on Twitter
and that would great will be bold so
that's what you know it's a fun thing to
do then you have math italics and you
have math script and you have math monel
so all these are unicode characters
that's very interesting
then you have you have several others
you have the room room the room
characters drawing is a script use in
Scandinavia basically around starting
around year 150 to about 1500 so this is
the run script and of course toe kyun ki
okay ie and this guy poke Ian who wrote
Lord of the Rings also has a hand in it
he's got a hand in everything
linguistics but not Asian once though I
mean but you know the European so
because he actually added several
characters to it and they appear
singing unicode but however the fonts is
not widely available so you see these
three characters those are from token
from his Lord of the Ring novels but
okay speaking of run there's something
interesting okay you know when I was you
know reading about it so you have a
keyboard with run key caps and also by
the way so another interesting thing
about run is that let's go - Sally :
now goal and people the the Rob Pike and
and friends they they in : they have a
datatype you know the type of the
language let's see
: datatype so let's see it's let's show
that there so back to the goal and
datatype basic types so you have a type
that is you int 32 which means an
unsigned integer 32 bits so basically a
binary number with 32 digits you know to
wrap it's an integer and and they they
use that type to represent unicode
characters and it has an alias so so
this type you int 32 is also called run
why is it called run just because you
know under the goal hand guys you know
they are nerds they they wanted to do it
so I suppose I suppose that's a reason
no other reason the proper name for this
type you int 32 should be Unicode code
point because that's what this type is
useful so you can you know so Unicode
code point but anyway they call it runs
so : they have a data type called run
now let's go there okay so I have a page
or tutorial about run where is it
they're so run so on this page I show
you what what this data type is about
the type you know one of the data type
of the language and how you use it
purpose of run what's caught point join
is just caught point ok Unicode code
point and and if you don't know what
Unicode code point is I did a video a
few months ago and so we so we're gonna
this rock star one dollar per bottle at
one dollar tree so grapefruit juice and
rock star and I'm gonna be a rock rock
star so if you are new to if you haven't
learned : I recommend it okay just go to
Valley goal and tutorial
I recommend : it's fantastic we and the
primary reason that the the actually the
important reason is because because
because because because because because
because it is practical and it is widely
popular you know it's gonna it's gonna
wipe our C&C first first and Ruby and
and Python soon okay I'm gonna tell you
so as opposed to you know the scheme
list the the Haskell okay the crosier
you know they are good but they are not
gonna be you you can you are not likely
gonna get a job but meanwhile : as of
right now there are tons of jobs you
know and it's very practical so I
recommend : so goal and you know they
they introduce you know they use the
term run to represent Unicode characters
and okay let's go back to Unicode so
that's about run that's
you know interesting thing about run so
let's see what what are you guys saying
leave a serious is here I come
so everyone grab a drink you have to
take a shot excise to turn JavaScript no
I don't have to turn it off so you guys
like actually actually I should you guys
are spared of taking a shot today
because I'm in chrome baby melodious
voice okay let's do that so guys thank
you thank you very much for attending my
show and you guys are great and and and
what so we are going to talk about run
in fact we just finished talking about
that so let's go to the next topic and
this is going to change your life this
is going to I'm going to help you change
your life so look at this look at this
one
this one will turn your life entirely up
side down if you follow what I mean okay
so okay so that's upside down letters
and you know it's fun to put it on to
for example let's demo an application
let's do an application let's help the
word let's make the world a better place
so let's go here a vibrant discussion
group and paste it there paste paste
oh my god what those black letter black
letter so okay so let's go back to
Chrome and let's go back to Unicode so
so inverted text and lastly we have
Braille which is great for those blind
and deaf excuse me but also for those
who are well who are capable in other
ways okay so this is real and it is
basically the X Y X HIV i t io an
exhibition of mathematical come button
Nitori you see they even have
exclamation sign so braille so that's
fantastic end so how long have I been
talking and we've been talking about 20
minutes so next thing what we gonna do
next thing so let's shall we do the
aboriginal what do you guys think so
let's pray okay so braille is
interesting and let me show you let me
say something interesting about Braille
so Braille is a basically a
combinatorial exploration of dots and by
the way by the way emily has a her own
writing system she created let's let's
do that so sorry
let's see Emily okay and it's I don't
know what that will come up let's say
let's go to Saudi keyboard okay sorry
keyboard and okay so let's show this
quickly so we have so young Saudi
keyboard oh yeah so
you know the these once we started to
talk about keyboard it's gonna be
nonstop we're gonna be lingering over
here and never be able to get out but
you go to the fun part
and there are these spatter stations you
can all go at so then you go to happy
hacking Emily this server then you can
see you can see this writing system she
created okay so she created this writing
system and it's it's also if you want to
classify it you will be a combinatorial
system because it's based on night dots
night dots similar to Braille night outs
then you connect the dots by a line so
depending on how you connect them you
have different you know configurations
and then you have this thing and she
wrote this diary okay so so that's you
know that that's the interesting thing
about the combinatorial systems
okay so let's post that here and then go
back to Braille and okay so Braille it's
actually made of two columns okay two
columns three rows so a total of six dot
six dots but actually not that's not all
because there is a new Braille okay
there is a new prayer that's made of
eight dots so you can see here this is
the this is not popular okay but it's a
some sort of extension so they extended
Braille Braille with eight dots but it's
not common but you can see you know when
I was doing this Braille page you have
an interesting mathematical question
that will interest you programmers okay
so the question is how do you order them
so you know you have a bunch of dots you
know let's say six six starts six starts
total like that six starts okay then
some dots can be on or off
now the question is you have this
different combination of dots now you
want to order them like ABCD so what are
the ways you order them you know of
course there is no standard way I mean
you have to come up with a okay in
mathematicians jargon this is code let's
see if I can pull it off in math jargon
this this would be code total order so
you have okay that's not a that's not a
obscure jargon yeah it would be better
if I can come up with some chocolate
that you don't understand
but anyway this is kowtowed okay so
actually so that it's let's digress into
the realm of mathematics total order
Pacha
shut shut up Wikipedia please go away I
know my money don't donate to Wikipedia
okay I made a video about that so math
so in mathematics a total order simple
order linear order connects order or God
what are these this this they should be
removed so a total order is a binary
relation on sunset X which is anti
symmetric transitive and connects
relation what is connects relation they
just added that God some some PhD
student just added that fluff because I
never seen that before
connection relation what in mathematics
a homogeneous relation is called
connects relation or already should have
in the property of Connect City it if it
relates all pairs of
in some way ash at Jeddah okay so back
to the let's go back to the math okay Oh
de todo de so he math a total de is a is
is a binary relation on some set X which
is simit and has symmetric transitive
and connect and connects relation a set
pair with a total order is called a
chain oh it's called a chain okay guys
we have a not see see also the our
problem to express this in a
mathematical way is that we want the set
of rails to be a chain so it's a chain
so you see then is they started to talk
about what are these properties mean
this is actually important okay this
this is how Hugh you know
so anyway Braille so you want to order
them by that basically means for any to
bear character you need to come up with
a function that says which one comes
before the other okay that's what it
means
however you know this math is actually
important you know because you see me
you see you see the mathematicians talk
about these things you might think ah
that's too much jargons necessarily so
actually so it's so necessary let me
tell you why because when back in 1997
1997 I was doing a lot a lot math you
know learning learning actually I know a
much more than at that time I don't know
that much math but I was you know so
anyway I was doing programming coding
and I want to sort in fact this this
problem is a major problem meaning a
practical problem you might you might
run across ok let me tell you the story
so you got bunch up so let's just say
brea ok so this you got these characters
and you want to solve
now each of these Braille characters
they have a Unicode code point you see
for example these six starts is that
number it's kind of like a ID integer
it's a code point for this character and
in hexadecimal is that then well wait
what
okay so wait the color point is this one
it's a bit confusing so this this six
starts the code point is one zero three
zero three what comes above that is
actually the Braille pattern thoughts
they actually have ID by themselves so
you see what I mean so let me show you
another another character so let's go to
APL programming language APL characters
so here we have the APL characters now
let's show one of them so let's see the
right arrow so you see the right arrow
the name is right right words arrow and
this number eight five nine four is its
code point basically it means it's an
integer that identifies this character
and in hexadecimal it's two zero one two
now with you and plus sign before it
that's the standard Unicode notation so
anyway you got the ID you know code code
point of this character but for the
Braille character the full name for
example these six dots is sprayer
pattern dots one two three four five six
so they have actually the Braille
characters themselves have a ID a code
to indicate this character then you have
this one zero three zero three that is
the unicode code point ID for this
Braille character okay then you have
hexadecimal so anyway if you want to
sort Braille of course you you could
just sort it by the Braille name you
know the Unicode name assigned to it or
you can sort it by the Unicode ID you
know your point okay that
Cocco point you can sort by that but
actually it turns out if you thought by
that it the result is not very logical
for example in this in this Colin and
let me get rid of that so in this in
this section they are sorted by Unicode
code point and you look at them they
don't you know they don't make much
logical sense you see one dot one dot
then two dots then went out again it's
not logical then okay let me show you
some you see you can see there are
several different ways to show them you
can sort by the Unicode code point it
doesn't make it doesn't look good then
you use thought by the Unicode name of
the Braille then it looks like that okay
like here again you can see you look at
that it's not logical you see you got
1.2.3.4 and five six then you then you
start with a 5.4 dot then what five dots
again it's not logical this is sought by
by the name of the Braille but however
the logical one one of the logical way
to sort it is by by dot count look at
this one okay so look at this one so you
have you see one two three dots then one
two three dots in in a different column
then you have variations of two dots
then you have you know one two three
four five six six seven eight nine ten
eleven twelve thirteen fourteen sixteen
over 15 wait fifteen variations of two
dots
then you have variations of three dots
so this is a logical way to sort it but
okay so so that's about how you how you
about sorting them but but when you want
to write a program to solve something
let's say polygon let's say some object
let's say the object River sends some
polygon some polyhedra in space okay you
want to determine the order if folks for
example have some polyhedrus volume is
smaller than it should be in front if
the polyhedron volume is larger it
should be in the back so it's like this
is like computer graphics computational
geometry so basically you have a bunch
of variables that each one is the data
type of polyhedron in space somewhere
and they have different sizes you want
to write a program to sort these
polyhedrons how do you do it so in
typically in programming languages you
have a sort function that takes the
second argument the the second argument
is a function that determines which one
comes in front right so you basically
pass your own function so then you
compute the volume of the polyhedron the
smaller one we are coming from so you
write that function but if you are not
careful you've got a problem the problem
is every time you sort the results is
not the same you know we you know it's
almost like there is some some kind of a
random thing going on even though your
program has nothing random at all that's
a problem you see that happens that
happens when you violated these
mathematical properties in your function
okay this actually happened to me back
in 1937 I was sorting polygon polygons
in 3d space you know doing
a visualization of math you know I'm
programming that in Mathematica so I was
I want to sort I forgot what's the
criteria but I want to saw the polygons
in 3d space so I read a function you
know I can write a function easy to say
which object should come before you know
a less than B or B be racing a but but
but every time the sword results is not
the same you know you saw that now and
you saw that again it's the same but
next time you saw that it's not the same
result the problem that that happens
when you don't when you're sorting
function does not happen it does not
conform to these three properties okay
so for example if you sort a less than B
it must always be so it should never
happen when be you know becomes B front
before a when your function returns that
you know and also the most important is
this one this one I violated unknowingly
so this one says if a is less than B and
if B is less than C then a when then
when you apply your function to a and C
it should say a is less than C so this
is called transitivity so if you violate
this function I mean it you know you
don't know you you have to analyze your
function for the order because otherwise
there's no this like you see this is
when unit test will fail like unit test
they will fail you know because you they
your program your function doesn't
there's no way to say you know when
given to object which one comes in front
unless you run your function but your
function must satisfy this property for
any a and B if your function says a is
less than B and B is less than C then
it's required that your function also
must say a is less than C otherwise you
you got problem so
that's when when you thought the result
is not always the same so that's about
that so you know this Braille so you
know I so writing this page you know I
tried to show them by by the Unicode
code point it doesn't look logical then
I tried to sort by the Unicode name it
doesn't look good then I have to sort by
the dot count how did I do that
I don't remember okay I don't remember
how did I did this
maybe manually no I don't think it's
manually but I don't remember how I
actually sorted them so anyway that's
the interesting thing about sorting
about two things
sorting three things okay the sorting of
the brows how do you sort them that's
very interesting you can go by Unicode
code point you can go by Unicode name
which is a browse own ID or you can go
by some kind of logical dot count that's
one thing the so the other thing is
about the mathematical property of
sorting you your function needs to
satisfy this so that's interesting
well that's about that so then we have
AP our symbols okay yeah so APA is a
mathematical programming language so how
long have we been been talking 40
minutes okay so maybe maybe that's it I
think oh let's look at the comment and
see what's interesting okay so yeah
that's that's all I have about brows but
I was going I was thinking I was
thinking let's add the Canadian
Aboriginal text okay so there is a
Canadian Aboriginal language writing
system but let's read the comments
where is it okay you today it's so busy
my god not the disco Channel I cannot
read all the messages anymore
where is it yeah so this canadian
aboriginal syllabics so apparently
there's a language in inch inuit okay so
canadian see the base
syllabic writing is a family of iboga
das okay which means writing system
based on consonant vowel payers notice
this just let's just call it phonetics
so it's a family of phonetics created by
james events to write a number of
indigenous canadian languages of the of
the Algonquian and inuit and formerly
alpha Baskin language families which had
no formal writing systems previously oh
that's interesting so it's it's actually
artificial that's that's still
interesting but it's not you know his
basically human man-made human created
learning system to cover the Canadian
Aboriginal languages okay so that that
that is kind of mmm that's still
interesting but in a different way
because I was thinking I thought I
thought this is some Canadian languages
writing system but so apparently the
into Inuit language you know the
language who has a thousand words for
since no Eskimo they have a thousand
words for snow guys so apparently they
they don't have a writing system okay
okay so I was thinking I'm gonna use
Emacs to create a Unicode page on this
maybe not so maybe that's it for today
so let's see what else
chikka box like Wikipedia what okay so
more comments more comments what do I
know about astronomy I don't know much
about astronomy well I know about
astronomy co-signs astronomy co sighs
you know the okay so a strand astronomy
co-signs you know it used to be in
astronomy we use these signs for example
these planets Mercury Venus Earth Mayo
Mayo and that's a moss they are named
after the Greek gods actually Roman gods
but a woman the Roman gods borrowed the
Greek Greek gods Jupiter Saturn Uranus
then astronomy because symbol for Uranus
and Neptune then you have the
astrology's yeah the astrology science
okay there is which is every day every
day in in newspapers and women's
magazines and you have to put them there
because you know people need it and then
they then you know a strong astronomy
astronomy is intimately tied to weather
which is enter me intimately tied to
food you know you know why why
trigonometry and all the math developed
because of food you want to eat you need
wheat and rice you want to have wheat
and rice you need to know the weather
the patterns the patterns of the gods
and if you want to know that you
you gonna know trigonometry and stuff
yes you've got no basic astronomy you
look at the heavens see what's going on
you know then you you know when is
summer when it's winter and stuff
the the commencement of civilization you
know math trigonometry but and in anyway
so there are some interesting things
here okay then
okay so futo then well you don't I don't
have found here some obscure symbols but
anyway in the in the early days in the
early days astronomy they used to use
these symbols not today because we
become more advanced and you have this
sick sextile sextile sick some semi
sextile so Chris quadrate then you have
quincunx okay then you have well
actually this one is this theis okay
this Unicode calls it dice face five no
this this is actually called quincunx
okay this character in fact you can look
up wikipedia okay such that for that
character your seek quincunx not not the
dice man let's see okay so let's just
type quincunx qu i n CU and x quincunx
fascinating the fascinating history of
human animals you look at that this so
this is called quincunx okay and why
because wow there's a history to it
somewhat complicated
I guess quincunx so you know so when you
look at the Unicode
you learn about these things you learn
about these obscure random things and
there we have the symbol for descending
extending not descending not conjunction
opposition and some of these are used in
astrology okay so for example this sixth
I think this sextile sextile and
sextiles scenery Emily sent some scenery
and hexxit Oh in sixth and hexam oh and
six six more okay so I guess I'm getting
boring so so so let's shut down in three
minutes
so you have this astronomy symbol so
yeah I don't I don't know much about
astronomy you know it's interesting so
much to study I you know astronomy
physics cosmology chemistry by our
biology and in fact I was watching a
video that tells you how to live up 250
years but be young stay young like you
are 30 years 30 forever and in fact that
is possible and we are approaching that
and yeah we are approaching that and
that the science of that is called
citizen se and ye see I and ye something
like that I spelled it wrong because you
know English very insane say nursing
okay say nursing is the scientific word
for the study of Aging
now what does aging means I mean from a
biological point of view you study
yourselves you know you you for example
we know what aging is you get old you
know you get ugly like me you lost your
hair that's aging but what does it mean
actually in turn
of your sales your you know biology well
this is a study that cinesín so that's a
would okay that says that's that means
biological aging you look at aging from
a biology you know the cells were they
what they what happens to them what they
do how you know what what's the
difference between a young guy young
person and the old person in their body
cells you know you study them so that's
called cinesín biological aging so so
today we actually know some of the some
of the reasons why we a age you know the
and you know so if you can actually we
and you can practice you know the you
can you know how to how to sell out how
to live up to 150 but stay like 30 years
old you suffer hunger and you suffer the
elements that is you want to do
intermittent fasting okay you want never
eat for never eat a full meal
you know you drink you go to Starbucks
and drink or good drink and you eat fish
you eat cuisines
you eat Kume fantastic wonderful things
that technology has brought us around
the world like in health well especially
in California well in many of big cities
you go to the 3ds or Chinese food
Japanese food of sushi Oh Indian Indian
curry Oh fantastic then you have lamps
then you have the Greek sandwich you
have the Islamic how do you go that
there's this kind of a blob of okay so I
need so you guys what's up what's food
that a rate that basically came from
Middle East Arabia country eat I can't
remember the words at momen it's on my
turn but it's like a plop of mashed the
it's made of it's kind of mixed with a
live audio so guys what's the word
what's word
no not gyro gyro is the kind of a Greek
sandwich I think it's it's okay the
texture is like mashed mashed potatoes
okay it's eaten in Middle East Shama no
it's pretty common okay so actually I go
to the fridge no no not those hummus yes
thank you
love us now have you guys seen that we
actually we have a restaurant down here
that's that that's just focused on Hamas
I didn't know what what the hell that is
until like 10 years ago I went to this
girl okay girlfriend in in in Maryland
and she introduced you know she showed
me this thing and this thing is
fantastic and it's full feeling this
this Hamas thing okay so it's you know
so the texture is like mashed potato is
all soft creamy you know but it's it's
made of you know oh yo and I don't know
you go look at Wikipedia and it's
fantastic in fact I have a actually let
me let me go get it okay so anyway the
trick to live longer and stay young is
used you do intimate meat and fasting
okay and I'm going to get that hummus
and that will be here today let's wish
allow me one minute
chick chick peas yes it's made out of
chickpeas and they put olive oil on it
and so there is the hummus so you can
see this is like $6 okay so it's like it
says organic well in California
everything is organic there's nothing
that's not organic okay so that and that
you cannot see where I guess
so let's and let's put this
hmm
you
janeshia so we cross on you a minute
thank you guys for coming and let's see
what you guys are saying what are you
saying
check out the tired of also darks
Christian monks show you know what what
what is Google doing so you cannot so
you cannot so when you say check out the
diet of Orthodox Christian monks Google
is gonna censor it in fact it did Jesus
Oh Reaper Hey Reaper finally I see you
on YouTube with the same name Reaper
grim correction Thomson impact of
developed utf-8 yes I know and they are
they they developed it on a napkin you
know that that's a UNIX you know the
UNIX people the UNIX philosophy people
they love to chant it every day chant
chant utf-8 it's developed on a napkin
okay bye guys have a good day Sunday and
tomorrow you cannot go to work
well you make money like so anything
else last words say your last words and
we we say goodbye you're gonna say your
last words keyboard pong so we have key
word poem we have California flags we
have Eskimo Eskimo Inuit how do you
pronounce it oh and Ali Jude wait how do
you pronounce Inuit
Inuit language
ah that God is so complicated then they
mentioned so many other things the
endless pit of the Wikipedia endless
good morning Bart yes I want your
salaries bye bye guys
where is it
hell not hit it