to another episode of EX talk show today
we are going to do emac lisp kind of a
teaching session for those of you emac
fans especially lisp fans am I live live
been kicking fantastic so let me
introduce my keyboards and let's move on
to emac dis if you have questions and
comments ask okay mostly about emac
today so my keyboards this is glove 80
fantastic this this is Ultimate hacking
keyboard to Fantastic functional
lighting different color for different
functionality of the keyboard and lots
of you ex uh wanted to see is the is
this s board s v a l b o a r d so I'm
getting onto it you know I will be using
it you know so but not ready yet uh and
actually I got all the cables if you
watched the last live stream I got all
the cables thanks to Clen I got all the
cables I need it's very nice so I'm
going to show you okay you just have to
be a bit more patient so let's move on
to emac this okay if you are here say hi
fantastic let's begin I think I got five
people watching three okay so uh emac
disp okay so emac disp I you know I fail
out that it is the best lisp today
because you know the major lisps lisps
common lisp scheme lisp emac lisp and
closure lisp that's essentially the four
major lisps today now common lisp is
kind of dead okay I mean you you you do
have Fanatics you know you have like
little bunch of fanatics but common LP
hasn't had you know the It's Kind it's
dead okay it's dead the standard hasn't
been updated and it's not likely going
to have any new update it's the standard
hasn't been updated for 25 years also so
common disp is kind of dead like Pearl
uh and scheme disp you know scheme disp
is a s story scheme L lisp is or scheme
racket
lisp uh because racket is uh let's see
let me show you racket lisp so scheme is
a lisp and racket is a you know in the
beginning it's a scheme disp but then
they changed their name to racket about
10 years ago and but is still mostly
just scheme disp uh so scheme disp is
much better than common disp common lisp
is a cancer okay com common lisp is a
cancer Amon lisp that just made the list
everything is bad okay now of course
there's a lot L common L phonetics they
will say otherwise anyway schim lisp is
a better lisp by techn technically by
the design but however scheme this has a
problem because it forever is connoted
with the notion of minimalist and
beautiful that basically kills it okay
for 20 years for 30 years you know we I
you know we wish scheme this is going to
grow and you know become popular uh
there up and downs but you know it's
basically de
well I mean it's not completely that
it's just like used among Academia among
the bunch of this you know this Fanatics
like forever you know it's never going
to use be in in industry in general I
mean of of course occasionally you'll
see skem this fans saying oh look at
this game or oh look at this popular guy
is saying we you know there's some
little companies that use schim this but
it's you know it's basically dead so in
comparison
for context for example for any scheme
lisp and Racket lisp combined there are
10,000 more jobs in goland okay in
goland 10,000 like 10,000 times more not
just 10,000 more 10 thou 10,000 times
more jobs in in in goland or in in fact
C+ plus Java or
python so in general if you want to com
anyway so schim this you know it's
forever in a niche killed by the concept
of beautiful and minimalism and killed
by the concept of tail recursion tail
recursion and everything is recursion
you know recursion Obsession and uh
killed by tail recursion and Co CC Co cc
is one of the most idiotic thing in
programming languages you know it's
among a niche like like if you view
programming language in a particular way
then course C is like the best thing
because it allows you to programat
programmatically control the
language control the the semantics of
the language essentially Co CC
essentially Co cc is the engine that
that is the heart of control flow if
while loop you know if you know those
conditionals are the essence of
programming languages without
conditionals any language seizes to be a
language because you cannot control it
you know you it just simply you know so
so conditional like if statements while
statements switch or condition you know
that Branch control that is the essence
that makes programming languag is uh
true incomplete in other
words uh so so so what is what what is
the cor CC thing cor cc is a like kind
of the heart of the mechanism for for
this Branch control okay so in most
languages you don't have that you just
have you know the the if statements
while statements for Loop and so on but
scheme racket scheme invented you know
they are the language Geeks they created
this called CC concept which can
Implement all that
so and Implement others so scheme so in
this particular view scheme language is
kind of oh it's the the most advanced
because you can actually
programmatically control all this all
this create all these conditional uh
structures uh I mean in the
language in real time
so in at run time so I mean so in that
view scheme is great but no no language
you know almost vast majority of
programming language don't have that you
don't need that you know that's for Tech
you know language uh Obsession you know
Enthusiast you know might want to do
that or if you need to create different
varieties of languages which is What
racket is good at but so in general
scheme is you know it's just used by a
few handful
phonetics Okay so in Kar Forum if you
guys haven't join joined yet hello guys
so Ina Discord you can see some of the
scheme Fanatics and common list Fanatics
for example this
zel what's his name you know he's a
scheme fanatic and and Oliva I think
he's also you know we have quite a few
you know like uh following schim LP or
common disp why because
lisp and common lisp was the kind of the
the
lisp meanwhile emac lisp usually have a
low uh reputation because you know when
scheme lispers look at emac lisp or the
common lispers look at emac lisp they
sneer you know this these phonetics they
sneer at emac LP why because imagist
is essentially is just a embedded
language for controlling or extending
emac so it is not a general purpose so
in fact it is not truly a general
purpose it's just working within emx so
for extending Emax so you cannot use it
to for example write a database write a
web server right write a email server
embedded into a robotics you know uh
embedded into whatever you know
microphone microphone microwave chips
you know embedded programming or writing
or operating system so anyway so emac
this is kind of just a scripting
so-called scripting language I mean um I
mean a embedded language for extending
emac so when the scheme lispers and
common lispers they look at emac lisp
usually they snear you know as far as
online you know chatting goes usually
you they just sne emx
so when so often but still they are all
lisp so lisp lisp people lisp
programmers tends to they just like lisp
languages so skim language will you know
do some emac lisp emac lisp coder will
you know go into scheme Lis or common LP
and so on so you know it's kind of like
a
family so that's common l dead scheme LP
kind of dead I mean niche in a Academia
and uh emac disp so we are usually
inferior in a sense but emac LP is
actually the most widely used emac uh
lisp because of emac because emac is
still alive you know used by many
programmers even they don't program this
or even they don't uh yeah they don't
program this but but they do you know
write in
files so all these init files you see in
emx it's all lisp it's just it's not
special
config code it's actually just lisp code
emac lisp code so that's uh kind of the
background and settings of common disp
schim disp emac disp and what I want to
tell you is that you know so schim disp
is dead common disp is dead and emac
disp in recent years I became more in
love with it so you know I you know so
that's what that's you know that's why
I'm saying emac Lis is the best lisp but
it's true emac this do have a critical
restriction you know see you know it is
just a language used within emac
okay am I doing good say hi guys okay
let me check who is here R uh head
count physics hello
physics leder
hello Lon I I IDK I don't know
hello uh zuu hello I remember the name
is
Ru can you show us a snippet of code
with this thing what thing what thing
emac list is the best list indeed okay
so let me continue let me continue so
today I mostly I want to show some emac
this code about doing sequences so on
the data structure list Vector
sequences hello uh
tjack so we talked about common LP
scheme disp Racket and emac disp now
there's another one actually let me
mention two other big lisps still alive
so one is closure lisp
okay so one of them in you know uh
actually I do have a tutorial closure
lips lisp if you go to um
w.info so you got go down you go down
programming language tutorials there is
a closure list I don't I didn't put it
here but you uh go here then you can see
there is I I started to you know this is
about 10 years ago I worked on closure
for about a year so I have some tutorial
not really good but so anyway closure
disp is one of the main thisp that is
alive in
industry but the bad thing is that it's
it's written on top of java Java virtual
machine so you need to install the whole
Java and uh it's intertwined with Java
so to
fully understand closure lisp you have
to you have to basically fully
understand Java that that makes closure
list not my choice you know like if you
don't have a powerful machine every time
you start some Java application all the
fans start to who and you know it's slow
and so on anyway closer lisp is the
industrial lisp this is a lisp you can
still get a
job uh not too many but you can still
get a job okay closure lisp and it
deviate from the traa traditional lisp
in a significant way because in closure
lisp you don't have the cons anymore
which uh which I you know we may talk
about closure Lis so if you go to my
emac tutorial you know this Basics or
these are fundamentals of
Lis uh so for example you see there's a
data structure list Vector sequence type
and hash table hash table is a
dictionary called a dictionary in Python
uh which is basically is a pairs key
value pairs okay so you go to list and
uh so you can learn everything you need
to know about list data structure list
data type all the functions how to
create a list how to get elements how to
modify it how to Loop overhead iteration
how to check a element exist you know
all these are list
functions so but one thing but if you
after you learn the basic you start to
learn about how list is actually made of
con sales okay this is this conseles
crippled lisp since let's say year 2000
now before year 2000 you know in a AI
era conel is is like you know from
1960s the birth date birth decade of
lisp to let's say year 2000 cons cons
work fine
but but but not today okay k k became
the quio you know this cons killed thisp
in my
opinion now this opinion is very
controversial because all the lisp
Fanatics you know from the scheme lisp
common lisp including Richard stowman he
has article about why
he like he don't know he claims that he
doesn't know closure and then he made a
comment you know closure is no good
because closure doesn't have
cons the most idiotic opinion okay so
this opinion is controver controversial
now in order to explain why I think it
that way um it will be uh somewhat
involved uh I'm not sure I'm going to do
it yeah because most YouTube watch us
you know uh so anyway so cons you know
list is made of con cells let me try to
Simply
explain so this is getting into our main
topic today list vector and sequence
functions okay so yeah let me wrap up
wrap up about closure so closure doesn't
have cons
closure when you have a list of vector
or whatever they actually don't call it
Vector they use closure uses the data
structure of java so in Java you
have interfaces interfaces is what you
deal with for different data structures
for example array list or growable list
or collection then hash table you know
they they have then stack uh linked list
stack or first in
last out you know
key you know so in programming you have
data structures or these are data
structures now in most programming
languages you
have you know that you have many of
these build in you have a function to
create a specific data structure and
then you have functions to deal with
that data structure for example in a
list you want to add a item or check get
a element at n index things like that
but in
Java you you have the interface concept
so you have the interface for list you
have a interface for key value payers
you know dictionary or hash table you
have a interface for stack data
structure you
see so so you deal with interfaces which
is kind of like the structureal concept
of what this data type data structure
you need to do with the data structure
then okay so interfaces then for
particular interface then you have
implementation code to implement those
interface so they separated into you
know kind of like the API application
programmers interface so you deal with
just the interface then you have inter
implementation beneath them they they
made it separate okay that's
so you have um so for example uh okay
let's look at
Java okay we I'm digressing a lot into
kind of a general discussion about
programming
languages uh but I've been talking for
20 minutes uh we'll move on okay so in
Java you have interfaces you know you
can if you uh you can look at my
tutorial then you can have a basic
understanding so interface is just
basically an API basically a function it
tell you what methods are you know what
arguments are the function and what
methods are available for the
function so interface you know so and so
closure so why am I talking about Java
interface and implementation because
closure is implemented on top of java so
closure ad adapted Java's way so you
don't have a direct list or direct array
or direct hash table or dictionary
instead you have closure you know
follows the use uses the interface of
java so in closure you don't have the
you know
list uh do we have you know you don't
have cones that which is a concrete
thing to implement list you don't have
that so you just have you know list
interface and so on so anyway closure is
the you know you can still find a job in
Industry closure is the main uh lisp
industrial risp
today so which is the best
list you know so common lisp is De I do
not like and I do not recommend common
lisp is the cancer of lisp the worst
[ __ ] possible or the most worst
[ __ ] uh in my last video I gave some
details this a lot you know if I go into
details it's going to be endless in this
video so you can search for the
fundamental problems of lisp that's one
thing but common lisp is lot of you know
it's just [ __ ] all over you know it's
filled with
um okay let me let me show a few article
quickly okay so let's um
famous programmers on how common this
sucks okay and controversy of common
this package in emac disp you know there
a big war for the past 20 30 years you
know there's a war in in in emac LP
because a lot people you know they they
want to change emac LP into common lisp
be because they are commonly
Fanatics meanwhile a lot the skin fans
when they use emac they want emac lisp
to become more like scheme lisp so that
it's more beautiful and it's more well
designed so the you know for the past 30
years you know the every every few years
there's a big flame wall you know even
to up to this day so anyway so
uh so you know for example this article
uh and this one is
new so famous programmers on how common
L SU you know you have gu steo which is
one of the creator of schim LP uh I
believe so yeah and he's also the
founder of emac okay before Rich
stowman K steel okay uh then you have
stowman also Richard San also don't like
common list and you have uh uh Richard P
Gabriel which is the founder
of uh AI company Lucid Inc which gave us
today the Legacy is XX which is kind of
dead but uh Rodney Brook is a computer
scientist you know you have Wikipedia
links to their Arles uh so and Paul bham
and Danielle wre who wrote the first
lisp emx lisp based
emx all by himself you know you know
Richard stowman emx came later so all
these people heavily
criticized common lisp you know some
would say common lisp killed lisp and I
myself after you know the past 30 years
you know be because I started in
1993 on wolam language that's another
thing I want to talk about wolf language
is actually just a lisp okay few people
know and every time I talk to this
common this people they they desp they
don't know nothing about it but then but
then they we just despise it you know
because they are
Fanatics usually this happens when in
online conversations even before you
know today before the social social
network social uh yeah social networking
websites you know back then in news
groups and and mailing list so anyway so
all these people despise you know you
know they think common this is uh WS you
know
cancer okay so and another AR
controversy of common list packages in
in emac LP so this is you know this is a
controversy for the past 30 years at
Leist uh you know between usually
between the common list factions and the
scheme L
factions you know roughly speaking so
they you know like every time emac you
know needs a new feature or you know add
a new function there's a war uh and uh
for example many people criticize emac
don't have threats every time you do
some something it freezes you have to
wait for that to finish that's one of
the major flaw of emac why does that
happen because emac this is not
threaded so it's you know it's this is
idiotic idiotic jargon loved by the C
C++ idiots thread okay thread should be
banned in programming but anyway
so they say so emac this is single
threaded basically just means it just do
one thing at a time then it stops you
know overall it there's a loop so you
know then it stops wait for your input
then you know so it's single thread just
means that it does one thing at a time
it cannot do parallel or concurrent
concurrent so that's one major problem
so a lot of people want to improve it
you know some people um so anyway
there's a big controversy between the
common list phonetics and schem list
fanatics on the future of emac lisp big
you know for 30 years you have to
remember you know now because I'm now
I'm getting old you are younger maybe
you haven't heard of it or maybe you
just heard the last one maybe five years
ago like every every five years there's
a you know
big uh either movement or argument you
know or someone implemented emac this in
scheme then they discussing you know go
emac people discussing how they're going
to change you know maybe replace emac
this so every time it's a huge
controversy for 30
years so how how do I know you know for
example for example uh this article in
written in 2008 thoughts on common this
scheme this based on emx I wrote this
2008 because back then there's already
you know big controversies for you know
as far as I know so I wrote a kind of my
thoughts uh okay so I digress too much
uh and here
is here is my new kind of article why
common list sucks
okay worst you know the worst
[ __ ] language uh you know Common list
you have the CLA thing
C which stand for common list object
system it's a worst [ __ ] possible okay
common this object system what does that
mean object you know that means
objectoriented programming like C++ in
Java object by ask the most
important uh aspect that this is a
greatest thing one of the Great language
is functional programming okay lisp is
the first functional programming created
by John McCarthy in
1960s first functional programming
language but this common list idiots
they don't they don't know it they
forgot they don't know they don't know
you know they don't know nothing about
the original ideas about mathematics
they don't know this common this object
system
you'll see it excited Often by the
common list idiots like they are excited
they they you know typically what they
are say that you know oh Java is stupid
C++ is stupid because in common this we
actually have this common this object
system which is a generalized system so
you can dispatch dispatch these idiots
these are extreme idiots
okay that's not mathematics that's not
functional program me that [ __ ] up the
essence essential good qualities of lisp
okay [ __ ] up by this common LP
[ __ ] you know common lisp object
system and then you have EI EO which is
basically
C that is implemented in emac disp
okay and then common disp has this set
F okay to explain that we'll take three
minutes I'll just skip it I explained it
in the past but set F set F you know set
set f is one of the thing that common
again it's one of the thing that common
will often mention why why this makes
common this this superb language in fact
it is most insulting idiotic [ __ ]
introduced into this okay the set
F what does it it do let me see let me
just show you simply quickly okay let's
say python okay everyone understand
python
so you see x equals to 3 print X okay
let's do that let's run that uh save it
okay let's save
it okay python you know X you know let's
run it three you see uh let's say x you
know
so what are we doing what is this this
is setf okay why how it's just
assignment why is that set up let me
explain so usually when you have a value
for example print x x is a variable it
has a value so the pring language
evaluate that variable to a value so
this three this x becomes three that's
why it prints three okay but now when
you have this assignment that X has
special properties
it doesn't you know the priming language
treated in a special way because if you
evaluate this x do doesn't make sense
because when if you evaluate that X that
becomes it's not n defined n defined
equals to three what does that mean you
see so in vast majority of
languages you have this
assignment uh operator which treats the
left hand in a a special way so the left
hand can be a reference so here it
actually become a reference which is a
stupid concept okay it's not a
mathematical concept so you know
magically you have this New Concept
called reference that doesn't exist in
mathematics okay so this x is you know
it's not like math math is you know X we
Define the value of x to be3 but in
programming languages that's not you
know it's it doesn't work you have to
you have to introduce the New Concept of
a reference and what what does that mean
oh it's a Memory it's address to memory
what is then it's a CPU you know it's a
CPU architecture you know bits you know
this C and C++ idiots love they love
this thing then you got pointers and
references and pointers they love this
so anyway this
assignment it has a
its semantic is unusual so programming
languages when they have assignment
usually they have unusual uh
semantics uh so the left hand side is
treated as a reference now this
particular this phenomenon this this
this uh situation this um particular
particularly stand out when you have a
uh list or array okay let me show you
let's
say uh X list okay so in in Python you
know so let's say
345 okay uh okay let's let's comment out
okay so let's say print X list okay does
that work yes the syntax is correct so
you got a list of 345 and you want to
print it so but now let's say I want to
change
the the second element to nine okay so
what you do is you can do this
okay that that okay the let's change the
first element okay zero index okay
equals to 9 okay 99 okay then you print
you print this okay do
it uh wait uh what
do it uh
what oh no uh I got the double wrong
okay just single I got confused with
wolam language been coding wolam
language too much okay so you say x list
at the zeroth index set it to 99 okay so
you run it so you got a new list 9945
okay so but look at this carefully
normally when you do the bracket at the
end that that means get get the element
of that list so the zeroth element index
is three okay then you assign 3 to 99
that doesn't make sense so again this is
assignment operator so the left hand
side becomes a
reference okay now that is what this
setup
is in normal languages you know they
they don't they don't have a special
name but the in but when it comes to the
common L idiots they call it
generalized
something gen what what they call
General generalized variable something
let me let's look at the documentation
there then we'll see
okay uh set off it came to emac okay
which is a it's a cancer that got into
emac disp okay you can see set off set F
okay you see then you got this this
incomprehensible documentation set F
Place V play what the [ __ ] is Place
normally it's a variable right set Q you
know but now it's place you know so it
says set each place to the value of its
V this is a generalized version of set Q
you see least
people you know in in Python in Python
oh it's this is basic this is for
children you know this is just a syntax
okay you assign an element to a you know
a list you know new you you change you
modify a element in a list right basic
for children but when it comes to
um uh Let's do let's uh when it comes to
the leis idiots they could you know this
is a generalized version Oh my God
generalized so superb fantastic
Supreme the the places may be symbolic
references such as car and AR R and then
you know then it gets esoteric you
know the most idiotic concept now you
wonder what why we can't have this in
Python but when when we have the same
thing in lisp it becomes
idiotic here's why because syntax the
most important element in a programming
language syntax because in
thisp uh because in
thisp let's show some disp code okay uh
so let's show some disp
code so why is it idiotic when you bring
exactly the same semantic to thisp
because the lisp
syntax make it
explicit you know make it make the
semantics of the code much more explicit
so when you when you bring this
exceptional irregular semantics into
this it stand
out uh for
example okay I'm digressing you know I
started to digress into the set of set F
and I haven't get into
generics I haven't got to today's topic
which is sequence functions but that's
okay that's the S talk show my style
okay so when you have set Q 3 you know
that's how you set a variable in lisp
okay but now let's let's duplicate this
uh this python into this code okay let's
do
that so let's let's duplicate the python
code here okay so let's say so this
would be set Qs list okay and uh uh okay
uh this would be list 3 four five okay
let's forget about Vector okay then uh
you want to print okay
print
uh okay fantastic okay uh let's show the
python side by side so you can
see how is python okay
okay that correspond to that then these
two lines correspond to these two lines
then then we have this set okay so here
is where set F comes in okay so set
F uh okay so set F then you have oh
then then you get you need to get the
first element of the list okay so how do
you do that you do
elt uh X list then zero okay then you
here put 99 okay that's
that then you just print yeah okay then
you just
print you see okay
so on top is python on at the bottom is
thisp they are you know like
translations so you can see where the
set F comes in set F so when you have
the lisp syntax the unusual semantics
becomes apparent because normally in
list I mean in list every element just
evaluate but here it doesn't it doesn't
because this middle part you are getting
the element of a list right you are
getting the zero gr
index so it returns a value but actually
no because when the E when the elt
function is placed in this inside this
set F the semantic Changed [ __ ] the
common lpus [ __ ] heads it you can see
the semantic changed so what does this
mean is that given a this expression
where you place it changes the meaning
okay change it changes the meaning CH
you know so in scheme this fans they
will say
the uh what they call transparency
um I forgot what's a Jon but
anyway so you um do okay
with this set
F the Lis expression changed meaning
depending on its context let's
say so it's semantically context
dependent
okay okay I digressed too much I think
maybe uh so it's 40 minutes shall I
continue to
discuss uh kind of a tutorial on the
sequence and Vector data structure in
emac disp because that's that was my
original purpose for this
video okay so let a common list problems
okay so this video will be probably
should be renamed to why common list
sucks refer referential transparency
thank you Todd Fisher yeah that you know
that's what you know you
see each programming language
Community they code okay each
programming language code typically they
have a few things they are found to
recite for example in emac that would be
um marro okay marro and scratch buffer
okay marro scratch buffer and uh and
buffer okay the emac people will just
cite it buffer is is buffer buffer
buffer scratch bu or and Meta Meta
scratch buffer and Mar okay it's a emac
now in scheme disp there's a few refer
referential transparency is one of the
things scheme lisp every time you talk
to SP scheme this one out of you know 10
times out of you know something they
they they mention referential
transparency tail recursion
do you have tail recursion why don't you
write this in tail recursion tail
recursive tail tail call and the other
one is call CC okay call CC scheme
idiot and common disp common disp it's
you know
CLA uh uh Closs and uh generics okay
typically
and python python has its own pythonic
and pro has its own you know more than
one way to do it and so
on usually C languages has it uh for
example some of the C languages
python Pearl Pearl python lisp
especially thisp Pearl python thisp
hascal when it comes to hascal the most
famous you know
monad do you have monad you should do it
monad way that's not a proper monad you
should this monad is is like a
burrito [ __ ] these cat
idiots uh and uh Java o you know
everything must be o op
methods okay
so so I kind of digressed all over let's
see what the comments and maybe we
uh okay let's regroup a bit let's put
this back
to let's put the code back to our talk
show uh today's talk show so we went
over
[Music]
basically why common this
sucks okay what is this article uh emx
blog okay so I was going to talk about
that
uh yeah so cut that and
uh okay syntax
color the fruit of today's code okay so
let's see what else so close that close
that okay so we kind of went over this
the whole disp yeah um and there's
another disp I want to mention w
language okay let me just mention it
quickly so you can you know wam
language um is kind of lisp you can you
can you can say it's actually totally
disp it's just a disp okay uh and uh for
example in this article disp versus wam
language you can see everything in this
there's a exactly basically exactly the
same comp
uh can same concept in wolam language
for example identifiers are symbols
everything is a expression everything an
expression is an is either an atomic
expression such as a string or a number
or a list okay so everything is a
expression expression is either Atomic
like a string or number or it's a list
okay so you know your whole program is a
list basically same thing in wolfen
language
purely nested syntax and predominantly
functional programming okay not not like
hascal like pure but you know mostly
functional for me and you have reader
maros and you have uh syntactical
shortcuts in Wolf language they they
extend the concept concept of rer Mar in
a systematic way in a gramat in the in a
language grammar systematic way
so it's not just you know you know the
the back TI and that
idiocy so read the maros then you have L
lisp maros in wam language again that's
extended into a systematic way so it
became a complete pattern matching
language in fact wolam language became a
term rewriting system
okay so example what what's the
difference for example in in in lisp
okay scheme disp common lisp emac lisp
if you have a
symbol let's say new okay if it's not
defined if you evaluate it let's
evaluate it you got error void variable
X
new okay but in wolam language it
doesn't treat it that way every symbol
if it's new it's just create a symbol
it's new so you actually
achieved the goal of symbolic
computation okay let me show
you so uh let's say start with
three uh plus 3
two eval
okay now let's say
x x new okay Enter you see it doesn't oh
error ER
you know X new is not defined it just
return the symbol itself so that allows
you to do lots of things for example
this is f a function evaluated at x x do
not have a value F do not have a value
it's all symbolic it doesn't generate
error it's you know that's what you want
you know symbolic computation so but if
you now
Define uh for example if you now Define
you know you can now Define f to be
let's say s + one okay let's just say
that now you define it now if I now if
you do FX again it becomes 1 plus X you
see so this both thisp and wam language
are symbolic because every symbol is is
a every identifier is a symbol but
wolfan language again take it to a new
higher level when a symbol doesn't have
a value it return
itself which in turn allows you to have
this kind of thing so for example let's
let me do another
um Nest let's say G three times okay
uh oh yeah uh okay so nest
of a function g at the initial value of
y three times okay so you got this you
know you got this symbolic
result G doesn't have a meaning right
now why doesn't have a meaning right now
but you got this in symbolic result and
that can became something else once you
define a value so this is this is the
root of what stepan wolam calls symbolic
programming language symbolic
computation you know symbolic
computation is known start from lisp
because everything is symbols that's how
it different from java python goand C++
you know however wolam language takes it
one step further
okay so that's about so wolam language
is you know so all the characteristics
of lisp is in wolam language and then
you know on this page you can see side
by side comparison of the syntax of the
grouping you know p o GN in W language
is called compound expression
arithmetics
functions uh buing how do you you know T
and Ne and or not greater than you know
so there's a corresponding one in wol
language just you know on
everything set Q in this you have set
and set delayed you know and let you
have modu block with with you know a bit
different naming uh a bit different
naming philosophy okay so flow control
if condition throw catch error it's
about the same thing in W language then
iteration while map car map C two times
you know about the same more advanced in
W language and in in fact in W language
usually you have like a lot more then
you have data structure list and Vector
now this part is interesting this is
today's main you know we were going to
talk about this so in lisp languages
typically skin scheme lisp common lisp
emac lisp you have list and Vector that
is the two primary sequential data
structure sequence of things and then
you have hash table
okay so same thing exactly same thing in
Wolf language you know in in fact
instead of list and Vector you just have
one single thing list okay so in Wolf
language it's like the whole language is
exactly it's just a list it's just like
a list okay the whole language is simply
a list a giant huge list you don't even
have a vector everything is a list
except except the implementation is not
like lists list with cons it doesn't
have cons okay
so in fact the wolfen language list is
actually lists lists Vector okay but now
you see here's another interesting thing
now in hash
table lisps has hash table like 30 years
ago but wam language does not so so wam
language is even more pure lisp than
then all the lisps than than common lisp
or scheme lisp it does not have hash
table data
structure but about seven years ago they
added it okay so that's what that's why
now you do and and wfam language calls
it Association which
is you know in lisp you have another
data structure called associate
Association list which is actually just
a list but wam language has you know
used the same name Association but that
is actually a hash table
but the thing interesting is that this
Association is
added uh only only like seven years ago
okay so we let's look at um the date it
is added so what is this emac
lisp uh yeah so let's go to wolam
language
Association uh let's go to the
documentation wolam language
Association turn on JavaScript and
magnify
okay so this is actually a hash table so
you can go down uh it's it's new in 2014
so it's only 10 years old for the first
20 years of wolfen language you do not
have a hashtable data type in Wolf
language there's a reason for that you
know I can you know I can go into detail
about why wam language avoided hash
table for a long long time well the the
essential reason is that because hash
table because wfam language wants to
wants everything to be representable as
a sequence of text okay but when H when
you have a hash table that cannot be
represented as a text or I mean I mean
in a consistent way in a typical list
lisp way
so and so
further what is the what is hashtable
table is essentially just list list of
pairs list of pairs of
list but it just have special behavior
okay but on a Surface from the look of
it it's just simply a list of list so
you you don't really truly need hash
table in a
sense so anyway that's some uh that's
about wam language okay
so then functions exactly you know
functions in both languages input and
output and packages this also gets
interesting because in lisp world you
have load require features autoload you
know these are from emac disp but common
disp is kind of the same okay so in wam
language you have exactly the
counterpart just almost exactly so it's
you know quite interesting then then
marus okay read the marus and uh oh yeah
these are reader marus this is not
um uh you know the syntax maros anyway
read the maros so wam language
expanded so anyway
so so you um so that's introduction to
kind of wolam language in the family of
lisps we talked about common lisps skin
lisp imag this closure and uh now wolf
language okay I think maybe that's it
for today um I'm going to answer
questions maybe that's it so it's been 1
hour how many people are watching am I
doing good 14 not too
bad okay so let's see questions CH Ching
pay me okay now if you uh Super Chat
Super Chat is going to take half thank
you blood seing Google but you can
always pay me by going
[Music]
to code homepage all the way bottom you
have patreon you have Amazon gift card
you have
PayPal
okay uh today's video is sponsored by
you let me tell you what great person
you are you must use you because you are
the best thing so please support
you thank you for
sponsorship can you show us a snippet of
code with this thing what thing youa
this okay conditional uh the racket
conditional
thingi uh you are talking
about the racket conditional
thing uh what will I
say I forgot what is the context
sorry
uh racket conditional I forgot what that
did so why is emac this being embedded a
good thing why wouldn't general purpose
disp be preferred okay it's not a good
thing I mean emac disp just happens to
be embedded language in emex so that
means there's a so that means it's a
significantly limited programming
language you cannot write use it to
write a web server or embedded
programming or whatever you know you
just use it for within emac of course
people have tried to make it a database
with emac but that's not
really you
know real
so it would be good it would be
fantastic if emac LS actually became a
general purpose like you
can yeah but that's not you know that's
not going to happen anytime soon you
know you can you of course you can run
emac this as a script just like python
you know I can show it but you know I
have a lot of tutorials on my website
you you search you'll just find it how
to how to run emac this just like a
python script you know you type P P
Python and The Script name and you
so you can do exactly the same with emac
this I showed it many times in the past
okay but it's not you know it's just
it's not a general purpose
language so no I don't you know so but
however as far as general purpose
programming goes there's one thing that
emac is even though it's not a general
purpose language but it is far better
than any language including wolam
language so in this if you are need if
you need to do this thing I'm going to
tell you what that is if you're going to
do if you need to do this thing which is
a kind of major is field of programming
if you need to do this emac disp is
better than common disp better than
schim disp better than wolam language
better than python better than Ruby Java
C++ better than than any
language in the world okay and that
thing is text processing okay that is
you need to you know like there's a lot
things you need to do with text
processing create a report go through
10,000 or 20,000
files but but but there's a issue about
scale if you're going to go in you know
go deal with one
Mega Tetra billion BTE of of text files
then emac this might be slow you know
but anyway emac this is the best
Language by a magnitude if your te if
your task is text processing even even
then even though it's not the general
purpose but if the text processing is
what you need to do go through maybe
maybe Financial reports or whatever
generate report or go through or
Wikipedia you need to kind of do
analysis you know
text you know extract some text extract
all emails in the entire Wikipedia emac
LP is the best thing okay most easy to
do most stable okay text processing emac
LP
uh oh there is interesting question I've
been working with Java for 15 years do
you think it would be easy to transition
into closer lisp if you know emac lisp
yeah yeah sure the main thing is about
it's not about transition into thisis
it's most about thinking in a functional
programming style
so so your main uh issue is
about you know thinking of of
programming from object oriented into
functional way so if you have experience
with that you have no problem you can
just switch to closure that's the main
thing op in to functional programming
way
okay uh yeah arinum aragam is
interesting character because he's a
giant huge commonly
fanatic so he he's not so he's opposite
of me he is a h the biggest common list
fanatic and back in the days you know
during the common list versus scheme he
always just attack the scheme people for
for lots of reasons and uh and you know
and in fact one of my
first post in the lisp Community com.
land. lisp is about the lisp fundamental
problem the Lis cons which I despise you
know
the search
for fundamental problem of
thisp then you'll find my website okay
that that is my
enumeration of the most fundamental Ides
of this okay one of them first of all is
syn syntax
irregularities you have the you know dot
notation you have the back quote back
quote most tic [ __ ] then you have the
you know back tick then you have the
comma you know the
and you know this is one of the thing
the common dis especially common dispers
they love it you know they oh read the
mar [ __ ] idiots that's one of the
most fundamental problem of leis they
you know if you want to improve this
read of it read of like remove all the
[ __ ] only allow the functional uh form
like you know F like parenthesis F
argument argument only allow that re
syntactical regularity that's a power of
lisp and if you read of this this
[ __ ] read the socalled read the mark
my ass read of them your this becomes
more
powerful okay that's one thing but but
but you see the the interesting thing is
that the the leis phonetics they they
they love this and they particularly
will go out and say why these are the
best thing
about
this read the read the maros [ __ ]
idiots okay so I give some reasons why
these are bad okay and you you know if
you really want read the maros you
should go with the wolam language way
extend the syntax in a systematic way so
that so that you know you can write um
so
that so that um let's see some uh uh
let's say arithmetics okay so you can
write 3 minus two like that you don't
have to like parenthesis minus you
know you know you you you have you have
systematic rhm aqual okay wam language
doesn't call rhm marus it's just a short
notation okay so you have a systematic
rhm so your entire
parenthesized expression can be convert
to this read convert to this short F
code um shortcut form I explained you
know this is a big topic so I explain
this in detail you can see your article
uh with
comparison here okay W language Advanced
symbols principles full form and full
form and syntax syntax operators okay
so if you are thinking of uh where is it
uh yeah so this this page explains what
they
mean so this this is a systematic way to
extend the idea
of
uh the lisps socalled reader maros which
is very limited you know with all the
read maros you cannot make it to make it
to infix expression which is necessary
if you need to do
mathematics and this this concept of
short syntax form is actually called
meta expression meta expression which is
a concept created by the creator of lisp
McCarthy John McCarthy okay but he
actually never implemented it so that's
why this just is just became paresis but
in his vision when he began you know is
you supposed to have this this meta
Expressions so any expression can
become like like what we see like Java
or Python's code you know but but the
common list idiots they don't know they
don't
know uh okay so yeah this uh you know so
I can show you a example
so for example here you can see the
difference you see in here it's purely
Nest expression but because you have the
so-called meta expression or short short
uh cut syntax you can write them like
this much more like traditional
programming language you see compare
this versus this fully nested way
you know you you you should follow this
code carefully because every line of
code is just F bracket
something that's it everything so it's
fully purely nested this is W from
language you can convert this to this by
by a press of a key there's one you know
one consistent map between them this is
the power of systematic grammar you
extend the reader marle
systematically to arrive to have this
kind of a shortcut or so-called meta
expression as compared to you know as
compared to
the as compared to the LEP idiosyncratic
read Arro foxs [ __ ] the dispers you know
like oh let's just let's just invent a
back quote let's invent this one so when
you see this it means that let's invent
a palm sign so so functions you know it
becomes function so [ __ ] the [ __ ] the
common dispers especially common dispers
they they they they they will say this
less so lesso with the scheme dispers
of course you can do that so there's a
question we were talking about you know
can you do that yes of
course it just return itself okay uh
except uh did we Define a value for x no
it just return itself it reorder it
because the plus has a meaning you know
the plus the plus operator is orderless
on the arguments so it automatically
reorder
it okay I think that's it
uh yes if you want dynamic dynamic scope
you just use um uh block okay so for
example block uh for example let's say x
equals to 3
okay now X is three now if you want the
local value Dynamic scope okay so you
just say
block uh
and
you uh so you let's say x and here you
can say xal to 4 and here is the body
let's say uh let's say you want let's
just say
print uh
okay so now if you run it you see it
says four because locally that's a dyn
this this block construct is a dynamic
scope okay so here 4X becomes four now
if you evaluate X it's three you know so
that's dyn that
Dynamic who who is my moderator I don't
have a moderator
okay I think that's it for
today uh because it's 1 hour I was going
to do um I was I was originally planning
to expand the sequence
functions but but but uh but I think we
did a
good discussion about the
lisps uh so if you want to know about
sequence functions of course you go to
emac I mean emac this tutorial Basics
you go to data structure section you
have list okay so then you have
everything you need to do you need to
know about
list uh including all the functions
dealing with list then you have the
vector data
structure uh how to make Vector what is
it what is algorithmic properties and
then how do you create it how do you
filter Vector okay
then then you can study the sequence
type so sequence sequence in iMac L is
just a
general well it just means either list
of vector or or string okay it's not a
data type by
itself a sequence data type in emac disp
is not technically a thing it doesn't it
doesn't exist it's simply refers to a
list or a array and array can either
mean a vector or string so a sequence is
you know either list or a vector or a
string you know that's that's what
sequence means so then you have the all
this bunch of sequence functions these
are new about seven years ago fantastic
sequence
functions that can work on any of list
or vector or string okay so this is very
powerful so now finally emac this has
you know you know before you don't have
like you don't even have a filter
function but now you do you can you know
so the argument can be a vector or can
be a list or can be a string so you have
filter you have also kind of you know so
you have sequence iterations um anyway
so that's what I'm talking about
sequence functions okay so that's why I
say it's fantastic you
know uh okay that's it for
today I don't think I have a moderator
no I don't have a moderate moderator
here okay bye guys