Hello, good morning everyone. Welcome to
another episode episode
of Kasar Talk Show. If you are watching
this offline, play at 1.5 speed because
I ramble. If you are watching this live,
enjoy and comment required. Okay,
comment.
And uh we going to code. So what we
going to do today? We're going to code.
So this is going to be emac this coding.
Pure Emacs disping maybe for 30 minutes.
Okay. So what is the job? Well, the job
is
let me show you.
So you see this format CSS code web
page. Now this page is on Emacs tutorial
on.info.
Search for it. You will find it. Emacs
practical Emacs and everything you want
to know. and Emacs Lisp. Okay, the
artificial intelligence programming
language, the daddy of that's Lisp.
Okay, so on this website, you'll find uh
formatting CSS code. Uh okay so for
example I go to uh list basics no kasar
emac packages kasar emac commands and
search for format and you'll find my
code for formatting CSS code. So let's
do a demo. So so what we're going to
write the command so that let me show
you. Okay so CSS code. So, this is my
CSS code for my website about 1,000
pages. Now, let's say I screw up the
formatting one line, but it still works.
Yes. Okay. But if I delete this part,
then the font is going to change.
Refresh. You can you see? So, I don't
want to delete that part. But I want to
like screw up the format. And back to
the browser. Refresh. You can see it
still works. Now I want to automatically
formatted. So I press a key. Press,
press.
Fantastic. You see they become well
formatted. I can you know do several
things like that. Save formatted. Press
a key. Fantastic and beautiful. So you
can see the command code on the pink
window. It will show SA CSS format
buffer. And uh on the left side is the
key I press. I'm using a Vorax keyboard
layout and I'm using KFly keys the most
efficient keybinding system for Emacs
and you can get it's free. There's a
video you can watch keys. There's a
video and there's uh uh you know the
most efficient more efficient than Vim.
Okay, that's what I'm using. So So back
to the back to back to back to CSS. We
demonstrated that code. Now where is
that code? So describe key press you can
see some CSS format buffer right there
and jump to the source code. Open it
expand window. So here's the code and in
this code you can see there is a URL. So
open that page and showing browser we
jumped to the corresponding
homepage for this command. Okay. So I
have like hundreds or thousands commands
you know every day I code emac this you
know I edit you know I update this uh
file. So normally what I do is that for
example if I in fact I just uh modify
you know I just improved this code. So
once I done that I have to like go here
copy the whole function copy defund then
jump to the URL open it then showing
browser okay back to Emacs then search
for pre-tag for example pre right there
so now then I have to like uh
delete whatever is in the pre-tag you
know delete it way select delete. Okay.
Then add uh then add emac this code.
Then paste a new code there. Then
syntax color then show in browser. So
it's kind of tedious.
So what I want to do today is you know
while I'm on this code after I'm done
editing it I just press a key and it
automatically update you know the
corresponding page on my website. That
is what we're going to write today. Okay
so so far so good. Hello go hello tamid.
Okay uh so let's begin coding that. Okay
let's code this command. So this command
is part of Emacs built in. So this
called V VC diff. Okay, you don't need
magic. Uh you know if it's for git
anyway. If you know what I'm talking
about, good. If you don't know, don't
don't uh never mind. So you don't have
to use magic. I stopped using magic for
since like four four or five years ago.
So VC diff is building. Okay. So that's
when you want to know the difference
between uh for example let's update the
date
then save it then call VC diff you can
see this is how it differs from the git
original
so anyway
undo undo okay save it now VC diff again
no change no change between working
revision and work file okay that's good
okay now Let's go back to the talk show.
So we going to uh write this code. So
let's commence commence
commence coding. Okay. Update current
defresponding
website that is copy the current define
function. Uh find the corresponding
website local URL file path. Update the
code in in in that file.
Okay. update the code in that file
in the HTML pre-tag. Okay. So first of
all defund. So we need to select the
defund. Okay. So how do you select the
defund? Uh there's a function um
uh
describe function mark defund. I believe
yes it's building. So there is a
function mark defund.
Uh mark defend put mark at okay position
point at beginning the defend mark is
one that contain point. So far so good.
So far so good. So far so good. Play at
1.5 speed.
Okay. So if the mark is active is
something something something.
Okay. So what um
Okay. So we need to go faster. Okay. So
here's a source code for mark defund.
By the way, there is a problem with mark
defund. You see, if your code is not
formatted in a traditional way, then
mark defund will fail. Okay. So let's
see. Uh is there a
mark defund?
Is there a key for mark defund? Yes.
Space TD. Okay. So, space TD.
Uh, wait. Space TD. Okay, let's try
again. Space TD. Yeah. So, but if your
code is not well formatted, sometimes it
will fail. Space TD. Okay, it works. But
I have a documentation about that. So
just go to uh Emacs tutorial page, go to
the search button and uh then and search
for
uh
I don't think it's marked different.
Search for
uh search for format.
Okay. So I I document
I documented this problem. So
reformat sentence to lines. Change file
new line format. Format CSS code. Format
HTML code. Format JavaScript. Format
PowerShell. Uh format lines for source
code. Format to long lines. Automatic
formatting emac code. Format Golan code.
Format Python code. Auto format.
formatter semantic refactor failed. uh
yeah that you know there are several
packages that does auto formatting of
EMAC lisp but most of them like
you know I think there's only one that's
good but
uh but you know
uh anyway so
yeah I think this one I think is good is
is still there okay so I hope is doing
well. And uh when's the last update?
2005. So it's still kept updated. So I
think this is the best one. Okay. Auto
format this code, but I haven't tried
because it's got, you know, it requires
Python and stuff.
Uh
so anyway so what I want so I what I
want to do is actually to show where is
the uh problem.
Okay go back. I want to show the problem
of
of of
a situation where if you have a valid
Emac V code however you do not have it
formatted
in a traditional Emacs way then several
problems for uh defund you know it it uh
doesn't work okay I have written about
it somewhere here okay I need I want to
find it. Okay. I'm not sure where is
that. So now I am
now I become insistent. We must find
that problem. Okay. You guys understand?
So let's try to find it. Emac mis
miscellaneous and EMAC mis miscellaneous
essays.
So these are a bunch of like some of
them are old essays criticizing
Emac these problems.
Uh so wait so this so what I want to
demonstrate is the um
okay so what do I search for?
So let's see function programming
function output should always have the
same structure. Emac list problem. Trim
trim string rejects uh list list
problem. List one versus list two issue.
Controversy of common list uh eagisp
versus javascript. EMAC this fixed its
namespace problem. Okay. So text
processing eag versus pearl relation to
cursor position beginning end of
matching pairs in source code
validate file links uh function type
syntax coloring meaning of list
symbol versus string what is a function
fn sum and every so that those are
essays about emacis the language emac
naming convention
coding style lead forms text processing
versus structured
uh common list why common list sucks
indeed emac this bite code manual okay
that's the manual eag this history
that's another uh long uh article so
it's not here
uh
functions replacement string multi-pair
replace unsorted Uh okay. So function
frequency list of all hooks beware
region boundary change directory path
should end in a slash unable to undo in
buffer problems of thing at point define
v doesn't override narrow to defend eval
defend bug there it is
okay so let me show you a code okay so
copy that
so here's a code and Let's comment this
out. Let's just com uh let's just
comment that out. So, we got the valid
code here. Is it valid? Let's see. Uh
xx test interactive. Let x set x=
evaluate it. Okay. Now, I can call xx
test
call with uh without output. Yeah,
because it doesn't what does it return?
It returns set set q. What does set q
return? I think it returns the value.
Okay. Describe function set q uh return
the return value of the set q form is
the value of the last value. So close
that close that. So in this case it's
going to be this vector uh this vector.
Okay.
So this is a valid function.
Why? because we just run it uh for
example we just run it uh and and show
uh message buffer. So run it xx test.
Okay. Uh return nothing. But we can also
run it uh by
uh okay. So by
you know like that. So we run it.
You see now you can see it returns three
four. Okay.
So this is a valid code. Now to make
sure let's add this um
okay let's
you know let's uh declare lexical
binding true save it go to the directory
by compile yes
okay unused lexical variable x okay so
okay so let's fix that you know let's
just let's just make Sure.
Okay. So, set Q then let's say messages
X. Let's just print it. Okay.
Okay. Now, evaluate the buffer. Make a
backup. Go to the directory by compiler.
Yes. Is there error? No error. Okay.
Open the by compile file. Delete it.
Close it. Okay. Now this is a valid
function
but now let's try the uh let's try the
narrow to defund what it does to you
know what it does is that usually in
EMAC Emacs you have a narrow function so
if you call narrow you can see narrow to
region
it just hides
h you know it it shows only the uh
select action the the rest of the buffer
the file is hidden. This is useful when
you do find and replace. You only want
to replace for example several
paragraphs. You don't want to re do find
and replace before that or after that.
So you can do narrow to region. So Emacs
then pretends the file is just the the
section you want. Okay. So if you want
to so after you are done you can call
widen
widen then it shows the rest of the
file. Okay. So very useful.
Now that command is called uh let me
show you describe function narrow to uh
narrow to region. You see they have
several ver versions. The most general
one is narrow to region which means you
have to select a region. Then you know
for example I up to here then I call
narrow to region
then it just show this part you know so
I cannot go down you know I cannot go up
you know
then I call w uh widen to a to a narrow
you know now I can see so now but when
you call narrow to region
you see there are several uh more
specific convenient functions. You got
this one narrow to defend. So what that
does is that you don't have to like
select the function first then call
narrow. You can just if your cursor is
inside the function you call it it'll
just narrow to this um
to this function body. Right? So now
let's try that. Okay. Wait. So wait. So
let's try that over here.
But but over here for example, let me
show you how it works.
Let's let's see. Uh
okay. Now this is more traditional
formatted in a trai traditional way. So
my cursor is here. Now I call narrow to
defend. Do it.
Beautiful. You see, you see I cannot you
see the the whole buffer just show that.
Okay. Now why
okay now but if my cursor is here when
you when you are on a function
the where the formatting is not done
traditionally but however it's valid in
Mac this code. Okay. Now you do narrow
to defend. Let's see if it works.
You know the last time I tried it failed
because the idiocy of the leisp you know
common leis and emac people because they
they have um obsession about certain par
and because they they they got a code.
Okay. Anyway it should narrow to this
function because this is syntactically
and semantically valid this code. But
now if we do it do it.
It got [ __ ] up. Can you see that? This
is not a a function. That's a let. Let's
widen. Okay, let's try it again. Widen.
So my cruiser is here. Let's say let's
go now to region. Let's see. Do it. That
works. Okay. Now widen. Okay.
Widen. Now if my cruiser is here, let's
do it narrow to defend.
It got [ __ ] up. Can you see that?
That's not defund. Okay. Now widen
again. Now, however, if if my cursor is
here, let's say even here, it will work
because this part of code is uh well
formatted. Okay. So, let's see. Narrow
to default. You see that works. So what
does that mean? The significance of this
is that this there is a major [ __ ] up
for 30 years in the EMAC lisp in the
lisp fanatics [ __ ]
Okay, listen carefully because this bug
has been around you know 30 years but
they don't they don't know they don't
care. They don't they don't even know
most of the time because in their mind
typical industrial programmers they you
know they you have to suppose you're
supposed to read uh programmer style
guide pearl style guide C style guide
C++ style guide this [ __ ] style
guides and they argue among each other
you know my style guide versus your
style guide there's Google style guide
there's Python Pep style guide which is
different from Google you know each
language then each corporation that they
have slightly different then the Linux
the Linux creator of Linux
he has a page about
you know C style guide for writing Linux
kernels and in the preamble he says you
know get a copy of the GNU C style guide
and burn you know they they have fight
and war they're [ __ ] idiot these
idiot industrial programmers, you know,
they they they they love to talk about
the style guide, how many how many
indents should you have, should you use
a tab or space, you know, I talked about
this many times, but they don't
understand these people, you know, they
they they don't know a thing.
So what I'm demonstrating is that there
is a bug where a valid you know totally
completely valid valid valid this code
but but but this narrow to defend
failed.
So not just that eval defund also
failed. Okay, like uh you know eval
defund uh so this command if you call it
it it should evaluate this uh this code
you don't have to move the cruiser to
the end and and call eval last sex
so it's kind of convenient but it failed
you see so this is this is you know so
so transparent a bug so if you don't
format in a certain way it fails
Okay. So this is and you know this is uh
very much tied to their notion of lines
should not be more than 80 characters.
You know this this this massive code
idiots in the industrial programming
industry or basically all programmers.
Okay not all but like 90% they they were
taught that way. They they don't think
they don't they don't have a brain. They
were taught you're supposed to stick to
style guide. You're supposed to follow
this these gods, you know, the the
leanest towards or richest stolman or
the python kid van rosen one of the most
idiotic [ __ ] you know you're supposed to
follow the guy you so so you got this
kind of issue. They they they never
imagined automatic formatting which
began in Goland 2008 and Wufam language
automatic
formatting on the fly which I
demonstrated you know few days ago and
many times before okay so
okay that's a little rant okay so I
talked about all these formatting and
demonstrated it a week ago
Okay. So, uh that's July 3rd, 2025,
episode 673. Format Python code,
JavaScript, Goland, HTML, CSS in Emacs,
and and demonstration of the on the-fly
dynamic instantaneously
instantaneous automatic formatting on
the fly as you type of Wufam language.
And not just that
your code can be type set in mathematics
and it will format on the fly well.
Okay. Uh so on that page so actually why
don't I demonstrate that again. So let's
copy that a little digression but this
is
necessity
because some people watch my you know
show they they don't know they don't
they don't know but seeing is believing
okay so let me show you this one one
more time one more time I'll be I would
be happy to show this 1,000 times okay
magnify the code so you can clearly see
now shift enter to evaluate it. Okay,
this is wam language code. So you got
that fantastic and beautiful. This is
geometric inversion which we did a live
stream about two years ago. Okay, now
see the code. Now the code now you see
uh you know you see
this is what we copied. You see there's
no indentation. There is no tab or
space. But when you paste it into the
notebook, it automatically become
well formatted, you know, well
formatted. You see there is no tab in
front of it. You see I move my arrow
key. Uh you see I move the cursor.
There's no tab or space between all
those before those indentations. Right?
But it just formatted that way.
Does it sound similar? Yes. Why?
Because. Let me show you.
Does that sound similar? Yes. Why?
Because. Let me show you. Okay. So, let
me show you. Emacs blog something
something. Um, let me just show you.
Okay.
Uh,
format CSS code. Let's go to that page
again. So you see this window when you
adjust
adjust you see the sentences you know
they automatically wrap the lines and
similarly for the code part you see
automatic wrapping of lines on the fly
as you change the width and also as you
type you know like any any any word
processor that do that. Okay, but except
the industrial coding [ __ ]
the C, the C++, the Java, the
JavaScript, the Python, because they
they don't know, they don't know.
Okay, so I've been talking about this
for 20 years, but the industrial coders,
they don't understand, you know. They
still think to this day blinds should be
80 characters long. Uh something
something something. Actually they
started to change the idea a little bit
today.
So Wuam language now as you adjust the
window you can see they still formatted
in the right way. You see on the fly
dynamically you see can you see that?
Okay that's a demonstration of the
formatting. Okay dynamic formatting.
Now let's go back to
uh what we are doing. So we talked about
kind of digression. We talked about this
uh this bug problem. Okay. So let me put
this windows back.
Industrial coding idiots. You know why
are they like that? My little rant. Hi
Diego. Hi Saha.
Don't know much about coding but you
seem uh fun to watch. That's why I
joined in. Thank you.
uh you see why are the coders
specifically specifically industrial
coders
are like that why I mean so why don't
they know anything about you know why
haven't they seen anything like this
this feature in wuam language by the way
you can also type set it okay shift
control and type set now you can can you
see the fraction there now you become a
fraction okay you can also have radical
square root and so on and and power you
know
and this fraction look at this y over x
over y you see they also auto format you
know on the fly as you as as you adjust
the window size okay on the fly
so this feature in wuam language has
been like this since 1996
wam language Mathematica version three
okay
1996 six
the but the industrial coding [ __ ]
you know the C C++ including the lisp
especially the lisp and commonly
[ __ ] okay I call them [ __ ]
because they because I there's a
tremendous hatred for me to them because
every time you mention it they refuse
they deny they refuse they attack you
they call you a troll but demonstrate
demonstratively they are just incorrect
but they refuse to listen. Okay. Now why
why is so so back to the question why is
the coding industry the coders they
don't know about this thing?
Uh so what I mean by industrial coders
that's typically the like the the the
average typical programmers in
programming industry for example those
people who work at Google Microsoft or
Facebook or Amazon or smaller countries
uh smaller uh companies okay Nvidia or
you know I mean including smaller
companies.
So typically what they do industrial
coding you know web pages writing you
know maybe Linux kernels writing you
know database financial systems banking
you know these are kind of typical okay
now this this these are different from
scientific programming. Okay scientific
programming is kind of different and
engineers they need to solve equations.
Okay, they you know they need to do a
lot of mathematics solve equations
integrals or
or solve matrix equations differential
equations physics physist or design of
car engines design of you know alo all
sort of things. So those people are very
different from the like typical the bulk
of programmers in the industry.
So the bulk of programmers are you know
the Java you know they you know they C,
C++, Java game programming networking
you know this these
so they they are like the bulk of
average programmers. Okay they are not
engineers nor are they scientists. They
are not physicists. They are not
mathematicians. They just know coding.
Okay. They know you know about operating
system you know depends on the person.
they they know about RN system
networking you know web you know web web
technologies okay so the bulk of
programmers these industrial coders they
are the bulk of Google Microsoft Amazon
and so on
so they why do why don't they know these
and by the way do you know how why where
does the convention of 80 characters per
line like that 80 characters per line
came from that came from the punch cards
you know like 50 years ago
because you got 80 holes per card, you
know, per per row, you know, that came
from punch cards, okay? 80 characters
per line. I've done several videos about
these, you know, every time I do it and
then some people like, you know, they
they are my followers, but they don't
they don't get it. They they say, "Sir,
you you are just wrong. How can you be
so wrong?" They don't understand. So so
incredible. This this thing is so
incredible. Okay. About formatting
uh code coding style and lines of you
know and the you know the formatting
style and automatic formatting this
these kind of topics related. Okay. So
why don't they you know how come they
don't understand you know how come they
never seen this technology? I mean would
would you want not want this technology
things like that?
Would that be I mean is it not better
and uh you know why should your line be
80 you know 80 characters long uh you
know because you got lots of problems
then you don't have this auto wrap then
so that means whatever you 80 characters
that's hard formatted you know that's
another way to think of it is hardcoded
okay you don't want hardcoded you you
want it to be flexible you know like
HTML you know you see like Almost
everything in Marvin text is like that
way flexible except
except the industrial code [ __ ] and
their code C C++ Java uh JavaScript and
Pearl and so on and particularly Python
the kiddo van russome idiots they he he
he he went one step further He actually
force every semantic must be hardcoded.
So Python you know so in Python the
language is not possible to auto format
at all like this will never happen you
know because the Python the creator made
the language impossible to do this
because the the indent is tied to the
semantics of the of the language. Okay.
So that's one extreme idiocy. So
I was going to say so why why are they
like that industrial coders? Oh yeah. So
let me let me briefly uh tell you why I
think. Okay.
So you know because they you know the
industrial coders they are just like
normal people like all of us are normal
you know maybe I'm a bit not abnormal
okay
but you see most people are just normal
people so just like in the fashion
industry you know women or the or
average person you know they follow pop
stars you know in particular this is
pronounced in uh women or young girls,
okay? Young women, okay? You know, young
women, they follow pop stars. Uh for
example, in America, USA, the most
famous is the Kardashians, you know, the
Kardashians, you know, they gossip, you
know, what what dress is she wearing
today?
Like for years, for decades, you know,
it's that way. You know what what is the
current fashionable head hair style and
dress and you know especi so women
especially are into that but men is
similar. Okay, men is similar. Men do
not particular follow fashion, you know,
clothing stuff, but men do follow
certain, you know, trend or thinking
patterns or what you should be doing,
you know, what is currently. So
it's exactly the same way in coding
because even if you are a programmer you
might think oh you know you might think
you are different because you don't you
because coding is very logical requires
thinking therefore you think you don't
you don't follow fashions and fats but
actually you do you do it very much you
you follow by since you began your
career you follow which programming is
the latest which programming can get you
a job which programming is the best you
know you look at go to hacker news or
slash dot like 25 years ago you know or
reddit you know you check you talk with
other people or what is the current you
know lead code you know coding golf you
know you participate you know
so why indust industrial programmers are
like that what you know why didn't they
know about these uh
lots of things because just like anybody
else they follow fashion and fats they
follow the pop. Okay, that is the that
is my what I think my conclusion. Okay,
that's a huge digression. Okay,
now
let's go back to coding this, shall we?
Can we do this quickly? So, I already
talked for 40 minutes. Can we in 20
minutes finish it? I think so. Okay,
let's So, the rest of the video is going
to be let's focus on coding it. Okay.
So, meanwhile, let's um
uh
what to do now? Okay. Let's let's make a
copy. So, let's code uh fresh. Okay. So,
we we talked about that.
Uh let's Okay. So, let's Yeah. So, let's
start to code.
Uh let's let's uncomment uncomment this
and uh delete that. Delete that. Okay.
Now this is actually what we want to do.
We want to now let's uh reformat
uh version created. Okay. So update
update current defund to be
corresponding
website
that is copy the current defund find the
corresponding website local URL file
path update the code in that file in the
HTML pre-tag that's that's right okay so
now we are back to code this code this
okay
so so we learned so Uh uh mark defund.
Okay. Mark
uh mark defense. So what does mark
defend return? Uh info type. So it just
uh mark it doesn't return anything I
think. Okay.
Okay. So let's just let's just do this
quickly. So that mark defund will mark
it. Then actually so you need to find
the URL.
So
yeah. So actually I don't want to mark
defend. Okay. So I want to
so let's make it simple. Okay. So let's
say okay so let's say talk show. So this
is today's talk show. Back back close
back to the code. What is this to-do?
Close. Um yeah. So let's say this is a
URL. Okay. Make it site
and uh make it the this quote is
required this kind of quote for the URL
to be highlight to be linked. So you can
click on it you'll jump to it. Okay. So
let's say this page URL is that okay so
um so let's let's make it simple let's
say if the current um
okay let's do it quickly let's just say
mark defund okay mark defund uh then
then copy
okay where is this Uh so mark defund
put the mark at end of this defund point
at beginning. Okay so point at beginning
and uh so so so let's have a local
variable begin end uh
and uh let's set
beginning point. Okay. Then
end is the last mark. Uh set X end is
the mark position. Now how do you get
the mark position? I forgot. Okay.
So
ininfo search for Emacs tutorial. So
emac this. So we go to emac this. So we
want to know about the mark region
active region. Okay. So uh push mark set
mark. You want to get the mark. Um
so region active region uh use region
deactive mark active set mark command.
Uh
pop mark I think. Do I have a pop mark
here?
Okay. Let's query
pop mark. Okay we do.
So copy that. So we want just to pop
mark. Okay. So what are the arguments?
Uh no arguments. Okay. Good. Now
so now we got the beginning of the
defund and end of def end of the
function. Then we can now just um
now we can just um
we can just deactiv deactivate the
region. Okay.
Uh
deactivate mock.
Okay.
Okay. Is there an argument? Uh, no.
Okay. So, so, so deactivate it then. Um,
then so let's uh
let's say body. Body is a text. Okay.
Uh, buffer substring no properties.
Okay. Uh, okay. Set X body.
uh x body to
that text. Okay. So you grabbed it. Now
you now you need to find the URL. So
So you need to find the URL. So what you
do is you go to char
uh x begin. Okay. Go to the beginning of
the defend. Then you search for word.
search for word for for this URLs thing.
Okay.
So search for word
that okay optional bound uh yes we want
you know the we don't want to go over
the end of defense so x end no arrow
true no arrow so if you cannot find it
arrow out okay
so search for that so once you found
that then you want okay let's create
another local variable x URL. Okay. Then
set x url equals true uh uh bounds of
thing at point. Okay. So
stupid. What why don't I have ur here? U
should be one of that. So anyway bounds
of thing at point now why is it not
colored? Uh
Uh something something is wrong with my
um
eag this mod. Okay. Is it interesting?
So uh so
okay let's see emac this mod. So search
for balance of thing at point. Why is it
not
uh this function?
It should should be highlighted anyway.
So get the URL then.
Okay. So actually that returns a bounce.
So we need to have another local
Let's say let's just say y. Okay. So
that's a beginning and end. So
then you need to say
y begin
set y begin equals uh then bounce. Okay.
x bounce.
Okay, Xbounds is going to be that. Okay.
Uh then set Y car expounds. Okay. Then
set Y and
C
expounds. That's how you get the Now
let's clean up the code. Clean up the
code.
This auto format. Okay. Power of auto
format.
Okay. So you get the beginning and end
position of the URL. So now what you now
you can set URL both a substring no
properties. Okay. Then uh this is Y
begin and Y end. Okay. So you got a URL.
Now you go to char.
Okay. So
uh
so okay. So now you go to char. You go
to ch the beginning of URL. Okay.
You go to the beginning of URL. Then you
find file. Find file.
Uh
wait. Why do you need to go to the
beginning of URL?
Uh oh. Okay. You got a URL. But now the
problem is you need to convert this URL
to a file path. Yeah, [ __ ]
that's that's a bit complex because
because you need to convert this URL to
a file path now. So but that depends on
each person because for me I got.info
which is special just for me but for
other people it may not be you know. So
you need some kind of map of domain name
or web root. Okay. So
I have a function to do that but but
then that you know but then you just
gonna call another code. Um
but let's suppose this is a file path.
Okay let's just pretend for now. So you
know I'm just going to de demonstrate
how this works. So so you got a URL.
Then you just uh let's say go to the
beginning. Uh then you just um so I got
this command. So this command is called
uh open file at cursuser. Okay. So let's
just call that command. So go to the
beginning of the URL then just call open
file at cursus. Okay. So we open we
basically
open this page showing browser. That's
today's talk show. Okay. Now go back.
Now we open the file. So uh yeah open we
opened it. Now go to go to chart uh
point mean go to the beginning of buffer
then search for word. We want to search
for word pre uh actually we want to
search for word um
uh
pres something class. But actually what
we need to actually search forward is
the is the function name. Okay. Uh but
there's more to do. So we need to grab
the function name. We need to search uh
search to the end of defend then search
to the beginning of par and grab the
function name. So that on this page you
can you can go inside the pre
is it getting complex? So you can you
see on this page you go to uh you go to
inside of this tree then you find the
function name which is you see here
uh but you know so there's a lot to code
so anyway so for now go to beginning of
buffer then just search for class
that won't do because well you got to
search for regular expression because
you basically what you want to do is you
want to search for let me show you
uh so you can see here is a pre-tag. So
you you want to search for the beginning
of this pre-tag then inside
uh then inside you want to search for
the function name. Uh but it must occur
before the end tag of the pre. Okay. So
you can call narrow to region. So this
is another use of narrow to region. So
you you don't search beyond it.
Then then you then what you have to do
is you just cut out delete that text and
paste the new uh paste um the X body
there. Okay.
Okay. That's um is it you know do I have
to finish it? you know, I've been,
you know, so if you guys want me to, if
you really want me to see me to, you
know, see the finished code, let me
know. I'll code it. Otherwise, that's it
for today. Thank you guys for watching.
Where do you see the overlap between
Ling and Wolf? Uh, they don't actually
overlap much.
Okay, so Diego asked the question, ling
is a proof system.
Uh, and woofam language is a computer
algebra system. They are very they are
quite very different in nature. Although
it's possible they should be combined
combined but we are not there yet. So in
last in few month ago I talked about how
how I was learning ling you know that's
an entire different topic topic that's
proof system that's a programming
language to do proofs for mathematics
and also for program verification so you
can verify you know your code is correct
in critical situation you know like nuke
you know launch nuke and stuff. So you
got ling is a proof system
programming language and woof language
is so-called computer algebra system
that's a classic name for it meaning
that it does it solves equations it can
do derivatives integrals matrix matrix
multiplication
uh matrix equation differential
equations
uh you know it's used by uh engineers
mostly and physicists and mathematicians
But it doesn't do proofs. It turned out,
you see, that's a very interesting topic
because as a young mathematician, you
know, like 25, 30 years ago when I was
so heavily into math, I want to be a
mathematician. I want to be the
greatest.
I failed.
Uh so
you know when I was learning math you
know and I'm also so so much into logic
and basically pure math is all about
proofs. Okay pure math pure mathematics
all often regarded is the highest form
of mathematics
you know you you might have heard of the
joke you know like chemists say they
chemists say they are the greatest
because chemistry is a foundation of you
know materials. Then physicist says they
are higher order you know you know
physics is actually how you know
chemistry works
then comes mathematician you know they
are the god because then you can't do
physics without mathematics mathematics
is is the how the universe works you
know so anyway pure mathematics is
usually um
uh in pure mathematics it's basically
all just about proofs okay so that's and
And today you have you know computer you
know ling it's a proof system but anyway
when I was younger I thought you know
I'm very much into proof uh pure
mathematics so I want you know study
proofs and but also you need you know
how do you solve differential equations?
How do you solve equations like x + 2
squared uh x^2 + 2 = to 4. solve for x.
you know that's a simple equation you
need you know how do you solve it can
get you know extremely difficult because
you know differential equations you know
so there's a so-called computer algebra
systems
uh and wam language is an example
computer algebra systems you know you
can do proofs
I mean you can do solve equations but it
turns out these two
they are not I mean they they are Oh,
they are both matics mathematics but
they are like very quite different in
nature. Okay. So you can do proofs but
they but the the the nature is like
entirely different from from from
solving equations.
You know if you solve equations once
once you got a solution then you can
plug it back into the equation then you
can prove it is true. But usually
but for simp but but sometimes you you
know for many problems you you don't get
the uh solution. So anyway these two are
turns out are quite different in nature
but so I wrote an article like 15 years
ago you know there should be a system
that combine combine this. Okay let me
talk about it. So you know just go to
search
computer uh algebra systems. Okay. So
math notation proof systems computer
algebra in one language. Okay. So this
is written in 2009 16 years ago.
We are getting there. Okay. But not not
today yet. So you got proof systems
that's one thing. You got math
notational systems. uh that's you know
lat you know like this you know type
setting latte that's another thing then
you got computer algebra system like
wuam language mathematica that's a
another thing so
why not combine them they should be
combined into one language okay
so that's idea and we are I you know we
are starting to do it but slowly okay
right now there's no system that do all
these together but it should be because
these obviously you know you got a
programming language why can't you
there's no reason you cannot okay
so uh we are getting there
okay so that's that's about that and uh
let's see any other things so we talked
for one hour already time to shut down
okay so
so yeah the question is uh is there
overlap app between Ling and Wufam. No,
not really. I remember you mentioned
your you were working on proofs. Yes,
I'm learning ling system. I'm learning
it. I don't you know I I got uh a lot to
go.
It's all ego group out group mental.
Couldn't you see uh set set Q sequence?
Yeah. No. You see that's another major
problem. That's ACP's question. Couldn't
you use set sequence for the thing at
point bounds up thing at point? The
answer is no.
And I have an article on that.
Okay? Like just just search you'll find
it. Uh the answer is no. And that and
why? Because the car and cad and lisp
cons is the fundamental damage to lisp.
Okay. Actually I need to talk about
that.
fundamental like that's another extreme
idiocy by the lisp and common lisp
[ __ ] codes okay I now let me say it
again the common list and lisp fanatical
[ __ ] I call them [ __ ] because
they are incorrect and for 20 years and
30 years they refuse you know to accept
you know like like but I can demonstrate
demonstrably show they are just
incorrect.
Okay. So, let's go to so you uh let's go
to search. Okay. So, let me show you
that first of all. Let me let me address
this thing at point. Um
so that's a good question. Okay. Get
text problem of thing at point there.
Okay. Problem of thing at point. So
behavior depends on syntax table. That's
one thing. Uh then return a conair
there. Okay. Okay, that's address your
question. So, you know, so the the the
the situation is that we have set Q,
right? Set I mean set sequence. Okay,
you know, if you don't know, forget
about it. If but if you know already uh
you know, if you already code lisp, then
you know what I'm talking about. There's
the set uh sequence set q which is um so
if you know another language such as
closure python uh javascript this is
called destructure b b b b b b b b b b b
b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b b
b b b b b b b b b binding. Okay, uh
dstructure binding. It allows you to set
a bunch of variables from uh a list or
vector or array. Okay. So you don't have
to manually you know like what we are
doing set begin at that then set end and
that you know manually extract items
from from a list array. Okay. So that's
called dstructure binding that's
available in Python in JavaScript in
closure in lots of languages. Okay. This
EMAC is this added about uh set sequence
about seven seven years ago something.
Okay. In 20 uh Emacs 28 2021. Okay.
actually
actually just uh four years ago. Okay.
Late when every other language already
has it. Okay. So it's great. So now you
can have destructure destructure binding
to you know you don't have to manually
manually extract uh you know uh array
items then you know so you know like
that set sequence then x1 x2 then two
just to a to a array. Okay,
but now but however the bounds of thing
at point they don't return a list nor do
they return a vector you know they
return this conspair the [ __ ] scum
lisp [ __ ] conspair so when you say
when you use set sequence it doesn't
work because set sequence expect a
sequence which means any of list
uh you know this is data structure you
know hierarchy Emac list this you know
list or or associative list property
list or array or vector string you know
you expect
a generic you know sequence type or
collection but it cannot take you know
conspayer is not
but the list idiots you know like for
example hacker news
recently about a month ago uh three
weeks two weeks ago
I'm about to be to die that's uh 2011.
Okay. Uh this these scums, you see, they
they they attack me because, you know,
especially this Lisp guy, you know, they
whose name is u uh you know, it's a
German guy. I I talked about in my live
stream in the past, but anyway.
Okay, let's just open that and then
click uh not oo Emacs. Okay, so not that
page. So about two weeks ago, three
weeks ago, someone posted my article to
um
to uh
what page is that not oo emac that
domain is kind of uh obsolate.
Uh
anyway, so you can you can find the
article by uh okay, I'm kind of talking
still talking. So programming blog
search for hacker. Uh there it is there.
Okay. So recently
that's the article. So someone posted
one of my article you know to hacker
news not me. Okay. I never I never post
my stuff. I never post anything to
hacker news except I did comment one
time about 10 years ago 15 years ago.
So someone post my article you know
problem of list cons then you got a
bunch of uh list dispers these are
common dis you know professionals they
they they don't understand they don't
they don't understand you know kasan
don't know nothing you know this um
you know they they don't understand but
except the zuma generation or anyone not
from this for example python coder they
understand okay except you know the the
people who attack me they don't
understand what I'm talking about are
these this coders not just these people
but they are like professional that you
know they've been coding this for a long
time they are like the cultist okay
that's these people that I always have a
problem with this these cult fanatical
[ __ ] they don't understand but
everybody else understand what I'm
saying in fact you know some people read
my article and argued with them and
cited my reason you know like rephrase
my reason to counter what they are
saying this list this com especially
common this these [ __ ] okay they
don't they don't understand for re for
some reason for be and I know what's the
reason I thought about this for 20 years
because code okay once you are in code
similarly you know like right now here
we are criticizing lisp but the python
coders who are not professional list
coders they understand what I mean you
know the or C or C++ they understand
what I mean but when I criticize Python
people then it is the Python fanatics
you know like who are leading Python you
know leading Python you know who who
have done you know lots of stuff
then they don't understand you know they
funny so so this is a concrete example
you know bound of thing at point it why
why why can't I use the set sequence
because it's using the cons [ __ ] the
cons pair okay
that I think that's it
I have a question in helix I don't know
what is helix okay I think that's
another editor. I don't know about it.
It's a functionality where we can select
inside the bracket and outside. Okay.
I'm also coding in ling
pravin Kumman. Oh, fantastic.
I do drop logic proofs in ling
proposition logic. Okay. Fantastic. Do
you think if we formalize enough
knowledge in ling, we can generate new
theories using AI?
Uh, yes. It's coming, you know. So, the
proof system and AI is is also coming
together. That's another thing. Yeah.
Okay. Bye, guys. We shut down in one
minute. Okay. So, if you guys if you
enjoyed
my comedy show, go pay me. Okay. Go to
kasali.info.
At the bottom you can see my Patreon, my
Amazon gift card. Donate to me, PayPal.
If you have a job, pay me $100, one
shot, you know, 100 a year. Not too bad.
If you don't have job, you know, $10
something.
Thank you very much. That's it for
today.
Okay, so that's today. We did u sizable
rant, you know, here and there, which is
not too bad because, you know, like
usually when you talk about just coding
and focused like nobody cares,
but but when you become dramatic, then
then your viewers went up. Anyway, so we
we didn't finish the code, but we got
like we explained how it works and
stuff. uh we explained quite a few
things and so I'm going to update this
talk show page so people on YouTube can
click on the description but uh section
and go to my website. Okay, that's it.
Bye guys. Uh
DAX
says hey
uh ACP so I hope to come to the day
soon. So we are in incredible uh world
right now you know the advancement of AI
and then the proof systems and computer
algebra systems such as wolf you know
still you know still tremendous update.
So the merge of
proof systems and computer algebra
systems and AI is coming actually they
are heavily you know like right now they
are heavy heavy really heavy working on
it you know you can imagine because
because the neuro neuronet network the
he the AI is actually kind of
we don't know for sure but it's like
taking over it's like the most important
technology almost like the most
important important technology because
they just you know they just taking
over.
Uh and then when because one of the
fatal like fatal flaw of AI like the
chat bots is because they are using
neural networks which means they can
never be precise. They cannot even do
simple computations. If you ask chhat
GPT or G to do simple multiplication of
two huge numbers he'll get it wrong you
know but you'll say oh because this that
and therefore the answer is that but
it's just wrong. Okay so the a fatal
problem a kind of fundamental problem of
neuronet network technology is that they
cannot do computation like the simple
one even simplest one. So, so that is
why became so that is why they are you
know the researchers are trying to uh
work together you know combine proof
systems with AI. So you can you know use
AI to get answer then and start a proof
system or call Python to do computation
or proof systems to try to prove it.
So there's so you know so you got
different technologies trying to work to
actually you know Google just created
created you know using their AI to solve
math Olympia problems right now and
together with Ling. So right now they
are at championship level. I talked
about this in a live stream a few months
ago. They are at championship level.
That means today you know the AI and
plus the proof system you know the
machine can do Olympic level
mathematical problems can solve them
better than vast majority of talented
young person or mathematician you know
that you know we are at that level and
the future we don't know so it's you
know
very hard to say bye