good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh and today we are
going to do a Emacs Lisp live coding
so today's 2020 June 10th Wednesday
civilan o'clock in the afternoon San
Francisco time so I'm going to in my
alive so I'm doing ok hi guys
say something say something in the
comments ok so we are doing Emacs Lisp
live coding if you have any questions
about Emacs or emag Lisp ask me type it
in the youtube comment I mean the live
chat box so Cortez good morning Cortez
so what are we going to do today let me
show you ok so we are going to write a
eMac list code ok let's begin its let's
begin second
good morning Alan so what are we going
to do today on first of all on the right
window the pink window you can see all
my Emacs command as I work on my Emacs
so if you are not sure what I'm doing
you can always look at the command on
the right window and also the key my
keystroke will show up there and I'm
goes I'm using a variety board layout
and I'm also using sulfa keys so let's
let's begin so we are going to write a
code let me show you what what it is
okay so we are going to write a code
that
is my key not working what's going on
Vince the command delete or the window
yes okay so so we have a text of this
format and we want to transform it to
this format
hey good morning Albert so we have
professor Albert Kim here Albert asked
me about this question so what what are
we going to do is that we have a text of
this format and we want to change it to
this format so let me tell you what
exactly that means okay so in this
format the first one each line you can
see sponsor organization you know
probably then then then you see some of
the some of the lines contains a colon
okay let me show it okay so actually
start a new window okay
magnify magnify and let's let's call
command now this is a useful command
highlight lying okay highlight line is
matching regular expression so we're
gonna do that with a colon and what
color do we want yellow is good so is
used you can see here some of the lines
contains a colon that's colored yellow
and and some of the Alliance does not so
basically so for example on the first
line is a sponsor oak then ACCCE so
actually this line continues to the
second line because the second line does
have a colon so what we actually want to
do is
to make them into one line so that you
can see the desired output where every
line he has a colon so for example these
two lines these two lines doesn't have a
colon because they are actually part of
this this line you know top manager so
what we want is you know for example let
me show you so what we want is you know
top manager you know someone's name
Department you know University they are
associated with so we are going to write
an emag list command that transforms
this text block into the second one so
let's let's start okay so let's start
let's go to okay let me start a Emacs
Lisp window okay magnify so d fun define
function okay define function
different yeah define function magnify
we want to first of all let's write the
docs doc stream okay to write the doc
string let's copy that we are going to
say transform the current region by
joining lines without a colon to the
line above okay that's essentially what
it does and for example for example this
text block will become becomes this one
okay and that's our documentation and
let's say version today state okay so we
are going to start that function and the
function name will be joining lines
let's say joining lines okay let's do it
more traditional joining lines okay my
joint lines
my German lines feature by convention if
a command name ends in - region that
means it works on the current region
okay so we are going to start to do that
how do we start I don't know let's see
so we want a command that transform each
line so first of all we want we want to
know where the region begins
so region beginning let's say begin and
variables so we have the let local
variables region beginning and end so if
you guys have a question just ask me ok
just type in the comment box am I still
doing okay let's check yes ok
so region start end and beginning and
okay let's so let's say begin we want to
set a variable so set Q the king will be
region beginning region beginning okay
and set Q and will be region end
okay so the beginning and end variables
are the region beginning and region end
positions in Emacs
every character has a position starting
with one the first character in the
buffer is one so now we got the region
beginning and end now what we want to do
is we want to we want to narrow to
region let's not do that it's okay let's
I have to think so anyway we got the
region beginning and region end now we
want to convert the lines so so first
okay so let's try it let's go to go to
cha go to char is a command that move
the character to a particular position
so go to cha so go to cha begin go to
the beginning position in the region
then we want to check
if the line contains the colon okay okay
okay so so there are so many ways to do
this since I'm going to do it live
coding I will try to just write the
prototype first let's not worry about
efficiency or the best way to do it yeah
let's just try to get it to work then we
try to improve it so okay so actually I
have to think about this so current line
so so if the line contains the colon you
want to move to the end of line and join
the line then remove the remove the
dashed space okay so if the line
contains colon move to the end join the
next line then remove the dash in space
that's it that's that's our algorithm
basically so let's type it out if the
line contains
wait if the line contains : okay then go
to the next line okay here is what to do
if the line contains the coal and do
nothing then just move on to the next
line
now if the line does not contain : you
want to join it showing it with the
previous line that's right that's the
algorithm okay so let's write it out if
the line contains : move to next line
okay and now
if the if the line honking if the line
does not contain : showing it with the
previous line until we reach the end of
the region okay so yeah so that's that's
right
so let's do that okay let's just do it
this way they are there better ways to
do it I'm possibly but let's just let's
try to get this done in in 30 minutes
okay so if the line contains : so first
of all you want to know does the current
line contains the :
we can do that by such forward rejects
actually we don't want regular
expression we just want such forward
okay such forward is a command that will
move your cursor to a particular
position and return true if it's such
successful returns force if it doesn't
contain that whatever you searched so
search forward for : optional bound yes
we want a bound the bound will be end of
lying position end of line position and
position okay so we want the command to
find the position of the
and at the end of line so I forgot what
the command that is so let's look at
look at our let's look at our Emacs
tutorial so you can find my tutorial on
my blog just such folks are Emacs Emacs
Lisp okay so we want to there is a page
basic functions about working with lines
okay here so line beginning position
line in position that that is what we
want so let's go back so so here we want
line in position line in position that's
so that's right and no arrow true we
don't want it to stop and we pull the
arrow if it's not found and count we
don't care new okay so that's what we
want search for word
now we need a if statement so if okay
if such forward that contains the line
then actually we don't want if so we
want fire actually
so why our search for word
okay why our search for word something
so if that lines contains the colon then
move it to the next line okay move the
cursor to the next line so forward line
is what we want
okay forward line one to the to the next
one Wow okay so when doing live coding
there is always not as smooth let's
think about the algorithm so if the line
contains the caller move to the next
line if the line does not contain : join
let's just write it out okay so let's
try it again so if if contains : then
forward line okay program forward line
now if it does not connect contains the
colon then then what we want to do is
move the cursor to if the line does not
contain : we want to remove the cursor
to the beginning of line beginning of
line
okay let's check if that's the command
we want
yeah let me just coat it beginning of
lines and interactive ok beginning of
line move point to the beginning of
current line
yeah that's the one we want move the
move the cursor to the beginning of line
so beginning of line so if it does not
contain color move to the beginning then
delete one character backward so delete
one character backward what is the
command name for that that is let's see
did it backwards ah so you know if you
are eMac this beginner you can always
look at my tutorial because I have I
have basics functions you know in these
pages so right now what I want to do is
to delete the character to the left of
to the left of the cruiser
okay divita didi cha is the one we want
so move to the beginning beginning of
line delete cha delete to the left that
means the that means join to the
previous line like that so then we want
to also delete to the right two
characters that is for deleting the
beginning - okay so let's go back here
let's see let's look at our code so if
it contains : go to the next line now if
it does not contain the code and go to
the beginning of the line delete
character to the left then delete
character to the right twice okay that
looks like what we want okay and let's
remove the wire block okay that should
process one line but okay that's process
one line we need to make a loop
so let's do that
we need to make a loop doing these
things so while
who'sa position the kusa current cursor
position is point
so while point is less or equal to where
point is less than the end of region
okay
why our point is less than in the region
we want to do this if block right now
looks like our code is in shape let's
save it ok let's shape save it I forgot
to show my command keys anyway
looks like that's what we want so copy
the command name let's gonna try it okay
so here is the the text we're gonna try
save these text first
okay
let's do the highlight again okay so now
we're gonna call our command so meta X
so first of all we need to select it
meta X my joining line is region okay
let's try it let's hope it works
enter okay
join is region it is not a valid command
name okay we forgot to evaluate this
code so if our buffer so now we have
that but before we run it make sure we
will not get into a infinite loop
because sometimes when you called emag
least you know it if you made a mistake
with a while statement you know you get
into an infinite loop and when when you
are in infinite loop usually it's a
problem sometimes your crash Emacs you
can always press ctrl-g to cancel it but
but may not be responsive
okay so let's double check the code
logic so while why our point is less
than
let's let's forward chart okay let's add
one more line here
so forward cha means smooth Cruiser to
the right so we have you know we are
keep moving the cruiser okay
give our buffer now we're gonna try it
first of all select the region okay call
the command and the command will be
what's the name I forgot the name so go
back my join is region okay
select region couette my join last
region enter symbols Mary was variable
is void beginning okay so we forgot we
get we probably have some syntax errors
here oh yeah obviously because the let
you know we have the let's by itself we
want instead we want we want this code
block to be inside it there it is okay
allow buffer now let's try it again
select it call my join eyes region enter
it worked you see they all become yellow
that means it worked but however there
is something wrong there is something
wrong because it son - okay listen -
there is something wrong because
apparently is trying to process the
entire buffer you know we don't want we
only wanted to process inside the region
I think that's what is what it I think
that's that is a problem so what we're
gonna do is we're gonna we're gonna we
got going to narrow to region okay so so
beginning and then narrow to region now
that narrow to region what it means is
that peeking in okay what it means is
that it will it will narrow the buffer
as if the buffer only contains you know
the beginning and then you know two
positions you will ignore the rest of
the buffer but before we do narrow to
but okay when we do now to region let's
do that okay narrow two region let's
just render code I'm gonna explain okay
so eval buffer okay then go back here
and let's do it again let's put it here
select it code a command my joint lines
region
success wait this is wrong okay now we
narrowed to region now we want to widen
because right now it's only showing part
of the region because now we need to
check two lines every time why is that
we need to check two lines every time
okay so let's fix that so let's go wider
okay so when you call narrow to region
let me show you okay so when you call
narrow to region there is something you
want to you want to make sure when your
command finished it returns the full
buffer not just the region you narrowed
to so so I have a tutorial here
I forgot where but okay let me do this
fast how long have I been talking this
is slower than expected 26 minutes okay
we are actually spending a lot of time
it's faster if okay so narrow to region
so so okay what is the save excursion
okay let me try to find the command to
mark and region okay there it is
what is region why is it always shrink
highlight region text region create
active region go to region
okay I need to find now to region so
stream functions buffer
examples okay so cool so text editing
there it is text editing no TD text into
the text stream functions buffer let's
look at buffer switch buffer create
buffer queue buffer okay it's not here
rewrite from file and directory path
okay and thank you Cortez so let's find
mark and region get buffer stream
okay so let me think now two regions it
I don't either I don't know let's let's
just search my Emacs tutorial let me
quickly find it
and let's get this done so so here is
all currencies of narrow to region in my
tutorial change brackets
Eevee's cuza position must be this page
whose opposition functions save kusa
position there it is okay so it's here
so it's a first one basic functions
cursor at the bottom you can see there
is an arrow to region function now when
you can arrow to reach region you will
need this code let me explain okay copy
and let's go back to our code close okay
so here we narrow to region and we
actually want here we want to preserve
users region
I mean preserve preserve users you know
user may have Cornero to region before
so the command is saved restriction that
that's what we want so copy that here so
put it here so here that's the code we
want now let's move our code into it
okay so now here is our current code on
our second let me show you
here's our current code we call restrict
reach save restrict save restriction
what that means is that you inside this
code you can narrow to region however
you want but when a command finished it
will return to whatever users narrow to
region so here's a restriction then we
call now to region then we go to the
beginning of buffer ok that's what we
want so evaluate eval buffer and now
let's try this command here again one
more time
selected co-ed my joining lines region
looks like it works it work it looks
like it works let's double check so is
it correct
Kim Albert so there is another command
safe excursion which we may not need it
now because what what say the excursion
do is that if you write a eMac viscum
command that moves Cruiser around when
the command is done usually you want the
cruiser to be wherever user the cruiser
was before you before the user called
your command because otherwise your
cruiser you know when user calls your
command winston kusa becomes somewhere
else random you know you don't want that
so when you want to preserve users cause
the position then you want to go say
save excursion but in our case we yeah
we can let's do that okay let's add a
save X is excursion usually it's
so let's put it here okay so save
excursion that's what we want okay now
let's put the whole code inside great
now eval buffer now let's go back to our
example let's go back to our example
selected couette my joining nice lines
region ok it's done now there are few
more things we want to done okay so
let's check if we our code is correct
Albert says check the line grant type
please
so let's such the line grant type oh
yeah so we yeah so here is the you see
we are missing a space basically we are
missing a space so let's go back to our
code when we delete when we delete
characters here we need to add a space
so actually just we actually just delete
one character not - because we want to
delete the beginning - okay now if our
buffer go back select it let's call our
command again
wait grant type okay so there is
actually another mistake
so the grande type should not go up so
where did our code went wrong and
score it so the grant type shouldn't go
up you know this grant type line
shouldn't be merged but it did okay so
the reason is because
okay let's let's remove this forward cha
okay
let's just try it okay go back here
let's try again call our command okay
yeah so I think I know what's the
problem so when we call the command it
actually kind of removed all end of
lines they become one single line that's
no good so so we have some logic error
here so the logic arrow is so if the
line contains a colon okay I think I
know what
if the line contains the colon let's
let's put the kusa - beginning of lying
okay
so beginning of lying will move point to
the beginning of lying okay Kiva Bertha
let's try it again
select it call the command No
so what's the problem such forward so if
such forward contains the : and what's
the documentation for such forward
so such stream bound and so bound no
error
we don't want it to move the cruiser
that's the thing and we do this when we
call such forward and when
[Music]
if such forward bound
we found so Albert says the problem
might be the DVT ah wait and see so if
if it does not contains the colon so if
the line does not contain coal and move
to the beginning of line so beginning of
the line more point to the beginning of
current line okay so move to the
beginning of line then
delecia seems right
let's remove this for now okay let's
remove this give our buffer let's try it
again
see what is wrong okay so let's not
delete char let's see what happens
let's see instead of delete let's just
insert insert some special character
okay
let's insert a bullet there give our
buffer let's go back try it again
call the command now infinite loop
cancel loop it inserted millions of
bullets okay so the problem the problem
is somewhere here
now second
wait
this is not good grant types what's
going on
okay let's go back let's go back insert
oh I see what I think I know what you
think what what's this wrong because if
the line does not contain if the line
does not contain the colon we did DV cha
to join to the up line to the to the
previous line but we also need to move
at the end we need to move the cursor to
the end of line so okay end of line yeah
because end of line in end of line move
point to end of the current line
okay how sure no okay that's just okay
eval buffer go back let's try again okay
actually this this is not the character
we began with so that's I mean that's
not the text we began with so let's try
it again
so now we here is the text we began with
okay so eval buffer give our buffer now
let's try it this time better walks do
it
now remove the highlight okay there's no
problem now the first line worked
obviously but this line how do we do and
do
Oh end of life end of line and also we
need to fold cha now I'm pretty sure
this works give our buffer Co the
command join me region yeah I think
that's that worked
finally right does it look right Albert
so now this is done I'm glad this should
be should be correct let's see how long
we've been talking then we can add some
niceties so we've been talking for 42
minutes so one thing our knowing about
this command is that every time we call
this command we need to you know
manually move the cursor to select this
block now we can automate automate that
so we're gonna write code and in fact
today I just wrote a tutorial about how
to do that okay so it perfect so now it
works so you see so now we have this
piece of code that will automatically
give us the beginning and end position
of a text block a text block is just
like a paragraph it's separated by empty
lines so this is so you know if we if
the code can automatically determine
where to begin where to end it will be
fantastic so we're going to add that
code here so we paste it here so you can
see here is a code so basically it's
just doing you know first of all let's
then it
then p1 and p2 are the beginning and end
positions that's a position we want to
know where it begins and end so in so in
this code we what we are doing is we
search for using a regular expression to
search for empty lines empty lines or
tabs or sequence of tabs or sequence of
space essentially we want to look for
two empty lines so if so if it's found
then then we basically set the beginning
position and in the same way we want to
search one more time - for the end so
basically the code in the end will just
tell us you know return this vector so
that is that is good so we can just
actually copy this part here so we're
gonna copy it okay and we we don't need
this anymore so we're gonna
change so here we have you know we have
set begin set and now we're gonna just
not region beginning we're gonna so
comment that out comment that out and
here we are set in P 1 and P 2 P 1
should be beginning okay
let's change it and P 2 should be end
name change of the variable okay now
formatted nicely so here is our new code
this should walk evaluate it go back to
our buffer and do so its original text
so now we can put the cursor anywhere
inside this text block then just call
the command without having to select it
manually so go ahead it works great some
time so now I think we finished today's
primary goal of coding these so any
anyone's got questions does does this
make sense
any questions
how does it look Albert so it's good
wait there is some error look at this
end date one second let's let's try it
again how do you form a Elise code which
package okay so that's easy to answer so
I'm using saw Elise mod so you know I'm
using saw Elise mod you know you can
just look up
it's on mail pass so you can install it
and use it so to reformat code all you
have to do is put kusa somewhere in
front of a word or in front of a paren
for example let's let's go this up okay
so put a cruiser somewhere before the
character then press tab here format the
entire list code but a however I think
we got a problem we this is actually not
correct let's call it again let's call
it okay yeah there it is there's some
error you see the start dates line and
end date line they should not be
connected but however they are they
become one line try it again okay so we
need to yeah so this is actually not so
so let's insert a bullet here so that we
can see where we went wrong give our
buffer
coda command okay so it inserted a
bullet here
why does it insert a breeder start date
end date
okay I think I know what what's going on
because because we need a extra line at
about a the bottom something like that
let's just try it okay we yeah let's try
it
so so narrow to region then go to cha
then what we're gonna do is go to cha
and go to cha and then insert insert a a
new line we need a backward slash where
is my backward slash key okay so we go
to the end of the region then we insert
a new line then we go to the beginning
maybe they'll fix it evaluated go back
to the code here called a command
yes it that fixed it so okay so yeah so
yeah so that that that fix it we don't
need okay so anything else that that
should be try to delete estimate it and
try again so I think that's it right the
reason it's not working because we are
you know the end of buffer so our region
is this region and and we have some
logic issues you know the yeah special
case you know because at the end you can
no longer move forward that's why it has
problems okay anything else anything
else anyone else any guys any anyone
else any questions about Emacs now if
you like my tutorial you know you can
buy my email is tutorial they'll be good
support me otherwise I think that's it
so today's email is okay so originally
actually so let's go let's chat for
three minutes also you know actually I
have other some other things to do for
myself you see I put in my Emacs blog
sometimes I have some to do that I need
to do for myself so to do write command
to convert PNG to JPEG while you are in
a HTML file so I need to do that
but we already talked for 45 minutes I
think so that they'll be it for today so
let's do a next one next time
because that so I'm going to send you
the code Albert
okay thank you guys for watching have a
good day and take care there's well yeah
there is coronavirus and take care guys
bye