good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
today is march 21st
2021 today is
and it's 11 o'clock in the morning san
francisco time
and today we are going to demonstrate
mathematica code
uh i haven't been coding mathematica for
about 15 or 20 years
you know i coded mathematica seriously
for 10 years mostly 1990s
starting from 1993
to about about 2002
then you know then i have coded
now and then but not seriously but
before it was
you know several hours a day so i wrote
a lot code
now this code you are looking at is
from 1998 okay
and apparently it still works so i'm let
me show you some of the images i have
for example i saw i wrote this package
this is a
transform 2d plot okay this is the code
so this is the mathematica code you are
looking at
now let me put i have a bit cross size
so let me put this uh patch
it's actually easier for me to see
this way so i will so so today we are
going to demonstrate
mathematica okay and maybe some tutorial
maybe i'll do a beginner's
tutorial to show you uh you python
coders list coders
how it is and if you have questions ask
me okay i'd love to see your comments
and questions
we only we only have five people
watching now so i wrote this package
this is transform 2d plot okay
programmers documentation
hold on a second let me see where is it
okay here is actually here is
this is the one okay transform 2d plot
now let's magnify and today's background
image
is you know one of these uh images
i created in mathematica i let me uh i'm
going to explain what how they are what
they are
so uh for now you can look at
um some pictures okay let me show you
some pictures
pictures pictures pictures
pictures now these are transformation of
a 2d plane
you begin with a grid okay so let's see
if i have
uh let me show you what they are okay
uh so this this one is gallery
okay i need to open the documentation
yeah okay so here is the
kind of the the most simple
documentation
so i have to show you the grid but
basically you begin with the grid
rectangular grid or triangular grid i
don't have a triangular grid here
but i'm going to show you so first of
all here is the code
uh here's the code begin package
and the documentation document online
inline string
for documentation of each functions
that's that gets exported
so in math mathematica in many ways it's
just
like other languages you can import
export symbols
in fact so mathematica is my first
language i learned
for like like 10 years
for for like seven years so
yeah basically the ex if you are not
counting
uh graphing calculators uh that's
actually my first language hp 28 s
but anyway mathematica is basically my
first language and i
uh code mathematica for over for about
eight years then i started to learn
pearl
and unix stuff so that's around 1998
that's when i began to learn pearl uh
unix unix gel and e-max you know
all those things and it's a great it's a
giant different
experience because mathematica is so you
know it so happens for me
this is my first language yet it is it
is completely different from
you know the industrial languages so you
are looking at for example you are
looking at the mathematical code
you you can see you have all these um
two-dimensional mathematical displays so
this is the package i wrote
called uh transform 2d plot so basically
what it does
is that you begin with a grid
rectangular grid
or a triangular grid then you can apply
a function
uh a vector function that takes you know
a point two two numbers okay a one
basically a point in a plane then
returns
another vector another you know return
two numbers
so you take a point and uh you put in
the function the function
basically move the point somewhere else
so you are looking at you know
beginning with a grid you are looking at
how
the function transform the grid for
example you can look at this one
you know it's interesting uh
so if you are wondering what kind of
math is this subject
that would be vector calculus
and but mostly uh complex analysis
well functions in complex plane and
actually it
it doesn't even involve complexion last
analysis because when you do complex
analysis
it usually involves derivatives and
integrals
you know gets complex so this is
actually pure geometry
and you don't need you know you don't
need so much math to understand it
you know if you're a programmer you can
understand it basically a function takes
two numbers as input and output another
two numbers
and these two numbers are considered as
a point in the plan
so basically the function moves the
point to somewhere else
so and this function
you know this set of functions i wrote
uh you know
does the plot you know transform a grid
or rectangular grid to uh you know by
the function
so you can see there's also animations
okay
so i'm going to i think i'm going to
just
uh show you you know random chat about
mathematica
uh so you can ask me any questions you
want
okay you can ask me you know uh type in
the live chat
any questions you want for example many
of these functions you can see
you know you know about fish lens right
so this is kind of like a fish lens
this is actual the actual function okay
so actually let me
let me start to evaluate the code so i
can
so we can run the code in real time so
anyway so here's the source code
page down so for example this function
triangular grid that generates a
triangular grid i'll run it and i'll
show you okay
and this is the source code again any
questions or comment type it okay i'll
get it i'll get to it
so that's the code and that's about it
that's the code for this
package okay okay so select all uh oops
not that select all and we are going to
evaluate it it's asking me to do i want
to evaluate initials no because i'm
going to evaluate everything
okay it's done so you can see
in mathematica every time you evaluate
you know the mathematical
okay mathematica has actually two parts
you know for example in java
uh in java you have java that's the
that you know the command line java
program that actually runs the
java compiled by code and you have java
c
that takes the source code and compile
into bytecode so
for the java language you have several
components you have the
compiler java c you have the java
runtime
you know which java you know we and then
then you know jvm and so on
and for python but for python ruby
perl or
javascript basically you just have one
one binary blob you know that
that compiles or interpret you know and
run the program
for so so for mathematica mathematica
the language or you call it wufam
language
um you it has primarily two things
two components one is the front end
front end is what you see
uh right here so uh you know so these
are the front end and you have the
kernel
so so what is front end front front end
is what you see basically you can think
of
it as a editor or ide integrated
uh development uh
editor ide so
so the front end is um
is the editor ide then when you evaluate
something let me let me show you okay
so one uh let's magnify
so let's say three plus five so you type
this in front end
you press shift enter to evaluate and
you get eight
so uh so front end is kind of the
editor then when you evaluate something
it sends
sends the code into the kernel again
mathematica has two components the front
end
and the kernel so the front end is you
know like the editor
you type something you evaluate it it
sends the
message via protocol to the kernel the
kernel does the computation
then send back the result and the front
end display it
so that's how it works
front end and kernel and and in fact you
can connect
to multiple kernels for example you you
know in the notebook
you can see in this section in this menu
evaluation
you have kernel you know default kernel
none or automatic or local kernel
you know you can choose a kernel and if
you buy
if you buy wolfram's you know great
computing so
basically your front end can connect to
tens or hundreds of kernels so
it's a parallel computation so front end
and kernel and front end is also
um the format of front end is a notebook
for example you are looking at notebook
so okay let let me try to start to do
some
uh some fun things okay let me show you
the
the functions let's see and i'm going to
look at comments okay common guys
uh so let's try a function here
polar grid and rectangular grid and
triangular grid okay let's try that
okay so you type question mark polar
grid that gives you the documentation
for the polar grid so
let's try it polar grid
uh and it says r minimum
r max so minimum let's say one let's say
max is five
let's say step uh
step let's say 0.2 okay let's see what
happens
okay so wait you need them to be in a
list
okay so you do need the second argument
okay let's just copy the thing then
i haven't used this i haven't uh
i haven't you know this is coded in 1998
so basically i haven't touched it
since like for 15 years
so our max is 5 then our step let's say
0.1 and theta means theta max
okay i mean i don't know see that i mean
let's say
10 degree or is it degree or
ah i i just want to get it run fast okay
let's say 50. theta step
let's say one color function
generate a list of graphic primitives
that represent the polar grid the
optional color function are used okay
color functions are optional so let's
let's write
arrow what's going on
so does not have appropriate bounds uh
let's say pi
ah this is this is this is bad the first
demonstration
is screwed up
what's going on let's try rectangular
grid okay
rectangular grid is simpler
and same thing okay
you need the same thing
okay x means x max x steps so this is
simpler
so let's just copy that
copy paste
and remove the quote
what's going on that cannot be followed
by
let's you know front end you know
actually it's
it's uh wow wow look at that
okay it's trying to do something fancy
what's going on
so select that ctrl shift
i to get input form
copy that select all paste
why is it pasting this all this
this is
copy
paste magnify let's just type this in
emax
12025.1 okay
0.2 okay
and repeat that copy it back to
mathematica
paste benedict
oh it returns the list of graphics
primitives i know why so you have to
what you have to do is graphics
there it is finally
so rectangular grid it just returns a
bunch of
uh basically graphics primitives that
means
lines and lines basically then you have
to wrap it around a graphics
um function then you have to show
show is like like print except it's for
graphics
oh thank you so connect gave me uh isk
fifteen hundred dollars for hamburger
thank you coney
uh so with all the knowledge you have of
programming and math have you considered
building a crypto trading bot
no you know crypto um
cryptocurrency is one of the things i
want to study
i mean it's one of the things i consider
important uh
so but i haven't you know i began to
study it
seriously about two weeks ago but
um i don't fully understand it yet
so first name last name says what are we
doing today so we are going to
we are doing mathematica demo okay uh
looks quite complicated to debug okay so
anyway let's get back to mathematica so
so i wrote this package like 20 years
ago so let me show you okay so
actually copy that
ctrl shift i okay here's
this is better now this this this you
you see the
uh wait did i miss a
you see the two different syntax here
so one is using the add sign well the
other is fully nested brackets
in fact they are equivalent to let me
show you okay let me let me talk about
this
now what i'm typing is called full form
okay
uh in lisp it's known as
meta expression uh yes
wait symbolic expression and meta
expression right so
in this
this is called symbol this is like this
lisp sex uh while this or this
meta meta syntax meta form
meta expression in this anyway so
so if you look at so all these three uh
syntax are syntactically equivalent they
are completely
equivalent for example evaluate that you
can see
that's the output evaluate that that's
the same thing output
evaluate you know they they are the same
now let me get rid of the
so you can compare
you know so all these three are exact
syntactically equivalent
now the difference is that you know
basically you
you know some for typical programmers
you call them syntax
sugar you know shortcuts so the add sign
so basically so basically all
mathematica
expression has this form so fx
you know for all f uh you know
g uh
something h x
uh something like so so every
mathematical
expression this is the complete
mathematical syntax okay it's just that
brackets symbols alpha
numeric symbols brackets numbers
and comma that's it okay every or
you know whenever you see mathematical
source code they can all be transformed
uh to a syntactic syntactically
equivalent form called full form
which is basically purely
nested syntax like that so this
is one example so but mathematica has a
lot of shortcuts
for example when you have a list like
that
you can also write it like that okay
i'm digressing a lot uh but let me let
me show you something else okay so for
example one plus two
that's the expression right that's
that's not
a necessity bracket but if you want
necessary bracket you can write
plus one
two they are equivalent now how
how can how do you know it's equivalent
because you can type full form
hold okay one plus
two so here we have one plus two you
want to hold it first
hold it means do not evaluate it then
you want to use the full form function
that shows you the
um you see it shows you the
pure nested syntax anyway i'm digressing
so
so i have showed
uh and and one more thing okay one more
thing so when you see something like
that
fx that is equivalent to
uh that okay for any function
now one one characteristics of
mathematica is very general so
so for example the add syntax is a
prefix form
wherever whatever f may be it may be a
long complicated expression x can also
be a long complicated expression
whenever you have a add sign that's a
basic uh
prefix syntax for
for these uh pure uh bracket syntax
so anyway let me get back to showing you
the graphics
so you so this is a grid and let's go
back to show the polar grid
uh the polar grid
okay i
pull a grid yeah that's why
it's wrong because i know what is wrong
because i copied from this thing
and that has hidden um
let me let me let's type in
let's type in emacs and
it's better than just copy and paste
so polar grid let's try that
okay that works so now again
graphics and
show okay so there you have it you have
a
polar grid so you begin with this
uh you know this grid that represents
a plane then you apply a function to
transform
them so all these are examples so for
example here is
kind of a fish lens and this one
and this is more you know this is
distorted lens
basically you can think of it you know
it shows how it
um how the function transformed the grid
uh okay so what what else do i have
then then you have this one um
so you see this function applied to a
grid
or applied to a triangular grid it looks
like that
or applied to a polar grid it looks like
that
then you have this kind of you know this
function
this function if you apply to a grid it
looks like that
if you apply to a hexagonal grid it
looks
like that and if you apply to a polar
grid it looks like that so it kind of
like i don't know how you say it
it's kind of like shrink some parts and
expand some parts
okay so that's the idea about this uh
uh this uh transform 2d
or which you know any of this function
it's a vector value function you can
also think of it as a complex function
complex function a function that takes
one
complex number and returns one complex
number
and in this example
this function the function is here
wait so that's a function and let me
magnify
okay
let's magnify so here is a function
and this function is applied to a
triangular grid so you can see a
triangular grid so what and what does
this function do
basically the further away the point
is from the origin the more rotation it
does so in the center there's not much
rotation but when it gets
further away there's more rotation
so you can see some kind of these when
you see a
i think a japanese ghost film you know
there's
you know these days these days with your
phone you have what's called
filters you know you can apply filters
to your face
so this the so i guess this is um
they are similar function field filter
for this it twists
your face so your face becomes you know
twisted
so that's what that is and this is the
same thing the same function
applied to uh part of the grid
and there are others so you know it's
pretty so i
so it's pretty um
okay that's about that now i'm thinking
now um
i can do a um
i can do a basic mathematica tutorial
uh starting with um
you know like basics how do you do loop
how do you do if
how do you declare variables how do you
uh
things like that we can do that or we
can do
some random fancy demonstration like
you know which is more fun
but uh
but less
instructive
okay so let me read the comments so
apparently isk now what is isk isk is
some
some polish um is it netherland or
poland or something what
very browser clear history okay
isk icelandic
islamic corner
thank you very much uh so what shall we
do today
let me think about let me think for a
bit okay
so i'm still going and i've been talking
for 30 minutes already oh wow
so let's show my let's see my talk show
and what do i want to say
about mathematica
uh
let's show let's see
this is too big
i'm thinking that
so you are looking at my python tutorial
and
so here is my python tutorial
and you and i can go through
the python tutorial and show you how
it is done in mathematica
uh why don't we do that yeah i guess
unless you have some questions okay
so python you have then you have
a turpo you have a list then you have
turple
data structures then you have sequence
types
then you have dictionary then you have
how do you loop through dictionary or
list then you have uh how do you
write a package and how do you write a
function
and how do you write a class and object
and how do you write the module okay
you know it's we can go over that
it's pretty simple could you explain the
basics
while showing the fancy stuff
uh i could try
okay so let's let me let me
um so polar grid
rectangular grid we haven't tried we
haven't showed triangular grid okay let
me try
and u
okay try and get a grid uh but
what is the syntax okay
uh okay so
you know i hope to create a soft like
keys in mathematica uh
i don't know
okay that generates a triangular grid
yeah so here is the output
but you need to so the so these
are graphics primitives let me tell you
what they are okay
so first of all you have a color then
you have a
this expression so this line
is a function then it takes a list
each element is a point basically two
numbers
x and y coordinates so that represent
the line
from this point to this point so so this
kind of thing this
is called a graphics primitive you know
it's like
it's in like a javascript scvg svg
or in javascript canvas you know you
have similar things
circle line um
things uh svg for example
svg tutorial you have
svg basics you have how do you you know
how do you represent the line so this is
the syntax
in svg how you represent the line then
this is the syntax in svg of how you
represent the rectangle so you say
rectangle x and y
width and height so in the same way
in mathematica a line is represented
this way
now remember like i said before in
mathematica every
mathematical expression has the form you
know like that
and all these it's pure pure nothing
else
so you are so that's why you know you
uh you have that so here is a list of
graphics primitives
now if you want to actually print this
so you say
so you have to say graphics okay
graphics then you have to say
show show is like print except it's for
graphics
okay so if i do that you know you got a
triangular grid
now let's increase that let's say 10
okay 10 doesn't work so you want you
want more triangles
50. there you have it 50 let's
try 30.
let's let's try 20 okay that's a nice
one
so once you have a triangular grid let's
okay so let's show you a function then
so we have a rectangular grid let's do
some of these
uh transform 2d plot
uh yeah let's let's uh let's do a demo
okay so let's
show one of these
uh
yeah actually this the simplest is
actually okay let's type it here
transform to the
plot
okay in you know in mathematica since uh
wait
okay that's actually my function and
transform
okay transform 2d plot what how does it
what is the
syntax so first of all you need a
function
then you need x mean y mean okay so
that's simple so
x from x from zero to
five okay
copy then y
is also paste y is also from zero to
five
then what is a function so you want to
give a function so
okay so let's say x and y
so this is a function that takes a
vector x y
and return x y so it doesn't change
anything so let's
plot it okay so it you know
it begin with a grid so nothing changes
so let's say
2 times y okay so now let's change that
2 times y so you can see
it kind of squash it
now let's say y squared
okay it actually squashed more so
let's say here is x plus y
so that so this is kind of a shear
you know this transformation is called
shear
you know it's part of linear algebra
let's say
let's say sine y okay
sine y x and sine y
okay so you got kind of like that
and now let's increase the
the plot range okay
i think it you can kind of see a wave
you know more condensed expanded
condensed
expanded something like that
uh we can show it
better by
oh no okay so let's try to show it
better
yeah you kind of see it but this is not
so good
uh let's see options
plot points
yeah so you kind of see it
okay any questions
hello everyone could you explain the
basic okay so
so let's let's do the basics okay let's
show
let's talk about
how do you yeah the basics of
mathematica okay
the mathematical language
okay let's begin here
so first of all two uh so here is you do
addition
here is uh you do three plus three
times two for example uh
so arithmetic is similar now remember
mathematica always returns symbolic
result
if the input are symbolic now the input
if the input contains a approximate
number
then it returns approximate number so
you you could
have a big number divided by something
okay then it returns just that and you
can actually
you know plus another
random number divided by random number
then you got you know symbolic
form and if you want
if you want the result to be numerical
you
you can just use the n function okay
which is now the slash slash
is a notation for postfix notation
like the unix pipe that's a slash
slash in other words when you have x
f you know let's say when you have uh
that
okay when you have
g function applied on x and return value
is
feed to f that is equivalent to
you know these these two forms are
equivalent so the slash slash is like a
unix pipe
and it works for any function so it's
very general
so so in here so that's why we use
this slash slash n otherwise
normally you can say you can say you
know this
is how you do it
yeah if you want numerical results so
that's arithmetics
which is very common and and
not unusual from python or anything so
let's see what else
now strings in mathematica is just like
other language
this is a string okay
and you can also contain unicode so
let's
let's let me show you okay
so unicode
i love new york for example
okay so here's a string go back to
mathematica
paste it so you can have unicode
and also one more thing in mathematica
so you can see
this is a notebook right so let's save
it
let's save it let's save it uh
let's see let's save it to desktop okay
untitled save
now i go to desktop
so here is my desktop
so here is the untitled is that file so
if you open it in emacs it's
plain text this is what you see so
mathematica file is all plain text
now you know it's got this rule box i
don't like those things
uh the reason you have that is because
error messages
but anyway it should be easy to read
okay so let me uh
let me get yeah you see this
this pin box tag box squid
box style back box tag box two tip box
that's um what are those
those are kind of like formatting like
think of la tech
that's how you get you know this like
table
kind of like thing so actually let's get
rid of that
let's get rid of all these table like
kind of thing
okay i don't want that i don't want the
style box in those
boxes
okay i shouldn't delete that but anyway
oops so
wait okay save again
save now
open now
open this again in e-max so you can see
now this is better so you don't see
those boxes
now this is common in math
mathematica you use the
parenthesis than the asterisk sign
so the whole mathematica is again
mathematica is like lisp right it's a
pure nested
um uh purely nested syntax
so you can see here you see this is the
beginning of notebook
you know notebook so then begin with a
bracket
that bracket is basically the entire
you know the entire file it's all
everything is purely nested thing
so that's the beginning so this is the
beginning
the thing above that is some kind of
machine generated cache
information so you know it says this is
the notebook you know who find notebook
file that's a comment
and the url created by you know what
product and cache id then
then you have the internal cache
information
you know all those are common so the
actual notebook content is this line
you know beginning with the bracket and
if you match the bracket it's basically
the entire
you see in emacs you can you can jump to
the
end of bracket you know that's the
entire notebook
and until you reach the end
uh so that's here that's the end of
notebook
then the rest of that is again cash
information and
some kind of temporary information so
everything is text
plain text okay that's a mathematica
notebook
including graphics okay so what about
graphics how does
it how does mathematica represent
you know for example these graphics
so you if you open again emacs you can
see
let me magnify okay
let's see if it show graphics somewhere
yeah okay so it represents graphics by
graphics primitives here it is okay
uh
yeah so this is this is actual graphics
so you can see
what is this
you know graphics is very long
all right let's go back let's see
transform 2d plot let's see the first
graphics okay
polar grid so back in emacs we go to the
top
search for polar grid okay
search for that search again search
again
uh polar show graphics again
you know again you see this rule box
kind of thing i don't like that okay
that means okay now go back to
mathematica that means you are looking
at this
is actually not plain text i mean
it's plain text but it's formatted let
me show you
ctrl shift i yeah so this is better okay
so it
this is actually like that
return evaluated oh yeah
okay once you return it shows you know
so what what does that mean so basically
what it means is that mathematica
automatically shows them
let me hold on a second let me figure
this out
graphics cell convert to
input form cell convert to
raw input form okay that's what i like
raw input form
okay shift ctrl r for raw input form
so now if i save the if i save the
notebook save and open it in
in emacs again
and magnify go to the top search for
polar grid
so you can see it's much more simpler
now before you are seeing a bunch of raw
box rule box
you know those are type setting things
you know type setting
so right now so now you see the real you
know
the basic input you know text input like
like a programming source code
then you see this cell thing the cell
thing is actually
so back to mathematica the cell thing is
actually
that you know cell is kind of a unit of
source code so they you know each um
the source code is grouped by this unit
you know
so that's what the cells are you can
expand them or you can shrink them
uh just like oak mod you know just like
oakmont you can also have title titles
let me show you okay something
title okay and select that
then you go to style format
you have headers you know uh second
level heading and stuff
uh style yeah style title one
okay then you have a
second level title title
okay so select select that
cell not cell format style
o2 for subtitle
so once you have a title you can you can
see the title groups the entire notebook
so you can shrink you know or you can
show
just all the second level titles uh the
second level title doesn't
group but but you can set it to group so
let's say this
is all three
the third level title
so you can see it automatically group
this
thing then you can create another
okay select that alt three
something five plus five okay
so what what title is that format
style chapter okay title subtitle
chapter yeah
uh what style is that o3
yeah okay i made a mistake there you go
um so it's just like oak mod and
also you can export the whole thing into
la
tech tech la tech or
pdf okay i haven't showed you some type
settings so
i need to show some type setting you
know in order to do so let's say
let's try this i showed last time
x from zero to infinity okay
so one over x squared okay
so in fact let's copy that again
we can evaluate this
infinite expression encountered wait
does that um
let's say one to infinity okay
now you can select that and go to
grab go to cell convert to
standard form okay standard form then
formats like that
you just press a key okay so
now let's save this let's save this okay
wait
hold on a second let's save the notebook
go back to emacs close it reopen it
magnify let's go to the bottom let's
look at those
um those cement summation okay
hold on a second let me try let me do
something else
okay let's select this let's make it
raw input form okay so raw input form is
like
just plain text
evaluate that then okay now
save this save it go back to emacs
close reopen
magnify go to the bottom let me show you
the corresponding part
so here so you see this part
that's the raw input form so you can see
it's very simple
sum 1 over x squared x from 1 to
infinity
and this input means input form
then this cell change time is the
internal recording
of when did you modify that cell
then then you have a cell label that's
that's where you see the
print you know input 152
expression uuid so that's all internal
stuff
the most important thing you see is that
part
and then you have a cell because the
whole thing is a cell
so back to mathematica so that's what
you see here that correspond to these
this part now you can see the output is
formatted pi squared over six so now
back to
uh e max actually we can display this
side by side
so here is the output compared to
compared to that so you can see
then you start to see this box thing box
data
fraction box superscript box
you know what are those those are type
setting things
so in la tech or tech you know you use
backslash
and curly braces things like that
but in mathematica this is how you
represent for example to represent a
superscript
you do that okay now what's this
backslash bracket pi
that represent pi in a greek font okay
so
so you see this string is pi and this
string is two
then you say a superscript box
that gets you pi over 2.
then you have then you have you see the
fraction box
you know that fraction box so you got
the whole thing
so this is how type setting is uh
represented in mathematica
in fact you can actually just copy this
and
and and your work okay you can you can
actually type this directly so for
example
let's try paste
enter oh um
you have to
[Music]
i forgot what you have to do but you
basically you
um do i have oh you have to say box data
maybe
let's try
enter no it's not formatted
um i don't remember what you have to do
but basically you can actually type that
in
but no nobody nobody does this because
if you want there are much more
simpler ways and but anyway i'm just
showing you
the the underneath the
how it represents type setting in
mathematica
uh and it's plain text so again you can
see
everything is nested purely nested
brackets
syntax okay so that's
maybe that's it for today but um
actually we can continue to
to basics programming so let's see
comments
hello beautiful people hi uh hi
uh so uh how long have i been talking so
i've been talking for 58 minutes any
any questions about mathematica that's
what we are focusing today
so let me just talk for five more
minutes
uh then yeah let's uh
talk for five more minutes then
okay so that's how you do so we covered
basic arithmetics
uh where's my firefox
so we covered how do you do string
mathematica
then join string
join string so so something
let's let's see if the first sign works
i don't think so
yeah it doesn't work so join string is a
drawing string
or join maybe just join
no i think it's string joining okay
yeah i haven't coded mathematica for
for 20 years but i still remember
the memory comes back so string join for
example
abc def
that works uh i want to show you
something else
there is another general syntax shortcut
that is if you want to uh
have a infix
there's a infix shortcut for any
function okay so
in that form for example
f a b okay so here is a function right
so f a b that's a you know f can be
anything
a and b can be anything that's a
function now there is
for any function there is also a infix
notation for it
for a function that takes two arguments
you write it like this
okay
this is general this applies for any
function f
so in the case of string join we can do
it let's uh let me show you
now if i remember correctly i hope i did
i i hope
i was correct
okay enter there it is
so again we we have talked about so this
is a generic
uh shortcut syntax for in
the infix syntax for any function we
also talked about
the prefix syntax which is the
add sign and we also talked about the
postfix
generic postfix syntax which is the
slash
slash which is equivalent to unix pipe
okay what else uh let's see
so we have so arithmetics uh
assignments assignment in mathematica is
basically the same like other language
uh well the basic ones at least
then true and false in mathematica true
is this okay true is a building symbol
true
force force is a built-in symbol force
so and you have the n function
that takes two that takes two
any two expressions and you also have
the
or function that takes
any two expressions let's say for
example um
okay let's try end okay 1 plus
3 equals to five
and true is that true
fourth okay one plus three equals to
four
and true yes that's true
so and or and again notice every
everything mathematical takes this form
you know function
brackets then arguments uh or nested
okay i think so that's it for today i
think so
uh yeah no comments today
leo cardo you are late okay leo carter
where are you from
you've been here for a long time you
know watching my uh
youtube thank you but
i i think you went on star discord once
but i don't i never uh know
or remember where you came from in china
or in russia
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching bye
so i'm going to do a lot mathematica
coding
you know um yeah i need to
update all my packages you know i was
actually surprised
that my you know this package everything
runs and i was
admiring my own code that's written 20
years ago
but there's a lot of changes you know in
20 years mathematica has improved a lot
for example a lot of functions i
wrote today is not needed anymore
okay let me let me let me talk about
this one okay
random color function generator
so this function you know this function
here's the source code
the first part is the inline
documentation
you know again like i you know i did two
video
within the past month
so there are two videos recently about
mathematica so you should if you're
interested in mathematica you should go
watch it okay
uh so two of them in in
you know uh and um
so so i i said that mathematica that you
know the nature of mathematica is like
it's uh part of it is from lisp
and part of it is from apl the language
apl
and another part is the pattern matching
the symbolic pattern matching
uh you know mostly stefan wolfman
you know created
then you know so here
this function is interesting okay so i
have a function
random rgb color function generator so
what does it do
let me show you okay so it generates um
let's go back to my notebook it
generates
hey uh where is my
you know one thing i don't like about
windows is that
everything is a window it doesn't
distinguish
for example on the mac things are
grouped into
applications not windows so you have
several applications
then in each application you have
several windows
but on microsoft windows everything is
windows there's you know it
so i cannot press the key to switch to
the next application
instead of you know i press a key it
changes me to whatever
um wait not that key
uh wait do i still have it i don't
remember i have
but anyway the shortcut is alt escape
yeah old escape let's see yeah
escape or alt shift escape that changes
you to next window
so as you can see as i change
you know i'm in mathematica then i mean
task manager
then in obs then in broad in firefox
then mathematica again mathematica
then you know in chrome then mathematica
again you know it
it doesn't group them so that's one of
the annoying so now i have to
so let me show you this okay i want to
show you
now i cannot find what's the other
window uh
yeah i want to show you this function
random color generator okay
this is here is the definition uh
and basically it returns a function
okay did i run this code yes i did
why is it not returning a thing
what
and i don't know let's run it again
oh i didn't i didn't run the code so why
don't we just copy the code
yeah paste it here
so now i run it
now random rgb
color generator okay run it so you see
so what it returns is this is a function
okay this is a shortcut syntax notation
for a function
let or you can call it lambda okay so
this function
takes no argument but it returns a
function and
the implementation of this function is a
little bit advanced
it you know for this people
you can think of it is as a macro you
need
you need a macro
uh
so what what am i doing now so what uh
i'm going to
explain what is the point i'm going to
say
so anyway first of all you are seeing a
function that returns a function
functional programming so functional
programming is the main thing of
mathematica is the primary
programming style of mathematica you
know basically you can think of
mathematical as a lisp
okay it's not pure like haskell you know
you can
you can assign a variable easily
x equals to 5 you can then x
is 5 then you can change the value
easily okay
just like this so mostly you can think
of mathematica
as a list so here's this function
returns a function
okay how does this function work well it
um
so how do you
why does it how does this function work
okay
so so it returns a function now this
function is the
actual function that generates a random
color
taking one argument okay so this
function
for example the output
so we are getting into functional
programming so anyway so this
function returns a function therefore we
can give it
a argument so let's say the argument is
0.5 then it will return an actual color
okay so it's kind of brown brownish
let's let's try it again okay a
different
shade now let's try let me show you uh
something more fancy table
table just uh give you a list of things
okay
so here n and from
uh m from 1 to 100 okay let's see
okay so you got a bunch of random
functions
okay i i wanted to show you something
interesting about
some uh actually
uh i wanted to talk about this markers
um in fact i want to tell you
how mathematica is actually
a magnitude
you know the mathematical pattern
matching symbolic pattern matching
is almost it's basically just list
markers but
a magnitude more powerful that is
what i'm thinking of trying to explain
and that is in fact in this code in this
in this code you are looking at right
here
okay um but in order to do that
i have you know
i have to focus i have to uh be really
concentrated oh you know yeah or
you know you'll take half an hour to
explain every detail how it works
now let's skip it okay okay that's it
for today thank you guys for watching
yeah it windows doesn't have that
windows tilde no
no windows doesn't have you know on a
mac
once you are in an application there's a
shortcut to switch
to the next window of the same
application
so you can cycle for example in
mathematica i can cycle
among all my mathematical windows but in
windows you don't have that
so that that's kind of annoying
okay bye guys
i