hello guys
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
so today i'm going to create a emaclis
xr emacs distro that is
you just download the xiao e-max distro
then you go going to have a great e-max
setup so it's kind of a competitor
to doom e-max and
space max today is 2021
uh july 17th
okay so today is going to be just
just emac this coding okay i hope to do
this quickly
and i hope that by the end of the video
it will
probably more than one hour uh and no
more than two hours
by the end of the video you should you
shall have a
uh github okay saudi github you should
see xr
emacs on github and you should be able
to download it
and have a working emacs let's see
github working emacs saw emacs distro
okay uh at least the draft version
okay now where is my distro i i forgot
to log into
uh github yeah
okay i need to sign in um
okay i need to sign in and i need to
hide my
uh my screen so
okay so give me a minute to sign in and
hide my screen okay let's see
uh video audio video let's see where is
it video capture
uh where do i video capture
okay so you can still hear my voice okay
screen capture display capture there it
is
so you can still hear me and let's see
let me login
uh
okay i need to verify the
phone number i mean the sixth digit
secret code
okay i'm logged in so now let me turn
back the
video the my screen
there you have it okay so
mark the time and let's start to work
okay now if you have any comments feel
free to comment
thank you cortes
uh very good ronnie rays okay
justin car hi guys so
if you have a comment feel free to post
it i may
answer it but i do hope to focus to be
focused on
you know working on these emacs distro
so
uh so so so so so so let me let me get
to work okay
let me set this up here so i can see the
new comments coming and then okay
so uh go to so talk show this is my talk
show directory you can see
then uh today we are not going to use
the browser much
okay i forgot to turn on the javascript
refresh okay that's today's talk show we
are not going to
uh use the browser much so uh home
directory let's go to
my home directory okay now my home
directory so
this emacsd this is my current init file
and so you see we are going to do let
why don't we write it down so perhaps
it's better that way so
yeah because uh so we have kind of a uh
you know a goal uh
spec specification okay today
create a xsa emacs distro
and put it on github
okay so what it's so what is emacs
distro
that's going uh that's going to be
emax distro is mostly just
fly keys plus about
10 of my xa
packages okay and i believe that gives
you
a plus some emacs settings i believe
that will give you
a minimum kind of min you know as
hackers say minimalist
philosophy but i don't really like that
word
it's kind of it will give you a basic uh
very efficient
lean emax setup
okay and why do i want to create this
because you know i've been using it
you know i want to create it so that
so that i can actually have a casa
system
you know you know like one thing leads
to another you know once i have this
whole thing set up
i can start to add keys and started to
deviate from the
emacs the glue emax convention the
tradition you know i mean
space max and do max they both deviate
from gnu emacs you know
uh i worked on ergo emacs for like 10
years
uh about five you know 10 years ago so
anyway so now i'm starting over
why do i want to make it because once i
have this package
and and i can start it to have a
kind of like system like all my ideas
so stuff like keys will be compatible
with all the other
kind of all the other packages i can
start it to add
you know a system uh and
you know it will be kind of a competitor
to
space max and doing emacs although it
will be
a bit different in philosophy of course
and it will be pretty much plain emacs
so
unlike space max for example it
space max has its own kind of
system it you know spacemax developed a
layer kind of a
kind of their own system directory
structure and for
for configuration for extension just
specific to
space max now doom e max
is not like that but it has its own
philosophy and
it creates like 400 packages it installs
400 packages and also both of them
are based on centered around the
veeam key binding which is
a good thing you know there are good
reasons there are advantages and there
are disadvantages
the advantage is that you can use emacs
once you get used to it you can use both
emacs
and you can use vim uh you can you know
flexible and they are fairly they have a
lot
users because of them veeam you know
veeam is
built-in editor in unix
kind of the standard the mainstream
editor
in unix systems or linux you know it's
you don't have to install it
on the other hand emacs you have to
install it even in linux
so vim has become very popular you know
even though it's kind of hard
difficult to use but it has kind of it's
a standard and
sort of just like microsoft windows the
visual studio code editor is kind of the
standard
and on the mac the standard is the
you know the mag i forgot the name now
that you know the
the mac os what's the code uh you know
we
go to discord then we can see
uh someone sietse
how do you pronounce your name csa he uh
he mentioned that
you know anyway the is staying at africa
let's get on so i want to work on stuff
like uh
so emax distro it will be centered
around stuff like keys
then i will you know plus some tens of
my packages
and i wasn't doing this before you know
anyway so that's enough about the
reasons let's do it
thank you george from australia
from cortes from america and george from
australia
am i right is that the georgia i know i
think so
[Laughter]
great uh
guillermo good morning from
is that italy palazzi franco plazi
okay so stuff like so imax distro so oh
my god
it's a big task how am i gonna finish i
already
wasted 10 minutes okay so
okay so let's begin so first of all okay
i already created a git
you can see here eight people watching
fantastic
oh yeah so let's find repositories
let's find my code you know the hacker
says where's your code
where's your contribution
okay i do have some i have some
okay emacs okay here it's empty
and uh it says emacs site it needs to
change okay so
uh i already also already set up a
bookmark so you can see this is the
directory
so corresponding to that git and this
needs
to change because emacs distro let's
dive into ishow
and let's git commit let's get let's say
git status okay
good status something something okay
get fire modified okay git add
something something get committed ado
that's right this is lots of a dude
that's committed okay
now get push
okay this is the standard operation the
unix
way okay refresh casa emacs distro
that's right that's uh
good
close that then first of all so
okay so let's let's begin okay so
so okay let's move this here
a little bit let's move that here
adjustment
okay let's go to settings okay
so you are looking at the directory uh
of all my emacs settings okay
so i know a few things i want let me let
me explain how these settings work okay
so first of all you have a need file
search for init
so there it is the init file you open it
and this is basically the main init file
it
this file tells emacs to load other
files in
and packages so first of all the most
important
uh thing is a few packages we need okay
so it you know it's going to be stuff
like keys and
ev smart because uh insert random id
card css smart
inside html and so on okay i need to uh
comments questions okay hello hello okay
i need to do this so first of all i need
a directory structure
um so this is this is the
emacs directory they gonna get they're
gonna get poor
get chronic and uh in this uh
it is five files okay so
so actually sometimes we can look at how
space max or doing emacs do it
you know even i i've i have created
ergo emacs before but
sometimes i don't remember okay this is
a doom
you know i did the video trying to
install doom before
and that video is one hour and it's
pretty lousy
because i forgot that i need to know
veeam keystrokes in order to actually do
something with 2max
but okay so they have a directory called
modules that's the way they do it and in
the modules they have several
directories
of different kind of different uh
tasks the map the module is supposed to
do
okay so uh folks for example emacs is
not going to be that complex so doom
also has a server directory or
it's empty then the test directory okay
and each other okay so that's doom emacs
so we are going to okay think
stop talking i need to actually think
so i need to create a directory the
directory so first of all
so you know about three months ago i
switched to
i started to install emacs on my other
other uh the laptop the surface pro
and there i have to you know install my
mic
saw config from scratch uh basically
oh okay i i talk too much okay let's
let's let's
let's um so first of all i need
sapphire keys okay so actually write it
down
knees need soft like keys
needs lots of casa packages okay
then
okay let's go let's start to do it go to
the my git directory
let's search for uh emax
okay so i need to supply keys okay
how the how is this going to be
uh
packages okay let's just create a
directory
okay open it and the sunflower keys copy
it
copy it over and let's go up
let's see
okay xr css mod
so what what the distribution will
include besides clock
supply keys
finish your story about the other
computer please okay
so it's going to be supply keys and
basically several other
uh my packages for css for html for
javascript
these are the main ones and for emac
bisp
and some of some kind of other utilities
such as insert random id and
smacks smacks is not my package but
it will be included in some e-max distro
uh so here's side streaming such as
because i find
diet okay because i find is another big
package
uh feature in inside emacs and casa diet
is another big
kind of big feature uh then some crucial
mod not so much because
php not so much uh these i can skip
uh cause i look up is uh very useful
that's gonna be another kind of feature
of
emacs then some math input will also be
there
basically my main packages okay uh
and and and it will also include
a few like like three or four other
people's packages that i find useful
okay my story about other computer okay
that
there's not much okay i was installing
you know i was using this uh
i have a surface book and a few months
ago half a year ago i
tried to run emacs on it so i have to
install
uh from scratch basically suppose i
go to your home
you know if you invite me to your home
if i have to say you know if you gotta
if you got a new job i have to set up
my emacs so and that's easy yeah
basically you finish that in
in 30 minutes you know
oh basically all i have to do so if
right now i'm on a new machine all i
have to do
is go to get you know this this whole
directory is on git
uh emacs init you know then download
everything then then basically download
all the packages i
requested require in the init file about
about 10 or also most of them my
own packages and and then
include the rest of the my settings in
info and that's about
it okay so in order to create the xr
emacs configuration it's actually gonna
be pretty much the same steps
except that now i have to worry about
directory structure because this is
going to be
used by everyone you know everyone just
download these emacs
so it's i have to think about what's the
directory name
uh you know properly as opposed to
whatever directory my init file is at
you know for example for example if you
go to my init file
so this init file is the main thing it
loads every other thing
so if you open it if you go to flight
supply keys you can see here is my
config for
soft light keys and as you can see it
loads the package
at my git repo
you know for me that works fine but if
you're gonna create a distribution
you don't want xsa
emacs you know part of emacs stuff
in some kind of outside directory
so okay let's let let's let's let's get
let's get this done
okay so so so cause i get things okay
this i need okay
so let's go over here and let's
switch to the init file okay let's go to
uh from the top then
actually okay go up actually copy the
entire init file wait copy the entire
init file over here uh
and rename it emacs init
okay then we open the init
then we do them one by one okay let's
see
required i do yes loading custom command
in functions
yes okay okay so let's
let's magnify okay so actually let's
drink
okay so we need that
so load start emac settings so that's
the first thing
let's go to emacs settings uh
okay copy the file and back to here
create a new buffer paste it then
save it and save xr
emacs settings dot el okay and change
the name here
to without the underscore
okay now we can open the settings file
open it
so here's the settings let's look over
the settings so this settings file
is the most fundamental basic setup for
emacs
because it does not require any package
it's the most basics
basic gnu emac setup
so you by the way you can find all these
on my github
but it's going to change once i create
the emax package
i'm going to load this is
you know as my i'm going to use it
myself like
eating your own dog food food then
then i'm going to load my own init files
which will
change anyway so settings okay
settings let's not worry about settings
because they are
uh they are the same for you know they
don't require any extra package
they just rely on the basic gnu emacs
okay so the settings you know electric
indent set default tab always intend and
so on
and some of the the others
we can worry about later okay now emacs
abbrev
okay so emacs a brief
uh a brief higher okay so let's go to uh
my agree
okay at this rate we are not going to go
anywhere
after two hours so i need to really
start to just
start to code instead of talking
uh emacs brief okay copy okay so let's
do it
so i'm going to create the emacs a brief
file
here rename dot el okay
uh wait okay
so okay so that part is done
now uh load path
okay load path uh load the current
directory load
file okay so now
i need this package start get thing or
selection okay
so back to the init file uh
close the settings
okay i need to open this file
so here is a package copy it
copy it go to the directory go to the
packages
new file paste it and
save it okay
so you can see there it is
now close that close that okay so that's
one thing cause i get setting good thing
or selection
okay actually at this rate
we are not going to get anywhere so i
need to actually
hurry up something uh the
load path will be
the load path the load path will be
okay i hope that i hope that does
because this is going to be
okay that's that's um
okay so far let's comment out the rest
of
it so you can see
so we just have right now we just we
loaded
two configuration files
and in one package
casa gets thing okay
then
god there are a lot to do actually
you know if
every time i start to do this
you know i think it's trivial well it's
trivial for me
after two hours but if i do this live
i have to explain a lot things because
otherwise you don't know what i'm doing
uh
yeah because actually i did one hour
video on this
about a month ago and that didn't go
anywhere
at the end of one hour so today i'm
actually starting over
but now there's actually a lot to do
so right now emacs
consists of these three settings files
one unit file and two other settings
file
and also two packages okay
uh okay now let's try to get these two
packages
to work so that we can actually start
emacs okay that's not too hard
so so let's copy the soft flag keys
config
let's go back to the init file
open it
with the sci-fi keys yeah
god
okay so so actually let's
load path now can add to this take a
relative path
i don't know describe function
uh list var element optional append
node path add to list node path
okay now can load path take a
relative path i don't think so so let's
see describe variable load path okay
so here is a bunch of all my load paths
let's copy that
new buffer and let's make it
uh space to new line
let's make it this way so it's legible
so you can see every path in
my load path is actually a full path
it's not
relative path so that means the value
for load path
probably needs to be full path therefore
this line of code is
wrong so we need to modify it we need to
change this to full path how do we do
that
well the magic of emac bisp
expand file path expand file name
there it is that's a command okay
so
so let's try it okay so let's see
expand file name this path
then optional let's forget about option
then let's evaluate this expression and
see what we get
okay let's evaluate it now you can see
in the mini buffer
the full path shows in the mini buffer
which is correct
you can see here so this is the correct
code
deleted
okay we need to put it here then remove
that you see
this line becomes this line okay so
that's how you do it
that's right okay now everything you
need a
expand expand file name so let's do
why don't we just add okay
so
add that okay so load path
actually so we're gonna replace
all these load paths something
query replace to load path
that okay i hope you can see it
yeah okay so that
okay so xxx
okay do it do it
kind of do it do it do it do it do it do
it do it do it do it
do it do it with the god this
how many 19
that means i have two you know move 19
packages
here okay so anyway let's fix them one
by one so get thing
get is like thing at point if you are a
lisp coder then you know what that is am
i still talking
check good
if you know if you called emac this
there's a thing at point
now socket thing is a enhancement of
that
and it is used by some of my other
packages okay
so now get replace pairs
okay so uh expand file and load path
okay
okay i discovered another thing load
path
we don't need a load path
should end in what
load path is a directory right yeah so
load path is a directory
that's right load path is a directory so
we don't need
this part okay so and
and yeah so evaluate the buffer
let me evaluate the expression evaluate
last expression
and we see we see
the uh path correct okay so that's one
time
thing we don't need actually do to do
that
so delete that
so replace pairs now it makes everything
simpler okay now cloud replace pairs is
a emaclis utility that
provides a simple syntax to replace
multiple pairs of strings find and
replace
pairs of strings in one shot
so you don't have to do a while while
loop
in emac bisp okay so
so what is this uh emac this utility
okay we need that
and what is this this is saffly keys
so load path we don't need anymore
i mean add to this load path we don't
need that's right
so okay so now we have three package
here three packages here let's add it to
the packages
okay now go back to my personal
uh you need file let's see where are the
uh okay you need file where are the so
what's the next thing we need to
add find replace
pairs that's the one okay so it's in
this directory
so copy it
over here over here new buffer
paste it back here go to the diet
copy the file name back to
this window save it as something
something dot yeah
done go to the diet you can see here
okay fantastic close uh
and close close okay now next
sar emac list utility
open the directory open the file copy
back here new buffer paste
save save as
copy the file name save as
xsa emac utility dot el
fantastic close it refresh you can see
it's here now close close
next soft light keys the big item okay
open the directory open the file
copy the file back here new buffer
paste you know actually we can use the
marker for this
uh but uh okay so now save the file
sapphire keys dot el close it
refresh you can see is here okay
close close okay now soft like keys
is there okay now
we can you know we can reach we
reached a break break point
so so far the so far so good
schneiderman van says hi girl gonna be
uh
okay okay buffalo meat oh
buffalo meat okay
so cassava okay so so far
emacs package has this config files okay
now let me recap the
emax init is what we have been working
on so far just
30 lines 70 80 lines okay
so emacs in it and this init files loads
all these other init files wait um
and also loads these packages okay
now these stuff like keys should
shouldn't be here
delete now this is you util
should be over there so there that's
right so right now it loads four
packages
and uh and this init file okay
we can call it a day and try it okay so
now this is
let's okay let's let's you know let's
show you the overall
the overall structure okay so now
git status what's our status git says
oh you got a new directory and so on git
add okay add them all
now git commit ado
commit and commitment okay
now let's go to github
thank you microsoft for github
oh we forgot to get push get
push
okay to https github okay
now github refresh in the browser
fantastic
now you can actually go there and
download git clone xy max
and we don't know if it works we don't
know
so the next step is to test it
once if that the test passed unit test
[Laughter]
once that passed then we we actually
have the
emax package we can just gradually add
more
configurations and more packages okay
now how do you test well in order to
test
you have to get rid of your emacs
directory
wait let's see you know
then we start to have to we we have to
now we are in a position to write
documentation
like you know people go here then they
how do you install it
what command what you know we have to
okay so what's the next thing uh so once
people
clone these all you have to do
in your emaxd is that
for example let's look at my emacs init
okay
you see so if i open it let's show the
pink window
so if i open the emacs init you see
there
there are not many things let me read up
the uh
comments i don't need these comments
okay
so actually what is this yeah
powershell gomas mix okay we don't we
don't need it
okay so the whole init file is this
single line
you know it tells in tells emacs to load
another file as your actual unit file
this is good
so let's undo this now let's
make a backup go to the directory
you can see the backup here okay
then open the init file we don't need it
anymore so
delete this part and tell it to load
the exact emax in it so this is what you
tell people to do
so where is xymax in it it's in this
directory copy the file path
let me show you okay so you can see
so basically comment that out so you
tell people to
in your emacs.emax.d
init.ell you tell people to add this
slide
and the file path will be pointing to
your
emacs directory wherever you installed
it okay
that's instruction we need to write that
okay
so open the soft like emacs
directory open a new buffer and
uh installation instruction okay save
the file as
install me something like that for now
okay dot txt
okay we it will be very simple okay let
me let me say you know
uh
create a file name
add
in that file put this line
okay
where okay wait
full path to emax
okay so this is the instruction
for installation
okay
directory path should end in a
slash okay that's the instruction
save it go to diet you can see
we refresh we created a install readme
okay now
now we are going back to our init file
you see the emacs init file and this is
all there it is okay let's
try it okay
let's go to e shell clear
okay let's magnify the e shell i mean
not each other powershell
microsoft powershell now do we have the
emax
path no we don't so
okay so we have to now i have to start
emacs from the shell
okay so let's go to uh
download
download emacs bing
okay run emacs uh
what why is it not completing
what e max d that's wrong
what
cd to the e-max being what's going on
glad it's not open uh
okay so here is the
the location of my emacs installation
so there's a emac c
there by mistakes i created by mistake
so you
actually want when you want to start
emacs you want to run the command
run emacs okay
the font is too small
and i'm not sure how i don't think it's
possible to increase the font size
on the windows the idiotic windows
there it is there it is run emacs okay
okay so back to powershell why the
okay yeah
yeah it's idiotic let's go back to emacs
okay
download emacs bing
search for run there it is copy the file
path
new buffer paste it that's much more
faster than doing it in emac
in in powershell okay so copy that
so clear you don't need to clear
actually just paste it
so this is how you run emacs in windows
on the command line
okay now once we run it we all know
you know once we run it let me repeat
okay if we are load
close that close that close that close
that it will load this
you know dot emacs d in my home
directory
it will load this init file init.ell and
in this file you just
tell emacs to load the emax okay
test do it
warning initialization an error occurred
while loading
c users.emacs.d init.el file is missing
cannot open load file no search firewall
directory
users are git xymax not
what do you mean no no search directory
let's try to open it
it opened what the
what
load file users get
split buffer open it
what do you mean what do you mean what
do you mean cannot open load file
no search file directory c user's site
slash git slash emacs
okay see users get slash
there is a directory what do you mean
you cannot
no search file directory
i don't know why so let's evaluate this
list
code and see what happens okay
so if our last expression
there is the error file missing cannot
open load file no search file or blah
blah blah
no such file your ass
now is that because of the c the drive
prefix on windows you know emacs don't
support windows well yes
cannot load file what do you mean cannot
load file the
file does not exist the file is right
there
oh oh oh
i know why okay now let's
get rid of the okay why
why this doesn't work because i
it up
this should be a file not directory
yeah okay so this should be your file
i'm giving it
it a directory that's incorrect this
should be a file okay so the file is
this file name okay
copy the file path close it select or
paste it fantastic
okay okay
file and let's let's also go back to the
let's
we need to change the instruction so go
back to kasa emax instruction file
install read me full path
to
and yeah so actually
okay that's that's right save it
okay then remove this line we don't need
okay
that's it that's that now try again
now close that back to powershell
do it okay
now a new error an error occurred while
loading something something
dot emacs dot d init.er file is missing
cannot open load file no search file
directory because i get thing
okay uh use it anyway yeah but it's
you see uh it worked
okay so yeah it kind of worked but we
got error okay so let's quit
what's going on my talk show let's see
my talk show don't up with my talk
show
okay so we got some path error
so no problem let's open the
wait what oh let's let's open the yeah
the xr emacs in it some path is
incorrect here we can fix that
now what what is the error i forgot
what's his error so
so load path um
so load path should be correct so
getting
packages
exactly thing is there
now why is sage thing is not what what
what
do it again let's see what's the error
file is missing cannot open file no
search file or directory
so get thing so
this part okay
why is it not why cannot you load it
you idiot
search did we have a spelling error no
uh so require socket thing
okay uh yeah but the socket thing is
right here why can't you just find it
well that's probably because your load
path is incur
incorrect
let's see packages did we spell it
incorrectly
search for packages no that's correct
okay so at this point what you have to
do
is you have to say
let's debug time
okay so we
okay actually if i just think it should
work
you know that's a thing so you guys have
just watched me
uh so what uh
file missing so it's you see it says
here it cannot
load the excel file thing i mean the
socket thing
thing why probably because the load path
the packages path
is not it's not getting it
okay so why
so you know what we can do is say
messages
okay messages load path
you know we can do that then it will
print
yo what timing i just switched to work i
expect your distro will be well worth it
will be one well worth it
thank you that's what i hope for so
okay so debug debug time so let's print
the load path shall we actually i
you know i don't need to do
this because if i just think i should
know what's going on
so why is the so okay let's
let me think okay
user get xa emacs packages
so that's a directory so load path
so you add to list to you know add to
the load path
the value of load path is a list
of paths you know a bunch of folder
names
and uh it should be a full path
so we just added you know we use the add
to this function to add this
this relate you know this this is a
related path but
we use the expand file name to get the
full path
so okay so i think
what's going on is that the expand file
name
stupid these i know what's going on okay
so expand file name
you know we are trying to use this
function expand file name to convert
a relative path to a full path now
in order to do that one of the
ingredients you need
is you need the reference path
so normally you know you think of
relative path is related to the current
path so the current path of course is
this file
so you know this file is the emacs init
you know this file is in imax in it and
the packages directory is a
is in the same directory so it should
load it
but however in emac this
when you use expand file name the the
current directory
is not actually this file it's not
actually the file it's actually running
that's a problem of the emac this
idiotic okay the current directory is
actually
wherever you run it it's the current
directory is probably
you know the my emacs you know being
something run emacs you know that
directory
so when you expand file name with
respect to that directory
of course there's no subdirectory named
packages under it
that's what i think okay i'm pretty sure
and
for this reason that's why this long
function i mean this function
exists you know get full path okay so
okay yeah so i need to use this function
stupid emax
so instead of using expand file name let
me show you
the changes we need okay so let's work
on this
copy it so let's
there so this is uh this is how you do
it start get full path then packages
okay let's try it
yeah okay so didn't you so comment that
out clean delete that
good back to powershell let's start
again now let's close this
emacs do we have another emacs instance
right okay so close that
now let's make it different so right now
my emac setting you see the background
is this you know kind of this is called
honeydew
color so that's you know in it let's
make it
set background color okay
what
why is it no completion set background
color okay oh
yeah i i forgot what's the syntax for
background color so let's
let's just search it okay so
settings uh
okay so that's how you do it honeydew
okay so it's a string
so okay set background color let's use a
color
let's this color display okay i forgot
what's the name i want
okay so cone silk okay i remember corn
silk is a good one okay
so in some packages the concealer
is gonna be the background now so now go
switch to powershell
run it do it fantastic
[Laughter]
kaza emax is complete
can you see that yes
hey yes okay yeah yes yeah
basically it's kind of like complete it
it
even loaded my closet yeah
so does do that do i have supply keys
yes i'm even using stuff like he's
fantastic
so final so today i would consider this
youtube
this today's live stream is successful
okay it's you know good enough you know
right
like okay let's give commit let's let's
give commit okay so let's
so summarize let me summarize again so
stuff like xiaomi max is a package you
can download right now okay
let's commit first okay let's go to
e-show
git status please get at all
please get commit
please ado get
push please
okay so it's not on github that means
you can go to
github go to github wait what the
why why do i have that on multiple
what
what's this black one oh that's a
comment common in a separate window so
you can go to github refresh
you know go to github now cuz github
then you have
sa emacs and uh
it's basically that's it that's that's
uh so
and you download it you read the
instruction let's read the instruction
install readme
follow the instruction and you will have
casa emax package
so what is what is left to do
close that so back to my emacs so what
is left to do let's see
where is it so you are looking at wait
wait oh the c
shell got you know the cone shell color
got over written
by by my init here so
okay so settings uh so let's let's let's
change it to uh okay yeah so let's do
that
conceal okay that's the background color
conceal
conceal so remove that okay actually
let's start
okay so let's not to have too many
windows close the new one
okay now let's not have too many windows
let's
close this window okay so
okay so now go to powershell start it
well that's what you're taking too long
but anyway so that's
that there you have it that's the e-max
so what's
you know what else we have to do we have
to basically add
10 more packages or 15
but it's becoming you know at this point
is basically the
structure is basically done okay
actually i
you know when you do you know actually i
i might have to rename a thing here or
there
um you know things like that
uh but basically the structure is done
so you see
it's not difficult at all it's kind of
trivial so we talked for one hour
precisely one hour now and we can call
it a day so what comments
so any comments you have post it now
well can you make these streams as part
one two
three like creating emacs part one and
so on would love to follow
okay uh yes i can do that you know
but basically we are done here uh
for xa emacs because you know yeah i
showed
you know you see it's nothing fancy you
know
space max and do max is much more
fancier they require
lots of structure lots of you know in
space max
yeah they you know lots of things but
for for my stuff
one of the reason you know my emac setup
is
very lean you know only required 20
packages
is because i like it that way i like i
want glue emacs
and also because i've been using emacs
for 20 years so i'm
either imagining this coder so i don't
use other people's packages
almost none of it you know except you
know a few
um anything i want i read my own so
and i also make sure that all my
packages are
the extreme efficient possible in terms
of
speed also in terms of key strokes so
for the users
it's the most efficient and also the
fastest
uh these you know many other emacs
developers and features packages you
know
doing emacs space max they include lots
of packages
and they have their advantages such as
they provide lots of user interface
coloring
you know the and but you know that's
uh we have different philosophy so you
know yeah you can try different ones
so my you know the one saw emacs is very
lean
uh and uh very fast everything you need
to do it mostly rely on the
glue emax power the internal power you
don't need you know
you don't need like i talked about the
um things
you know for example a lot of people
like
uh hedra you know there's a hedra key
binding
there's a god mod key binding there is
a you know there is a
helm you know there's icicles which is
the old one
there's you know there are quite a lot
of these very popular you know
uh and they are good you know and they
in them some people are like
projectile and some people like
in there and you know there are tens of
theme
add-ons you know make every package
veeam
compatible evil mod compatible and so on
so they are good they are different
feature set okay but
um you know you know many of them
with lots of prettiness usually means
it's slower
unavoidably okay that i think that's it
uh okay let me drink and that's it for
today i think
let's let's add one more okay so let's
add one more thing
to emax in it so first of all close this
so i i'm glad this is actually done
actually so i can use
soft light keys to quit emacs so on
vorack
it's it's space
w q so watch my type space w
q fantastic
okay so you see now i'm back on my
my my emacs so let's add one more thing
maybe okay so let's see
so now we have three package we have
actually four packages
you know uh exactly think some replace
pair xre this
utility and supply keys and also
since i'm doing this package for other
people i need to remove that
you know vorack because other people are
probably not borax
okay remove that then
then um then smix
okay smix i need okay
oh okay so that let's let's install that
smex smix mix is a great one i like smix
smacks is a meta x replacement
the full name is
the emacs command full name is execute
extended
command you know that's that's the
command name for when you press meta x
and smax is a replacement it's a
fantastic replacement
and let's okay let's let's go to let's
go to smacks
uh directory okay so let's go to let's
see where is it so that
i need to go to my settings uh
okay search for smacks there it is
okay open the file copy it
go back to the excel emacs packages
open new buffer
save it as smx dot e
l okay now go to diet you can see
there it is new okay refresh
yeah there it is okay then
then then we can start
start emax again
it's too slow okay but anyway
it it there it is okay and course makes
wrong arguments command p
smacks what
uh smacks is here so why is it not
in packages right smex that's right
let's open it
smex spelled correctly close
that let's go back to init file
open it secure
uh oh yeah because you haven't loaded of
course
what an idiocy you know you configured
you configured it for safely keys but
you haven't actually load
smacks okay okay
where's max where did that loads max
let's search
smex okay kind of late here
uncomment uncomment it
and uh just say load okay
delete that let's load here okay let's
load
it here in
instead of load let's require smacks
okay
fantastic now
close that try again
emacs good
press a for smacks you know press a
because
i mean stuff like keys so i press a
fantastic can you see
let me let me cancel okay ctrl g let me
try again
now this is qwerty okay control g is
here
get that back my god i'm on
soft light i'm i'm a quality physical
keyboard
but the soft light keys on emac is set
up to use
i mean i'm i'm on a roll rack physical
keyboard
but the stuff like keys on on emacs is
using quality
so in qwerty to
cancel should be ctrl g
so i need to type control g in rorack
okay so
ctrl g there it is
okay so now press a
press a to call smax do it
fantastic you can see magnify you see
so that's smix okay cancel okay ctrl g
cancel yeah
wait cancel yeah so this is side e max
okay
now let's i think that's it for today
okay so let's
go to e shell again git status
git add git commit
get push
now back to google chrome
github
go to emacs magnify
okay so you click on packages you can
see
smex is there a lot of ado okay that's
it thank you
guys for watching fantastic
what do i think about auto completion
yeah that's okay that that's a good
question auto completion is a very
useful package
uh you know there are several of them
you know one is named autocomplete
the other one is called company what an
idiotic name company
it actually stands for
complete you know something like
complete or something
c-o-m you know actually if i write it
down
c-o-m-p-a-n-y you know there's a company
mod which is a
complete any okay so company mod
it actually stands for complete any
which is supposed to be a improved
version
improved version of the autocomplete
package okay those are external packages
you know that
you know this is one of the problems of
the new emacs and free software
foundation
they should have built it in emacs but
all you know
the emacs also have completion but that
is pretty old you know old technology
you know you don't have a pop-up you
know thing
widget you know at at the point you want
to complete
but however however auto complete
and that company mod they are hacks okay
they are extreme hacks because emacs
emac these do not actually have a
infrastructure
to let you have pop-ups okay so this so
i'm gonna start to talk random now
i'm done with today's main thing let me
talk random
okay let's look at javascript javascript
let's look at dom
okay now you scroll down and
turn on javascript yeah turn on
javascript you go to
um popup okay two tips in
mac it's called balloon help
okay not pop-up window wait wait hold on
a second okay
uh image rollover stopwatch uh how to
create a tooltip okay
so you see i hoover over here you have
this pop-up okay on windows this is
called tool tip
you know you it will you see uh
you see when you move kuza to a certain
widget you'll say
what it'll give you a short explanation
what that
widget or button do so
in html with javascript technology and
dom
in css you can also implement that and i
show you how to do it
okay that's this that's this you know
search for javascript how to create
tooltip with my name
add my name to it you'll find my page
that's how you do in javascript in e-max
you can also have that
there are several techniques but anyway
anyway the way
auto complete and uh you know the way
their interface is not is is a hack okay
basically you cannot you
you know you you kind of can you can you
know you can achieve this effect
in imac in imax by a hack
so the code is very complex so i don't
like those
so but completion is a
greatly useful feature what do i do what
what do i do
if i don't use autocomplete or um
or company mod okay here what i do
for example let's open let me show you
okay
switch to emacs so i want the fun okay
so uh different so let's see
let's let's switch to emacly smart okay
so
uh core emacs lisp
mod this is the default emacly smart
from gnu
okay so let's magnify let's say i want
to type
defend press tab
it doesn't work a pack i just want
defund
press tab and it gives you that
different
declare declaration 80s different prompt
rejects
i don't want that i just want the
different
function to define a function any
magnets you don't you know
so instead i have to type
let's try control alt tab okay
oh oh oh
yeah that's another thing because you
know emacs default keys conflict with
windows and mac
so now i have to stop you know either
change emacs keys for conversion or i
have to
change windows key from stealing
you know e-max keys
that's an e-max problem you know they
need to fix this but the e-max people
they are elite
we are here first you know you should
change your windows keys to
to e-max keys emacs
them that's they that's why the
emacs users there's no users
shrink and shrink and shrink but they
don't know they think there's a lot of
emacs users
look look there's a uh on youtube
there's so many emacs
you know hackers that's such a sadie
they are all glorifying emacs eventually
the
so anyway so completion you know
different
so what you have to do you have to
actually add the parentheses first okay
you so
you type parenthesis then
then ddf okay then you press tab then
then you got the completion okay let's
see the d d-d-f-u-n
okay let's tap again
okay so possible completion are that and
that okay enter
yeah
complete
possible completions are different yeah
i just want different how do i
i forgot what the tab doesn't work
space okay so that
did i um anyway so that's the
e-max way okay so that's this for most
people this is when you want to install
company mod or autocomplete you know
actually i can show you
once how beautiful that is okay so these
packages okay let's
let's ramble okay let's ramble about
emacs
so let's install uh let's install what
the
uh let's install let's call
this packages let's install company mod
okay search for company
okay this you know they have a lot of uh
compatible comp
you know let's see
you know so now they have 160 matches
for company mod
because you know so you have this
company mod which is
for completion but then you have like a
bunch of others
that adds uh compatibility for other
mods you know that the company erlang
company flow
company flicks company 1 000 packages
you have to install yeah and you
and as an e-max user you have to figure
all this out yourself
that is why space max and do max they
become popular
nobody is using glue emacs
that's the e-max problem that's the
mothership the problem of the mothership
richard stowman he should be
responsible for it
because he's not you know he did anyway
so company mod okay so i'm just going to
go into company mod here
and i'm going to install it okay open it
okay install yes yes yes yes
okay i have company mod let's close it
close it okay
back to my uh single window
single window close it close it okay now
let's try the different let's turn on
company mod first
company mod enabled in current buffer
okay now press tab
wait no let i don't even have to press
tab let's just type different okay
let's try again d e f
there it is d f u n
no no why why why doesn't it have just
different
mark ah the problem
i don't know what is going on but
usually you just uh
you know i why why is it not giving me
oh okay
okay it also needs a parenthesis first
okay
a pain in the ass there it is
oh wait why doesn't is there a way to
they knew anyway there it is company mod
okay then you need white
snippet why a snippet which stands for
yet another you know submit
which is 10 years history i know it
personally because
10 years ago i was thrilled about it i
wrote lots
several tutorials and so on i don't use
it them these days
so anyway there is your company mod then
if you want the template for the default
you need wire snippet which i
actually contributed the these templates
okay
but i don't use this in these days okay
so what i do i use
so let me show you switch took soft like
star emacs this smart okay now i mean so
emacs it is smart
magnify okay now i just you want
different
okay there it is okay let's try again
actually i just type d
okay enter you got different enter again
you got the whole
template parenthesis and you can also
you know you you have all 1000 emac
these functions templates okay
uh the most frequently used
ones you know the top 150 the top 50
ones
you have a one letter or two letter
abbreviation okay so
um you know i you know i have a website
just search for xa emac this smart you
can see my explanation why
you know features so this is
how i do completion but what if you are
in javascript
what if you are in golan what if you are
coding php
where is your completion then do you
actually have to write a mod
for every language that's what i happen
to do
i happen to write a mod
for the completion the way i like
for the languages i use which includes
e-magly's javascript
mostly just these two okay emac is
javascript
html css
and what else and i also have a package
for closure but it's not you know it
hasn't been maintained for several years
anyway
so so what is the solution
for completion inside emacs distro
because i don't think i can you know
write a mod for every major languages
there are too many it doesn't take much
time though by the way but
i'm not going to do it so i will
probably
bundle autocomplete possibly okay i
don't know i don't know for sure
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching
most videos on youtube are about 100
years old
huh
i can't even means i cannot convince
myself to switch from vim to emacs i'm
very accustomed
to my vim key bindings well there's evil
mod which is
veeam in emacs
okay that's it thank you guys and thank
you cortes
thank you george
for the pizza and uh bye guys
bye my tutorial okay by my tutorial by
my javascript tutorial
it's a best javascript tutorial in depth
top three okay top three javascript
tutorial in depth
and in breath cover the entire language
in the english speaking universe
okay i would consider my javascript
would be the top three
including whoever wrote them you know in
the
history wherever you can find online
or printed books you know there are
quite a few you know also
by the uh
you know i can name you know by by by
the yahoo guy
by the guy who created jason what's
what's his name you know by
whoever javascript you know literature
out there
that teaches javascript in depth or even
as a beginner okay
even as a javascript basic for beginners
or in depth
okay all that exists out there
print it all online i would consider
javascript in depth is the best one okay
or to be not so arrogant i would
consider my javascript in depth
to be top three top three you know one
of the best
so it depends on your preference for
writing style for organization for
explanation style okay so you guys buy
it
and buy my emacs tutorial
okay that's 90 minutes today thank you
guys bye
so i'm gonna finish uh the exam since
we have a structure now i'm going to
finish the
uh you know emax distro so i just need
to
go through all these files you know my
own init file and to
put them into cymax that's it okay so
but
before we go i want i'm gonna talk
non-stop
i wanna let me show you my javascript
completion okay
well actually yeah i i um yeah so
let's see okay okay so switch to
javascript mod so you can see
javascript right here so i want error
function so
af for error function there you have it
so
if i want to write a function
that add adds one to whatever number i
can just write it like that
for example let's see uh constant arrow
function should just
just three keys just three letters okay
press enter there you have it okay so
add one for example
so here x plus one okay
so we can test it so console.log cl
space console.log okay so add one
three okay now run it now this is
another
command in software key so i can run
this file
but first of all i need to save it it's
untitled so if i don't do anything
so let me show you okay so let's show
the pink window so you can see the
command icon so i've i run the file
he asked me to save the file first so xx
dot
js okay for temporary save it
okay so you can see the answer in the in
the buffer here it's
four you know because i'm learning deno
deno is
you know using this funky output color
uh
you know i don't like it but uh anyway
so that's how i do completion javascript
yeah but uh okay so but by the way you
do you don't have to just type
so you know i demonstrated the
abbreviation
but if you don't know the abbreviation
you can type the console
for example con and press tab
and you're just you know in a
traditional emacs
interface it will show you the
possible completions you you could have
with starting with col so let's say
console
co and s
o l okay so console.log
do it there you have it okay but this
way it's not so good anyway
bye
you