Everyone welcome to another episode of
talk show. Uh we are going to code of
advant of code. Can you see me? Yes.
This is my keyboard UHK80
ultimate hacking keyboard 80. I have a
video review on YouTube about a month or
two months ago. Check it out.
And uh let's do so we are going to do
advent of code
let's see can you see my screen so
advent of code 2025
day four take two so we began yesterday
but we didn't finish and we are using
wra language the most advanced
programming language so we are just
going to do exploration starting wra
language and if you don't
You can uh search for sali wam language
uh for programmers uh complete tutorial
from the ground up for programmers and
you can find the download link on
wufam.com/developer.
There you can download it for free. It's
about like 4 gigabytes or five. So it's
a huge programming language. It's the
most uh high level than by a magnitude
than all existing programming languages
such as Python, Haskell, Lisp,
uh Rust or F.
Okay, so code. So let's begin coding.
Okay, so start the wolf uh kernel. So
begin at three. Let's magnify.
Now if you are here, say hi. Love to see
your comments. Keep the comments coming.
Hello uh Doy Gap. If you are watching my
uh video offline, play at 1.5 speed
minimum or play at twice as fast. Okay.
So, we just going to explore. We're
going to go slowly and uh have fun.
uh as I go I'm going to teach you
something about wam language which is a
from computer science point of view it's
a programming language based on term
rewriting system it's a term rewriting
system what does that mean basically it
just means whatever you type the syntax
it's all symbolic string so it's like a
string then what the pro wam language do
is just keeps transforming in the string
the the the sequence of symbols until it
arrives at what you want. So it's bas in
other words you can think of it as a
syntax transformation
programming language that's how it does
computation. So in other words you can
think of as of it as a the programming
language is just whatever you type the
source code is just string. So you just
keep doing regular expression find and
replace. That's one way to think of it.
So you have a programming language. Your
source code is like a string. So what
the programming you so you just write
rules about how how to do find replace
on your source code. So the source code
change to another string change to
another string until it arrives. So
that's a term rewriting system. You can
look up Wikipedia. Okay. So hello dosi.
So yesterday we began
[clears throat]
excuse me or the end of code. Okay. So
the advent of code uh this this annoying
advent of code they have um
problems. So let's let's view let's turn
off the page style no style. So now it's
like simple and plain and you can
magnify it.
Okay. So that's advent of code 2025 day
four. Okay. So we uh we going to
continue from yesterday. So let's just
start coding. Okay. Uh all I'm using
Emacs of course and all my command
course and uh
function name are shown here. So let's
make this uh that. Okay. Just like a
side type. You can see uh
you know I moved the cursor so you can
see the ping window updates.
That's for you Emacs users show in
browser. Okay. So let's begin coding. So
let's go to yesterday. So we need to
[clears throat]
wait. So wait so yesterday episode 729.
So yesterday we wrote some function that
returns that given a matrix. You wrote a
function get neighbors. So get neighbors
of a matrix and you specify two index
that's a row number and the column
number. Then it returns all the
neighbors around that cell. Okay. Uh and
let's uh let's improve on that. Okay.
Get neighbors. Hello.
Uh
hi there. So, uh get N. So, okay. So,
let's see. So, there it is. So, here is
a matrix there. Can you see it? Okay.
Video check. Uh audio check. Okay. So,
let's start to improve it. So, first of
all, I'm using a block here. I don't
want to use block actually let's
evaluate this so you can see uh so you
so here is the matrix input
uh in fact let's delete that search for
xx okay so let's put the matrix here
so
you see so the matrix is there so that's
our argument then two
two okay So if we run this
it will return 22 is the number five in
the middle. So it will return 1 2 3 4 6
7 8 9. Run it
there. 1 2 3 4 6 7 8 9. Okay. Now uh now
you those are from the documentation
here. So you need to put a semicolon so
it doesn't show the output. Run it.
Okay. So you can see copy the whole
thing. Go to the Wrame notebook. Select
all paste.
Shift enter. You see that's a result.
Fantastic. Now let's improve the code.
Here we are using a block structure.
Block basically means local variables.
So instead of block, let's use con uh
constant. Okay. Actually let me think
about this. Um
[clears throat]
so block is for local uh variables
dynamic scope. So we defined we first of
all pad the matrix uh but we but instead
let's use width you don't need block
okay because we are not changing the the
variable x padded okay so let's rename
that
uh
padded matrix
okay so that makes easier to understand
Okay.
Uh returns all the neighbors of a given
cell of 2D mat matrix.
Um
yeah. So um
so let's we need to improve the
documentation here. So instead of saying
cell five, you should say 22 two.
Okay. Then
then cell six would be
uh two three.
Okay. So, let's improve the document.
Okay. Something like that. So, um
Okay. So, what else? So, let me So, what
else you want to do? Um
now, yesterday we have a bug somewhere.
So
in this example you also need to say
you see
when okay so let me show this example.
So copy that go here paste it. Now if
you say uh one one one
which is the first and the first on the
upper left. Shift enter. So you get
002045.
That's because
copy that
matrix form
at that shift enter. So that's a matrix.
So if you say one one one here. So the
neighbors are 245.
So it returns 245. That's correct.
Um, [clears throat]
so you need to say when the neighbor
when the cell is on the edge of the
matrix,
the
neighbor it
the neighbors uh
outside
of the matrix
is considered zero. Okay.
Uh is that a good result? That's
actually not so good, but it works in
our case. I mean, but it's not generally
a good thing because you might have a
matrix that's that's zero and
um so what do you do?
Uh you don't want to return zero
actually, but actually zero works in our
case.
Um
so you could add another parameter that
says what what entity you want to use to
represent
represent out out of the boundary
neighbors.
Let's see. Uh
How do you solve this problem? I don't
know.
Well, I know. But
okay. What how do you want to do this?
So, you pad it. It's zero horizontally.
So you can pad it with a uh
you want to pad it with some kind of
special
value
then in a return result you want to
remove those value. Okay. So you could
so you want to pad it with a special
value.
Um you could use almost anything. You
could use a string but however you want
to avoid whatever you use you must
assume that does not exist in the
matrix. So the matrix can be a medium by
a median. You don't know what's in
there. So whatever value like a
temporary value you use to pad the
matrix to uh
uh uh pad the matrix. So for example we
we did this here.
So you can see
So matrix form
a matrix form
paste that
you see it adds zero around it.
Okay zero it adds zero by default but
can you change the padding value? I'm
pretty sure you can use a specified
padding. Yeah. So if you pad it by so
for example let's say something x string
then you got x okay so if you want to
write this function in general
whatever temporary values you use you
must assume it does not occur in in the
matrix.
So how do you solve that problem? Well,
you can solve that by
um
by calling this function unique. Okay,
you that will return
okay that will return a unique symbol
always. So you can let's read the
documentation. You see unique generates
a new symbol. Let's magnify. So
150 125 generates a new symbol whose
name is of the form dollar sign a
number. Okay, that always generates a
unique number. So So you can
so you can say this example. So you can
say copy
paste.
So over here instead of X you can say
unique. Okay then you get that then you
then you need to save the value of
unique. So you so later on when you use
when we defined our neighbor it returns
0000 for the neighbor. You can then
remove them.
Okay. So there's uh more work to do.
As far as advent of code, you know, we
can just use zero. It doesn't matter.
But uh let's let's do it properly. Okay.
Since we are just going to explore the
wolf language.
Uh
okay. So check video check audio check.
Yeah. Am I good? Yes. Okay. So unique
uh returns a unique symbol in terms uh
in the form of dollar sign something.
Let's see what we want to do here.
Right? You don't want it to, you see it
returns the neighbor, but you don't want
it to return 0 0
like for example here, you know.
So let's do it properly. Okay. So let's
do one thing at a time. Fix it one thing
at a time. So, so here
uh then uh width and unique.
So you need unique. So you need uh x
unique equals to that it generates a
unique value constant. Okay. Then
then you then when you pad oh you okay
so actually you can do this uh you see
you need a you need array pad you need
to put a unique value here so uh but you
can't do it here because when you use
width that's for constants it gen you
know these are constants
so you have you know these two are
constants uh and they cannot be chained.
So for example this
you can do you know this is what you
want right you unique is a unique symbol
then here you call unique but that
doesn't work because
because width cannot be chained so in
order to do that you need to nest width
yeah annoying u it can be chained but
only on the latest version of wolf from
language like uh released just about
three months ago not in my version my my
version is like two years old I need to
update but I haven't yet so
so anyway so let's just do it the you
know the [clears throat] more um way so
so that is a
local constant unique then let's do
another width okay then here.
Yeah. Then here you can uh do this.
Okay. So delete that, paste that, delete
that there. Okay. Then whatever
expression. So now we just
put the expression there. Okay. So do
you guys see what I'm saying? Uh do you
guys see what I'm doing?
Okay.
So here so there with that's one local
constant then we use that local constant
here they are unique
uh okay then
okay then we can combine like this or
this okay okay that's one step done
so we generate a unique number now once
you generate unique you you need to
remove it Okay. So let's remove it. So
D. So after the whole result
let's see you see Wam language is full
of these nestings.
Okay. So after this result
you you want to delete those unique.
Okay. Then you can say
delete
Delete
cases
something. And what you want to delete?
You want to delete the unique
constant. Okay. And the same thing is
that. Okay. So, do you guys see what I'm
doing?
Okay.
That should work. Should.
Okay. So if we run this code now we
don't need this uh if we run this code
it will not contain the 0000 0. Okay. So
in this case it's 1 2 3 4 6 7 8 9. Okay.
Run it. Let's see.
1 2 3 4 6 7 8 9. Right. So, but if we
copy it, let's say one one
okay so one one is that value so the
neighbors are 245 so it'll just return
245 not 00 something two zero you know
so let's run it run it
fantastic thick and beautiful.
Okay, so that's the example output.
Let's copy it. Let's paste the sample
output here. So you can see we improve
the code by quite a lot. Okay, we use
the width which is creating local
constants instead of uh creating uh
instead of using block which is creating
um local dynamic variables variables of
dynamic scope. That's what block is. So
we used local constant and and we create
a uh intermittent unique value then we
remove them. So now this code seems to
work well right
um
right we we use the unique okay so now
you know we can further improve it
because unique is very um
it's kind of slow because unique it
because it generates a new symbol unique
symbol in a current session
and it tends to increase um memory usage
you know over long term anyway let's
leave it so this now so so so now the
documentation we can say when the cell
is on the edge of the matrix the
neighbors outside of the matrix is
considered zero now we can remove that
because we don't we don't have that
problem anymore okay so this is Good.
Um,
so let's say let's
uh what the what
we want to
change that to one.
The result is 245. 245.
Okay, that's like better example.
Okay,
so this function get neighbors.
Is that right? Yeah. Now each time this
functions is called it actually uh call
array pad.
So
it is not the most efficient but because
every time it's called on a particular
cell it creates a entire array array
pad. So if if the given array is let's
say 1,00 by 1,000
then you want to find the neighbor of
one single cell then it's going to
like generate the whole 1,00 by 1,00
array. In fact, 10,002
by 102 array huge,
right? So, it's it's not very efficient.
Yeah. But but that's a beauty of this
because this avoid you having to
manually check the boundary. Like
whenever you have a row and column if
they if they are on the edge you need to
you know you you need to make sure that
they don't they don't they you don't get
a you don't you you don't try to get an
element beyond the boundary. So this is
array padding very convenient. That's a
that's a beauty of a wam language. And
here we use turppos to generate all
possible neighbor neighbor indexes.
That's another very powerful um feature
you see.
So as far as advancable code goes, this
code is just fine. But you don't you
don't want to use this in real life one
one,000 by 10,000 arrays especially when
you need to call get neighbors multiple
times in a loop because you need to know
you know you need to check every cell.
So let me think let's think of uh again
okay
so this function gets the neighbors are
are there more efficient way of course
one way is just manually make sure the
index doesn't go out of bound but is
there other like more automatic way like
this but but more efficient
uh so that's So you know so we are just
um exploring okay this is going to slow
down
like almost we are doing nothing but
let's do this exploration because um
because that's a very good way to learn
about things about wraim language.
So you can so so so what so you want to
get the neighbors. Okay. Our code works
but uh not that one but this one. Our
code works but
but is there even better way? That's the
question. Um
is there even a better way to
to get
neighbor? The other thing worth
mentioning is that our function can work
on arbitrary arbitrary dimensional
matrix. Uh what you need to do actually
you need to amend it a little bit. You
need to do here is row column. You see
this row column row and column
right now this function only works on
two-dimensional matrix. You need two
indexes to specify any given position in
a matrix. Now what if you have
three-dimensional matrix
you also the neighbor concept also works
in any dimensional matrix can be
fourdimensional, five or 1,00 dimension.
Okay, they always the neighbor concept
of a cell always works. So,
so you want to you know you may want to
make your function works for any
arbitrary dimensional matrix 3D matrix.
So you need to so in in in the case of
3D mat matrix you have row column and
another index. Okay. So when the matrix
is dimensional three or higher you don't
say row and column anymore. you you say
like
I one index one index two index three
index four so you you need n indexes for
n dimensional matrix okay so if you
actually write a function
uh for example let's let's just for
example um matrix uh and uh
i j k
I J K. So for three-dimensional
uh matrix you would have a whole syntax
something like that. Okay. And for
fourdimensional matrix uh I J K L you
have four indexes. So in general
if your matrix uh N
B okay let's say matrix
3D wait
3D okay so
4 D right so ND then you're going to
just have a list of
indexes you see you guys see what I'm
doing. So in our case it's if it's 2D
in our case uh wait
right now our code is doing this okay
that's what our code is doing
and when it comes to 3D you want that
for so it's it's better to have a list
to so this is like one unit because
that's a list of indexes
this is one unit. So in general you
should
make the syntax to be like that. Okay.
So so that works for any matrix of any
dimension. Okay.
But right now we are hard coding it for
two dimensional. So but once you have
three-dimensional or fourdimensional or
n dimensional matrices then you see this
row column doesn't work anymore. you. So
you have the generalized the first item
in a list of the list of indexes, the
first item, the second item, the third
item.
So then you can over here instead of row
column you use um like a range to
systematically generate all the possible
indexes plus one or minus one. So they
they will form all possible um
indexes around that neighbor. Okay,
that's that's what I'm saying.
Okay. So but should we um actually write
such a matrix?
Well, we can. It's not too difficult.
But then we are getting away from
solving the advent of code. So
So let's not do that. So let let let us
right now just put some comment.
We
can make our
get neighbor function more general. So
it works on matrix of any dimension.
Okay,
what you need to do is of the following
form. Okay, so that's uh some kind of
just comment.
Okay. So, let's uh
cut.
This is our current
form.
Better form would be that.
So, it can be generalized
because the second
parameter is a list of indexes.
Okay, so that does that make sense? This
comment. Okay, let's cut that comment.
Put it back.
And uh we can make a comment here. Wam
language. Paste that. Okay. Now, this is
this is actually from yesterday. So uh
if you know what I'm talking about this
is yesterday's event of code but we are
doing
you know this is yesterday so we need to
um
put that.
So yesterday is episode 729. Today is
epo episode 730. So let's put
uh today's here
show in browser.
Yeah, we are talking about generalizing
this to this function for any
dimensional matrix.
Okay, so that's one idea. But let's go
back here. So yesterday's talk show we
were also we also fixed our code
so that we actually improved our code.
Yeah, we improved our code here.
So that should be moved to today. So why
don't we
let's see.
Yeah. Why don't Why don't we move this
to today's
Wait, you sure is this part? No, that's
not that part.
Yeah.
Mhm. Let's run it. Just to make sure
this is working
correct. Okay. Now
put it back.
Now cut out that entire
block
syntax. Cut out the whole page.
Go back to today's talk show.
Open it. Then paste the new code here.
Now syntax color the whole page show in
browser. So today's talk show we talked
about generalizing this function get
neighbors for arbitrary dimensional
matrix. Okay. And here is our improved
code. Okay. Now next
let's move on to the next problems. I
mean the next um whatever we have to do.
So now we make now let's we want to make
sure this this actually correct. Okay,
seems correct. I I cannot pos I I don't
see anything. It might be wrong. So,
let's try to solve it. So, yesterday
we try to solve it and we run into a
problem. So, let's see. Copy the code.
Uh what what we doing? Yeah, we try to
solve it, but our answer is incorrect.
Okay. So we copy the code. Close.
Close. Close. What is this? To do two
two uh 70
9.
This episode 2729.
Now go to today. Let's try to solve the
problem.
Start a wound code. copy it out and
paste. Okay, that's the code from
yesterday.
And we need to we have a new version of
this uh get neighbors. So, let's clear
it.
Let's clear it.
Okay, we got a new version.
So, this is what 729.
So go to talk show.
This is today. So we got our new version
uh get neighbors. Okay.
So let's paste it there. And we don't
need the examples.
Okay.
Okay. We got the code. So in the
beginning we got this text
and that
this will turn this text into a matrix
of zero and one. Let's run it.
You see it uh returns so let's see
it returns you know a matrix of zero and
one okay that represent this okay
uh
okay so far so good yeah
let's put a comment so people can
understand okay then so this new we
named it matrix.
Okay. So we uh we turned it into a
matrix, right?
And now
now we define our function here. Okay,
that's already tested. And next we what
we want to do next? We
uh
we want to apply the function to all
possible indexes. So
yeah.
Okay. So
okay let let's define it here. Okay. So
let's go to language not notebook
um
okay let's make a copy of that
so people can D.
Okay. So now select all paste.
Oh, not not that it it made a copy. It
pasted pasted the image. Okay. So, but
we want uh we want this code.
Copy.
Paste. Okay. Shift enter. There is a
result. Fantastic.
Now next we define our neighbors
function.
Copy
paste. Shift enter. Okay. We define get
neighbors function.
And
now
dimensions matrix. Dimensions matrix
returns the um paste return. [snorts] It
should return 10 by 10 because there's
uh the this input is 10 by 10. Shift
enter 10 by 10. Okay.
Copy. Copy back here. So dimension
matrix is 10 by 10.
Dimension of the matrix. Now
now you just uh you want to generate all
the indexes of the matrix for every
cell. Okay, that's what you do. this.
Okay. So here we hardcoded the 10 but we
can make it um not hardcoded. So what
you do is you
so what you do is for example let let me
show you this. Okay. So you can paste
now range at 10 just returns a list of 1
2 3 4 5 up to 10. So, so you got 1210
and 1210 and that just return all the
cartesian
combinations
cartesian product 1 one 2 1 3 and so on
and 212 3 2 uh 2 4 and so on. See? So,
but this is this 10 is hardcoded. So
instead you can you you should just say
turbo turbos add
uh turbos at the dimension 1010. Okay,
that will give you exactly the same
result. So let's go back here.
Back here,
paste it. Shift enter.
Oh, [laughter]
uh no atomic expression expected. So
which one goes first? Wait. So
why is it Oh, you need Okay. So you need
Okay. So you can What you need is you
need to um
you need to apply range
range
map.
Okay. The matrix. Okay. Then
parenthesis.
Wait. So dimensions. Okay. So here is
what you need to do. Okay. So basically
like that
paste. So let me double check on the
operator precedence.
Okay. So this part okay dimension and
matrix that get computed first then
then range map to that. So you get 1 to
10 and 1 to 10 uh
a nested list. Then you need to add add.
Okay. Uh add add means replace the head.
Okay. You guys probably don't know what
I'm saying.
So
not add that, just add. Okay.
So delete that.
There it is. Okay. So in so basically
just that. Okay. Let's do it again.
Select all. Paste it. Shift enter. So
this way we don't have hardcoded numbers
like the magic number 10.
Okay. So that's what that is. So delete
that. Uh if you are wondering what is
that slash at that just means let me
show you. Okay. So if you have any
function f slash at bvbb. Okay. So if if
you have any syntax aa slash at bbb that
is a syntactical shortcut for
for that for map a bvbv. Okay. So these
two are
equivalent because whenever wam language
sees that it automatically transform it
to this map something. So this is uh
just the syntactical shortcut and we are
using it here
and and this add. So [snorts] let me
introduce you guys the syntactical
shortcut. So you see that add. So
whenever you have
something add something that just means
a square bracket bpb okay actually we
can run it
you see it returns that and this you can
also run it.
Oh, wait. Well,
well, yeah, it returns BBB because uh
because that's what this return because
B needs to be a list. Okay, so but
yeah, so B, you know, the BBB part needs
to be a list. But anyway, these two are
equivalent. Okay.
Uh
shortcut syntax.
Okay. So
is same as uh set. Okay. And that is
same as that. Okay. So let me just put
that out so that people know.
Put it back. So create a new one from
language paste it there. Okay. Syntax
color the whole thing show in browser.
So we covered so so we covered shortcut
syntax. Now on this shortcut syntax
let me show you the my tutorial that
explains the whole thing about a wam
language for programmers. Search for it.
You will find it. Then you go down. So
uh you'll learn that.
So data structure advanced symbol
principles full form. Okay. So there
uh so this part is
kind of advanced explains
how the whole wam language
syntax works. Okay.
Uh in fact the entire fu of wuam
language is of this form nested form a
symbol square bracket then inside it
symbol comma and they can be nested in
any way any symbol can be any one of
these form so that's the entire wam
language syntax but then you got
shortcuts so because it's very uh
inconvenient whenever you say 3 + 4 you
have to say plus bracket 3 comma 4. So
but you can just write 3 + 4. So how
does that work? That works because of
the syntactical shortcuts.
So to understand that you can you can to
get the entire list of such syntactical
shortcut you can check out this page wra
syntax shortcuts and operators. Okay. So
3 + 4 is a short syntax for plus square
bracket 3 comma 4. Okay. Similarly for
uh for um for all these equality or
greater than you know. So on the left
hand side is the full form syntax.
Okay. So what about the things I I was
just talking about the add sign for
example. Uh so for example when
we were talking about
this you know top of right so we were
talking about tupo at and this slash at
those are also shown here. So you can
see if you scroll down
uh expression separator in interactive
session pure function uh you can so you
see f at x is the shortcut for f square
bracket x okay and f slash at x is a
shortcut syntax for map fx
so so you see that so you got or many
other syntactical shortcuts. They are uh
cryptic of course when you but so when
you became familiar with warm language
you often use them but I avoid using
them uh because they are cryptic you
know otherwise mo most people wouldn't
know because they are not
wam language is not based on C syntax
which is used in C++ Java Rust
JavaScript Python you know everything
So, so usually I avoid this but except
kind of the the you know the add sign
and slash add is one of the most
commonly used. Okay. So anyway that's
that's about the syntactical shortcuts.
Now let's get back to our um to solve
this problem. So okay so syntactical
shortcuts. Yeah copy that. Let me paste
the link here so I can so there is some
example.
Okay, language
syntax shortcuts.
So now
so where are we? So so now we are we
define the function. Yeah, now let's
continue to work on the advant of code.
We turn that into a matrix of ones and
zeros. and we define the get neighbors
uh function should be very good. Okay.
Then we get the matrix the input
dimension of the matrix. Then we created
uh this should be called uh all
possible indexes.
Okay. So that's that's uh equals to
that. Okay. And effectively this is what
it returns or possible indexes. Okay.
Then um
then you see um so if you copy that
so basically that but uh
so let's see how well
paste it. Um okay anyway
so that's all possible indexes then
basically you want to apply get
neighbors to to all of them. So what you
can do is you simply map actually we are
doing that here. So
so you see we took so we uh okay so how
do I explain this? So
you see the all possible indexes is is
here. So we don't need this tuple
anymore. We just say all possible
indexes. So we are mapping a function.
So ignore the first line first. Okay,
ignore that line. We are mapping this
function to these all possible indexes
and this function get neighbors. So we
get neighbors of our matrix. Then we you
know this function x is the parameter.
So then you take the first part of x
which is the first index then last part
of the index with which is the last
index. For example we can try it.
So for example let's say um well
actually there's an example there. So
copy that 99. Okay. So let's see. Paste
it. 99. Shift enter. So one one one one.
So that's matrix. That's nine. So where
is 99 n? Let's go up.
1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9. So nine is here. So
99 is this one. So you should have one
one one one
51.
So is that right? One one one. That's
correct.
Okay.
Uh but I want to make a modification.
Now remember we talked about before
where
if you want to make this get neighbors
function to be more general so that it
works on any um dimensional matrix.
The better
form is to have the second the indexes
parameter as one single thing as a list.
You see we explain here and now in fact
we run into that problem because here we
write a function x. We want to apply
this function to all possible indexes.
You know any one of these 72 73 74
right? So the function takes you know
the function gets the argument x. Then
here you need to separate because the
the get n neighbors takes like you know
takes them as two separate arguments. So
that is no good. This is not the right
style in wam language
or in all the languages like Python even
list uh C, C++, Java, you tend to you
don't you don't make these kind of
unit you know you you like whenever you
write a function it's just separate um
arguments
even though you see even though for this
function let
explain this. Okay. So for this function
get neighbors
you have parameters right. The first
thing is the matrix the input matrix.
The second thing you want is the indexes
of the indexes for a particular position
of the matrix. Now if you think about it
the indexes should be one unit
right? You know it doesn't make sense if
if you just have one of them you know
row or just column they they they are
like from a logical mathematical point
of view they are one unit.
So why don't you so so so
as far as code
um clarity goes these two should be like
a list of things not just separate
argument they should be one argument
because they always come together
especially if your matrix is
three-dimensional then then the index is
three items right they they are indexes
they they cannot do without each other
they must be should be one unit.
But in all other languages, in lisp, in
JavaScript, in Java, in C, in Python, in
whatever, Ruby, Pearl,
you almost never do that. You don't you
don't do it just for the sake of
clarity. You know, you change the
function parameters so that they create
they become a list. Then you fe you
know, you never do that. But that's but
you should um typically in wam language.
So so that is why now I'm going to make
a modification of our get neighbors. So
it so it has improved form. Okay. Did I
miss a lot comments? Okay. So um
yeah. So let me answer it in a minute.
Okay. Awesome keyboard. That's This is
Ultimate Hacking Keyboard 80, UHK80.
I have a video review about last month.
Check it out.
Uh, I probably answered your question 20
minutes late.
So, coffee says, Coffee House says,
"Yes, I'm setting up it up on my PC
again."
Another alternative to Wuam is GU
octave. No, not really.
Let me explain that one. Gunu octave is
a um is a clone of mat lab basically.
Am I correct? Yeah,
something like that. I'm I'm pretty sure
it's a it's it's like the open-source
because MATLAB MATLAB is a numerical
computing um software designed focused
with linear algebra applications. So if
you have to do a lot linear algebra
matrices,
MATLAB is a commercial product.
Then about 15 years ago or 20 years ago
the open source people the GNU they
created GNU octave they basically copy
basically clone of MATLAB they write it
from scratch but essentially the
semantics the syntax is like a copy of
MATLAB. Okay. So they so they um
okay we can look up this Wikipedia.
Okay, GNU octave. Um,
so let's go Wikipedia.
You see mat lab. Okay, compatible with
mat lab basically a clone or in other
words
in un in a unpleasant but more direct
way to say it. It just it's store. Okay,
it's store from mat lab. Matlab is
proprietary.
these GNU people free software
foundation or open source they don't
like it they don't want to pay so they
copy they steal you know they just copy
it without copying the code you know
they can code it but basically they copy
the whole design is actually the most uh
takes the most effort to come up with a
system but they just they stole it okay
in other words okay so that's a
background that's a g octave so when Did
it begin? 1993. Oh, wow. Okay. So much
earlier then.
Much earlier.
Uh I didn't realize it's that it's that
early. Okay. So, you know, anyway, it's
like a clone of MATLAB. Okay. So, syntax
and everything is similar and it says,
you know, mostly compatible, right? So,
but how so how is MATLAB? Matlab
back in you know even today there's no
comparison to wam language okay mat lab
is focused on numerical computation okay
let me explain this so you open mat lab
mat lab that's their logo very well
known um so is a proprietary
multiparadin programming language and
numerical computing environment okay
[snorts] developed by math works which
origin originally they are from uh
Canada. Okay. Anyway, I have long
experience with these programs back in '
90s
and and you know so anyway my point is
Mat Lab is mostly a numerical computing
software focusing mostly numerical and
linear algebra. Okay,
that's the
the focus. So it doesn't do symbolic
computation. It doesn't do symbolic
integrals. It you know today it might do
some but it's not its focus. It doesn't
do uh neuronet networks, artificial
intelligence and you know because over
30 years there's so so many other things
going on.
So even back back 30 years ago
when you compare mat lab to uam language
there's no comparison. Okay they are in
different category. Mat lab is mostly
numerical. Wuang language is symbolic.
You can do symbolic solve equations or
matrices in symbolically and it also can
do numerically. Okay.
So they are kind of in different uh
category and if you must say which one
is better ma mathematica wen language is
uh like far more general. Okay. So
that's so that's you know that's a
situation. So when you say alternative
to wam is good octave. No that's like a
joke. Okay. So you guys don't know. So
I'm telling you guys. Oh never mind.
Wait. So what are you guys awesome
keyboard saw your review. That's great.
So perhaps not as popular due to not
having as much reach but it's a great
alternative for for hobbies. Yeah that
you know that's not bad. Especially
uh GNU you know this open source it's
open source so it's free that's the most
important that's the most practical
reason you know you can just download it
and try play with it right
so yeah but I don't you know you get
what you want you get what you pay for
just like Linux Linux is also free but
then you have to spend you have to be
know how to to do a lot of things like
format your drive. You have to reformat
your drive to EX4, whatever. You know,
most people don't know what that that
is. Then then you have to Oh, what dro
are you using? Oh. Oh, what? You must
switch to Wayland. Oh, but there's a bug
in Wayland or something something. You
uh you can make an octave notebook using
Anacondra. Okay. Yeah, it's too complex.
Anacondra is Anacondontra is this Python
thing you know Python huge library is
like 4 gigabytes that combines all
Pythons's
libraries for scientific comput
computation for linear algebra for
numerical computation it tries to do
everything
on a contra okay but again there's no
comparison if you want a coherent the
most powerful
uh
programming language or app you know a
system for for anything possible in
computation.
Okay, there's nothing compared to FM
language. Okay. Okay, that's kind of
digression. So let's get back to this.
Okay, let let me quickly
Oh god, I digress so much. We haven't
been doing the event code. Let's let me
quickly uh now get back to this. And we
want to modify this function get
neighbors. So that so that instead of
taking
um separate argument it's just one unit
of indexes for the matrix. Okay. So
let's do that.
So row column. So that's a
documentation. Let's change that. And
also let's change that here. So make a
list. So this is symbolic. Um this is a
pattern actually. So that's what we do.
just you know just just um make it at
least here and and in fact that's all
that's all we need to change. Yeah
that's all we need to change and uh are
you sure? Yes. Yes.
Then later on if you want to make this
work for three-dimensional then you
instead instead of that you you just say
you just say a list. Okay. Then you also
have to change this part because you
know anyway so we change that and here
then we make also change here. So you
don't you no longer have to say first X
last X because this X is the input. Now
you just say X. Okay. So uh you know
just X.
It's a list of two items. The index is
column and row and column. Okay. So,
so we got so we got dimensions, we got
all possible indexes. Then, uh we have
that set. Let's uh let's write it. Let's
define it. Uh we didn't define our
function. Okay. So, I mean we didn't
define our new modification. So, let's
do that. Hold on a second.
So remove that and
remove that and comment that out. Wait.
Okay. Comment that out. Yeah.
Uh what shift?
Okay. So that's our whole program. So we
can run the whole thing. Let's see.
Starting from the above. So
copy it. Go back to language. Now,
select all
paste to override and shift enter.
Fantastic. So that's our matrix mat
matrix uh matrix. This is the dimension
10x 10. And here is all possible indexes
of this matrix. And here is all the um
neighbors of the each cell. Okay,
fantastic and beautiful. All the
neighbors of each cell. So there are 100
of them because 10 by 10, right? And
then you just sum it sum it up. So you
all you have to do so let me try it
again. Okay, wait. So you just all you
have to do is you
map this function. So map x if total x
is less than four
then you say it's one otherwise
zero. So so now this is a function. Okay
you slash add map that function to this
output which is the neighbors list.
Okay. So what do you get? So let's try
it. Copy it back to Wuam notebook. Go
here. Paste it.
Please make it work. Fantastic.
So each cell becomes a number because if
total neighbor is less than four then
it's one special meaning that that cell
does um is accessible according to the
uh
to the advant of code L story. So if
it's not less than four is zero. So you
got you know this special. So what is
the total?
Total
at percent sign means the last output
means this. Okay. So shift enter 19
which is incorrect
because yesterday we saw
um you know we saw that should be 13. So
we need to figure out so we run into
this bug just like yesterday.
Very annoying. This is kind of
annoying to debug. Can you guys see it?
Like here, right? Yeah. Now you can see
it. Um,
so according to the advent of code, the
proper solution, the correct solution is
13.
13, not
19.
How did I get 19?
So,
so what you can do is you want to format
this into um let me show you partition.
You want to format this output in groups
of 10 so that you can kind of see this
is a result
one zero one one one.
So according to the result that is not
um
not right. So you want this axis axis.
Wait did did I get it reversed or what?
less than four.
Uh so what is this? So,
the forklift can only access a row of
paper if there are fewer than four rows
of paper
on the eight adjacent positions. Right?
So, these neighbors most of them has
eight entries. One, two, three, four,
five, six, seven, eight. All right. And
some of them has five entries. That's
because
that's because let's see.
One, two, three, four, five. When they
are on the edge. One, two, three, four,
five. Right. And then some of them has
three neighbors when when they are in a
corner.
So
So three is in a corner. 1 2 3 4 5
That's on the edge. That's on the edge.
That's the top. That this is this part
is the first uh kind of the first
row. Then you got five.
One, two, three, four, five on the edge,
you know, top. Then you got three.
That's the top right corner.
Top right corner. So, which is this is
incorrect. Top right corner.
How many neighbors? It should be two. So
you got 111. This is incorrect. So let's
we need to dive into details. So do you
guys see what I'm saying? Do you guys
understand?
So let's let's work on the neighbors.
Let's debug our code. So with this get
neighbors,
actually we got a bug.
So when you say get neighbors, let's say
one one.
Okay. So
what do you get? One. One. The first
entry.
Paste. Shift. Enter.
Uh
what?
Oh, not X. You got extra X.
paste shift enter
011.
So, so the first
part 011 that's correct. You see the
leftmost
uh this code. So,
can you guys do you guys see what I'm
saying is saying? So
the
top left that corner it has 011
neighbor that is correct.
Now if let's if you go second
011 one one. So so the second is zero on
the left then one one one. That's
correct.
Uh what about the last part? The first
one and the 10th
column. The first row and the 10th
column. That's on the upper right
corner. 111.
That seems correct.
Okay.
So, so what is the criteria? I must got
the criteria wrong. So
the forklifts can only access a row of
paper
if there are fewer than four rows of
paper in the eight adjacent positions.
Fewer than four
That means [clears throat] less than
four, right?
In eight adjacent positions. Okay, if
you can figure out which rows of paper
the fog can access. What what if there
are zero rows of adjacent uh neighbor?
there's no such occurrence
because if there is then you got you
need a box of dots.
So I don't I don't get it. Why why is
our uh code incorrect? So what if they
Oh, okay. Actually, you don't need
you don't need to compute all the
indexes. All you need to is to compute
the
cell locations. That's that's a dot. So
all you need to is to
um That's right. That's right.
Oh, that makes sense. So for example,
this this position let's see let's say
can you guys see? So this is 10th row
ninth column 10 9. Okay, it has two
neighbors right above.
However, does that count?
You know, according to me, it would. But
but according to this spec, which is
kind of lousy, you know, the cell that
already is a row of paper does not
count. Okay. So simple.
So you don't want all possible indexes.
You just want the ones that are already
zero.
Is that right? Yes. Okay. So, let's fix
that. So, how do you uh do that? You you
can do that by
cases. Okay. Syntax confusion. Okay.
Cases. Uh then you say
X matrix. Okay. X matrix. That's my uh
matrix. You want the cases of zero.
Okay. Now let's look up the
documentation
not matrix okay the cases look up the
pattern gives a list of case you know
elements that match this uh level spec
so what by default level spec is one I
think now if you don't know what I'm
saying don't worry about it okay
uh cases use standard level so the
default That value for level spec is
one. Yeah, just level one. So you don't
have to worry. So so this will return
all possible positions their indexes
where
zero occur. So what?
Oh. Oh, right. You then you Okay. So you
need um right so you you don't want to
use cases you want to use position okay
so let me let me show you
position will return all positions okay
of of of a nested list
where it matches zero and you want it to
apply a level two only. Okay. So let me
show you that that will work.
Okay. So if you do that that's the
result. Okay. So you want to say
so not cases. So you want to say so this
is um
all
uh
so this is all indexes.
uh or indexes where the cell is empty.
Okay. But what is the word a vend of
code uses to describe
like empty
you know
they didn't say so so either it's
occupied by row of paper or it's not so
it's empty. Let's just say empty. Um
so index of m
uh something like empty cells okay let's
just do that index of empty cells okay
equals to
that
okay so we can manage
fantastic
now we can refer to that index of sales.
Um, we don't need that. Yeah, we don't
need that. Index of sales
here. Okay,
copy.
I'm pretty sure
it'll give us 13. Shift enter.
Oh, then you need to total. Okay. Total
at uh at percent sign means the last
output. Shift enter.
Six. God. Jesus. We got up.
Oh, why is that?
Why is that?
Now it's six but the solution should be
13. Now is there anyone watching?
Nobody. Okay. You guys need to help me.
Okay.
But unfortunately nobody is here. I
don't think so. Few people.
In this example, there are 13 rows of
paper that can be accessed by a
forklift.
Now, is there something I didn't
understand?
So, is it true only?
Wait, wait, wait. Look at this one.
Okay, look at this example on the upper
right corner.
So, it's got three
neighbors that's
that has row paper.
Oh, so now does it mean so you see on
the upper right corner
that cell got three rows of paper. So
technically it qualify because
because you know stupid available code
they format
you know so because they
where does it say less than
fewer than four rows of paper, right? So
on the upper right corner, you got that
cell got three
rows of paper.
So that should count. But however, if
you look at the diagram, it shows
the solution. You know that upper right
corner is not one of it.
So what does this mean? So
we didn't understand the problem
correctly.
The forklifts can only access a row of
paper if there are fewer than four rows
of paper. Fewer than four. Okay. The
upper right it has three. Is that fewer
than four? Yes.
Okay. If you can figure out which rows
of paper
Oh, what?
Oh, it you should deal with the cases
where there's a row of paper, not the
empty slot. idiotic. Okay. So,
not empty cells. Not index of empty
cells. You want to work on the index of
non-MPT cells.
But stupid. So, let's just
uh
Okay, let's let's just try that. So,
instead So, instead of um so this is
easy. So, in so instead so it just you
can just say one. Okay.
Okay, copy that and just replace that.
Okay, that should return the answer.
Okay, copy. Let's try it.
Paste. Shift enter.
Okay. Blah blah blah. And then total
at percent sign
13. stupid problem. Okay,
basically we solved the problem. Now we
need to use our personal input. So
three more minutes, we'll solve it.
Okay, now clean up a little bit. So all
possible indexes, that's not what you
want.
Indexes where empty cell is empty,
that's not what you want.
Indexes of non-MP cell, that's what you
want. So in terms of the advant of code
jargon, you say this is all indexes
where the cell is a paper row. Okay,
that's what you want.
Then you just map apply and then you
just say total
at that's your result. Okay. So now we
can actually copy the all copy all.
Let's uh not output that. Okay. So let's
yeah so let's copy all
fantastic and beautiful select or paste
shift enter
uh wait okay wait you got the wrong
answer at the end because of the
operation precedence you need to
uh make this like that okay select
Select or select all paste. Shift enter
then 13. Perfect.
Okay. Now back up. Now you need to get
your own um personal input. Okay. So
where is our personal input? Search for
text
band of code 2025 day for personal
input. Okay. This giant Copy it.
Close. Close. Wait, don't close. Uh, but
also okay, move here. Then this is a
list. Huge list. Okay. And let's just
say input equals to this. This this this
this.
Did we hardcode anything? No. But it
should work. Yes. Copy all. Go back
here. Select all. Paste.
Shift. Enter.
Oh, it's taking a while. Impossible.
It's done.
So, this giant input go down, go down,
go down, go down, go down. Giant input.
We forgot to uh put a semicolon
to suppress the output. So, anyway, the
result is 1527. Copy that.
Back to advent of code. So,
paste 1527.
Enter. Submit. That's the right answer.
You are one gold star closer.
Thank you very much. We solve it. We
solved it.
So,
anyone watching, congratulate me. Okay.
Seven concurrent viewers. So, thank you
guys for watching.
We had fun. So, let's clean up. We shut
down in about three minutes. Let's just
clean up. So there is a solution 1527.
That's correct. Um
so put it back syntax color the whole
HTML page show in browser.
So we did
we um we modified our get neighbors code
so that it it has the form where the
second argument which is a list of
indexes is more consistent comes in one
unit for arbitrary dimensional matrix.
We explain that part where you know and
then we also modified our get neighbors
code so that so that it's a bit more
efficient but still it's using array pad
so every time you call this function it
creates the whole array padded array so
that's not efficient okay so if this is
a real life problem you don't want you
don't want to do this because you are
going to call get neighbors like
hundreds of times or even millions of
times each time it it's called it
creates a whole array padded array. So
you don't want that
but you see but that's a trade-off you
know if you want convenience you if you
want elegant code this array pad is
fantastic so so you don't have to like
check if the current index is out of
bound it doesn't have the next neighbor
you know things like that
then we talked about the shortcut syntax
of the wuam symbolic
language also
known as formal language in computer
science where the source code is
actually everything is just symbol so
you kind of treat it like a string all
you do is string manipulation or find
and replace that's how it computes okay
syntax shortcuts
by the way for lisp fans this is called
meta expression as opposed to
uh symbolic expression Anyway, that's
list history. Okay, so
syntax shortcuts then we talked then
then we finally solved the problem.
Okay, so huge input. Okay, finally solve
problem. We we were wrong before because
we are working on the wrong cells.
You need to focus on the cells that's
that's already occupied like one. Okay,
bye guys. Thank you guys for watching.
If you like my stuff, donate, okay? Go
to kasad.info
homepage here. Kasar code kasadi.info.
Uh go all the way down and you can
patreon me. Okay. Do Patreon me and
Amazon gift card me or PayPal me.
Bye guys. Congrat congratulation GCS and
noob.
Bye guys.
Tomorrow we're going to do part two.
I'm going to don't know how many
millions of hours we're going