on recording yeah I'm alive we could
okay today I'm going to show you what am
I going to show you I'm going to show
you the wonderful word YouTube what a
banda it is but a banda how star wars
was saved in the edit whoo it's trash
[ __ ] trash video now this one is good
this guy this guy is an expert on swords
you know the being observing technology
and over the past 20 years especially
the past 10 years this incredible amount
of stuff you know like they say you know
like technology and sciences they are
growing exponentially you know have you
ever studied what exponential function
means that means they increase like
quickly beyond you expect expectation
like beyond you can possibly imagine
like quickly they they can beyond human
comprehension
that's what exponential growth means now
exponential growth is a classification
of a function basically you have
polynomials like powers x squared X
third power X hundredth power first of
all you have linear linear is just you
know grows linearly like a line like you
know you you may grow this fast or this
fast or this fast that's linear function
then you have power function which is x
squared or X to the nth power like that
then you have exponential now
exponential is basically like that they
they grow they become a vertical line
very very fast so there's a story
classic story about unexpected quantity
of exponential function is that you know
in some Asian times increase
Rome where the King needs some problem
to be solved and some Joe you know solve
the problem and the King asked what
reward you want I can give you anything
you want and the guy says okay I don't
want too much I don't want you know much
but on a chess board chess board you
know on the first square you put a rice
then on the second square you put two
rice on the each time you let's see on
the second square you put two rise on
the third square you put eight rice is
that right yeah and on the fourth square
you put sixteen rice v 32 then 64 then
then 256 so each time you multiply by
two okay
and yeah that's exponential so you know
until all the chess squares are you know
filled there are 64 chess
squares you know 8 by 8 8 times 8 is 64
then so you go on this so basically the
answer is 2 to the 64th power so let's
see goal and let's try let's start try
to compute it so I'm going to create a
file save it X X okay save it xx dot go
okay so this is : and I'm going to do I
forgot what's the exponential function
bingo No
okay : so it's such then gonna
exponential function no you know the
exponential function is a problem in
many languages because they're usually
in the math package and the syntax I
mean it's you know it's problematic I
mean it's not standardized so let's see
and sometimes it's called power
sometimes it's called exponential
okay anyway let's see - I don't think
that look
invalid indirect of to okay yeah that's
some kind of pointer or something I hate
the [ __ ] pointers there it is
exponential X float X flow 64 let's see
what's the difference
exponential X plus 64 exponential 2x
plus 6
what the [ __ ] is the difference Oh
e to the X
oh when one of them is based to you
expound angel that's not what we want we
want the power function then let's go to
power
Oh PQ R so opq and people [ __ ] stupid
name God okay so the function is math
dot PO lowercase so 2 to the third power
that should be a yes piece 2 to the
fourth power 16 2 to the 64th power oh
you know that's one followed by 1900 1
followed by 19 0 so let's type 19 zeros
19 0
what okay 19 0 okay wait
19 okay we phase T by zero okay so it's
something like that one eight so
normally one two three so that's that
number so that's K M so let's write it
out god that's K that's him that's G
that's tetra I think so
so yeah that's oh that's one thousand
one thousand you have 1 million and you
have one chica then you have [ __ ]
then you have one tetra you know
basically the number becomes so huge
that's beyond the number of rises in the
universe
is that actually true yeah but anyway
you can look up and let's say let's look
up the story oh yeah there it is singing
but I want to go to Wikipedia
wheat and chessboard problem
okay the weed and chessboard problem
sometimes expressed in terms of rice
grains is a mathematical problem
expressed in textual form as in the
chessboard blah blah blah the problem
may have may be solved using simple
addition but I want the story ok orange
and the problem appears in different
stories about the invention of chess
some of them include the geometric
progression problem the story is first
known to have been recorded in 1256 by
ablum calico
another another version has the inventor
of chess in some Terran assassination
India Minister requests his ruler give
him wheat according to the wheat and
chessboard problem the ruler wraps it
off as a meagre price for a brilliant
invention only to have court treasurer's
report unexpectedly the huge number of
wheat grains would coach would outstrip
the rulers resources
ok so it's a legend it's not actually a
true story
here okay so it's a legend okay but say
but you know what is the oh it's not
just this number it's the addition the
sum of the Exponential's is so it's not
just this okay
[Music]
the REA cuz well guy is a he says cook
never liked anything he says like any
I'm interested in futurology you know
yeah I mean the huge the future of
humanity as with regard with respect to
technology and that's a broad topic and
it it's also a permanent topic I mean
throughout history it's a you know
general topic philosophers discuss now
especially in our century I mean today
it's especially relevant because
technology has become to the point of no
return shall we say you know because we
have artificial intelligence now you
know you know the Google alpha 0 AI you
know a machine that beats Chinese you
know top go players the go game that you
know the go game is supposed to be the
problem that decides you know if that is
up you know if machine can beat humans
in go then we say that artificial
intelligence is here you know that has
always been the ultimate problem
considered a good example of a good you
know ultimate problem of artificial
intelligence and now it's it's done you
know the Machine beats human by an
absolute certainty in fact estimated by
chest by by by the go experts you know
the machine is quite a lot stronger than
human you know it's this is a harder
problem than chess you know chess was
solved I mean the machine speed chess
champion world champion like 20 years
ago officially and after that you know
basically no human can beats check the
machine chess I mean even just the
common
chess software running on your PC like
doesn't matter what champion you are you
lose it like more they have for the but
half of the time you know doesn't matter
how good you are
doesn't matter how mad you are about
cheers what the genius it doesn't matter
you lose to you know average chess
software running on your PC even again
his champions well I mean again his
champions they doin a little bit
powerful PC you know like eight
processors or something but basically
yeah you know the chess machines beats
human like easily trivially hundred
percent you know so it has become to the
state so but few years but the chart
challenge organist machine versus human
for the go game is remained open until
you know two years ago how Fargo beats
human and since since then they are
other go software that came up that uses
Google's that learns from Google's you
know AI technology the neuro networks
and and indeed it just speeds humans you
know by quite far you know like there's
quite a gap that human cannot you know
machine had human there's so that's
that's just incredible you know I have
been watching the games like three years
ago when when uh Fargo competes with the
Japanese one of the top player then the
next year the alphago chat challenges
the Chinese guy he was the world
champion considered the number one and
the machine won't and since you know I
have also been you know reading comments
and watching YouTube's explanations
about go and the machine is just beyond
human right now
I mean there's no chance for human to
catch up to machines as far as spring go
is concerned again you know just like
chess so that is incredible them I mean
that's truly truly incredible I mean you
know so as you know so I mean so back to
you know previous topic we were talking
about
I've been observed observing technology
you know I want to know I you know I'm
curious about where is humanity going
you know what happens to society as you
know technique technology and machines
become smaller and smaller so you know
these futurology you know something like
that you know the who studies future or
you know trying to and and also involved
are things like prediction you know how
can you predict is prediction go away
you know how accurate are they and you
know you look at past predictions and in
you know so many you know aspects about
this you know looking into futures you
know where is humanity going you know
it's just say where is human animals
going you know I like to use the word
human animals instead of the humanity
and you know human beings especially
human beings you know those are you
familiar basically they are just fake
fake fake words words created created to
pretend to hide something else you know
we want to say human beings instead of
human animals because you know we like
to sometimes we don't want to say you
know we want to like give give it give
it a little color of you know how we are
hi different beings from God or
something else you know that are
different from other animals but but
actually if you you know if you are not
religious person and you believe in
science you know as much as possible
then basically it's just human animals I
mean human human is animal like other
animals we are you know organisms that
we we need to eat and you know ingest
food and turn that into energy and we
live and we sex and we have children and
we die you know in in basically you
could say in almost all regards you know
a human mo is it's just the animal and
but some people like to say Oh human
animal is the only one you know that has
such an in such discrete discrete
distinguished distinguishing properties
you know such as such as such as
intelligence in Africa that's it's Oh
[ __ ]
you know sometimes or sometimes they say
human human animals differ from others
because we have intelligence or we have
conscious consciousness or we have we
can feel pain or we have emotions or we
have self-awareness I think actually
it's all [ __ ] you know you don't
know I mean some of these concepts are
defensible
I mean arguable for example
self-awareness you know but no actually
that zachary force you know first of all
these concepts like self-awareness it's
actually hard to define you know there
is no Universal definition there's no
concrete mathematical definition that
that says okay this is self
self-awareness and that does not qualify
there is no such so same thing with
intelligence and so we just have some
rough ideas like but but why you know
like why can't you just you know take it
as is that we are just ham animals why
do you have to like find a distinction
well partly because psychology you know
again psychology is another science you
know we don't like so we don't know
things about the universe
the great mysteries of the universe with
so we study and we let's see so we study
and we you know we learn things about
our aspect of things so anyway so so
back to psychology oh yeah the one of
the reason is that you know
psychologically you know if we feel
better if we are like different from
other animals like pigs so you know
catalyst or dogs you know otherwise you
know we feel you know if we are the same
as pigs then it seems like we slaughter
pigs all the time like daily like we
have a slaughtering farm we we raise
them up they have a family go have a
girlfriend go have a boyfriend and [ __ ]
and have children and you make sure you
eat well then we kill you and eat you
once you have a baby you know then you
you know you you you have this next
generation but we eat you those cows and
you know the pigs and cows in beef in
you know the cattles and porcine RT you
know and then then also we somehow make
a distinction for dogs or cats you know
now can is cat meat you know I don't
know about cat meat but dog meat you
know we dogs we somehow make a
distinction especially the Western
society okay the the white people what
about black people I don't know what
about [ __ ] people I don't know but
anyway so anybody in particular the
Western society which is in general
considered the white people you know
they so they make a distinction about
dogs Oh horse for that matter horse you
know they somehow the dogs are low your
so they have
you don't you know you don't kill them
and eat them
but dogs for example in China you know
we them we eat it no problem there is no
problem now what what about cats you
know I don't think we eat why I mean I'm
sure some some Chinese or some regions
or in some times in some some past we
eat cats but I mean this that's an
interesting interesting question why do
we don't eat cats or do we eat cats I
mean we don't hear that as much though
but dogs yes we do eat at least some
places then yeah so we make a decision
but but why about why you know you
wonder why you know and is it you know
for biological reasons or symbiotic
reasons you know because dog and men
basically we say yeah we are friends you
know usually you don't eat your friends
because once you eat your friends even
if you know your friend is dead it
begins the path you know begins the path
because sometimes you are friend but
maybe you have some fight about
something a quarrel then then then
because you do eat other people then
suddenly you think [ __ ] you know I'm
hungry now I mean why not just kill him
and eat him eat him so so that begins a
path that gives you the idea you know so
so maybe maybe that is why we don't you
know we don't eat our friends so that
includes dogs you know but yeah but well
it's interesting to look up you know why
don't we eat cats but on the other hand
we eat you know where else yeah quails
you know they eat in Japan or in Finland
- something like somewhere there
ix Scandinavia maybe I don't know maybe
in England but they do and I think even
in America I guess I don't know for sure
but you know but maybe in Alaska you
know people do eat you know Wales and
Wales is generally considered more very
good guy you know the good guy you don't
want the key of Wales
you don't wanna eat them and and we also
eat octopuses like okay in America the
white people eat artists purses all day
you can you know or seafood you can eat
lobsters in octopuses and squids but
know that octopus is actually one of the
most intelligent animal okay so if you
you know test the intelligence of
animals
you know besides human animals octopus
is like on the top well there's also
toppings and cats and dog are kind of
stupid
in symbols I was on the top so close for
example crows and octopus and they are
intelligent I mean it's a surprising
lead I mean they can oh my god they can
you know do things this so there's a lot
story you know today you can see a lot
stories on also on YouTube I mean
verified accounts not just saying or
legend you know they cats I mean the
octopus you know they and and the
clothes and they they are extremely
intelligent they actually they actually
can octopus can actually recognize
people recognize people I don't know by
what means is it by sight or by by voice
by boko bus by sound or by
maybe smell I don't know but octopus can
recognize people like I've read a story
that you know like if you go if you go
you know in a Korean aquarium you meet
you walking aquarium and you know
octopus come you and go there and he
recognized I anticipate once a year or
something and he the octopus recognizes
you you know like this so there's a
story saying this female I think walk
seeing and hug the octopus squish squish
water or something you know anyway and
yeah so octopus is extremely intelligent
so yeah we saw in we make a difference
but wait wait but but we do eat octopus
you know well so what you know what
makes what do you make of it you know
why should we eat this or not eat that
actually all things considered the
rational reason I mean the typical
conventional reasons does not make sense
it must but there there is a scientific
or you know we can explore the reasons
why we don't usually not not not the
moral reasons given typically moral
reasons but rather it's because biology
or you know psychology or you know the
social like social science like the weak
are connected we depend on each other
things like that and sometimes it's for
religions religious reasons for example
some religions they don't you don't eat
cows and other religions they don't eat
pigs you know they just they just don't
you know and
and then okay then America you don't eat
dogs you know it's just like oh no you
how dare you you cannot detox but in
China I do and then and then we eat
whales in some places then we eat
octopuses all the time
Wow squid of some sort yeah and yeah and
then um so you consider the whole I
don't and I think it makes sense but
okay so yeah so we're talking about him
human was about back to a futurology
future futurology so you know and back
to the exponential problem and back to
whatever I was saying I was talking
about something something something goal
and and something I forgot I forgot what
were we talking about yeah so oh yeah I
was saying so I was saying I was you
know observing you know I like to
observe
I'm the script kind of guy I'm a
historian you know so you observe and
you and you record it you know as is you
know without euphemisms without you know
you know pretension trying to hide
something you write down things and so
I'm looking so yeah so I was thinking I
was looking at you know observing future
of humanity so in the past ten years
this incredible amount of technological
advances so I was saying yeah Sciences
in technology they are they have been
growing exponentially in the past 20
years now especially technology is such
that why do they grow exponentially
because once you know some especially
technology okay
once you know that you know science for
example math you know a lot then what do
you know helps you to know what you
don't know yet then you know that
then that adds to it that then you can
you can find out more about what you
don't know that's why they grow
exponentially now especially technology
technology such as you know computers
but you know everyday things like
plastics soda bottles you know like like
that you know this tremendous technology
in this thing you know sometimes you can
read an article in Scientific American
you know I remember this there was this
America scientific scientific America
article about this you know just
everything everyday things like even a
pen there's this actually quite
tremendous technology although this is
like old technology but you know just
imagine the convenience is in this thing
you know it's just so like before you
use you know you use you know quill or
you know ink pen you have to inject ink
a mix mess but not with this and with
modern paper you just write and write
you just write and so what is the impact
of that you know on a horse so this is
tremendous impact so this is just one
image and then we have computers like
personal computers you know at home
tremendous impact then you know now and
we have the phone iPhone you know
Android phone or smartphone
beginning with Apple's iPhone you know
you know Apple's iPhone it's not the
first but it's the first to make it
extremely popular because Apple has a
knack you know Apple is good Steve Steve
Jobs not Apple but Steve Jobs the guy
that he he has the ability to make
something extremely popular to to for
for example mouse mass is his summation
in lots of CD player
well of course CD and DVD player are
gone now but USB there are lots of
things you know a desktop publishing but
anyway so
so computers say so iPhone and with
iPhone then now everyone can video chat
you know remember 20 years ago if you
want to go to China to speak to your
friends or in Europe one minute per core
1 min is like $5 or $10 u.s. u.s. dollar
today's dollar is like $20 something
every minute and but now with Internet
you know it's like almost it's basically
free you talk to anyone first with a
video screen you can see your dad or
your friends or your grandma you know oh
grandson you know all over the world you
know and so what it's basically
basically free
so he says tremendous so I mean you
don't think about it much but think
about what what is the impact to the
humanity on a whole or focus on aspect
what is the impact of this cell phone
hung on the sciences on the growth of
Sciences almost specifically on
programming languages oh you know in you
know and we have things like Wikipedia
you know Wikipedia I've been observing
you know starting with it you know 2002
or 2003 in the beginning you know
Wikipedia linked to many of my website
articles math plane curves hyperbola you
know and then I thought what what the
[ __ ] is is weekly you know Wikipedia
what what is that you know and they
their information is you know scanty I
have you know back then I have lots of
sites link to link to my website because
my website was like a Wikipedia you know
for for certain math in some programming
you know it's part of the internet you
know we some of us you know our early
birds in blogging you know before
there's a word block you know so we
write a lot we'd write what we know and
so anyway we havea came up and
so I've been reading Wikipedia starting
in 2006 so somewhere around there almost
every day half an hour a day on average
I'm talking about you know starting from
let's say 2005 to today if you average
out all the time so I'll just went on
Wikipedia it's maybe half an hour an
hour a day
so I read you know 5 10 articles a day
and so but I observe so the the
information today I mean even in 2010
the information is greater than almost
any book even specialized math topics
like esoteric math hammocks but today
it's even more I mean it's it's even
more I mean I mean so what's the impact
you know like 10 in year 2000 if I want
to know something I go to a library and
maybe look up the Britannica
you know encyclopedia there and that's
of research you have to go to the
library you know he drives there walk
there you know it takes half an hour go
to there then sit there and you know
find a book you need find the
information you know this index cards or
whatever then you have to read it or
maybe this is not what you want you have
to find you another book or check the
reference okay that's a citation you go
find that book you know to find the
answer what you are you know your
question but today it's like oh my god
this is a Wikipedia like within one
second within you know five seconds you
basically find the information you need
it doesn't matter almost doesn't matter
Wow
I so tarik it is how specialized you
find it within five five seconds and the
content the way it is written the
writing quality the information density
the including special I'm talking about
including specialized information not
general information specialized what do
you mean for example topics in
mathematics or programming you know we
are programmers right and we
we talk about foreign languages go pearl
UNIX or HTTP protocols or TCI tcp/ip
protocols and any on Wikipedia they have
in-depth details I mean these are like
specialized knowledge like we are in
this in the field so we know but to most
people that's just like the
incomprehensible but the information is
there and similarly for mathematics you
know so Graduate mathematics you know
you find information in Wikipedia and
and and I and in general it's actually
even better than professional written
graduate math textbooks actually that is
true ok for most for I would say more
than half of the topics for in graduate
mathematics graduate graduate meaning
like after PhD well after four years of
college majoring in math but I mean they
also contain research math anyway the
point is the point is you know that's
incredible modern information quality
information so within five seconds but
not you know within five minutes let's
say you know yesterday you know in the
past few days I was reading about swords
you know like swords and and and rape
here and sabers you know in Chinese
swords Chinese Tao in jet so you know
I'm a nerd so I'm interested you know in
swords you know fighting swords or
weapons or what kind of spheres in
weapons and and swords swords in
particular because hoods have the high
esteem you know this is just more
dramatic but yeah it's actually less
practical the most practical weapon is
actually the sphere or some kind of poem
you know it's it's more effective but
anyway so yeah I'm a nerd so I mean
interesting sword so I've been reading
Wikipedia or elsewhere
on the internet for swords or Japanese
swords you know katana you know that's
the most famous poker
you know katana every movie wants to
talk about that so yeah I've been
reading and I thought you know I read a
lot about them you know you know over
the years you know as a hobbit hobby you
know like you know you just find the
topic interesting so you casually you
know every time every day every time you
you saw some article about it and you go
read about it and so you know you
classify swords you know especially
Japanese katana which is a Japanese
sword you know you know you see it you
see you've seen it in movies and you
know they they give the technical
terminology of each part of the sword
how they are made and you think and by
the way before the days of Wikipedia
this fa Q's about about katana and in
this kind of topic so basically nerds go
into detail about how they are made you
know you know is it involves quite
tremendous technology of sword making
you know you have different kind of
lawyers you know you want to make them
so that it's hard or flexible or it
doesn't get to you know you don't have
to shop it shopping yourself often so
this is tremendous technology in it in
science in it but yeah so you read about
it but today so we here today it's
tremendous you know that the information
has gone far up even compared to ten
years ago a foul-up like you read it
about swords you know agents you can
just read it we go to Wikipedia right
now and you know tap swords then you
have the classification you know
different cultures different words for
different type of swords in whatever how
they are made and why it ties to culture
you know yeah so yeah so it's in and
yeah so in also with pictures I mean
also you know before when on the subject
of swords it
to be nerds talking about swords like
nuts they just want to talk about swords
and they you know Knights in you know
knight in shining armor's or how to
sword fight Oh katana versus you know
fencing sword you know with things like
that but today's Wikipedia it has
actually more truth I mean so I mean
that's an interesting aspect but that's
not you know that's not the only topic
or primary aspect it focus on so on we
Wikipedia you talk about our key
archaeology evidence like it doesn't
talk about just but you know nerds
interest but rather yes nuts interest
but also the history of swords I mean
with proofs or evidence to back it up
like this is in what period and this is
and so we have a picture this is in how
this sword is found what year it is made
like a thousand years ago two thousand
years ago and where it is today in what
museums or whatever and you know so this
like archaeology so it's like history so
you actually you know you know you see
the history as aspect you know as it
should be you know it's not just swords
but all sort of weapons and and how how
inhuman armor was fight you know the
formation or whatever you know the
tactics and you know so it's not just
you know nerds interest in you know
dragon and you know chickens and princes
and swords but you know so it's that so
you see the whole history and the thing
is like that especially like Chinese
weapons you know Chinese we have we have
kind of many weird weapons weapons and
before you know kind of swords and
hooked sword or you know weird shaped
and before you know when you when you
and you run into any article about them
usually
from kung fu you know kungfu related to
come foo for our group and you know they
talk about they come first up but what
you actually want is the outside over
overview the comprehensive overview of
the the whole humanity and history not
just kung fu or kung fu this style is
good or that style is good you know not
the drum dramatic things anyway so so
today I will keep it even if you look at
Chinese swords it it you know it has the
historical information but however some
of the more exotic Chinese swords you
know they still like mostly they talk
they are talked in the context of
kung-fu this you know this style
confuses is and how it is used it's
limited to that point of view that's not
good but so you know in in next five or
10 years that will also be improved
because you know and why why because
smartphone you know technology you know
so you you know nobody you don't think
about it but today you can talk to
Chinese people you don't know you can
how to European people you don't know
you know people 10,000 miles away you
can actually not just talk to them know
them you can chat to them face to face
so you know that's incredible amount of
communication so information exchange
that's how is part of the reason you
know Wikipedia becomes so good and all
other things imperceptible I mean the
thing about exponential growth the the
growth of a tech of technology is that
you know each person we live in our day
life you know we only see these much
things you know we are focusing our jobs
or family or whatever our culture you
know we are like our culture is like
kind of like a region we just live here
we can only see this far you know you
cannot see ten thousand miles away
but now you can you know you're actually
came with smartphone and all that you
know with webcams in or that now you get
so so this communication so you can you
know talk to like I don't know about you
but well I'm Chinese right so I can well
I can't I can I never been to Europe for
example but I can if I want to I don't I
don't know much about Germany for
example I don't know actually I don't
know not much about England for example
I don't know much about Africa or
Islamic countries so you know you know
Middle East countries I don't know
anything about them not much you know
but but now if I want to I could
actually you know start to know a lot of
thing about them because for example
let's say I want to know about Islamic
Middle East country you know I don't you
know you can look at the map there are
different countries they act there
actually they are not they are actually
different you know they they have
different it's like if you are a white
person you might be confused you know
about Chinese and Japanese or Korean
you know you might you know to you they
are just oh they are just easy on me
they must be together they are alike
actually know yeah like you know when
you know people get angry offended when
you you know when you come well if I
confuse for example English people in
French people friends you know in the
same way you know even Chinese and
Japanese in Korea they are like
neighbors but they are not exactly
friends you know so I don't know
anything about Middle East for example
so I could if I want you know picnic
let's say pick a specific country
they have many countries you know okay
Iraq okay Indian because you actually
some of the most popular because we had
Iraq war ten years ago so let's say you
act so I can actually know you know I
can contact you know I can let's say
dive into their forum and talk to them
you know some of them speak English and
I can video chat with them although you
know there's political issues that kind
of restricted restrict it because you
know the middle is in in America and
Western they are you know not exactly
friends so but anyway so but in general
you can you know you know a particular
for example you if you are a white
person or a black person you can if you
want you if you are interested in
Chinese you know about China for example
you know don't you know there's lots of
articles about China on US news every
day that's usually [ __ ]
but what you can do if you are really
interested is actually go talk to the
people you know in China who lives in
China I did I didn't you know I've never
said my set foot on in China but I
talked to because I want to understand
you know I was going to as I you know
I'm curious I you know after I'm Chinese
so I want to understand how China people
or the programmers there is like you
know so you go there I mean you online
you can go into their forums where it's
you know like kind of local Chinese you
know programming forums and you talk to
them then you know how they what how
they see or how they feel so how the
situation is like you can learn and you
can you know ask them to show you photos
because in different regions you know
their daily life is different from your
daily life in your region in USA or
whatever you are they see lots of other
things and they have their own concerns
and issues and politics you know they
are dramas in whatever it's but it's
different it's typically different from
yours so you wanna go
they mix them you know mix in and talk
to them and they you you see a different
world you know you see different they're
different concerns the website they use
you know you know what are the things
they talk about every day
so yeah that's in that's technology okay
so we've been talking for like I don't
know how long for 40 minutes or is in an
hour
you know I have a cross-eyed problem I
think I had this problem since young
since I'm young but it's kind of only
enough it's not too serious but but when
I'm tired or sometimes when I was like
20-something after I swim I was on the
swimming team you know in college and
after I walk out my eyes would go cause
so it's you know it's but but not all
the time but but sometimes now I just
you know it feels better if I just cover
one of my eye so I'm you know this is
just toilet paper you just folded up and
very practical is this practicality in
efficiency with consideration of
efficiency because toilet paper is one
dollar one dollar a row and you can just
you have thousands replaceable pieces
and I just work and also in
consideration of comfort you know but
though one flaw is that it's not
aesthetic but you don't talk about
aesthetics about that you have to old
this is no this is not aesthetic you
know the aesthetic is you know you have
to prettify yourself you know put on
contact lenses or have ice surgery risk
of going blind and then you look pretty
pretty yes yes okay okay so we've been
talking about technology and technology
and technology and technology what else
so I was going to talk about yeah okay
originally I was going to talk about
certain videos I watched him but
okay so that's it for today okay yeah
yeah that's it for today bye