good morning guys welcome to another
episode of saw talk show today is
September 28th Saturday nigh o'clock
a.m. in morning San Francisco time and
today's topic is I don't know yet
email is basic so uh Richard Stallman
apparently is looking for a temporary
housing apartment or something you know
he posted this on his blog Stallman
oke so he is looking you know for
housing you know apartment for a place
to live for two months to half a year
you know it's on his website you know I
know that Richard Stallman in in 1980s
or night in 1990s he sleeps in his MIT
office you know he just sleep on the
floor and but I'm not sure you know
perhaps he has been doing that all his
life he have possibly you know possibly
he have never lived on his own he's that
type of person and also let me mean you
know this is this is pretty bad you know
he is this utopia community you know the
GNU Free Software Foundation bedo
so he is considered by many to be the
god or guru sort of people those kind of
people that you it's almost like a cult
leader and today you have lots of that
in the new-age community such as you
know such as yoga yoga stuff those kind
of thing you kind of like a coat so let
me mention this again I talked about
this again there is this article
let me show it this article the title is
why utopian communities fail this is
written in 2018 by this guy a Wong
Morrison he you know he travelled the
world and he surveyed all the utopian
communities basically this other
communities just like free software
foundation you know they practice kind
of commune the you know these like
hippies
you know utopia you living a community
no no one has higher pay everyone is the
same
there is no officers or commanders no
leadership no hierarchy community
communities like that they are quite a
few you know throughout history and some
of them still exist some of them moved
into a little town and they will
establish your communities there you
know so the question is what happens in
this kind of communities what's really
going on how do how is the you know
power structure how you get things done
you know how you who buys the food who
pays you know how does it work so he
travelled and looked around and here is
his report you know the report is pretty
good so I recommend you read this
article good morning people so I have
quite a few people thank you for coming
by good morning George
good morning to Australia good morning
to just in Canada good morning to
Bartholomew in Germany and okay so
George says so last time I asked what's
your programming language would like if
you design one do you have time to go
into it today yeah that we can talk
about that I don't really have much to
say though because you know
I have I have written down sketches but
let me show you
so Justin says groaning come on
interesting author of me says I waited
for your schedule now I'm it's two
minutes of his scream yeah I did I only
started the schedule like ten minutes
I've you know I forgot yeah you know
yeah might be a glitch George says spot
the stream seems to start after he was
already talking about strowman oh well
yeah YouTube I don't know what's going
on but anyway Richard Stallman is
looking for housing on his frog so good
afternoon good afternoon cool for school
where you from cool for school so guys
okay type a topic oh I'm just going to
go random I don't have a fixed topic oh
yeah so so George asked me what's my
opinion about the best language I mean
what what is my language syntax going to
be like I actually have a sketch of that
because I wanted to let's go to my
programming blog okay hold on a second
let's go to excel talk show and let's
get today's magnify star talk show let's
get today's topic notes up so Sonya page
create a new page make it a list posted
here go there open okay first question
is what's your language syntax okay
let's try to find it I have a note here
somewhere
not Emacs cuz with my programming blog
go to the diet this matching lines
what would I search for
Len okay then I think there's too many
articles I have a article written
excellent design there it is the last
one okay here okay it's a it's a sketch
so you know I wrote this in 2011
okay last update 2015 so well I can tell
you basically my language the syntax I
want okay this will lead to several
interesting topics we can talk about
that now if you guys have other topics
just type it okay good morning Lloyd
Eloy it Anderson so my language design
so the syntax I wanted I probably wanted
to be something like Mathematica now
that's the topic I talked about
yesterday and there is another so go
through my programming languages you
know you go to my website programming
Parag and you go to syntax OOP no
actually you go to on Lisp then you will
see this video this this video is
one-hour talk about this syntax symbolic
expression meta expression Mathematica
and meaning of sugar syntax so in this
article and also yesterday in this video
also yesterday I talked about a syntax
system you see Mathematica so so first
of all that's what I want that's yes
that's what I want
the yes and so first of all it's going
to be 100% regular then it's going to
have a system there is a transformation
of syntax so that so that expressions
such as arithmetics can be it's easy to
read and it's convenient to write so
math America it's systematic and also I
wanted to be
as another example of regular regular
syntax or uniform syntax is XML but XML
is very cumbersome okay so that's the
first thing I want to have then no I
don't have a forum so gold go with
bathroom you bottom you is creating one
okay I have a read it sorry but I
haven't been active used actively using
it reddit Sally fanclub
let's see if we can find it it's
basically arc Saudi okay so our capital
X aah
now reddit is annoying because you know
because two years ago yeah so this is my
I had I don't post it there often oh if
you wanna PayPal me here's an email it
must be this one must be specific
okay so at solid are old okay if you
want to you know if you want to PayPal
me that's gonna be excited Saudi dog
must be that one because because
otherwise I won't get it I also read
that in email yeah you can send it to
excite Saudi dog it's your email you're
on the same message I despise reddit
okay I know I mean email okay yeah so my
language is the language I want
for a few things about matching parents
so a little on semantics okay yeah so
basically the the syntax will be
assistant systematic syntax like
Mathematica what about the semantics I
haven't decided on semantics semantics
you know one of the big question to me
when I want to if I want to design a
language is the first question I mean
beside after the syntax ok for the
syntax part I pretty much have a idea
what I want in fact I can you know I
would be happy just to copy Mathematica
but they they may not let people do that
they all see you because they have
copyright because I remember that's what
happens back in back in 1990s there are
people who tried to create a clone of
whooping you know Mathematica and you
know if M is not happy you know they
they send cease and desist letters you
know cease and desist is one of the
jargon in idiom in English you have you
have to say cease and desist it's pretty
idiotic but it has a particular
connotation to it you know you have to
say cease and desist
so for those of you don't know who is
English you know English is not your
first language that is so let me show
you what that is okay hold on a second
show this in browser and go through some
talk show and today and so the word is
cease and desist okay I hope I spelled
that correctly yeah cease and desist
desist it just means that this cease
means stop okay this means stop okay so
it means stop and stop and let me put
that here okay so my language design
choices so for the syntax part it's
probably gonna be like roof I'm language
so
some are senior at least at least you
know the systematic grammar
now the semantic part I'm not sure yet
but one of the first question before you
go any further
the first question is whether whether it
should be a symbolic language symbolic
such as Lisp or Mathematica you know
again I talked about this topic in in in
I think in that in this video I talked
about yes
Lisp syntax symbolic expression mid-high
expression so check check this video out
okay 2019 July 19th is one our talk on
that topic very focused it's one of the
one of the best ones of my videos and
actually so yesterday we also talked
about that yeah actually actually
yesterday we should I let me put that up
here so yesterday here is yesterday we
talked about also about syntax system
language syntax ad hoc versus uniform
syntax system in syntax algebra so this
this I will phone and we are now put put
on on the on here so let's do it
let me just show you some Emacs okay so
I'm gonna open open so what I do is you
see in the browser I select the URL copy
it now I switch to Emacs I call command
let's our open file from clipboard okay
now that file is opened you know I give
it the URL that this this local file URL
you see that file colon slash slash
slash so I can open that in Emacs and
now and now I just go to youtube section
this section I copy it close it and oh
wait oh wait so YouTube so I I want to
add another YouTube here
so I go back to max on Tokyo yesterday
which is this page in this page and now
I go to the YouTube at top copy it copy
switch buffer paste it here now showing
browser so now on this page you see I
have two videos yes so not what I want
to do is just go to Asia and kokum and
to sync to my web server okay now close
that now I copy the file path of this
file open a new buffer magnify paste it
here
okay paste it there and make it into a
link with title so now I copy that
switch to Chrome switch to Chrome and I
paste in a chat box and if you guys go
there now you will see you know the
video I just added so those two videos
for those of you interests in syntax you
know to read watch those two videos so
let me see let me check over here so we
go through my website let's see so
that's about syntax okay but so the
about what what about semantics what
would how do you want your language to
be first of all I want it to be
functional okay it's not going to be
opie it's possible to add a piece
support I don't know you know so I
haven't really done anything with it you
know I haven't you have to you know
first of all you in order to create a
language you you need to be able to
write a parser and compile it I haven't
I don't really know that yet
so I haven't I you know so so I but I
know I wanted to be functional language
possibly supporting over P or this but
functional for sure
but the first question then is whether
you wanted to be symbolic so so that's
what I talked about in this video
whether it should be symbolic you see
what you see languages like Lisp
and mathematic Mathematica they are
symbolic but but I have always been
puzzled about what is the exact utility
when a language is symbolic now if you
ask the Stefan Wolfram you know the guy
who created Mathematica he'll just say
oh you need to be symbolic because you
know because because that's the most
powerful you know but but you know he's
you know he's he's always he's a
megalomania you know he's always you
know talking about his language
Mathematica and but if you ask Lisp
people now it's this is interesting I
actually have not seen much much you
know common commentary from these people
about why a symbolic language is that
great yeah I actually in my 20 years you
know in this community I have not heard
them talk much about that or they talk
about these mark was this Marco's they
are idiots okay at least people as you
know that Common Lisp people the
generation of these people since I would
say 1990 so mm my opinion of them they
are kind of idiotic idiots they don't
see you know Lisp is great invented by
John McCarthy in 1960s it is great it is
one of the first language that focuses
on abstract mathematical ideas so it
came from math basically but not today's
list was the common list was the all the
list was I talked to or emag list fans
they are like they are rather extreme
idiot English they they are not they are
not much different from other languages
phonetics
just purl you know back in 1990 90s
pearl you know you have if everyone is a
programmer you know they are more than
one way to do it they cite this chance
all day then you have Python you know
come cite our us Python people so so to
me that these people you know after
being in this community for 20 years the
way I see them is that they are just
they are not much different from the
phonetics of other languages you know
for idiotic thoughts that they think
they insist it's a best thought of all
you know they kind of insist meanwhile
if you ask them why they cannot come out
with any substance substance
you know they cannot really explain with
substance you know that that's what
happens and those yeah you know
typically like what these people are you
know the Perl phonetics Python phonetics
this phonetics for example typically
what these people are these phonetics
okay they say all have including Haskell
phonetics typically what they are is
that they are just just a average
programmer well maybe a bit of above
average okay and they sum up many of
them are students in in college they are
hotshots like when I was young okay they
are you know they read a few books they
think they are better than everyone else
they think they know everything about in
the universe
you know suffer morons you call them
suffer morons in college so somewhat
half of them a lot of them these
language phonetics are college students
hotshots you know they think they they
are a bit above average and they think
they know everything but the other half
mostly are they they they you know they
they might have ten years for where my
experience or 20 years or even thirty
okay but so what they are is like
typically everyone gets out now you are
a programmer right now you are a
programmer you
we'll get old now my eye I myself have
like 30 years programming experience
yeah since 1991 you know you will get
there to everyone we are so you will
have billions literally billions of
people or have like oh I'm a programmer
I have 30 years of experience that
doesn't mean you are you know very good
or something there anyway so so the
other half of the programming language
phonetics you know espousing four
particular language or way he said they
are just these average programmers who
have you know 10 10 years it also
programming language you know like you
know in first five years of your job you
may be you know see then maybe you know
Perl they may be you learn you know you
do JavaScript you know so you know a few
languages let's say five so that that's
the average that's their situation you
know they've been programming for a long
time they know several languages and
they have they they have opinions you
know just like everyone they have
opinions there and then they have strong
opinions but it yeah so you know just
like if you go you just go to Street and
ask any old people old people have
opinions right so anyway that's these
people they have opinions but so so what
you know they don't know you know
really they don't know
you know they that's not you know this
is this is not just the flame flaming
them or you know unfair criticism this
is you know I think this is a valid
criticism because what I'm saying is
that they they have never actually
studied language design okay that's a
thing you know you see the subject
matter is about language design you know
when you say oh python is the best
language or pro is the best or Lisp is
the best language that subject matter is
language design okay now and that's a
big topic you know you can dedicate your
life
to it and and the part of it has to do
with computer science no theoretical
computer science part of it has to do
with practical you know industrial
programming so they're experienced
industrial programming certainly count
but that's not all that's only part of
it and part of it has to do with you
know so what's involved in programming
language design ok theoretical computer
science you should know you know at
least know the basics practical
computing experience programming
experience in industry you definitely
that's a asset if you know that okay you
definite definitely need that because
you can if you'd like many academics
like scheme people ok they are they are
academia professors they never worked in
their life in their entire life they
never you know worked in industry code
you know coding in the industry for for
one month so they have no idea you know
it's very different being in academia
and the industry you know in industry
almost every company you go the code you
know the code base is like the spaghetti
code you know so you you you do need
industrial experience ok so anyway so so
what's the elements what do you need to
know to be able to what's involved to
design your language you know what
should you know ok so some basics of
theoretical theoretical ok computer
science meaning formal languages you
know like that theoretical computer
science and also compilers and Pasir
theory
now that's a entire you know branch of
topics you can study for years passes in
compilers which below they kind of
belong in theory theoretical computer
science well compilers also belong in
the practical you need it ok so it's you
need to know the you need to actually
know where else
some part of theoretical computer
science automata you know and so on the
different classes of language you know
the language hierarchy the context-free
languages and these are important when
it comes to syntax okay the other day I
was going to talk about it but I kind of
botched my talk because I because I was
not able to I was not I was not able to
teach you compiler how compiler works
well because I don't know the subject
well this is like three days ago four
days ago I made a video on that so
anyway so you need to know theoretical
computer science then you need to know
MS young yes okay theoretical computer
science you need to have practical
programming experience okay then you
need to know you need to study the
system of notation systems okay notation
system for example the history of math
notations okay okay it's such it I have
I have you know several articles of that
problems of traditional math notation
the concepts and confusions of prefix
infix that's my true title packing this
is I guess this this is one of my
article on the so anyway it was supposed
to Python back then like 15 years ago so
problems of traditional math notation
let's read it out okay so copy that
let's put today's talk here okay cuz
that cooked tres talk
okay and what is this today is September
28th
okay language design who is it oh I'm
down there okay so pay see here so list
index on list
okay math notations problems of
traditional math notations you need to
know these okay and and also history of
math notations let's let me talk about
this so they are actually you know this
is not a trivial topic okay because when
you talk about math notations history of
metal notations in fact I can show you
several history books you know I have it
here yeah let me just show you because
it's some talk show it's fun okay you
talked a lot about syntax okay matt says
you talk you talk a lot about syntax but
there are so many factors that makes a
great thing great language okay here's
the thing I know what you're saying you
know you are saying you are thinking you
know programming language is not just
syntax in fact syntax is probably the
least important right that's what you
think you are so you are thinking there
are so many much more important thing
that's that's if you if you are thinking
in that direction that's the wrong
direction actually there are some
computer science scientists I can tell
you right now
for example the scheme guide the racket
one of the racket team member he wrote a
program he wrote a book I think the
language design or something in the
first chapter there is a quote syntax is
say something along the line of syntax
is the least important right like you
know the way people they are thinking
the way they most programmers and in
some of these computer scientists
you know they are chanting is that they
are thinking syntax is this important
because you know you it can be any
syntax though the rather the more
important thing is a semantics okay
that's totally wrong now in my opinion
okay this in my opinion that that's the
most idiotic thinking the most important
element of a programming language is
syntax that's the most important element
of programming language not not
semantics okay in fact it is the syntax
that determines how how good is language
syntax alone now now if you interpret
interpret what I just said
in some extreme sense then that's wrong
okay I mean I'm not saying Oh semantics
is not important I mean you can push it
to the extreme so you can say okay I'll
say is you know language is nothing
except syntax that's obviously not true
you need semantics you know if your
language for example functional
programming versus ROP you know versus
you know speed speed of the language and
and somewhat if you don't like me you
could say Oaks are things those are not
important the only important thing is
syntax that's wrong okay but what I'm
saying is that I showed that okay we are
starting to digress into lots of things
I for example let me show you this this
syntax OOP okay wait
syntax OOP wait where's my quote
semantic noodle okay so semantic new dog
and you need to go up here complan pervy
let me read my quotes syntax is the most
important aspect of a programming
language the quality of a programming
language can be judged by how much of it
can be explained by its syntax alone
okay this is my idea and this is a this
this idea I mean it's it's not just me
saying it okay you are thinking oh it
only casarse said that's not true
because you don't I mean you you got
most people okay program asleep there on
they that they don't know
they never studied things you know
actually so I digress a lot I want to
try to ogen try to keep my thoughts
organized so anyway that that's about
syntax this this okay this this kind of
this this line of thought about how
syntax is the most important element it
has to do with formal languages okay
formal you know if you if you guys don't
know what formal language is formal
language is the heart of theoretical
computer science okay most programmer
don't know the industry
programmers you know at you know
everyday they may say Oh to me machines
streaming completed and what the idiocy
or or sometimes they say lambda calculus
but you will almost never hear them
mention the word formal language okay
formal language is the heart you know if
you you you you could say it's the heart
of theoretical computer science nothing
else okay
you know so that's one way to put it
okay for more languages lambda calculus
is is one you know one branch of formal
language programming language grammar
theories are passing it's that's one
branch of formal language and formal
language has to do it has to do with the
foundation of mathematics okay formalism
Hubert's formalism you know I I start to
get my blood start to boil because when
it comes to the idiots of the industry
programmers formal language okay
formal language here but formalism okay
let me magnify okay
formalism okay one of the foundation of
math okay Hubert's formalism okay you
can look up Wikipedia okay and I have I
have like I have I have so many articles
I've read I've written you know on my
website yeah you know each you know each
time I want to mention one of my
articles I have to spend one minute to
drink you know so anyways yeah but but
yeah actually I'm going to show them
because they are related oh these are
related
okay formalism formal language syntax
design that's what I'm saying that's
back to the my topic about what are the
elements you need to know in order to to
to say to be well educated about how to
design a programming language okay okay
so so let's just summarize again so you
need to know you need to know some you
need to know some you need to okay let
me write it down then what's what are
the things one need to know okay now
writing tip sorry writing tip instead of
saying one need to know say you okay you
is more direct and understandable so
what are the things you need to know
about designing a programming language
okay
okay actually that's not the way to say
it because I'm not talking about the
things you need to know but rather I'm
talking about what the things you should
know if you want to consider before you
design language if you want to consider
yourself you use yourself very qualified
to create the best language okay let me
put it that way
what are the things you need to know you
should know about designing a best
programming language okay best in some
sense in southern sense the best okay
because there's no absolute definition
of what is the best language okay too
many on what you know what's your what's
your goal of your language things like
that so so what are the things you
should know you should know for example
first of all let's keep the take you
know the the things everyone need to
know so for example unius lee you need
to know how to write a parser obviously
you need to know how to write a compiler
but I'm not mentioning them here because
that's too obvious and obviously you
know you should know what function means
right what a variable means that we are
skipping those so so what I'm saying
here is what you should know is first of
all level let's say ten years of working
in the industry as a programmer okay
that's one thing then you also need to
know need to know theoretical computer
science okay th yo are you TRCA or
theoretical did I spell it correctly yes
theoretical computer science okay then
now those two items everyone kind of
already know let me tell you what less
people know you need to know I was
starting to talk about this subject you
need to know the history of math
notations okay why why do you need to
know the history of math notations
because programming language is let me
just write the things you need to know
okay
right in systems of the world history of
writing systems okay let like like
English Latin alphabet Chinese
logographic systems things like that
okay writing systems of the world and
you need to know neuroscience
some of neuroscience there helps that is
for example scientific study of how
human how the brain perceive text you
know how the brain perceive text
communication science of communication
things like that for example
science of communication and and also
things like for example you know like
now and then you will see news
you know websites reporting these
scientific findings for example they are
quite a few scientific there they are
about two or three paper papers you know
from academia I know that talks about
that that research look into when you
have a variable whether camelcase
is better or snake case you know you
know that right when you have a variable
name you have a issue of style should it
become okay source snake case you know
and programmers argue about all about it
all day you know or which is better you
know but there there are a few academic
papers that study that so you have that
you know they they get a hundred
volunteers you know programmers and they
they test you know so they have one
program using chemicals another program
using snake haze so they have they
divide people into two groups one is
control group or things like that and
they test you know how fast they can
understand the program things like that
you know you might have seen it you have
to go in a few minutes okay so so okay
so yeah so the you know so anyway so you
can know case versus snake case okay so
so so that so you so there are several
papers talking about that they give you
the result basically the result is not
conclusive okay but why am i mentioning
that because that is an example of
communication scientific study of
basically writing systems one aspect of
writing systems so if you are designing
language you know you need to know this
these kind of things these kind of
things are part you know it's a part of
you know it's part of writing system and
writing system is part of what governs
you know how good is your syntax we
because you need to know human how human
read it okay as far as I know like it's
almost like nobody ever you know that
this language you know study you know
academia or or programmers in the
industry they don't know they don't know
also in academia so why is academia I
haven't mentioned the things I mentioned
because academia they flow with fund
money where where there's money they go
that way
because they don't you know they don't
just study random things you know they
should hire me okay the true spirit of
academia is you hire people to study
things that's interesting
not following by money you know grants
you know that's what you know as today's
society has become so I was talking
about so one of the element in in you
should know when you think when you
think you want to design your best
language okay one of their element is
about related to neuroscience about
human brain perceived text about you
know science of a communication and
about for example the for example the
the papers you know about camel case
with a snake case okay that's that's an
example of that okay so let me show you
actually I have a article about that let
me show you my articles you know I'm
obsessed about these kind of things so
here is my article about camel case
versus snake case I've read I've read
everything on the web ok everything and
there are a few academic publications
like masters theses or PhD theses things
like that and I list at the bottom
somewhere here okay here's a PDF okay
for example this one an eye tracking
study on camel case and underscore
identifiers identifiers Styles you know
2010 by bonito
Arif and Jonathan malarek and stuff
Department of Computer Science Kent
State University okay that's what and
here's another one to camelcase
or underscore 2009 by Dave blinky Dave
Binkley and so on at all then there's
another one
okay well that the the those those are
from academia then you have you know
guide or the big shots you know they
want to tell you their opinions anyway
that's a camel case was a snake case
okay that's one element of that's one
example of a study of writing systems
one aspect of writing systems which is a
more efficient which is better okay and
neuroscience about perception okay let
me show you another thing another
there's a collection yeah of articles
about that so we were talking about
remember we were talking about we were
where was I okay so I was saying you
need to know the history of math
notations okay let me show you articles
about that sorry
history of math notation I don't think I
have article on that but but yeah let me
show you these problems of math
notations you know so Y twice math
notation important because they are all
related you see writing systems in math
notation now when you study math from
notations and also you studied a history
of math notations you learn things you
know for example you will know you will
know that you know some notation in fact
yeah
in fact many it is often the case I
think it's very significant I mean it's
not not just say it's it's it's
important to such a degree that many
branches or advancement of mathematics
for example for example calculus okay
meetry
linear algebra okay in algebra you know
we today we have equations those are
modern notations you know before before
we have x squared equals 2y something
like that that you know modern equation
notation before that we were using
descriptive like we were using English
words to describe something so we all
say you know oh X when we when you have
a number then then suppose that number
attempts itself then that number is
equal to something you know you you you
use words very inefficient then you have
algorithms described in words but now
but once the the mass notation you know
the the kind of the algebraic equation
begin okay instead words you have
algebraic equations use you begin to
have a entire progress like branch an
entire branch of computer algebra will
use you start to manipulate symbols like
okay okay you know you add you add a
number to both sides you add X to both
sides so the X becomes you know what
comes to to the right side you know so
you can start to isolate you know the
the variables and things like that you
you do symbolic manipulation then after
a few years you doing that you started
to realize okay you start to realize you
know a automated system to manipulate
symbols and eventually the you know that
become programming languages you know
today we have computers algebra system
and symbolic pad imagine you know it
traced if you trace the history you know
it goes through that it goes to the the
notation for for math problems like
instead of description like two thousand
years ago in Egypt in China you don't
have you know super for example let me
show you let's say X X x squared plus
five equals to equals to 10 okay so
something simple like that 2000 years
ago you don't have you know know
patience like that you instead of you
said you see you see and usually you say
it like with a story you know instead
instead of abstractly so you say Oh a
children who you know we have two
brothers and they are age multiplied
together plus five is equal to 10 so
what is their age you know you have to
that's that's how you describe a problem
then eventually it becomes you know then
even you know after a thousand years or
something we got the notation once you
have a notation you start to do symbolic
manipulation the the concept okay the
concept of this idea of symbolic
manipulation comes up you know it's an
entire it's a new direction why does it
come up it will not come up without the
notation okay
so this is why this is just one of the
example of how notations change the
entire math you know it it it it it
direct your direction it you know it
tells you where to go so once you have
this for example you for example how do
you solve this you you minus 5 to both
sides okay let me let's do that let's
use double equal sign so so programmers
are more familiar with it okay so you
minus 5 to both sides okay so you can do
that and then you got 10 minus 5 is 5
right so this these two cancel so x
squared equals to 5 then you square root
2 both sides okay yeah okay so let's
okay
then the answer is the the left side
cancel out so x equals to square root of
five right so that is the so so you see
this seems so so you are adding
something to both side but eventually it
just becomes knit so it becomes
manipulating of symbols and once you
have this once you do manipulating of
symbols for you know for 100 years then
a new idea comes up people start to
realize oh then we can just I can you
know it seems so mechanical we can just
automate it that's when you have
formalism and formal languages okay okay
so after you have symbolic notation
symbolic equation to describe math then
you begin then then the concept of
symbolic manipulation comes came up okay
and once then after you do that 400
years the automated
symbolic manipulation comes up then we
have formal languages okay formal
languages that's me that's that's the
history of lambda calculus you trace it
back what why is lambda calculus created
because back then
it's it has to do has to do with math
foundation you know trying to answer
questions in the foundation of math you
know you know solving equations things
like that foundation of math and logic
okay so so then you start we have formal
languages okay so that's some of the
examples this this is so that's the
about explaining why you know so I was
saying math notation study math notation
and history of math notation is is
critical if you really want to design
your language that's you know you can
see the best so you need to study the
history of programming language I mean
the history of math notations okay so
let's make that math okay so here is one
example of why study of history of math
notation is important because often math
notations creates a entire new branch of
math or entire new thought process okay
this is this is historically true now
I'm just giving you one of the many
examples you know the the the symbolic
notation for equations okay that's just
one of example another example for
example the switch from Roman numeral
code system to the Arabic number system
okay
so are you guys still here another
example the switch from Roman numerals
to Arabic number system you know that's
another example you guys know what's a
Roman numeral right you can look it up
ok so there's something wrong here let
me fix ok I don't want that
ok that's good so so another example
switch from and let me give you another
example another example is matrix
notation for matrix mode another example
ok
matrix notation that so these are some
of the examples where when you have a
notation that that change it's almost
like it's a game changing thing you know
it changes the entire thing now let me
tell you a concrete example how this
influenced the programming language
design a concrete example ok for example
this in Lisp you have nested parentheses
right and these people they say they are
singing the songs of this Marko's all
day you know you will say you will see
them all this Marco is the best thing
this Marco is the best thing programming
languages is the best thing since sliced
bread
ok this Marco's ok now let me tell you
this if this programming language if
they if they do not have the nest nested
parentheses you know the regular nested
parentheses the least marco idea will
never come up okay
now you understand
why does the least Markov idea come up
because to begin with you need a regular
nested parentheses then then idea comes
to you then then you start to have you
know oh then we can do Markos we can
have you know transformation of the
expression yeah so let me say that let
me write it down so a concrete example
if these languages do not use nested
parent parentheses for syntax then the
list marco idea will not happen okay
that's a concrete example how critical
syntax is in my opinion I mean I kind of
biased or dramatic way of saying is that
syntax is the most important element of
programming language okay so that's
another example so so let's see let's
kind of stop for for a minute and see
where are we going how long I have have
been talking one hour okay good
six people okay not many today okay so
so so far we so we we are talking about
programming language design and what
makes you know what do you what should
you know or without other elements you
should know well before you can consider
to design your best language you know
some sort of best language so you need
to know you know you need to have
experience as a industry programmer for
for for 10 years 10 years is may be heid
it's just say 5 ok and you need to know
theoretical computer science such as
limits ages such as such as formal
languages lambda
calculus CA LC urs and Y Combinator's
okay for example and for in the first
order logic first order logic type
theory and let's just say symbolic logic
okay let's not leave me to for soda okay
hold on a second okay so so you need to
know theoretical computer science such
as formal languages lambda calculus Y
Combinator's symbolic logic type theory
because because when you talk about
computers theoretical computer science
in the branch of formal languages
because what what is formal language for
more languages or about syntax nothing
else just syntax what you do is find
replace you know it's all just strings
syntax that's less formal language is
about and that that is related to the
foundation of mathematics okay the
almost the deepest possible science of
all Sciences like you know like people
say oh you know chemistry is just
applied physics you know biology you
know biology chemist chemist you know
there's a joke running running joke
among the scientists you know you know
biology you know chemist chemist will
say oh biology is just a prior came in
chemistry okay then physics physics we
all say oh chemistry is not you know
it's not important it's justified
physics okay
the mathematicians we will say Oh
physics that's nothing that's just
applied mathematics okay now this one
one person above mathematician okay
that's logician logician comes in will
say oh math that's nothing that's just
applied logic so we are talking about
logic here and what is logic today
modern logic is formal language okay
logic first order logic second order
logic
hi-oh logic type theory lambda calculus
Y Combinator's symbolic logic that's all
in the name of formal language okay and
what is that you know you can you can
read in Wikipedia now I gave you some
kind of you know layman layman kind of
you know explanation unprofessional
explanation now you go with Wikipedia
you start to understand what they are
talking about formal language okay so
that's important you know like average
programmers these people talking about
Oh what which is the best language they
know did they don't know okay
like the including this person has cow
people
good morning just so yeah in summary you
need you have some you need to have
experience in the industry of
programming okay I explain why about
that before you need to know for more
languages okay then you need to know
history of math notations and history of
notations in general and and in general
writing systems of the world history of
writing systems that that's you know
that's not critical okay I mean it's but
it's suddenly related because it will
because math notation itself is a it's a
writing system then you need to know
newer science by the way some of these
should be grouped together okay it's not
separate
so in anyway so you also need to know
things like the scientific study of the
efficiency of writing systems that
that's a way to put it okay so you know
which usually they belong in your
science so you know new science is one
of the one way to put it for example how
how the human brain perceives text you
know a sentence science of communication
for example the paper about chemicals
and sneakers so that so that okay so
what else besides that for to you need
to know for designing in the best
language
what about semantics part I can't think
of that as something I need to write it
down because because um first of all
obviously when you want one want to
create a language you need to know what
it's going to do right so that's not
something you don't know I mean that's
not something like you for example like
what do you need to know before you
build a car of course one of the most
important thing is that the car must be
able you can drive it right but you
don't need to measure it so in the same
way what do you need to know to be to be
able to design you know best one of the
best programming language well depends
on what you have mind
in in mind what you want your language
to do you know then you need to know
that you I mean the language needs to be
able to do that for example for example
let's say marker markup languages or
this script you know like HTML markdown
those are markup or OGG Mart or even
post PostScript or tech you know the job
of those languages is to render render
things so of course you need to know you
need to have knowledge about what how
such things are used PostScript you know
how are they use you know what are they
useful and how do you actually how do
they actually walk things like that like
the rendering systems you know
so that part I'm I'm going to skip so
because I was thinking so ok but what
about other elements of semantics for
example functional programming or with
opie or array languages or you know
things like that there's many branches
should you have pattern matching so
those kind of things
yeah I guess they are important you know
you kind of you know give yeah but
anyway so so the the thing I mentioned
here is is what I focus on okay I kind
of I mean to me to my personality I feel
these are important I mean of course
whether you should have list
comprehension like many features you
should have Korean automatic Koreans
should it have tail recursion should it
have course EC should it have you know a
bunch of other features that's it's kind
of up to you should it have lazy
evaluation you know that's kind of up to
what do you want to do you know that
yeah you should know those so yeah so so
how do you describe those things in one
sentence how do they know where the
semantics and styles of languages
something like that okay semantics and
styles and features of language kind of
like that and also also it's good to
know know the history programming
languages okay that's very that that is
actually quite important because because
you study old languages in the past then
you have good you at least have a good
overview of what had happened before you
know you know all the different ways to
do things okay so that's about that
about the elements of designing a
programming language okay so no
questions no comments so so Justine says
it's interesting like closure
programmers don't really encourage using
markers yeah yeah in common list it was
so does the programmable foreign
language e and you should go crazy with
Marcos yeah the reason you know I
I can kind of tell you what I think why
I kind of know why the reason most most
programming language phonetics the
reason they say certain things not
because certain things are really good
or something it's it's really just
because it so happens that in their
community community it so happens it's
pet benefit then for saying that that's
that's kind kind of my outline of my my
thought about why certain things
particular phonetic of a language we our
community will say you are mentioning
all the time for example in this it
typically is Lise Marcos in scheme
typically its tail recursion and course
EC you will find them like mention other
proportions all the time in Haskell its
monad ok in a scow it's mornin in now so
here's the interesting thing in closure
closure is one of the you know
considered to be a least family but
however enclosure they don't talk about
Marcos this is kind of funny okay they
don't talk about Marcos why because it
just so happens it's you know it's not
because Marco is truly good or bad not
because monad is truly good or bad or
any of these feature is truly good or
bad
good or bad it's just because certain
things you know in this community
certain kind of features or words that
makes them feel better or makes them
look better or things like that and
other languages don't have for example
so least whispers will say oh Marcos
because why because you guys don't have
Marco's I have it this like that any
Emacs for example in Emacs it's a
scratch scratch buffer
it's the email is you know that that
tends to become the identity of the
language in Haskell its monad okay so
but in closure they don't have Marco's
because
because let's see how to how to see
enclosure they don't have you know they
don't
can you define Markos enclosure but III
forgot okay I don't remember I'm not
sure I'm not sure you can define I think
you can but anyway it's not emphasized I
know I know one thing for sure is that
the crosier language they they do not
have a real reader okay in these
languages you have this thing another
like identity crisis thing identity
issue in these languages such as
commonly scheme Mathematica racket okay
new lease I'm not sure about new lease
okay anyway and and and so you Annie Mac
this okay you have this thing called
reader yeah reader it's kind of weird
and complex and okay so reader is kind
of like a parcel
it just passed Parsley's syntax so you
type you know you type this code the
reader you know it's called vido
okay so reader will read it it will turn
that actually into eight some kind of
internal language internal code not bite
by internal list it essentially it turns
it into a list into a bunch of lists
okay list then the compiler read that
okay read that list a bunch of you know
list then the compiler with that and
turn that into either byte code or you
know the machine code okay so so so to
lispers okay like this this is very
idiotic thinking of least you know
because least lispers they have like
they have a different idea of what
syntax me
I have an article about that on least
okay
so you go to our list this is another
one of my thing you know I argued with
this eat these idiots fighting with them
for for over a decade
here list can list mark well change Lisp
syntax this is related to Marcos okay in
this you have the reader thing okay so
anyway I have that article I'm not sure
I want to let's see then let me see the
comments and see where we go after let's
see where we go next
oops not that we went to racket so
actually I want to copy that
so anyway so that's the so you you read
this article anyway let me check the
comments so Justine so so so closure has
limited support of mark oh yeah I think
that's why you know that's why they are
not so good with mark what I know one
thing for sure is that closure they
don't have they don't have for lease
readers okay this this meter thing so
reader is kind of like list passer
it's a passer dedicated to this language
okay every you know all the code you
know all the common least skim this they
all have a reader okay so it's a main
feature of you know these languages so
you have the reader what what the reader
do is I just read your source code you
read your source code and you turn them
into a bunch of lists so for example let
me show you this example
so in this you have this write a B okay
let's say I can write that okay I can
write this okay so I have a quote ' you
know I have a pass trophy then
parentheses a B now this is actually
- equivalent to that okay but the way
they are equivalent is via the reader
okay so so when I type this when I type
this line in lists and I'd run it so
least reader will begin to read my code
when it sees this it change it to that
okay that's what happens in a same way
in the same way when winning at least
when you have a dot B you'll be turned
into cons a B okay so it's a list reader
that's doing this and it has crooks okay
when you study this video as lots of
kooks so so what I was thinking to say
so yeah so so you have this list reader
thing which is kind of odd then so that
so the reader reads your source code it
turns it into basically a bunch of lists
like nested parentheses then they then
compared with reads that then it turns
into machine code or whatever bytecode
but okay and these readers I know in
Common Lisp and I think it's also true
in scheme B's but I don't know it so
well okay I don't know neither of what
them well they the list reader you can
kind of modify so you can actually tell
the reader to read your code differently
okay so so that's why some lists per say
that the list video can't this can
change syntax but actually you cannot
okay that's the topic of my disorder go
it cannot change syntax list cannot
change you are forever stuck with nested
parent you cannot do anything about it
okay I've argued with this with many
whispers they don't know you know argue
by the way whenever I say you know this
list first in my mind
those list phonetics so actually then
they may not be they name may not be the
actual you know average common least
Coda's maybe those are good you know but
my experience came from you know this
handful of this common these phonetics
and so I been arguing with them for over
ten years fifteen years I essentially
you could say I spent 15 years of my
life doing frame work with this list
phonetics and Perl Perl and Python
phonetics
that's how I wasted my life okay yeah
you are right so so so so closure they
don't actually fully I know this for a
fact you know because you know one of
the rich rich Hickey
you know the creator of closure he wrote
a essay you know they don't they do not
fully support that we the list reader
you know the the full-featured list
video you can modify it but not in
closure okay so so that's that's one
thing so so with cheeky so that that is
also the reason a lot commonly Spurs I
know you know I know some common list
phonetics they hate closure you know
they they would characterize closure as
as you know it's not at least you know I
know this this guy for example let me
show you this guy his blog ASCII life
form okay he has a nickname no he is
known as ASCII life form is his okay
this is just such my name
he is a very old I mean he's an old-time
common lisp er but he has a nickname of
ASCII life form I don't know where is
where is his blog
sorry ASCII platform
anyway I can't find it for sure but okay
so no more comments guys so Matt says
let me answer mask questions I recently
saw a talk where language design was a
topic I think it was about the cursive
IDE one point was that when creating a
language the tooling system around it is
very important you know for me I don't
really get idea about tooling you know
the thing about tooling in the world the
terminology tooling and and the
obsession about tooling it like that it
came up like in the past ten years it
wasn't there before
like in in 2000s you don't have you you
almost never hear about the word tooling
there's no such thing a programming
language is just a language that you
don't hear about there's no such concept
about tooling it that came up a lot I
noticed in the past let's say five years
you know programmers will constantly say
Oh tooling something or you need tooling
so so I don't fully get what's that
about
so you talked a lot about syntax okay I
answer that question but I answered that
how would you rank those factors syntax
documentation tooling community that
depends on what's your call for example
now that yeah that really depends on
what's your goal and also it depends on
your language for example community
I mean community is kind of a social
issue so so it's community is almost
separate from the language you know the
technique technicality of a language
almost okay somewhat it also depends so
so how would you rank
factors yeah they really depends on the
person like what do you mean community
like okay so for example if I create a
language and I wanted to be the most
popular possible
that's one of my let's let's say that's
my number one goal I want my language to
be the most popular possible then in
that case I would consider community the
most important between syntax
documentation and tooling community is
the most important because it is the
people that spread your language okay so
this is almost like politics so you know
so that's so community is really nothing
to do with you know the design of a
language is rather about about social
issues you know so if you want
popularity community is the most
important you want to be you better be
sure in that case you need to be a PR
person you need to have tact you'll need
to learn how to talk well you need to
study those books about psychology about
how to convince people yeah you know
position to say nice things
then don't swear okay this
that that's what how you wanna go syntax
documentation tooling that's kind of
less important you can get people to do
it for you okay you just yeah that's one
of the actually that's the most
important thing about making a language
popular of course you do have some kind
of technical maybe you do need some
technical background to start a language
okay but once you then you focus on the
community you you want it to be popular
if that's a goal so you focus on the
community treat people you know become a
leader you have to be a leader ship type
of person okay like when you are unsure
about something you have to pretend yeah
this pretend you are sure you know you
say oh well just do that and be nice
okay so there are many techniques and
styles of leadership you know you could
be your dictator
very you know for example reaches from
he got kicked out now and you know you
can be like Linux Leena's to vote
he's another kind of harsh kind of
leadership you know how she in some way
but not in other ways and then you have
you know social justice kind of leader
or you can look at all the presidents of
the USA or other countries in his
history there are they are quite a lot
of different kind of leadership depends
on how you want to go you know what kind
of person you are but anyway you want to
be popular of your programming language
you be a good leader okay then you build
a great community then people you
basically it is the people that is the
important element not not the technology
you know that's how company works you
know Google Facebook that's how you know
CEO how you become CEO or things like
that so you you know it's a people you
you get people to like you to support
you they will do things for you they
will create they will create you know
tunings great documentation syntax you
know or improve the language you know
that that's kind of that okay so that's
it for today no comments no no
comments okay that's it for today then
thank you guys for watching okay we can
I got less and less people watching it
okay thank you bye guys