good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of talk show
today is 2021 july 20th
3 o'clock in the afternoon san francisco
time
and today we are going to do wufan
language coding
so i'm going to code mathematics so let
me show you some of the
fantastic fulfillment language so i did
this
this is 1990 you know i wrote this
a visual dictionary of special plan
curves
i wrote this code mostly from 1994 to
1997 most of them
so i haven't touched them for like 20
years about 20 years
and today we are going to i'm going to
code some of these
so uh and but first of all let me show
you some
uh news okay emacs news casa live
news good morning emily fantastic emily
the the most technical person in our
group
uh okay so the uh we're gonna do uh
yeah so let me tell you some of the news
i've been working on emacs my emacs
website
and emacs list i've been coding a lot
emac this
in the past month so
so you know there is a lot of things we
i did
uh so what are we so let me uh just go
over
like for 15 minutes something then we're
gonna do muffin language coding
so if you have comments questions post
it okay uh
it's today's like random chat
ish uh emacs so
so i want to go through my emacs blog
tell you what
update i have been doing in the past
month
and interface change and e max distro
okay
so emacs distro let's open that and
okay let me tell you about emacs distro
so about
uh a week ago i did
live live stream creating this
e-max distro so now it's kind of in
shape
so you can just download it and you have
you know a great emac setup
uh you know i'm going to work on this
for years
probably you know this is just just a
start the reason i want to create a
distro
is that you know i create i did a distro
before ergo emax
from 2007 to 2004
okay about seven years and i stopped
uh because no money and you know you
puke blood you work on these several
hours a day and you become
tech support and but but now
my life is better so and uh so i created
this
you know i don't want to create another
distro because i'm just going to be tech
support
then people are just going to talk about
how you do do this old son
imac sucks about imax sucks that you
know they didn't you know
usually kind of okay of course they are
also
good news like people thank you for it
anyway
so now i think it's mature i mean it's
uh
great for me to you know i create a
emacs distro so this distro
so what's a point the the main point
is that it's going to be revolving
around xr flight keys
now soft light keys is probably the most
popular
package i've done and a lot of people
use it
so you know it has a
uh specially designed key binding it's
like
vim but however all the key choices in
command
map are from a efficiency point of view
on the other hand veeam is mostly
historical so
this package has a lot of uses and it
it has you know introduces complete new
key binding system to emacs
but one of the issue is that when you
use lots of other packages such as
augment
org mod or you know the most popular and
also
the magic for
git they have you know they follow the
trade
they cut they follow the traditional
emacs key binding so
if you use those packages you
it's you know it's not compatible so you
go back to when you are in those major
mods you go back
to the you know cumbersome control c
something control something uh keys
so now if i create uh
any and it's not easy to create a key
system for them or for the other major
packages so anyway so the point of start
destroy so
since i now bundle everything together
i can start to you know create key
bindings for the major
mods so in other words ideally
this can end up as a as a systematic
uh keybinding system for emacs in the
future
sometimes you know so and i'm not going
to slave over
it you know i'm not going to just be
tech support and
answer the questions i try my best
uh okay so that's emacs distro
uh that's some emacs distro i did okay
so
that and let's go to xymax blog so
so if you so you know i've been working
on my emacs
web tutorial a lot in the past month so
let me give you a brief introduction to
how to
you know how how this is like so the
main page the home page you have
basically
six major sections uh seven okay
emacs tutorial so just click on them so
you have seven major uh
entry points emacs tutorial which is all
about
learning emacs the you know gnu emacs
then you have emacs in it
it's about is about all the details
about
emacs in it many minor mods what's a
major mod what's a minor mod
what's a ms customized uh
what it how do you organize your you
need file you know one
one of the way there are so many ways uh
by compile list what does that mean
things like that so this
this section is about emacs
initialization
then you have emacs keys uh section
emacs keys so this section is all about
emacs
keys you know emacs the most the
fundamental
part of emacs is the keys uh in fact
that's
the historical origin of emacs techo you
know uh
keyboard markup basically keyboard
marker so as
opposed you know this is interesting
because in other editors
for example this is startup show let's
open uh
let's okay pink window shows all my
commands
uh using soft light keys and roll rack
layout
so i open this uh
where's the command uh
[Music]
where did i just call it yeah because
i'll open in vs code so i open this page
start talk showing vs code uh in so
in many applications in general in other
applications
they are not uh
the way they are coded is not from
it's not centered around key keystrokes
uh this is interesting because emacs is
almost the only one kind of
yeah i would say probably the only one
where it is actually
centered on keystrokes so any so the
first thing
you know you do is keystrokes then
keystrokes
is mapped to command essentially
eventually you call a command
then the command runs do whatever
including
for example one of the interesting
example is for example
so i'm going to type abc
so i'm pressing i just pressed three
keys and
actually those keys are calling the
command let me show you
okay and describe key then press
a you see so then then it tells you
you see you can tell it tells you that a
runs the command self insert command
so even if you are just typing it's
actually calling a command it's calling
this command
so so this is this is different from
any other editors when you type
something
it just you know just you you know you
just insert the character it's not
according to a command to do it
but however when you press a shortcut
like when you hold down ctrl
alt or you know control and command
keys then the applications such as vs
code then they interpret it
then then it maps to a command but emacs
is different so
so so self insert command is the example
let's go back to talk show so let's uh
today's talk show let's insert
the things we talked about okay
self insert command emacs okay so
uh in fact i can you know what if
actually you see
all the commands you see on the pink
window but actually
it's not showing self insert because you
see a b
c d e f g it's not showing anything here
because i actually turned it off
let's turn it back on so to demonstrate
this point
okay good morning comments okay
braveheart
okay so let's uh so you know let's go to
the command
log mod okay so you describe function
[Music]
disrupt function start command log mod
okay so you go to these functions
uh source code so here is the source
code for start command log mod
it will actually just create this ping
window so
it it's calling this command
so you can see the source code is on
email okay i modified it
some myself so here's the source code
and let's
search for self
insert command okay so so here you have
a variable
clm log command exceptions okay
so the value is a list so you can see
your list
so that this list means any command if
it's
any of this command do not
you know log it so you can see
self insert here
uh wait not wait why is it
i want to show self insert okay
uh
but it's already commented that wait
okay so i'm not
okay yeah i know what's going on this is
actually not the file i'm using
uh wait so go to kazaa
emax actually we need to go we need to
talk about mathematica so
let me uh quickly see if i can
so here is command log mod
and let's search for self insert it's
commented out
but why why is it commented out
and search for that again so search for
self insert
uh command log exceptions what's the
difference
clm command log exceptions
okay i have a duplicate copy of it
okay let's show it here so under you
look at the right side so you can see it
okay so look at right side so you can
see
actually i have two copies of it oh okay
oh there it is yeah so because i'm
you know i i modified this uh
file and i let's comment the whole thing
out
i've been sloppy so i have a duplicate
so this
is the part so you can see self insert
command is
you know it's there so it doesn't show
but now let's show it okay
now second so let's go back to let's
comment that out then
let's set it evaluated
and now if i open a new buffer and
magnify
if i start to type a b c d e f g
you can see self
insert command seven times you can
see self insert command so
so that's the that's that's a demo of
how emacs is
the implementation is of emacs is very
much
uh keystroke based okay
uh i believe that's uh not the case for
basically any application
any other so but i want to show you
another demonstration for example
if you um if you type
fee let's say pi okay
let's say you see
we got the pi so you can actually
you can actually bind
a command to that character
you see it's okay i
let me say this it's actually not key
based it's character based okay
it's character based yeah that's more
appropriate so
any other modern application they are
keystroke
uh they are keystroke based you can say
that but emacs is actually
character based but what if you do when
you do control
f or something that is actually also a
character it's a ascii character
but what if you press uh you know let's
say
backspace key that's not a character
well backspace is actually a character
um let's say function key f f5
uh anyway i'm getting i'm getting um
anyway you can it's it's a character
based okay let me explain
let me let me show you this uh
demonstration okay i can i can
actually bind a key to this character so
uh global set key okay uh
let's go to xr emacd smart global set
key okay so
so i want the character whenever i type
the character pi
you should do something okay let's see
let's see
open a new window okay let's say split
okay so
what's the command for split okay so
whenever i type the character pi tell
emacs to call the command split window
below okay
now evaluate it now i'm going to um
let's see how can i uh let's see let me
try paste okay i don't think
paste works pie okay
um
i want to demonstrate this but now i'm
running into a problem how do i actually
type it
so i don't think this work neither
yeah okay let's let's try a brief okay
uh i have an example on my website but
but but
let's not use my website if we can avoid
it
so let's say p
p i equals to let's say pii
okay pii equals to pi
okay evaluated so i just defined a brief
so now let's type p i
i enter okay that doesn't work
so i mean what we want is that for emacs
to split
window below whenever you type pi
yeah that's that doesn't work so
yeah okay so okay that's a too fancy
example but actually we can show another
example let's say
let's say dollar sign okay so evaluate
that
now i'm going to type dollar sign and it
splits window okay
this is not a um
this is not the best best example to
demonstrate that emacs is actually
character-based
character-based owed the way back to its
taco roots yes
and emily showed me taco yeah
yes emily also showed me uh you know she
dig into taco
and she actually installed it
on a emulator and read the manuals and
demonstrated
some very interesting things
okay so so let's uh okay that's about pi
so let's i mean that's about that so
let's cut that
let's uh remove that i don't want that
close my
brief close that let's go to back to
talk show and
let's again
hide the self insert command in command
log mod
close it save it close it close it
close it close it yes close it
and back in talk show and paste it here
okay pretty fine and showing browser
okay i've been talking for how long
22 minutes okay let's i'm gonna get to
mathematica in
uh just about ready okay so
emacs tutorial so then emacs init then
you have everything about emacs keys
then you have practical emac lisp
tutorial
then you have emac list examples then
more emac this and this section is about
how to write a major mod
so it's kind of a bit more advanced in
emaclis
so that's the main seven sections of
of my emacs website
now so i i worked on a lot of it before
like before today
you will see lots of uh the
main emacs tutorial section on the side
panel you will see a lot
rockets symbol okay so where is the
rocket symbol let me show you okay
well yes you will see a lot of items
here
that is my custom emac list code to
enhance emacs
but i i moved them now to the elise
examples section so
you know there are about 20 of them i
moved here
so this way i hope it's more clear
so that when you people read the emacs
tutorial here you are just learning the
the fundamentals of gnu emacs but when
you are
you know when you want to extend your
emacs to make it more efficient and so
on you can go to the emac these
these examples so everything here is
emac this code so let's see so for
example like
so open file fast direct sort file by
time or by size
uh rename file space to hyphen just
press one key
and a file isn't it let's let me show
you that okay so for example i
i create a new file something
this that okay
something this that copy that save it
something this that dot txt okay
so you can see the file and i dive into
the directory this is the file
magnify now you see there's a space
i want to change them to underscore so i
all i have to do is press one key
press it then the file is changed
normally otherwise normally you would
have to call
let's hide the details okay wait high
detail is
a left parenthesis so normally if i want
to change the file name of this file you
have to call
this command dial toggle toggle read
only
see then then you can
change okay you know you can change that
basically you call
query replace space by underscore
enter wait i typed it wrong space
by underscore enter yes yes yes
okay so once you are done
then you press cc to call
right direct finish edit okay
then the file name is changed
yeah but now but now i can just press
you know with
with this rename file you know space to
hyphen low line command i can just press
one single key
so saving key strokes is all these
uh always about okay so let's open that
deleted we don't need this file refresh
so it's automatically
deleted and also made the backup so
that's another command you'll find here
so that's um
so that's uh that's these okay so
let me show you some examples i search
current word okay i search current word
this is an
enhanced command to search the word
under cruiser
now emacs also has that but actually
it's not so good because
i explained search text
so this section is all you everything
you want to know about
search text in current buffer or
find and replace in kernel buffer or
in the in your directory okay so this
section
all the details you can read about
or highlight text uh and
you know so you can search current word
but however you know emacs got you so
you use these commands to search uh
current words
i search forward symbol at point the
default
key is alt s then dot
but one of the problem is that it checks
boundary
that means if you have a text with x y 2
and you try to search x y the x y 2 will
not show up
because you know the two is kind of the
boundary
so this version the emax version is
useful if you are coding
you know in programming languages you
kind of sometimes it's useful that way
but most of the time
for me at least when i search something
i want everything every string that
contains that those characters i don't
want
you know checking boundaries so that is
why
you have you know this command i search
current world
okay and so on so that's what i worked
on
uh in past month uh especially
you know yesterday uh i walked on
you know and also yeah something some
interesting things i updated
you see this screenshot this screenshot
must be
um this screenshot is about 10 years old
you know i updated a lot of screenshots
to
you know usually it doesn't matter
because emacs is still the same
exactly the same but however you know
just for change sometimes you want you
know so now you i have new screenshots
now before it was you know this is uh
on linux around this is 2010 or
something
and now
for example i have it on windows and
some of the old screenshot is on mac
for example uh you know so let me show
you
the interesting screenshot because
that's interesting okay
uh so okay so you need to go to
[Music]
e-max go to diet go up directory
and go to this directory unused okay
this is unused images okay so
now you open them
showing desktop okay that's a command
then you can see
you know this is on a mac this must be
12 years
old screenshot and this is
on windows vista this must be 2009 or
something
and you know it's interesting because
when you look at your old screenshots
you'll notice
uh the minor differences in
changes in emacs for example today it
doesn't say like that it
the wording changed a bit
then you have this screenshot is on
linux
and this one on the mac um
yeah this must be 2007 or something
uh you know another one on linux you
know interesting
yeah so also here this is the menu from
emacs diode okay the ed you
notice that the keystrokes are in
parenthesis
not not any longer so
we are in diet let's look at you know
let's see
mark okay mark menu
you see the key strokes are no longer in
parentheses and they are right aligned
so it's
actually better slightly
okay so that's some of the random talk
oh and this screenshot is new okay they
updated
and this screenshot is also uh seven
years old you know i haven't been using
linux for
like seven years so every time you see
my linux screenshot those are at least
seven years old
okay i want to and also in linux i
have you know used different uh desktop
windows managers so some of them are in
x
f x d f c x f c
you know i don't i even get the wrong
name
uh names wrong and some of them are in
different um
you know systems anyway let's not
let's forget about that so i let's talk
about
wufam language okay so i want to do
yeah so it's just random coding okay so
i'm not going to
so there's no plan i'm just going to do
some
live coding of wolfram language
you know just show something interesting
maybe
okay so that's what i've been doing with
emacs okay that's enough about
emacs okay so let's do
let's go to woofam language okay let's
do the visual special dictionary of
playing curves the famous
emily yes uh
yes so yeah good morning fuzzing
so so let's do some
uh mathematics uh wolfen language okay
so let's go to what is this
emacs blog close close close the
directory
what is this talk show close go to
e-blog
no let's go to desktop
uh go to documents okay open external
so wufam language see so let's open that
uh you know i don't know what i want to
do i just know i want to update
some you know start to code these
um so let's see
let's pick something so you know you are
looking at the directory this directory
is basically
half of my will most of my wolfram
language
uh mathematical packages for example
let's look at plane titling
so that's plain titling package so this
you know this is pretty old
so 1998 i wrote this and last update
2016 uh not really i
you know i didn't really work on it so
2016 i only worked on it for two days
because um
so you see this package draw
you know you can just say wallpaper plot
and give it
a number and it will plot it and you can
you can say how many uh how many uh
copies of it
uh you know
so what i need to do is actually i need
to update you know to make these
compatible with the latest version of
wolfram language
in fact i think you know if i just try
to run the code so you can see here is
more fancy
wolfram language code you got fractions
and so on
and here is the illustration of all the
17 wallpaper groups so this
is part of group theory these things are
called group
wallpaper groups okay they are just
called wallpaper groups you can just
look up on wikipedia so there are
illustrations of their fundamental
region
and their symmetry points so what so
what
so what they what are they exactly you
you see when you have a
carpet or when you have a yeah exactly a
carpet or a tire padding on the floor
you see there are many symmetries so
mathematicians can
study it and can create a specification
for the symmetry of a particular pattern
so it turns out the total number of
possible you know cement symmetry the
way they are symmetric is only 17
for wallpaper groups so once so so you
know mathematicians give you
uh gives them an id for each of the
symmetry
groups okay so since we are talking
about
that let's go to let me show you this uh
this uh thing this project
i did like 23 years ago
1997. uh this is one of my most
cited uh page you know uh
project okay so the the 17 wallpaper
groups okay
so mathematicians has a given notation
overflow notation this is invented by
zhong
kongwei john houghton conway who
died two years ago due to covet
you know one of the mathematicians died
one of the early early person died
from covet so he you know he's a
mathematician he
you know i admire his work uh
so he's an overflow notation
is a notation to describe each and every
of the 17
possible wallpaper groups you know
similar to symmetry
so each so so then you have the
crystallographic notation this is
more traditional so what's what's the
difference you see
the crystallographic notation is kind of
mnemonic based
uh you know so you know it it will take
some time to explain but anyway
so why did why did conway invented the
overflow
notation the overflow notation is
because
this notation gives you know just by
reading
you know their identification just by
reading their name
they give more information about
the symmetry of that type okay so that's
why the overflow notation
but the crystallographic notation is
already well
established by you know useful uh
useful used increased crystallographic
you know that that's essentially the
analysis of crystals okay
so for example you know anything i'm
talking about you can go to wikipedia
wikipedia has
you know tremendous information
crystallography basically is the
classification
and identification of crystals crystals
such as
quartz or in snowflakes and you know
sugar structure things like that i don't
know much about
them condensed metal physics okay so you
know so here is
kind of illustration of what they are
like about you know
basically the structures and this is a
3d
case now when we talk about wallpaper
groups
that's a 2d case so let me show you so
these here are the 17 wallpaper groups
um or paper gallery okay so
so first first of all let me show you
the 17 possible wallpaper groups
so you are looking at a example
of each of the possible wallpaper
group you know in other words you each
of these wallpapers represent a specific
symmetry type so you can see here's a
wallpaper
so what defines a wallpaper essentially
it's a something that repeats
okay a pattern you know on a floor that
repeats
and mathematicians has to classify how
how are they symmetric
so this one and then you see this
diagram
this diagram illustrates how
it is symmetric of this wallpaper okay
so you can see another one where is my
okay
next let's go to next
so here's another one uh here's another
one
so this one you have a red line double
line there that means there's a
there's a mirror reflection symmetry
you see you see there's a mirror
reflection on each of the line
but there is no vertical reflection you
know then then you also have this
uh that l-shaped thing that means it's
um
it's a translational symmetry okay that
means you can move
part of it and move forward a bit then
the whole thing is
exactly the same just repeat
okay so then you know then you have
several others so you have this
now you have this kind of thing now this
kind of thing you know
you know one way to put it to to explain
it is like footsteps
footprint so you know like when you walk
on a sand
you have this kind of symmetric pattern
so and again there are 17 possible
you know 17 possible symmetry patterns
no more and no less
that's how mathematician proved it and
so in my project
i have some i give you some i proved
part of it okay uh so derivation and
classification of groups
okay so
yeah then then you get prettier then
then you started to see some of the more
prettier
uh patterns symmetries okay now in all
these
examples what i use is i use this
a star you know a five-pointed star
to to demonstrate all the 17 possible
patterns
so each one of them oh you see the motif
is just a single
uh one or more stars five pointed stars
so again you can go to wikipedia
wallpaper groups
then they have you know lots of other
examples
so i so you know so all these are done
with mathematica you know
this is so you know you run this code
and you will generate
uh you know this illustration and uh
okay too much uh you know you know i
wanted to actually code
i haven't you know started to code with
questions so i just
explained the whole thing so is it um
any comments uh
but i've got my server turned off yes
emily
uh sounds crystal clear to me
very much reminds me of researching
tessellations
and patterns associated yeah i'm very
much into this and uh you know
i'm kind i feel i you know i kind of i'm
getting old
but one of these states if i wish to i
want to you know
revisit uh okay let me show you some of
the patterns okay
for example so you
you you see you can you can generate
these
islamic titles by
you know by giving basically by giving
one pattern a fundamental you know you
can see the illustration here you can
just find the geometry you know the
locations for each of these points and
just
draw that then you can call one of the
commands to generate the entire
wallpaper
and you can also generate random ones
you know you
you pick a specific symmetry um
id then you just say okay use this path
pattern and generate a symmetry of that
uh then you know so
this i did this long ago i
i want to uh i'm interested and i i want
to write them in javascript as well and
first of all i need to update this
woofam language code
i've been delaying them so
yeah so these are very interesting so
you know so i haven't
you know i so the question to myself is
that should i
you know actually start to code some you
know code ufam language or start to
talk about the mathematics of it instead
you know let's let me just talk
mathematics about it
you know some something about it because
if i start to code wufang language i'm
not
you know really ready you're gonna see a
lot stumbling
and stuff so patterns you know so
study of symmetry there they are quite a
lot very
interesting things uh about it
not just wallpaper groups okay so
yeah so let me give you uh you know
like non-professional account of the
interesting things about
symmetry and symmetry groups group
theory
and titling theory and patterns theory
and so on you know related things
okay
uh
but before we do anything about that
yeah there's quite a lot of interesting
things because you there there is also
um
there is also uh okay look at this one
this is a fractal base okay
this is uh fantastic
you know in language everything is uh
scalable it's a
post script you know the image behind it
is actually
encoded in postscript so it can scale to
any size
so this one you know you might be
wondering so first of all you know we
talked about
so we will be we have been talking about
the um
wallpaper groups right which is the
classification
of the two-dimensional symmetry patterns
now you can go into so
that so it's part of the study of
crystallography
and you can go to into three dimension
of course crystals are in three
dimension
uh in three dimension i believe the
possible symmetry groups
there are 270 okay
wikipedia will say it somewhere okay i
believe there are
270 of them and
it it is my dream since like 20 years
ago
to actually write a program to visualize
the 270 possible quiz 3d crystallography
groups that would be amazing especially
in today's technology you know game you
guys gave gamers you know 3d games
you can do that so imagine you can fly
you know in a three-dimensional space
you can fly through
uh any of the quick you know 270
possible crystal crystallographic
groups in 3d so i wanted to do that
i just never get to uh
i hope i will do it you know soon
someday
so 3d case okay so as far as i know i
have not seen
yeah i don't i don't ever you know even
although i haven't looked
for the past like 15 years but i have
never seen someone actually do it
so here's a you know a project you guys
you know you guys young people might do
it
write a program just like you know the
2d case but
but rather 3d case so people can fly
through
uh each of the 270 um
uh crystallographic 3d groups what's the
proper name let's search the
proper name okay
i want to
group symmetry so periodic space group
okay so it's called
space groups yeah so that you know we
talked about wallpaper groups but they
are
quite a lot very much related things
okay yeah so
you can see all the highlighted here
they are all related okay
now point group it's very interesting
let's open that
space group very interesting let's open
that okay hold on a second
let's magnify okay go back
then symmetry group that's kind of
related okay
but let's not open that that's a crystal
graphic
point group then crystal graphic group
okay those are very interesting things
okay
now point group uh
yeah so you you started to see the point
group symmetries okay
so what's the difference between point
group and the wallpaper group
or the 3d crystallographics group well
essentially point group is only
considered a point
so for example when we have wallpapers
here
you know these patterns they are not
points but
if the only possible figure is allowed
is just one single point
then what are the possible symmetries in
2d or in 3d
you know or in 4d you know they can go
on to higher dimensions
4d 5d 7d higher dimensions
so if you allow the motif to be just a
point
then what are the possible you know
symmetry groups
that's a that's that's a point group
okay let's let's read it
just to double check in geometry a point
group is a group
of geometric symmetries that keep at
least one point fixed
okay uh
okay these okay i might be wrong point
groups can exist in a euclidean space
with any dimension
and every point group in dimension d is
a subgroup
of orthonormal orthogonal
uh group okay point groups can be
realized a set of
orthogonal matrices m that transform
point
x to point y so uh that keeps at least
one point fixed
did i get it wrong cairo and cairo so
you know i
okay i think i might be wrong in my
explanation what i was talking about
what i was talking about is actually
lattice groups
you know i don't know i don't know you
know so don't read
don't take my word for it read wikipedia
meanwhile i think the point group is
just um
basically you just have one point in the
center
uh okay so this goes on but you know i
can i can know for sure if i take five
more minutes to read it
let's not okay point group is very
interesting then space group okay yeah
so this is very interesting space group
symmetry
so you know one of you as a project
go write a program in maybe javascript
or in wufang language you can download
it you can use rootham language
that would be easier that would be 10
times easier
or but the problem if you use them
language to
to write this program the problem is
that you cannot
you know you you require the wolfram uh
engine to run but however most you know
it would be nice to play this as a game
like you can tell other people to go to
your website
and and fly through fly through this
three-dimensional space with this
symmetry structures so that's
interesting in order to do that you can
use javascript
webgl uh you know that's that's probably
the
easiest way or you can if you know about
programming games you can use a game
engine i believe that's possible yes
since we are talking about euclidean
space so
i would you know that's that would be my
dream okay that would be
my dream for 20 years someone you guys
okay emily
emily would be the best most suitable
candidate
oh justin scarfi justin scarfa is a
mathematician a professional
mathematician
are you a in fact he's a professor right
well i haven't seen you for a long time
how are you so justin scott
scarface but justine justine is not a
coder okay
so so one of you guys or maybe bot okay
one of you guys read the program you
know again engine okay
unreal engine you know there's lots of
game engines you know
i don't know how to i tried uh you know
but
you go write a game engine you know
write a
uh you know programming in game engine
use using webgl whatever whatever
to fly through a quick
uh space group structure
of order 270 230 okay so
it says here how many uh there
are space group okay in math physics and
chemistry a space group
is a symmetry group of a configuration
in space
right usually in three dimensions okay
in three dimensions there are 219
distinct
types or 230 if cairo copies are
considered
distinct okay cairo that's another very
interesting
uh concept basically it's a left right
mirror okay
uh space groups are also studied in
dimensions other than three
where they are sometimes called uh
bieber back
groups and are discrete
compact groups of isometries of an
oriented euclidean space okay
fascinating
this group theory that's what i love
okay
uh unfortunate you know
math math is my true love but
she has been difficult
[Laughter]
okay then there you see the overthrow
notation we
talked about let's open it so reading
wikipedia is what we do
you know in geometry overflow notation
is a system or overflow
signature is a system invented by
mathematician william thurston
and promoted by john conway oh it's not
it's invented by william thurston oh
okay
uh two for representing types of
symmetry groups
in two-dimensional spaces of constant
curvature okay
that's the detail so so you have
wallpaper groups we talked about
you know in you know 20 years ago my
website is
almost the only one that talk about this
then
wikipedia becomes better and better and
better and you know
wikipedia now has lots of examples
and explanation in detail so you can see
actual
patterns in real world demonstrating
some of these symmetries okay uh
you know and there are other sites that
you know photographs of actual tiles on
the floor or carpet
and things like that so
wikipedia you know go check it out so
they also have a diagram similar to mine
uh but i didn't invent it of course i
read it
somewhere else in the literature you
know this diagram is used to illustrate
the symmetry
of a wallpaper group pattern
so yeah so you those of you
interested in math you might want to
check it out very interesting wallpaper
symmetry groups okay
overflow notation symmetry groups then
crystallographic
point group so point group is what i'm
we have been talking about
yeah uh yeah exactly that's what i was
trying to explain about point groups
okay so there you have it then you have
uh space groups we talked about why is
it two
oh yeah yeah so crystal graphic group is
the same as space group
it's a alias okay it's the same thing
okay so that's about that okay
uh screw makes you smarter okay
so we talked about an hour maybe that's
it
so oh yeah so back to the
interesting things about related to
these uh
wallpaper groups or you know the
patterns patterns and symmetry and
titlings
there are so many theories from
different aspects okay
so we talked about the the symmetry
group
basically pattern symmetry groups of you
know two-dimensional space three-minute
space and higher and also we talked
about if we
if we do not allow shapes but just
points
what happens to the possible symmetries
okay
so there are different considerations so
that's why you have also
you have all these kind of uh groups in
math okay
now uh of course you know you guys go
read my page okay since i'm like you
know read
this read uh my page introduction
uh this is real math okay this is real
mathematics you
consider it undergraduate you know third
year or something
then theorems about rotations in
translation in a plane
uh then the
discontinuous groups okay then
uh you learn some of the concept
fundamental region and
what the symmetry means isometry and so
on
uh translation reflection transitivity
of translation that's a theorem
then two-fold rotation on midpoint of a
lattice
okay that's um and what and and by the
way there's a theorem okay there's a
theorem
for example there's a question is it
possible
you know you see all sort of patterns in
you know in tithing or stuff have you
ever seen one
that's five-fold rotational symmetry
you know so this is six-fold you know
that means you this is three-fold
actually you see those triangles so you
rotate it
you rotate it by
by 120 degrees you know one third of a
clock
then you you repeat the pattern
and there are also uh so this so this
one is
has many six-fold rotational symmetry
now
the question is two mathematicians have
you ever seen is it possible
to have a pattern that's a five-fold
rotational symmetry you know like a
pentagon
you know so mathematicians try to do
that so it turns out no it's not
possible
uh and then you can read about
why you can prove it is impossible
uh from this theorem okay theorem
crystallographic
restriction okay that's the name
uh you can see the proof and i believe
there's a wikipedia
article i believe yeah crystal graphic
restriction theorem okay so they also
explain it here uh
you know lots of math then you have okay
higher dimensions okay they will
they actually go into higher dimensions
okay
so apparently it's not possible in
higher dimensions neither
so there's a lot of math you know yeah
uh that's why
i love math okay math
so um so what i want to say is
that yeah so the symmetry of a pattern
in n dimensions that's one thing we've
so far talked about
let's talk about some other interesting
interesting things then that'll be it
10 more minutes maybe
comments okay comments guys
so let's talk about um
you know if i'm being too repetitive
just say it okay
like tell me like say whatever you are
interested in justin
uh justin scarfi say something how is
canada going
how is your health
okay so i want to say uh so yeah so
symmetry symmetry aspect that's one
interesting thing let me talk about some
uh many you know other interesting
uh things okay so for example this one
so if you look at this pattern uh this
pattern okay let's go show mathematica
so if you look at this pattern
first of all we can analyze this pattern
by symmetry just we did before
so if you are a mathematician you look
at this you can say oh
so there is a symmetry point right here
that's a six-fold rotational symmetry
and also right here there's a vertical
line
mirror symmetry there's also you know
basically there are six
lines of vertical symmetry mirror
symmetry right reflection symmetry okay
on each of this point then on here
same thing so so you can see on this
pattern
if we go back to the you know on this
pattern if we go back to
wallpaper groups you can you know we can
we can
we can find out what the symmetry it is
let's see is it this one
okay that's only okay that's six-fold so
it's probably that one
then in the middle it's three-fold
it's like okay this one doesn't have
reflection or symmetry
okay so it's not this one this one
okay so so we are saying that this
pattern
probably has the symmetry of this one
now that's homework okay you you look
into detail
check if this pattern is the symmetry of
that one okay
now you can find that one on my website
here some
somewhere here
here this one okay there is a ui out
there
um yeah so
okay so from the symmetry point of view
but
you can you know that's one interesting
perspective aspect
but then another point of view is that
this
the way this graphics is generated
is actually by uh by what you call
by fractal means okay by nesting by by
what's the proper name is uh
called um i forgot
yeah what's the name lfs
systems um
iterated function systems ifs
systems okay it's kind of uh it's a
fractal okay
or you can also do it by turtle graphics
you know the with the logo
programming language which made the
concept of turtle graphics
famous okay so let's go to we
you know let's let me just show you some
of the
okay turtle graphics uh okay they also
came to python
but it was made famous by the
programming language
called logo logo is a dialect of lisp
invented by a lisp expert
okay he he's in berkeley um
i did heap yeah he's in berkeley but
anyway he
so he created a lisp variant
but without a parenthesis called logo
and the intention of the logo
programming language
is to teach children about programming
but essentially it's a lisp okay
so i want to go to turtle graphics
wikipedia so
so this is in 1980s okay logo
programming language
so they made the logo graphics turtle
graphics very popular
okay so you basically you
you have a turtle that basically your
pen you say where you know which
direction to go
when to you know not draw you know
things like that
uh yeah l systems okay the the name
yeah the name i'm trying to think of is
our systems okay so you can see
a lot of math is going on here so l
systems uh
linda male system you know it's a system
to generate
iterative uh graphics originated from
the study of plants
uh basically you know you guys
programmers would be
interested in this because it's
essentially based on recursion okay
you skim these fans recursion okay
uh you know so you can generate you know
you can see all these
uh then it's really you know then you
can study the graph
the fractal dimension of these uh images
uh that's more advanced math concept
okay don't ask me any math because i
don't
i'm not that good
okay so but i want to show you some the
some of the
uh other another things i've done long
ago okay so let's go to my website let's
just go to cassandra math
okay some math go to my home page
then let's go to the math
software okay so open math software so
these
are fantastic all sort of software doing
uh visual mathematics okay i mean
beautiful and fun to use math
softwares with high
uh real math this is not for children
like typically you see
for example you see people talk about
math usually it's for children
and it's idiotic squares triangles so
you put this triangle here
that's idiotic okay what you see here
is beautiful it's fun it's easy to use
and it embodies
uh real math you know the
advanced phd mathematics okay many of
them embody the
you know there's a lot to study about
them for example
here you have go you have you know you
have go you have 3d go
on different topology
background then you have hex so you
getting into game theory depending on
how
how deep you want to go you know you
have chinese game theory okay
game theory and algorithmic um
zero sum uh games you know algorithms to
to play games you know
or ai depending on how far you go you
know you can create a neural networks to
play these games
of course google did it three years ago
uh breakthrough
they you know ai beat humans in playing
go
so that's one thing good book you know
so
similar for others they are not math for
example
before i talked about flying through
three dimensional structures
okay here is one of search program
written by
jeff weeks okay jeff weeks is a
mathematician he studied
cosmology he's a cosmology specialist
and he has written books okay the shape
of the space i
have this book you know i read it like
in the 1990s mostly uh
great books okay go buy it so i but i
want to say
uh shape of space let's turn on
javascript
so that we have um
okay then you know this is actually a
program so you can go to his website and
download it okay it's available for
windows mac and linux
okay shape of of space this is pretty
old 20 years ago and he has updated
uh ever since curve you know
basically you know is so you know
normally we are familiar with
euclidean space that is flat
you know like just like a piece of paper
euclidean space
you know we imagine it's just straight
it's not like curved
you know it's not like a flag so it's
straight it
goes through infinite dimensions and in
three-dimensional space
we have normally intuitively we think of
our space
euclidean meaning is just flat you know
you can go in any direction
you know infinite direction you know
further away
but it turns out
mathematician discovered it's actually
there are different type
different topology different shape of
our space
so but it's very it's impossible to
imagine
so here you have a curved spaces in 3d
okay all these are three-dimensional you
know in math you have the dimensionality
2d 1d 3d 456
then you have more complex more complex
concept of fractal dimension or infinite
dimension
but anyway given a dimension you have a
geometry okay you have a topology you
have a geometry so
here in this program we are talking
about three-dimensional space
you know just like uh our world but
actually
they show you different shapes you know
actually there are different shapes
some are so weird that if you go
straight forward you will come back to
yourself
you know you know if you live in one of
the search uh
you know three-dimensional space if you
have a if you have a
infinite powered binocular or telescope
you'll see back of your head
you know so that's a topology of
uh space okay we i actually i rambled
over
i wanted to show you the
uh fractals okay the
we get back to tidying okay so yeah
fractal curves and
l systems so these are these programs
are old actually
yeah these are old 1990s mac os
programs now you know i removed the link
uh but you can still find the link in
uh where did i you know in old map
software here i believe
okay these are you know i've been
obsessive about this kind of software
since 1990s
and i kept i kept updating them but
essentially i stopped around 2005.
uh so many of these programs are dead or
old or no longer maintained
so i put them into this page you know
some of the a lot of them are java
you know but java no longer runs on the
web
although you can it's still possible to
get them to run
so there are many of them titins or for
um
you know some of them some of them are
mac or some
anyway so i want to say
i want to say yeah back to so that's all
i want to show i wanted to show you
these uh l systems okay
uh the best source to study them is
beginning with wikipedia so just go to
wikipedia i showed the article before
our systems this this this page okay
um so so that's what i'm saying so this
image aside from the
symmetry point of view you can also
study
you know as a fractal you know the our
systems
um for example how many possible ways to
create this image
or exactly what is the you know the way
i
i coded this is by line transform
you know so actually
let's see let's see the code okay gp
where's
gp okay there it is
so i begin with
this grid okay then so this grid is just
several a bunch of lines
then for each line i transform them into
this
kind of shape then after several uh
after three steps of recursion that's
what you get
so you know it's fun and interesting
so facto so so so l systems uh
recursion and generation you know that's
another
uh way to look at a pattern a
two-dimensional pattern
another way to look at two-dimensional
pattern
is from a tithing uh perspective
so so uh
titlings okay so
timing gallery okay so how do you uh how
do we
discuss about that for example you have
all sort of
uh toggle contrast so you have all sorts
of tidings
and let's see if we can actually you can
magnify that so
tidings so when you think about tilings
they are not just
um symmetry of course
for each one of these image or titling
you can consider the symmetry aspect and
identify
you know which one is it but there is
also
theories about tidings for example let's
see let's show
example for example this one this one
is made this pattern is made
up of a single shape you see this
triple arrow so you have this this is
called prototype okay
so if you have imagine actual tile
you can you know or you can use paper
and cut it
so you can use this one single shape to
tile the plane
so the question is what are other shapes
that tie off the plane
somehow is it so oh another way to say
it is that
given a shape how do you know it's going
to tire the plane or not
so you have to do math you know you have
to start to create
theories of math
so and that's another very deep topic
okay
tightening and patterns uh and and and
this one is another thing
so this for this one this pattern for
example you can look at it from a
symmetry perspective
you can also look at from a tightening
perspective
so if you look at from a tiny per
perspective you see you know so the
white thing is a tile
then this rhombus shape that's another
tile
then this this you have like
these three different tiles of the same
same shape
colored red okay then you know you don't
think of them
as links rather you think of them as
separate pieces
so then you think about the titling
aspect
but another aspect here is linkages so
you know when we look at this we
naturally
think of you know the red are just
actually
a circle you know it's a link of a
particular shape
so when you think about them as linkages
then that's another
theory that's not theory and uh you know
not theory and linkages link theory
uh they're very interesting okay so
let's show
another one you know
[Music]
okay that's that's about that okay
i think that's it for today
how many people are watching night
people
um okay we're gonna stop
after five minutes okay let me run
let me run the mathematica code to see
if they actually run okay so i haven't
been running this for
a long time let's run it
so let's
so first of all okay so
i want to go to the top
uh this is my p.o box that's like 20
years old dead
like like 10 years 15 years dead
so you let's try run it okay plane
tiring
run it run
do you want to automatically evaluate no
cannot open plain tiding okay
okay so it cannot open let's run let's
open this one
okay so here is the source code
let's show you
so this is comment all these are common
then here you begin to have source code
unprotect something
and unprotect symbols so again wufam
language is just like
lisp okay so unprotect means
why do i want to unprotect because just
in case
i already evaluated these so i want to
because actually i protect them later
yeah you can see the code down
you can see all these code protect
protect protect means
do not allow any change
to these symbols definition that's what
protect is
so if someone run the code then
they will not be able to modify you know
or redefine let's say star motif
or translate 2d graphics you know they
will not be able to
but if they want to
load this package again for some reason
then you need to unprotect them you know
because you know
in order to uh make change to them so
anyway
so here's a code then you have letters
called the nuts then you have
let's let's let's show some of the
uh main code okay let's show some
interesting code
so here we begin to see some interesting
code
let's shrink okay let's
shrink so we can see
[Music]
okay that's too big
okay so anyway i
want to do no code okay
this is a package let's run it
oh okay so is there any error
fantastic no arrow this is 15 years old
and no error
wait is that true oh fantastic
now i can run these pretty graphics okay
um let's try this
do it oh let's try this first of all
let's delete the image okay
delete it run it
my code works okay let's try some
variation okay
let's change the parameter okay we want
to try some variation
plot point let's say 16 okay 16 is a
different type of symmetry
do it there you have it
so so in this example
the motif is a l-shaped thing
and now we are generating two different
wall paper with it so let's try 15 okay
then it's gonna be something different
let's try
nine okay
okay so there it is
uh let's try this one okay this one was
interesting beautiful now let's try 16.
let's uh let's put it code here
16 okay do it oh wait
do it oh okay
16 then you got that
then let's make it more copies plot
point
uh 99
okay so let's see what we got
okay interesting okay anyway the code
runs fantastic that's it for today thank
you guys for watching
uh woofen seems to be the opposite of
python it just works
even after decades with python you never
know
that's true yeah what you know it's one
of the things wolfram
7 stephen wolfe is very proud of you
know he he would say
you know my language after 30 years is
still the version one code still runs
mostly yeah vast majority of it
true because in order to do that you
have to you know in order for this to
happen
you know we are talking about language
design you have to
be very careful you have to have like
a very good vision yeah
he which he does you have to have a very
good vision in what
you want in your language and also
in wufang language there are some
you know let's say there are some
advantages i mean
i mean he's because when you do
high level when you design a high level
language very
very very high level language then
it's more possible to have a language
that does not
change after 10 20 30 years
okay but if you are doing low level
language that's more difficult
okay uh yeah
okay so
so i demonstrated my code you know it
still runs
and uh what uh is there anything else
um you know so for example this one is
illustration of the you know of the
of of one of the symmetry you know a
hexagon means
at that point there's a six-fold
rotational symmetry
a rhombus means there is two-fold
rotational symmetry there
and a double line means there's a mirror
symmetry
a triangle means there's a three-fold
rotational symmetry
so if we change this to 16
let's see a different you know there so
this is
type 16 there is no mineral symmetry
uh okay so that works great i'm actually
very happy i'm quite happy my code still
works
yeah that's it for today so
that's uh oh that's close to 90 minutes
okay
so thank you guys for watching bye guys
oh yeah last thing i want to mention uh
wolfram language is
free okay so you just go to
just just search for the
farmland okay then you go to
my page and you go down
i have several videos and tutorials more
focused
on teaching you wolfram language
mathematica
which i did two months ago 203
then you have uh wufam language download
for free
you know just go to this page it's free
okay the engine is free
then i want to
i want to uh yeah so i started to write
a tutorial
you know it's it's a mess i haven't done
yet
but i started to write a tutorial for
wolfen language
great thank you bot and thank you guys
for coming bye
oh now i have 14 people watching