Hi guys.
I think I'm alive.
Live or alive?
Let's see how many people are watching.
Zero. That's good.
So what I'm going to talk about?
Okay. Start my Emacs blog.
Start my programming blog.
Now there's something
where I I wait for people to come in.
You know, basically if you have a
question, just ask me.
And what I want to say is, okay, so I
have been doing videos in the past few
you know, few months actually.
And
you know, when you look at yourself, you
realize something, you know, that's a
interesting thing to do actually.
You know, you can
you know, record yourself actually, you
know, if you never streamed before, you
know, actually you can try it or you
know, do a video and you watch yourself,
then you learn something about yourself
actually.
For example, one thing I learned is
that, you know, in my life
I'm pretty much a
pretty face and you know, like kind of
elite person.
You know, like I'm above average in, you
know, intelligence and you know, I like
to, you know, I wanted to be the
greatest mathematician, but not just
that. When I was younger, I also wanted
to be the greatest pianist, the greatest
juggler, and uh um
Yeah, and also a millionaire. Oh, you
know, like today, million millionaire is
like a dime a dozen, you know, because
you know, money inflation, you know, you
know, money increases, and also the
opportunity increases has increased a
lot.
But anyways, so when I was younger, I
was very ambitious.
And uh you know, I'm also a pretty face,
you know.
So um And you know, one thing I thought,
you know, I came to Canada. Actually, I
left You know, I was born in Taiwan, and
I left Taiwan. I went to South America,
and uh lived there for a year. I left
Taiwan when I was 14.
So I lived in South America for a year,
and Central America for like half a
year,
and then Canada for 3 years. Then in
1989,
I I I came to California, basically in
Bay Area, San Francisco, Bay Area. And
since then, I've been living here.
And uh
Hi guys. So I saw some questions. I'll
get to that.
Um
So I came to, you know, USA. So and uh
you know, I want
And you know, I learned English, you
know, basically by myself. You know, I
never actually finished high school.
You know, in Taiwan,
you have middle school, and I did I did
not graduate middle school. What I get
is a certificate for having done middle
school,
because my grade is below F, you know,
so I was not a studio person uh at all,
you know, um
but things changed, you know, but
anyway, so I never went to high school
and they but I learned English, I
learned programming, you know, just on
my own and you know, things change, your
life change, situation change and you
might change into something else.
So, I learned that English and but
basically my point like get back to my
point, what what I was saying is that
you know, I think I was very capable
man
and I'm not just capable man, but I'm
multi-talented like I I am, you know,
like the Prince musician, Prince, you
know, who who died a few years ago. He
was, you know, one of the
multi-talented,
um
with respect to music, you know, he he
plays drums, he plays guitar, he plays
piano. He composed composes, he write
lyrics, like he does everything by
himself, the whole album is made by
himself.
And uh you know,
and and so that's one of the you know,
few talented people and not just I mean
there are others, you know, there are
also for example, if you look at
historical figures, there are people who
are
you know, not just mathematicians, but
also they are
you know, they are very they are expert,
they are scholars in history, in
literature, in poetry,
uh or you know, or sports like fencing
and you know, there are many people like
that. So, I thought I was
I'm kind of, you know, not you know, I
at least I thought I was. But anyway,
let me get back to the point. I
So,
what I was saying, you know, in terms of
speaking English, you know, um
communication skills, you know, or
charisma, like talking to a lot people.
And I was I always thought that I was
like um
very good at because I'm very good at
everything, you know, anything.
But actually that turns out that's
that's
false. That's actually I'm actually
below average in terms of at least
speaking English to people uh to to an
audience, for example.
You know,
the way I learned I mean I did never it
it never occurred to me
um until, you know, I was watching my
own videos, you know, in the past few
months. You know, I just um
you know, in some sense I know, but
but the my point is that it I have never
thought that I was actually in terms of
communicating skills
um
I'm actually
below average as compared to an average
American.
Show.
Yes, exactly. I was just going to say
imposter syndrome. You know, today
Wikipedia and information are so rich,
you know, you you there's like
psychology things and other things you
learn about on social media and and all
that. So there's, you know, the imposter
syndrome.
Um
Oh, wait. Wait. Hold on. I'm confusing
two things. Imposter syndrome is is is
such that um
Well, correct me if I'm wrong.
It is that you
you are capable
at something, but you think you are not.
That's the
syndrome. But the other thing I was
going to mention is that there's
there's another psychological phrase. I
forgot what's the name. But, that's kind
of like the opposite. Like, people think
they are good at something, but actually
they are not.
Right. Okay. So,
So, actually it turns out I mean I find
myself when I look look at my own
videos. Um I don't speak well. You know,
I don't communicate well. I mean, I know
I'm like introvert already and and
especially when people are around in
social situations.
Um I've I feel like I can I can I will
always feel there's a pressure like
people are watching me, you know, and
when that happens, which happens often
in social social situations, um I don't
do well. I talk I do not talk well. I do
not talk clearly. I um
I stutter, you know, and all the terms I
forgot like, you know, it's like half
half of my brain is not working, you
know.
Um
but I already know that. But, I mean, so
let me just be simple, you know. So,
what I'm saying is that since I watch my
own video, I don't
I don't actually communicate well. So, I
mean, aside from being, you know,
uh
uh feeling nervous. So, you know, so I
want to improve that. So, I mean, you
can do that, too, you know. I So, you
know, if you watch your own videos, you
I mean, every people every person is
different, you know. It may not apply to
you. I mean, like on the internet, like
I have no idea who you are. And you
probably have no idea like what I am
like until you watch me, you know, doing
videos. So, but you know, all walks of
life, you know, they are, you know,
business people and artists kind of
people and programmers and they are they
live in different countries and yeah, I
mean, it's
I mean, you cannot
even begin to describe the diversity.
So, I don't know what's your situation,
but I think
for many people you can if you do if you
record yourself, then you can learn
something from it, you know, um
So, anyway, and and also, okay, so the
other thing is that that since I'm doing
video, you know, I learned a few things,
you know, so for one thing I
I will try to um
you know, learn to, for example,
communicate well, you know, don't just
like
stop stuttering, you know, like first of
all, you know
be calm, you know, be you know, I can
when I'm calm, I'm I talk well,
relatively.
And then stop saying, you know, you
know, you know, like I
I watch myself, I say you know,
something, you know, it's like that, you
know, like you know, all the time.
Like every every sent other sentence.
And also, I don't, you know, when when
I'm trying to say something quickly, I I
don't articulate well. So, and that is
that is important actually because a lot
of people watching videos, they do not
necessarily have the video on, you know,
they listen when they, you know, drive
to work and, you know, so forth.
You know, there there it is again, I'm
like, you know, you know, you know. So,
I I I will try to stop that, you know,
that's an interesting thing, you know,
like you can
Okay, stop that.
You can explore
you know, the speech patterns like you
like each person you have a habit
actually, just like writing, you have a
habit when you do certain things. So,
you know, people can analyze your speech
patterns and know that, you know, it is
you. You know, for example, you know,
Trump
he's got speech patterns. Obama,
you know, he's got particular way of
speaking and also he's got particular
way of mannerism, you know.
So,
So, anyway, let's look at the um
questions and let's see what I'm going
to talk about because usually I have a
lot of opinions about
everything.
And I feel like I can, you know,
talk about it and especially today, you
know, technology changed so much in the
past, you know, 20 years.
And, you know,
Okay, stop that. So, before you write
blogs, that's a primary means of
communication at least between, you
know,
between most programmers.
But now there is video um
and it it just exploded, you know,
everyone is like watching video. The
other thing, okay, the other thing I
want to mention it just have occurred to
me. You know, I when I talk, I tend to
have like every moment I have like a
million thoughts, like 1,000, 10 10 more
thoughts happening at the same time and
before I finish a sentence I want to I
speak the other thought.
Actually, quite a lot nerds are that are
like that, you know, some
some famous programmers, for example,
the JavaScript, the guy who invented
JavaScript, Brendan or Brenda or
something, you know, he's on YouTube.
He is not a well he is not a good
communicator, you know, he does not talk
well. Like if you watch him, you know,
there's some videos, of course, you
know,
there are a lot videos of him talking.
You watch him.
He's kind of like me in in some way,
okay?
Uh so, he stutters and before he finish
a thought, he talk about something else,
and usually the end result is that
you don't get clearly what he's saying.
Like, you get confused, you know, he
touch on a lot of things, but on the
other hand, there are other
other people, for example, Camille
Paglia. Pag-
uh Camille Paglia. He's a well-known
so-called feminist, okay? He he
not like today's, but anyway, Camille
Paglia. He's considered
by some people one of the most
um
one of the greatest intellectual. But
anyway, when she talks, oh my god, she's
like machine gun non-stop. And before
she like she has, you know, 1 million
thoughts happening at the same time, and
she
tries to say all of them at the same
time. However, she does make the point
across, you know, she's so knowledgeable
about
uh history. I mean, history and culture
across, you know, across the countries,
continents. And yeah, she's just
amazing.
On the other hand, there's a Jordan
Peterson, if you watch him.
Okay, I always wanted to be like
like that. The The Jordan Peterson way
of speaking. Like, you are able to
uh communicate a very complex ideas
precisely using the
using the
uh the right words, the diction, you
know, the just just the right There's
only one word for each situation. He
always use that. So, you know, Peter's
Jordan Peterson, um so, he has become I
have watched a lot videos of him in in
the past 2 years.
And he has become one of the person one
of the top three, let's say,
I admire. So, so basically one of the
top, you know, the top, let's say top
top few person I admire
English speakers I admire. So, Jordan
Peterson is one of them.
Camille Paglia is the other one.
And I also
admired Thomas Sowell. Thomas Sowell is
a black guy and he's a economist. He has
written a lot books. But, however, he's
very old now. He's like 70-something,
you know, long retired. And but if you
watch videos of him today
he's kind of old, you know, when when
you get old
um for a lot of people like above 70,
you you you cannot talk well and you are
slow, you know, you are slow to respond
and usually
it doesn't come out coherent. But, there
are a lot of videos of him when he was
younger, you know, 10 or 20 years ago.
But, anyway, so Jordan Peterson, Camille
Paglia, Thomas Sowell. You know, Thomas
Sowell I knew because I was trying to
understand economics.
Uh so, I read a book called Basic
Economics. This is around 2000 uh year
2000, 2001. I read that book like three
times over the past 20 years, three
times from cover to cover.
And I didn't know he's a black guy, you
know, until I read that book.
Um and that really opened my eyes
especially with regards to open source.
Um he doesn't I mean, the book it
doesn't talk about open source stuff,
but he just talk about basic economics.
So, that book open open my eyes. So, I
recommend that book. You should
especially if you are programmer and uh
you know, you are probably into, you
know, open source
philosophy or free software philosophy.
It you know, you should check out that
book, Basic Economics.
And also I have a article about that
book. Um
you know, you can just search "Sadi
basic economics".
So, okay, so I was saying, you know, the
the few English speakers I admire. So,
besides those those three, there's also
my classic is Bertrand Russell.
Uh of course, he's dead uh
a while like 50 or 100 years ago.
Bertrand Russell maybe 50 years ago, but
anyway, he's a
mathematician, logician. He's also a
Nobel laureate, you know,
Nobel laureate, quote and quote, meaning
that he won a Nobel Prize. Um
but for literature, which is kind of
silly, but he anyway anyway, he's a
mathematician, he's a logician, and I
share, you know, my my minds my my
mindset, my philosophy, my view of the
world pretty much uh I think he's the
closest I share, you know, he viewed the
way he look at the world.
Okay, so I've been
you know, rambling about different
things. Let's let's get back to the
questions.
So, functional programming got gotchas.
Um
Let's see.
Well, functional program Okay, let's go
over the questions. There's a few. Let's
see what I want to say.
Looking for input on Emacs package
managers.
Looking at straight.el. I never tried
straight I never heard of straight.el,
but
I'm not I don't use packages that much.
And uh
the way I use packages is very basic,
you know, I just call
Okay, let let me start. Yeah, let's do
some Emacs because most of my most of
you guys are you know
following me because of my Emacs stuff.
So, let's do some Emacs.
So, I'm going to First of all, I'm going
to turn on the key lock mode.
Key lock alpha.
Command lock mode. That's a good mode.
This mode will show your key and
commands
as you as you type them. So,
run run run eval.
So, you see so all my commands will
show.
So, anyway, let's put this window here.
Okay, and uh so, whenever what I
whatever I'm doing in Emacs and if you
are wondering
what is the command he just called, you
know, just look at this window on the
left. You'll You'll show and it will
also show the key
the key binding I'm using to invoke it.
By the way, I'm using a Dvorak keyboard,
so you may find the letters strange. And
also, I'm using Safely Keys. Safely Keys
is a model mod
uh I created, so I you know, of course,
I
I recommend I recommend it you know
because I wrote it. So, you know, you
might try it. So, it it's a
and you're not you also notice I you
know, almost never you will never see a
control or meta in here because
that is the purpose of Safely Keys. Um
So, anyway, so as far as packages, first
of all, I don't use that much.
Uh let's go to Elpa.
Okay, so you can see that you know,
that's it, but of all these actually I
don't I
they are just there because I installed
in the past, but I don't actually use
them. So, the one the ones I use
Let me show you.
What is this? I don't even know what is
this.
Camel.
Um
Project Crystal. Oh, that's OCaml mod.
Okay.
So, that's OCaml mod, command log mod I
use.
Company I don't actually use. Dash I
don't use. I don't like Dash at all.
Dash Dash is one of the package. It's a
Lisp library
that
the goal of Dash is supposed to be
So, it provide convenient interface to
Emacs Lisp functions, you know, like
list processing functions.
It's basically just a wrapper. You know,
it's it's one of those things it's like
JavaScript library that it's created
created so that if you don't know much
Lisp, you will find it convenient. But
if you actually know Emacs Lisp,
you don't want you know, you it's best
to not use it because it's just a
wrapper for people who don't know
you know, it's supposed it called
itself, you know, the modern
Emacs Lisp library for you know, for
Lisp processing, something like that.
It's it's kind of a marketing thing.
So, I don't like it.
Don't mod line I don't use. I tried it.
So, let's delete it.
Um and also many many of the libraries
today when you install one, it installs
10,000 other ones, you know, it's really
criminal.
It's very annoying. So, I don't like
that at all. You know, you you write a
package,
you know, um,
try you know,
try not to use other other libraries.
You know, well, I mean, it's that's not
necessarily a good advice, but basically
my, you know, my opinion is that you
know, you want to learn Emac Lisp well.
You know, I don't mean you have to
master everything, you know, in one day,
but try to
understand, you know, if you program in
language X, try to master language X as
you go, you know, at least have the
mentality of doing that.
And then, you know,
so you write good code and don't load a
bunch of libraries like today in
JavaScript land,
you know, each library is just like 10
lines is one library. So, if you want to
use something in JavaScript, you
download one library. That library
loads, you know,
100 other libraries and some of them are
just five lines like trim string or
something.
It has become extremely idiotic, so
um,
okay, so that's So, that's another
topic. So, anyway, so Dash is is one of
the library that's kind of like like
that.
You know, part of the reason Dash is so
popular, it's one of the most popular
library, um, in the, uh, Elpa.
Part of the reason it's so popular
is not just because, you know, it's
marketing, although that's part of the
reason, you know, it calls itself the
modern library of for Emac Lisp, but the
other reason is that
the Emacs the Emacs Lisp documentation
and the Emacs Lisp itself, it really
sucks, you know, there's a lot problems
with the Emacs,
you know, free software foundation
organiza- organization like, you know,
there's
not, you know, just political problems.
There's a leadership problems. There's,
you know, you cannot contribute code,
you know,
there's a lot problems. So, so Emacs
Lisp, the language is kind of stagnated,
you know, it doesn't grow.
And you cannot easily contribute, you
know, code to Emacs, you know, there's a
lot obstacles, you know,
political or organizational or people,
you know, they you know, you just cannot
do it. So,
the only way
you know, basically the most practical
way to contribute is just create your
package and put it on Elpa. You know,
that's why So, that's the that's part of
the reason dash um
becomes huge hugely popular because
you know,
Emacs Lisp
sucks, you know, you know, people cannot
find how to do things in the dark, you
know, things like that. So,
you know, so he just, you know, this guy
just created it, so people use it. So,
you know, that's you know, so you know,
it's problem of the Emacs, you know,
free software and in general, it's a
problem of open source um and free
software.
So, let's go to Elpa. So,
click.
So, you see on Elpa, you see let's sort
it by download, number of download.
Okay, reverse.
So, you see dash is a number one. It's
the number one library the a modern Lisp
library for Emacs. The The name is
offensive.
You know, what do you mean modern? So,
you know, it's like So, it's you know,
it's so it's like contradict
contradictory to Emacs fans. You know,
people say, you know, in Emacs
community, you know, we all love Emacs,
right? You hear that all the time. Oh,
Emacs is
is God sent. Emacs does everything.
Emacs Lisp is the best language.
But then, okay, you look at this, you
know,
Melpa. Then there is the the number one
package, a modern Lisp library for
Emacs. Does that, you know, does does
that look contradictory to you?
I mean, if Emacs is so great, why do you
need a, you know, what do you mean
modern?
So,
you know, so if Dash is so great, you
know, it's a modern Lisp library for
Emacs,
then does that tell you, you know,
something is wrong with Emacs Lisp? You
know, what Why do you need a modern Lisp
library?
You know, so there's a lot problems, you
know, in Emacs community. So,
okay,
so what is the
What are the things you can do? You
know, actually I don't
I couldn't say you there's that much
things you can do, you know.
But anyway, let me go back to
the questions. So, okay, so I don't use
much libraries. So, I haven't used
straight.el.
So, the only way I use libraries like
this. So, let me show you.
Um
So, I just, you know, if I need some
package, I just call list-packages
and I just search for it. Let's say
smex.
Now, these are the packages I have
installed.
Um
So, you know, once I found a package,
for example, this one,
I just uh return
uh and and tab to install. Usually, it's
install because I
I already installed it, so it says
delete.
So, and you know, then I install it,
then that's it. That's That's how I
install packages. Now, there's another
one
that's very popular. It's called
use-package. Let's see.
use-package
Uh
why is it not there?
Why is use-package not there?
Oh, is it building?
Okay.
Uh
Let's go.
Wait. I thought it's not in yet.
Let's see.
No, it's not there.
So, I
That's interesting.
So, it But anyway, use-package is one of
the
package manager kind of It It It's It
helps you set up It helps you install
and set up packages. So, a lot people
like to use that.
And it's written by a Emacs Lisp expert,
Steve Purcell.
Is it by Steve
or is it by the other guy?
Uh
no, I think it's it's the other guy.
I think but anyway, he's the current
Emacs maintainer. You know, you can look
it look it up. Sorry, I forgot his name
but
but why is it not um
in
this packages?
I don't have it installed because I
don't use it.
Okay. Okay, now it shows. You know, I
noticed something sometimes in Elpa.
Uh there it is. Finally, you have to
wait.
You know, this this is the package um
this one. Uh
this one, use package.
So, a lot of people use that. I don't
use it.
So, let's go back.
Okay,
um
functional programming gotchas. I
Well, that depends on what you mean. I
my idea you know, the way I program, I
like functional programming and I don't
like OOP at all. All the programming I
do is functional programming.
And uh
um
and basically my only concern is that um
in general, I just write functions that
without side effect.
Be aside from that, I don't actually
care much for some of the fancy feature
features of functional programming such
as provided by Haskell.
Um
you know, uh monad and and other stuff
and currying.
Um
uh
I don't you know, I don't use them much.
But, um
I think they are good. It I just happens
to not use them much. I mean, especially
okay, in industrial programming, in
practice practical industrial
programming, uh you don't usually you
don't use them because they are not
practical unless
unless you are using a language like
Haskell. Okay, so if you if you are
programming in Haskell, then those are
good. But, if you are programming other
languages that supports functional
programming such as JavaScript,
um Golang,
uh
or even Emacs Lisp, uh things like monad
and uh currying, they are not actually
that practical or you know, uh tail
recursion. Um
So,
my CD to you that changed the 21
Package managers.
So, so this is my tutorial for packages.
Yeah, that's basically that's all I use.
So, I don't use any package managers.
But, if you like them, you know, go
ahead use them. Use package is very
popular and uh
I can trust the code is good.
Um
Okay, why her son
So, I'm reading out I I'm reading you
guys' comments. Um
Oh, yeah. I like So, doing stream with
interesting guest. I really like to
You know, I like to There are some
people in Emacs I like to invite. Who do
you like to invite? Taste You know, type
it here.
Type it here. Let me know. So, but
the the issue with me is that I haven't
done that yet because
First of all, let me log in to Twitter.
So that I can see the interesting
people, you know, in in recent memory.
I'll go Emacs.
You know, so I've been coding You know,
I've been living in Emacs for
like 20 years since 1999 or 1998.
So, and uh I
I talk I use online features a lot. I
mean, I talk to people a lot. I mean,
online.
So, I almost know all the at least all
the people or the
uh
well-known people in Emacs and also, you
know, in
Emacs developers, you know.
And I also because I argue a lot
I'm not afraid to show my opinions. I
And also, I'm
also I criticize a lot. So, a lot of
people consider me a troll.
You know, like when I criticize Emacs
this or I criticize Richard Stallman,
you know,
people don't like it.
They don't like it not necessarily
because I'm wrong. They don't like it
just because
you know, usually when you are in a
community X,
you don't, you know, say any negative
things in community X. All they want to
hear is positive good things like like
in a
it's like community building.
Uh but I'm not really into that, you
know, I like I like to say whatever I
think is true. So, even though, you
know, some I'm not
always correct, of course.
But anyway, so
so I do have some issues with
some some people have issues with me
with my opinions. You know, and besides
I'm a nerd and I'm not much of a social
person, so
that that also plays into it.
But anyway, so there are many
interesting Emacs people and especially
there are some interesting people I met
in I met last year like, you know, Emacs
people.
Notifications
home.
And uh
um
Yeah, so what I'm saying is that
following that's a following. So, I like
to
you know, I I I would love to talk to
them
and invite them to you know, video chat,
but
I'm not readily
into doing that because usually I have
to wait and
to for them to
contact me or because
because, you know, I if I just talk to
them, you know, I I'm afraid, you know,
they don't they they don't want it. They
don't like me.
You know.
So,
it's attention, you know, especially
today because of the political
situation, you know, the
let's let's just say social justice, you
know, situation, you know, USA is very
divided and most programmers are
especially the white programmers in
Silicon Valley area. So, they have
you know, there are certain things you
cannot say. This is This is new. This
This happened only in the recent 5
years.
Before, it's totally opposite. So,
you know, some So,
like before, we nerds, we can talk about
things and usually nerds are actually
abrasive, you know, not just not just
me. Especially in Emacs community, a lot
people, you know, they criticize you or
they criticize that.
You know, it happens you know, each
other way.
But But today,
there's also, you know, it's
certain things you don't say. So, I'm
I I mean anyway, so I'm did I'm getting
uh
um derailed, but
Okay, anyway, let me show you some
people. So, Steve Purcell, he's a person
he's a very interesting guy and I think
uh he's a very uh good person. He is
currently the Emacs maintainer. He's a
leader,
you know, of of Emacs development right
now.
And uh you know, so use package is
written by him.
Um
So, I could I could, you know, contact
him. But, you know, I it's I just
I could if he wants to, but it it it
gives me a lot pressure because
because if I invite him to my
uh my video, you know, sort of talk
show, you know, I'm I'm
I'm kind of running my stuff in semi
jest, you know, like saw talk show and
he's like well known and and if I invite
him, all people is going to watch it,
then
it's like I have pressure in doing that,
but I would love to do that.
Uh
you know,
first of all, I have to be like I have
to
be myself in order to you know, so
that's why
in order to do that, that's why I'm
doing videos, you know, I have been
doing a lot videos recently and part of
the reason is that so I can
get myself used to it, you know, I can
get better and talking to people.
So Steve Purcell is a great and
uh
I'm not sure how do you pronounce this
guy's name, Wilfred Huge. He he's also
very well known and I don't know him as
a person, but he's a
uh
great coder.
Uh he he uh he's he started the Emacs
Rust Rust Emacs project that is trying
to implement Emacs
um in the Rust language and it's getting
fairly popular and that's a great thing
too because
I don't like the Rust language, but
anyway, it's Rust language is like
um
C level language, but better, you know,
because it's new and modern and uh with
modern understanding of compilers and
technology. So he's trying to um he's
leading the effort to
uh create uh translate all the C code in
Emacs into Rust and that project, you
know, you can look at his uh website uh
Rust Emacs.
And I hope it succeeds because
it gives us an option uh alternate
alternative
uh path for the future of Emacs.
Uh I'm just you know I'm not going to uh
name everyone because some of them I
don't know well, so it's so if you
happen your name happen to be here and I
skipped
um don't feel bad about it. So Jeff
Trout, Jeff Trout is a guy he does uh
Emacs meetup. He's the organizer, you
know, he initiates the Emacs meetup in
San Francisco area. So I've been I have
attended uh several times in the past
year. So it it was it was great. You
know, you get to meet people
and uh
uh talk to people.
And Howard Abrams, apparent he's he's
also a very he's a
uh well-known um
popular and uh
very very well-rounded
um
old
uh
Emacs blogger and you know, Emacs coder.
By old I mean
been been there for a while, you know,
like me. So
um
so he he's he's a great guy to talk to
and he you know, he's also expert of
Emacs Lisp. Uh
you know, Emacs Lisp and
uh
this guy uh Emacs
tips is his name is
Aug like A G.
Uh he's a Clojure expert.
Uh of course he's also very
uh into Emacs, but yeah, he's also a
code codes Clojure.
Uh Steve Yegge is very interesting guy.
I'm sure you probably
know, but actually, you know,
time passes, but you 10 years ago
everyone knows Steve Yegge.
But today there's a new generation, so I
don't know, maybe you don't know him,
but he's when blog when blogging is
popular.
You know, Google killed blogging
basically. Um when blogging was popular,
he's a one he's the most he's he's one
of the most famous blogger. He used to
work for Amazon and Google. But he quit
Google last year.
Um a lot thing, you know, things has
been changed in society. A lot of things
changed. But anyway,
he he is a Oh, he is one of the greatest
he's the one of the greatest programmer.
Uh he's a master of Java
and JavaScript and Emacs Lisp.
Uh
and other other other things. So, he he
has been he has been
he's he's
expert of doing low-level programming
like system programming as well as
high-level programming like and also
writing games. But anyway, so you know,
that's Steve's uh Yegge.
So, I mean, so there are a lot of
people, you know, I'm not going to it's
like this is not
you know, introduction to uh um
Emacs people because there's a lot. I'm
just mentioning a few very famous ones.
So, Mike Peterson is also very famous.
Uh
he he is he's known for uh writing the
book Mastering Emacs.
Okay.
I You know, actually, I don't think he
likes me. You know, I don't know for
sure, you know, because
and also um
you know, I don't want to get I'm not
sure I want to get into
some of the rather
you know, details. Um Anyway, so he he
is he's the guy who who wrote Mastering
Emacs. And also, he has he has been
interviewed by Sacha. You know, Sacha
you probably know Sacha is one of the
most famous Emacs blogger in in the past
like over 10 over 10 years. Sacha, and
she's a
So, she she did an interview of Mike
Peterson about
maybe 8 years ago. You can watch.
Uh John Kitchen is also very uh great
guy. I met Actually, he came
to visit me. So, I'm very happy for
that. He's a chemistry professor, and
he's uh
also very much into Emacs. So, and he
has written the package called uh
scientific
I'm sorry. Sorry.
Yeah, some hiccups. So, he he wrote the
like Emacs distribution called Sci Emacs
or something. But anyway, it's for it's
mostly for academics to use Emacs to
pub- publish their research.
So, that's a big package, you know, lots
of code, does lots of things. So, I
mean, if if you are doing publishing, if
you are a professor kind of in in
academia,
um
you know,
it's it's worth checking out.
Okay, this this author Malabarba
Malababa
He's also He doesn't blog much today,
but he
you know, he also he's also a
author of many packages, and also he's a
Emacs blogger.
Uh
Tassilo Horn
This guy I know like at least 20 years
ago, at least for 20 years. He
he um So, So, he apparently he lives in
Japan.
Uh he's a white guy. Uh he's the author
of uh PDF view in Emacs uh uh uh
a package in Emacs that views PDF.
Uh
So, anyway, there's a lot people, you
know, and some of them, of course, many
of the Emacs popular Emacs people are
not
on Twitter. And also a lot of them I
don't follow. I'm not following. Bastien
uh
Gary or Grary. He he's a French guy. He
is the leader of
Org mode for over 10 years. He still is.
So,
uh
So, anyway, many Sacha is
is probably the most well-known, you
know, go visit her blog.
And oh, John Wiegley
No, no, okay. I made a mistake before.
John Wiegley, he is the current Emacs
leader, not the not Steve Purcell.
Yeah, Steve Purcell is the maintainer
the leader of Melpa.
Now, John Wiegley is the
the current leader of Emacs and also the
author of uh
use-package.
So, anyway, there are a lot people I'm
not going to you know, begin to
uh
list them all. Then I feel pressured to
like, oh, did I miss someone? Because
there's too many I cannot do that. And
uh John Abrahamsen is also interesting
guy. He's the He's the author of
Magit mode. Huge
huge popular.
Um
So, okay, let's stop that.
Uh Andrew Haylett, anyway, it's Emacs
Rocks. He Okay, he he is the author of
Dash.
Uh and he's also the Of course, he's
he's a creator of the extremely
popular YouTube series Emacs Rocks.
So, what else? Uh
I recommend to watch videos on x2.
Oh. Uh
Like two times the speed. Yeah, well,
especially when you watch someone who is
not
uh prepared or who is not, you know,
very familiar with v- uh who doesn't do
edit, you know, so like my, you know, so
you can speed up. So, the other thing
about interesting about video is that
once you do video, okay, especially
professionals,
you want to edit the video, like, you
know, cut out the boring parts or, you
know,
insert some interesting image, like when
I say something, you know, like
especially today people insert some
funny images, like lol and stuff. I
Actually, I don't like that. And also, I
don't like I don't like edited or
prepared video. And also, I don't like
to read off from a script, you know,
especially like politicians today when
you give a speech, they First of all,
they have a prepared written, you know,
script. They just read it off. So, you
know, like there's many microphones and
they read uh
"Dear fellow Americans, we are here
today uh you know,
That's that's not good. You know, it's
prepared, it's fake. You know, in many
in many ways it's fake and and it does
not it does not reflect
your um
your emotion or you know, yeah, it's
it's
Yeah, I would not say it's I mean it's
not not it's not really you know, fake
is the wrong word, but you know, but
anyway, I like to
speak directly and I I like to be able
to
uh hone the skill of speaking without
you know, a written script. So, for
example, if I know Emacs Lisp, if I'm
going to teach you Emacs Lisp or if you
are, you know, if you are going to teach
some other people of something you know
well
then you know it. You can teach it
without having to actually, you know,
read off um be prepared. You know, I
think that's a better way. And you know,
in one way because partly you
you solidify what your knowledge, you
know, and you you get better at the
skill of fishing them out, you know,
teach people dynamically.
Um
and also for the audience, it's it's
better for you um
because audience can see your ability to
uh to do something to teach you some
something about, you know, a particular
subject instead of, you know, reading
from a manual script or you know, a
scripted prepared. Of course, on the
other hand, those who like to, you know,
read from a script, they say, "Of
course, it when you have a notes, you
know, it does give you
it does remind you what you like to
cover, you know, something important."
That that's also
fine.
So, I think I've been talking for 50
minutes. That That's That's usually, you
know, the time.
Um so, let me read off some
more questions.
I think listening to Jordan Peterson
really helps me learn communicate
better. Yeah.
If you watch JP and Sam Harris.
Yeah, I have watched that. That's
interesting. Um
you know, in that one
in that one, you know, Sam Harris is
interesting guy. He's um
Of course, both of them are very sharp
and very knowledgeable. But, however,
let me point out Sam Harris is kind of a
selfish guy.
A little bit, okay? And he's also
highly competitive.
Like me, okay? I share that aspect
because you can see that because
whenever like when you know, for
example, if I'm talking to someone or
even my friend, and they mention
something
and if I heard of that or if I have
opinion about that something
I'm in a hurry to say, "Oh, I already
know that." Oh, yeah, by the way, I you
know
you can see that. You know, that came
from competitiveness.
Um it's not necessarily bad, but usually
it's um
it's somewhat negative in in some
sometimes. Anyway, so and so Sam Harris
is very competitive competitive, you
know, he
he
it it came from the reason he is that
way. I think it's it came from
internally. You know, maybe when he grew
up, he does not get
um
you know, it it's it's it's
psychological from from my observation.
And also, Sam Harris
Okay, so he has that trait, being
competitive, and it shows. And sometimes
it it shows in in in not a good way
because you can see he's, you know, not
not making a great decision. Anyway, so
the other thing I noticed about Sam
Harris Harris is that he's kind of
selfish. You know, the he's, you know,
he wrote
he wrote religious, you know,
anti-religion books and uh
he he always like promote himself, you
know, he he's there to promote you know,
he's everywhere. So and but his primary
purpose is to promote himself, you know,
to promote his ideas, even though he's
usually
uh fair, but but but, you know, behind
it he's always there, you know, just to
promote himself. He's He was always like
that.
Now, Jordan Peterson
I greatly admire, but in that video when
Jordan Jordan Peterson and Sam Harris
talks about God, you can see that Jordan
Peterson he got stuck. You know, he's
like he got stuck.
You know, Jordan Peterson is a guy who
tries to articulate so precisely very
complex ideas.
He tried to use, you know, just the
right word. I cannot do that, you know,
even though I thought, you know, that's
what I want to do, but
in writing I can do some of that, but
definitely not in real time in speech.
I'm actually pretty bad. I noticed I'm
pretty bad. I cannot find the right
word. But okay, Jordan Peterson he
always he he used very precise and
words and articulated and structured it
so well, but in that video you can see
he's stuck.
Due to that, you know, he tried to
you know, sometimes when you hear listen
to Jordan Peterson, when he tried to say
some complex ideas, the way he, you
know, with his way of elaborate
um words.
Sometimes you you can see that it
doesn't it's not good, you know, it
starts to break down. And that video is
a particular good example. He
he breaks down like he's stuck.
Um
But any anyway
And that you know, that's like two
videos I remember and it's like two
hours something.
So have you watched JP? Okay, so some
reading for you from a great speaker and
communicator.
Sita May, okay, I'll read that. I'll
read that offline.
Yeah, for all intensive Yeah. Okay, so I
think that's it for today.
Okay, last is there any questions?
Okay, Maple.
I assume if I know
hey the other day I want to know what is
Maple. Hi Jack. So Maple is a software.
It's it's like it's software for
symbolic computation. So it's like
Mathematica. It's the competitor of
Mathematica if that's what you mean. You
know, Maple is a word you know, it's a
tree.
You know, it's a Canadian's national
tree, you know, leaf.
You know, we have maple syrup, but also
there's a software from Canada. I think
from Toronto. It's it's just called
Maple. It's a symbolic computation
software. It's a competitor to
Mathematica.
So any other questions?
Ask ask.
So, I wait for I wait for 10 more
seconds. You know, then and then if no
questions, then that's it for today.
And thanks Thank you guys for coming.
Okay, thank you guys for coming. Until
new until next time. You know, you can
subscribe. You know, I hate it. Okay,
last you know, let me say this. You
know, every video video today you see
people talking and they say, "Please
subscribe and please thumb up." You
know, there's many styles of doing that,
you know, but almost every video, you
know, "Please subscribe. Please thumb
thumbs up."
And that's no good, you know, that's
that's really that's really painful
because
because um
you know, it's good if you do it
naturally, you know, like
nobody tells you to do it, but you know,
because, you know, "Hey guys, you know,
I'm doing a good show. If you like it,
you know, give me give me a like. Give
me a thumbs up, you know, and subscribe
to to my channel. So, thank you."
Um that's natural, but however, today
it is not because first of all, you
know, they they do that they they want
to do that because they it's it's like a
commercialized systematic enterprise,
you know, it's it's a it's clockwork.
You know, and why do they do that?
Because of of course, self-interest, you
know, you watch my video. "Hey guys,
subscribe, okay? You know, so I get you
know, eventually I get money, you know,
please donate."
And but also because why people do that,
why is that every video say that? Of
course, if I want to subscribe, I know
how to subscribe. I can see it. I don't
need to I don't need you to tell me to
subscribe. You know, but
but it's so happy, you know, people do
that because, you know, also because
YouTube, of course. YouTube tells you to
because, you know,
if you don't if you do videos or if you
write blogs, you know, in social media
or, you know, so-called SEO
um
uh search engine optimization, that's a
euphemism.
You know that you you will know because
YouTube, of course, YouTube want
everyone to use YouTube. So, he will you
if a lot of people subscribe, it it
grows the YouTube business, which in
turn means more money for Google. So,
YouTube will tell you like on my on my
page somewhere YouTube will tell the
you'll you will have a lot help, you
know, information. How to increase your
audience, how to, you know, make more
money, you know, where to put put your
ads, you know, that's So, you you know,
it's a whole commercialized system. It
and it's just not good because it's not
good because it
it shapes the entire every video, the
entire society into certain uh form, you
know, so
that's, you know, that's what it is. But
anyway, so anyway, the question about
web dev, let's talk about that next
time. So, because this this video is
already uh 1 hour.
So, Haskell, yeah, let's talk about that
um another day. So, you know, um I don't
know when I'll do next because I don't
have like a fixed schedule.
Uh
maybe I'll try to do that because every
time if I have a fixed time a plan,
uh
you know, sometimes I don't do well
because I feel a pressure to
to do it well because so um
anyway, so
thank you guys for watching. That's it
for today.
Bye.