good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Star Talk Show today is
random okay I'm going to you know if you
have questions
ask it post comments and if you are
watching this offline post time stamp
YouTube in the comments okay and Spread
spread it
put it on Twitter and stuff so today I'm
just going to talk random
okay and meanwhile when there is no
activity good morning Reaper when there
is no activity I'm just going to cold
uh emac Beast you know I was thinking um
I'm going to code either wufam language
or
um emac beast okay so anyone there is
there anyone there let's see the
poverty the paucity of Saudi viewers
three
okay random you know so AI so we talked
yesterday about AIA and stuff AI is
taking over
so I declare that in the year 2023 is
the beginning of real Ai and the future
is uncertain okay the future is
uncertain
so here's today's talk show and we just
started no topic okay no topic random so
comments hello if you have questions
post it now this is the right time ask
me about questions uh
and stuff okay so
since today's so yesterday we talked
about this bot this we talked about Duck
Duck Go search about qqai drawing bot
amazing you know it's taking over it's
you know so we have the
uh the real the age of the real
artificial intelligence we talked about
AI open AI poems on ksari.org amazing
and timpu and Lauren Southern
some cultural War stuff okay so okay no
questions I'm just going to uh code then
okay so uh let's see so today's talk
show yeah so
um
let's see today's talk show random
and the video check audio check okay
perfect wait let's see one more time is
the
screen position correctly
okay it's
it's good
okay so yeah so random random okay
random reminding you guys the topics Is
Random so what where we are going
depends on what you're gonna ask so
meanwhile I'm going to uh start coding
emac this now
uh old fan language you know like once I
started to talk about something usually
it's gonna be non-stop so the you know
every time in the past few days you know
the past few videos every time I started
to code emac Beast then
the topic went somewhere else
okay so now yeah so we I want to
continue working on my emac this okay so
let's see how many sucks yes emac based
codeine sigio rejects old syntax
uh this topic I don't know if you Reaper
would be interested you know the
alternative Syntax for regular
expression there exist too and I covered
in this video
2022 1125
that is uh November 25th
you know the naming of the month is
problematic in English it would be
better
to say to name each month as the ordinal
the name of the ordinal number for the
month so November would be 11th month
and December would be 12th month that's
how in Chinese in other languages are
the numbers are named the months are
named but in English we got great
up
because of the
history and so on so
so for example uh you know December the
dec that means 10 but December means 12.
so that's a up because they doing
the calendar change they added a month
or something like that you know long
history of the you know the the history
of the calendar
is a giant chapter of human's history
and from it you can see
a lot of things
history of calendar history
you know it it touches upon a lot of
things so
Huang
Vietnam blood in Germany says I watched
the three the three-seater demo from
emacs conference and he said it
he said it is similar to part edit but
you said that part it sucks okay let me
explain that one
three seater is not similar to power
edit okay
this I don't know who who said that Juan
posted who who is a guy who claimed that
okay if you post a name I might I might
give you some more information but
anyway
I can guess what he's saying already
because I've been in emacs community you
know arguing with him
and not always negatively you know I
mean emacs Community for 20 years and uh
often you know he did argument so I can
tell you what they are thinking so they
a lot of emacs people the phonetics okay
emacs phonetics and emacs Priests by
that I mean the the high-powered you
know the many of the emacs dev you know
in the new emacs
uh Dev mailing list you know they
actually write a lot of this code you
know actually yeah so a lot of them have
a lot experience writing this code and
they are not just emac beasts coders
they are also coders and they are also
some of them right compilers so many of
them I respect I highly respect their
um their emacs expertise many of them
have more exp expertise in emac baseball
than me or in programming even so not
not all of course some of them you know
since I've been programming for 30 years
and uh and using Pearl Wolfram language
Wolfram language term rewriting system
and the Linden scripting language I'm
also expert which are extremely
different from all the other industrial
languages
what is my Twitter handle just go to
kasali dot info you'll see it there okay
so uh so so yeah so so let me get back
to the question uh Pi edit
so
so basically all these many of the e-max
people in emacs community they think
power edit let me show you pie that okay
so because I'm doing a talk show so a
lot of people don't know what is part so
first of all you you must be your emacs
user okay first of all and and also you
must be a emac this coder then power
edit is relevant to you because power
edit is a is the Emax package or in vs
code you might call it extension or
add-on it's an emacs package that helps
you that makes you
that helps you edit emac this code okay
so again let me show you soft like Keys
source code for thousand lines of code
so you see these are
these are emac this code
and these are my all my packages let's
delete
um wait let's delete those
um
uh backup files okay delete then you see
this you see this is the power of diode
in emacs so anyway so I have you know uh
uh iMac Bliss mod you know
four thousand three thousand three
thousand seven hundred lines uh starfly
keys
3 800 lines and cosine HTML mod this one
is a big one okay
you know all these at least code you see
this this code this code this code
commonly skim this racket list closure
list they all have they all look like
this okay so this is PSI HTML mod 5000
lines okay so all these are my packages
so what is pi added par added is a Emax
major mod or emacs add-on you know a a
package that helps you
edit when you code lisp it helps you
edit these expressions for example let
me show you I'm not using pi edit okay
I'm using softly keys and in my opinion
it's more efficient than power edit more
efficient
now I haven't get to the to your point
yet okay but I'll get to it let me talk
about power edit for today for 30
minutes maybe 20 minutes okay probably
that so so emacs add-on it's a package
written in e-mac this of course Pi edit
it stands for parenthesis edit okay
that's a short Pi edit parenthesis edit
so so let's um
again let's go to talk show let's start
to uh show you the power edit home page
so that
okay
uh package
uh
emac Beast package
AKA major mod
for uh actually it's a minor mod for
helping you edit list code okay that's
what part edit is okay now let's go to
its home page now you know I'm not going
to look but I'm going to uh
so where's the home page uh
Pi that visual guide that's probably is
very hard to use okay you have to spend
time to learn it but I'll get you up to
the point okay so Pi edit um God you
know Pi that is a very old package by
now in 20 years okay uh let's see
okay so they don't even you know pilot
it is written by this guy yeah let me
explain let me tell you the history
about that a bit okay that is written by
a
a lisp hacker you know he's a lisp
expert he is uh and primarily I think
he's a schemeless coder and also a skim
this coder are you listening Juan so
he's a skim this coder you know I I
chatted with him uh with him a little
bit around 2006 okay he's a scheme this
hacker and also the new
um you know good news version of skim
this called
um
Kyle okay he's he's also a guy or user
and he
he hates Kyle he thinks Kyle is the
worst you know one of the worst
implementation of skin disp you know guy
out is a lisp you know it's it's an
implementation of skim this so a lot of
fun things in history but I'll get to
the point yet okay so scheme
full name scheme lisp okay scheme disp
it's one of the lists okay and Gaia
yeah
okay is basically a implementation of
scheme please okay you know usually
people don't say skin this they just say
skin scheme language I I would call it
skinless because you should not forget
your parent okay scheme is a lisp skim
lisp closure is a lisp closure lisp and
and you have commonly of course and emac
beasts you know and wolfam language you
can also consider it a service I talked
about
um language a lot uh this uh in my
videos so actually let me show you but
I'll get to the point okay so but let me
just Ramble On so wolfam language uh you
know I have a full tutorial I talked a
whole lot about this and actually
there's a person that's me so
search for Sally woofam Language
tutorial
so you find you'll find my web page
and
first of all let me tell you so there's
a video tutorial okay there's uh tens of
them so you click on this now there are
several five or so six seven ten ten
okay ten here now this these are some of
the best ones I've done more than 20 you
know in the past two years so Wolfram
Language tutorial by video Saudi dot
info Sally dot info you'll find so if
you are interested in move a language
watch them now in particular for example
one of them I talked about the wolfam
language syntax
uh for example Wolfram Language tutorial
for programmers demo symbolic
computation and term rewriting system
okay and this one geometric inversion
this one who find language type setting
Tech La Tech problems of traditional
math notation syntax and proof systems
okay this one characteristics of Haskell
python lisp mathematical Stefan woofer
okay and the demo of I'm like okay it's
not here so there's another video
um where I talked about the syntax of
Wolfram language and how they are the
same as the lisps
symbolic expression okay
it should you sit here
demo of term rewriting system uh okay so
okay yeah part of I you know maybe it's
another video maybe it's you know I talk
about a lot of things sometimes
interweaven uh in different videos so
anyway so Wolfram language is one of the
least okay let me get to the point so if
you don't know already it's free
I'm sponsored by wolfman research so
that's why I'm you know and I've been
coding Wolfram language for 10 years
since
1993. so and so I want to uh mention
wufan language and you can trust
I'm one of the major uh resource if you
want to learn Wolfram language so it's
free you can download it starting you
know since like two years ago three
years ago it become free you can
download it and use it with certain
conditions of course and I just I
recommend you just buy it okay buy
Mathematica because that way you get the
notebook and everything but but let's
get back to lisp okay so and recently I
updated several articles so for example
you go to you know
Wolfram Language tutorial then you go to
um comments okay comments questions okay
uh Wolfram Language tutorial then you go
to
um
actually let's go up okay we'll uh wait
with the Wolfram Language tutorial you
scroll down
uh miscellaneous
Mathematica logo history uh
then
lisp and this here's the article this an
APL root of Mathematica or from language
Mathematica is a product
the Wolfram language is the language
used in Mathematica so they are
essentially the same but Wolfram
language refers to the the programming
language the syntax Mathematica is just
a product you know you know so okay so
so here is article I recently updated so
here's a
it's a Wolfram language I'm telling you
this
ignorance you know many of these people
I've been arguing with them for the past
20 years in particular uh from year 2000
to year 2010 in that 10
years decade one decade I I have huge
amount of argument with the whispers in
particular in particular the common
disperse okay so I know all about pirate
and what they are talking what they are
thinking which is incorrect okay next
time you know next time you see someone
says power edit is the is kind of the
semantic editing uh uh
a package help you edit list code in a
semantic way or something like that
that is incorrect that is actually I
would say partially correct you know but
but it's it's like missing the point it
it forces you to manually edit your code
you know it so anyway let me get to it
okay so first of all
language I have more than 10 years of
coding experience and move from language
is a lisp it's a superior Superior lisp
okay in in sometimes people say it's
less than right okay that's CV but
anyway so here's a history of Wolfram
language and for for those of you uh
familiar with lisp yours immediately see
all the similarities like every
again how do you define these okay there
are four or five characters just let me
Define it okay let me I I haven't get to
the power edit yet but let me give you
the history of this okay so how do you
define a language is a list how do you
you know how how do you define it okay
if if this language that has four or
five characteristics then it's a list
okay one symbolic everything is symbolic
okay variable names they are symbols it
exists as entity okay symbolic
nested syntax purely nested syntax such
as you know so you are looking at here
um
I talked about this actually before but
anyway so purely nested syntax okay
symbolic purely nested syntax or
sometimes chords
symbolic Expressions s-e-x-p okay
sex in short simile okay symbolic nested
it fully regular regular nested
expression just like XML X XML is also
example Wolfram language is an example I
have a lot examples here I you know I'm
not going to show because I'm getting
starting to you know otherwise I get
endless okay symbolic nested fully
nested regular uniform x uh syntax okay
Marcus okay you know if you are at least
coder you are very familiar with Macross
because macros oh my YouTube It's a
goddess God feature a programming
language that's that's what least
phonetics think about Marcos they love
it
obsessively Marco this marker okay
symbolic nested fully nested regular
syntax
lisp Marcus okay
then you have reader markers read the
markers is a layer between syntax and
the compiler that helps you transform
some of the Expressions such as for
example you see you see that that little
apostrophe lets a that's a reader macro
okay
it's not a simple concept you see you
see this this found something there's a
apostrophe in front that's a that's a
marker okay
and there's more
uh
so okay let me repeat
symbolic fully nested fully nested
regular syntax
Marcos okay Marcos
and reader Marcos reader markers such as
you know you have thoughtful cons
a b can be written as a dot b
parenthesis that's that's a real marker
okay
even you know we're getting into
technical details so if you don't
program in lisp you don't you wouldn't
know but it's it's kind of the syntax
transformation okay
so let me so so so when you type uh this
code you know the the compiler will read
it and the first thing it will do it
will transform the syntax by reader
macro
into into all just lists so that's the
first step
so after the transformation the result
is still pretty much like this okay that
is at least people consider that is the
real syntax which is a idiotic idiotic
way of thinking but anyway so five
character if any language if they have
these five characteristics then it's a
lisp okay
let me repeat it symbolic
nestled syntax regular regular necessing
test syntax mostly okay
uh Marcos
reader Marcos
uh wait Simba
symbolic fully nested syntax
Marcos reader Marcos and one more is a
functional programming okay most you
know the the kind of the
it's a functional programming language
meaning that most almost everything you
do is just calling a function okay
there's no special there's it's a matter
of degree but it's mostly functional
programming okay you don't do oop for
example you know these two some of the
least support all people in general no
in general it's it's the language is
designed for functional programming okay
but it's not like like Haskell Haskell
is something else okay Haskell is like
pure functional programming and and
Haskell is almost the only one or camel
erlen
okamo erlan and many other languages
F-sharp they are F sharp is part of a
camel which is part of ml meta language
they are the same family they are not
pure functional programming like Haskell
okay but anyway so lisp if you satisfy
these characteristics that language is a
lisp okay it's per you know during the
past 20 years when Pearl is very popular
sometimes people will say oh Pearl is a
lisp that's the most idiotic con opinion
because Pearl is it symbolic no is it
regularly regularly nested expression
now it's it's not at least it's not at
least okay then when python started to
become popular during around 2002
because because year 2000 year Google
started to use Python so python started
to become popular programmers started to
hear to to be aware of python so and
some of the commonly idiots they will
say
some some of them they will say python
is less than right
it's a idiotic fact
they have no clue what's going there you
have no idea what is going on they might
be a communist expert they might be
python coding expert okay but they don't
understand what the concept of language
classification they don't know okay so
Pearl is not a lisp his pattern list is
it symbolic no is it regularly nested
expression no it's not lisp okay Ruby
when Ruby becomes very popular you you
know just in fact you can type it it's
Ruby lisp than right it's per this turn
right it's python a lisp you'll find a
lot a lot of blogs by these idiots
doing the era of year 2000 you will find
a lot of them okay so it's Ruby at least
is it symbolic no is it regularly
necessary expression no okay so Ruby is
not a list so what's the least common is
yes symbolic yes regularly necessary
expression yes
macros yes
read the markers yes mostly functional
programming yes okay common this is a
list emac this check check check check
check check check check is a list
Wolfram language Wu fam language check
check check Similac nested expression
purely neces syntax
read the markers read the markers check
language is a lisp okay
okay so that's a characteristics of lisp
and in fact you'll see I talked about
that you know in lots of my past videos
okay so I'm just regurgitate some of the
main points what so here we talking
about what what is the least what
characterize a list of language okay
so so okay so let me get to it okay Pi
edit Pi edit hold on a second
so at least so so okay so hold on a
second let's let's get um
organized so we don't go over let's get
back to talk show and write down what we
um
what is a lisp okay what is the
characteristics of lisp languages okay
you know so that's what we talked about
and the guy asked scheme and Pi that we
are we were talking about the author of
power edit and I'll get to your point
you know why do they why do some of the
emac lispers think that power edit is
this or that okay so
they don't know yeah they don't know
they don't know things okay they they
might be they
one thing I admit I mean one thing
that's true that many of these people
they are
emac these coders and they are expert
emac these coders for five years or ten
you know
but when it comes to the general
language issues programming language
issues what does computation mean
what is theoretical computer science
well you know what is a formal language
what is a regular expression what is uh
automata you know they they don't know
they don't know they don't know they
don't know a thing
but
ninety percent 99 of all the talk you
see on Hacker News and and by all the
programmers are by these type of people
who are they well they are they are
professional programmers they so they
know programming very well very well in
multiple languages but when it comes to
seen tax issues when it comes to
characteristics of language when it
comes to you know language design they
don't know you know they are just like
Carpenters telling you how house should
be designed you know it's just because
they work with it all the time they you
know anyway so I'll get back to the some
of the main point so Wolfram language
okay so Wolfram language is a lisp okay
so let me get to that
uh
okay so here is the article let me uh
one by one I'll get to the um uh Pi it
in okay
let me uh just get some of the um links
ready here okay so some of the links I
want to talk about
okay sound talk show uh 12th month
sixth day
we the main thing we are talking about
Pi edit okay so we are talking about
skim this what is it we talked about
Gaia so why are we mentioned then
mentioning them because the author edit
is is is a schemeless expert and he
doesn't like Gaia he think that Gaia is
one of the worst
skin okay so and what is this we cover
that what is the characteristics of list
languages we cover that
uh
okay so and uh listen okay we haven't
covered this uh much yet but I'll get to
it so first of all first of all
history of Wolfram language you can go
read this article just search for it
lisp root in mathematical language okay
so you can see there's Marco you know
how it's the new there's Marco in
quoting now remember we talked about
reader Marco that's what this is quoting
you know in in this in common is in
scheme disp any emac this you have this
apostrophe as quote you also have this
spectic you know X accent signs you know
which have a different meaning okay so
Marco and and here is the history of
Wolfram language written by Stefan wufa
so this this this section lisp
is written in 1988 okay
1988 and then wolfan language is also
borrows a lot have a lot of the nature
of APL API is another functional
language very succinct okay you will see
all these weird simple symbols that's
what APL is famous for APR it stands for
a programming language that's just the
name of the language you know I talked
about APR often in my videos as well so
AP so Wolfram has this
Wolfram wolfam language what is nature
of it it came from primarily from two
languages one is this and one is APL
kind of kind of combine them okay APL
combine them then then Stefan wolfam
you know the the element that that is of
his own creation is the pattern matching
pattern matching
uh and uh and mathematical functions you
can say that is his his creation okay
kind of matching which is which is which
is basically essentially it's a
it's a advanced
this marker far beyond far beyond the
least macro you know that the common
lispers are obsessed about far beyond
okay they don't know they don't know
what they're talking about you know read
read this page okay if you are a lisper
or common lisper
read this page okay this APR root in
mathematical roof and language and read
this section on macro you you can see
the
how they are designed different you know
you know differently
basically
in Wolfram language you it's a term
rewriting system and what is the term
relating system term rewriting system in
in a sense it's a glorified
macro
you know like in in this community you
know you write code right you know you
you write um
you know lots of least code and and you
know one out of 100 one out of a
thousand lines maybe you have a macro I
don't use Marco in this because I think
it's idiotic okay I I try to not
go go out of my way to not use any
marker in this because I think it's
idiotic
of course this is a controversial
opinion you you you use then see oh all
these list first they'll say oh sorry
it's an idiot because yeah
but I'm telling you
this Marcos is like
petty petty when you when you when you
actually sing when you're actually
seeing a terminal writing system
okay not comparable they are they are
actually this kind of the same thing in
nature basically what so what is at
least Marco Lis Marco Marco is a feature
of the programming language that
transforms your syntax okay so for
example you see so for example here is a
uh let's pick a short short code here's
a function
start delete left child selection let's
pick something we can understand okay so
okay so
okay show key or ring okay so this
function
I can call it and then it will show all
my past cut copy and cut you know the in
other words it's called clipboard
in emacs you have history of old audio
copy you know text you copy so so that's
the command show curing this function
uh why are we talking about that because
I want to show um Marco I wanted to what
oh yeah I want to tell you what is this
marker so you see here's a function so
what does least Marco what it does it is
that the better a better name is syntax
transformation Transformer okay syntax
Transformer okay so you can write the
macro
hi why I won't be writing it I I I don't
you know I don't have I don't use Marco
much so you can write a marker basically
you just transform
this a given parameter into something
else
okay transformation of syntax okay
that's what this macro is and how how is
how does it do that it requires two
things one symbolic your language must
be symbolic or these function names
function names and variable names they
must be symbolic you know it just
doesn't you know it must remain symbolic
so you can manipulate the function names
and variable names you can
manipulate them as a program then I'll
put a different syntax you know that's
what this macro is transformation syntax
Transformer okay that's a better name so
next time you hear about this Marco
think of it as syntax Transformer okay
oh God then in so in in ufam language
is a term rewriting system so in this
you know maybe once in a while you write
a marker in Wolfram language if you look
at wolfen language source code half of
your code is all Macross almost 90
percent of you so wuframe language one
way to think of it is
like a lisp but all your code all your
functions every function is macro okay
the lispers don't and they never they
never sing in their life including many
of these common these experts they've
been coding these companies closer this
for 10 years for 20 20 years but they
have never ever seen a single line of
terms rewriting
language you know that's glorified it's
a full these market system they never
they never they don't know because they
don't understand theoretical uh
computation they don't no you know they
are the average industrial programmers
so that's that's why they don't know so
when it comes to debate you know
argument opinions they just Post
opinions uh garbage okay so at least
Marcus and
okay so so we were talking about the
Wolfram language and least their
relation okay not the small okay so so
here's that's one article you should
read you know history you know this man
APR route of Mathematica okay that's one
article and the other article
uh this one okay let's reverse the odor
so I want that one to be first then that
okay show in browser
okay so the other article here lisp
versus language okay magnify so
so remember before we gave we gave five
characteristics of lisp languages now in
this page in this article it's a full
detail where I
put side by side every lisp functions
and features in this
I put on the other side the Wolfram
language equivalent okay so first first
of all uh you know identifiers are
symbols okay symbolic symbolic
computation okay symbols identifiers or
identifiers are symbols
so what does that mean basically it
means when a variable you can
a variable that doesn't just become its
value
in Pascal
in Python in Ruby in Peru in Java in
JavaScript in C in C plus plus all of
them when you define a variable the
variable becomes the value okay you
cannot you cannot say what's a variable
name you cannot you know it doesn't make
sense once you have a variable variable
is the value
you cannot see it okay it just you the
you know as a program you only you know
that variable is not symbolic in this in
woven language
variable or function names identifiers
they are symbols that means you can
manipulate them okay you can you can
tell the program to not evaluate them
that's that's what made macro possible
okay so in movement language
identifiers are symbols everything is
the expression just like this expression
is either Atomic expression
or a list you know so everything is at
least and what's a atomic expression
those are numbers numbers strings and
symbol okay
you know so pure the United States
syntax yes
predominantly functional programming yes
be the marker yes so you are looking at
you see in this these are reader markers
okay
you see so in this you know the square
bracket that stands for a vector
you know when the compiler the list
compiler reads a square bracket it
transforms it into parentheses with
Vector in front so
so read the marker is a is a is a
transformation of a syntax as well okay
so
so here are some of the reader markers
characters you see in this
and wufan language has a lot more where
I give a full complete list of them in
this article okay a lot more an example
code for example example code
so let's go back
so read the Marcus and this Marcos okay
pattern matching symbolic pattern
matching okay
uh okay so anyway so this article is a
full comparison of least entities in
Wolfram language
you know side by side so in lisp your
syntax is like that parenthesis then
fabc you move a language is parenthesis
square bracket ABC with comma in between
so you have you know syntax comparison
comment syntax and you have how do you
print in lisps is usually just print in
movement language is also a print how do
you do arithmetics you know you have
lists on one side wolf and language on
the other and and so on okay
how do you do if statements you know if
same thing conditions
same thing well in this view called Con
c-o-n-d in communities in e-max this in
wolfen language you have two you have
switch or which you know okay and you
know so
while while loop map car map C two times
cons this Vector so every element in in
every list function I give you the
analog in wufan language
okay
so the purpose of this article is just
just to show you how how they are uh in
a sense you you know wolfen language is
a lisp
if you ask Stefan wolfam
and you know he wouldn't say that I mean
well I mean he the way of of course
because he that's his language you know
he thinks you know this is actually much
more inferior which is true
which is you know true but historically
you know lisp is a fundamental
structure different you know the
fundamental
um
influence in design
you know so that's wolfam language so
that's why you know so I I I give this
the purpose of this page is to
to to prove or to show to reinforce the
idea how they are how they are similar
okay Wolfram language and this okay
let me talk about Pi edit okay Pi edit
so
foreign
so I re I watched the three-seater demo
from emacs conference and he said it is
similar to Pi edit of the most
ridiculous
crap
three seaters similar to Pi edit okay
okay so let's go back to Pi edit okay
you know before we expand what is a lisp
and what's the least nature which is
required knowledge
before we actually talk about power edit
because again remember what is pi edit
Pi Pi that is a Emax package that for
helping you add at least code
okay so you need to understand what this
code the list syntax what what is the
nature what you know the least syntax
first before you can fully understand
what power added to okay but now let's
go to uh Pi edit let's let's uh let's
get the um website
so I talked for uh well already an hour
so
uh so power edit is written by this guy
okay actually
um
you know it's written by uh old emac old
lisp hacker okay so that's why you know
you there's no GitHub for it because
he's before GitHub time like me you know
when GitHub was there we we don't want
to use it because that's some kids new
kids in town in this thing so we don't
put our code into GitHub that's the
reason
so where is it so yeah God so I mean
actually today there's a lot packages
that's that improved upon paid piloted
and named uh and they named themselves
something else for example this one
called smart paren
so they all got the idea from Pilot and
tried to improve it pirate is one of the
old thing like for 20 years 20 years or
more
uh where is it
but um
but it's not part of emacs though so I
don't think it's it's ever included per
edit
yeah so it's not part of emacs
but where the is the you know
oh there okay so pilot get repository
okay it's on the gnu
wait pie editorg so it has its own
there that's a guy Taylor R Campbell
Campbell
you know I I I I I chatted with him on
IRC back in 2005. I asked him
I don't know you know um so you know you
often my opinions don't don't agree with
these people like I asked him long ago
you know I want a auto format I don't
want pilot and he says that oh that's
impossible to do it's very idiotic
but you know
so I don't you know I I don't know this
guy too much except that we just chatted
one time oh hey I'll see 15 years ago uh
so but he's a lisp expert okay that that
he is a lease expert and I would say he
knows coding this
or emac this better than me even okay
but so but when it comes to some syntax
design issues I don't you know I I don't
think we agree and I don't think you
know uh
um you know like I find it strange like
because you know anyway so this is a guy
who wrote it um and what
what else to say
um
so okay to the original question okay
so power edit you know so
I don't have it installed and I actually
I never used it because I refuse once I
know how it works you know how the
nature I refuse I never use it
in fact you can find of one of my
article just search for
sorry info
go to search
there it is pi edit smart parents this p
and Ergo emacs stuff like Keys that's
one article and
the other article is
why I don't use Pi edit okay so you open
you so if you want to know read this
article okay so let's copy the link here
uh so let's put it here
okay two articles
so
yeah I have to look at my articles
um anyway but I want what I want to say
is that um
so before I read my article I can tell
you so what they are thinking probably I
might be wrong so these people they are
the way they think about power edit is
that they think it's a semantic based
at um editing that means so what does
semantic based editing let me show you
okay
so here's a list code let's copy it
paste it to a new buffer and turn on
side emac this mod okay so what what
does semantic based editing means for
example let's go to somewhere okay so
let's uh
okay so for example here is a if
statement so you can see there is a if
statement if
this is true then do this otherwise
kneel okay
you know actually here you can better
you can
anyway this is That's So anyway here's a
if statement so
normally when you let's say you want to
um
remove this if statement
okay you are a programmer you want to
delete this if statement you don't think
you need it okay so what you do is you
you know delete uh what
you know you you just started to delete
right so you you keep pressing delete
until until the whole if statement is
gone
something like that but now your Lambda
is empty but anyway that's the example
okay but let's undo
undo undo and do and do okay
so once you delete a for example in the
middle of your editing your your code
becomes invalid
the you know you are missing your
parents here you know during the editing
your code becomes invalid syntax Okay so
so what's the autonomous alternative for
example you want to delete the whole if
statement you just in like sorry
it is smart you press one key
that whole
if statement is gone and your code
remain valid
okay that
is what semantic editing means your code
always remains valid okay
that's what
semantic editing means and that is what
these people who are excited about Pi
edit
means so they they they say they think
that Pi edit is a semantic
editor meaning that at no time
your syntax is invalid you basically you
edit by code unit okay so for example
so for example here is the variable name
found you
you either you know you you press one
key you just remove that whole variable
you know so here is the arrow expression
you press one key remove that whole
expression you never
when you added your code you are never
in a situation where you created invalid
you know
interim called that's invalid you never
happen so this concept is a very
powerful concept
okay and and
coupled with the lisp syntax because
it's all regular necessary syntax it
becomes super powerful
so that's how I work with my code
because uh SAR code you know delete that
or delete that or delete this whole
function
undo delete undo you see that's semantic
editing and in the same way you can do
that with HTML you see here's HTML code
you know so here is a
list okay let's go to the top about the
author okay so for example here's this
here is the about the author
uh you see there so I can select that
header
select more
delete it
back to browser refresh you see at no
time my syntax HTML syntax is invalid
this is called semantic editing okay
as opposed to you know about the author
so you're gonna you know you're gonna
um let's see if I can do it so so you
know
although you got a invalid syntax and
later on you forgot you you know you are
editing somewhere else then your
your language you know your source code
is fact
okay
okay semantic editing okay in no time
your your syntax is invalid that's what
semantic editing means and that is
part of
what pi edit does
am I am I am I making myself idiotic if
I claim that I believe I believe
I believe that's the case okay it's it's
so if you yeah it is the case Okay so Pi
that is a Editor to help you edit a lisp
code
uh in a semantic way okay meaning at no
time you your synags is invalid okay but
but it's not it's not a it's not a pure
semantic editor okay that's what I'm
trying to say that's my point and this
is an important point
Pi edit helps you do semantic editing
but a note but it's not a complete
semantic
editing system because even if you use
Pi edit you can still
delete one parenthesis if you want you
know because it doesn't prevent you from
pressing the back delete key or you know
forward DD key doesn't prevent that
okay and and and there comes the problem
so so let's get back to are you still
here one so am I like repeating myself
am I like getting uh boring
so that's the so that's what they are
thinking so so these programmers you
know this these programmers they think
part edit is one of the most fantastic
thing
I agree it's very you know it's useful
in particular because it it makes it
possible for you to edit list code
semantically in a semantic way
but however it does not prevent you from
editing your code it's not pure okay
it's not hundred percent it doesn't
force you into
purely you know only added by semantic
way okay that's one thing but the other
thing about Pi edit is that that's the
most damaging part that is the reason I
don't use it
is that when you use Pi edit
even though it does you does help you
edit semantically but there's a major
problem it if you use Pi that it induce
you to
to to to to
manually format your code like almost
every every at every Point manually like
manually indent like uh like indent this
part
uh oh my God you know it it forced you
to you know I don't have it installed so
and I'm using some okay let's switch to
um let me Demo okay let's switch to emac
this mod meta X
the
you know the building iMac be smart so
now we are not inside emac this mod
anymore we are in a building like this
so here you can see if I added
oh I still have stuff like this well
I'm using soft light Keys which which
has this semantic edit feature so but
what's my point okay so let me let me do
this okay so for example you can you
know if I remove this indentation
there's no
way for me to press a key to
indent this whole block I have to intend
this line wait
oh God I I have to configure it
um
you know it it doesn't help you know you
see that's a problem this is a problem
that doesn't doesn't help you
you know it doesn't do automatic
formatting things like that and that is
a major problem because it induced you
to manually reformat your code because
for example this this piece of code
uh this piece of code is supposed to be
is supposed to be formatted like
like
that according to the emac this
convention okay but if you are using
some flag keys
you know let's let's uh let's if you are
using PSI emac be smart it's called
okay so if now I want to format this
whole code I just go anywhere inside it
press tab
there it is
yeah let's re let's redo you see you see
this I can jump around Pi that also lets
you do this you see you can jump to the
you know to to wherever uh
you know you can jump to wherever the
the unit of the beginning and end unit
of a
uh
syntactical unit okay so if I want to
you know purify this whole code inxa in
inside iMac be smart I just press the
key and it's done
with power edit no
okay that's my main point that's the
main answer okay
that is my answer to your original
question Hua okay so these people you
know oh oh they're small okay let me
finish that five more minutes and
they'll be done
so first of all probably that is a
semantic editor helper that helps you
edit this code
that's good
but however it's not a pure semantic
editor meaning that you can still
create code that's invalid because it
doesn't prevent you
to to always use the private ways okay
in fact in practice that's that's what
you do often you know so when you so
that's my point when you use Pi edit you
actually often still create invalid code
it simply helps you you know in in some
ways okay
and then
Pi that doesn't support automatic
formatting okay which is essential which
is essential
in in in in a sense of the semantic
editing okay
that's okay that's one thing that's
that's about the nature of Pi edit and
that is why
I do not recommend power edit why I
don't use Pi edit you can read this
article okay why I don't use Pi that and
then another article
uh probably added smart paren DSP you
know smart parent is another
package came out 10 years ago around
2008 or so let's kind of build upon
party I don't know I don't remember it's
a fork or it's just uh but basically
they all borrowed the idea from PI edit
so smart parents like the new the the
the Zuma Generations one so new one and
this piece another one they are all
borrowed they all borrows ideas from pie
that pie that is the granddaddy okay
but in my opinion they all all of them
all of them have the same flaw
they don't support automatic formatting
code that's a major problem and they
induce you to ditto with your code ditto
like diddling like ditto oh this one
this this one should be intended this
way you know they all do that
they'll do that okay they they they just
not do that they induce you to do that
because if you use them you know you
habituate yourself with the way they
walk coding your list code then your
title your your do this detailing a lot
a lot that is my main point
so that is why I don't I don't think I
don't like them okay
no my I'm expressing I'm expressing my
opinions here maybe a bit too strongly
okay maybe but but I hope you see my
main point
that is they induce manual diddling and
they they are not actually fully
semantic editors okay
but
you know I want to say these are great
people you know they they could they
they write this code they
um actually I should uh add back the
link so let me let me let me do that for
example
uh oh I up the URL
so let's open that open that page uh
what
oh yeah I forgot HTTP uh http
just refresh it copy the link back to
emacs
paste it here open it
show in browser so here's a local copy
of that article so what I want to do is
go back to emacs
uh search for git so here I want to
linkify it linkify it show in browser so
now it's better because at one time I
removed all links on all my website you
know seven seven thousand files I
removed all links to these major
commercial websites because they are
scums you know and First Press GitHub uh
being bought by Microsoft anyway I
should some of them I should add back so
here is the Smart parents by Foucault
he's a great guy okay by Foucault he's a
expert you know so again this came
around
the small Korean came around 2010 maybe
uh oh 2014.
wait no it it came around 2008 or
something like that okay you can do
smart parent is one of the derivative
of Pi edit and there is the least p
now I don't know if they are exactly a
fork or not but I don't I don't remember
I never used them anyway so Abu Abu of
course I know that guy Abu Abu he wrote
a lot
very popular
um emacs packages so
okay so I what I want to say is that you
know they are great people okay they are
great people and they have great
packages you know I trust I fully trust
their code works great
but however I have my own opinions about
I think they are
I think you know they're great packages
great people but I think they are
interested their idea the fundamental
idea about the way they the thing they
created is harmful
and it's of inefficient okay it's
harmful and inefficient too if you are a
professional this coder okay because it
makes you do more work it makes you
manual diddling with your code and
format okay that is my opinion
okay that's all that is all one more
thing one last thing about three-seater
okay three seater is a parser okay this
three-seater these packages they are not
passes okay understand they are not
passes they are just like well well they
they have a bit passer feature based on
emac lisp
um building functionalities so they they
do pass this code a little bit but they
are far as far as password goes they are
far far a magnitude inferior than three
seater
okay three-seater is a real password
designed to pass syntax on the Fly and
and incrementally they are not this this
pirated smart parents needs to be not
are not comparable
okay so when so if someone say oh tree
seater is just like power added that's
that's idiotic that's that's
incorrect okay that's all I want to say
you know I want to thank many of the
emacs the live developers okay did you
know great people but I have you know
some sometimes I think my opinion is
different and
and I think they are uh incorrect okay
so
let me okay let me cover one more thing
three minutes we shut down okay one more
thing
because this is the pen in the ass a pen
a major opinion yes by this this
phonetics they I think you know great
people but they they don't know what
they are do you know they don't have the
overall General view of things that's
why that's what they are Geeks like the
Linux people like Linux trovert
high IQ you know extremely smart he can
create kernel operating system he can
create git
highly complex but they don't they don't
see the overall design of things so they
so their products such as Linux and git
is extremely complex it's suitable for
nerds for themselves for you have to go
learn this and trick this button and get
this you know lick you know trick this
button turn this and adjust this knob
and you need to put a jumper here
otherwise it doesn't work that's what
they are Linux git
pirated smarter in lispy okay do you see
what I mean do you get the overall since
so what should you do what what is the
proper way to do things what is your
opinion what
okay my opinion is three seater
that is a proper solution and automatic
formatting what I want is press a button
it formats the whole file Auto format
predified whole file hold directory 45
or files in your directory let me I want
to emphasize this this part okay so let
me show you
uh and that's it for today okay so I
want to emphasize this part because this
is critical
so I want to yeah so he uh three seater
so so here again we I talked about this
for one hour yesterday so what do you
want
is
go format so you have go format press
the button formats your entire code
doesn't matter it's ten thousand lines
or hundred thousand lines you press one
button one thousand lines is formatted
okay go land
python someone wrote that in Python 2
okay in fact you have you have more than
two of them the most popular is
yapf and black okay
here's my instructions how to use it and
in fact I have integration with emacs
okay for all these python Pro I mean
JavaScript Powershell
and uh and uh JavaScript Powershell or
Golia and python okay so Golan can do it
python can do it JavaScript you can do
it too press the button format 110 000
lines hundred thousand lines I've tried
it you know I tried I tried this with
000 lines something like that the the
the the source code of typescript
it's done within one second
source code of typescript
I forgot how large you know have you
know it's like uh
50 Mega but I I forgot but it's huge
okay 50 at least 50 000 lines of code in
one single file
you press the button formats the all
whole thing within half a within one
second okay
which one is it demo yeah I believe
that's so that's 10 okay Daniel fmt okay
that's how you do it
uh then you have also available for
Powershell you can also do that for
Powershell
okay Golan python JavaScript Powershell
you can all do that
can you do that in lisp no
that this the parent pirated
fact that these idiots okay you do you
understand why am I angry
you know after 20 years at least the
least syntax is the most easy to do
automatic but you don't have it you
don't have it why because the power
added and these others you know they
they watched
phonetics they don't they watch people's
brain so people don't get the idea they
don't know
they don't know
where are all these other more complex
languages with more you know ad hoc
syntax they all have Auto formatter you
know you have a few of at least for
example
this one
semantic refactor
you know you try it within five minutes
it fails it fails miserably what the
these people I don't understand
they are they are Advanced code you know
you you try it you know within five
minutes it fails
you know it screws up your code your
code becomes invalid after you call it
you you try to reformat it what the
and you know semantic refactor they all
sound very fancy you know here's a
semantic refactor
you know excuse me for ranting okay
these people are good people they do
what they do but I just want to express
my opinion okay then there's another one
okay so here semantic refactor fail then
this this one uh called
um
I'm sorry the ideas man you know he's he
he's sometimes on my Discord uh you know
a great guy but his code also failed
you know he claims here it works you
know on this or these uh or this but it
fails
he fails okay that's the situation
that's a that's a situation of the this
extremely insulting situation this
syntax is the most regular yet yet all
these languages now have you know Auto
format but you you don't have one for
lisp
foreign
guys that's it
donate okay donate to me if you like my
video
paste it to your Twitter or whatever put
a timestamp uh in the you know in the
YouTube comments
and you can go to my website
PayPal me you know put your money uh to
people
where they did you service okay that's
how we want to uh have a good Society
bye guys
so we shutting down so let me just uh
let's see I want to yeah so let's copy
that code I want to put the links in my
talk show
so make sure I didn't screw up code here
okay that's important article
okay this p
you know they have a lot popular you
know 1 1 000 Stars
oh these are and this one smart
appearance 1.6 000 Stars
oh
very popular you know but not good
we uh yeah we have that already close
bye bye