good morning everyone
welcome to another episode of star talk
show
video check audio check i'm good to go
today is 2021
july 21st today we are going to do
emacs lisp coding for the first 20
minutes or so
then probably wufam language coding
just like yesterday so um
yup so if you have comments questions
post it okay
so let's let's start coding emac beast
okay so let's see
what are the things i want to do so
so here is a write a command to combine
html skip tag backward and html skip tag
forward
okay so hey emily good
good evening uh so emac is coding so we
are going to code html
so here is what we need to do today
show in browser so yeah that's the one
so let me explain what is it that we
going to do so okay so
tag forward okay so you see let's
magnify this so you see
there is a uh end tag
now i want to jump to the beginning tag
i want to move cursor to the beginning
text so what i do there is a command
now if you look at the pink window you
will see
so i call this command i press two keys
you see
my cursor is here so that command is
called
uh skip tag backward now if i'm on this
tag my cursor is here i want to jump to
the ending
tag i press a key then i'm at the end
now however the problem is that you see
you have two commands
now when you jump to the beginning tag
or the end tag
basically you don't need two command you
just need one command the command can
figure out
whether the current tag is the beginning
tag if so
it will jump to the end tag if it's the
end tag it it'll jump to the
beginning tag you see so that is the
so you don't need two commands because
when you have two commands you have to
think
oh i'm at beginning tag i need to call
uh go to the end tag then you do it you
know
so one command you just go back and
forth
which is similar in e-magle's side
emac be smart for for example let me
show you
uh okay so e-max is smart
defend okay so if i'm kuza is here
i can press one single key look at the
pink window okay one single key
to go back and forth of any uh
parenthesis you see you don't need to
think about whether you are on a
beginning tag or in text so
let's code that this should be uh pretty
easy okay
so emac list
start a empty uh bracket i mean the
empty
buffer then defend
okay then html
jump
[Music]
jump to uh what's the name
begin and tag
okay so the naming
is unsure because
uh because this is too long because html
jump to begin or end
tag this is you know the proper name
would be that but
it's kind of too long so what what is a
better name
hello not not jake uh i'm not sure what
is a better name
so jump to begin or end let's go with
that okay if you have suggestions
posted okay version can you use that to
select
everything between the two tags when you
also hold
shift uh yes you can write a command to
do that
but however i do not recommend any
command with a
i do not recommend the key
uh code key you know typically in
in in programming languages you have
shift select
that is you hold the shift key then you
can press arrow down and
you're selected i turned it off in emacs
uh
so let's save it okay let's save this
and the vs code let's open in vs code
let's show that in vs code so you see
uh can we magnify the cursor yes we can
magnify the window
so i hold down the shift key then i can
press the arrow key that's no good
okay this is a this is a inefficient
way to select text
so close uh close the visual
uh studio vs code do you want to save
changes
don't save okay close the visual studio
so yeah so i recommend do not use shift
select
and uh you know for any command so
rather so the more efficient way is
actually to have a keystroke to begin
actually the most efficient way is you
just have a single key
for a command to select what you want
for example i can select
the current word or i can select the
current line
or i can select the current paragraph
the text block
uh you know uh you know
let me show you the pink window so you
can see okay select current line
or select the current block
or i can you know i can keep pressing
the key
or keep selecting the block or if i'm
selecting a line select the line
i want to select the next line too i can
keep pressing the key
or if you want generic selection you
know for example from this to here
then you what you the efficient way is
to have a
command that start the beginning of
selection then you
then you move your cursor to wherever
you want okay so don't use
shift select that's a inefficient way
okay so let's go back to the code okay
so let's
uh so begin to jump to um
yeah we want to write the tag okay so
this
the name is this descriptive enough
now let me find out what's the command i
need to call okay let
we are starting to write this um
oh actually the command call is here
already so
let's put them here okay so here we have
basically we're gonna we are going to
first of all
determine whether the cursor is on a
beginning tag or end tag
then call one of this command okay so
that is easy because i already have a
code to do it so let's open a new
window let's look at some html mod okay
so this
is
so go to
space space space edge that is the
keystroke to turn on
html mod then you go to the source code
then you
[Music]
these matching lines all lines about
different
one there is a command that tells you
whether you are
opening tag or in text so there it is
site html is opening tag p
now p stands for predicate in e-max
in lisp in general the there is a naming
convention
when a function ends in p that means
that function is a predicate
which means basically that function
returns true or false
now this is so in commonly speaking emac
but in scheme disk they use a question
mark
at the end instead which is a better
convention
because you know petacut is from logic
predicate
but the programming language predicate
the meaning of credit card is actually
different from the logic's predicate
kind of similar but but actually very
different
because in logic a predicate is actually
a statement
that says it's true of you know it when
you have a credit card
is make a statement in a programming
language when you have a predator
it just returns either true or false
okay so in logic
you see this is a pen that's a predicate
you know it's not a question in
programming languages
you know is this a pen dash p in
in lisp that's a question it returns
either true or false so that's a
major difference but anyway that's a
convention you uh predicate okay
and by the way in mathematica in wolfram
language the convention is using q okay
i'm starting to digress
but you know but why not we i have
article on that
so you go to xr home page
then then you go to uh
yeah this is interesting you know
because i've been doing
this coding live for so many videos
let's uh digress a little bit
so you go to um syntax soup
semantic noodle let's try semantic
noodle and search for
preda cut okay it's not here then you go
to
comp land perving all these videos are
great you should go watch it okay
complain perving
then search for predicate
and where is it syntax soup
uh let's go to syntax search for
predicate there it is
computer language predator function
terminology and naming convention let's
open that
magnify so here in this article i
explore the the meaning of first first
of all i explain the meaning of
predicate
in logic and in programming language
okay meaning of predicating logic and
computer science
then actually it should be computer
primary languages
okay then i explain the various
conventions in programming languages
on how they name the you know how they
name their functions predicates so in
emaclis
you have all these examples of
predicates
integer p function p file readable p
file exists p string p symbol p
but actually it's not very consistent in
this
because you see
so ideally any function if it
ends in a dash p then that returns true
or false
but that's not the case in emac these at
least
and i don't think that's the case in
commonly needed
because first of all you have
inconsistency of synth
of the syntax of the naming okay so some
ends in dash p
sum does not end in dash p okay that's
first problem
it's a problem okay language design
problem
of the lisp of the
of the lisp faction now this
also this besides that
also it's not true that any function
named
ends in p means it's a predicate so
do we have an example did i show example
here yeah
for example here you see pop
define group make sparse key map
forward sex you know those functions
ends in p
but that's not a those are not predicate
they don't return
true or false so lisp this is a
flaw in this programming language design
okay
now we look at scheme lisp and closure
list
they are they did better they did
excellent
any predator if a function ends you know
their name ends in a question mark that
means
it returns true or false that's it
period
simple logical and uh systematic
consistent
no exceptions okay great language
design of the syntactic this is you know
naming of things belong actually belongs
to the syntax
syntactic issue of the language okay
so scheming closure this great design
now wufang language you know wufang
language went one step further okay
that's why i love wufang language the
design of language in wolfram language a
predicate always
name ends in a queue capital q for
question
okay why because you know
when you design a language you actually
think about things you know
so why do they list for example this
will scheme this
closure this they end in p well that's a
tradition that's a
you know computer science tradition p is
predicate okay predicate
but who understand what is what the
is the predicate you know
so in wufang language you know stefan
wufam he has you know he has
his way of thinking which oftentimes i
agree with
so he just named it q q stands for
question okay
if a function ends in q capital q it's
it returns either true or false
uh but why not question mark well
question mark is actually a better
a better system well wufam language
cannot use
a question mark because question mark is
used
um it's used on
uh why can they not what did i explain
uh well basically they have a convention
okay in wufang language there's a naming
convention
every blm function is a camel case
starting with the capital letter and no
punctuation symbols whatsoever so
every function is just a
alphanumeric um
sequence of camel case no punctuations
that's why they cannot use
a question mark so you can see there are
several design
issues and constraints once they decided
this is the naming convention for all
functions
then of course then you have the
disadvantage where you cannot use you
have not you cannot have a question mark
in your language but however you see
there is also a flaw with
question mark you see yeah it's great if
you have a
system where any function ends in
question mark
means it's a predicate return true or
false but however you got a problem now
now if you allow question mark in
function names then
what's you know there's no prevention of
any of people naming
something question mark that okay
so people can use that as a function
name
you know so what does that mean you know
it's so you got
other disadvantages okay but anyway
wufang language they choose the
convention of ending
queue as a pelican okay and here are all
basic yeah i think that's not
uh these are not all of them they are
more
and ruby okay ruby is also a great
design they follow the scheme this
tradition ending in queue so that's
great so okay
that's a digression of a digression of
about the naming of predicate in
programming languages
and what does it mean in logic okay so
let's go back to talk show and comment
okay
uh back to talk show and let's
post these we talked about okay now
let's go back to code
emaclis
uh where is it so wufam language
okay so uh close that close that let's
raise up this code here
okay so so yeah we're gonna call this
function
good morning pablo
so actually writing this function should
be easy okay
uh open is open tag okay
let's let's create a variable set
that variable and uh that is
our variable so then
if actually we don't even need the
variable so let's uh
well let's let's keep going let's not
first about
you know the formatting or style style
of coding stuff
so if it's open hack then skip tag
forward okay
then otherwise skip tag backward okay
pretty find the code that's it evaluate
the code
then copy that let's go to html
uh let's go to html so uh
what is this page programming block okay
close close close
go to talk show go to let's test it okay
so let's put the cruiser here okay
then call metax
exact html jump to begin or end tech do
it
fantastic now move the cursor here
call it fantastic now what if the cursor
is here
will it consider this or will it
consider
that so let's i don't know let's try it
okay it actually consider this tag when
your cursor is here
um you know anyway that's those those
are
edge cases you have to so
basically we are done with this function
but however we need to refine it
you know we have to consider about edge
cases for example if my cursor is here
you know between this end tag and
between that open tag
where does it jump to does it jump to
here or does it jump to
you know there so you know
we i don't know i don't know let's try
it
okay it jumps to the top in this case
what
what what if my cruiser is here let's uh
let's try it okay still jump to the top
top but if the cursor is here it jumps
to there
if the cursor is here okay i'm not sure
exactly
exactly what is the behavior so anyway
that we have to refine that
and in order to do that we have to find
out what
yeah what what what this function do
exactly when
uh when it is um between open
and closed tags uh yeah
but first of all we can
okay i think i should i should move on
to wufam language
shall we so we talked about 30 minutes
great yeah
so delete that paste it here
prefi showing browser fantastic that's
our code
uh let's move on to firm language
shall we yeah because i've been doing so
much emac this
in the past few months i want to do some
okay we don't need that
in window anymore
unless you guys have some questions you
want to bug me
um then we're gonna otherwise i'm going
to go
into a wu fam language coding bulk
cube bulk cube is fantastic
oh it's actually this is this this is
not bulk cube this is just me testing
something
uh what is this this is not bulk
cube this is testing
internet okay this one i believe it's
testing its plotting
internet speed growth
over the over the decades you know
basically you want to know how fast
does internet speed grow you know we
know that the cpu speed grows about
1.5 times a year something like that you
know they say double every
every one and a half year or something
or two years uh
the hard disk also grows
similarly so but how about the internet
speed
okay so that's what this is about i have
an article on that
let's let's let's go show it okay so
go to software page go to there
and go to technology pass in the future
then you go to do we have a chart here
internet speed
basically it grows like also similar to
1.5
times a year yeah
here so internet speed growth rate
so yeah so i you know this is a plot
from that notebook
and uh you know it's i need to do this
in javascript
yeah so basically equals 1.5 times
the factor of 1.5 a year and
right now i have 160
let's see how let's see how much is my
speed can we
my internet speed google google does it
let's run it
sucks it sucks it should be like
it should be like 100 at night i think
you know usa internet speed is pretty
low
in comparison to uh many other countries
70 megabytes 70 megabits
per second upload so that's slower
also because right now i'm doing live
stream
uh okay so that's uh that's that
so this is wufam language
uh you know i want to tell you okay
anyway this is not too interesting okay
this is just a
bar chart uh i want to do
actually i don't know what
i want to do okay this is a notebook i
did like
um 20 20 23 years ago
uh and today
today there is a lot you know today
there is a built-in graphics primitive
for drawing tubes you see what i want to
draw here is three
tubes you know headaches helical tubes
you know this is done
in do i have a year 1997 or so something
like 1997.
okay and uh but today so so the way i
did it
is that you you
you know you build you you build each
and every
of these um can we still evaluate it
let's
let's try okay continue with updated
starting okay
do it okay uh clear
do i need uh oh yeah i need geometry
rotations that's obsolete
uh so i cannot if i run a code it will
not
work because this package
is obsolete about 2006 i think
because in 2006 mathematic mathematical
version 6 they have all these functions
filled in so instead instead of using
the function in a package
all those functions are building so
anyway uh so the way i did it you know
you start with
three circles then you extrude you know
extrude is a
operation in 3d geometry you basically
like you like you grow buildings okay
but every time you go at you
you move it a little bit so that's how i
build these
uh graphics then you then you
build the polygons the triangles between
between the two circles so it's quite
tedious
but today you can draw this
to you know since 2006 or or something
you know
it's been 20 something years there's a
building primitive let's try to do it
shall we
uh you know if i do this it's not going
to be useful to myself
because actually i wanted to do
something uh
more relevant aloha aloha braveheart
are you in hawaii
so let's get in touch with you guys what
are you guys
doing so uh should i
should i try to generate this using
you know ufam language or should i do
something else
because i was thinking of doing working
on my
my tithings package which we talked
about yesterday
plain tidings okay
you know all these packages i need to
work on
any comments
transform 2d plot okay
uh which we talked about dubai
oh in dubai amazing wow
so do you speak do you speak arabic
are you are you are you uh
are you uh you know you you are born in
mid-east
arabian are you like how do you describe
the race uh
of people there
so uh
let's try it let's try the tube okay
since we've been talking about that
so actually so um
oh so you do so you are so amazing
uh
okay so what i want to do so i want to
helix cubes untitled uh
let's graphics 3d
okay
let's turn on help
magnify graphics
3d so
i want to um find the tube
primitive okay so the structure of
graphics
interactive graphics uh polygons
polyhedra
the structure of graphics okay
now that's too that's that's kind of too
much i need to find
the primitives building symbols
let's go to um
solid geometry
actually we can just search for
so there is the building primitive
tube okay
okay that's getting complex graphics 3d
cube
so tube takes
two arguments the first argument is the
beginning and end position
you know a coordinate two coordinates
the second argument is
thickness okay uh
but i want it to be a curve
so point two point two okay so actually
we can do this easily
yeah so first of all let's draw a single
helix
okay single headaches first of all you
need to
know the parametric equation for the
headaches
which is um
parametric equation for helix
okay that's a space curve uh
that's a space curve do we have um
do i have the formula for parametric
equation of
uh no i don't think so but
act actually we can write it you know we
don't need
we can you know we can write it
so you know because it's simple okay
so let's see
emirati what does that mean
oh
emiratis are the native population and
citizens of the un
united united
arab emirates
uh their largest concentration is in the
uae
where they are about one million okay
oh okay so
interesting okay so
so let's let's write the function let's
write the let's find the parametric
equation
for let's write it okay
let's derive the parametric equation
formula for helix
okay if you search wikipedia it'll tell
you right away
but basically you have x
y and z okay
so basically the formula is x equals to
you know a circle is cosine
t sine t
okay that's a circle now so
essentially yeah so this uh yeah so
basically
so this is what you want
cosine t sine t and t will just
uh be linear okay t will be
z will just be t okay so that is the
formula
now we need this formula to be in kind
of uh math
wolfram language notation okay so
so this is how you do
so you represent the parametric formula
by that
so you can now we can plot it
parametric plot 3d
okay now what is the um
hey bot
okay okay so parametric plot
let's paste our
then t from 0
to 10 okay let's say nine let's see
oh there there we have it fantastic
now let's say
okay yeah that actually that's uh that's
perfect
for our example so now we got a bunch of
so we so let's go back to the tube
so tube takes a bunch of points exactly
so
now we have what we want so we can um
what we can do is that
okay so this is our points we want uh
we want to generate at least the points
okay so the
easiest way is just to use table but i
don't like to use table
so i want to use
so let me yeah so let me show you some
something
fancy okay so i'm going to create a
lambda
which is a pure function so in wolfram
language
this is a pure function okay which can
also be written
as
it which can also be written as
like that like that
okay so then we want to map this
function okay let me just
let me just code it instead of talking
okay let's
then we want to map this function to
to a list of values
so range is just like python's range
from
0 to uh
nine okay in in steps of
0.5 okay
okay so well so so
so that is harder to read this one
so let's write it this way so it's more
intuitive okay
so evaluate so you got the you know
bunch of 3d points
so you want to point you want to put
this inside the tube
inside the tube argument okay so let's
do that
ddos we don't need so so basically
that copy
put it here then the tube thickness
will be 0.2 let's try it oh
[Laughter]
fantastic my friends
fantastic after 20 years
from this lousy image
and much ado coding it now we have
just this single line of code
and and the and the rendered you know
rendered
you know this got thousands 10 000 you
know
polygons now this is you know this you
can rotate
you can you know this you know it's
using
your uh graphics card to do it as well
when you um
you know i wish i can regenerate this
one but but
but it will take me some you know 20
minutes to actually
recode these so we can compare two
different versions
so anyway we once we have one of them we
can create
uh more of them so you know just like
the
the one on the right side so let's do it
okay so table so tube
so tube this is one of them okay copy
copy uh actually you know i i
i type fast much better in in
um in uh
in the emacs okay so basically we
we want we want uh
let me show you okay so so so this is
what we got
this one we want to turn that into
uh actually let's let's let's
stop this idiocy let's use the
you know the advanced way
i'm just going to show you the power you
know the advanced
fan language syntax instead of the
easier to understand but more cumbersome
notation of the function
so this this is the lambda
where the pound sign the the number sign
stands for arguments
so pound sign means the first argument
equivalent to pound sign one so if you
have pound sign two that's the second
argument that represents the second
argument
then then this uh ampersand
symbol is a syntax shortcut
to represent the function so you know i
explained this many times okay so
actually let me let me do it again let
me explain
one more time okay so this i'll show you
several equivalent syntax for these
these okay so that's also equivalent to
that
and that is also equip equivalent to
that okay so all these three are
equivalent
okay and then this is also equiv
equivalent to um
that okay so you see
all these four are equivalent e
syntactically equivalent i did a video
about three or four months ago just
search on youtube
that i explained this uh
you know meta syntax in detail so now
anyway so so
so so now anyway so so we have this one
so let's go back to here so
you know so that works you can see it
does work
but we need three of them
each one will be rotated a little bit so
so so let's see the beginning point uh
x y okay so basically you just want to
add
cosine sine okay so it's
cosine sine
you want to start at a different point
you know we we want to rotate the helix
basically
so cosine sine you want to
uh plus t okay plus
plus uh how much how many degrees
120 degrees so so
a full circle is pi is two pi
okay so a full circle is two pi
radian then one third of it is two pi
over three okay so you basically want
that
okay plus that okay so you can see
so that okay so for example we can
plot our tube yeah okay you can you if i
rotate it you cannot see it but anyway
so let's um
okay let's do this okay
then where's the tube function
copy
copy back to emacs
so
uh wait
yeah so this is what we want okay let's
try
i'm pretty sure it'll work do it
fantastic now we just
need one more what more
fantastic man okay copy that let's just
uh one more
all right uh
yeah i need i i i need to write a
wolfram language mod in emac this
so that i can you know type in e max
so uh divided by three
so one over three two over three times
two over three
times uh where is my key
okay this is kind of stupid but this is
actually the intuitive intuitive way to
write this
so this okay so anyway let's not talk
too much let's
just do that copy it
do it fantastic okay
yeah so
that's what we uh want a twisty pipe
okay i think uh maybe that's it for
today
i got lots of things to do you know i
got
i got you know i need to i need to
update all these
uh transform 2d plot plane titling
and we i really need to work on this
you know it's been delayed for
plane timing we talked about yesterday
you know i need to update this package
but but it's been an hour so i talked
you know
i gonna work on them offline i guess
that's it thank you guys for watching
uh if you like my stuff buy it okay
donate patreon me
paypal you can see all the you know
links on my website
or you can buy my emacs tutorial or
javascript in-depth tutorial
and one more thing i want to say so if
you are interested
in wolfram language it's free you can
um you know you can download it
you know you go to my website just
search for sally
ufam language free then you see this
page
you'll get it free if you buy a
raspberry pi
if you are into kind of you know do it
yourself
stuff or you can download woofam engine
it's free
or download wufram script if you are
kind of the unix
you know you are into bash your
powershell kind of you know you need to
if you want a the most efficient
you know using woofam if you want to use
wufang language
to do sys admin okay if you want a
replacement for bash
for z shell for tc shell for powershell
you know a magnitude more powerful
no more expressive language for doing
those things
you know you download woofam's script
it's which is free okay so it allows you
to use the wufang language just like
you know what you've seen you know the
same syntax everything
to to write a bash script
so that's a wolfram script okay
uh but then if you want graphics you can
download
you know woofam engine but act you know
actually if you don't you know it's free
but you don't get graphics if you want
graphics you you need to go to
you know the the python jupiter project
which they have a package that
integrates with them
uh engine then you know so you have to
download woofam engine and also the
uh the the jupiter you know just search
for jupiter python
woofam engine then you'll you'll be able
to do
basically what i do today or just buy it
i would recommend it
bye guys
go here and go
go to where is my google go
here
yes uh wolfham script
well wolfham wolfham engine works with
uh jupiter you know wolfham engine and
wufang script
they are essentially the same thing they
are just the wolfram language
but however woofam script is is designed
for you just run shot scripts you know
no no graphics no sound no you know
it's just a script so
so so so if you are using jupiter which
is the primary
you know purpose of jupiter is for you
to have a
graphical notebook
therefore it doesn't make sense to use
it with
wolfram script i i think i think it does
i
i think you can i'm not exactly sure
because i haven't
uh installed them you know i'm using you
know they the wolfram
ink they gave me uh you know the
mathematica i'm using
okay bye
okay actually i need to you know have
this
on my screen for a while so that
google youtube will take this as the
main screenshot for my youtube
you know there actually there's more
improvement you see these
kinks you see this kink kink kink
i can remove you know why don't we try
it you know i don't want these
kinks i want it to be smooth so
how do you remove the kinks well you
look at the
documentation for tube
okay so so you know there
there is an option i believe
the radius of the tube can be specified
if no express
explicitly uh okay
okay so you can use also base your curve
oh okay so that's you know
that's probably what i should use
yeah but base your curve you know right
now i'm using line segments to generate
the cube
but if i use space your curve
it's gonna it's more complex you see
this your curve
is um
control points p1
i'm not sure that will work but let's
try okay let's
actually just try it because
you know this is uh this is the
interesting part okay so actually
let's copy that you know let me show you
the you know the power of
language so actually
so you know i i really need a wolfram
language mod
so i can predefine the code in emacs
so instead of tube
yeah so instead of that so i i say here
b e z i e r curve okay
now i hope you don't need extra control
point
okay so base your curve
that's right okay actually just
let's just try that
so okay so let's let's get this
clean
okay so you can see what is going on
no i don't think it works because you
know
actually we need bezier curve 3d
now do they make it uh
it also works in 3d
okay but it might be you know because
when you have a base your curve
you have control points but i'm i'm not
used i don't have any control points so
i don't think you'll work let's just try
it
yeah it's missing you see it's missing
the one we changed
uh but can we fix it quickly
so let me try to do it okay
base your curve so base your curve takes
a bunch of points
okay so actually i think maybe this
okay
do it now
okay anyway that's it