Hello, good evening everyone. Welcome to
another episode of Pasad talk show. We
are going to do code emacisp today.
So this is technical session for emac
lisp coders or I'm going to teach you uh
if you are watching this offline play at
1.5 speed minimum. If you are watching
live say hi love to see your comments.
Okay so let's begin. So uh I'm going to
cover some of the things I've done. Um
so let's begin. Okay. So so for example
when you learn a programming language
it's good to know the top 100 most used
functions. Okay. So here is an example.
So I just updated so you can see if you
are learning eaglist these are the top
top 300 functions. you can go up to 100,
you know. So anyway, so this is like
English, like when you learn a foreign
language like French, uh, German,
Russian, Chinese, you want to know the
top 1,000 most used, most frequently
used words because that's the things you
want to learn first. That's those are
the priority. Hello, KPX,
KBT, XXZ.
What does that mean? Hello hungry man.
Now an announce fantastic an
[ __ ] announce. So you want to learn
the most frequently used words. So here
is a list of them. Okay, it's on my blog
on kasali.info
emac. Okay, search for it, you will find
it. So this is for Emacs 30 updated.
Emacs 30 is released this year. But how
do you get this list? Okay, so here is
the code. Okay. So, uh here is emac this
code so you can actually learn it. Okay.
So, let me let me just demo. Okay. So, I
I already have the code here. Let's just
copy. Okay. So, copy copy.
Make a new buffer. Paste it. Save it.
xx.el.
Okay. Let's just say that. Okay. And uh
fantastic. This is this is uh 56 lines
of code. Now let's just run it. Done. So
you see, so here's the result. Number
one. So now let's show the line numbers.
Press press press press.
Fantastic. Now you can see the line
numbers. Can you see it?
Yes. Okay. So you can see this this is
the most frequently used uh functions.
In fact, all of them uh 5,400 of them.
So So that's a script. Okay. So you can
study it. I won't go through it. Okay.
So let's delete it. We don't care
anymore. Delete it. So there it is that.
Okay. So that is uh demo emac script
count function frequency and the emac
30's most frequently used functions. Set
Q. Obviously when you want to set a
variable if something something if
statement the foundation of a
chewing complete programming language
that's the most essential if
define a function define you know let
declare variables you know and so on.
Okay. So that is that. So let's today's
talk show uh let's search for frequency.
So we talked about that.
Uh so cut move go to go to the top and
uh and uh let's paste it there and okay
so we talked about this and in the past
years you know I've done for Emacs
version 23 year 2020 and Emacs version
uh 23 is year 2010 that's when I begin
to it in the beginning I was using a
python script so you can see where Is
it? Uh, okay. Yeah. So, so here is
the Python script because back then I
was more familiar with Python. So, you
know, I did uh with Python script.
So, anyway, so that's that's that that's
that. Okay. So, let's go to the next
topic. Uh next topic, let's see hasht to
list. Okay. So, let me Okay, let me
organize a little bit. So
uh generic map functions let's combine
the list combine the list okay combine
so all those are about hash tables okay
combine then okay so this section is
about hashts but let me talk about this
thing first okay now in Emacs uh uh not
this one okay so actually so let me get
the link correctly so you can look at my
emac blog I've been busy working on it.
Just search for it on kasali.info
kasal emacs blog. You'll find it.
So you got a few region problems. Okay.
Not that one. Uh yeah. Okay. This one.
Okay. This article. So
So hold on a second. Let me check
something.
Let me close the door.
Okay. So you see in EMAC this you have
this thing called field region which is
a very idiotic name. So what does what
does it do? So for example when you have
a paragraph. So for example this
paragraph. Let's copy it. New buffer.
Paste it
on the pink window. You can see all my
command uh command core names and the
keystroke on the left. I'm using softly
keys and I'm using a vora keyboard
layout. Okay. So for example few region.
So usually you have a you know you type
and type have a long paragraph right
like this. So usually you want to
like in the old days like 1990s you want
to truncate them like no more than 80
lines. So let's turn on ruler mode.
ruler mode. Okay. So you can see how
many number of characters.
So let's Okay. So one line. So you can
call command feel paragraph. Okay. Do
it. So you can you see it cuts each line
no longer than 80 characters. So you see
undo. You see before it's like hundreds
characters. Now you call it field
paragraph then then it becomes multiple
lines. Okay, that's a EMAC command.
However, there's no way to go back. So
if you begin with a uh uh let's say let
let's let's put let's make them very
short. Okay, so if you begin with
multiple lines, there's no way there's
no command to turn this back into one
line. Okay, like like that
I can do it because I'm using Starfly
keys and I have this for reformat lines.
Okay, so this this is uh in the back in
the starting in 1980s because the Unix
idiots, the Unix [ __ ] [ __ ] because
back then their their their system their
programs cannot process long lines.
And when when does the convention of 80
characters per line came from? They it
came from punch cards. Okay,
this is uh you know like Asian
computing history. So in the 1960s
punch cards, okay, it looks like that
you know this is like before I think
even before digital computer era. So you
got this card and this is actually code
you know the the programming code and
you got holes on it you know this is the
way this is like a storage system like
your flash drive you know whatever. So
back then this is what year? Um
1960s n 1890
1890 okay long ago 100 years ago. So
this 80 characters per line convention
came from these punch cards you know
because because convention and habit you
know every generation you change
slightly but you know so we trace it
trace it back like who the [ __ ]
started to say that you know we we need
to like manually you know put a uh line
wrap line return at every characters
that's the punch cards okay but the
idiocy persisted especially because of
the Unix [ __ ] Okay, I talked about
this many times.
Uh and uh so let me quickly show you. So
let's let's quickly show um let's go to
search
uh
Unix email protocol for example. Unix
Unix has this email protocol. Okay.
And in this protocol uh RFCA something
something not not that one. Okay. So
let's see
um
okay so actually you need to search for
RFC
Unix RFC.
Uh
RFC yeah really [ __ ] common. That's
what it stand for. RFC Unix RFC and
Pearl email library 2010. Unix IFC line
truncation that is the one. Okay. So I
document it the damage the history that
you don't usually read it you know it's
there but they they they don't talk
about it. Um things like that. So so
where is it? Uh
where is the article?
Yeah Unix IFC. So this is my previous
like four years ago I talked about it.
Okay. U Unix RFC line truncation. So in
Unix Unix RFC 22 2822 that's for email I
believe that yeah for email protocol
they they say every email sent must be
line must be truncated no more than 80
characters because the Unix idiotic
operating system they cannot process
long lines and even back then even today
I think when you do ps command they
automatically truncate lines like
silently okay so very that. So anyway,
that's where this came from. So and one
of the Emacs so so Emacs has a feature
called field paragraph,
you know, that that automatically
uh reformat it, you know, like field par
uh wait yeah few paragraph, right? So,
but there's no way to go back to long
line. And what typically what they tell
you is that you have to uh set Q
you have to set the field column to like
1 million then call field paragraph
again because every time the command
works by a by a variable called field
column. Okay.
uh
field column there it is okay so by
default it's 70
okay so anyway so how do you get back so
you you you you basically you set Q fo
column to let's say 1 million then you
call field paragraph again so that's how
you do it but that's idiotic so so I
have a command that just uh just
truncated for you okay so wait what what
is I uh
Okay. So this this font is really large.
So you can see I call the command. So
anyway,
so that's the field paragraph idiosacy.
Now I have a question. So let's see. So
I have a lots of articles on that. So if
you want to code, I have several
versions. Uh reformat to long line
region. So you got unfill region and
unfill paragraph and you also got the uh
command that just toggle if the current
line is very long it just do feel if the
current line is multiple lines it just
do an feel okay and also you don't have
to make a selection first because this
this field region you have to make a
selection first so these are very
convenient and but there is another
problem when you are in source code such
as such as eacisp or Goland or C or C++
or or others. Usually you don't want you
know you want to treat sequences of
white spaces to be equivalent. So in
other words when you do feel you don't
want it you don't want the command to
mysteriously add some characters or
remove some characters. Okay. But
unfortunately
that's the emac field command does that.
Okay. So I have a documentation of it of
the fact uh this is written like 10
years ago but the article I just made it
uh independent article this year. So
anyway so it it it automatically adds
whites space when when there was none.
Okay. So what's the example? know the
extra white space in um
yeah for example you can see here it
adds automatically add a white space
before and it also some you know in a
situation like that it will add uh it
will remove asterisk you see when you
have multiple lines it will just remove
it so if if this is programming code you
don't want that okay in because most
programming
language syntax they their whites space
is equivalent. So but you you you can
not allow to add extra character you
know non whitespace characters things
like that. So that's why so field this
field command does not work well if you
are working with a programming language
that's why
that's why you want to uh let's uh
that's why you want to um have a special
command. So that's what that's what my
command do. Okay. So that command name
is kasa format reformat lines. Okay. So
let's see where where is the code. So
you can get the code on sard.info
uh field region problems few paragraph
problems. You can get the code uh reform
reformat lines for source code. Okay.
It's so you know just copy and uh put in
your Emacs in it and you got it. And
here is a explanation in detail what
exactly this function how exactly how it
differs from the FE emac field paragraph
you know ex explains here in this
function it treats all sequence of white
spaces as equivalent and it will never
add extra non white space characters or
remove any sequence of whites space.
Okay. So, that's the key.
So, hello uh from South Korea. JSG.
Uh great to have you here. South Korea.
Fantastic.
Elusive destroyer. What? Okay. So, let's
go back. So, we talked about
field column field region. Okay. So, let
me let me just grab the other code. So
that um
copy cut.
Okay. And paste link
list. Okay. So we talked about this
field issues. Okay. Cut it. Move it to
top.
Fantastic. Now next topic and last
topic.
Let's talk about map function. Well,
maybe that's it for today because my
wife is back. Uh, it's dinner time.
Oh, there's a duplicate. So, test hasht
equality. Okay. So,
let's show all the duplicate. Okay. So,
delete that. Delete that. Fantastic.
Refresh. Fantastic. Now, let's ask Gro,
you know, why is it called field? Okay.
So, let's let's demo. You know today AI
technology it's amazing.
So guac
why is Emacs FO region command called FO
okay let's
have a say
I think that's it for today you know the
other question uh I mean on the hash
table let's talk about it next time
maybe wait we only talked for uh 20
minutes okay we got some more time so
right now it's this is Gawk 4 just came
out last month So in expert
mode, so it takes like a minute or two
for accuracy.
Let's see what it says.
You know, AI is amazing today because
here's what I recommend.
Anytime if you are on Twitter talking to
people, you know, there are billions,
you know, uh millions and millions of
people like they talk about politics or
coding or whatever. Okay,
ignore them like every person like
whatever you they are talking about if
you are interested in what they in that
topic ask. Okay, ask or other AI bots
because the AI bots are like one one
billion times superior more correct uh
than whatever human animals are talking.
Okay, so this is tremendous. This is
like like you have 100 professors around
the clock for you. You can ask any
questions of any field like chemistry I
don't know much physics electronics uh
micro electronics what is microwave
what's a radio frequency how they are
distributed what's the governance you
know what what laws you know controls
them what's signal processing or
mathematics psycho scientry topology
like any any question or any or politics
okay like who is the president who is
the 10th president of USA or what
happens during the 10th president like
list the the most important events you
know like anything everything so here's
what I my recommendation like whatever
you see even talking to your friends you
know like of course usually you talk to
your friends you want to just chat right
know get to know the person whatever but
whenever you want to actually know
something like such as on Twitter like
you have like millions of people talking
about all sort of things ask AI instead
then then then you will know the truth
you'll know you you you will you know
you do it this as a habit you know like
a year you will know you will not be
misled okay you you will know a lot you
know uh a lot better about everything
but of course this does not mean you are
just going to be brainless. Okay, this
is for people who really want to know. I
am an example of such people. You know,
I really want to know like if this is
this true, you know, before Grog
the there is the Wikipedia evolution.
You you know you go to Wikip Wikipedia
then you spend an hour or half hour to
read about math, engineering or politics
or history like like history of China.
Most Americans don't know nothing about
it. You know, they just know CCP CCP CCP
don't know not a thing.
Uh and you know, so China history like
you know China's like 4,000 3,000 years
recorded history. Um so you can ask you
know so so you can ask all sort of
things. Um but you have to but this is
not for someone who does not wish to
know. Okay. One such example are college
students. The college idiots. You know
they got paid by their parents. You know
you must go to school and they just go
to school and [ __ ] around. They don't
really care what's going on. Oh there's
homework. If I don't do it I'm not going
to I'm going to fail. Oh let's ask AI.
That's what they do. Okay. So that
that's that's a situation when the
people they they don't you know the
person actually not interested
when you do that when you use AI in such
a way then it will rot your brain you
know after five years you will become
incomp incapacitated you become a [ __ ]
like you don't know you don't know how
to think anymore okay that's the
difference
hello Hank thank you So much ching $5.
Have you tried an embedded database like
SQ Lite? Um or HSQLDB?
Oh, that's a new one. I haven't heard of
that. Uh no, actually I haven't tried
embedded database. Um SQL light is
fantastic. I can highly recommend it
especially because the SQL light person
I forgot who is the guy um he is
anti-corruption SQL
light okay um he is very anti-corruption
he fought against the social justice
warrior code of conduct fox okay it's a
great guy and the technology is also
Great because it's a embedded database
you know it just make it like very uh
you know condensed so you don't have to
be elaborate like typically SQL database
are very elaborate
uh so so they have a section on code of
conduct that's related to politics you
know code of conduct is a crime okay so
anyway the technology is a great is
fantastic and the person I believe he's
a great guy and he's a great coder
because this SQL light is very popular
like it's like one of the top most
popular u application for programmers so
I highly recommend it but I myself never
uh actually used it
uh okay so what is it uh C language
libraries I mean I mean okay do they
have uh do they still have like code of
conduct stuff. I mean they they they
created their own code of conduct.
So anyway, so I never had the
experience. Uh and database is usually
boring. So I actually never
got so much into but I was I was the
mysql expert
uh in the 2000s because I read their
documentation 1,000 pages cover to cover
every word MySQL and I've been using it
for for for like six years or something
but that was a while ago 10 years ago.
Does your wife have any programming
knowledge? No. Uh, not at all. My wife
is just a a country woman.
What do think about prologue? Uh,
prologue is a logical language. That's
very interesting. I looked into a little
bit for like a week or two with some
friends in China. They they are telling
me about it. Also, Emily. Emily, a great
I think she's the top programmer. She's
the OB on Discord.
Okay. But she doesn't post often today.
So Emily, she she is the I would say
she's the top programmer
of all discord history of the past five
years. So she is very now prologue is
her latest hottest heart language. She
she recommended very much. I I don't
know much about it.
Hank, if you are dishon dishoned, you
will be misled uh by chatbots. Uh yes,
re uh Dr. Richard Hip. Okay, that's
that's a SQL light guy.
Uh why do I why did I read entire MySQL
manual? Two reasons. Okay, reading
manual is my habit. I'm obsessive. You
know it it is one of my obsession. Read
manuals because
long story but you know I like to read.
So not just read just read them. I read
them from cover to cover. Every single
word, every punctuation I if there's a
punctuation mistake, I must know. Okay,
that was my mentality back in the 1980s
and 1990s.
And that's how I learned English too,
you know, by reading dictionaries. Any
anyway, so
reading manuals is my habit. Okay. So,
it's my obsession in in the past, not
not so much today because it's actually
kind of waste of time because so here's
a tip, okay? When you read a manual,
your goal is not to read every word, you
know, find every, you know, spelling
errors or grammatical errors and get
every nuance of every sentence. That's
not the goal. when you read a technical
manual documentation like programming
language documentation your goal is
simply to understand it as fast as
possible so I would recommend also for
reading books non-fiction books okay you
when you read just you know your goal is
to understand what it's saying and you
scan okay when you don't when you see
something not interesting skip it scan
skip you know go back and forth okay
that's your goal. You want to just
understand what it's saying. That's the
most important thing about reading
books. Okay? Not about, you know, I I
must start from the beginning. Like
usually usually a book, you know, like
they have prologue, epological
jargon for a book, you know, like I I
know every one of them. uh you know
preface prologue epilogue um postcript
and uh and there's another thing called
that's like what's it called that's like
how is the book made you know what found
what type setting you know what's that
called someone someone mention it
and uh then preface table of content
contents table of figures index uh
bbiography
And uh uh there's another word similar
to index um called uh I for I forgot
uh in fact I was just uh using it in my
EMAC tutorial. So what's the word? So
let's see
uh uh glossaryy. That's right. So anyway
there's this jarens. How do I know?
Because I'm obsessed obsessed about
reading, you know, knowing all these,
you know, back then. This is like ' 90s.
So and I like to I must read every word
you know every preface every every
usually sometimes there are several
preface several introduction or like um
uh you know like usually another author
introduces you recommend the book you
know you sometimes there are few so I
must start from there you know I must
for I must know everything so that was
my habit and turns out that's not a good
one okay don't do that
So why am I reading MySQL? Because I was
using it. So when um I was using it. So
in two year 2000s I was using Oracle
database. So but in year 2005 I think
around 2005 I was working for a project
for Hoover Institution
over at Stanford University. I happened
to work for them for a project. So to
create a website, so I used MySQL. So I
read the documentation. Uh by the way, I
think MySQL is one of the Unix scum
[ __ ]
Uh anyway,
okay. I think that's it for today. So is
that right? So what are the other topics
I have here?
Uh field power. Okay. map functions.
Let's talk about that some other time.
So yeah. So okay, let's go back to why
is Emacs field region command called
field? Let's see. The field region
command in EMAC is named field.
Excuse me.
too much cigarette
because it reformats the text in a
selected region by breaking it into
lines that fit a spec specified width
defined by the field column variable.
That's correct. Effectively
filling each line with words up to that
margin
while handling wrapping and optional
justification.
That's that doesn't make sense. Yeah.
What? But how is that feeling? Oh, okay.
So, you you have an empty line. Let's
say you begin with the empty line. Then
you feel it. Feel each word. It's a
[ __ ] idiotic
idiotic perspective.
This terminology originates from Oh,
okay. So it originates from early
computer text formatting programs
in the 1960s.
Okay, that's the payload. That's the
reason
Emacs code field that that's not the
reason. Well, actually it's because from
it's a convention from 60s. So in the
1960s they view it
not as reformat but they view it as like
begin with empty line then you feel
words okay such as run off one of such
one of the first search tools where
feeling describe the process oh of
extracting words from input and
assembling them into output lines of a
predefined length That's why I see the
concept carried over to later systems
like enro trough Unix fox with commands
like fi for field field mod mode and
influence editors like emacs which
adopted similar language for text
reformatting features. Okay, I learned
something and thank you guac. Thank you
AI.
Amazing. You know, I've been using Emacs
for 30 years. I kind of had this
question vaguely, never bothered to look
up. And usually these kind of questions,
I know if I search a web, usually you
don't get answers, you know, then you
have to dig like chat forums, then you
got to, you know, dig, you know, because
this is like history from 1960s.
But today, AI just answer it, you know,
in in in one minute. Fantast amazing. So
this is amazing demonstration of the
value of AI. It's not just the value
they are changing humanity. They are
they are like in such a system they are
changing how we um and we are kind of
too slow to understand to catch up
what's going on. They are changing our
behavior like like
incredibly
uh typography. No, that's not the right
word. Okay. How do you uh toggle
justification with field region? You
can't. Okay. You basic that guy talked
about are you late? So you have to set
the variable field column. Okay. So you
can call
Customize set. Okay. Then
save value. No. Um.
Okay. Customize variable. Okay. You call
that command. Then you say you type
field column.
Then you give it a different value.
That's how you do it. Okay. Then you
call the field command like field
region, field paragraph.
Then we'll use that width. Or
alternatively, you just go to a eag
uh wait,
you know, you just you just you just
type this and evaluate it. Okay, which
is what I do. I don't use the custom
thing.
Have you tried two monitor? No, I never
tried it. I believe I prefer one
monitor, but I never tried two monitors.
Lag behind on chat. What? What? Okay, I
think that's it. Anything else? Okay,
donate to me. Okay, if you guys like my
stuff, go to kasali.info.
kasali.info.
go to it
and lots of stuff and programming like
uh how many pages are there? Uh there
are there are like 4,000 I think 8,000
pages on this
8,000 articles, okay, on programming on
mathematics. So go all the way down.
Patreon me, Amazon gift card me, PayPal
me. Okay.
Okay, I think that's it. Let's see. I
think my microphone is set too loud.
Actually, it's hitting the red bar. I
think that's it.
So why AI? Why is it called field? Let's
copy it. So now paste it. Lingify make a
list and uh ask AI. Okay, so there is
the answer. Fantastic. And the other
things I'll be next day uh hasht. Okay,
actually next next live stream I think
I'm going to do wam language.
Okay, bye guys.
That's my wife talking. She speaks
Cantonese.
What is the word that describe how uh
how a book is made like what kind of
font how type setting what m machine is
used? Uh what's uh it's it's um
it's called
I forgot. Let's ask AI.
What's the word that
word in a book
that talks about how the book was type
set or printed
col uh colon?
Oh yeah, caller phone. That's right.
Okay. So let's list uh these words we
talked about. Colon
pre preace
intro
table of contents
bibliography
index.
grocery
uh
Apple log.
Sometimes there's pre-log.
Uh what else? The the and there is a
blur. Blur is like a little uh like
usually marketing material at the front
cover or back cover. usually at the back
and there is um jacket you know
it's a funny funny you know book uh book
uh jarens let's see I'm I'm pretty sure
there's a Wikipedia article on that
let's see
book jarens is the
Uh,
the book of jargon. No, the the ultimate
guide to business jarens. No, that's not
what I'm talking about.
Grocery of book terms. Let's see.
Advanced reading copy. No advertisements
or edge or edges guild. Okay. appendix.
Oh yeah, the appendix right there's
appendix and uh there is
and there's inserts
uh the uh uh uh yeah so um
so these are kind of topics appendix um
uh
inserts is usually like in the middle.
Um,
a new audio book blah blah blah biblio
bio class biblio maniac biblio file.
What the [ __ ] Uh, no that's not uh
breakers cloth broadside breaker. A
person who breaks up books so to sell
the plates separately.
Okay, this is more advanced
conjugate leaf. Yeah, there's a leaf
uh leaf.
This is a uh this colophone
comp binding conjugate leaf. What the
[ __ ] is that? The un unsevered second
half of a printed page
corners. Okay. Bye.