good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show today I'm going
to teach you Java Script to begin us to
two intermediate so you guys you know if
you want to learn JavaScript you are
watching the right video so I think we
are I'm going to do about an hour let's
see how far I can go
yesterday I was talking about a
JavaScript topic about web scripting Dom
you know about the not list versus HTML
collection and you know when talking
about that I discussed some other things
let's go through my JavaScript block
okay just to begin begin with so this is
my web dev blog you can see my HTML
tutorial CSS tutorial JavaScript
in-depth and so on and you know back to
my blog you can go to my blog by just go
to Casa Jay JavaScript in-depth just
such that and you will find my web page
so I'm going to teach let's see if I'm
live okay I'm like two people watching
so I'm going to teach today JavaScript
two kind of beginners if you never you
know you know to someone who had at
least one programming language
experience you know he you know if you
programmed a little bit then you can
follow I hope so so go through so yeah
today's topic I'm going to teach
JavaScript and so yesterday I was
talking about not least versus
htmlcollection this page it's it's quite
it's somewhat advanced it's very
complicated and when talking about this
then we I went on to talk about some
other stuff in JavaScript in particular
the why do you have
ray and array-like object they are
different you know and that's a big
problem complexity in JavaScript so I
try to explain that yesterday anyway so
today I'm going to try to teach you Java
Script you know to beginners so let's
let's begin then yeah JavaScript let's
begin ok first of all first of all
JavaScript basically there are two parts
to web to do web programming you know
web programming including programming
your smartphone Android phone or Apple
iOS phone you have you know JavaScript
is critically important it's almost like
the number one important language when
you want to do any sort of web
programming now javascript in order to
do that to learn how to create a web
application you know interactive single
page web web application you have to
know JavaScript the language but also
you have to know HTML you have to know
CSS you know you actually do have to
know so you know HTML CSS then then you
have to know JavaScript the language
then you have to know tom-toms scripting
so why so HTML and CSS
so anyway I'm not going into detail
about that you I assume you probably
know what HTML and CSS is about but
white what's the difference between
JavaScript and Dom you see JavaScript is
just a programming language for example
like Perl Python you know you can print
fine numbers you know 1 200 you print
you can print you know or even numbers
and you know do things like that but if
you are going to create a desktop
application using for example Python or
Java or C++ you know you need something
else other than the programming language
you need
you know libraries to draw you know
buttons menus windows on your screen and
that part is very different from the
programming language because you learn
Python Python you know you know how to
create object classes you know least you
know dictionary data types you know you
you know how to compute numbers one plus
one or you know you know and deal with
strings you know and all these things
but there has nothing to do with how do
you create a graphical user interface
you know mouse click you know things
like that so in order to do that you
need to know the basically so that's the
other part of the thing you know if you
program for window that you know windows
operating system you need to know the
windows system you know how do you call
the system functions to create a window
how do you create a button how do you
create a menu what happens when people
click on the menu you know so you need
this part and this part is also very
complex it's fairly complex and it's and
it's also different on different
platform for example on Windows if
you're gonna write a Windows application
you know suppose you are using Python
you learn Python but you also have to
know the Windows platform how do you
actually do that a Mac it's a different
you know Mac libraries Mac OS system
system calls and all that to do that on
Linux is another again sniffing on cell
phone iOS iOS or Android again sniffing
so you know so you need to load no
JavaScript the language but the other
part about drawing you know menus
windows buttons those part is about that
is what Dom is about so for example
let's see you know I have some some
example it's ok so let's go to let's go
do some examples I'm going to show you
some basic
application okay so you go to Mike's our
website sorry website then you can go to
Unicode and that's why not let's go to
keyboard Oh actually and let's go to
play chinese chess you see there here is
some examples of web application they
are written in javascript so for example
we have here is chinese chess i can
start to play against the computer you
know we trying to play a speed chess so
that's an example of web web application
now that's pretty bad you know I'm gonna
lose a piece should have known that well
too bad
so if you are watching you have any
questions or comments or opinions just
post ok I love to see your comments the
more comment is better for my channel as
well so you like my stuff you know keep
the comment going so this is a example
of application you know with retain
JavaScript you know that you need to
know the JavaScript language well then
you need to know in this case is Dom you
know how how do you create these you
know pieces these graphics how do you
manipulative in positions then you have
menus here you know play ok again it's
human or computer you know these menus
widgets you know these are called
widgets so that this part is stomped so
you need to know JavaScript and you need
to don't don't you need to understand
Dom so this is one example in fact if
you are actually working with JavaScript
everyday most of your time your concern
your the time you spend to to know how
to do things is actually about Dom you
know it's less about JavaScript language
and similarly for other applications if
you're going to write a desktop
application to plot math graphics and
you can rotate it in 3d you know that's
a similar situation you have to know the
Python language but most of the time you
you you are probably spending in dealing
with the you know how do you how do you
control the mouse how do you control the
you know with the the environment the
the system you are programming so that's
one example of JavaScript application
let me just show you another couple
because you know I wrote them so I'd
like to demonstrate them so there is
let's go to Saudi keyboard layout and
there is this interactive character
frequency counter you know so first I
type you can see the bar chart changes
they are
calculating the frequency of each
letters hi type you see they you know so
this is another example of JavaScript
web application you need to learn know
JavaScript then you need to know the Dom
how do you control how do you draw this
bar chart in this case is actually SVG
the technology is SVG you know part of
the web technology so that's another
example of web web application then I
have this Unicode example let's search
for water w 8e e R so it shows all
Unicode character names that contains
the word water
let's try fire if I ah
e ok now here is all the character
Unicode characters characters whose name
contains the word fire now let's see if
there's a Unicode character that
contains both whose name contains both
the word fire and water ok it's not that
no such let's try Earth see what comes
up okay so you got several characters
about Earth including emoji so here's
another that's another example of
Unicode I mean I mean not Unicode the
JavaScript so you can go through my
website I go to my website and I look
you see here is the JavaScript code you
know so anyway we we kind of digress
into JavaScript applications the
examples of them we will but I'm going
let's begin to let me begin to teach
JavaScript you know that's you know so
let me read the comment good morning
Sean Sean Penn zero just wanted to say
thanks for the beginners guy approach to
Thomas to it thank you
now again like you know if I'm too
verbose just tell me to get on you know
just comment by
you know in comment so yeah so it's okay
let's begin so first of all JavaScript
you the first thing you need to do is
how do you start to type let's say let's
say let's say you want to do 1 1 plus 1
okay so you just go to a browser any
browser Safari Chrome any browser then
typically in the menu you can select
developer tools some time is called
console ok then the browser will show
this console then you can just start to
type JavaScript let's say 1 + oh I have
1 + 2 there let's say 1 + 3 okay and
that's JavaScript let's say let X equal
to 5 okay then X plus 9 is 14 okay and
and let y equals to an array okay so
let's type array
1 2 3 you know and why why is now array
3 elements 1 2 3 so this is how you
evaluate JavaScript okay I think at this
rate we will not be will not be going
anywhere okay already 13 minutes 5
people watching so anyway because that's
okay because you know when I you know
what I have a like specific goal like
you know then I start to have a pressure
you know like oh I have to do this well
then things don't go well so let me just
you know random rant is okay so anyway
so I want to show you my website okay so
you go to JavaScript in-depth then this
first section here our JavaScript basics
that help that teaches you the basics
now of course if you are a tight the
type of person who wants to know
waste time watching videos you can just
read my tutorial it's you know one page
by page it's concise condensed you know
information you can read at your leisure
you know at your faith you have a face
whatever speed you learn things so
anyway the first thing we learned is
that how do you actually you know
evaluate JavaScript so you just go to a
browser
you know you studies JavaScript console
you know tools and I have actually an
example here I show you in detail how to
use browser browser console that's
basically what we just covered okay
that's one way to do it but another way
to do it is you want to go to install
not j/s okay you go to a website not j/s
okay you go to the not jeaious website
then you download they are binary so you
go to not GL suicide there's a download
for Windows Mac or Linux okay in my case
it's a Mac you can just download it once
you download it you will have a you will
have a binary a program code not you
know you can call in command command
line so for example not let's say not
help okay that's not help let's go into
not then so now we are in not let's
magnify so let's say one plus two it
returns three let's say let x equals two
array 3 4 5
no then we got the answer now let's say
show X you see so this is not you know
you just you just download it so you can
have that drawn in terminal now I'm
using it in Emacs issue of course and
let's see exit okay control D okay let's
just close it cue it
okay so so you want to download not the
advantage of that is that it lets you
for example you can open a new file and
type in account in a file let's say I
type 1 plus 2 I say console.log wait
console.log console.log 1 plus 2 ok and
save the file as X X star Jas ok so the
file saved us X XJS now I go to shell
now I can I can type not then space X
XJS enter so it output 3 you know so
that this is another way to run it so
the advantage of installing nod is so
that you can run JavaScript again it's
the file but actually in browser you can
actually do that you know in browser if
you start up the the tool the 2 is
actually very complicated there's a lot
huge amount options you know this is
like you know today's modern browser
with the you know JavaScript console the
whole thing is actually more advanced I
would say more advanced more complicated
than any typical IDE for tsipras first
or Java or C or C sharp okay because
JavaScript today is a huge business it's
also the number one programming language
so let me see yeah so it's extremely
popular and that is the reason why you
want to learn JavaScript you know that
is that is the reason because you know
it's a good thing to learn a few
languages so JavaScript so now you you
know how to run a program by via the
browser console console log or installed
an RJ
okay once we know that that's a big
thing we have covered actually we're the
one to close that oh wait okay so now
you know how to run the program where
the browser or the not binary now what's
the next thing we're gonna talk about
good morning after a man after rope
Abdullah man
natty so what are the next thing what
what's the next thing okay now we know
how to run the JavaScript program you
can either run it interactively in
browser or you can run it you know
interactively using a nod or you can run
it as a fire you know using nod now the
next thing we want to do is to cover
some basic language syntax of the
JavaScript yeah I guess let's do that
but this party is rather very boring
okay so in the next five minutes let's
cover some basics of JavaScript language
syntax okay so JavaScript language it's
it's actually it's a very dynamic
language it's and it it supports
functional programming I would say even
more so in some sense even more so then
disp then common list then emag Lisp
okay I you know because JavaScript
supports the feature where a function
can be can be the argument to another
functions a function can take a function
as argument as yeah argument input and
it can return a function in a clean way
now this very feature just this feature
is a tremendous help in functional
programming it is almost the most
fundamental critical feature of
functional programming languages so so
JavaScript is very much functional
programming if you want okay it also
supports those objects
and and it's very tiny dynamic so so in
some sense javascript is very much like
Ruby I would say Ruby in Python and in
Perl
you know dynamic languages as opposed to
C c plus first c-sharp Java those kind
of languages where you have you know
typically you have to compile and
typically you have a main you know
section
you know like min you don't have that in
JavaScript you know you just you just
you just run it like a bash shell script
so I'm let's go over some basic
JavaScript syntax now I'm gonna not
going to go over this in detail you
should read this part because it's kind
of boring so it shows you what comments
how do you what's the syntax for
comments how do you print something into
the screen like print hello word for
example it's let's so basically it you
use console.log so i can now run this
command console doin this file and the
result is three let's say console out
hello doing it and we I see the output
so that's how you print things in
JavaScript then you have string syntax
the for example the definition the let
let x equals to let's say love okay then
let's print X okay granite I get love
and I can also see if it II
if X is equal to the string love let's
run it it says true here so you know how
that's how you print things then we have
a substring yeah let me show you an
example string so string first of all
string can be double quote or single
quote
that's a little bit detail actually
that's not important so anyway so you
have strange then you have sub strange
so let's do substring so let's I love
earth let's say I love earth okay and
that's a stream so let's say we want
substring so let's let's do X dot slice
starting from 0 index 0 to let's say
start from 0 1 from index 1 to index 4
let's see what we get run it
we got arrow V so let's say 1 to 5 then
we got arrow B so that's that's how you
get a substring you know from a stream
so these are the basic syntax of
JavaScript now I'm not going to go over
them because they are so they kind of
boring you know the end you know if I go
over them you cannot forget anyway the
only way you to learn is actually you
have to start coding it then then you
have if-then statements then you have
loop for loop for loop is just like C or
Java then you have array and object now
array an object that is becoming you
know starting to become very interesting
that is when we see that that is
actually beginning to be the things you
want to learn about JavaScript ok so we
are going to so let's see what what to
do next okay let me let me check how
many people I had watching for people
so let me think so so far so good
this is this is going too slow let's so
yeah let's think what to
we're gonna talk about JavaScript yeah
let me let me let's just speaking about
some topic you know we just talked about
some topics so array in object okay
first of all so javascript you know you
learn you know the syntax you can just
read this page later on but let me start
to talk about something interesting
about javascript you know that can get
you begin to understand the language so
so first of all the most important thing
is that the the value types of
JavaScript
now JavaScript every every value has
belongs to a type so they are they are
these types in JavaScript you have
undefined type know type boolean type
number type symbol type and object type
variables when you use variables in
JavaScript there is no type associated
with with variable names because
javascript is is dynamic you know so you
don't have you don't need to declare
variable to be you know it's a specific
type such as int float you know things
like that you don't have to but any
value you know any number three any
string any value belongs to a type so
you have this one two three four five
six seven seven types let me go over
them you know it's it's not too
difficult to understand them all and
this is very important this you know you
like memorize this part okay so you have
this undefined type now what let's let's
say number so what is a number type any
value that is a number is belongs to
number type so three is a number it's a
number type 3.2 is a number it's a
number type and the one way to find out
what type it is about value is you to
use the typeof operator so let's say
type of three
let's print it you know it says a number
in fact it actually returns a string it
returns a string and the string says
number that is actually what it returns
so you see we get true so you know so
the button so by the way there is no
float type there's no ink type the
JavaScript does not make a distinction
of them you know the languages have a
number type now there's a undefined type
the only possible value of that type is
the literal keyword undefined so
undefined that that's that's a value so
for example we can run the program we
can console up and define when it you
know it just trained undefined then if
you say type of undefined type of and
check if it's equals to type of
undefined returns the string undefined
big you know it says true because that
is the type of the literal value and
defined that and that is the only
possible value just the keyword
undefined so in that's undefined type
and in the same way there's another
literal keyword code no that's
it's like undefined it's almost have the
same meaning so no is the only possible
value for the know type so you have
undefined you have no you have true and
then you have boolean type boolean type
are the words keyword true and false
so if you run that it returns true so
it's just the keyword true and force you
run it it'll return true you know so the
literal keyword true and false ah these
values of the type pulling code pooling
there's and there are only two possible
values of this type the keyword true and
false so so that's that covers about a
special case undefined type know type
boolean type okay and then you have
string type strings any string and
symbol type is a bit complicated the
symbol type we we don't have to worry
about too much because that is
introduced in 2015 a symbol type is
basically a value that is not human
readable and that value basically is
always always unique you know it the
symbol type kind of function as an ID
identifier you know it's like a unique
symbol like an you know it's not even a
number you cannot see you you cannot
actually see the value a symbol type is
just a value that's kind of unique and
that's that's created in invented in
2015 for the purpose of creating
properties so that other properties will
not override it that's basically the
purpose of the single type we talked
about that passed not probably now today
but anyway the last type is object type
object type is the most interesting
notice that in all these types you don't
have a function and you don't have the
typical array or list they they are not
here they are actually or a subtype of
the object type
now what's interesting here is that the
JavaScript object you know the types
they don't you know JavaScript do not
technically have the concept of a
subtype there's no such thing you will
not find a ninja in a JavaScript
specification the Eggman script you know
2015 16 17 so there is no concept of
subtype but then but arrays and
functions and and quite a few other
things they are all of the type object
so anyway so kind of lost because I'm
starting to I'm starting to kind of just
like repeating like almost like reading
of a book that saying things everyone
already knows that's what happens when I
try to actually you know formally teach
something on the other hand if I'm
ranting about something you will learn a
lot more things then anyway so a lot
more than you know what I'm doing now
but anyway so let's go back so so you
have these types in JavaScript okay you
remember you know the object type is the
most complex so what is the object type
let's not talk about object type object
type is technique is is basically the
meaning basically object type are a
collection of key and value pairs plus
it has a special functionality you know
like any value when a value is the
object that almost always means it is a
key and value pair now when you use a
type type of operator and when you say
type of Nohr it will actually return
object you see is this true and this is
this is bad because no is actually not a
object type
you know this is this is a one of the
problem of the burg in in JavaScript no
is not you know no the type of new
according to the spec is supposed to be
new you know new is the only possible
value for that type no but when when you
use type of operator on the new value it
actually returns the object you know
yeah string he says it's object so this
is this is it's this way because because
it was a bug in the first implementation
of JavaScript because when you go to and
read this article from you know linked
from my website you will see this guy
he's the JavaScript master you know he
he dig into the or engine Y type of nor
you know his object it basically
suggests a bug in the C program the
implementation so so that's one of the
problem of JavaScript so what what is
object okay I kind of get lost I'm kind
of like don't have a call right now
okay let me just talk about objects okay
object so object is key and value pairs
almost always in the syntax for the
literal expression for object is like
this I'm going to show you so for
example let a be J equals to this curly
quote and let's say x1 y2 okay this is
the syntax and we run it and wait we can
we missing a colon here so we run it it
runs and now we can print it
obj print the object and you know it
means x1 and y2 so remember by
definition object is just a collection
of a key value pairs and typically the
key value pairs they are not ordered
they are not guaranteed to be ordered
but browser tries to order them anyway
so it's just a correction of key value
pairs now every object live ok then let
me show you so away you know object is
the primary data type in JavaScript
because you know like in other languages
you have array you have list you have
hash table or dictionary you have you
know all these things in JavaScript
that's just called object by the way the
word object here is not is totally
different from the object in the Java or
Python since you know it's totally
different from the object oriented
program is sense of object so JavaScript
object so limited so what so what so
object you can have for example I can't
have a function that shows me all the
keys of the object key value
so I call the function reflect out on
keys and let's say object here and let's
say print it vennett and it gives me a
array x and y because X Y are the keys
so objects is a key and value pair and
the keys the keys the type for the keys
there are only two types allowed one is
string and the other one is symbol
symbol is complicated let's just talk
about strings so in this example x and y
are actually strings even if you don't
type them as like that but they are
automatically converted to strings so so
so key key the type of the key allowed
is either a string or a symbol the value
can be anything that value can even be a
function so let me define a function
then okay so I'm kind of lost
I'm kind of lost like right now I
becoming call as I'm like there is no
specific thing in my mind I want to show
you and so any questions like what what
like what are you maybe you are you know
you've been watching this for 10 minutes
you are expecting me to say something
and you are you know like type it type
your opinion like once I get you know
you have I have chat you know I have
people talking and then I can talk about
lots of things these things
javascript so I'm thinking so let's
let's let's let's try the function let's
print 1 to 100 okay so let's open a new
window open a new window and save this
window as X X 2 dot Jas okay now let's
print 1 to 100 okay so we're gonna we're
gonna do for loop I equal to 0 I less
than 100 and let's print print it
hi okay granite sink tax arrow
unexpected token oh yeah so here
Lynnette so we can see 1 to 100 okay
let's say we just want even numbers now
wait let's say we want to put them into
a list so we let be a is array
so we declare empty array here a is
empty and for when we do this for I
equal to 0 to less than 100 we want to a
r dot push okay
then I okay so each time it will add the
number to the array so now we do that
then we print a R okay run it you see we
got a way here because this square
bracket now let's take let's say 10 you
see we've got an array here now array
has the length you type AR dot length
okay so console.log printed you can see
10 because there are 10 items
and let's define a function so the way
you define there are many ways to define
a function one of the way is the
traditional by the keyword function and
you can let's name the function f so
arguments X and return X plus 1 ok
that's our function then we call it
let's say F at to return we got 3 that's
the answer correct another way to write
a function is by arrow function you'd
the syntax is like this constant arrow
function so ID ID curve a let me show
you so here's a function the function
will X plus 1 so here here's a function
this function is usually called lambda
or anonymous function it doesn't have a
name it's just a function so here is X X
plus 1 and if we run it it runs if we
want to evaluate this function let's say
at the value of 2 you just do like the
normal way you know you put a bracket
parentheses behind it then 2 inside so
now you run it it runs but now you want
to print the value so let's say let R
equals through that okay then
console.log so now you've got the number
3 so that's how you define a function so
there are two ways why is the by the
keyword function and the other way is by
arrow function arrow function is much
better you should try to always use a
helper function if you prefer you know
if you want functional programming so
what we have done here is actually we
assigned the result of a function to R
but we can also
do it this way
personal function so here we so F equals
to this anonymous function and what that
do is that let's not say let's say f -
okay so f 2 equals to this function now
we can call F 2 and let's say put two
there
vennett and we get three that's a result
that's good so two ways to define they
are more than two ways but the two
primary practical way to define a
function is by the keyword function or
by arrow function okay so that's that's
about function and we have a example of
array
we have shown a function example of
functions things that what am I gonna do
next
so any any questions so far
so let me let me think about the
JavaScript functions in a race so I want
to teach JavaScript and so far I'm not
doing a good job because kind of lost
the purpose but at least you know you
learn how to evaluate how to start to
learn JavaScript programs you can do
that in browser or via the nerd binary
then you want to learn about the syntax
of JavaScript and the best way to do
that you know is just to read this page
of my tutorial you can spend like 20
minutes and you learn the basic syntax
of printing of string of read
arithmetics like 1 plus 2 or minus
multiply the version then you learn
about assignments like let Z equals to 5
assignment assignment is important it's
critical then you also learn about
numbers of course numbers you know
numbers is everywhere is its fundamental
then there is a string and number
conversion because sometimes you want to
turn a number into a string you know
let's say you want to print three point
five eight usually it's done
automatically but sometimes you know you
want to manipulate things you turn a
number number into a string and one way
and you can do that by just type the
number dot pass float or number dot pass
int you know that's how you do it but
you see that function name involves a
dot now I'm going to explain that later
you're then learn that when you get into
objects and properties but anyway so so
you have these
numbers you know first of all you
understand numbers and you know you can
try this code number in strings then you
have variables now variables is also one
of the fundamental element in
programming languages you variable
allows you to store a value and use it
later so in JavaScript in modern
JavaScript the way you declare variables
is using the let keyword you know let
something let X let x equals to 4 and
you know things like that that's how you
declare variables and when you have a
let the scope of a variable is within
the within the curly bracket for example
let me show you your example so another
new file say with X X 3 dot GS so let's
say let let X equal to 3 but let's put
it in a curly bracket okay then we
console.log X ok let's do this so in a
curly bracket we have x equals to 3 then
we print it then outside of it we also
print we again print the value of x
let's see the what that we saw will be
it will be you know make a guess make a
guess what the Risso will be and I'm
gonna show you what it is like right now
okay so the result is actually an error
because it says X is not defined you see
because the the second X is outside of
the curly bracket so when a colleague
bracket finishes you know there's no
more X so X is actually local variable
to the curly bracket so in JavaScript
when you use let the scope of the
variable is within the
curly bracket you know the nearest outer
colleague bracket and and and there is
another keyword called constant Co NS t
that has the same syntax as let the only
difference between constant you know Co
NS T and let le T is that when you use
the constant to declare a variable you
can never change the value of the
variable in other words you are defining
a constant so that's the two difference
otherwise let and the keyword constant
are exactly the same they have the same
scope as well now there is another
keyword code var in JavaScript var is a
very old you know keyword in JavaScript
that and constant is new in JavaScript
in 2015 they added that now the keyword
var is also for declaring a variable but
the behavior is very very extremely
complicated because it depends on you
know how whether you have assignment in
conjunction when you declare a variable
or it depends on the placement of your
variable declaration or whether it's
inside a function the scope and
availability of the variable changes you
know in a very complicated way so
basically in modern JavaScript the
keyword var is considered absolute like
nobody uses use uses it it's one of the
mistake of JavaScript it's one of the
the most worst error you know mistake
bad design in JavaScript so but today if
you code JavaScript nobody ever uses it
you know it's it's considered absolute
so so we I'm not going to go into the
detail about why
is very complicated actually actually
that's a good topic to go into just to
give these talks and flavors I mean you
know so I actually finally have
something to talk about the the worst
one of the worst part of JavaScript why
people hate JavaScript because var is
the one of the biggest reason there are
so many reasons but why is one of the
biggest reason but you know in modern
JavaScript you don't use it nobody uses
so Shawn says if you could explain more
about dumb stuff that would be super
helpful okay Tom
okay let's this why not let's jump over
to Dom so that so I'm going to leave
JavaScript the language for now because
you know I'm just doing random talk like
this is informal lecture it's a talk
show you know and so it's talking so you
know we're gonna drop JavaScript because
I was just like repeating I feel like
repeating boring stuff so let's talk
about Dom so because there's a question
then you know so let's go to Dom then so
anyway so javascript the language you
know you you can I'd you know by the way
you know go to my website I have this
javascript in depth you know I bet you
know I bet you money that I can I can
see that I myself I can I worked on this
for two years I read all the specs of
JavaScript very complicated aspect so I
wrote this tutorial in two years you
know with I spent two years so you know
check it out
and you can learn you'll learn a lot you
know JavaScript basically in one hour
and if you spend few more hours you will
actually understand some of the extreme
complexity of JavaScript but explained
in a very logical create clear
way such that even if you have let's say
two years experience programming
javascript industry you will learn
actually you will start to see when you
read my tutorial you will see finally
you understand something you know
because javascript is actually very
convoluted language so you know I you
know so you can check out my tutorial
and I I want to mention that I'm selling
it to you know pay for it as a
commitment you know you you Pay Pal you
buy this tutorial I send it to you that
is good you know do that very few people
you know vast majority of JavaScript
programmers I would say more than 50% in
industry even if you are working at you
know big companies like Google Facebook
I would say you know most JavaScript
programmers more than 50% of them
professional JavaScript programmers they
don't you don't actually understand
JavaScript the language too well okay so
because because the JavaScript language
is really complicated there are lots of
horse in a language so anyway let's talk
about Dom then so Dom is the technology
that allows you to use JavaScript to
program websites so what so you know if
you go to my Dom's tutorial you will of
the first section web scripting overview
they are about six pages that gives you
an overview how tom is used what it is
you know how do you use it what kind of
environment like what what's going on
like what what do you have to know what
are the things you need to know you know
that's the overview so first of all tom
is just a the everything about Dom is in
the browser okay Thompson
stand for document object model Tom was
invented in 1996 also 1999 eight about
1999 okay it was invented there back
then the expectation is entirely
different from today so tom is very kind
of old Asian tech and and it's pretty
bad in many ways because in a beginning
nobody knows what they are really trying
to do but in with anyway we are stuck
with the word Tom document object model
but anyway the the most practical
practical thing in dumb about scripting
website is that you go to the console
log and you will see this window object
type window okay
enter now that is the object in
JavaScript now let me let me explain how
JavaScript relates to Dom how
technically are they related together
you know how so javascript is a language
technically it's called
a hosted language hosted language now
this is a very different concept from C
Java Python Ruby okay those are not
hosted language JavaScript is a hosted
language that means how Java scripts
behave depends on what what is the
environment I mean in aspect there's
this there is this thing but the the
most practical way to understand is is
that javascript in a javascript language
now remember we said javascript has
objects you know one of the type of a
value is called object now in JavaScript
every object by definition have a link
to another object called its parent okay
may or may not have but you know it may
so every object may have a parent and
only one parent and that object again it
may have one parent only one parent
you know so the all the objects that
exist in JavaScript so they have these
parents eventually some object doesn't
have parent then that's kind of you can
say it's dead
so some object eventually you have you
you come into this parent object good
morning Danielle so you have this parent
object in JavaScript that parent object
is object prototype
object prototype okay that this this
object a prototype is the root object of
order standard building or the standard
building JavaScript objects okay but
what is the parent of object dot
prototype now that depends on the
environment okay so so that is the
meaning of hosted language now but
respect the environment of the the
parent of object of prototype in a
browser is the window object represented
by the keyword window so you can say for
example you can type type of window and
the return object telling you what you
know it is object you can you can say
window dot length zero because it's not
a ray yeah so window is an object and
now you want to know how many you know
how many number of keys are in a window
object you can say so let's go to
JavaScript let's let's go to
so let's go to JavaScript properties
leased properties so object are keys so
let's go back to JavaScript object oh
you you got it right okay object keys so
window and you know so it you know the
browser shows they are 209 items 209
items then we can say object dot keys
window then dot length because length is
a property of array so you show shows
you you know to 0 night items so my
point here is that in a browser window
is the global root object and every
JavaScript
Archy object including the object dot
prototype is part of the is the is a
children of Windows so for example we
can say window dot object that photo
type you know that is an object we press
enter you know is it actually shows you
the object and we can say object up keys
of window third object dot prototype you
know it returns an array
yeah so so hosted language so that so in
English you have the the the root of all
everything everything of the JavaScript
language every keyboard every object
there is a root that is the window word
okay
and that thing is called the global
object now when when I'm in Emacs right
now I mean Emacs I don't have you know
in Emacs when I run when I run this
script it's actually running the not
binary so in an odd environment the
global object is not window you know
that's why it's called hosted language
you know it depends on the environment
so what is so for example if I say
console out window it will complain you
know reference arrow window is not
defined so in not J as the global object
the parents of everything else is is
this keyword represent represented by
this keyword GL obal I think let's try
it you see it runs you see it returns so
we are printing global and it returns
this humongous list you know that is the
global object in in a not J's
environment now and we can also try the
same thing like we can try global dot
object dot prototype and that will print
that object because the object dot
prototype is a child is a property of
the global object you can you can see
yours it also prints out 250 lines so
window so now in browse now in so in
browser
you know just remember everything is
part of the window that that gives you
the whole JavaScript like kind of like
the JavaScript language
as far as object is concerned so you
have the window environment another one
critical to understand is the document
object now that is actually Windows
Start document now when we when people
talk about Dom that's when you want to
how to insert a HTML element web page
how to remove a HTML element how to
change things change text you know
rotate graphics um you know 3d object
you know you want to rotate it
Peyman and the 3d image are represented
by by HTML elements of course everything
on the web is represented by HTML or xml
elements so when you do these kind of
things you want to manipulate these
elements all those methods are from from
this object called Dom it's you know
it's called document object and the way
you access that is window dot document
so the the keyword that the the string
document is actually a property of the
window object you know so window
document and there's another interesting
thing about the window object because
window the word window the keyword
window is the global object so
oftentimes you do not need to type it
you know you can just for example let's
let's start a console log let's say you
know window dot document okay now that's
a object you can see you know this is
the object and it has lots of properties
and keys and if you try document without
a window it returns the same thing now
you can say window dot document
triple equal and enter here say true you
know because because window key word is
that's a global variable you oftentimes
you do not you know always you do not
need to mention you do not need to type
the window dot something you can
directly just use the properties of the
window object so that so that is about
the idea where every everything is with
within the window object you know
everything is just a children of the
window object and the other important
thing is the window dot document is the
Dom think that you deal with so that's
that's ok so let's go to the next topic
about web scripting so we so so tom is
about manipulating HTML elements and
it's represented by the window keyword
or window dot document now the next
thing you want to understand is that
when you're programming a browser
everything is event based so what is the
event like when you do a mouse click or
button click or type on keyboard those
are event or even if you move a window
that's also an event so events so those
are events and in JavaScript you can you
can when so when you click a mouse move
the mouse everything typing or clicking
everything is an event now you can
attach a function to event so when that
event happens your function will be
called now this is the primary way this
is basically the only way to write any
sort of interactive application you know
when you have an application of course
users you know type
numbers you know spreadsheet or a
calculator or whatever you know you need
user interactive interaction with user
so that's so that's called event based
programming so in javascript in the
browser
specifically everything you know this
mouse movements keyboards changing
windows size switching window switching
tabs all these everything at every every
activity is an event you can attach
functions to any one of them this is the
way you control the interaction between
you know your application and the end
user and the way you add a function to
an event is like this I have an example
here so you for example in this example
we define text equals to document get
element by ID
so remember document is the object so
get element by ID is a key you know in
JavaScript you have the concept of
objects and objects are key value pairs
correction of key value pairs so in the
case of the document object it has a key
named get element by ID and this key the
type of this key is a string so the way
you access this Keys value is by
document dot get element by ID so we can
show you here so let me show you some of
the examples of the thing so I think I'm
kind of repetitive but anyway you you
you type document dot get element by ID
it returns a function because because
the document object has a key which is a
string named get element by ID and the
value of this key this property is a
function what does this function do this
function actually you know get element
by ID you know grab a
element from the HTML webpage and return
return they are object that represents
that elements then you can manipulate
that elements things like that so but
you know so I you know I'm trying to
reinforce the idea of the object key
value pairs you know get element by ID
is actually just a property name which
is a string which is a property of the
document object by the way in Java
there's an important thing in JavaScript
you know every object object is a key
value pairs correction of and the value
of keys can be possible types are string
or symbol vast majority of the time they
are just string keys so we so a document
you have these properties key value
pairs they are called properties of the
object every object may have you know
these properties which are just key
value pairs now a by definition an
object can also have a parent object
meaning there's a link to another object
and the other object is meant to be you
know we call it the parent object now
the parent and children relationship of
objects objects is entirely different
from the relation of a object and its
properties now this is important because
the JavaScript our notation is kind of
confusing so when you see document dot
get element by ID now this syntax is a
syntax of property access this syntax
means the document object has a property
whose key is a string get element by ID
okay it does not mean the document has
you know object has a children called
this object get element ID it does not
mean that
at all so keep this in mind because this
this this will get very confusing when
you try to understand the parent and
children relationship jects so let me
summarize in other in another way
in JavaScript when you see a dot B dot C
or something those start means only one
thing it means whatever appears on the
left is the object and what whatever
appears on the right is the property
name of that object
you know remember this this is very very
different from Java or Python in Java or
Python when you have a dot B dot C the
you know the the first a dot B means a
is the parent of be class then in the B
class you have a property called C so
that's JavaScript I mean that's Java but
in JavaScript the thought only means one
thing that is the property you know
between an object and the property key
name okay let me read the comments a
little bit so it seems obvious now that
you said it okay good point about hosted
language so in JavaScript there is
always a single global object defined
that is always available in a web
browser the grow per object is the
browser window represented by the
keyword window yes and then you say is
any global variables or function can be
accessed as property of the window
object that is true actually that is not
true for a variable declared with let
okay nitpicking because you know that's
another complex complexity of JavaScript
so for example let's say var x equals to
3 now we just declare the variable x
equals to 3 now
show X so X is 3 now let's say it's
magnifying a little bit now let's say
window dot X you see it also says 3 now
let's say window that x equals 2x it
says true you see so when you declare a
variable global variable with a with the
keyword var that variable automatically
becomes the property of the global
object in a browser it that's that's the
window object but this is not true when
you have a variable declared with the
let keyword so for example let y equals
to 4 okay now let's say Y we got four
now let's say window that why he says
undefined you see so so when you declare
a variable with var which is the
absolute construct you know we don't use
that anymore it's it's bad you know when
you declare a variable with var that
variable name automatically becomes a
property key of the global object in a
browser that is the window object you
can do the same in in a in a not J's for
example let's try not just let var X
equal to 3 then global dot X we print
that then we also print Grabow dot X
equal to X then with we let's try that
oh it says we have to do it this way I
think
now it's force well I'm gonna I'm not
going to
well what so why is it what why why not
J s the variable does name does not
attach to the global object as a
property well the reason is basically
there's no good reason this is one of
the reason JavaScript is very complex
but anyway let's let's read small some
some more comments query selector so
Shaun says what about query selector so
query selector query selector is a
element of the windows of the document
object so let me show you some of the
for example window dot has own property
okay then we call that and we say
document okay you can see so that means
document is a property of Windows its
own property now let's say document dot
has own property and let's give a string
query select did I type it right
query selector okay no okay so let's go
through my tongue scraping get element
by ID tag name class CSS so go down you
have query selector okay
now let's go to the console again query
selector so document does not have the
property query selector so
so let's find out what is query selector
type of query selector okay then it says
undefined let's say let's try type of
document dot query selector it says a
function now so query selector is a
property of document so let's try
document as own property query selector
why is it returned force let's see so
let's go back to JavaScript in-depth
let's go to the properties section let's
go to property existence section so we
have object has own property
so we are trying to find out where does
the query selector come from so we know
document dot query selector is a
function let's try a different syntax
for array access so document
okay so document it looks like document
okay so query selector it might be a
property of the window object I think
that's true so let's try it window dot
has home property parentheses query
selector force
document that has some property force
okay now here's a perso so what is the
query selector function came from now it
is a function now we know in JavaScript
a function Oh almost every building a
function is a the type of function is
object because in JavaScript there's
actually no type code function you know
everything is you know we talked about
before so it's an object so but in
JavaScript
every object may have a parent and
basically almost you know every standard
building function or browser stuff they
almost always have a parent now our
problem is to find out what is the
parent object of query selector you know
so maybe that will be helped
help us you know study JavaScript so you
know the process of trying to find that
out so we want to find out for so first
of all we know document dot query
selector type of is a function so
apparently document dot curry selector
returns a value that is a function
object so is query select a property of
document so another way to do that is we
do reflect you know we are getting force
result here that's possibly because
there's a complexity in in in the
property inheritance stuff so what I'm
going to do is reef is going to call the
method reflect that apply which takes
three arguments the first argument is
the function we want the function we
want is
you know we we want to find out what's
the parent of the query selector so
first of all so we can go to the no no
wait hold on a second there's a too
confusing things going on one is to find
out the parent of the document dot query
selector function you know that function
object it because it's an object it has
a parent so that's one thing we want to
find out the other thing is the query
selector string is a property of some
object we want to find out what object
that is two different things this is
important this is where confusion begin
you know because you know you can see
that you know we are getting starting to
get confused so we so first of all the
the first goal I want to do is to find
out which object has the property query
selector okay which object has the
property query selector and to do that
lets go to the JavaScript in-depth
property section
property existence
I'm surprised that his own property does
not walk let me try it his own property
okay let's go true has own property so
object out from photo type has own
property
so what are we doing here we are calling
the object dot prototype I mean we are
calling a reflex apply function and we
give it three elements the first
argument is the function we want to call
we want to call the function object that
prototype has own property then we want
to give it a a value that will be used
as the this keyword in a function in a
function object a prototype has on
poverty then we want to get we want to
pass an argument that that is actually
the argument for the function object
prototype has on poverty so let's
evaluate that in browser and see what we
got taste
evaluate force
so query selector is not a property of
document and is a property of Windows
then let's try it force query selector
is then not is not a property of window
actually this this might be difficult to
to find the answer because so any anyway
let me read the comments
Kimani nomen good morning ossifer okay
so good morning Daniel the the Daniel
says the late statement declares a block
scope local variable that's correct
but however when you don't have a block
scope that let is global scope you know
when you say let X equal to three
you know you you in your source code
without any outer curly bracket then
that variable is global variable
yeah reflect has returned stop you know
if you call reflect has with two
arguments document and the Curie
selector string it returns true what
that means is that query selector is a
property it is in the property chain of
the document object that's what reflect
that has function to that's what it
means it means the query selector string
is a poverty key name in either the
document objects you know own property
or document document objects parents
objects or that objects parents object
basically when reflect out has returns
true it means you know the property is
exist in the prototype chain but it does
not tell you you know which object
actually has the property query selector
we can find it out though because
because we have tried we know that it is
in the document prototype chain but
however we also know it is not a
property of window object
no is it a property of the document
object so where does it came from
but we do know it is in the prototype
chain so between Windows in document and
we also know document is a property of
Windows because let's see Windows Start
has own property
document do see um ent he returns true
so so document is a property of Windows
ok so now we get now remember again
there is this confusion there is one
concept about an object and its property
an object and its poverty the other
concept is about an object and its
children objects so we want to find out
where is query select selector came from
we know it is in the prototype chain of
of the document object in the prototype
chain of document object so what is the
parent of the document object that is a
question and let us find out what is the
parent object of the document object
okay so in order to find out the parent
you can go to JavaScript tutorial you go
to object property you go to object
inheritance you go to
prototype chin you go to find objects
parent so there are these ways you can
find a objects parents so let's use
reflect get prototype of so reflecting
agate prototype of and document so let's
do that
okay so now we are getting somewhere
you see so this so now did you know
let's not be confused
remember the document object is actually
Windows I mean window dot document so
the window object has a property of
string key and that string is document
so window object has a property named
document okay and the value of this
property is the document object okay
that's another object and the parent of
this object document object is is this
HTML document prototype okay we can see
here it's you know this so this is how
we begin to understand the kind of
complexity so that the parent of the
document object is actually this HTML
document prototype okay now I believe
one of the property of this object is
the query selector let's try it
HTML document proto type can you
actually refer to it you cannot even
refer to it because I think it's
internal but we can still get its value
by using let's say reflect start let's
say these dead Sadie's let x equals true
reflect out get photo type of document
so so right now X is basically the
parent object of the document object now
let's say X
that has owned poverty and now let's try
query selector force
okay then let's try reflect let's try to
find out the parent of X so reflect
target prototype of X okay then we got
document prototype
okay so let's assign that to Y let's say
X W so let's say W let W equals to
reflect that get prototype of X okay
then W is this thing now let's try W dot
has own property query selector true
there it is we found we found the object
that holds that has the property key
query selector and the value of this
poverty is the query selector function
okay so I think I think I'll stop here
about this today kind of JavaScript
tutorial so I mean in the past 10
minutes or 20 minutes we have covered
covered this one of the most complex
thing about JavaScript that is the
confusion between a object and its
property you know key and value property
key that's a relation you have a you
know you have an object it has
properties each family is represented by
a key string usually your string then
this value it has a value the value is
often typically a another object okay so
properties and its keys now a second
important concept is
each object may have another object that
linked together we call we call them
parent and child so a parent so another
so any object so so that implies a
parent may have another parent and so on
so these are two very two concepts that
are often confused together now let me
just summarize again repeat that in
JavaScript when you see a dot B dot C
that dot always means a relation between
a property on the left side I mean a
object on a left side on the right side
is the key of a property the key name
has almost always a stream okay so when
you have a dot B dot C that means P is a
property of a and C is a property of B
they they have no meaning absolutely
nothing about the relationships between
the object ABC okay the piece parent can
be anything piece parent can be f sees
parent can be you know this edge you
know something you know so so so today
let's say you know this is important
thing to remember about the thing I'm
talking about and we have shown an
example because we are trying to find
where does this query selector came from
you know we know that you know we can
say document our query selector it gives
us you know you say it's a function we
so the value of this property key query
selector is a object you know it's a
function then there are two questions
one is that this function which is the
parent of this function the other
question is which object actually hold
the property key called query selector
you know so so we have tried to look
into both ways you know and we have
found out you know we have
found out that the object that actually
holds the property key query selector is
this document prototype thing that's
that's internal in a web browser you
know that's that's internal in the web
browser probably you know as that itself
is probably a property of Windows you
know object you know so so we are
getting you know you see these things
you know this this thing is not typical
you know I you know you asked a typical
JavaScript programmer who work in your
company for two years they do not know
you know you you you you show them this
you know it's it's you know 50% of these
programmers
there's a good chance that they've never
seen you know this object HTML document
prototype you know we are doing we are
seeing them because we are trying to dig
into the JavaScript language in depth
you know in practice you never you know
like you never run into this kind of
thing like the parents you know what you
you know where things came from anyway
that that I hope that is some kind of
useful information and I was rambling a
lot and you know I'm so that concludes
today's talk show about these JavaScript
so you know part of the reason I'm doing
this is this I'm you know I'm getting
for myself I'm practicing how to
articulate you know some subjects such
as JavaScript ideas in real time with
our preparation and present it smoothly
you know so I'm learning for you know
I'm running for myself you know the
ability to cheat teach JavaScript in
real time now without preparing you know
because JavaScript script I know it
pretty well you know so I'm I'm honing
on this skill of you know live
presentation so that's that's a benefit
for myself
so let me read the comments and that
that's about it today so Daniel made
some comments so Daniel
apparently is a expert in JavaScript as
far as I've seen Daniels comment he
knows you know but what he's you know he
knows this stuff for - probably not
Thanks okay so thank you guys for coming
that's it for today yeah so you know I
have all these written out in a much
more clear fashion in my JavaScript in
depth so if you like it tell your
friends by the tutorial thank you very
much bye bye