hello hello welcome to another episode
of s talk show today we are going to
code wolam language Advent of code get
ready for an adventure of programming of
the most advanced programming language
totally vastly different from all the
others you know different from rust C++
C Java JavaScript python Ruby goand uh
and different from hascar Julia or camo
all the functional programming
languages okay so uh let's begin so my
keyboards I introduce it so many times
scub 0 fantastic ultimate hacking
keyboard fantastic newly trackable
fantastic I have video reviews on each
one of them just search for it and this
is SW board SV a l b o a r d
SB search for it you'll find find my
videos and other people's uh websites
and
information cheers apple juice never
drink sugared water such as Pepsi and
and Coke okay let's begin coding uh
let's do see you know let's try to you
know not to talk too much and focus on
solving this problem this is you know
ADV vanable Cod potentially it's going
to be 2
hours so here is it uh it this is
today's talk show page uh so if you you
can search for
a.info Advent of code 2023 we did so
many problems in the past and oh there's
a mistake you see this uh list so let's
fix
that so I'm using emac Sly keys and uh
oh you got extra Ur So there it is uh so
we are doing day 13 of Advent of code
2023 day 13 okay so showing browser okay
go back close showing browser okay let's
begin and today's thumbnail image pretty
Chinese girl with a wolf Wolfram
language that's the reference with the
wolf generated by AI two videos ago we
talked about artificial intelligence
it's a fascinating thing and the giant
stride in progress of Technology huge
uh it's just amazing so W uh yeah so
let's begin okay let's uh start read the
uh let's start to read the problem hello
if you are here say hi it's always nice
to see a wolf language programming
episode fantastic thank you Dan okay
let's let this time you know last time
day 12 Advent of code 2023 day 12 about
last month we did I failed you know know
it took me two or two almost three hours
you know talking about it and uh didn't
have a
solution and and we'll go back to it you
know later because that problem if you
just Brute Force code it it's going to
be you know not too interesting but that
problem the solution is just a real is
just a math formula okay you just
compute a math
formula okay so anyway today uh day 13
let's begin
so with your help the heart Springs team
something there's just one problem you
don't see any uh any lava you do see a
lot of Ash and ingenious rock uh as you
move through the valley of mirror
something you note down the patterns of
Ash represented by a DOT and rocks
represented by a pwn sign okay you not
down the patterns of Ash and rocks that
you see as you
walk okay your personal input
perhaps by carefully analyzing these
patterns you can figure out where the
mirrors are so okay so I've learned you
know via ad Advent code you can ignore
the blurs you know that comes before Al
[ __ ] you know one one of the issue in
their wording of the creation of the puz
is that they do not this story the
background story about elves is not
tightly integrated into the puel so you
can actually completely ignored ignore
whatever the off say you know just start
to you know just start to read the
paragraph before the this thing okay so
let's copy
that uh okay so let's begin to do it uh
okay so let's go to the bottom uh okay
so yeah uh section okay so this is some
kind of P personal input
uh to input okay okay uh
actually
yeah yeah so there there showing Bowser
okay let's actually do it in
front uh code so let's do it at the top
okay so there is our toy input it's it's
just focus to
input so so so here's a input to find
the Reflections in each pattern to find
the Reflections in each pattern you need
to find a perfect reflection across
either horizontal line between two rows
or across a vertical line between two
columns okay in the first pattern the
reflection is across a vertical line
between two columns in the first pattern
okay act so they give two patterns one
and two uh so let's magnify more so the
first pattern uh let's let's shrink
this ah stupid you know the you know I
digress a lot you see this is a problem
of the web design their page does not
use a flow layout so if your window is
not you know big enough they cut off
idiotic uh okay so you have to yeah okay
let's focus so you got this this text
input find the reflection okay so so in
the first
uh okay so in the first pattern the
reflection is across a vertical line
between two columns okay between two
columns let's
see okay so you can see so apparently
you can you can see a symmetry so there
is a middle line like somewhere starting
there that reflects
the patterns on the left and right but
not necessarily the whole but you can
there's a symmetry okay so the problem
is probably find that line okay in the
first pattern the reflection is across a
vertical line between two columns the
arrows on each of the two
columns uh points at the line between
the columns okay what so 1 2 3 4 okay so
they showed that so
yeah yeah okay so in this pattern and
the line of reflection is the vertical
line between columns five and six
because the vertical line is not perfect
perfectly in the middle of the pattern
part of the pattern column one has
nowhere to reflect onto and can be
ignored every other column has a
reflected column within the pattern and
must match exactly column two matches
column n uh yeah and so on okay okay so
the second pattern reflect across a
vertical line instead okay so you can
see it's between line four and
five okay this pattern reflects across
the horizontal line between row four and
five yes indeed let's see uh yes so 4
and five yeah uh Row one would be Row
one would reflect with a hypothetical
rule eight okay but it's not there okay
um okay okay to summarize your pattern
notes add up the number of columns to
the left of each vertical line of
Reflections add up the number of columns
so it's a sum incremental sum you know
you add 1 + 2+ three something probably
add up the number of columns to the left
of each vertical line of reflection to
that also add 100 multiplied by the
number of rows above each horizontal
line of reflection okay so
add So to that also add 100 multiplied
by the number of rows the number of rows
not the real number the number how many
rows above the each horizontal line of
the reflection
okay in the above example the first
pattern's vertical line has five columns
to its left and the second pattern's
horizontal line has four rows above it
okay so total 405 so wait how so how
does that uh the first pattern has five
columns to its left
so okay it's not it's not incremental
summation it's just the number of
columns to the
left okay multiplied by 100 multipli by
number of rows okay so you find the
vertical if you know depends on whether
it's vertical symmetry or horizontal if
it's vertical you count the numbers
number of columns to the left then you
so there's a total number of columns
let's say V for vertical so V is a
integer
you uh uh count of
columns okay okay then H is a kind of
columns above the reflection
row uh so V * V + H * 100 is that is
that what
uh okay okay so yeah but make sure we
understand this part what the answer
basically the the problem is you you
want to find the
mirror uh column or row number okay but
but
uh let me make
sure number of columns okay to the left
of each vertical line of reflection add
up the number of
columns what does that mean add add up
the number of columns so in the first
example the number of columns to the
left is five 1 2 3 4 five
so and the second example the number of
rows is four okay five and four
so first P vertical L have five columns
to its left and the second okay so the
second is
four oh [ __ ] stupid phrasing of
English
incompetent you see it says add up the
number of columns to the left
this this I mean you just say the count
total count of columns okay wow the
number of
columns is a bit uh you know it's not
perfect description so this pertains to
technical writing you know I wouldn't
say this advant of code tech technical
writing is average not not not you know
not
superb so so so the basically count of
columns okay then plus the count of rows
times
100 okay so okay so uh get your personal
input uh let's get my personal input
okay copy copy and uh let's uh new file
new buffer and you want to save it
as uh let's say
Advent of code
D13 okay uh then text okay copy that
close and uh link here that's my
input uh
what
what wait oh
God uh so you got a space in file name
you don't want that so let's fix it copy
the file path close close paste link
make a list showing browser there it is
okay so let's look at our problem let's
just have a
look
so each block so you got several kind of
blocks okay let's can we do
that okay you got several list of blocks
and let's let's just show in emx it's
easy so you got several list of blocks
so you first of all split them into the
blocks then you so each one has a either
vertical symmetry or horizontal symmetry
something like that so total number of
lines 1,300 okay so let's look at one of
them uh
so so so you have to determine whether
they are vertical symmetry or horizontal
so what is this one can uh is it easy to
do by visual inspection okay not so easy
to do by visual in
inspection uh interesting problem so far
I don't I I have no idea how to go about
but let's
see where is the
huh so you want to find the Symmetry
where where would that be so you got
this odd
thing
uh okay let's focus on horizontal
symmetry
first so I mean horizontal reflection
symmetry I don't seem to see
it now is there a case when there's no
symmetry that's a tricky part you know
Advent of code tricky [ __ ] they don't
say so if it so happens there's no
symmetry what what is uh what are you
supposed to do you know you have to be
careful to read the problem again
find the line of reflection in each of
the patterns in your
notes okay
so I think it implies there's always a
symmetry then so let's just search
oh okay wait that occurs there and there
but no one nowhere
else so what about this part doesn't
occur anywhere let's use emx for
help Okay so this doesn't happen
anywhere this doesn't happen anywhere
this okay wait this doesn't happen
anywhere this doesn't
happen so there's no horizontal symmetry
what about the vertical
line oh
God
so one way I think the best way to solve
the problem is for first for turn it
into a
matrix once in a matrix you can do
transpose because a trans because
transpose is a standard procedure in
linear algebra so you can transpose so
given a matrix you want to find the
Symmetry row or symmetry
column uh which one is
easier uh going by Row first is easier
because typically you compare by row
okay so once you done you try try to
find the row then you just flip it you
know transpose then you do you know do
it again so okay so in this first
pattern I don't see a symmetric row what
about vertical line is there a mirror
line oh God how how okay so how am I
going
to how do
you do this you see when you have a row
all you have to do when you are checking
out a horizontal mirror line all you
have to do is
find the
same row okay so you go all over if you
know they must have pairs of rows that
that are the same then if you compare
then you cannot you
know if the
pairs match in a way that they they you
know you know the alter pair match the
then inner pair of matches then you you
got the mirror line
okay so if none of the row are same as
the other or or if they are only like uh
you know It's tricky because what if the
mirror row is right
here that means there's only one line
that's mirrored you see so what if is it
possible for the mirror to be
now remember the mirror is between the
rows
so yeah so it's possible the mirror is
just just above the last row in that
case you only have one row that that is
the
same well actually you know actually the
other row might also be the same as this
one but
um so this is tricky how do you ident
you know so how do you find the mirror
row that's the first problem okay uh so
first of all in order for
miror to in in order for a mirror line
to exist that
means there is at least one row that's
identical I mean at least a pair of rows
that's identical for example at the
bottom two at least okay but that does
not imply only because you could have a
line over there ler that's the same as
the one in the b in the
bottom but uh but you know only these
two are the same you know
so okay so let's write out the condition
you
know uh let's
do finding
the mirror line first
I like to write out my my my my you know
my documentation because that gives me
Clarity you know that's just my habit so
the disadvantage is
slow uh you know but uh yeah anyway so I
don't like the those speed coding
things
um
so let's
do first find the mirror line horizontal
first
then so actually turn the text block
into a matrix
because because then we can use
transpose a standard function in linear
algebra okay so that's one thing then
first find the mirror line horizontal
first
because rules are more common to deal
with okay in a
matrix
okay in order to have a mirror
line at least two rows must be identical
okay that's you
know at least two rows must be identical
so but that's not that's not the but
this is but but this is not the whole
condition okay so what is the what are
the other conditions to be sure that
there's no mirror line so at
least two rowes must be identical and
then
then then the pair of rows okay the the
pair of
rows that so you got several pair pairs
of rows that are identical
okay
um each pair you know the the the real
number of okay for each pair of RS
that's identical you got two numbers of
their R number okay they must be such
that you know for example rule one 12
three you know suppose if you have the
line between three and four so Row one
is the same as
uh six row six row two must be the same
as row
five uh Row
three is paired with row four you know
so one six you know 1 2 3 four five six
you know they they must paired in a
bracketed way so how do you how do you
turn that into mathematics how do you
um so the sum we can uh can we use the
sum of the real number must be constant
so for example
um let's let's let's let's do one
example one two three let's say this is
a mirror line four five six okay so
there are
some
suppose this is a matrix with mirror
line okay then
um then
the sum of
pairs that are the
same have
constant is constant
okay so for example six equals to 7 okay
something like
that 2 five then three uh
four okay I don't know you know this
works out or not but I'm
just uh you know go along thinking so
one way is the same sum is the same but
um you see you might have more than two
rows that's the same you you might have
three rows that's the same for each of
these
um so
so when you
have more than two rows that's the same
it becomes more
computational okay so but
um
um okay we we we must go through this
and finish it hi guys let's let's not
like last time talking for 3 hours and
no result
at least if I if I cannot solve it
perfectly at least we should you know
just Brute Force show who found language
solution Brute Force way so there's
something okay so you know to determine
you know finding out there's if there's
a mirror line that's a first job you
know once you have algorithm for this
then you can just transpose The Matrix
and do it the same way okay so but so
how do
you
um okay the
the the pair the pairs
of rowes that are the
same is constant okay now is this always
true
uh well is it is this always
true let's
see let's open my text problem
okay so pairs so I just have to think so
pairs okay so another Insight the mirror
line
when you have a mirror line let's say
this okay let's say between these two
then they pair of numbers are the same
so yeah this is a great condition
so so
so if
two rows are the same and have a
adjacent R number
it is
potentially a mirror line okay that's
one significant thing yeah that's all
you have to do you just have to compare
adjacent
rows that's right so this is the more
important thing okay so let's put that
because
um you know this this filter out a lot
of other
cases if two rows are the same and have
adjacent row number and and are adjacent
okay
okay so if no if there's no two rows
that are adjacent and the same then
there's no mirror
symmetry okay that's first condition
once you
find a pair a and rows that are the
same
then then what is the possibility you
see oh God so what if all the rows are
the
same then you have arbitrary mirror
lines you know each one of them you know
all the lines can be a mirror so this is
tricky
[ __ ] let's write that down
too uh another another thing
what happens if all rows are the same
then
any row is a mirror line okay so does
that actually happen in their problem
you don't know because Adent of code do
not say uh where is my file
so you know so if that happens then what
is are you supposed to do it doesn't
say wait so if that happens yeah so if
that happens then yeah depending on
which row you consider to be the midor
the the answer will be
different that's right so but the Advent
of a code doesn't
say so you know so if you take extra
precaution to find such a case you're
wasting your time other people speed
brainless speed coder speeds you [ __ ]
the Advent of code [ __ ] I despise this
this you know I truly despise them
because if you are a thinker you really
good you know some this but you your Sol
your thinking get got
wasted the like the goldan not cutter
you know that's another topic we talked
about in our dis Discord
uh okay so anyway
so find a pair adjacent pair okay so
further so what happens if if so okay
you find first of all you find two
adjacent pair that's the
same
then what if there are two pairs of them
so you have
four you know so for example you can
four all adjacent and all the same okay
but
however wait
so okay so the rest will determine we'll
make sure it's the you know it's like
between it's in the
middle uh
I would say if all R are the same then
you choose the one that gives you the
highest
[Music]
count interesting I don't know but you
know but yeah but you have to go with
what the problem says you know we
skipped we skipped skipped the elf part
I didn't read so maybe it has some
indication there
okay so
anyway okay you know I want to let's let
me Focus we are already 50 minutes 30
minutes
in so okay
so so we we we we are stuck with this uh
if two rows are the same and adjacent
it's potentially a mirror line okay what
are the
other conditions what about four of them
are adjacent and then and the same what
do you
do
it you know so if four are four of them
are adjacent but something outside of it
can [ __ ] it
up so this is a minimal this is the
minimal condition two rows are add uh
adjacent
so so let's go condition one by one so
if there's only only one pair of two
rows
adjacent okay then then it's easy you
just do the compare the next one you
know the outer
rows if they are all the same keep
comparing the outer ones until no rows
or all the same then you got the
answer whether it's that symmetric line
or it's
not okay so you see we uh okay so first
find if there are two
adjacent
row if not it does not have mirror line
okay period
if it does have two adjacent
rows
compare their
outer row are the
same if so continue to compare outer
rows
till no
rules
okay when
anytime when
anytime the outer rows no
match not
same the
initial adjacent
Rose is not a mirror line
okay we kind of we kind of have a
um we kind kind of have a subalgorithm
okay subalgorithm let's put it here
if all outer
rows checks
out Outer row
pairs
match then
it then the
initial adjacent rowes is the
mirror line
okay now let's check this
subalgorithm so first of all find
uh okay we are starting to get into the
algorithm of this okay first find if
there are two adjacent
rows and S if not it does not have
mirror line
okay if it does have two
adjacent same rows compare their outer
rows are the
same okay if so continue to compare
outer rows until no rows when anytime
the outer row is not the same the
initial adjacent rows is not a mirror
line that's right if all other rows
pairs match then the initial adjacent
rows is the mirror line
okay that's complete that's one
algorithm sub part
okay so but is this total does this
fully determine the Matrix has a mirror
line yes oh no wait okay
so if the above
fails find the next
adjacent same
row adjacent rows
that are same okay
repeat okay that's the full
algorithm uh this is a full algorithm to
determine there's a mirror line for the
Matrix okay
fantastic okay
so yeah
then okay then we know now is it
possible so we now we know whether the
this Matrix has a mirror
line horizontal line
okay um
now if it does then good we kind of find
the answer but if it does not we
transpose Matrix to the same to find the
vertical
line so this mirror line is ambiguous we
need to
say uh
horizontal is that spelled correctly I
don't
know
yep
so yeah
so if there's no mirror horizontal line
you transpose it then you do the same to
find vertical now
what if there's no mirror lines at
all then according to this
problem is see find the line of
reflection in each of the patterns in
your notes what number do you get
summarizing all your notes so if there
is
none then still works so if it's none
it's zero zero zero you know just that
block is just
zero okay
um now what if there's a mirror line
horizontal line but there's also a
horizontal I mean a vertical mirror line
so let
uh uh crazy
situations okay
let's let's fully document you know my
style to to fully analyze the
problem what if all rows are the same or
all columns okay that's one
issue now what
if there
are both
horizontal and
vertical mirror lines
okay that's another
question and and another
uh situation is what
if
no mirror lines at
all in this
case the block is zero okay but the
first two case we don't know I mean the
the you know the problem doesn't
say
uh okay let's begin to code okay let's
uh let's begin to code instead of um uh
you know so let's begin to code and's
see where do we start to code okay
that's analysis of the problem uh let's
say
code okay so we starting to code let's
get the toy problem input so this toy
problem input
okay
so so first of all you need to pass this
uh input so input equals to let's just
quickly pass it so you want to pass by
two line breaks
okay uh
pass in put X
input one okay equals to uh string
split
okay split input
by two line braks
okay and uh
yeah and
then then you got uh you got then you
got
blocks
okay text blocks
okay uh okay so for each text block you
want
to let's say for each text block you
want to turn it into a matrix now I
forgot how do you turn into a matrix
well
okay so
let's uh Matrix one let's say just for
example
uh so you got the
first text block that's part one then
what you do to it you split split string
again
okay uh
you split string on the first text block
which is this uh and then
you then you split string This Time by
a by a line number now remember yeah
okay so yeah so that can work so you you
want to split by a line return
character then you got bunch of rows
okay then you got bunch of rows of
string then you need to turn it
into you need to turn it into a list of
characters
okay let's see if there's a
function uh let's look at the
documentation for the function character
turn the JavaScript
on okay character represent the Single
Character okay that's not what we want
let's say
characters okay characters given a
string gives a list of characters in
string that's what we want okay so you
want to map the the characters function
map okay the so you want to map the
characters
function
by okay so let's say this is a matrix
one okay you want to map it to Matrix
one
okay then you got then you got uh actual
Matrix so actually so actually let's put
this
here
there this is the actual Matrix let's
try it so let's run it in wolam Notebook
start
so the result Matrix one is the first
part of the text
block and uh it is a matrix okay and
each element in the Matrix is a
character A Single Character okay let's
say three shift enter to evaluate it and
magnify um
um okay let's put this
here let's let's lower this level
so yeah okay so wam language three so
let's copy
that paste it run it okay then what is
Matrix one okay run it fantastic okay
that's what we want now we don't want
Matrix one because actually this is just
showing you how it works because we have
several of them you know the the input
has you know so many of them so this is
just example so instead we want to map
it to M we want matrices
okay let's let's just say x
Matrix list okay each one is a matrix so
um so this is is how you get one of them
and you want to map
again you want to map to text blocks
that's what you want to map to
okay you know not not extract it
manually like we are doing there so you
want to so but how do you map okay so
you want to map a function of course so
here we need to write a function okay
function okay function uh variable X
okay
so so each one so the the X each X is a
text block okay so the expression is
going to be something like that
okay uh so this is
X okay that's that's that's
it uh we don't want the semicolon there
so map a function of
x to text blocks text
block is a list of text like one of them
each item is a block of text okay then
for each text block you you split them
by line then you
map characters to that line to get all
characters okay so this is a matrix list
okay so let's let's run
it yeah so you got two matrices
okay so
next next heiness
heiness how am I
doing then say if they are both
horizontal and vertical mirror lines
should you have to analyze them both
independently I I'm not sure what you
mean but I
mean Oh you mean if there's one shot
solution that you identify both
horizontal and
miral yeah you can do that but that
that's a to that's another different
algorithm you know if you goal if the
problem is changed such that there is
always a center of mirror lines you know
both horizontal exist hor both
horizontal and vertical exist there's
always a
point
then if that's the case then you use the
algorithm to do that a more efficient
one but but but right now the problem is
just focused on you know either or so
let's
not uh focus on that so anyway so we got
this so now let's continue
to
uh we want to
check given a
matrix does it
have
horizontal mirror
horizontal mirror line okay that's the
next thing we are doing
so a matrix we can test it out with the
first
Matrix so the first Matrix has a
horizontal you know this so so let's go
back to uh algorithm
uh we were
saying so basically here is the
algorithm
okay yeah let's
um find if there are two adjacent rows
are the same if not it does not have
horizontal so find two so first of all
find two adjacent rules are the
same let's comment it out I mean that
let's have profused commentary so you
guys
can see what I'm
doing so the first problem how do you
find there are two adjacent rowes are
the same
okay very easy
okay so what do you do so this is about
wolam language kind of special to wolam
language in other languages you
basically are the loop you know you
write the
loop uh you know like you know X you
know you know for each row you compare
so so row current row equals to you know
the current n you know I I you know Loop
for for I to length of the real number
you know then you you see I then next
loop I + one to see if your I is same as
I + one you do a loop but in W language
you do partition
okay so partition two arguments the
first argument is the Matrix okay let's
say uh
first okay let's let's
say okay let's just say this is
temporary to illustrate this is the
first Matrix okay so you give the first
Matrix
uh
then
you yeah so yeah so you first Matrix a
matrix is a list of rows each item is a
row okay so you partition
it so that you partition it and you want
to have repetition of one item so let me
show you what that do exactly okay let's
say one two three 4 okay so you can
see 1 2 3 4 let's say uh five six 7 okay
so you uh this visual example is much
easier to understand so you see it
generate this 1 2 2 3 3 4 4 five 5 6 6 7
it partitions so that each result is a
pair you know a group adjacent things
but with a overlap of one items so
that's what you got if you don't do the
over if you don't want the overlap then
you just get 1 two 3 four five six right
okay so we are doing the partition to
this then then once we got pairs you
know then we can just map map a function
to compare if they are the same okay
so partition so let's do it here so uh
Let's see we need to use random numbers
okay let's say 667 okay then once you uh
then you
map okay you map a function to this
partition okay so first of all you need
a function
there so uh and the function will be
just same Q okay same Q means equality Q
means question any any function that
ends in capital Q in wolam language
means that function always return either
true or false always so you just map
this same Q to that since you know same
Q is a function name you don't need you
know that part so for example I'll show
you
here uh wait
uh what
all right so let's
see one two two three so then you map
same
Q why what happened there
that's not true what what's going
on one and two are not the same so why
is it return
true uh so wait so you got that one two
two three
what God wait wait why is it
true one two two
three none of these are true so why is
it um
okay
so I don't know what's going on I think
there's something wrong so let me just
do this okay for example one
two and
uh 2 three eval the current
line Force right
so so what is is uh wait okay so let's
try that eval the current
line
true okay so the problem is when you use
sim sim and you just have one argument
it just return
true yeah
CD so what we do we don't um yeah so we
actually want you don't you you want
apply okay so
basically uh a little bit W I'm
syntactical trickery okay you don't know
what I'm doing
but but this will work okay let me just
show it you see falce force force force
true falce why is it true because you
got six and six so in other words you
want to map a function to these pairs
but you don't want just pass the whole
thing as a single function you want the
function to you know you want the this
items to become Arguments for the
function so basically so that means you
say apply so the way a more
understandable way to write this part is
just apply let's let's do that okay
apply same
Q uh with a x Okay so so let me just do
that in fact this will be a function of
X and there okay so that is much easier
to
understand okay so for example copy
that paste here there it is okay okay
so so let's see so we the so that means
the first Matrix in our T
example the line number so how do you
get this line number
so you see this one two three so if if
these one two three are real
numbers right they are real
numbers
uh so they are one less
okay so one two 3 4
five the fifth item is true so what does
that mean so one two three
four five so that means fifth and sixth
rows are the same so if nth item is true
that means nth and n + one row are the
same
okay
yeah
okay very simple okay so so let's apply
to the Matrix so when if we apply to the
Matrix it should return one two three
four it should return three okay we need
to um find the true position okay let me
show you
position do that and uh and let's say
the above okay then you want to find
the pattern for uh true
okay you know you want to find a pattern
that
is true okay let's look up documentation
for position I believe that's yeah you
see position takes a
pattern second argument okay so there it
will
return one two three four five okay
you'll return five that
means uh wait control um what shift
enter okay so you need shift enter shift
enter five you see so that tells you the
fifth and sixth row are the same
fantastic now it may return multiple
results when there are more adjacent
pairs are the
same okay so far so the you see we we
are not doing any Loop this is supreme
functional programming Supreme in other
languages you don't do you know you
don't do this rarely actually they don't
even have partition I think python just
added that few years
ago uh and but I don't think they even
have I mean in our case we
need we need partition with the with the
overlap of of one I don't remember if
the python functional Library have that
I I do think that they added partition
uh
anyway so let's remove that more hard to
understand version so put it here so I
can
write notes later so so this is what we
want so it returns this returns a bunch
of true and false okay so actually we
can run
it okay so actually let's do
this uh okay so we didn't you didn't
so it returns that okay uh then you just
need to use the position okay let's
see
uh let's just say these 10 variables
okay
so now you just say X3 so that
returns if it's empty means
no s adjacent
rows else result is
a
index
int
oh
meaning result is a list of
integers each
means
the let's say the result is
say
for
N means nth and
uh m +
one rows are the same okay
okay so something
okay
so so now we
identified so if there is you know we
need to string all this together into
one like one one one block of code so if
there is no suchar index then there is
no mirror rows at all okay we
determined then if there's a me there if
there is then we need to guard then we
need to like then start to compare outer
rows
yeah oh God tedious [ __ ] now I'm I'm now
I'm kind of I I want to
stop yes you have to give two arguments
to same
Q uh so Dan are you a wolam language
coder looks like you are did you did you
buy the wolam language or are you using
the wolf from
script so anyway
so you know so then you know yeah we
made some progress the the next thing is
to
compare okay then we have have compare
their outer
rows oh
God this can also be easily done you
basically you have a list of rows once
you find a pair of adjacent row you
split this
matrix by that you know you so you split
you know the rows above and the rows
below okay so you got two sub Matrix
then you
just then you just
um then you just flip the first one like
reverse order okay so they row are
reversed then you just compare the two
submatrix row by
row to see they are all the same until
one of them run out okay
run out of those yeah
so God more
coding okay so we we need to start to
like have some sensible variable names
okay so first Matrix
partition
um what is this this this is actually
just a example
yeah okay example of
partition so that's actually not
a problem
okay uh yeah so I mean
let's just show
it okay so the
same uh this will wa when it eval by
line This returns force of course and uh
if only one argument it returns
true which is
mistake okay so but what we want to do
is actually this um okay
so this
is syntax shortcut
example okay the wolam language that's a
whole chapter about it very
interesting you see because in wolam
language you can turn the this you know
when you paste this you press the key
shift control n it will turn this syntax
into uh well not exactly like that but I
mean well let me show you control shift
n okay it turns into that but you can
turn that into this syntax by just
saying by saying this okay
hold uh full form
okay shift enter there it is so you see
you you know you see so they are like
syntactically equivalent 100% at the at
at the you know because the wam language
even if you do 3 + five before it
computes that it turns that into the
full form syntax it turns that into Plus
35 so it basically turns that into a
list syntax before it does anything but
but it offers you this kind of syntactic
shortcuts like that and like that so
this in thisp you would call that reader
marro okay so again wolfen language is
like you know it's it's it's a lisp so
anyway so we are digressing here so but
but but let's go back to our problem we
want to actually solve the problem okay
so the first Matrix is that then then
you partition okay so you don't need a
variable there so you actually you put
that
here um yeah so that's the actual Matrix
you want to partition then you apply the
function then you need to say position
okay
okay position you want to find the
pattern that is true so put this part
into the first argument
okay so this will
return return all
row
numbers
return all raw numbers
of the first
row that are adjacent and uh same okay
that's what this
does is of
in each is a RW
number means it and next
row
are are the same okay better technical
writing this is the OD of technical
writing return a list of integers each
is a row number means it and next row
are the same so if
empty if
empty
then no same adjacent rules okay now but
if it's not empty so so so now we can
properly name this uh
Sam
crazy long file names which I usually do
same neighbor real index list okay
something something like that okay
getting crazy so now but anyway we have
we have nice variable and uh you know
you know very short so you see the whole
solution to this problem is one single
line like every you know every of these
these uh Advent of code their wolf
language solution is one single lines of
code no more than 200 characters at most
characters okay so anyway same number
okay so what you're going to do with
this so if it's empty you know there's
no uh it's there's no horizontal mirror
line but if it's not empty then you need
to go through each one of them [ __ ]
tedious
uh then you know it's a [ __ ] tedious
then you need to split then you need
to
God oh you got a copy of Mathematica 13
fantastic
uh yeah fantastic yeah uh functional
programming no
Loops uh God I I I want to stop you know
because it's
how long have it been now
it's 70 minutes now
yeah
[ __ ]
pain repetitive string injury typ in too
much in the past month right here so we
have this special marble ball
prepared that
is that so I can you know do this feels
comfortable these are kind of heavy this
is a crystal ball fantastic oh this is R
tracing physics you know like Stephan
wolam cellular autometer computational
Universe you see at this moment there
are billions busy computation going on
there so that they can show show your
face you see any more you know all the
atoms atoms light rays neutrons you know
they are busy calculating which way
which one where should I be you know
they are so Al busy so this is stepan
wolam science of cellular
automat and uh okay a
break okay so do I need to push through
yeah I I will sure find a solution today
but uh maybe I have a break or
something uh ah god
so let's see do I got any
okay who else is watching is it
fun so let's see two three concurrent
viewers thank thank thank you Dan Dan
you are the only one
watching uh okay so this this um yeah we
need to finish it where is Steve Steve
is actually watching in the background
take a 10 minutes break okay yeah
actually that's a good idea
so yeah that's
a good idea so let's let's be back in
five minutes
okay so let's clean up a little bit so
that uh so we got you know let's
okay so that's our code basically shrink
a little bit right yeah that's our whole
code
um okay so can you guys see it yeah yeah
so I'll be back in five minutes drink
drink and
smoke smoke got into my
eyes
for
e for
e
okay yeah y okay let's let's let's begin
Let's uh continue I'm back welcome back
so
first let's say first
row
indexes let's say
first
so so are these still the same
Matrix yeah we are working on just the
first
Matrix so first
Matrix
same
neighbor r
index massive long list okay so yeah the
first one is just that
okay then
uh then you do something to that
so you see it returns you know I let me
show what it returns okay let's select
all go here paste it evaluate it then X
same neighbor show what's a value okay
there's a number now what if it's all
empty
so yeah you see the problem right now if
you want to say
if you know what you want to say what
you want to check if it is empty list
but the list may be nested
empty
list is so first of all you want to
check if it's you know nested list but
it's all empty so there are many ways to
do that so for example uh you know I
can you know I can focus on solving the
problem
but or usually
I you know distract and do the easy
problem easy problem is just showing to
examples of how to code bam language so
for example if you got the list this
list you want to
determine
um if you have this
list you want to determine if it's all
empty okay what do you do so the that's
what we need to do you know if this all
these index is is empty wait
so
um okay actually that's not the case so
the actual the possible case is actually
just either that or not that okay so
let's let's for forget about
this the actual case is either that
or uh like like a list of numbers you
know like that okay so these are the two
possibilities let's say let's write it
out two possible
results
this
or something like that okay let's put
that uh here
that's what
this that's what this
is
okay so to determine that is easy so um
to determine that is
just that that that okay so if this is
true that means there's no horizontal
mirror
line uh by the way same Q can be
Rewritten with triple equal so another
easy w f language
tip you know this line and this line
line are exactly the same they before W
and compiler do anything they first turn
this syntax like this into that in fact
this is still not full form in fact it
turns it into this
okay so it turns that into this they are
the same thing now why is this this is
actually very important the full form
syntax or Lis syntax because when you
started to do pattern matching it's
matched against the full form
okay so
anyway uh
so let's put the tips here it's you know
something we explained about the
tips syntax
shortcuts and uh full form it's called
full
form
ARA
uh syntax shortcuts AR
L reader
Mark and for form ARA six in in lisp
jargon thisp
Fanatics
okay do I make
sense then do you code uh thisp so
anyway so uh so anyway so so we want to
yeah same uh so we if
so if this is
true
then then basically means
no horizontal mirror God this is
otherwise okay something oh god there a
lot to code [ __ ] yeah
so basically if the if it's empty then
stop but if it's not then we need to do
something we need to for each of
these number you know there may be
multiple for each one of them you want
to split it by that
row
yeah okay how do you split the list
let's just start to code okay so is
there split
list uh spelling correction
so I don't know it's uh we need to look
up so you need to do this here so show
all function names that contains the
word split okay so basically we want to
split the list
audio split split by string split file
name split split okay let's what to see
what is
split split a list into sub list
considering a run of identical
elements this fantastic you see we don't
even need to
do consisting of runs of identical
elements yeah we don't
you know we actually can skip this
partition thing this directly
split
okay exactly split into run of identical
elements yeah so yeah actually we can
skip this
step yeah so you have a bunch of rows
you split at any two adjacent row
numbers so
you know if there is no okay so that's
one thing what's split
by split by split uh into list of sub
list consist consisting of run of
successive elements that gives the same
value when f is
applied now we just need
split okay let's go here let's another
Excursion split
okay let's say three three
four five six that's easy
okay uh oh okay it just uh it returns
that
so nah that's not that's not what we
want
what about options there's probably
options yeah basically it's doing what
we are doing SP can be used to perform R
run length in coding okay if can be used
to do run length
encoding
uh okay for
example increasing run okay oh you can
do less so if that function
applies
huh oh God
okay I I I I I really need to focus on
solving the problem okay because
otherwise it's going to take another two
hours
um so let's just continue so
split so we got a bunch of rows we want
to split on adjacent so if we do this
split uh then but
then we got things like that
on yeah so we got kind of a
pair each result so if the result has
length two that means it that's it so
the result each element in the result
will either be length two or length one
is that true I think so because you
can do for example now remember uh our
case
remember our case each item is actually
a
matrix
so so for
example uh
so
God so our example is actually each item
is actually a matrix so something like
that okay so you see this is is a matrix
now if two of the item are the same
let's say you see adjacent row so what
do you
get okay so it's starting to get complex
you get
that 3 three four you see right so
that's still correct so each item in the
split result is either length
one uh uh is either length one like that
length one or length one or length two
so length two is where
you where is this adjacent row but the
rest of rows they
become an item of
themselves so but that okay that's not
how you want to split it
oh okay let's do a reverse UNAM okay so
you see let's
do so UNAM Q is basically not same so
the not function reverse of same okay so
if you say un same Q then you get um
let's let's do it here
okay so first first of
all if you run
that you get that okay now if you run
this you will that's I think the result
is what we want let's do
it okay let's
see it returns
that uh
now yes that's what we want you see this
this is one group exactly so a matrix of
rows it split at you know the split it
into
two uh but what if we
have yeah so you see what if we have
more oh
God what if we have let's say
x y
so another same pair there and uh then
let's just say random
okay
God so you got that that so these two
the same these two the same what do you
got we forgot to save it okay anyway so
let's do
it okay comma ENC counted okay so extra
comma you don't want
that well you're missing your comma here
okay so let's check okay run
again uh so you got this result how do
you so
again so now it's split into three
groups okay so you can see 4545 there
and xyxy
there
right so now but actually we just want
the
first you see because we want to do it
one one thing at a time the first pair
of the same rows adjacent rows at a time
then do the next so if if there is there
another optional argument that says
return the first
nend uh no I don't think so
so okay this is not good this is going
too slow okay this by this way we will
never
finish uh this this is too slow okay so
let's just focus so you um
let's just
do now we need to a function that's
split by position you can
range nine okay so let's say range n
let's say six
okay 1256 that's correct and let's say
drop 78 9 yeah so this this is how we
can use we can do split okay each of
this this number is that index number
where the the row is the same okay so we
can you know this is split by position
okay so once we split the second part we
re uh the first the first group re
reverse the order then compare each God
there so much more coding so yeah
um so it's Matrix indexes okay so let's
see so
far
copy close that let's see what this x
first okay so it gives you a
index uh
is show in it
okay it's just
okay much easier
shorter uh so first name so so so this
first
same the first same index the first same
index so if if the first same index is
that then no horizontal mirror other
otherwise otherwise you need to split it
okay
god let's put that there this is our
like scratch Pad uh so paste it there so
if the first
Sim delete that so then you got split
by
um you you basically you want to
split by a matrix I mean this
Matrix okay so so that's the above row
and bottom row and the uh um so you want
to split on what is this x first
same okay
so and uh this this will be the
index so the this will be the index
something like
X
so we need to write a function okay so
the function will argument of X and will
return this which is split okay now for
the second part for the first part we
need to reverse
okay reverse the old
okay check the documentation reverse
list
yeah okay you so you want to
reverse
uh then you want to compare oh
God and you can do partition again so so
I don't know you guys know if you have a
question questions ask okay so uh so we
apply the function reverse and we want
to compare each
pair let's
say uh one two three so one two
three and uh yeah let's say the second
part has small numbers you want to check
them so that
um so that this will be considered equal
okay
so map
thread what do you get if you do map
thread
okay yeah the length are not the same
then you need to shorten the length [ __ ]
I don't want to do you know this more
tedious
coding so let's let me think if there's
more elegant solution now this is
getting
too complicated
so so you have adjacent samal
number somehow uh is there a function
that the
Symmetry uh Matrix symmetry okay
like we want to know if there's a
function
that automatically can determine if
there's like a r
symmetry okay so let's do this
again yeah this
not yeah
where is
this stupid okay it pass
possibly can you just run uh no it's
like three rows okay so argument
symmetry pres persistent symmetry okay
so uh not symbols s y m m okay 2 m shift
return okay
symmetric Matrix
okay now
that you know so yeah so that is not
what we want because symmetric
Matrix to a structured a array okay so
symmetric
Matrix
that usually is like diagonal symmetry
symmetric matrices when represent as a
structured array allow for a convenient
specification
[Music]
uh
so yeah this symmetric means they are
symmetric along diagonal
axis uh so that's not what we want we
want
permission Matrix what is her Mission
converts a her Mission Matrix into
structured
array
so so what is a her Mission
Matrix okay hum Matrix is a matrix
symmetric Matrix but plus something
else uh let's
see herion
Matrix Mission
Matrix also known as self joint okay
works for symbolics okay so Matrix m is
submission if m equals to conjugate
transpose
okay yeah so yeah so that's still
basically symmetry along a diagonal
axis uh so but in linear
algebra um yeah you don't really
you don't really have the concept of
like symmetry of rows so what what is
there some kind of
so yeah too slow
so so do we really need to do this
manually yeah but if you do it manually
you got just small codes to
you know I you know the worst is like
the bunch of if statements you know like
that that's what C coders would have to
do they have no other
choice you know for example we want to
compare two matrices if they are the
same row by row but however one of the
Matrix Matrix may have less number of
rows right so
of course in C you just do a loop you
know you check you know each one you
have the length you know the short you
first of all you have to find the
minimum which one is the minimum length
then you go from one to up to that
length then you compare each row you
extract Matrix and so on right that's a
typical iteration I mean the imperative
style procedural style of Loop in C
that's your only choice you have no
other choice you know but in W language
that's how how you do it you
um you you can use this map thread but
that's not you know but then we have to
drop you know this part uh that's not
what we want so let me just think
about uh yeah so uh only tricky
to this type of problem can be tricky
really tricky to program using only
functional and patter
magine uh yeah well I mean p i mean
functional and pattern imine it just
require more thought oh actually pattern
imine so let me think about that is
there easy way H yeah maybe there's one
shot solution to the whole thing pattern
maging okay so patter imine let's see
that's a potential you know one single
line pattern magine we'll find
the yeah exactly so let me think about
patter maging so uh patter magine you
have so you want to match a pattern
so such that such that the top list of
rows is like reversed from the bottom Le
rows
okay so and
uh and you know the number of rows are
may not be the same you know you might
have uh yeah so but it's possible so
let's see p matching you want to have a
list of
rows yeah actually it's very possible to
do this whole thing in patter matching
okay okay so uh let me you know I don't
know you know I can
either uh match C expression form okay
so yeah we can use that to
yeah expression form so what level does
it match the the levels the whole
expression
yeah so stream match remember free Q
replace patter okay
so um we can do that but how do you
specify so the if you use P matching the
issue is how do
you specify the pattern so that it fits
the problem you know find find the
symmetric real
number yeah that's actually very
possible
but you um
so you know I can show you a example for
example
um so for example you need a matrix you
need the Matrix somewhere
so uh Matrix list same index list first
Matrix so let's get the first Matrix
okay so that's your first
Matrix so for
example that's what it looks like oh
God oh God why is it
yeah so that's our first
Matrix
uh yeah so then you what you do is that
for example this first
Matrix uh
you yeah we can use you know so the
first Matrix yeah so there's a
horizontal line then you
can so uh so you put the first Matrix
here and you want to specify a pattern
that matches that how that that's that's
the just of question how do you is it
possible so the the pattern uh to find
the horizontal line is
that is that you have two first of all
you have two shapes of Matrix
exis uh so one or
more so this is a sequence of things one
or
more and
uh okay
so this this part basically means one
row okay two means one or
more okay so this so the first you know
this part means a row and adding that
means many
rows so you want to give a name to this
pattern so let's say Rose okay so Rose
is a name for whatever matched pattern
that you can give a parenthesis
okay but then you want to say that
this God so then then you need another
uh you
know then you need
a rest row okay let's also give a name
rest rows okay so so uh so the rows are
split into two patterns okay then you
need to
say you need to add a condition for
these two match and the condition is
that so this is a Syntax for condition
the conditions is that you know we are
back to what we were trying to do there
you you have to use some kind of
function to do it or can you purely do
it by pattern now if you want to do it
purely by pattern then you need to give
each row a
name yeah so this is not this is um
okay let's go to patterns okay pattern
matching so here's a introduction to
pattern matching what exactly does p
maging syntax I
updated these uh pages
last week or so so uh blank so you want
um close that you want to be able to
find the
symmetry
so yeah so basic named patterns then
repetition one or more or zero or more
then you have repeated
patterns right um
yeah and then you have conditional
pattern yeah so this is what you have to
do uh condition I need more example here
um I forgot which one is which
conditional pattern test but anyway one
of
them uh okay okay so let's let's
check so let's check so
condition let's see example so
condition condition is using a
expression
okay okay now I got it so now pattern
test is using a function okay so pattern
P matching can be supplemented by a
condition clause you have two ways one
is pattern test which given given a
pattern when it matches you got you you
know you name it such as here row and uh
uh rest rows then you can apply a
function to your named thing to see if
they are true if this function return
true then the pattern is considered
matched okay so that's supplemental with
a function to test
pattern the other thing is this
condition which instead of using a
function is simply use a expression
okay but basically they are the same
semantics I mean they are the same thing
one is just using a function form one is
just using expression so okay we got
that part clear so but here we so you
know either case so we want to basically
we want to compare the rows and rest
rows such that the reverse of
rows is the same as rest rows item for
item so we need to write a function
here now but one of the problem is that
the rows and rest rows may not have the
same number of
items so that
[Music]
really yeah so you know like ultimately
you you do need to write this
code but suppose we do that suppose we
do have this I mean it's easy it's not
hard to write this code you know you
just have to it's more tedious you just
have to find the shortest of the two and
drop the you know extra rows so if we do
have that function then this pattern
matching then we don't have to do all
this manual thing before because this
pattern matching can actually I believe
so okay I don't know
but so okay let's Focus let's write this
function uh how do
[Music]
you so let's see so uh so rows a bunch
of rows and uh so first sequence of rows
and rest sequence of rows then you need
to
um okay and uh let's look at map thread
so if the is there a way to
automatically drop when their length are
not
equal uh so let's see thread threaded in
a
transpose uh through
that's no Co map that's experimental
this
is that's not what we want okay let's
see through through is more complicated
through is hard to
understand
um yeah that's nested app nested
function
application and so we want something
like a map so we actually you know once
like if you you work out at the end it's
really simple just like two or three
lines for the whole
problem um but the problem is just
figure out what um thread thread is
another complicated
thing threads F over any list that
appears in O Okay thread a b c
[Music]
so
what a x b
y yeah that's not what you want so
so you see you can do it by hard coding
it but I'm trying to find a simple way
of dropping the last
elements droing the extra elements but
uh but we need to actually solve the
problem okay
uh
drop so you got two bunch of rows two
Leist of rows you want to drop the one
that has extra
length
um you know okay
so yeah got tank drop
yeah we can do this so I
mean so we can like do transpose and
partition yeah transpose and partition
then you just map same yeah trans but it
gets more complicated
so you can just
just
uh or you can pad you can pad the
smaller one so there is you know you can
pad Matrix
actually array pad that's what we want
array
pad okay so array pad you can
move okay I I I need to
okay this is taking too long that's no
good concur viewers four Okay so
he
so function reverse yeah that splits The
Matrix into two
submatrixes so once you have split then
you then you then use some kind of so I
need to cut off the one that's longer
yeah definitely cut out the one that's
longer but I don't want to do manual
like manual find which one length you
know get the length of both and compare
which one is the minimal then drop the
other create a new you know new list of
row dropping the extra line I don't want
to do it manually there is absolutely a
simple way okay so it's just about
thinking about it so we got uh you we
got two lists so you want just to drop
so this some kind of
um
same map
so so if you have
yeah so the length are not the same how
do you do that so [ __ ] God I stuck on
this pure ideological problem
okay that's a problem given two lists
inside the list create a list like this
namely drop the longer list rest items
so what is the proper I mean what is
the like
the prec nice way to do
this uh and can we do pattern matching
okay so back to pattern matching we can
reverse row I'm not doing a good job now
so okay so if we focus on this Sub sub
problem pure
problem
um how do you do that so
and
just so array pad yeah you can use a r
pad if you use array pad you have to
find out you know the dimension of one
of them which is then like manually
manual
coding because you need to find you know
how many you want to
pad
uh but I'm I'm so what why is the map
thread I want something like map thread
but
ignore extras so think let's think about
this
so so yeah we want to map thread we
thread it in a applying function to part
of Expressions applying function to a
list list manipulation let's
see uh table array range
subdivide uh no no Spar array numeric
array no toes no next list
no uh so list subtraction first last
take drop take list extract a pend
replace parts so drop can be used uh uh
but and again you need a explicit number
of items to drop but we don't want I
don't want to
manually you know to get that
information so uh select and cases
select
so so is there a way or am I just stuck
in Pure Fantasy Land like academic
Fantasy Land I'm pretty sure there is a
way splice okay no that's splice no so
flatten okay so these are kind of what
we want
okay uh rifle okay rifle
rifle is basically
interweaving two lists okay so you can
see in this example it interes to list
now what if one of them is shorter that
is a question you know there it is
rightful
okay so rifle let's say it takes one
argument or two so it can take yeah two
arguments okay so back here remove the
bigger one do
it okay one one 2
two and uh one one two2 and three it
dropped at
three uh why does it drop at three
I don't know but rifle is probably the
answer okay let's reverse the order
let's see what happens
okay evaluate
it okay so 1 one 22
four now this should return three three
but it just got one single three why is
that uh y a list in which every nth
element is X okay that's you know
interweaving things that's what rifle
is because once you know if this returns
one one two two 3 three then we can just
partition it and that solves our problem
you know partition into two every you
know groups of two
so uh yeah so we getting closer okay not
yet uh now we want to find out why is
this rifle it should be 1122 33 why is
it you know one one two two take one
from each and three
uh okay so why is it stopped short
there if there are few XI then gaps
between e and rifle the XI are used
cyclically okay the order matters the
order of the
argument the X1 uh is used
cyclically okay one one two
two
3 so you want to put the longer list in
front Okay so you can one way to do that
to solve our problem is you put the
longer list in
front then you do the rifle then you
just partition partition it into groups
of
two when you do partition it will
automatically drop the indivisible rest
of
items so when you partition into group
groups of two you if you have odd number
of items the last one is dropped which
is what we want so but what if this what
if the first one is significantly longer
let let's try Okay 1 2 3 4 4 five six
okay R
it so you got one one two two 3
three then okay then it uses the second
argument to to inter weave cyclically so
1 one 2 2 3 3 then 41
52 and six six okay so you see the rifle
doesn't you see rifle interweave things
in between so it doesn't that's why it
doesn't have the last part but we want
the last item there's a way to do
that so uh here a list in which every n
elements okay so you want to Rifle but
you want the last
yeah you can do that but then it gets
more complicated
so oh
[ __ ] and let's let's just say it's
getting too complex located what's
delimited
sequence uh represents a delimited
sequence of elements of the specified
form in interpreter and related
functions what does that
mean I don't know go back so let's just
use pad then you just have to get the
length yeah you just get the length of
these two lists then just drop one of
them so finally you you have to
use I mean you have to call
length so pad left we want to pad right
yeah we want to pad
right so pad right pad right just add
extra item so this is actually the
easiest but if you use pad right right
you still have to get the
length
uh uh okay
what
pad
what yeah then then you still have to
get the
length Victor hello
uh P
right
so okay you think too much so let's just
code
it so if this is a function that drop
reverse and then
okay
so patter matching solution
now when you use a condition what's
what's fed to the
function patent
test oh okay so it just so when you use
a
function you can
only
check the whole matched pattern that's
the argument pass to the function okay
so you cannot
use in our case you cannot use the
pattern
test you need to use the
condition yeah
yep so yeah that's right so that's why
you use you have to use this condition
the condition is
that the first rows the first
rows is reverse of first rows is the
same as
restro yeah we can do that okay so let's
see the condition would be let's say
parentheses reverse first rows okay
reverse the
rows and so yeah we need another pattern
here
so reverse of the first bunch of rows
so we need another match Q okay the
another condition nested pattern
matching
so so this reverse of
rows
matches okay so the reverse of
row yeah but then we make sure we need
to we still need to know which ones got
more
rows so
reverse Rose
uh let me just do this
okay we need spice
okay
then then one or more so zero or
more
matches mattress rest row
Okay so condition is
that
or this is really getting
complicated or we reverse this
two okay that way we don't have to find
out which one is more items
yeah I'm not sure this will work but we
can try so let's
see uh let's see the syntax is correct
so yeah so let's try it now this is
purely Advanced
test now if this returns true that means
we have one single line to find out a
matrix has a row uh mirror line
horizontal okay run it okay syntax
Arrow
got expression cannot begin with dot dot
dot dot oh what oh because yeah so this
should
be uh this should be blank blank one
item or more so
wait yeah one item or more blank BL
okay
so do it
false which is not correct
because our
Matrix is symmetric there is
a you know there is a you know these two
lines
horizontal mirror line so this is false
obviously because you know we need to
refine it yeah we can do this in parine
for sure but it's just that now what is
the alternative I forgot what is the
alternative but let's just forget about
that okay let's see yeah these two lines
so the first group got three rows the
second one two three four four rows so
the first one is shorter so this should
work wait so wait so when so
um you know let me just let's make it
even simpler okay so if there's three
items let's say
x
y z
what what are we doing
so so that's that's one row and repeat
it okay one or more now is it possible
for zero or more
uh R rows
so so you want to re uh condition okay
with a condition such
that
you reverse the row and the
spice got to finish this problem got to
finish finish this
problem reverse row reverse the rows
okay so but make sure we got rowes
though are you sure we got the
rowes can can we like
print it will do something you will
print every time it tries to
match yeah it does print you see print
uh
wait wait it got the whole thing so this
is okay so now we getting somewhere
let's
[Music]
see pound one two two one okay one two
two then one two
one okay it's actually printing the
whole Matrix so this is wrong 1 2 3 4 5
six 7even
1 2 3 4 5 six 7even it's sprinting the
whole Matrix so when you do this one it
already matched the entire
Matrix yeah obviously because you are
saying any
row zero or
more okay now but um
[Music]
P matching business is insane yeah it's
like regular expression you know except
it's more even complicated regular
expression takes a year or two to really
to really Master but here with the
symbolic patterns on
Expressions there's one significant
difference with compared to regular
expression is that you can nested Nest
you can match nested
things so then there's whole more
complexity because even with regular
expression which is which does not allow
any you cannot use it to match any
nesting even with just that that in some
cases you have exponential growth so
here it's even more but anyway so but
the this matches the whole but why
doesn't it tries to continue
to have
um why is it just matching
once I mean you should
try with rows being just one row then
two row then three row so okay uh then
so oh God this is so complex
Fu
uh uh so we have to go back to drawing
board so I mean we let's try something
or simpler let's try to find the
adjacent um lines okay you can do that
by uh you know
real uh
okay well row
x uh a so that is a
row and uh
actually
uh okay so row a is a list okay that's
okay
then uh okay row a is a least row b and
anything uh zero or more okay three
triple underscore means zero or
more of anything okay so then you got
row a row
b then okay so this needs to be row b
okay then
anything uh this remove okay so that
will let's remove
that and we need to add a condition
condition condition give a
parenthesis row
a uh row
a
row a uh row a equals to is the same as
row b okay that will uh
return okay you don't want to use match
you want to use
cases cases will return all possible
cases so cases take two arguments the
first argument is whatever expression
the second argument is a pattern in our
case our pattern is that with the
condition of
that okay now let's see pattern syntax
again
uh pattern yeah condition yeah slash
semicolon okay shortcut or you can write
the full word condition let's write the
full word
uh condition okay so condition has a
syntax
condition yeah it doesn't it only use
the short
syntax now condition two arguments
pattern and test okay so you got to have
a pattern then you got a
test okay so we can you know we can see
if that works
by I mean the proper syntax we can
see by that and
by uh let's say
x let's say this is our pattern okay
then let's say with a condition so we do
that hold it don't evaluate it then we
call full form on this thing so this
will give you the full Syntax for
condition there it is so you got the
condition you got two arguments the
first argument is that a list of
patterns which correspond to this XY so
list then pattern x blank pattern y
blank then the second part here is the
same same qxy so you see that's a full
form of condition got that so to rewrite
that with our condition we can just
say there and condition a pattern with
this condition add it okay second
argument Okay
so so if we do that
then then it will list the
line two and three
okay and what is it
[ __ ] one two three four
no yeah I mean this is you know we just
have to work more on this we're getting
closer and closer so now it return two
things why why does it return two things
that because there are two cases
that
two sub expression that this match
so so the only thing so cases let's see
what is
the default level level
spec Cas is this is this I'm not doing a
good job because a simple a simple thing
that you know you you can do it in a
loop in 10
minutes is becoming too complicated but
that's what that's why I'm doing
the Advent Advent of code because it
gets you to
exercise because I haven't used you know
I haven't really coded wolam
language that much since
1990s uh the default value for level
spec is one yeah so is one that's right
so it's one okay so you you don't want
one the level spec you want
to uh you know that's a bit more
complicated to expain the level of spec
you want it to because when you have a
tree when your expression is not just
flat Leist you know because we have a
matrix which is a list of
list each list is a row so list of list
so when you have a expression that's not
just a flat
then then you have when you want to try
to specify a pattern to match it
basically you are trying to match a tree
you have the issue of what you know what
levels of Branch what depth you want to
match because a match can happen at
several depth so that's why it's more um
comp you know more comp much more
complicated than than regular expression
because regular expression is just
flat so uh so what is the level we want
to match level one and uh
see we want to match this so this is our
pattern basically
this is our pattern we want to
match uh we want to match a zero okay
so
wrong zero let's
try so when it matches now uh now now
what does it return so you need to uh
when it
match it just return the whole
expression I
think
zero 0 to one okay so yeah so it returns
so you need to replace it
by let's say if it match you return F
row a
and row b okay if it match okay now
let's try again shift enter fantastic is
that
beautiful now we are talking you see
this single
line gives us the rows the adjacent rows
that
are the
same yeah so so uh so what about this
one why is this one happening let's go
see so we are talking about Matrix one
here so what is this pattern pound pound
pound pound Pound starting with five
pound where does that come
from oh it came from here
wait what which which one Matrix are is
this
oh Matrix list that's so we be all along
we've been working on this both of them
that's we just want to focus on the
first one so let's do it again so not
Matrix list we want the not the Matrix
list okay we want just the first Matrix
this
okay so go back
here regroup okay now third argument con
zero to now oh yeah so now we have to
redo the level yeah so level z uh
level level zero okay so I think so uh
let's try
okay so we are working on the first
Matrix okay so which is this you know
and uh it will return the rowes that are
oh we we forgot to use the
transformation function okay so you need
to so when when you match you want to
replace it
by
uh okay you want to replace it
by by that okay so let's
see finally you
see now what if you have the second
Matrix you know this is fantastic okay
so let me just go here let's put that
there uh so this is working and now
let's
try okay now we remove that let's not
use match okay so this remove remove
remove those we uh kind of try to work
uh remove match Q okay so this this is
what we want and I
mean I mean that's not the final result
but but suppose the uh let's not use pad
right so what is the the full Matrix
list uh okay so where is okay so the
full Matrix this okay so now let's try
the second one
okay this will
return the second one you see pound dot
dot dot pound pound dot
dot pound dot dot dot pound pound dot
dot so you see this is a second text
block but now let's use let's find all
lines adjacent lines
that's um the same okay so it says it
did find it because otherwise you
wouldn't get this F you know you are
replacing that any occurrence of that
pattern by
just FF okay so you found it and that's
pound pound pound pound Pound do pound
pound okay
so there it is so they are
all wait what the [ __ ] okay the second
one is horizontal symmetry right so
anyway at least
we we have successfully used pattern
matching to find the adjacent lines
without you know without actually
writing code you know like
um like like this map and partition you
know and apply and position
so yeah this is going somewhere you know
so
so this Returns the
um Returns the rows that has the
horizontal use pattern matching to
returns neighbor
rows that are same okay
now so the fact that it only return one
item means there's only one pair of
neighbor rows is that true that's is
true neighbor rows that are the same
what about the first one the first one
you also return uh one
item you know you see the first one is
result is
here
so but what if there are more rows
that's the same well they have to be
adjacent so yeah but that can also
happen you know two adjacent same row
and somewhere else so it could return
more than one result okay more than one
element uh but in any case so this using
pattern
maging will
return a list of adjacent rows in this
case is one only one pair at least of
pairs okay
and uh okay so then you know so we are
you know we at this point we can instead
of using cases we can use position to
return the index of these rows you know
for example we can use position uh
pretty much the same okay just use the
position function okay position
function it takes a pattern and Returns
the position with where this pattern
occur so level level spec level spec uh
what should level spec be in this case
Okay so so we can do that for example
let's show it um so but you cannot do
the replacement so for example let's
remove that so that returns empty wait
uh level spec position Matrix
2 something like that
what
[ __ ] but anyway it can return you the
index instead of the
item okay but something we did
wrong I don't know what that is it
requires a lot of thinking okay
why is it not working now so but this
works still yeah that works but why is
the
position
position so you have to think about the
level what is what level is it
it should be zero
okay returns
nothing what about 0 to Infinity
okay it's Z returns nothing but uh I
don't know what's going on
there oh God so but anyway so this
Returns the pattern
then then you just need more
um yeah then then you need you need to
basic you need to find the mirror line
not just the you know not just the where
they are you need need to determine the
whole Matrix do they have the horizontal
mirror line or not uh but we can you
know but we
work on top of this so this pattern
returns
you so you can if you name the
rows most
so you name the pattern rest okay so if
you add the rest of
rows then with a condition that in this
case you want to
know so we are going back
to this kind of thing wait not we we
need we are going back to that reverse
kind of
thing
God yeah
here
what where is that
reverse did I delete it I did okay
so oh God so we have to check the
reverse you know the RO reverse
God this is no
good hey
coffee okay I want to stop you know it's
been three hours basically going nowhere
[ __ ] fa failure this is actually just
failure you
know yeah but it's not I mean it's it's
not it's common okay so you want to do
this problem you don't want to do a you
know imperative
style you want to do purely function
functional style and you don't want to
manually get to check the length so
that's kind of like artificial thing you
know I'm doing that uh with wolam
language because if you are given
python you have no choice you don't
think about you don't think about
like so what what is our problem I
describe the problem here you know you
just check the length and check what
which one is maximum or minimum you know
smaller then you drop the you know extra
parts then you finish your job so I
don't want to do that so that you know
for that it takes 30 minutes and not
done yet and then you know then rifle is
probably the solution but maybe not but
anyway then then we want to do pattern
matching so this
problem I'm 90 98% sure that this
problem given a matrix one single
pattern matching function
call can tell
you which line if you know can tell you
that the line number that is the
horizontal mirror line or it doesn't
exist one single line of pattern
matching okay so we went on to do this
and we made we made some progress okay
we made some progress at least at least
we can we so far can use pattern
matching over here to return the two
adjacent neighbor neighbor lines that
are identical
so that's a seed of the horizontal one
one of the first condition must be so we
made some progress there but
um but the part is that we need to
reverse you know all the lines before
this row compared to the rest of lines
and see if they are
equal and ignoring extra number of rows
okay so we need to so what we need need
to do is we modify the pattern by adding
more for example here you see this
triple
underscore that means zero or more items
that's what I start to do here so you
know any zero or more row then one of
the row then one of the row then the
rest of rows okay then you give a
condition condition that says row a
equals to row b okay then you need
another condition such that the you know
the first and row
a together you reverse them is the same
as the row b plus the rest of rows
okay yeah okay so that's you know you
just need to add another condition so
you have like kind of now nested
condition another condition within
condition
can you do that yeah so
um oh okay actually you don't have to
Nest condition you can
do you can do an
end uh wait maybe not end because
condition does condition return true or
false what does condition return no
condition is just a pattern it actually
doesn't return but anyway any anyway you
can you can have a end you know like
patter matching in patter matching you
can have Alternatives or you can have
like both of these condition must be
true I mean both of the pattern must be
true okay some somewhere here
okay longest shortest and you know when
when you have longest shortest it gets
exponentially complex like regular
expression uh and you know so
yeah but the result will be spectacular
so you also have orderless pattern
because the result will be like one
single line like this that tells you a
matrix has a symmetric horizontal
line okay uh that made me think another
issue with this problem is that you see
so far the Symmetry is between the
rows but it it is it is also possible
for Matrix to have a horizontal row
symmetry such that the center of
symmetry is One S one row okay is that
part of the problem it doesn't I I mean
I don't I don't know if it's described
precisely that's you know they
don't so that's another thing to look
into so anyway so one single line using
pattern magin that without you know just
specify the patterns just you know I I
think I can do it but but now I'm tired
hours so you know act you know we
deleted the code before but basically
the condition will
be the condition is
that okay so this you know so this is
one of the condition you have adjacent
real
numbers but the other condition is
that uh you need to use match Q okay so
actually so instead of cases you match Q
match Q will match the whole expression
you know uh at you know the at level
zero okay so you don't need to worry
about the level spec so you match
Q so you
have you want to match this
pattern okay expression form return true
if expression matches pattern
form okay that returns true or false
okay so you can see some examples here
they match plus they match uh whatever
golden ratio equals to zero
okay so yeah they they trying to
determine if the expression is zero you
just use zero as the pattern okay so
pattern matching is very complex and
they are doing more more fancy things so
here is a pattern with a function to
test and also it involves Association
like a hash
table um and this look at this is a
weird getting compx
okay wam
syntax okay so and
here you know you want to match um but
anyway
so that okay I'm pretty sure match Q is
what we want it returns
true then it means this Matrix has a
horizontal line of symmetry
so one single pattern magine but what
exactly is the pattern so we need to uh
so a pattern with a
condition so how do I add more than one
condition so let's
see
condition
expression um you you you you don't have
that okay so you don't want that
part so condition so second argument so
the first argument is expression the
second argument is the condition what
condition a = to B+ n oh so now here you
can use end okay so
end uh do we have a shortcut
no uh and
okay so
and this and another condition is that
you want to
somehow uh the
first so let's not use the first word
let's say
front Okay first replace by front
okay so
condition
front and
rows uh but they you want to make them
one single list okay so
you splice front
Okay
uh forgot what is the
sequence no you want to splice
okay yeah
so
front and row so that's one
thing you want to check if this thing uh
then you want to reverse
rows and I
uh you see when you I mean actually over
here you need to do another pattern
because wait do we need to do another
pattern I mean yes because because
otherwise because what we want to do is
like this okay what we want to do is
like you want to check if two items are
the same so the first item did I just
delete that thing [ __ ] I
didn't so we want to check uh the two
things are the same the first check
is one group of list this is whatever
before the mirror line is the same as
the second group okay so this will be
row
a you know reverse of row a is equals
to
um row b with the rest okay so this will
be
rest okay we want to check the re
reverse of whatever comes in front of
the rows is equals to the row b with the
rest okay
and but but however when the rows are
have different kind of items then this
won't work they won't be the
same so what can you do then you again
you either write the function to like to
to you know to see which one is is is
more number of items then you cut the
one that's shorter you know that's
longer you know or so if if you don't
want to do that which we don't want to
that we don't want to we spend one hour
trying to not to but if you don't want
to do that then again you start to use a
pattern so you actually have a a pattern
within a pattern so so here instead of
this you have to say so wait what what
is this the rest okay we don't need this
rest here so
yeah so one of the solution is here it
gets you know it's nesting start to get
problem so let me try to format it so
you can kind of
see
and yeah condition so you see actually
we need um
you know
condition
uh yeah then you know match so match
takes two argument one the first
argument is the Matrix itself the
expression the second argument is a
pattern it checks if this Matrix matches
this pattern now what is this pattern
this pattern is a condition meaning that
you match this pattern but but then this
condition which is the expression must
be also true based on whatever named
things you have in a pattern okay so you
want to check this pattern you know
front row a row b first of all you check
row a and row be are the
same and then you check that
whatever comes in front of RW
a and and and the reverse oh okay so you
actually you reverse it wrong you want
to reverse not ra a you want to reverse
this whole thing okay so whatever comes
in front of row a plus row a reverse the
whole you want to see if it's uh same as
r b and the rest of items okay
then however you got a problem here
because if the row numbers are different
this always
fails so how do you solve that well you
can solve that by starting to check the
length of the rows you know like the
problem we have here you know like this
problem then you know drop the longer
one so you have to write a function to
like manually do that or
so instead of doing that if you don't
want to do that then we replace this
part by another pattern
so uh so let's you know so replace this
same Q by another pattern
okay so match Q okay
so
M uh M
ACH Q so yeah B another pattern so what
is a pattern this pattern would
be another condition okay
so this pattern will
be uh What
uh so what so the available values are s
x front B will be
rest oh God you know so another P okay I
need to
stop thank you guys for watching you
guys are so still here but now it's
three and a half
hours yeah you know I continue 1 hour or
two I'll finish it eventually
but ah but this is not good you know
I mean
but but it's kind of common okay if you
want to you know if you are trying to do
it this way uh but the whole solution
will be beautiful is just just just just
like just
just 200
characters uh yeah but
yeah so you want to yeah so can you
actually use another pattern
yes the match CU will always return true
or false so you can use it inside end
you know and means several argument must
be true so first of all row A and B must
be the same adjacent rows okay
then then we want to know all in front
of the adjacent row and rest of adjacent
row are the same when you reverse them
because they are mirrored you see you
know match you know so the rows you
know you know they they need to match
outer pairs so how can you do that you
know you can just reverse one of them
can
you did we forgot something uh actually
we need to based
on the shorter
one you can just yeah okay another issue
you can't
just the shorter one must come in front
if you want to do it that way okay let's
rethink okay is there a
way just reverse the whole thing okay
don't does you know it just reverse the
whole thing and you just add this you
know zero or more patterns that will be
able to pattern match that's the beauty
about pattern matching you you know you
don't have to be
specific you can just pad the pattern by
zero or more
so so all we care is that one of these
you know so we are given two list of
rows All We Care is that
once one of
them matches a sub expression in the
other okay but one of them they must
reverse rows so the smaller one yeah the
smaller ones you need to reverse their
order that's
right and we have to write it out got
so we given to this of R we want to know
if
you know so we want
to to know if we reverse the one
with
smaller
length it is a sub
expression of the other
larger okay now if they are same length
then everything works we we can actually
you know no problem but if there's one
of them is smaller then we need to do
this you know and this can be done with
pattern matching you know we can start
the next step is to start with a toy
example instead of using our Matrix
because you know because we use the
Matrix
that's complicated to compare which you
know we can just use a toy
example um yeah so for example each
number represent the Matrix you can do
that um do that do that do that so for
example uh so for example okay uh
okay paste random number okay so imagine
each number is just a row okay so you
have you know these two
rows uh let's
see okay so imagine each number
represent the row a to example then you
you know 156 156 that's the row A and B
they are adjacent and same then you just
want
to find out which group is smaller
number of items you reverse the
smaller uh wait yeah you reverse the
smaller one then you try to match
pattern to see if this revers smaller is
a sub expression of the larger but older
must be the same okay so in order to T
that you can for example test you know
for we can for example start with start
with you know given two groups this is
already given to us okay so you know one
like that one like that okay so we are
given this okay two groups of
rows then we uh try to use uh match
you know then we start to play with our
pattern
so um and we know you know so that you
know so we start to work on this which
is
um okay
so yeah
but yeah so so what we do so
we oh God
okay uh let's let's try to get something
actually works okay so you know so we
actually
show so this works for
sure so
let's let's work on
that this is a matrix this okay so
remove
that so conditional so given a condition
a pattern let not okay there condition R
B A and B okay let's add some items here
okay let's first of all assume the real
numbers are the same numbers of items
okay 1 two 3 4 5 one 2
three four five same real numbers okay
oh then you must
also make sure they have the same
numbers that's annoying
God okay let's just cheat okay let's do
reverse
here okay reverse add that
evaluate okay we got that
so for testing
purposes we can you know this is our
test case 156
156 963 check 94 check 5 93 check 646
check so we
got they are so if we have this Matrix
they are you know symmetric then this
will return true this this thing will
return true
hopefully I don't know for sure wait so
this part we this part needs also
to yeah this that's not SP so hold on a
second let's see what if you splice with
a empty brace brackets
okay let's say
[Music]
t
what okay so you need so basically you
need that let's say
three it just remove the bracket
okay so but what if it's empty what do
you get
yeah so that works uh but what if you
can you like have two of them
together
no yeah spice only takes one arguments
yeah so let's
see uh yeah it takes only one thing okay
so okay but it can be empty
right empty also works okay
so now you see so now you
got now the front is potentially zero
item okay so what if you splice with
zero uh no argument at
all God it doesn't
work and so this this you got the issue
because this this named pattern this
fronts
uh uh
what oh God we named it wrong f n TS
okay uh let's
see okay rename fronts to just front
Okay Okay so this fronts is potentially
no item at all it's a list okay it's a
list of
one item or two or more but also
zero so when you so but when you know we
have seen this when you cause flight
with zero items it's got a
problem um
so better way to do this you know so
instead of
splice font is like what zero or more
items zero or more they must be at least
so let's be specific okay the rest is a
list too list means a
okay
so
now front is the
least okay so let's check
sequence let's check sequence sequence
is also like splice Okay so
sequence
okay okay so let me this is a normal
kind of normal wam coding
session uh it is indeed like this I mean
even if I'm coding by myself you kind of
got
I kind of have to do this kind of thing
so when you do sequence what you
get uh
nothing so sequence expression one two
three uh so normally it's something like
1 three yeah but that doesn't work you
need a bracket out side okay so this is
a normal
usage the difference between sequence
and splice is that for sequence the
arguments are not
leasts for spice the argument is a
least okay
so so the typical actually the typical
example of using splice is like least
more than one one item like
that okay yeah it basically just remove
the
brackets yeah so but for sequence it's
um you see it returns that
good uh What if you you just have one
item let's say that's two not one okay
so what if you just have one item let's
do
it okay two yeah that's good now what if
you have no item what you get this
should
be it should return return an empty
list yeah it does okay I don't know why
what I
did I don't know why I something I did
wrong before okay so here is a sequence
here so sequence allows you see splice
nothing is
Arrow yeah that's actually good that's a
good thing because splice is you're
supposed to have you know a a list
inside so but when you have a sequence
and you give it nothing it returns
nothing that's good result so
so here we want to actually what you
want to do is you want to yeah I know
what to do now so you want the sequence
okay
uh
sequence okay but you want
to apply the sequence to that this gets
complicated but and just trust me
okay and the
rows yeah the row a you don't want okay
so then okay you need to do the same for
the rest so this sequence something add
add something to is to basic it uh it's
to make sure
that you see you have a list of rows but
here you just want the rows you don't
want the least you you know
because oh or alternatively you can a
more easier way is you append row b to
the
rest and here you
prepend I mean you append row a to the
front that actually is
easier uh but if you do I mean easier to
understand but if you do a
pend what happen is
that you again you need to test for
example let's say one two okay
uh weend three we got one two three okay
right now but the situation is that what
if you
append uh nothing at all so I mean yeah
so this front this front thing because
they are pattern matching this front
stand for zero or
more lists so when you got zero list you
got a problem you can't I mean when I
don't even know what zero list is you
know you got a problem so you cannot use
a pen
okay so okay so that's why we are using
this sequence we work okay so this is
our test to example to see if this so
what does this do is
that you attach the rows in front of the
row
a and you reverse
it then uh not same Q you want to see
match okay so this needs to be another
match because same Q doesn't account for
different RW count but in in this
example there the same RW count okay so
this will
work uh double check one more
time uh sequence you don't you don't
want that okay so sequence at at font
okay double check one more
time okay so let's evaluate this
expression it should
return true true okay do it
please false what the
[ __ ] oh
God how the [ __ ]
now how do you debug this well I mean
you have to use some other P magic
because match CU always just return true
or
false uh but you need to now you need to
dig what the heck is going on
so can you like print this
thing I am not even sure that will work
so let's use a compound expression this
Sprint is just a side effect it doesn't
do anything okay okay so but I don't
even know if that
works you see it's still
forse I don't think you can use Sprint
um here so but so you need to change the
match Q to like cases like we did before
cases so that we actually see you know
what is going on
[Music]
got you know
so so okay so let's let's move this to
to our test pad and me to our play
ground okay so that's about sequence and
back here so we okay yeah so you want to
use cases then okay I'm
like right now I'm
a case Q what's going on case Q not not
lower case
fact case
Q cases okay this cases Q okay uh not Q
okay it's just
cases okay so we are right now I'm a
living zombie just mechanic mechanic
drill down trying to work this out
living zombie without thinking out of
the box you know maybe you shouldn't do
this maybe you
should but let's just let's play with
the living zombie part so what do you
what what is going on if you use
cases Jesus what so cases you need a
extra optional argument you want to
match the whole expression okay I don't
think it'll work it just um you know
empty yeah so you need to think about
what is exactly going on with this uh
thing uh okay Dan okay thank you Dan
yeah so what is this so what the um
so cases reverse sequence
we we need just we need just to uh test
this so sequence is the rest what is the
rest rest is
like oh we forgot wait the input uh the
toy input is incorrect [ __ ] the toy
input should not be a sub expression it
just should be just like that okay it
should be just like that the toy input
is [ __ ]
wrong you know it's a minor mistake so
it's not that okay so let's put that to
the bottom you know comment this
out yeah so that is supposed to be the
you know that's what we are trying to
match you see the front row a row b yeah
so that you got it wrong in the first
place of course it not match let's try
this one do
it
Force oh then then it cannot be a list
okay then it should be a
integer okay you need to change all this
list to integer because because this to
input we try to use a integer to
represent a row a row is a list okay a
matrix row so now since you are using
integer you need to replace that
by integer how do you spell it in
intg yes yes yes yes do that okay now
let's eval this please let it be
true options expected instead of 639
Beyond position three in apply sequence
so uh what
oh yeah
then then we what is the sequence row
a x front oh X front is not
integer wait yes it is one zero or more
integers so this a sequence of zero or
more integers what are you saying
optional expected options expected
instead of 639 639 which one is that
639 instead of 639 Beyond position three
Beyond position one two 3
okay in so in here so it's actually
trying to you see this at at that is the
apply okay so so you are saying here you
know WFAN language is saying that so we
are trying to evaluate this
sequence options so this apply is used
wrong
so what is the front you know the front
is actually possible zero you know zero
or more integers now let's go back here
zero or more integers right does that
work uh two three works one single
number does it
work two Works zero items does it work
oh but then you are doing you are like
uh you are then you are doing apply
[ __ ] okay okay so you are doing apply
Fu let's check again oh yeah so don't do
apply Fu
okay there there okay run it
oh true the most beautiful thing for the
fast
hour
true truth is
beautiful okay so this part works
out use pan maging to return neighbor
row that are the same that's what we are
doing for this exact
example we use integer to represent a
matrix R that's what it is okay but it
works however the next problem to solve
is
that we need to check the cases when the
when the row numbers are different in
this case the row numbers are the same
you see before and after
so you know 1 2 3 4 4 four rows before
the neighboring row and four rows after
but if the rows are different in length
you got a problem so where where is it
so yeah
so cut
paste make a line what the [ __ ] what did
we
do cut undo go down make a divider
paste okay yeah okay so so now we have a
copy now let's work
on now work on
when the
front rows and rest rows
have
different length
Okay now that's that's when you use we
need to replace this same CU with a
pattern okay let's do that okay you know
we went so far let's do that however it
takes mechan zombie coding Style Match Q
again you want to match okay what do you
want to
match well you match you want to match
first of all you want to match a
expression and what is the
expression you are given
okay now you are given the expression we
can actually create the expression okay
uh you are given something like that
okay front row a row b
rest okay and your sequence uh sequence
thing is still
useful uh yeah so we want to do
you want to
match okay first of all you well what
you want to match is front and rest okay
front and rest and reverse okay
so basically you want to match just
these two expression I mean this one
single expression just made out of front
and rest
one either one of them can be zero item
like no like empty okay
so you want to match you know and we
kind of have to go back here so we have
to create a new pattern because the new
pattern
will
accommodate like extra rows
okay so so how so
um yeah you know so again we can break
out into a to problem here I mean a to
example that that purely focused on
this oh
God yeah so again we break out into a
toally
example let's let's remove that whole
thing so
actually remove that we got a toy
example where we
got this is where we are
before
like front and back this time let's say
the back is missing on the
item okay so you know so this is our
example we want to match this you know
this this part is the front this this
part is the
back okay and we can you know we can use
the word front to for it because it's
named pattern okay anyway so we so front
and
back hey how do you want to do it and
and but this could be zero item though
that's the thing you want to be
careful so the whole thing can be like
empty this
if you do it that way
um H tricky you know
so but what do you want the pattern to
be well the pattern now can be again we
utilize the the triple dot which means
zero or more okay that
can you know like just just like before
just like what we did
here uh let's try it here so you know
so you know let's say new
front something and use new rest
okay and uh then you don't need the row
A and B you don't need it because they
are the same we already
know but you want this pattern with a
condition that uh but wait but this
pattern you need to also add
new front okay
wait oh
God I need to think I do I want to solve
this yes now my drink is gone okay
another five minutes break okay uh
another five minutes break let's clean
up our code where are we going let's
clean up our code so far let's see you
know we're going to work 10 hours to
finish this
problem uh since we so what is this does
it work
no because you didn't Define the things
above so before we were using like the
functional I mean manual coding but
right now so manual coding up to up to
to up to this point okay up to here and
we didn't finish the functional you
know it's functional programming but
it's compared to pattern matching it's
more manual because you are telling it
exactly what you want to do but we with
pattern matching you don't even you know
you don't have
to like exactly tell it you just
find if the pattern is correct okay but
the trick part is to come up with the
pattern okay that's what we are doing
but anyway the first part is we are
trying to you know functional
programming so far so good this is the
The Matrix X Matrix
list okay then we test out using the
first
uh wait this is not actually this is the
first Matrix okay so actually
Matrix list and the first Matrix here
okay so this is the first
Matrix looks like that and then return a
list of int each is a real number let's
clean that let's let's let's put it
return a list of int each is a real
number means it and next row are the
same if empty then no same adjacent rows
okay
if empty list okay so this is how we use
functional programming and actually also
contain patter matching to to to get the
adjacent same rows okay index of
[Music]
then then what do you got then we got
okay so two possible result is that
empty or at least of indexes that's the
adjacent row then
we uh then we get the first
adjacent Sim rows then we do something
with that we kind of stopped here
because we want to be able to because we
don't want to we refuse to manually
check the link of row count compare them
find find which one is minimal then drop
the extra R count then reverse actually
we can do that we you know let's just do
it manually and we solve the
problem [ __ ] this [ __ ] oh
God okay so that's a summary of what
where we are for the first approach okay
the first approach is that you know is
this is is is this thing is is we don't
you know we refuse to call the function
length we want to have a
[Music]
more how do you describe it kind of like
more
mathematical by a mathematical condition
or
mathematical uh way of expressing you
know ignore the extra length so we tried
rifle rifle is kind of on the
spot we you know map thread is what we
want to do but map thread does not
ignore when you when one of the length
is got more items so map thread is just
map the function to
each uh element in the list you know
they feed you know if you have three
lists the function uh receives three
arguments if you have two lists the
function receives two arguments two yeah
you know so map thread is what we want
but map thread does not
ignore extra items in the Leist it gets
an error so that's why we want to you
know maybe use rifle but the easy way is
just to you know manually check length
and drop the item okay so anyway so this
is a sub problem we we get into so now
but
now then we went to into the pattern
matching approach okay like pure like
the using ping to solve the whole thing
okay so first of all this one we'll Sol
we'll return we'll get you the rows
that's are the that are the um same
adjacent row okay which
one this
one H [ __ ]
yeah because you didn't evaluate it okay
so we you know you need to evaluate the
code before the code so what what is
this oh yeah so this is the first Matrix
so this works we know because we tried
it you see fantastic okay um and then we
tried the second one actually so
actually we can just um use that you you
know the first one
okay but you need the least so where can
we get the Leist um well the list is
here so you can copy I
mean so you you could you you could um
put this here uh okay then you evaluate
okay yeah you will but
what empty uh but uh but yeah then then
you need to grab that
[ __ ] you see then we need to copy this
okay we can do that it's not too
bad so you know this single line
solution okay let's run it shift uh uh
tab e
H split stream problem but uh no God
then you don't have input input is a
string [ __ ] then you need to copy this
whole thing that's not
good
[ __ ] oh
god so let's forgot forget about this
hole let's just use this
uh okay this is the MJ matx number one
the first text block okay that works
then uh so let's I mean here is the
what's doing use paning to return
neighbor rows that are the same it it
does that and here's another
test on second Matrix okay it also works
let's try it here do it yes you see they
have different results because both both
the first one both the first one and
second one happens to have a
horizontal uh adjacent same horizontal
row right but the first one actually
don't have a a miror horizontal line it
has a vertical okay but once we you know
solve the horizontal we can easily solve
the vertical just by transpose okay so
again we are like I'm repeating what
when so what went so far so this works
and
then okay then we don't need this
one oh yeah we added the name front and
rest okay delete that
then then okay then we are trying to use
patter
magine to solve the whole to solve the
whole problem okay
to find if a matrix has a
horizontal
mirrror line okay so this code is not
working because we have the issue of the
length oh but and also it's using splice
okay but anyway it's not working uh
given two list of rows we want then sub
problem we want to know if we reverse
the one with smaller length Okay so that
is that then we um yeah so this is not
working then we going
to okay so we use the integer to
represent so delete
this this even what okay to
delete you got extra okay so anyway so
then we use a simple example to test our
pattern that works that works
fantastic okay so we getting better now
it works when the before number of rows
and after rows are the same count okay
but the issue is when they are not the
same count so we use another toy input
to try to get it
and uh okay then this this part we
delete delete delete delete delete okay
so now we are at this
stage which needs more thinking so but
um
bre okay I suppose now nobody nobody's
watching seven
F seven okay but anyway so let's Mo
let's go on let's break time 10
minutes uh so but but uh can we can I
like put this onto the web first so you
guys can
see you know kind of my I mean where
today's talk show so here's today's talk
show yeah because I if I put this up
then people can see what is the current
state of the
art let's do that okay
so uh backspace B to pop this
back make a
backup syntax color sh browser so this
is so far what we have the toy input the
algorithm description and algorithm
exploration that's all still correct and
some thought process Crazy Edge case
situations that this
edotic Advent of code no say it rewards
the brainless it punishes those think
throughly about the problem well
supposedly part two will deal with that
you know part two will pun fin those
those spread boot Force according to
Steve so anyway we got the situation so
here's our code let's upload the code so
people
see what is going on okay so let's do
that control X the pow shell multi
language
exploration P so all you need to do is
say ask
sync uh R sync rame r r r sync there it
is
okay do that let's uh I have to type
password so let's stop screen for a
moment uh what is this uh desktop show
uh okay my brain is somewhere let's see
desktop audio audio input or Logitech so
let's try this one Jun no not that one
that's keyboard I want you gotta see my
hands no not that one that's face oh
display
there okay sync server okay so sync
it okay are you sure
yes
and fantastic
okay so it's
uploading quite a few
things now
let's let's see what is it so a b of
code and lots of my other website
updates lot typing of the Dead t34
layout keyboard night keyboard keyboard
1,000 function keys happy hacking
keyboard light two but spring Atrius
keyboard or update um and China
something
something politics or Deco very squ okay
so
now okay so let's close this yeah so
close this now return the
screen now you can see nothing happened
now so now you go to talk show it's on
YouTube description
okay
uh so now break 10 minutes be right
back wait what's going on so
wait magnify magnify magnify the food
Glory now you need daytime so let's
insert daytime you need the full daytime
what uh the American the this this this
ISO date full time okay
so uh be back in 2018 16:00 and 16 uh
25 25
spectacular go to
here to see the current state of the
art the
art yeah perfect you'll see you guys in
a
bit now today's wolf okay beautiful wolf
girls we have to show
that no comment comment comment
guys now I have to remember to turn back
audio
e
e e
okay I'm kind of
back make sure I don't have
four
messages
okay everything
good let's see who who is on Discord who
is
talking first picture wolf second
picture the
girl okay
programming so we are doing
programming uh
okay we back so everything check
yeah yeah so back to code yeah so
um this is
intermission okay
intermission close it close it close it
now we back to code make a backup copy
copy delete that and and uh showing
browser go back here and uh pop this
out okay back to
code still the same problem
so before we you know we use functional
programming without you know real patter
matching that all we have to do is just
check the length Okay uh that will make
things you know we can do this you know
we can just solve it if we just check
the
length
um
yeah yeah so the problem is you want to
when you want to actually do limb kind
of in a perfect way then then it's will
be two or three four
hours okay
so if this empty then first this empty
so otherwise uh otherwise you just you
know functional
approaches I mean yeah it's kind of kind
of
simpler so functional approach what's
the first St so you need to map this
okay I mean each each row number of the
adjacent same row you need to try it so
this is just assuming one adjacent same
Row one pair
and uh you want to compare reverse take
then uh then okay the function then you
can yeah it's it's you know you you can
easily do that but it's just let's let's
try to complete the functional simple
kind of
approach um you know that we can do in
10 minutes I think
okay then thanks for watching you see
you later
yeah so you know so let's just do the
function okay and you know you all you
have to do is just use width okay so
width then you you assign two
variables uh that you know that is so
you give it two variables kind of so the
first let's go it front equals to that
and
uh rest equals
to back okay so that is a constant width
is a way to allow you to define local
constants so we Define local Constant
front which then um take okay
take uh take the first s in index yeah
that's the index
wait no that that's that's wrong okay so
let's remove that so um first St is the
index first Sam so you have the index
list so but what's the first Matrix same
index list okay that's actually for the
first Matrix yeah so this actually needs
um so the first Matrix let's put that
first Matrix there so actually let's not
put the first Matrix
let's let's claim more code so we don't
um yeah
so replace or first Matrix
by let me show you okay
this is what that okay replace the uh
first Matrix
there
by by that okay so remove one Global
variable okay oh there's one
occurrence so same index list that's
also the first one okay the same index
list
okay so the same index list is for the
first Matrix
okay then the first occurrence of the
same index list okay let's also remove
that variable
so uh hold on a second let me double
check something okay doesn't occur good
now this occur multiple times you want
to replace all occurrence of that
by by that
okay ignore that one for now that that
that okay now search okay now we don't
need this anymore remove one more
variable okay so same index list is a
list of items of the row number of the
first row
of the same pair that's that are
adjacent okay like
that so when you get the first so uh so
when you get the first one if they are
the
same oh yeah so if the list of index is
the you know it's empty then you don't
have horizontal
mirror no horizontal line mirror okay
make because that's confusing when you
say horizontal mirror does it mean
horizontal line mirror which is
mirroring up and down or does it mean
horizontal
mirror meaning that
um you know the the horizontally left
and right uh mirror so it's kind of so
you but when you say horizontal line
mirror that makes it
clear uh horizontal mirror line okay
that means that's
clear that means up and down are the
same so if it's empty this same index
list uh let's double check same index
list yeah we are you know right now it
only works on that one so this you know
this code needs much more uh clean
up yeah
so yeah but uh I'm taking too long so
you define a local
variable so
so the TCH yeah so you map it to what
the
function the function takes X yeah so
you want
to so what is X x is a
index all right so X is a index
Okay so
let's let's just write that
so you take
that okay you flatten first of all you
this same index you don't want you don't
want this nting just flatten
it okay so we just flatten it
yeah actually just
flatten okay at is a short Syntax for
the square bracket so you can so it's a
prefix notation so you don't have to
Nest the square bracket so you say
flatten okay flatten and the position
actually takes another argument of
level level SP okay so position you know
so if you actually give it a position it
makes it
faster so you want to level one only so
position true and level just level one
that should return
same then you flatten it so same
index so same index will look like
that or looks like uh you know like that
okay list of
numbers okay so if so if the same index
is equals to
Mt
then wait same index least first
one uh
what why is it first one same index
yeah you don't need even first one same
index
list okay so potentially it has more
than one item right so it's empty list
or more than one item so but if it's
empty then there's no horizontal mirror
line you need to rewrite this in a
functional way here
but if it's not empty we need to do
something okay so that something would
be so you start basically you need to
map a
function you map a function to each one
of these indexes each one of those
number means you know if it's three that
means row number three and four are same
if it number is seven row seven and row
eight are the same okay so you need to
you know try each one so you write a
function to map this list okay so
actually you can just
map uh you want to map but you know once
you
find something is true you want to stop
but okay so that gets another
complication
so if you want you know so that for
example let's go to my wam Language
tutorial you'll find s w Language
tutorial so you want to Loop in
iteration okay so so in the past month I
did a lot rework on that lots of update
so here's the all the things everything
you need to know about Loop or iteration
with wolarm language you know it's
beginning with intro to
iteration so in this case we want you
know actually we don't want just map
because we want to test where as soon as
we found that a matrix is symmetric
around a horizontal line we want to stop
we want we don't want to continue
computation
right so we don't need to check the next
pair of lines that's the same
row as soon as we found the pair of
lines that's the same row and the rest
of the outer rows match a symmetric we
stop so in that case you don't want to
use map go back you want to use
um create a list uh recursion procedural
Loop
scan uh what is this uh list operations
Okay so
so wait so what we want uh we want to
stop a loop as soon as we found a
condition so yeah so that would be scan
for each also known as in JavaScript or
other languages so scan simil as map but
return nor and
[Music]
uh so you can use return to return
results so
so there's so many ways to do this
so yeah so you can use scan
okay so let's use you use map because
map everyone understand if I say scan
people don't understand what is it we'll
change to scan
later so map takes two argument so the
first one is a function of course so
here is our
function okay then the second one is the
same index list
okay that's not a good name you know
what does it mean same index L that's a
this of real
numbers whose next row is the same
okay but anyway let's keep going so so
you map a
function you know so to this list so the
function takes an one argument that's a
index then you compute
the yeah so now you want to compute same
index list okay so you want to compute
that here is wrong here you should take
the Matrix matrices okay
so let's go back here so you need to
take yeah the matrices okay so you need
to take the
Matrix let's see if it's defined you
know so this is a
matrix uh yeah so you you so okay so so
here and
then
you and and over here you take the
Matrix
uh yeah we need to work on the first
Matrix okay so you take the
Matrix from zero to the index number
okay so let's see take
documentation take list and takes the
first n element right okay you you know
given the Matrix you take the first up
to
the same row index okay and then you
also drop the first end so that is
[Music]
the given a list with its first end
element dropped so you got the front and
rest okay you got two list of rows okay
then then um then you
do God
[ __ ] then you want to see which one is
bigger that's then you need
um
God so you can do
not let why is let here
even okay length front and
uh so you get the length and see which
one is smaller if that
um you basically so let's think about
how to do this again so this is our
problem okay so our problem is written
out
here drop the longer list of
items yeah you need to do that so you
want to drop okay so
minimum will return the minimum of items
okay the the
smallest okay so then you just can do
that okay you return the smaller of the
either one of them then
you take
okay then you
take God you cannot modify you know you
know so many issues you know we want to
do functional programming so if we
really want to do that that means we
cannot modify variables you
know if we can do that then it's more
easier so but I don't want to do that so
anyway so so but if you don't want to
then you define more constant for
example you can do this so more constant
you know a nested constant definition so
here is the smaller
count smaller length Okay equals to
that then you do things here okay so you
got a smaller length then then you uh
God you need another
Let's see we got several nested
expression so then you then you uh new
font equal okay new font equals
to okay then basically you do that okay
so let me show
you okay X new font
X new rest okay new font will be equals
to
take oh wait we got the algorithm wrong
but let's finish this part this finish
finish the sub thought sub
thought okay take front and the smaller
length Okay let's put that X there just
to be
consistent kind
of okay and
also this is not efficient but
uh but we are like too much
late so you got now new font and new
rest now you can actually do whatever
you want to compute okay so what we
actually want to compute we want to
compute something
like
um oh forgot where is it same something
like here okay let's let's copy this
code so we don't have to type it again
we want to make sure
that X new front is equals to X new rest
okay we don't even care about that
anymore so we don't need the end so
there there there
okay uh that's kind of it so you see
that's of these brackets nesting nesting
that's like lisp okay the same thing so
anyway so this code over
here we are map we are doing a map maps
takes two arguments the first argument
is this
function and the second argument is just
this same index list
that's not a good name you know it's
it's a list of Ro
pairs same row
pairs okay so anyway so so the function
takes the index right a argument one
argument
then it okay so so so we have to think
about this so you got a bunch of
rows now let's say okay let's imagine
it's the first problem so you
got one two three the first three row
then one two three four the second part
has four rows okay so
you you you need to re reverse the
smaller one okay so algorithm is wrong
we cannot just reverse it first we need
to reverse the smaller
one
right yeah [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ]
it oh wait but uh so yeah don't don't
reverse yet okay don't reverse yet just
take the front take the
rest
then see which one is
smaller okay
then then you want
to you need to know which is smaller
though but right yeah you need to
know which is the
smaller you need to know which one is
smaller not
just not just there the smaller count
the smaller
length
because you need to reverse the smaller
[Music]
one this is real pushing on without
extra [ __ ] okay so you need to know
which one is smaller so this is not good
so ah thank you have to do if statement
you know so the pure most elegant code
is not to do any if statements
uh yeah I feel like you know my w
language I feel like my wam language
hello Dan is you still here stamina
strong to stream such long oh Crystal
hey
okay so you you know the most elegant
code you don't want to use State you
know if like when you use if statement
that's like you know then it's like C
manual you know you just manually coding
things so the the the you know the ideal
situation especially with W language you
know there are several levels so at the
lowest level it's just procedural
programming C you don't have any
choice you know JavaScript and python
you can do a bit higher level okay so
low lowest level if statements you know
manual Loop you don't want to that do
that assign assign variables mutate you
know change State you know higher level
is functional okay now functional you
can say there's also low level and high
so the the the less pure function of
programming is that you you know
sometimes you mutate a variable you have
a variable you know like like emac thisp
like thisp in
general but the more pure functional
programming is that you just have
functions you don't have mutable States
like hascal however you can still use if
you can have tons of if if you want to
if if if if NE if or condition you know
but that's not you know so so that's not
elegant so next level is
like uh you know I don't know how you
say maybe like wam re uh language where
you don't you know when youever you have
if
statement uh you know unless it's
absolutely
necessary you know you you can try to
avoid
it in other words you don't want one
bunch of if statements like 10 five you
know like like that's manual checking
code so instead you want to think about
the algorithm you know what like then
usually there's one function that just
does it so anyway so so how here we
let's let's stop talking again let's
back to code so we so we have these two
this of rows we want to know which one
is smaller
okay uh and uh can you do
that let's let's let's just code okay
let's just see older I forgot what is
you know so older let's say one two
three let's say 1 2 3 4 does
it put this in front does it work does
it first use the length so if you have a
two list does it first use the
use why why is this key doesn't doesn't
work in wam language what is this Q
reformat lines so why is
it oh
okay so let's see run this run this
order negative one oh okay uh you can
tells you the order so you need to use
sort you know usually most of languages
you don't have this function but you
have sort okay let's see what it
does so sort put that first okay now
let's
um what about this God
God there's something we need there
okay it's ugly here ugly ugly okay so
run
that that returns itself run
that that also returns itself okay so
you want order by length Okay so so
let's let's see sort
by
G let's see sld by uh P so yeah so you
can give a prut but you know that's
not you know s by is better okay
yeah okay you sold by so so you you sold
by by just length function okay my hand
is hurting
now right here so length code with two
arguments
oh
[ __ ]
function
wait what why is the length not working
one argument is expected why are you uh
giving it to sort
by sort are elements of L in order
defined by applying F to each one of
them yeah that should work why is that
complaining oh the you of uh
wait oh so the first part is a least
right there do that that should return
return itself right but now if we
reverse the
order it it will reverse it
back
correct so this is what you want sort by
okay uh sort by Del delete so let's
delete delete delete that so we can use
S by to um
deal with
this oh God so soort by
drop yeah but what are you doing
so so this will give you the smaller one
in
front but uh
take Matrix index s by so now I'm like
you know I really want to stop but let's
consider this
is death
march you have to continue or you're
going to
die and continue until you finish it
okay so
so we got a two list we need to uh you
need to compare each one item so you see
better way so jop by so you just minus
another way is if you minus can you you
know so I'm just uh going to try so many
different so many things
okay let's see does it give you uh okay
cannot combine
[ __ ] what is
the rifle so rifle interject you want
the smaller list in
front Okay so let's go back to the idea
of rifle
again you know we tried
rifle what oh okay so
back so we Tred the rifle
here the smaller uh first let's see a b
c d
okay it's EAS easier to see so here is
the result
the second part so the second
part wait so which one you want you want
the smaller first yeah smaller first
okay so you want to uh you want the
smaller than front in front so 1 a 2 B
three but you need you do need add extra
there so I mean there's lot things you
know we just blindly trying because it's
faster in then if you look at the
documentation okay uh let's see negative
one what does it
do okay so something
that third argument should be a positive
integer oh positive integer
okay increment for started and position
of the and the space in between rifle
elements given in one cannot be
satisfied for the input list of length
three I don't know you have to look up
the documentation for rifle
again tab
Edge yeah so we you know we we are
basically we
are thinking of how to solve this uh
this this kind of trivial problem this
this problem this pain
yes two this one is small than the other
you want to just reverse it so minus
truncate uh minus difference
Union Union
intersection no you want keep the order
and uh you just want drop up okay you
just you know so take the difference so
you need to
know which one is
smaller and you also need to
know that number you know that length of
that um is there a better way so is is
there a better way
is it a better way so we have you know
this this still haven't done once we do
this then we still have to go back to
the pattern maging approach because that
will that's kind of beautiful but even
that
anyway even that with P matching our
code is getting long so you need another
one hour to to shrink it to refactor but
anyway
so so we are using uh so right now just
functional approach okay functional
approach now we are kind of stuck on
this
thing uh what
so
so so you need uh uh know which one is
smaller and and the you need the
length and uh you need to to reverse
somewhere okay so reverse somewhere so
you need to like reverse
somewhere yeah
[ __ ] okay so
I cannot believe
this so
by so if you use
rifle rifle is almost
done rifle and something about pair okay
something about
pairing fold
pair no F pair at least no so what is
fold pair F pair is uh last element of
four pair least
okay it's like reduced but somehow
different okay anyway that's not what we
want
uh pair bar CH chart pair why is this
plot okay so we need some kind of
pairing
to a god it's just you know
the do we have like anything truncate
distribution truncate some truncated
polyhedron rifle is the one we want
actually but rifle but but you need to
read the documentation thoroughly to
understand what's going
on
uh surval list x equals to equivalent to
so rifle X is e x e2x e3x okay so that
means so when you give a Leist uh I me
IMX
in I mean IMAX
in the type use intake is of the type
use
intake what
and you have to understand this uh you
the list in which X appears if possible
at position I mean I mean plus
n right every n item so
that
uh no I don't think maybe Ione cannot do
it because it's inserting into
it's inserting between elements
not not
um so partition so partition takes
so
um pad we don't want to pad it's
inefficient it's just
um you need to know the smaller one and
uh you need to
truncate so you need to know the smaller
of the one list of rows so that you can
do
by God yeah you know you can always do
it manually by just get
length
uh let's do it manually something okay
something like
something something okay not do that
okay okay so you can always just do
that so uh and uh let's not
you can do that okay that give you the
length of the two then
um yeah but if you do that then you need
a module so uh let's stop with
functional you know let's
now with is the most better form because
it Define constants so if if you really
really have to use a temporary variable
I prefer to use width because once you
you know with you know withd takes two
arguments the first block is at list of
variables you must have a value for it
okay so they are constants you cannot
change once you assign it then the
second elements to withth is expression
whatever you want to compute so I prefer
that but before our problem you kind of
like you know if you want to use width
then you got to have nested WID because
then you want another variable or if you
want to do something like that you know
um which doesn't allow you to assign
parallel assignment called uh
destructure assignment so then so you
use module instead so there is this
thing module which is like uh like this
Le okay modu is like lpsl here's
variables and here's expression okay but
I don't you know I don't want to use
that
because because in wolam language that
means every variable name will get ter
Rewritten by a new temporary unique name
internally that's because wolam language
the engine you know the way it works is
by patter Magic so unique name is all
critical so but this module you know we
are talking about few micros seconds but
you know but um so anyway so should we
what should we do with um you know with
using width gets a bit
complicated because you can not modify
it so but I you know if you don't if you
do not want to cannot allow modification
of variables then you you got into
nested list then you got into um you
know you got like three or four nested
Leist nested
with you know but if you
allow
variable if you allow variable
um I mean if you allow variable mutation
you just use that but I don't really I
mean I don't really want to because then
what's then what's the point just you
know use C or
python H actually I'm kind of actually
I'm just too extreme you know that it's
not really
because I mean module is really quite
often
used
uh so what you know this simple problem
you know I'm Runing you this is not good
so
um I need another break okay so let's
you know I my back need another
break where is the uh let's see
where is that let's do
this there it is
what what the [ __ ] you need to modify
that yeah
FU oh yeah we we we can you know open
last closed everything is temp saved
so insert date I is all date full
time okay so let's see
20 25
okay yeah need a
break
e
e e
let's get back to work okay need to
finish this
okay let's
see let's remove that and see how
many people are watching five concurrent
viewers okay
so yeah let's [ __ ] [ __ ] with with let's
just use module let's just get
the thing done okay let's just get the
thing
done modify variables
okay [ __ ]
it so with so take drop and uh this s by
that can tell us which one is yeah we
don't need that so so length we can
actually do that
and uh then you just declare variables
there you know just declare the [ __ ]
bunch of variables forget about you
know elegance and and all that and
smaller length we can also get let's put
there for for now and here remove the
width oh God the nested width
uh let's put there whatever that is and
uh
new is equals to so this is the final
test this is what we need final test you
guys can see me everything good okay so
this width width
width read up so now we just the
function and we just have module
okay see this is a module so module takt
two arguments the first argument is a
list of variables like the list let uh
and and the second argument is uh
whatever you want to do so uh so we have
lots of variables
so God so let's meanwhile I'll make them
better better variable names so so you
so you so you kind of let's not do this
okay let's do one thing at a time so
it's
simpler and uh let's use compound
expression and uh let's length equals to
that
okay you forget about fancy things okay
so you got the font this length and this
this length and then you need to so
forget that about that forget about that
then you need to know the which one is
smaller
so it's abuse let's just use if
statement so if x front length
uh the front length is greater
than
uh let's say if it's
smaller smaller or equals to the rest
length Okay rest length then what we do
then uh
then oh God you need to reverse them
[ __ ] if the front is is the is less than
the rest then use the front Okay so you
basically
just so is that is that uh fine you
don't want
that you do want that so
if okay so wait so
what if the front is smaller or equals
to then you reverse the front Okay then
you just um reverse the front Okay
forget about takech
take new front so so you here you need a
new
width you new no new local variables
okay
and okay you declare two local
constants okay so if it is
um you know so if front is less or
equals to rest then you
reverse the front new front and
uh and uh then you take the rest uh uh
by what length by front length
Okay yeah you drop
it you take the first yeah so yeah so
once you have this now it's so
simple now but
um okay so but now what if they are
not then you do a a width
again you do kind of a WID if they are
not then you do this but now
you so in this case the rest is smaller
so so you have to
okay so okay
so reverse something like that okay so
reverse X rest okay then here you take X
front
uh X front not length x front just front
by the rest length
Okay so yeah
new font new rest then something then
what is that something the something is
going to be do we still have that
somewhere no good so basically
um then you just do this okay [ __ ] so
easy just you know whether it's true or
not if it's true that means this Matrix
has a horizontal mirror line okay so uh
new
font X new
front equals to X new rest
yeah same thing here okay same thing
expression here okay that kind of like
that's
it oh God this is too much you know I'm
now not in no I'm just in a like pushing
mod so you're missing a comma there so C
so you know know too bad my CA woan
mod I'm using caoan mod that allows you
to code wam language in emac but one
feature missing is that it doesn't have
formatting of code
so uh so by the way you can get it for
free you know go to this website just
search for w mod it's on GitHub so it
allows you to call language in emac why
because emac you can more efficiently
operate well because sofly Keys you know
but I can you know I will be down the
road make wolam language also use sofly
Keys you can program the keys by the way
you can program The Notebook so the
notebook is just like o mod you can and
you can also program keys so it will
behave like soft like keys but I haven't
done that so right now this missing
feature is that you cannot intend it so
uh wait so for example it's very so once
you have long code it become uh you know
unreadable so for example if you paste
this in wolam language
notebook then it auto you know it
becomes that beautiful thing so actually
copy
that
copy and uh paste it back you know
that's that that's that code so let's
delete that
[ __ ] okay so we need you know so I need
to code this it can be done but I you
know I haven't I don't know how yet um
so
that mod can just press a key and it
form like
that okay so we got the is uh so what
what so we we need to make sure this
actually works so we need to double
check the logic so this part we don't
need if same index Leist um no
horizontal me okay
so this we don't
need
this if this return true means there
means the
Matrix has a
horizontal mirror
line else
no okay that's what this is doing and
uh okay so now it uses map but actually
you you need to as soon as
it as soon as as it's valid you want to
stop so
uh so when um so you want to use scan
instead okay
scan uh and then
here it just
say if this is
true when this is
true return okay so
wait yeah so if so you need to add
if okay if that returns
true you need to say return
okay uh return true okay that's how moam
language is
otherwise otherwise do nothing okay
otherwise other right otherwise just
return
false Okay so
yeah so this gets you know this
formatting is a
bit so we need to copy this
expression wait uh wait you copied it
wrong this nesting problem you know this
like like thisis you got this nesting
problem you got to be careful okay so
there yeah so there so you can so copy
that paste it here you know it format
automatically copy
it paste so this is our new
formatted uh code it's you know
it's so anyway so this delete
so make sure this is right so
uh
front first of all you get the front
yeah let's just run it I got I got
pretty tired now so let's let's just run
the whole thing see if it works return
true or
not and right now this only works on the
first Matrix so only works on this one
so the expected answer is false because
it's not horizontally
symmetric
[ __ ] returns that why is that
[ __ ] I don't know I don't know so this
you
know why is it not returning anything
what is
it why is this not returning anything
what the [ __ ] come on
scan yeah scan is like map map this
function to that you God [ __ ] why why is
that let's say
map okay
so Force that's expected but if you
change the Matrix to two it'll return
true
okay you know two means this one this
one's got a horizontal miror
line okay let's run it yeah force force
my
ass okay I I not
good F [ __ ] you know so this atent of
code you really got to be careful
especially when come becomes 13 day or
something it
gets it's gets you know it gets more
difficult and uh then if you are trying
to avoid procedural coding it's it's
more difficult so I I was already
prepared I kind of think about that
because last
day I didn't complete but then
still now it's like 4
hours it's like 5 hours
uh it's not working we have to debug I
don't know what's going
onu so if that is true then return this
so why is it so is the front less than
less the end or what so in the first
case the font is one two three three
rows the rest is 1 2 3 4 4 so the front
is
indeed less than rest length Okay now
did we get the length right so front and
length equals to that length rest SP
equals to that that seems
right
[Music]
so so variable font L rest L and then
drop Matrix uh
font oh [ __ ] I forgot another thing
module does not take chain
assignment [ __ ] so if you go back to my
tutorial you can
see scan so let's go to the variable
section the variable section Global
variable local
variable so here is how you define local
variables warning when the body is more
than one expression add semicolon
between them okay that's not it uh
warning the latter variables value
expression do not know the previous
values variables value so you
cannot uh wait but we didn't do that we
actually yeah so actually we defi declar
them as variables and we did assignment
here so why is that wrong
so front end
front length rest length if front length
is smaller than the rest then uh then
new reverse
[Music]
front new front equals to reverse front
new rest equals to take rest and uh take
by take is take the
first first
in uh
let's let's not let's just say that
okay let's forget the if
so okay
so new front new
rest you don't need the width okay so
[ __ ]
[ __ ] reduce variables
okay then you don't need the
width so Sim similar here okay so
this needs to go out so take front rest
then new front
Okay new
font new
rest okay DD
that DD that okay so now it's
simpler if front length is smaller then
rest length then reverse front equals
to then you map the whole thing let's
say map not scan
okay uh but uh but it's still
wrong it's still wrong my friend you are
wrong you are just wrong no you no you
false now the second Matrix please let
it be true please did
we what go
down now okay why is it forse what
exactly is the Matrix now second one so
let's see oh God
so Matrix
form okay so this got symmetric it's
symmetric why are you saying it's false
what the [ __ ] with this with
you so you know so let's print let's
just
print you know debug um let's do it here
so
print
God print is a side effect okay phone
L let's see if at least it uh do that
correctly okay let do do that do that
that that that front L three rest L
four that's
right and uh let's print front okay then
then you want to print
front front is
front [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ]
[ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] F [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ]
[ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ] [ __ ]
[ __ ] front is that rest is that uh so
what uh well because this is Matrix one
Matrix one is always not it's not it
doesn't have a horizontal mirror line
okay so let's say two so let's show me
exactly what the [ __ ] is going on run it
so
um so this
thing you know they they put this so
hard to see oh god so let's copy that
copy that there that that that uh Matrix
form okay so that's one part so the rest
is this thing
copy
paste Matrix form okay now
compare what [ __ ] is going on so compare
let's go all the way so we are doing the
second Matrix which is this one let's
see what what is our front and end so
this one the front is got one two three
4 and the rest is got one two three okay
okay so the front is got one two 3 four
four items the rest is one two three so
so the rest is smaller so the rest will
be
reversed and
uh oh wait then the font needs to you
need to drop the Top not drop not not
drop the
last
okay
so uh logic is wrong so here
when the front
is greater than the rest then you need
to not take you need to like drop drop
the difference okay or you need to take
from from the end okay so it take take
can take a negative integer that means
take from the end okay yeah so let's try
that it should return true it
better
uh Force what the [ __ ] so let's do this
again Matrix
form ah Matrix form okay yeah that's
that's what we want we want to apply a
matrix form so it's easier to read okay
so copy that paste do it again so now we
see now let's see make a backup go to
the top now we want to focus on this
part so front is three items that's
correct wait wait wait wait
wait you
dropped what no wait okay now it's all
confused okay
uh uh wait this is before we drop so
actually so we are our print function is
wrong this is the before okay so we
actually want to do
them uh yeah we want to print the new
font and new rest new rest
okay God so now you have to oh
God now you need need you now you need
to have a variable again with
again do that make sense is it
uh do I make sense
okay
yeah so oh God so you need to
um yeah why don't we just write it [ __ ]
it
[ __ ] [ __ ]
[ __ ] okay so this is a new font and uh
uh new rest okay so
God you going to be really careful here
you don't want to [ __ ] around [ __ ]
around okay this is emergency I mean
this is not emergency what's the proper
name this is like pressed coding okay so
like you you got a uh death death
match like the you know you you just
have to
continue and until you until you drop
that see this is the pen so WID actually
so this expression needs to go to inside
there yeah there
so so okay so let's do that so this this
is if statement okay so need turn this
into a width statement
cut okay so we okay okay comma that
so new front a
God uh just copy here so right copy copy
copy copy okay go go go go go go go go
go go go go so copy go go go go go go go
go go go go go go go go go go go go go
go uh not that wait and Define there
that that that that new rest equals
to that that that that that that that
that
that that that that okay now think about
the
logic don't don't [ __ ]
up now think about logic okay so new
font so then you need to print [ __ ] so
new font new rest okay so you need to
print it do you want to print it yeah
okay print it so print it so X front
this is new font so X new
front Okay X new front Okay now this is
X new rest okay copy that rest okay
Matrix fun copy that and uh we do the
same thing here copy that okay okay now
let's think about logic before we try it
so I know something is wrong there you
know kind of tell wait
I don't know actually so
so so
uh so if the front is smaller let's look
at the when the front is larger case
because that's the that's what happens
with the second Matrix so when font is
larger when front is larger than the the
rest okay so you want to take
when front is
larger let's always reverse the front
Okay let's don't do nothing with the uh
wait let's just figure out where's the
bug
you need to drop okay so you yeah so
instead of take from the right side and
say take
two rest then rest rest is smaller
okay uh
wait so if the rest is
larger you want to
drop the
first okay so you you want to let's see
what
exactly always reverse the front so
always reverse the front let's do
that but you want to drop the
first okay so
take yeah so you want to
take take takes take gives the last in
element right so what's wrong here
there's nothing wrong
take that number of elements that's
right then new rest is reverse
rest that should
work okay now I don't know what what the
what logic is you
know it should work as far as I know so
let's kind of compact this you know this
is getting long so let's W language
formatted
please what press this
button what does this button
do yeah this button copy let's see if we
get prettier
somewhat oh they use the map they use
they they change it to the map function
syntax you
see you know they they converted you
know know
before you know we are using map okay so
let's go with
his let's go with his uh I mean the wol
I'm
suggested I don't I don't know so I mean
let's run it let's see run it just run
it let's
see okay new font and new back let's see
so remember we are dealing with the
second Matrix is that right second yes
that's right
there and uh so the second Matrix the
front is 1 2 3 four four
items no you got three items so
what what so we got it wrong even
earlier what the [ __ ]
uh wait there's something H we got the
bugs we got bugs man what what is this
index uh and what is this same index
list did
we that's
incorrect [ __ ]
it same Index this is not three it
should be let's say one two
three three and uh one two three four it
should be a Leist of three and
four oh God
so did
we Fu get same index
is not three man see
[Music]
three oh because this only does one this
only does two Matrix one
God so that's like a programming typo
you know we got we got tired there's no
logical error it's just that we forgot
you know because we when we did this we
were just testing the Matrix one we are
not you know mapping the whole
so that's just for Matrix
one [ __ ] oh
God you know I'm I'm kind of tired I
want to
go what is this n people concur
viewers uh so so far we've been coding
almost 6 hours six
hours but right now in the past hour or
two we are like in
a death march
mod
uh um so we got a you know we got a
obvious SP you know I'm kind I'm tired
well the the issue is that this same
index list
is it it's a list
of yeah so if you want to fix that you
need to change this to Matrix two since
we are doing the Matrix two here you
know all this debugging turns out yeah
because because our input is [ __ ]
wrong because see we are Computing
Matrix this
one can you quickly fix it like just
hack it just say to yeah we can actually
so do it that uh and what is the result
you should say four you see and now if
you go back here do this do this do this
true what the
[ __ ]
[ __ ] so it tells us now code is correct
it says the second Matrix this one has a
horizontal mirror
line okay so what we do now we all we
have to do is just
map so that it applies to all matrices
then
um then actually true or false is not
the answer because you need to know
which line is that you know you need to
know this index number actually we have
it here x index okay wait not that you
know this this number four and three for
each Matrix then you need to like uh sum
them up and and and [ __ ] count and
sum them
up this Advent of code day 13
so and uh another five minutes break
maybe so it's um well I mean overall
still good ex exercise because I
haven't being a painful coding situation
for a while because when you work at at
the day
job that happens you know you you need
to you
know uh just get something done um
because you you know you you you delay
delayed and at the end you have to get
it done so
so right now it's
clear with a simple functional approach
okay it's now what how many lines is
that so far you know this bunch of
[ __ ] well I mean most of it is print
statement I mean have of these PR but
that's but basically this is solution so
what all we have to do now is just fix a
little bit things like
map uh map then we need to do transpose
to do the to do to check the vertical
mirror
lines then find out the number that's
easy but that'll take
another 20 minutes I mean it's easy in
principle but you always end
up uh with a bunch of
[ __ ] so let me think about what to do I
think another
break and uh after 6 hours now I'm
hungry
and my hand here is
hurting and I'm kind of hot is the is
the fan even
on and uh back sitting on this chair for
like five hours it's not
good oh God
actual actual [ __ ] going on
but no result can you tolerate can I
tolerate a [ __ ] live stream video of
six hours and no result oh but I mean
this actually you know should work but
you know all we have to do is just S A
little but no actual answer that no so
we have to finish this okay okay finish
it
then
break okay let me go break let's let's
go to the break page where is the break
page let see open open what wait we
already have the break
page
uh there so you just need to update the
time stamp to another break ISO daytime
full uh remove that crap crap
crap we will return by 610 okay
and uh and the current the current state
of things you can see on my website
actually I need to update it so let's
update it okay so go back to the
code not this one what is this one this
is the talk show go open the code so
which one of these do you want to show
people uh let's
see almost done okay so uh you know
so God this one is returned by wol
FR and uh that one is returned by that's
our code uh I want to use our code
because we're going to change this to M
uh to scan instead of function I mean
instead of map later for more efficiency
because once you found that the Matrix
has a
horizontal mirror line you stop you
don't check next pair of same adjacent
rowes okay so we're going to change this
to scan later so but now here's current
state of code uh basically almost done
okay syntax goad make a backup showing
browser that's today's algorithm
description and the exploration and age
age situ ations Edge situations of the
problem of V code uh then you know
here's our
code yeah
so even with this code it's going to be
300 lines right but it's it can be much
reduced it just a matter okay so break
okay uh this time longer break okay 8:15
so together I've been taking 30 minutes
break already I
think okay but hold on a second let me
upload to my stuff
oh
[ __ ] actually I should do this every day
so it will be you know because the more
you do the more you get familiar with
the live extreme situation you see part
of this of course you also learn I mean
move coding you know like you know uh
you become more
fluent s can you name a function in
Chinese in
what oh in Wolf
language in what in Wolf
Mathematica oh Jo jman Molina yes you
can
okay let me show that okay so let's say
function let's let's say variable okay x
equals to 5 let's say not X okay but X
is some Chinese right no so let's switch
to Windows Chinese
input uh I okay so that character is
love so now switch back to my keyboard
so Shi Shi
enter five okay now you copy that
character copy paste there return five
okay so you can oh oh [ __ ] I forgot to
show
screen oh
[ __ ] so can you see you know I already
typed it so you know here's Chinese
character we can we can try another one
let's try another one okay okay so
switch to Chinese keyboard in Windows
let's say uh Sue okay that
means uh number six that means
tree I wish to see a tree or running
water let's say 3 = to 6 shift enter
okay now contrl L to get last input
delete that now just evaluate that
that's a Chinese character for tree
shift enter there it is okay now let's
be back now I gotta be back at 8
um 820
okay T 10 minutes
break
God so much
what are we doing
here so can you guys see
yeah so show that
um show
that and show that something
okay and uh
okay
something
e
e e
oh my God what a session what a
session I need more break
64 so 6 minutes supposedly finished
three cups of drinks apple
juice now let's change my
chair now this Armic
chair okay we going I leave leave the
chair one
true that's not for good for your
back got I finish this prob [ __ ]
problem Oh
God
okay and do I want to finish it yes must
finish okay let's just
start I'm back early let's just code
okay let's now let's code it so that um
so that we uh actually have the whole
thing I want I mean the whole thing is
going to be one
line uh Matrix this equals to so that's
the Matrix yeah matrices that's a bunch
of Matrix okay Matrix list
yeah in my back voice check video check
audio
check
so Matrix this is a bun is a list of
these
blocks okay and
then Matrix list and
what okay so one of them looks like that
that's the first one
then the same Index this needs to be
okay so this need to be a map
again this yeah I'm going to show you
because right now we are only doing to
this Matrix okay so so copy this code
I'm going to modify it here so you can
see a copy what it looks like map a
function okay function and this one
variable y y okay y y something and uh
uh and you want to map
to so wait so this this is
the this is
uh yeah okay so
this this part needs to be y y okay and
the whole
thing is cut that's this y y will
be okay that's a body of the function
and what you want to map it
to you want to map to the Matrix list
that's right you don't need
that okay so that so now this will give
you this will give you basically three
and four three is a row
that the the starting row number of the
adjacent same row okay for the first
Matrix and four is the starting row
number of the adjacent same Row 1 two 3
four for the second Matrix
so so this uh
here so this will return that okay and
we don't need the we don't need um
wait
actually it actually it returns
uh it returns this okay because now you
are mapping
so potentially more than one item
okay uh you know we can
try yeah but this commment now is
incorrect except if we
doit
wait oh God
[ __ ] and so okay so anyway so we can try
it and so you can see how it works
out you know run it so you see uh what
where's the result okay so you need to
show the result X okay turn off Chinese
back to
English x
s index list okay you see as I as I
expected uh okay so that uh so God we
need to get this to work okay let's see
Not That Let's ignore that okay let's
not do that uh and actually the proper
way is to
say uh okay so
then okay then you got the list you know
each of this element is a list of the
row you know same row index and and the
next element is for the next Matrix okay
because we have quite a few so
so the possible results um you know is
like
that okay so let's ignore the comments
let's let's do this quickly and now you
need to turn this function into map so
you need another map okay so let's
remove the debug shall we yeah
[ __ ] so copy let's just for backup
purposes let's put it here in case we
want the code back now go back here
let's remove the
print uh okay so you know in emac we can
list or uh list or
print yeah God I hate that you list or
print function so delete or delete or
print you know that print lines
okay just [ __ ] delete them so now
it's much simpler so uh and you are
using map you need to turn that into
scan and then [ __ ] then you need to
check the vertical line you need to do
transpose so there's a lot to do uh [ __ ]
so same index list so you cannot you
know you cannot just do that God this is
so much
pain I'm suffering so you know in this
this jumbo code now it's becoming a
jumbo code not not really but I mean
actually this is normal is W language
code
H but now you need to uh map to that so
this
function so this used to be just
[Music]
one so you need to map again so you need
to map okay so it's just write down okay
map function let's say uh mm okay that's
a variable I mean the argument and here
what is what you want to map to you want
to map to the XM index list okay then
the fun the mm will
[Music]
be the mm will be this thing okay this
will be mm here so give a unique
variable you can see so this is the
body okay cut so put that there can you
see you know that that's how fancy we
become still pretty simple
okay and the inner function is not map
it just should be scan yeah but [ __ ] it
okay so this will return what will this
return I can tell you it
[Music]
return you return return foral true in
an nested list meaning that the first
Matrix is do not have horizontal mirror
lines the second does okay so we can try
it yes we can yeah copy that go back
back to language paste it do it there
exactly okay now you just oh yeah you
[ __ ] you need a the column number
Jesus you need the column number for the
problem because it wants the column
number
so so okay so instead of returning true
false okay
H return the column number
okay that's easy okay so okay so wait so
hold on a second let's just you know Be
steady so this map you want to return
the column number okay
so can you return zero yeah you can
return zero if you
want but the point is as soon as you
find now is it possible ah [ __ ] another
possibility is it possible ible given
the Matrix such that there are two
mirror lines
yes [ __ ] the Advent of code so there's
another special
case where we document the special case
here ah crazy situations okay let
document ADV of a
code uh where is it not here
here crazy situ situations okay what if
there are more than
one mirror more than one
horizontal mirror
lines or
or more than one
vertical that will that's you know
that's a valid situation it's possible
to have more than one
mirror uh wait is it possible actually
so
right
so yeah it is possible for example let's
show example show show them show them
example okay [ __ ] the big times okay so
is it possible for the mirror lines to
be
uh to be try you know to to be
um yeah
so in this
example in this example here is a mirror
line
okay here's a mirror line [ __ ] Advent
code here's a mirror line okay so it's
it's possible to have multiple mirror
lines Jesus
but the problem description does it say
does it say what to do in that
situation I mean it's not about where
does it say that mean does it affect the
final answer did he word it so that so
that when you have this situation is
unambiguous did he that's the question
so when you have this situation or maybe
this situation never happen if this
situation never happens but then you
think extra you are wasting time because
they don't
care uh those who didn't think of this
situation they
benefit in other words those people who
are inferior in coding skills they won
they
win you see so if if if the user example
does not contain this situation then
it's it's just bad problem it's a bad
puz
if the so but anyway did did he say
exactly what happens when you have this
situation okay so make sure we we are
correct so there's one mirror line
here there is one mirror line here yeah
is that right yes obviously correct I
mean it's true there is one mirror line
here because you
know so did he say that you have to
start from beginning or something let's
check let's just
I'm I'm too tired now this pattern
reflects across the horizontal lines
between row four and five what yeah okay
it's a simple you know unique unique
example uh so to summarize your pattern
notes add up the number of
columns uh number of columns to the left
of each vertical line of reflection to
that okay so it's it actually start with
vertical lines then for the horizontal
you have to add you know you have to
multiply by 100 then add them okay so so
for for us we have to multiply by 100 so
for
example for example in this you know
anyway so in
this some some cases okay let's say
three two let's make this more clear so
that's one example okay now another
example
is that uh let's
say well in this example you also have
two mirror lines so actually I think you
want to
maximize so when this I
mean and I don't know if he says that in
a spec specification but ideally
in when when there are multiple mirror
lines you want to find one the closest
to the center therefore you get the
maximal like n line numbers I think
suppose I suppose that's a
situation but you know did it did he say
that a [ __ ]
annoying any input hello George George
I've been coding for six hours so I'm
kind of too tired
ch ch hey thank you thanks for soft like
keys I'm getting used to it and so far I
love it thank
you Dam fat
try uh George says you are overthinking
it you just need to make it
work yeah that's true no but I mean not
not exactly you know you know you just
need to make it work for the input and
output you provide yeah that is a
problem but
however does does the user input the
example input doesn't contain situation
like that right
but does the user input contain
situation that like that you don't know
you know each person have a different
input so the the the situation is that
if I'm 100% anal analytical I thought of
this problem this is a problem because
when you have this situation it's
ambiguity your problem is not well
specified you have two different several
diff possible answers that's
right so if this pattern does not occur
in the input first of all it doesn't say
what you have to do when this situation
occur
so if it does not occur in his
input in or in everyone's input that
means it's a lousy problem because the
problem punishes those who correctly
analyze the problem which you will
encounter in real
life you know the problem is under under
specified
ambiguity you know I got the answer you
got the answer our answer are different
but both are correct according to the
specification underspecified
okay so if the
problem you know you know the all the
user input if doesn't contain situation
like this you know like these cases I
listed then it's a lousy
pu but if it does contain the situ the
situation I
listed it's also allows a problem
because then it doesn't say what you
should do in that situation do does it
mean multiple anwers are accept accept
acceptable so that's right that's my
answer I mean that's you know I'm
correct uh so
anyway you know ranting so basically we
got
this I I I'm going to stop okay I'm too
bad we we we you know we just need a
little more work so yeah but I'm going
to stop so I'm kind of really
tired um so here's a wolam code you know
it looks like that it you know it kinds
of tell
you yeah and also you need to get the
column number not just you know column
number is here this is this uh yeah it's
it's this index well except when you
have like multiple mirror lines then you
don't know which one it is so
so because it's relevant because right
now for efficiency reasons I need to
know as soon as I find a mirror line
should I stop or not right because if
this if the problem specifies by
specification there's only single mirror
line then the
efficient solution is not to use map if
you use map it's inefficient because you
know maybe the first line the you know
the first two row is miror the rest you
can ignore as soon as you find that you
is ignore but if if then but if you have
the case of multiple lines that
also refresh you
know then you do need to
continue but the problem doesn't say
which one is you know what the [ __ ] [ __ ]
the problem [ __ ] theant of code okay
that's okay I think I'm going to stop
okay so here's a wam
code uh you know so so much uh 6 hours
coding
basically and okay so that's one part uh
but also we started to do uh pattern
matching solution which is so elegant
here so you know it just for example use
patter matching to find if a matrix has
horizontal mirror line so this will do
it uh you know we showed the code before
this will do it uh okay yeah because
because I changed some
variable uh yeah so the Matrix is is at
the still
thing anyway so it was
running so the other situation is that
just completely use meod patter matric
no function no no checking out which
length is which row you know at all you
just Pam mat it solves the problem so
but but we haven't completed that we all
know so anyway that's it for today thank
you guys for watching okay bye
guys oh my God that's 6 hours
coding what 6 hours and 30
minutes okay clean up you know let's put
this
back color it showing browser so that's
what we have
today uh too bad you know
so yeah so next time I got to be more
more
like knowing the situation so this
cut okay so let's go back to talk show
let's put this in the talk show
page these are some of the like
demonstration of wolam language code
simple code and uh uh coding issues with
you know
some okay color it showing browser so
it's
here for
now you know some of the function wam
language function
explanation okay that's it for today and
this this one is a
break it's also put it's also
put uh the break announcement inter
intermission you
know in the old days it's called
intermission
so text paste there okay what else okay
let's we don't care about that message
sper and delete that this AR message
okay that's it bye guys