good morning guys welcome to another
episode of Santos show today is 2019
October 12th 10 o'clock in the morning
Saturday San Francisco time so good
morning guys
so I have actually lots of topics
prepared ok and guys go to discord ok
like go to use use this code like I'm
gonna show you so shut up show this is
today's topics and you go to saw talk
show on solid info and you see here is
the hobby club on this code ok join it
and and where is bathroom you but pot
possum is not here today I got actually
I got something to say about I need to
talk to bottom you bother me we need we
need to talk ok so let's see what's up
so League of news is 7 o clock similar
clock in Italy it's 7 a.m. but losing my
eyesight and I thought it was nice what
so let's see 10 o clock here so night I
am in California time would be something
like 6 o clock in UK similar 7 o clock
in UK so you are in Italy ok so more
crack like morning nibel good morning
George
George's from Australia Perth which is
which is like 16 hours ahead so it's 3 o
clock in the morning something like that
he's alright
oh did part say that I didn't see
I didn't hear when did did bar say
that in yesterday's chat you know every
time I did finish the video its it takes
a lot of time actually usually I go
through the chat but but you know is it
there's a lot to read sometimes I miss
the information so George come on in DP
good morning Matt George good day so
nigh p.m. League of noobs nigh p.m. okay
night p.m. would be somewhere in Germany
Oh to the east of Germany right Nick
League of noobs okay it's similar clock
so anyway okay so let's begin so if you
guys have topical questions posted okay
actually I do have a lot question topics
first of all let me show you this toilet
we were talking on this code
yeah I actually let's go to discord okay
we're talking about AC and toilets
it's sniping or crock oh my god those
24-hour metric system I like it but
usually I have to think about what time
is it
so 19 minus 12 19 minus 12 is 7 okay so
no we were talking about what is this
video someone are discussing mommy Tama
I don't know what that is that but
basically so there it is there is max
raters desktop system open link open
imagery new tab let's see and it's too
small so you got a cricket then open
image in new tab so this is max raters
setup he's what they called it you know
the gamer the gig
raiga okay this is max Raiders week he's
in like somewhere in the east side of
USA so you got this giant 40 inch TV
screen and with a test keyboard tray so
he's using a Apple's touchpad and he
likes it but we were talking about the
AC on the toilet in Japan it looks like
this okay I think they are facing it out
ways is picture so small geez okay let's
just let's just view view view image
here okay it's not too big picture so
toilet in Asia mostly like this but I
think they are facing facing it out so
you don't see it much but I think it's
still common in school you know it's
basically just a hole on the ground so
okay so that is that I have some topics
to talk about
wait don't close these okay so Nick Hope
League of noobs okay so let's talk about
something so actually bottom you is here
he's not here today I guess so well I
wanted to thank him for showing me the
steelseries keyboard so we talked about
this keyboard yesterday this is actually
a good one and I watched the video it
turns out Hyosung 22 has a video of it
so it's using its the key switches on
this keyboard is actually the best
basically pretty much you know the best
key switch in the world in the history
of keyboard basically and this keyboard
cost $200 I still wouldn't recommend it
at all I mean first of all for me it's
not for me because I have to have
economic split you know this is not
it's not good you know when you type
several hours a day all these are not
good doesn't matter how good is a switch
so it's not for me first of all but for
for you guys I don't think I don't
recommend it neither because for $200
you get well the switch is nice but you
know there are many people in a keyboard
community they are fanatics they are
fanatical about keyboard switches such
as such as choir song he is one of them
he is also a key keyboard switch expert
the you know pretty much the top expert
in a world you know one one of them so
anyway so many keyboard fanatics they
are in two key switches like Oh cherry
IMAX and then video and but but that's
not too important to me once you have a
mechanical switch let's say cherry brown
the most average mechanical switch
Cherry MX brown that's kind of good
enough you know you can get you going
the other important things is about
other designs in particular the you know
split auto linear layout and split
intended that's actually important once
you have mechanical switches because I
mean what so you know how do you church
why do you say it's important you know
you might say oh yeah but I I'm fine
with Oh gonna I'm fine with a flat PC
keyboard you the thing is you know yeah
that's fine you know you if you like
this flat key PC keyboard that's perfect
perfectly fine but when we are talking
about you know judgment which one is
actually you know better like you know
competition then the criterias must be
strong you know basically basically if
you are forced like if you are imagine
if you are in the prison you know you
are you into you are forced into labor
you have to do you have to type
continuously for let's say four hours a
day then then you will know this is no
good you know any flat you know you you
for example
example you can compare you either use
these let's say economic keyword and
let's say let's say this one microsoft
economic keyboard scoped it's not
mechanical keys okay it's not mechanical
keys however it does have these
ergonomic shapes now suppose this one
compared to this one now this is the
best mechanical keys ever but however
it's flat now you are a prisoner in
prison you are forced into labor you you
have to type continuously non-stop you
know like a data entry clerk you know
you you copy text for example you have
to do this for for our four hours a day
then you know you're gonna be in prison
for three years let's say with this one
chances are you you start to have hand
pain you know after few months you know
this one is probably better you know so
that that is my point about how do you
exactly judge which is the best I mean
the concept of the best keyboard is kind
of seedy it's like what would you know
what is the best programming language
you know but if you really want to say
you know you have to pick you know which
one is really truly the best keyboard
then one of the major criteria because
we are talking about keyboard what what
is key were useful it's for typing so
one of the major party RIA is you know
you type several hours a day then the
shape is probably I would say it's
probably you know this one is more
important than then then then the you
know mechanical keys so I'm not too much
into mechanical keys as long as it's
mechanical key switch that's good you
know but of course I also given two
different mechanical switches I do have
my preferences I would love these of
course this this is a horse which you
know a very good key switch so let's see
let's see we do some of the calm
in classic way if your employee won't
allow you to allow you your own keyboard
DP says what if your employer won't
allow you to use your own keyboard the
work
what kind of employer is that you don't
work for such company then I know of no
company that does not allow you to use
your own keyboard I've heard companies
that do not allow you to use your own
computer like you have to use the
company's computer especially in
security corporations but not allowing
you to use your own keyboard that's kind
of seedy so Matt says it's also kind
kind of funny for a girl reasons
keyboard actually should be tended from
top to bottom from top to bottom but the
mainstream is just the other way run run
yeah I see what you're saying no I think
you know what he is saying is that like
it like if like if I'm sitting on a
keyboard you know if you look at me this
way
you know keyboard like okay so the
normal keyboard they have legs in a back
so you you would be like that that's
that's basically nope okay let me try to
if I can do this well yeah okay so like
normally you have to show the flat you
know suppose you're out on a table
normally the keyboard have lakes on the
back so you would do like that that's
not good okay you rather want the
keyboard lakes in the front so you
actually do like that that's better
so in fact that is that is one of the
Microsoft's design Oh OBS updates Kip
remind me later
so actually Microsoft keyboard let's
seek Microsoft keyboard they
they actually designed so that it's
sloped in the back let me show you okay
I think I have a picture here yeah there
you see like that so you you you because
that way you it's better okay it's it's
very because you know you don't want to
paint up your wrists and with this
keyboard it's your wrist is actually
flat then your fingers tip on the keys
you know your wrist is that straight
line you want to keep this straight line
but I know you know like I said before
most people when they come through
keyboard and stuff they are just go by
habit so when they see this they find it
weird oh this is weird I can't get used
to that's okay because first of all they
don't touch they don't touch they don't
type much okay for you average
programmers that's okay you can like
anything you want because you don't
really touch type that much but like I
mentioned if you are in a prison you are
forced to type several hours a day then
you will know right away this is better
that's the thing most people they don't
think about it because they don't they
don't type much you know they got other
things to do but because every
programmer they use the keyboard so
they're gonna tell you you're their
opinion so I don't like this one Oh
speed is not good
Oh ergonomic is useless you know they
could not tell you they their habit you
know like oh I'm a programmer type all
day therefore it should be this or that
you know that's all garbage slow him
forward for some reason you know these
words are kind of confusing like what do
you mean sloping forward like slope can
be up or down so so usually when we talk
yeah so when we talk about keyboards you
know and also lots of things in
programming like what does at least me
what does array mean the term means many
things depending on your language and
your experience
so when you say slope for you know so so
when you talk about some of keyboards or
you know for
you have to kind of rephrase it so it's
actually a very precise can prisoners
choose their own keyboard yeah that the
the you know that that is the how they
say it's not an analogy it's a
metaphorical metaphor it's not even a
metaphor it's just an example anyway so
let's see so okay guys go there I have
this JavaScript so we talk about
keyboard okay so hold on a second
steel series so thanks thanks to both of
you who got me looked into that that
steel series that you know that keyboard
that is actually great and find
JavaScript window size okay so guys go
here and and type your type what is says
about your monitor size like if I can go
there right now yeah Google Chrome show
link in chrome okay so you see it says
your viewport size is 12 77 by 8 8 3 my
viewport size then you have the window
size you know as you as I adjust the
window size you see the number will
change you see that's my window size and
viewport size you see browser
Dom JavaScript and JavaScript is very
complex so you have viewport size you
have window size now window size is
basically what you are thinking you know
the whole window but viewport size is
the area with not counting a score bar
and not so basically starting from here
not counting the URL bar the you know
the bookmarks bar and sometimes you have
a status bar at about it so that is the
you know you viewport does not count
those so you have viewport size good
morning in green deck and you have
windows size
then you have screen size okay so my
screen is 1920 by 1080 so go there and
post your numbers let me see
and actually when you change when you
magnify these numbers usually also
change because you know JavaScript Dom
started to define them precisely why so
anyway so DP says he saw his viewport
size not viewport size I mean she showed
not the viewport show your screen size
because the screen size basically should
be supposed to your full screen oh okay
so you have 1920 by 1 1 1200 by 1200
okay so so your screen is like longer
than mine okay yeah so that so that is
that I just want to show that that's
just so that's JavaScript of course so
so you can look at you know you can in
browser you can view source code then
you can see this here is the source code
for for doing that and also it works on
a coming on your phone to your it works
on your phone and if you reorient your
phone it will change you know your
changing real time or if you adjust you
change your window you know you know
Jade you you're also changing real time
so that's JavaScript so close that cross
that in and let's show let's back to
some talk show let's see the next topic
so there is another thing bottom you
mention about how Microsoft is
repairable you know that so I didn't
understand what he's talking about
but I do now you because I read about
the comments
let's talk about it next time when ba
from you is here oh god why is Google
sensing or that another moderator just
handle this who what who is a moderator
now is C ad moderator but I don't know
what's going on I don't think I have any
moderators your screen size okay so I
guess most of us have the standard 1920
by 2 by 1 0 a0 okay so that's about that
so let's talk about the next things I'm
thinking I'm talking about some goal and
yeah I'm gonna do that
but first of all let's go true so there
are some new Mouse I want to tell you
guys so this one so let me tell you
about some of these new Mouse that just
came out a month a few months ago so one
of them is so Logitech came up with MX
master 3 what do I think of Python it's
ok but I don't like it personally but I
think it's ok you know I I did a video
that's one hour I talked about that
Python a few times but if you go to my
youtube channel League of noobs you go
to you know YouTube sorry
there is one hour talk where I frame
Python you know the guide ovals or some
guy I don't like Python the language
language almost in every way because it
doesn't you know it's not it doesn't
really support functional programming
because you know Kaito van Rossum
doesn't like it so anyway so there's one
hour I think you know check that out so
anyway this Logitech came up with ma MX
master 3 Mouse I think this is a great
one I never had it so the version before
is this one
so this is their previous version you
know what's special about this one
because it's got two wheels you got the
mask wheel now that's a spin wheel okay
let me show you so if you see here is my
setup you turn around and you see me
from different angles you see a side
view and my and and you see my room it's
a mess okay I'm gonna show you you see
that's my room that's and that's my bed
you know it's it's a mess so you turn
around that's a window and you turn
around so that's my desktop then let's
zoom in on the mouse
it's got infinite squirrel okay so let's
go here let's go to some page on a
second okay so let's go here sake ball
guides our blog so now hold on a second
so let me move that here so if you see
my mouse it's got this wheel I can just
heal kill to spin it's a spin wheel you
see and this is fantastic and if I if I
swing hard you just go all the way it
can keep spinning for like 20 seconds so
that's a spin wheel and is fantastic I
want I must have that because I'm so
it's really it's really great so that
Mouse let me show you that Mouse so you
go to the the mouse section that Mouse
is this Logitech 5:02 okay and I have a
video showing showing the mouse wheel
spinning
I have a I have a I do have a full
screen set up let's see shofu head okay
so now you can hear me but you cannot
see me let me fix it let me fix it on a
second let me take you know this this
this the reason it's not working now is
because there is this problem with OBS
software because sometimes after a few
restarts
he lost the my setup so you have to add
it again so let me do it now okay let's
see you try that okay that's right
so now you can see me except for the
rasp highway Mathematica is to be
bundled what Mathematica good yes quick
pretty good you'll be good if I don't
bad Jason de Nate what is that what is
that DP so anyway so let's go back to
sauce screen so then that becomes that
anyway so I so this mouse at so you see
I have showed the spin wheel but on this
on this model on this model
it's either always spin or you press
this button then it's creaky so you can
switch between quickie and spin but you
have to press this button to switch it's
a physical physical button but however
on the mx3 you no longer have that
button because so what they did what
what they did is like if you just push
it hard then your spin if you if you
push it slowly means creaky so so this
is a fantastic I think it's a fantastic
but I don't have these smells okay so
besides that they also have this wheel
for the Thunder why is it useful because
for example now I can press the keys on
my mouse to switch around let me show
you so if you look at you see if I I can
press either these two keys for example
I can press press that you it's you know
is switch around the tabs I can hold it
down and it's gonna fly through many of
them are loading anyway so you see what
it you see what it's like okay so so
yeah that so so but as I mentioned I
talked in my video of my other video
before that when you have a command
that's forward and backward
for example arrow up and down arrow key
right and left to move kusa up down to
move screen oh for example or page up
and page down Oh previous hat next tab
or previous window next window or
previous workspace next workspace when
you have like 10 10 10 10 pairs of such
commands when you have those commands
the best the best way to control them is
by is by up wheel some kind of wheel
okay so that is why I think this thumb
ko is is fantastic
of course you can program it to be some
other things such as volume up/down is
another example sound level up and down
now there is another interesting
linguistic issue you know the IOA I
never liked the the word volume of you
know volume down you know when you turn
the sound you know it rather the better
more logical and easier to understand
term is sound level sound level you know
some level ovens
but however valium the word volume is so
you know it's part of English idiom you
eats you cannot change it so anyway so
this mouth I find it very interesting
because you know it's called automatic
spin wheel and it's got a second wheel
and then then this version new versions
better than the old because the old one
of the complaint in this older version
is that you have two buttons here that's
tiny hard to press okay so the new
version they fix that by having it
separate and also you have a thump
button here you cannot see it's
invisible it's like you know it's
invisible thumb button soap so I think
this is great so you buy it okay you
know buy it for my website okay let me
in post a link if you are you know if
you shop from Amazon on in USA just buy
it so I get you know I get 50 cents or
something okay so there is that Mouse
then there is another one this one now
this one Coolermaster mm7 1-0 Mouse this
is the lightest Mouse today the you know
III for my own preferences I always want
the lightest Mouse the lighter the
better you know you have you have some
gaming mouse you know it's very common
today in gaming mouse you have you have
like Mouse with weights like city you
know you like you have you you can add
weight to it and usually and also for
wireless mouse you have batteries so
these are typically heavy you know have
much heavier and some people like them
because there are different methods of
holding a mouse so again this is my set
up you see these towers these towers are
like my wrist pads so I just let's see
so this you see this how functions my
wrist pad it's great because it's
like $1 you know $2 each and you can
throw throw in the washer to wash them
and you can take them out and fold them
any way any hate you want and but if you
buy the dedicated mousepad usually they
are too too low okay they are too low
you know they is supposed to be made of
this fancy plastic you know space-age
you know form or whatever those and they
cost $10 or $15 that's no good so anyway
the mouse okay so so you click that
no it's creaky okay so hold on so now
you see it doesn't spin it's quickly
quickly sometimes good if you want to
right now my click come out is very slow
actually let's go to Emacs ok creaky
yeah one one line each time oh you can
have a spin hey it's it's too slow too
it's too fast for Emacs to handle anyway
so what I wanted to show oh yeah I was
talking about so so deep I don't hold
you know there are many different ways
of holding a mouse its hold on a second
let me show me okay there are many ways
to hold a mouse my way is like a claw
it's like almost I don't even touch the
mouse usually I don't touch the mouse I
just I just nudged I also also I have a
auto click sometimes called Hoover click
or sometimes called trail ok I have set
it up on my Mac I have articles here you
can read it you know if you go to let's
see key binding not key binding go to
software you have e you have particles
there so anyway I'm talking about the
waste - you hold the mouse so for me
it's kind of extreme I don't even hold
it sometimes you call it crawl but fall
on the other hand some people hold it
like that you know they did
they move us and quick they move us and
quick you know when I see that it
sequence it's like too painful to me
it's painful to watch
that's how you get repetitive strain
injury okay second let me get back to ya
injury with palm palm method of holding
the mouse I don't like that so yeah so
we were talking about you know mouse
with wait I think you know that's not
for me either to me that's stupid so go
back to keyboard go back to Mouse so
mouse with wait so what I like is the I
want my mouse to be as light as possible
of course provided it doesn't fly off
the desk if there's a strong wind so so
anyway this one is the lightest now and
I have a mouse weight comparison so this
one is only 53 grams and so on okay we
got a trough what's it what's your issue
I like the hexagonal horse okay so so
about mouse so what's what's your
problem
ship she quipped Kemah type something
more so I know who you are like you know
what you are into okay so Mouse so
that's I think that's it about the mouse
let's see what else yeah so the other
thing I want to mention is that we have
these actually let's see how long we've
been talking I wanted I'm thinking we
can do some goal and today yeah I I'm
gonna go to some goal and and we can do
some demo only 35 minutes okay so we
gonna do some go learning demo
okay so Mouse now let's put this window
back okay so so there is this so there
is this keyboard keys assembly okay so
this guy put on Kickstarter saying that
he is going to create this and this
happened in 2012 or 2013 so it's like mm
you know his it's five years ago six
years ago so he got $239,000 but as of
today it's not delivered yet so some
people are complaining you know he's
swindle scat you know they are a lot you
know it seems it happened a lot of them
happened like that on Kickstarter where
you announce a product but you never
delivered this is how their website
looks like according to them they are
still you know working on it like you
know every time they read they run into
a problem
then redesign or something you know so
right now they on their website you have
pictures like these it seems it seems
very fancy very different from their you
know seven years six years ago but you
know they got two hundred thirty nine
thousand but they didn't they have not
delivered yet after six years so I think
they are questionable oh there's a
YouTube about show called Kickstarter
crap okay I gotta check that out because
I never actually look into Kickstarter I
mean they make money when when when
people for example this product now
Kickstarter how many percent they take
how many percentage they take so I never
really looked into Kickstarter you know
they are you know what
and what's their policy when a product
does not deliver okay so I'm gonna check
out his YouTube channel so okay that's
about that
okay I'm gonna look read it offline so
there but there's another similar they
actually they are quite a few similar so
someone else this guy from a SIA
somewhere in Asia I forgot where they he
created this so it's kind of similar to
the king kings assembly so this one but
however he didn't get enough fund on
Kickstarter so he never went anywhere so
you're going check his website
mooom dream moving rim
you know keyboard okay so anyway so it's
kind of dead and also there is another
one I mean let's go back to oka keyboard
let's go to it yourself
there is another another one this one
key Mouse now this is a real product
actually last time who was it you max
rated or someone else actually I forgot
who was it you met someone actually has
this and said it's really good so this
is actually a product you can buy right
now
chemos you know it's a mouse and
keyboard combined so actually the
keyboard function was the mouse but they
also have a scroll wheel on the on a
keyboard so you can see bottom I think
you can I think they yeah I think that
yeah I think it functions the mouse but
but also you have a school trackball on
a keyboard so anyway this is the one you
can buy but to me I don't think that's
these are for me and I think these are
too clunky for me I don't
think it I don't think I like them so
it's you know so it's expensive I don't
know how much like $300 or more Oh five
hundred dollars five five hundred
dollars yeah those are not for me so
that's about that I so that's about that
and let's do some goal and then so yeah
I'm going to do some demo of goal and
and and that's that that would be here
today I think so
Kickstarter crap okay I'm gonna check
this out
I see tabo's to be useful okay so I'm
gonna do some go line and I'll be it
today let me read the comments
Troy is gonna so there is even a youtube
show ok for most Hardware I still prefer
trying it out install yeah of course be
right back okay so let's do some Golan
so next we're gonna do Golan so go and
read the tutorial and I'm gonna demo so
I wrote this scholars script I'm gonna
show you go so I wrote this script this
is basically just great okay so for
example I want to find I want to I want
to find all strings let's say Haskell
okay I want to find all files in this
directory actually
in this directory okay sorry
info keyboard in my keyboard directory
this one I want to find all files that
contains the word Haskell or HTML files
files ending in HTML okay so now I run
it there it is here's the output that's
done showing okay now I call saw find
output mods so it's colored ok magnify
then I can jump to occurrences in and
and press ENTER to show the file so it's
right here there it is the word haskell
and showing browser actually so this
actually is a comment it out okay so
what so mouse versus keyboard so in this
article I was talking about Mouse versus
keyboard is Mouse bad for programmers I
wrote this article because it's a
frequently asked question I mean it's a
frequent frequent conception among
hacker types they will always say oh
don't use the mouse don't use the mouse
always use the keyboard I think that's
idiotic
okay so that's why I wrote this article
in fact I talked about this in my videos
just search for sorry Mouse you'll find
it in the past you know for example you
have the Emacs or vim users they keep
telling you don't use the mouse they
they're going to tell you on Linux to
use some kind of tiling window manager
okay they are crazy about that and in
the browser they tell you about vim
pareto activator you know that's the hey
I don't I I think those I think those
opinions are not not not really good I
talked about these in past videos so
look for it they are not good because
because those people they don't actually
type much okay when you type much like I
said before
Prison if you are suppose if you are
forced to type let's say let's just say
three hours a day continuously then you
don't want you don't want to touch the
keyboard okay you want to you you want
to use the mouse sometimes you don't
want to force your hands on keyboard all
day you know even just even if you don't
do not know typing at all just put your
hands flat on the on the desk like that
just just leave it there for three hours
three hours a day you got problems you
start to you have pain
I know because because that's from the
experience from actual experience so
anyway so you see so this goal and
script you know works it finds all files
that contains the word but now let's say
I want another word I for example I want
to find all files that contain either
the word Haskell or or the word list
okay but I cannot use this program to do
it because it's not written for you it
only does one string so I modified that
yesterday so I have I have this script
now this script can find 10 or 20 or
more strings you know at the same time
so you can give it 20 or 100 you can
give it 100 different strings you want
to find any file that contains that
those words so this script will do it
why do I need to use these because for
example let me show you first of all why
do I need this okay so you go to my
keyboard blog so that's my keyboard blog
you see all these little little icons so
you need to create image files you know
with these icons you see so if you go to
the directory if you go to the directory
let me let me do this okay split magnify
actually don't magnify go to issue then
kids check out TN I I deleted the
directory well let's do it
KITT check out he and okay does not
match any file known to get ok I removed
wait it should ok so I removed it in get
what's the command to get it back
does anyone know on a spot anyway so I
was just going to do a check out but
anyway let me show you another example
so you go to my odd directory I mean my
art saw saw arts dog ok then you see
this leader in Swan you see all these
images you know these are icons let's go
there let's see here ok so you see all
these images classic paintings
those are icons now you go through this
so we go through the file close that
because that open the file go to the
directory and you see this key and
directory you see and I open it show you
browse I mean showing desktop ok so now
you see all these are tiny icon files
you see that's open ok so yeah these are
very small tiny icon files let's see
yeah you see those are hearts you know
this is a famous painting which they
have historical significance right but
anyway these are tiny icons so on a
second let me get rid of that curse ok
so all these are tiny icons so
see yeah so you can view in Emacs let's
go to VI since a sculpture let's not
sure that Batman okay so this is a movie
screen shot from a Batman movie so I got
these icons but okay so oh my god this
is getting complicated so if there was a
more modern version of Acme editor I
probably would use it so green deck says
don't use Mouse probably originated from
people learned computers when there were
no mouse hmm I don't think that's I
don't think made you know that maybe
that's part of the reason but more I
think mostly the the the is the the
fashion oh you know the the fashion of
telling people to not to use a mouse I
think basically it's a code formation
from the hacker types from Emacs use a
theme user you know the UNIX people use
it I think that's mostly they created
this thing not because not because back
then back then in in 1994 for example
you don't have mouse on Windows you
don't have Mouse basically before 1990s
you do have but not not popular
space versus fat people anyway so I do
have these icons okay so they are small
and also for example let me show you
also their path structure is such that
for example let me show you this okay so
on a second
I think know their path structure is
what is this
okay so let's show that one so copy that
the their path structure is
okay I said
anyway my point is that all these tiny
thumbnails are or in this one directory
TN so all this directory are thumbnails
every awesome nails are pressing here
but you know I started to do this like
10 years ago 15 years ago but eventually
I decided that the thumbnail should be
in the same directory where the large
size image are for example let's suppose
your keyboard let's go to SteelSeries
for example search for jpg so this image
for example steelseries keyboard if you
go to the directory you know here is a
directory that's this is a file you know
this is a file and here's the directory
and this directory so if I'm going to
create a thumbnail of this image it
should be exactly in the same directory
not not you know in you know different a
separate directory you know so this kind
of design issues I mean this kind of
structure issues that's this really know
right answer also it depends on year
like every decades
you know the thinking changes like it
you know during 1990s you think in some
way you know ok awesome nails should be
in one directory you know things like
that and but for some other people they
think that for example right now I think
that all thumbnail should be in the same
directory as the image so anyway I made
this change ok so so for example these
SteelSeries this image if you go to the
directory you can see this file this
file is a thumbnail so I open it you see
it's in the same directory and in fact
they have they have the same name you
know that's the thumbnail so I decided
to do that so what I need to do is that
but but you see but all my files
oh my you know HTML
they are already linking to
the thumbnail Tian you know director ET
and slash something so this is
tremendous walk you need to regenerate
the thumbnails or move the thumbnails
you know to rename them things like that
you have to change all the link there
hundred thousands of links so that's
what I you know that's one of the thing
I have to do so once once I did that
okay I already did that for this
keyboard directory for you know for
example all my keyboard my keyboard blog
on this or this they are done you know
you don't you no longer have T and
directory for the thumbnails it's done
but however I am left with a bunch of
you know I'm left with this T and
directory still they have a lot images I
want to make sure that no HTML file is
actually linking to the ODE TN directory
you see what I'm saying so let me show
you this okay so let's go back to : okay
let's go back to golden visuals so so
this so okay so you see all this file
path you see all these file path so this
one affirmative keyboard that's a
keyboard this is another keyboard
keyboard keyboard a mouse Apple to
keyboard so they are these are or
thumbnails they are in a key and
directory so I want to search in my
keyboard directory for any HTML files
that contains any one of these paths
because if they contain it that means
it's bad at you know I didn't fix that
one you know things like that so that is
why I want a multi stream search you
know utility grab which I wrote this
this which is this one this this :
script so you can see I need to search
all these lines you know they are quite
a lot you know a few hundred of them
so you want to search all HTML files you
know so the whole script is only like
hundred lines like you know if I delete
this part the whole street squib is only
200 lines so anyway let's DVDs part
let's just do a demo let's say let's say
I want to find a word Haskell Lisp Perl
and the goal and okay let's say Python I
want to find this string in my keyboard
directory so actually so so I have a dis
Emacs command let me let me show you
okay I just call it press ENTER press
Enter so it becomes strings it changed
it turned lines into strings okay now I
need to add a comma here because colon
in Cola and you have when you anyway you
need the comma at the end so that
command is called
sock for lies okay it's on my website if
you want to use that okay so now we are
going to run this script so so we are
going to find all files in okay so let's
actually let's go to keyboard so we want
to find all files in a keyboard
directory this one any file that
contains any of these strings so let's
run it run it there it is so let me read
Oh actually I have a lot files
containing those words why is that it
shouldn't be so now it's done
let's show oh I know why because okay
let's quarks are fine output March so
it's colored I know why because Lisp
because they have so many these
keyboards so you see that these are our
currencies
that's why this now let's see if there
are any Haskell or something oh they are
so many so now I'm going to do another
thing hold on a second
so press up arrow press down arrow press
up arrow I'm going to delete all lines
containing the list keyboard okay so go
to the top delete matching lines Lisp
okay now all the Lisp lines are good now
let's press arrow keys okay there it is
now we found a instance of pearl okay
let's show what file is that okay
miscellaneous do it yourself keywords
now we are talking
Jessie heart keyboard now this keyboard
is the precursor of the keyboard IO it's
a precursor of this one and it's
designed by Jessie Vincent he is a old
Perl programmer you know from 1990's
he's a well-known for Perl program so
that that is why I mentioned Paul in
this file so where is the pearl so PR
there it is just Vincent is a famous
Perl program actually he's got a
Wikipedia entry you know there there it
is let's go back so anyway so so we
demonstrated that okay so here is the
line containing the world house cow so
anyway we demonstrated these closest
closest this script we demonstrated this
script you can find multiple words and
that's about it actually that's that's
it we didn't talk about you know so let
me read the comments let's see where we
go there
so Sheen to say scum oniy into thoughts
aren't trackpads the Mack trap pads is a
joy to use
yeah actually someone talked someone
Maxo Reiter also said the same thing he
likes trackpad
where is he stays top so max Reiter you
know he's got a Apple trackpad he likes
it I think it's good but I I know I I
think I prefer Mouse I never used Apple
trackpad except you know trying out in
stores so yeah I would like it but I
think ultimately I would prefer Mouse
because because I don't like you know
rubbing your fingers on something you
know keeping your fingers but yeah but
Apple did this it's a very nice track
pad pad because usually when you rub
your fingers on on the typical trackpad
it doesn't feel good you know you rub
your finger doesn't feel good but Apple
I've tried it in stores they created
since the last version or something you
know
they created a trackpad such that you
know that the surface is feels good to
go up to rub it so yeah which is not the
case you know in their early versions of
trackpad you know it doesn't feel good
to wrote to rub your fingers but but
their latest version is good TV says
hence the need for some use in CMS
content manager system like type type of
three what do you mean
okay so TV says when I was young TV says
when I was young those were the Amstrad
versus common dog people
oh yeah
Oh some some use CMS or gallery tours to
automatically generate thumbnail preview
image files I can't do that I mean I I
have that script actually let me show a
demo of that automatic automatic
generation of thumbnail let me show you
okay so you go to so go to Saudi Python
just such folks are Python you'll find
my Python tutorial and miscellaneous go
to the bottom miscellaneous you see this
script thumbnail generation so here is
the script I wrote in back in 2006 and
actually it's also home so let's go to
so so where would I find it then create
thumbnails there here is a script I
wrote back in 2006 so you see I'm doing
lots of yeah anyway so here is a Python
script so what it does is that you give
it a directory for example let me show
you where okay so here is the so you
give it a root directory and you'll give
it a thumbnail directory then then you
specify the thumbnail size and basically
it will go through the root directory
you find find any HTML file or any HTML
file and we'll go through it find any
image tag then you know get the path of
the image file then you will create a
thumbnail for those for those images so
it's you know it's pretty nice actually
we can run it let's let's try to run it
okay so let's go to Mike's ah Arts blog
okay so this is actually let's go to
visual so this directory
so let's go through this directory
Visual Arts and but before we do
anything let's go to git git status I
want to commit okay so git add okay then
get commit okay
then hold on a second so I show the
command window so now we do a remove all
backup files okay so now it's all done
so if we make a mistake we I can revert
right now so anyway so in this directory
copy the path now go to the Python go to
the Python thumbnail generation script
make a backup of the script now input
path directory this one okay no trailing
slash okay so here is the input
directory and image lists
okay so image list should be empty so
it's all commented out okay
because if you have an image list
anything there it will just process you
will just generate thumbnails for these
images if you do if the image is empty
then you will go through every HTML file
in this directory and extract the images
automatically okay so image list is
empty that's right we don't want it
so let's actually just delete it okay
now if I all lists also leave it empty
otherwise if you have any file in file
list it will just process those files
okay so thumbnail size area okay yeah
then okay depth for that's good so I'm
going to run this actually thumbnail
output let's find where is the thumbnail
output
I haven't used this script for many
years so anyway let's just run it and
see what happens run yeah global name
the name is not defined what the name
yeah I'm not going to fix it I haven't
used this for several years I think I
changed something and
are we ID yet what I D I think that's it
for today anything else anything else
interesting
so we were talking about squatting you
know in Asia in China for short and
Taiwan this in Taiwan where I grew up we
squat often you see this often but
however in America you don't see people
do that almost it's kind of weird you
don't see people do that but but this
person my craft my club but says it's
because white people don't squat it
because it says so it's a sub so it
looks like like your legs needs to be
thing in order to do these something
like that I don't I didn't know about
that but anyway yeah you don't see white
people do that that's I thought you know
so I didn't know it's physical because
you know fizzy physiology you know
because I always thought it's just
cultural thing ok that's it for today
anything else otherwise we're gonna shut
down in a minute so if you have if you
if you have a question for me
type it
so tomorrow 10 o clock a.m. San
Francisco time same time so tomorrow is
Sunday so same time but next week I'm
thinking of changing some other date and
you can find the date I'll probably
announce it in this code and on my
Twitter but you can use also find it on
my YouTube you go to my youtube channel
homepage then there is a communication
or something tab you go there I should
post my next week's schedule good
morning Erin horse era horse we need to
talk about democracy topic yeah that's a
controversial topic you know actually I
talked about that two days ago or maybe
was it yesterday so anyway and I
understand your point of view because
actually that's also debate with many
other people you know like right like
actually we debated about that today on
this scored you know so I want of course
I want to I want to put out my opinions
you know I think I think many of the
American typical American beliefs about
China are unfair so actually we
discussed that yeah this morning about
so you know I was talking so this guy
actually this this guy America and his
American guy but he lived in China for
long and his opinion is very
pro-american he his opinion is like you
know what I would say is you know kind
of typical American who believes
everything should be the American Way
okay like you know like the super
Superman movie you know flying with a
American flag the American Way
everything must be you know American way
is the only way although all of you the
list of what must do things the American
Way so II so even though he is very
pro-american but but he does you know
but I think if you watch his video this
video is you know his name is la whaai
that's his youtube name but he's not a
corporation you know in America every
day the fake news mainstream media they
hung out you know YouTube videos you
know and and also text read and you know
this is propaganda
don't don't don't read those okay so I
would even recommend his video so even
though he is very pro-american I mean
especially in the past few months you
know about you know Hong Kong is
happening so he always talked about oh
hey China is evil you know but however
he's not like cooperate you know pushing
out propaganda so I would even recommend
those of you you know watch his video so
you actually see at least you know even
I disagree with his opinion but you
actually see something video about China
you know there are people because he
actually has a Chinese wife and the in
my opinion you know he put out a video
in the past month you know past few
weeks where she he says you know my my
you know the title is something like my
my wife changed her opinion you know you
watch that video it's to me okay so it's
kind of like topic and propaganda you
know he he gets his wife to talk about
in English of course to talk about oh
yeah I didn't realize China is so evil
you know they censorship you know so to
me it's a propaganda but however the
point I want to bring out is that you go
watch his video not the corporate
mainstream media that you know the about
Hong Kong or did those laws are so
extreme fake okay you go watch his video
at least you can see something that's a
bit more real even you know I really
don't like his opinion you know I
disagree I think he's just propaganda
you know he tell his wife to go on video
and talk about things yeah anyway that's
but that's my point about that
Chinese censorship is reaiiy mean okay I
think so let's see we want to continue
about this week yeah we can talk about a
few more minutes so the question is
Chinese censorship real you know we have
to you know I know what you're thinking
you know like yeah yeah I said this many
times I know you what you guys thinking
since yeah it's real change in China you
have firewalls right everywhere everyone
knows for example you cannot go to
youtube youtube twitter facebook our
sensor Oh censored okay like you cannot
go you cannot visit Twitter you but a
lot of people a lot people in China they
they use you know VPN okay they use VPN
to do it but but still you have lots of
problems like I have people I started to
know you know Chinese people I've never
been to China
okay I was born in Taiwan but I but but
since like seven years ago I started to
know people in China you know I go there
I go to the online you know in China
forums where Chinese programmers talk so
I understand what they are you know
thinking I mean because I never been to
China I was born in Taiwan I left Taiwan
when I was 14 years old for the past
thirty years living in USA and I'm an
American citizen
okay so I'm not I'm you know what you
call chinese-american okay and I came
from I lived in Canada before for three
years so I don't really know exactly
what's going on in China so I talked to
people that's what you have to do you
know don't don't believe you know the
mainstream media that's all fake you you
today without technology you can
actually go you can actually I mean well
you can fly to China if you want to but
online you can actually talk to people
also you know I mean if you really want
to know the what is true what is not
true okay
I mean Church for yourself I'm not
trying to you can I'm just telling you
you can go spend the time the question
is whether you are willing to spend an
hour a day to do such a thing that's
that's a thing you should
most people we are not because this the
China issue really doesn't concern you
you know you just want to believe Oh
China is evil oh they have credit card
they have the entire lemon you know the
the score is social score system you
know but it's kind of it's all
it's store twisted okay so like garbage
this is fake news okay so let's talk
about censorship let's focus on one
specific thing censorship so is it it's
China censorship we oh yes it's
absolutely real Facebook Twitter you
cannot use then you have to use with
here many Chinese people do especially
programmers almost every Chinese every
programmer in China they use snip here
but it's not it it doesn't just walk
okay it's not just like that or vvm
solves everything no they have like
every day every week every month you
then you know it doesn't work then you
have to switch VPM things like that you
hear I hear complaints from Chinese
programmer all the time like
firewall you know you hear that all time
so yeah so so censorship is real but
however I know you know I know what
you're thinking you I mean typical
Americans you know oh yeah so therefore
China it's not like that UFO let me give
you an example something we I think you
know my followers agree a USA Today
you cannot say men and women are
different you know you guys know that
because you know you guys follow me we
are kind of we are untied as social
churches you think about that
you cannot say men women are different
yes you say that you get banned on
Twitter you get fired if you are
professor you get kicked out what's
going on with that I mean really I mean
think I have so many examples okay but
let's just focus on one this one simple
exact thing in USA Today United State
the United States of America you cannot
for example on Twitter say men and women
are different you cannot say that you
can say that in China in Japan in Middle
East in almost everywhere except the
white countries today
since the past four years this is Vicky
become becoming quite bad okay you know
so you can so what's going on so we'll
have a China has censorship but in USA
you cannot say men women are different
which one is worse I mean what's what's
going on you know what what's going on
so I know you know like before and you
know you typically you ask typical
American you know because I'm American I
lived in here for 30 years
doesn't matter it's a left-wing you know
the anti anti power the you know
democratic today or you know the extreme
left wing or the right wing when you ask
them about China they they don't know
nothing about China but they all just
tell you all China is so evil you know
think about you know we have Cold War
Russia Russia vs. USA you know imagine
in the 90s or 80s oh you hear every day
about Russia is how they are so bad you
know but I have people following me on
in Georgia for example who greendeath
right green deck tell them you know
green deck tell them tell the Americans
you know how extremely ridiculous there
are you know the American thoughts about
Russia it's like ridiculous
you know you you go today you can
without technology you can actually talk
to people you know in Russia or in China
you know you talk to them you ask them
dislike what you're talking about they
don't know what you're talking about so
for example about China's censorship it
is true okay yeah but it's but but what
you are thinking is kind of all twisted
you know it's like oh twisted like for
example you mean it's they mention
another social justice thing it is true
that Americans are you know white people
are patriarchy or privilege you know is
it true you suppose China China China
they're asking me is it true is it true
I heard that Chinese you know the
Americans are patriarchy you know or the
men are so evil white people is it true
that white people have privilege what am
I going to say you know I'm going to
well yeah
in some sense is true yeah you know
typically you know in some sense you
know the SM level is true but not it's
nothing like the way today's social
justice wants you to believe you know
the the whole entire history of humanity
is patriarchy you know it's not like
that okay is it true that women cannot
vote yeah it's true you know in the past
you know this but it's not like what
they are you know the social just scan
are telling you in the same way it's the
same thing about China
is it true China has since the strip yes
but it's you know people are happy yeah
you a lot you know then we get into
details you know that's the thing the
social rating system okay I think I
should stop you know because that topic
is interest social rating system it's
like it's it's it's just like just just
like the sense that's kind of just like
the Chinese censorship yes it's it's
there but it's not what you think okay
it's not like what you think for example
I have roommates they you know they you
know the dad has been USA for like seven
years this his son came here about three
years ago if you know if I asked them
you know if I ask them well what do you
think of the the China the socio is a
rating system you know do you think it's
bad you know you know what's their
reaction it's gonna be what what you
talking about what what what are you
talking about you know and and they the
way I you know I you don't even ask them
because you see them every day you know
that they'd love you know they did they
tell me I had never been to China but
they tell me oh the the American system
you still write checks what the you
know they we go we go to China we just
swipe the phone they tell me that you
know to to you you are thinking whole
scary you know the the China's but it is
you know the mainstream media you know
great social rating system Oh everyone
is you know
control tightly monitor that's what
ma'am that's what not they think at
least at least my roommate they never
thought about it in fact they're gonna
tell you they date you know what they
tell me you know the mountain view you
know they are building houses and I have
other roommates before ok they tell me I
never asked them they just tell me oh
the the the building the building houses
here is so slow you know it takes 1 2
years to build a house in China is like
1 month is done they tell me that I
don't I don't know you know and and so
anyway so that's some of the things
okay now we started to have a lot of
comments once we talked about this topic
because it's controversial topics so
ever anyway that I think I think that's
it for today oh yeah pink king hearing
says that's because because people have
been propaganda dyes since birth yeah
that's another common you know thinking
that's what you want to believe I could
tell you I could tell you American you
know you guys actually I literally view
it you guys Americans you know that what
I'm American to you you white people
we're people is a proper word since you
are children what every day your brain
is thinking about justice justice
freedom since you are child why because
you can see in the comics you know
Marvel Superman Batman DC Comics Marvel
Comics every day since you are children
you you read the comments it's it's
about justice you know Justice League
your your brain is like since you are
small you are concerned about let's say
controlling other countries the the
American Way like anything deviate from
these thoughts this justice freedom
democracy do you know the justice speaks
Superman with the flag let me show you
that sir Wonder Woman okay
Wonder Woman from bondage antes that's
um supposedly according to the story her
injuries from Greeks but you know you
can see Captain America with a giant
star you know the American symbol
Superman they are you know let's go to
Superman I don't want to do is when
don't want a woman let's go to Superman
Superman look Superman issue one you see
that it's American you know it's not
just Superman it's not a story about Oh
from alien space we have a you know
Superman great hero okay it's not just
that you see that ego you see this
shield blue you know Stars and Stripes
Superman so what I'm saying is so
English sense since you were born
you are brainwashed into the American
Way can I say that I mean I'm giving you
a different perspective because you are
saying oh because China they are they
ask this about China because they be all
propaganda the government washed their
brain well you've been washed your brain
your brain has been washed too into the
American Way since you are pong is that
not true I mean is that not true you see
Superman that it's not just a story
about some aliens hero right you see
this this American you know symbol over
poor Eagle right in what sense
what do you think Chinese people there
they look at this they say they don't
think this is American what do what do
they think this is you know it's a it's
a it's a question of perspective so if
you are American you you don't see this
as a propaganda this is the right way
just is of course Justice League you
know you know and and also by the way
the background story of Superman why are
they created they are created because
during the Cold War era we we are
fighting with the Russia communists we
don't want that so we that's how
Superman
one a woman in Captain American War bomb
you know they would what you you again
you could say as a propaganda for
mainstream media they created it to
fight the Communists you if you read the
history you know like today I will give
video they they change a lot of things
for especially young Wonder Woman they
you know it's all social justice
perspective but if you go to Wikipedia
you go to Wonder Woman Superman Captain
America let's skate you go to Wikipedia
you go to the history tab look at
Wikipedia from ten years ago you can see
the history of this superhero where they
came from and in the background and and
fighting with communism that's that's
that's the arrangement of these
superheroes fighting Russia the
Communists you know it is it's about
perspective if you want if you want to
look at the truth
okay so let me read some more comments
and that's that's it for today okay so
so why do you excuse the things China
does but also hypercritical of
everything u.s. does they both do bad
things and it's fine to put out to point
our bad things at both that's true I
that is absolutely true but you know but
why do I you know what do I just you
know almost like just attacking USA and
not China because you we are in u.s. I'm
you know I'm American you guys most of
you know half of you are American for
example like programming languages why
am i am i what why do i attack unix all
the time because among our hackers the
UNIX that's a mantra that's the
mainstream and I tend to want to you
know I'm a nonconformist I want to throw
away what is not true that's why I say
it because otherwise what's the point
yeah you know yeah of course everyone is
bad because yeah because you guys
because I'm Chinese so it's this the
skin color is a bit different from you
so I have different perspective so some
people ask me what do you think about
China so I give you my opinion that's
that's that's all you know and of course
I'm probably you know to to be sure and
probably more bhaiyya you know I'm
probably biased as you know for China
that's just because that's my skin color
just like in exactly the same way you
are white people you are biased towards
America you know if you are from England
or Scotland you know you are probably
more biased towards Scotland or England
then American that's natural you know
okay so that's it for today okay bye
guys
by