hello good morning welcome to another
episode of EX talk show so we're going
to do uh wolam language coding Advent of
code Advent of
code uh we going to
do uh where is it let's
see okay let's go to emac show Advent of
code uh 2020 three day 14 part two uh
this is take four we are going to
continue to do some you know the find
the periodic of uh function nesting
sequence and uh let's begin Advent Cod
wam language how are you guys and oh but
I want to show you some of the Fantastic
things I have been doing by the way this
image is generated by AI artificial
intelligence we did a talk show about it
about two month two months
ago wam language so I have written this
PL Tiding
package uh I did a few live stream about
it it's fantastic in wam language it's
about plan Tiding so this package you
can use it you can generate it generate
any type of periodic patterns or Tidings
so so it's on GitHub free you can
download it uh on GitHub right there
okay and and there's this
guy uh there's this guy who who did
great work with the package this um uh
you know what's his name he's got a
sandov COR you know something he's got a
website so it's Spanish uh you can check
it
out but let me show you so some of the
great beautiful things he sent me see
can you see
it uh yes okay see this this then this
math formulas
geometry uh lots of square roots and
stuff and uh then you generate this this
this now what how exactly are the curves
let's see how does he how does he
generate the curve convert Circle to
line uh fundamental region fundamental
domain okay so first of all in order to
create this Graphics the most important
thing is to
create this curve so how does he create
the curve convert Circle to
line
uh join from cap from round circle so so
this part I'm not
sure uh you know you have to look into
so what is convert Circle to line that's
a function I wrote I think I don't
remember it's uh you know I wrote this
package like almost 30 years
ago and uh I have just been I have just
updated it few months
ago but okay so I need to actually I
need to load the package so let's load
the
package the event of code uh yeah so I
need to load the package where is here
is a package okay PL tying
documentation uh there it is so
you load the
package now it's loaded now let's go
back here let's see what is
the
uh if you are watching this offline skip
around
okay
uh oh this this is
old control C copy I think that's
the old package
question mark paste
it oh there it is convert all Circle
Graphics primitive to line
yeah so where is it
defined it is defined yeah it's defined
in my
package so anyway so let's see
very
pretty but still we haven't found out
how exactly are the curve generated so
let's let's go back and let's go
here okay let's evaluate this control
and shift enter
okay convert Circle to line so you got a
circle so this is fundamental domain
plate uh cap form join form line convert
to
Circle Arc cosine there it is
so part of it is Arc cosine so basically
you got this then bunch of Lines line
seg ments based from a circle so part of
it is a circle and part of it is AR
cosine uh you got a circle AR co sign
there again
yeah so yeah so I guess so this part is
a circle then that part is AR
cosine uh AR cosine yeah I guess
so and maybe that part as well so you
get this
beautiful then the next so basically the
fundamental region is this one you want
to generate that then you just use res
set Motif that will just repeat it into
a like a symmetric rotational symmetry
pattern then
you so so you create a new fundamental
domain region and what do you do you use
the
original then you add this bunch of
lines okay one line two line 3 four five
then more
circles and then you add more circles
then more R cosine yeah so you want to
generate you want to turn a line into a
strip now is there uh there is there no
simple function to turn a line into a
strip I'm not sure so then eventually
you generate this beautiful then you
remove the internal line then you
generate this now but the here's a
question how do you remove the edge
Crossings how did he do
that uh let's
see so
does he how do how do you
remove okay you I guess you just
manually Cod it you see in this bu of
code you don't have the edge
Crossings oh then you actually no so
this is interesting then you actually
weave it you see once you got this
pattern you want it weaved because we
weaved when you have it weaved it's more
beautiful you see now you got this it's
more
intricate it's kind of like the Celtic
patterns so
fantastic fantastic so what is the
difference between this one and the next
one uh I'm not sure
beautiful that's that one so what about
here here is another one and uh this one
uh you see this one is a tiing it looks
like that so you start with this you
build this fundamental
region yeah so you begin simple with
lines then you can generate this
tiing pattern then you refine it by
turning lines into strips then you got
this
pattern then you remove the in uh
initial lines then you got this pattern
it's
beautiful so go down then what do you do
then you start to weave it then you
create remove certain lines so they
cross each other then you got this
pattern this is like Islamic styled
pattern wow that's
beautiful truly
beautiful then what do you do then
[Music]
you uh what is the difference of this
one if you are here say hi if you are
watching this offline skiper around and
play at 1.5
speed so what is this
one versus this
one oh it reverse it flipped the
fundamental
region so
so does it reverse
the yes it kind of re you know reverse
like a mirror
image
fantastic okay so now let's do um let's
do the vand of code so um we I want to
continue V of code so last time we need
to finish this
code yep
okay this is today and uh let's put the
code
here okay let's start to code so here is
a function of mod over five and here's a
table let's see if we can yeah we can do
that let's evaluate the
region so here's
output
uh
wait here's the output of this function
mod uh Mod Five okay then then we
discuss periodic then okay then go down
find cyclic tail this is interesting
function because
given a list it will return the
repeating
tail
so uh so if we run that let's let's get
some
example run
it so yeah so the input if the input is
932 32 you got you get 32 okay okay copy
that so let's put
here uh yeah
okay okay that's that function then the
function we really want to write is get
this uh this one get period uh in fact
this should be named get Nest nested
period so you want so this function
takes takes a function and initial value
uh and Max Max maximal number of nesting
and uh it will return a periodic of the
function like the function apply to the
initial value get output and feed back
to the function get output and feed it
back to the function repeat until you
find you find a uh repeating you know uh
periodic like 1 2 3 1 two 3 so then this
function will report the periodic okay
so so this function should be named not
get period but get Nest period
so something like that
okay okay get Next Period and
uh okay okay and this function is not
finished last time so let's finish it
now hello Kola Kaa wam uh wam language
didn't you see the YouTube title wam
language
so we want to write this function
getting okay so so first of all um we
Define a module module means a variable
block
so we have a local variable F test so
this so basically we want to call Nest
while so Nest while is a function that
we take a function and initial value and
the test function it will simply Nest
the function
until until your test function returns
false okay
so
that's nqu so we call that give the
function initial value and give the test
function then this all means feed the
test function or pre previous results
okay then uh Max Nest Max Nest is the uh
the maximum number of recursion we want
to
do because we do not know the function
repeat or not it may it be a may be a
function when you nested it does not
repeat so we need to have a maximum
value otherwise it's infinite uh
computation so so the interesting part
is this F test function so the F Tex
test function
basically we call this fine CYCC tail
okay evaluated at pound pound sign means
all the arguments
so
uh so we can see here is a
function okay and the function body is
just if
statement so and where is a function
argument argument is represented by the
pound pound sign that means all
arguments
so this braces pound sign means is is
the braces pound sign is just a list of
all the arguments so this is a list and
you pass this list to find cyclic
Trail so that determines if the
last you know if if the result is a um
repeating with a repeating tail
now if that returns a empty list then me
uh return true true means
continue the
nesting so otherwise return forse return
Force means stop the nesting so this
nextest while so it will stop but every
time you call this
um let's see you see this function is
meant to find the
period
uh
so so you don't want so Nest while
simply return the last result of the
nesting but what you really want is to
find the period
okay so what do you have to do so
yeah so let's see if there's a option
that allows you to like return
something return the result found when F
had been applied in few times okay
so apply F extra end times you want to
return next s
uh interesting so next why I'll Tak a
function and uh basically according to
this documentation the next wire we
always return an output of the
function it always returns the output of
the function okay
so but our function get n period should
be turn a
period so we need to do something here
so so this Nest while is actually just a
byproduct that's right we don't actually
care about the output of the function we
really we just we you know we just want
to we just just want to run the code so
that we can see whether it repeats or
not so this next file is
actually uh
byproduct okay so that shouldn't be the
result the result would
be so
if let's see Find Cy tail
if it's true if it's empty repeat
otherwise otherwise return Force but you
need
to uh you need to let's
say something temp result okay so
otherwise temp result equals to
the
input
and so this is breaking pure functional
programming because you are setting a
value yeah but let's just get it to work
first okay so if there's no cyclic tail
then you return true that means continue
the nesting now if if you found the
cyclic tail okay you need to temporarily
save the cyclic tail exactly what's
their value that's right so okay so we
need to modify this function okay so let
me show you how to do that uh we write
again module
here so we write the module put this
whole
thing here that's a function body that
mean the module body module is a local
variable block
um and
uh so let's call this x result okay temp
this is local
variable
so so what you want to do is you want
to oh wait actually you need to yeah you
need to put the module inside the
function okay not
so you you need to put the
module inside the function so here so
cut that paste it here okay so you got a
function and inside the function is a
modu
uh okay let me just Cod
it well actually why don't you put the
function let me just code it okay
function um
yeah how does this work so you want you
want um
well the thing is the test
function the test function
is
is is called by this Nest while so let's
think about this so you are nesting a
function here you are nesting a function
you do not actually
care about the function's result
but rather you just want to know the
periodicity of the function when it's
nested and uh so you do need to you know
Nest the
function because you need the function's
value to determine the periodic so this
is a
byproduct so when we do n while but we
also need to have a test this test will
determine whether to stop or not okay so
right now we are trying to Define this
test
um
so so basically so the test is a
function the test must be a function
that's right okay that resolves that
okay the the test actually needs to be a
function um so remove that so the test
needs to be a function
then then inside the function we need
some kind of temporary variable okay so
let's let's use a
module
um for it okay and inside the
module uh should we use module block
block modu is lexical scoping but it's
fairly slow because every time you call
module every variable it will just
generate a new variable new symbol so
generating a new symbol is slow uh in
fact it generates a unique symbol and
the way wam language does that is
it it appends a number incremental
number to each variable name whatever
you know variable so it has to
internally keep
count so when you use module it's so
basically it means it's relatively very
slow uh you could use Dynamic scope yeah
so yeah so block uh or you can use a
constant should you use a
constant let's see um what we need the
variable
for is that we need to store
uh we need to store the result of this
cyclic tail so that we can get the
length and find the
period
so yeah so so yeah
so so
ah
what equals to so let's do that there
that will temporar save the result Okay
then if the result is
empty return true continue running
otherwise return Force Stop the Loop
okay and
uh okay but however you see the result
we need to
right now this result is local we need
to you
know we need to save it so that you know
so that we can um get the length of
return the length
of the result this is the the real the
actual thing we want the
periodic so over there let's see
so put a comma comma means suppress the
output well the comma syntax the
semicolon syntax actually
means in this it's like
P so when whenever you have a
semicolon it actually just turn the
whole expression into compound
expression bracket then you know several
expression it's is like the this P
GN so anyway so we Nest it every time
you Nest it you call this test function
so let's rename it
okay test
function okay
then then
okay so let's remove
this okay so you define a test function
to be a
function uh and
uh oh you don't actually want the module
yeah so don't do the that's right so you
don't want this result to be local you
directly say save it to
there okay
so so this modu
thing yeah remove
that that's right and
then and you uh and you don't need the
clyra it so this line directly
save
this tail to the result then if the
result is is
empty then return
true uh now I want to check
if I want to check if Sam Q Returns
the if that's is true okay eval
line true okay so it's able to determine
two empty braces are equal you know
these are kind of tricky
because testing equality is one of the
most complicated thing in programming
languages um and that is
because you know like for example in
proof theory in type Theory testing
equality is the most complex thing
because you cannot uh
um because for example integer three and
three is equal for
sure uh but when you have a empty list
you know maybe you you know you are
checking the re reference of
that array or you are checking something
else or you know and or if you have like
3.0 versus three
integer you know
intuitively we we want them to be equal
be but on the other hand they are
different type one is a float one is
integer
therefore uh depending on what you want
exactly so it's very hard to Define
equality and especially in lisp common
lisp and emac lisp uh for example let me
digress a little bit so for example in
iMac LP you go to this Basics then you
go to uh s emac
tutorial then you have a section on
equality okay buing equality test so for
example in
lisp um you
have many equality testing functions you
have equal you have
EQ you have eql
you have the equal sign you have string
equal then you have char
equal uh and uh so you know it's fairly
complicated now in wfam
language if you search for wfam Language
tutorial search my name and you'll find
wfam language only has two equality
tests
uh you can go to buing and go to
equality test so one of them is called
same q q means a question true so any
function that whose name ends in a
capital
Q that Q stand for question that means
the function will always return either
true or false no no other possibility
either you always return true or false
so that's same q and and uh it has a
syntax shortcut of triple equal sign so
the same Q will basically test the
structure
uh you know because wam language is a
symbolic language everything you see is
just a sequence of symbols there is no
actual integer or float you know is just
a sequence of
symbols you can think of it as a string
so in wfam language all this source code
is just like string symbolic string
so you know they it's
called terms you know that's why it's
called term rewriting system it's you
know it's called terms in computer
science anyway so you got this same CU
which test structure of two things then
you got this equal function as which
with the shortcut of double equal sign
and this allows you to test whether you
know 3 is equals to
3.0 things like that but the but so you
only have these two uh functions to test
equality in wam language you know so you
might think it's simple but actually not
really because then you you can see some
of the
quo for example you you know if you have
nested list of you know like
one then equal equal one single list of
two it returns
itself like it cannot determine whe
whether it's equal or
not and that behavior is
because I suppose I think it's designed
that way
because because in you know in this in
term Rew writing system there's a lot of
situations you
[Music]
um you you know when when you you can
you cannot be
sure I mean the the bottom line is that
it's very hard to
Define what is equality so notice this
function equal does not end with a
capital Q so it does not always return
true or false it return true or return
False only when this function can
absolutely
uh determine it's you know true or false
so so you got this weird situation you
know a empty list equals to two yes or
no it cannot say so it just return that
expression
itself okay so that's about equality
very complex things in programming
languages um especially when you have
nested list for example in Python then
in Python then you got the situation in
Python rubby or JavaScript or almost all
languages you see when you have nested
this then you have
the you know you know whether you are
not sure whether you need to compare
each the content of the elements or the
reference of the uh
elements uh also known as Shadow uh
shallow copy versus deep copy things
like that so in Python Ruby JavaScript
whenever for example you want to
determine two nested list are equal or
not you usually you got some
issues uh
yeah so anyway so get let's get back to
uh these things so we digress into about
equality test so uh uh this test
function zagd says why is most of
YouTube content simply uninformative is
it impossible to find quality channel uh
there are quite a few quality channels
you just have to find
it okay I think today's this is kind of
boring uh and uh I'm okay let's finish
writing
this okay I'm going to relax and um yeah
instead of doing a boring stuff let's
let me just enjoy myself I need to do
this myself
anyway so say hi of those you um Wan
language coders or interested in this
you know computer science and
stuff I'm writing too slow I mean this
is like
um yeah okay anyway so let's
see so you said the result was kind of
like a
global okay so they are fine tell that
then test okay uh then you run then you
run this okay so you can see here we
have a function
X test function okay now this function
is only used
once you see it's defined here it's
declared there defined here and only
used once so we could just remove the
def you know just put the function in
line like in line
here yeah but anyway so we run next s
and
uh
okay then then once it's
done
[Music]
we there's a you know we can return the
X result the length of
it if the function is
repeating but if it's
not and uh
yeah okay so if if the max Nest is
reached then the result will and if it's
not still not cyclic
then then the X result
is uh going to be empty
so then the length of empty this is zero
so this function returns zero so I think
we got it
yeah I think that's it so save it close
it reopen
it uh
[Music]
copy I think that's the code we want
okay I think we got
it okay so
wait so it's red
here
uh oh yeah so this needs to be a
semicolon yeah nice nice wam language
syntax coloring it caught the error so
before we were using module that's why
so now now it needs to be semicolon
okay let me explain the semicolon thing
okay so when you have
something semi colon uh let's say GGG G
FF any
something okay when you you know any of
this symbol is any expression you know
it may be super long or whatever so when
when when you have any like that it auto
automatically this this is the semicolon
is just the syntax
shortcut this uh
what this will
become it will
become okay it will become that you see
when you have a semi col and there's
nothing after it then it becomes nor so
this becomes
that or if you don't have a semicolon at
the end then it just become that you see
this becomes that
um and you can see that in my
tutorial search
for semicolon
uh graphicss programming syntax
operators Association list Advanced okay
data
structures uh pattern matching Define
function go up expression atom head
there semicolon so click on that so it's
you see it's a just a syntax shortcut
for compound
expression and uh this is similar to
lisps
PN okay
okay so now let's um now let's go back
to let's put this back let's put
some copy
that so we know we uh we logged what we
talked about so here's a code make a
backup color syntax it let's show
and uh here's our code today so we need
to test if that works so it's over
here uh did we fix
it yeah we did semicolon so if oh yeah
we forgot
wait this you need a
semicolon yeah you do need a semicolon
length result okay that's nice that's
what you want that's
right okay so let's do copy this again
copy
it
paste run it okay now
now if you
um do we have the mod 5 defined no now
we need to test this function so this
should work how do we find a function
that we can test this um last time we
didn't find the uh we didn't find it we
need a function such that when it is
nested with a you know given a initial
value then when it's nexted the function
is
periodic last time we also
determined the
periodic may be dependent on the initial
value but what we didn't have is a
example of search function we need a
example of search function to test to
really robustly make sure that uh get
Next Period
works so yeah so last time we have this
hellstone you know these hellstone
numbers uh hellstone
sequence
what uh why is this
27 undo oh we need to paste it here okay
so why is this 27
red oh you need
three you need three argument that's
right yes starting and you need
to yeah end times so next this you need
in
uh let's say 99 times
okay so we have this so
2799 let's run this yeah so
it did not return let's
say
299 okay it it takes over 100
repetitions
to nesting in order to get to um
one so
hellstone function or collapse
conjecture function this
function will
cycle we you know it has a py of three
412 421 421 p c of
three for basically any input
okay
so so when we use the hellstone function
so we can try to test our function with
the hellstone okay so let's try that
let's try to test our
function so get n
period get n period of the hellstone
function and initial value of let's say
and the run time maximum of 1,000 times
okay now this should return
three okay so let's
hopefully did we evaluate yet we didn't
evaluate so we need to run it okay get
Next Period now run this three
beautiful okay I think I think I saw of
it so uh we didn't test so much
yet but I'm fairly confident it
works
um yeah so let's try the mod so we
haven't defined you know so if you
define the mod
function did we did we Define the mod
function
yet no okay so we need to to paste it
shift enter Define it so for the mod
function the function has a periodic of
five it returns 0 one 2 3 4 0 1 2 3 4
You Know
repeats but when you Nest this function
the periodic is just
one because when you Nest it basically
it
um you know we can try it so let's try
uh Nest list okay so you want to Nest
the XM 5
function okay and initial value let's
say
30 okay let's say five then maximum of
100 times shift enter
you see you got 0 0 0 periodic is one
because the z0 is repeated and
uh and the unique value in the
repetition is just one value so that is
why the periodic of nesting the Modi
function is
one uh you can try with different number
let's say uh
three you know you got the same thing
so so if we try our
function you know to find the period of
of the XM 5
function okay and starting with whatever
number and the maximum maximum of 1,00
times it'll return
one enter one so correct so we tested
two examples it
works not a full test but I'm pretty
confident our function works
okay so our
function this Get Next Period suppos you
know should work you know let's copy
this
for the
record uh yeah it's already you already
did so the result is one there and here
the result is three hellstone
numbers yeah so okay now this function
works
now now we can go back to the original
problem of the Advent of code okay so
let's see what what is this this belongs
to this is about getting the cyclic tail
so we can move
it CYCC tail
okay okay now put this back
it showing
browser uh I think we have a kind of a
stop so yeah so the next so
fantastic this this this function is
what we want now let's go back to the
original problem Advent of code 2023 day
14 part
two okay let's see
so that problem is fairly complicated
okay okay so we
got yeah
okay let me look at
this one cycle okay so we want to go to
take two because we have better
code so we have move north move west
move South South move East
okay and we have one cycle then we have
all
moved then we have list of moves and we
did an animation of it that's
fantastic uh and we started to try to
write this function fin Next
Period okay this is written by someone
else okay so this code is by written by
someone else so we can actually compare
our code with uh that
one I believe I'm pretty
sure mine is more efficient
faster faster and uh
okay
so okay
so so what we do next so we want
to yeah let's continue the Advent of
code
the yeah so we need to so here is the
manipulate copy okay let's
see yeah okay so now
so now we paste all the previous
thing okay now go to the top refresh we
got the input we turn it into Matrix we
got row count and we got column count
which I don't think we need so delet it
then we Define the function move north
move west move South South move East or
by pattern
matching then then do them all F1 cycle
is uh you know all the movements in one
shot
then then all moved is the final um
let's
see next one cycle Matrix yeah so do
this 1 100 times then to total
okay but the question is you have to do
it 1 billion times okay
so you know do it 1 billion times find
the final board
configuration and count the number of BS
in each row for each one multiply by the
inverse of the row number of that row
then add them all together so that's
what this does but the essence is that
you want
to you know find the final board
configuration after one billion cycles
and we tried that it's you know it'll
take a long time so so we discovered we
need to find the cycle
because after all this roll ball rolling
there's a cycle we need to find that
cycle once you find the
cycle okay so yeah so you need you need
to find the
pvy of nesting this function F1 cycle
okay so let's so what we can do is we
can X get
periodic uh
oh X get Nest periodic okay get Nest get
n period and uh of this
function and of initial input is a x
Matrix and the maximum number of times
let's
say this you need to guess but you can
you can say 1 billion okay 10 raed to 99
but for now let's let's you know let's
just say
three uh let's just say four it's not
too big okay so this will get the
period so one billion times would
[Music]
be
so the so what you got
is mod 1 billion
by by the period okay so for example
let's say 10 by
[Music]
3 mod 10 by 3 is
um is one right there's always of one by
one thing so let's say mod 5 by3
mod by 5 by
[Music]
3 is two right let's try
it right so it gives you the remainder
okay now if you got one
billion
um wait so wait so you need to think
about
this so if the period is three
okay so you need
to so let's see the P how do see how
does it go so if you have five so if you
have 1 two 3 four
five five different board
configurations and uh but you want it to
do seven times okay so it's a it's
cyclic
okay okay so you see the the it's a bit
tricky because this function one
cycle it doesn't cycle in the beginning
it may not you know it it's only
after wait does
it oh it does cycle from the very
beginning right okay so that makes a lot
simpler you see the the F1 cycle it does
cycle from the very
beginning almost I mean after the first
when you move all the ball to the
north if you
consider you know you you got off by one
issue here but if
you so the initial board let's call it
zero
configuration so the first generation is
all the move all the BS to the
north and uh
wait I mean the first generation is
completing one cycle so all the boss
ends up on the
East so and uh then then you got
uh so this so you want to complete let's
say seven
Cycles okay you want to complete s seven
cycles and
uh 1 2 3 four five six
7 so there's this off by one
issue kind of tricky
because um
uh fairly complicated problem so if you
have seven so let's focus okay
so board
configuration so what does this one two
three four five means this one means
after running one cycle two means after
running two cycles
3 four five six
7 so seven Mod Five is two okay so after
seven times you end up the same board
configuration as the second
cycle so you take the remainder that's
right and uh what
about yeah okay so so one cycle two
cycle three so if the
board has a periodicity of five if this
F1 cycle
function then that means does it begin
with yes it begin because the first
cycle we move all the balls North West
South East
so once you te that it's kind of all
like flushed
out
so so after the first
cycle then you go into the second cycle
yeah so if if you know if the
F1 is periodic when you
nested then the cycle will begin
in the first um generation meaning that
if the tail you know if there are five b
different configurations they
repeat it means the entire result is 1 2
3 4 5 1 2 3 four five you know it
repeats from the very
beginning okay so if you want to do 9
billion I mean one billion times so you
just take that
number divided by the number the the
periodic of
nesting then you got a remainder the
remainder is just the index of your
cycle starting with Cycle One index one
based okay so you just take the
remainder so it's now it's
clear so you just mod 1 billion by the
period That's a remainder then you just
cycle it that many times
Okay so don't do that so basically you
want to do that this this
okay this is all moved so you Nest
F1 initial value of the Matrix and how
many times to Nest you take the
remainder of the
billion
um remainder of the billion divided by
the period okay
yeah okay now what about the period what
is the maximum number of tries you want
to
do that depends on the board size okay I
mean what is the maximum upper
Bound for the
periodic of the cycle function well that
depends on the board size and the number
of bards and the number of
Wars
so yes
so and mostly it depends on the number
of
Wars but in
general yeah it in general it can be not
cannot be too large cannot I don't think
you'll even be more than 100 so this
becomes another pure math problem
so the problem is to determine what is
you know given a board like
that uh or do we have a uh no we don't
have the you
know you know given a board like that
and we could have a bigger
board uh for
example here you know this user input so
this is I think 100 by 100
so given a board you want to determine
what is
the upper bound what is the maximum
possible periodic of this F1
cycle so it will
[Music]
be I think it will be less
than you will be for sure less than the
width times the height of the
Matrix that's still a lot uh so if the
Matrix is 100 let's say it's 10 by 10
the cycle is less than
100 if the Matrix is 100 by 100 the
cycle is less than
10,000 that's
right but that's still too much of a
upper bound I think it's significantly
smaller because then you also have to
count uh
yeah yeah so the cycle is like the you
know the upper bound is pretty
small
so now knowing that we
can we can kind of get idea what of what
we want to put
here so we know our initial board is
like 100 by 100 okay so yeah that's a
good number
actually okay so I think that's it we
can run the whole thing that this should
give us an answer let's hope so okay
so so where is our function we uh yeah
so let's let's we need to clean this
okay so number of
Cycles delete that that's from let's
delete that okay board history
delete okay
delete okay delete delete manipulate
manipulate T delete find this period
that's what we want uh but last time we
failed so now let's just delete them
okay we need to move this
up because we use the function uh
actually the function we need is
just this fine
cycle and
uh okay let's copy it
okay so actually so let's put this part
at the
bottom okay move to the bottom paste it
there okay select all let's just run it
one last double
check okay so we
mod Hil
Stone and find cyclic tail
then get Next Period that's the
important
function then starting the Advent of
code
problem okay let's run it so wait here
so get
period okay
then all moved yeah so then total
yeah R
it 64 I think that's the right
answer ah finally this took three
days okay so it says
64 and now it wants my own uh personal
input okay so let's try my own personal
input
copy so this is what you want
cut
close Okay copy
all paste
right what
[Music]
three wait
what oh it's still running
wait come on
did
we okay that this doesn't look good it's
still
running uh
shift control Escape let's see if
it's using one Gab
memory
okay okay so find psychic tail if match
this is taking too
long not good
got okay maybe we can do some clean up
okay for
not looking good
okay well it is
running why don't we clean up the code
that's right why don't we yeah let me
just clean up the
code okay
so so I want to
first of all make this just to be
that
okay and uh
without without a b of code
okay so that is one part then this part
will be just for the event of code so
you don't need this test
functions remove all the thought
process uh remove
hstone remove remove the algorithm
description that's what you
need uh and the remove
example also remove the Aro
description here is another function you
need in fact this function you know you
don't need separate
functions yeah but it gets complicated
you see here's a function and it's only
used here one time so technically you
don't need
them to be separate you can just in
inline the function
here okay but okay but so anyway remove
that remove that so here is the
input now the
input if you try it you see this is
still running so that means it's not
good something is
wrong so but the last time the result is
64 that checks out
but why is it with the user input
something is wrong I don't
know yeah
this is really
nasty so now the input now you will
count move north move South and R cycle
so why is it wrong
period now let's search for the period
the period you get the next
period so how do you
determine the
equality let's go back
here nextest while the test function
okay if res equals to is
empty then
true oh okay
[Music]
so head tail
tail so it's possible that this function
is
incorrect
because this works for flat list but if
you have a matrix list of
lists
yeah God so you need to test this
function you know we can you make need
to be sure this function works you see
what we need to test is
that if you have a flat list such as 2
three one something something 23 one
then it works but let's
say your list let's just say you one to
2 one two one okay let just say 21 two
one now but if your list is nested okay
like
2121 2121 let's say 21 two three okay so
in this case this is not a
cyclic
uh list but
however however this pattern matching
you know this head tail might just match
this sub
expression so therefore it returns 2121
but each actually not so
maybe you know so actually
yeah so if it match yeah so actually all
we have to do to test this
hypothesis
is just
run this
okay so we can run it
here this is independent
uh so it says
false oh yeah so it matches the whole
expression so that should work but
then uh hold on a second so yeah okay so
that worked that's
good and uh what about
what about this part okay so what if you
do that okay let's try
it this is incorrect
wait this is correct okay uh yeah so it
didn't change anything so this should be
correct so what if we run this find
cyclic tail
okay
uh should be this should return empty
okay if we run this thing it should
return empty okay let's try it
yep it returned empty there so you need
to put semicolon there so that it
doesn't you
know it it doesn't print this uh usage
string so this return empty that's
correct
and
uh yeah but
however our program is still running so
that's
incorrect I don't know what's going
on and uh remove this test code okay uh
this test
code remove
remove okay okay now let's copy or let's
stop this all
period about it okay now select
all and uh paste with our new
code Okay so
paste our new code so the input so you
see when the input small it works shift
enter uh oh that's why this
thing you know we don't have the
semicolon so it's generating a huge
output
there yeah yeah
possibly uh when you generate a huge
output
it can be very slow okay you don't want
to show
that
so okay so go to the top
select all paste actually select all
copy copy or select or paste let's break
them into sections
okay so the above is all the definition
shift enter run it
[Music]
then
period now let's say
three can you have a period period
seven so this period is 74 this small
board for this small
input huh so period is seven okay it's
good to know
then shift control D split that then
this this is a final board
configuration then shift enter total is
6 C4 okay but now if we try this user
input okay now this we try this user
input okay that's good that's good let's
good go
down okay
shift enter okay now let's be careful
let's see what is a
period we it run
forever no it should stop at at least
100 times
so uh it should
stop you know in it you know no more
than 20 seconds
because we are trying to find the
nextest
period of the F1 cycle function nesting
it no more
than 1,000
times so the time we'll take is no more
than nesting F1 cycle 1,000
times now
this Matrix is just one 100 by 100 so it
shouldn't uh
take that long
okay okay this this video
is bad nobody's
watching uh
yeah we got a problem yeah it's so bad
this F1 cycle nesting is got a
problem
[Music]
so so where is our
problem Nest while okay Nest
while let's see in the test
function I'm not see why should there be
a problem
X getness is
period I don't
know oh period to stop it now close wam
language let's start from the ground
up okay so yeah so Tidings close don't
save
next this close tying don't
save and
uh close okay let's start a
fresh maybe
possibly we have some you know some
trash in our
memory so contrl n to open a new enter
three then shift enter to eval
valuated
magnify
now copy
all
paste and now go to the
top okay now
actually we want
to this
input okay then remove that copy all
select or
paste
now now let's
go uh this is our code now
let's split
here evaluate create all the functions
and
input
now
split okay now let's test period maximum
of 10 okay let's see that should return
something come on Max of 10 times okay
that's not returning that means
something is wrong
something is wrong with the get Nest
period okay
so max n least why is
it so did we get Nest
while incorrect or something
yeah so that is wrong
there just 10 times why can't you stop
just 10
times and we need to
debug still present
zagd solving problems others wish not to
is a reliable method of
learning yeah
okay
so uh this today's talk show is no
good uh
[Music]
because well when you do a
YouTube it's a good video if it's
interesting all the
way but
today we
struggled most of the time it's like
just
nothing no result to show
no aha moment you know it's kind of
boring for an hour for now two
hours uh so it's not good maybe I I
should delete
it hello rodolph
nonsense Okay so
yeah but as far as coding you know like
you know real life coding is just like
this like usually half a day you just
sit by yourself and uh scratch your
heads uh but I'm not happy
because I'm not happy because I've been
coding you know I mean like this Advent
of code I should be considered trivial
I've been coding for so many years and
now you know it's not going anywhere so
anyway so to solve
this oh God I don't really want to so
right now we just stuck on
this get Nest period it's not
stopping that means something is wrong
okay and we look at our code the maximum
nesting you
know it's only 10 but it's still running
so something is
wrong um so we need to debug this
okay you know you can add print
statement but you know why why is
it even just for 10 things okay so let's
stop it out
period so what so what you going to
debug so you're going to
print let's do this let's every time you
every time you call the test function
you're going to print it out
okay so every time the test function is
called then you print okay
wait yeah so you print the result you
know
you print
that so every time this test is called
you print the result so it's just going
to print a lot
though well yeah but okay so you need to
let's
try this definition
you're going to solve this step by step
okay done now we go back here instead of
Max times 10 let's just say
three okay because potentially it's
going
to do a lot of things okay con uh shift
and let's say three okay shift
enter and it's not even printing okay
something else is
wrong did we get the syntax right F1
cycle Matrix
3 something okay something is totally
wrong wait but uh but for the small
input it works okay something is wrong I
don't know can oh period to stop it
maybe something really Cy okay shift
control d to split this and now let's
make
this run okay let's next 10
times shift enter do
it so F1 cycle 10 times come on 10 times
is so
small it's stuck okay old period stop
it let's say one time this just what the
is going on shift
enter so even one time it's
stuck
stop okay something wrong with your F1
cycle okay let's just try the F1
cycle uh before we do that comment this
out okay
can you actually uh do we actually have
the X Matrix well defined shift enter
yeah yeah that should that is right okay
it's a big
one no
problem okay we have the Matrix defined
then
F1 cycle Matrix right F1 cycle means row
northwest southeast shift
enter okay here's a problem even running
one cycle it's like
stuck
wow wow
wow that means our pattern matching code
is
that so we got a fundamental
problem all pattern matching
code
what uh this is really
embarrassing even running one cycle you
see the f one cycle is defined to be a
function that you just apply move north
move west move South move
East very
simple but now even running just one
cycle is taking taking more than 10 or
seconds so a problem we got problems
so that's not good so old period to stop
it yeah so next step to deburg is let's
call the move
west you know I cannot
believe I don't believe it
that you know even even even the move a
simple move is got a problem so let's
say
Matrix shift enter move
west okay it's stuck okay now I feel
better
because if this function is stuck that
means the problem is not my code it must
be we for got
to like did
we we forgot to
like wait can this actually take that
long for pattern
matching wow I can't just believe it
let's Okay we don't know let's
say what is our
Matrix
right so okay that's the
matrix dimensions
100 by 100 correct okay now let's see
what exactly is all the items okay let's
magnify okay now take the first element
shift enter okay that's the first row
now contrl
L then you take
the take the first element then take the
first element okay that's a pound sign
that should be a
string okay and uh okay then you
querry post fix notation by the function
string
Q okay you ask if it's a string yes okay
so that means the first
row the first element of the first row
this pound sign is a string
correct now what about the first row but
the second element the dot it's also a
string control shift let's see
it shift enter yes so we do have a
matrix this is 100 by 100 Matrix and
each element is a string
check so so far so good yes
but but this move west function is
failing a simple function such as such
as you know
this simple function is let's say
question
mark
enter there it is our function a simple
function is failing on this
Matrix cannot possibly be let's
try Okay shift
enter now how can this be
this this Matrix is just 100 by
100 and uh this
pattern now it's possible you see
because because pattern matching the wam
language is so powerful such that you
can get you can easily get into
combinatorial exponential
issues uh but in our case you know we
just have a
head on a 100 by 100 Matrix I don't
think
so you see even this move
west it's not returning
now this means all the past days we
tried all this you know this elegant
solution it's not
working even for even for just a 100 by
100 Matrix so this is
very discouraging and
embarrassment godon
law talk
show what non sense talk show okay L
most
unfortunate yeah
so you see it's still not returning we
got something really really basic that's
wrong so right now we don't know
why but our function move west it was
working before okay let's try okay let's
stop stop this now you if we redefine
The Matrix to be the small one
again okay copy
it redefine The Matrix to be just just a
small
one uh shift enter okay then
we then we need to turn it into a
matrix okay so here's a code turn into a
matrix do it sh shift enter okay got the
Matrix now we do this move
again move west shift
enter the result is
instantaneous oh God so what what is the
problem is it is it possible I have a
typo
somewhere no no okay so
wait it's it's all capital O and
uh right did we it seems all
good so is there a sheer
possibility that
you know something we haven't considered
when you move all the o to the
left you run into a infinite
recursion that is why yeah that's Al
very likely so that is why your pattern
matching your my all pattern matching is
possibly running into a infinite
recursion because we are saying replace
repeat it ah
uh but we move to the
left why should
be oh God in the beginning we have zero
or more
head that's that must
be that must be the problem so so you
got you code replace repeated start by a
head zero or more items then you have a
pattern of all dots then you have a
pattern of all zeros or oos and
then then that then you replace okay so
when you have this pattern when the
beginning is zero or more
okay zero or
more okay no it's too bad we run into
this problem so so for this problem yeah
we run into this very basic problem but
it's also a clear Problem by itself you
know simple independent problem
you know with this Matrix just 100 by
100 our function move west is not
working it's taking
forever and the reason is
likely this replace repeated this
pattern this
just repeats forever but why is
that pattern so this pattern is one or
more not zero or
more so one or more dot followed by one
or more
o okay so at least there's always one
dot followed by one
o when you found that you swap them okay
that's the move
west okay
so yeah and then
okay so whatever head is zero or more
items okay so let's look at one example
this is a long row 100
items so
you you swap
swap So eventually every time you swap
eventually you should you'll find
that it's no longer the case you have a
situation where you have at least one
dot followed
by one
zero because you you you swap them all
so it should not be
infinite I don't understand but
let's you know maybe I'm wrong so let's
maybe try let's red find
this this is a very nasty
problem
uh so if we redefine our function to
be wait so right now what is our Matrix
Matrix Dimension shift enter so 10 10
now let's get back
this
okay okay so you need to get back the
The Matrix okay so let's get the Matrix
let's put the input here this is one
input then the second
input this is the user
input
okay so if we evaluate that so that's a
user input then turn into a matrix and
that
okay paste
okay then now let's check our Matrix run
it that's too big
okay
cut delete so let's just check the
dimension 100 by 100 okay and uh remove
that you know we we we have already
checked these so we don't need to check
them
so we now got the 100 by 100
Matrix now we want
to move
west okay and uh okay so hold on a
second let cut
that let's paste it here Define the
function move west okay shift
enter now if we run this
it will run
forever shift
enter yeah it runs
forever okay meanwhile let's clean up
this uh and let's clean up
this okay it runs forever no good so all
period to stop it now let's change the
definition of
this so that may
maybe so we can so that you know we we
we find out what possibly maybe you know
there's something
wrong so we are instead of longest let's
let's don't do the longest okay and
remove the
longest
okay so copy
that paste it
now evaluate this part so now it's a new
function different move west now let's
run the move with shift
enter okay I think something is wrong um
rather disappointing
because you see so right now we narrow
down to a very clean problem you know
this function is
not correct for some reason because it's
running
forever so it's running forever likely
means this replace repeated is running
forever
um so
that but it should not because when you
have a board you know you you simply
move all all the o to the left
nothing else you simply move all the o
to the
left okay so I
mean so the problem should not repeat
forever so unless maybe our
pattern for some
reason this pattern zero or
more it changes is to
that dots and balls wait dots and balls
balls and dots
so it shouldn't repeat
forever there's no way there is no
way so very interesting you know so we
have a hard Clash
you know because this problem now is so
simple I mean this Matrix is not too big
only 100 by
100 because in real life you might have
like 1,000
so uh million
rows so
but I don't think this pattern repeats
forever but that's what we get so next
step is actually just start to look at
this
pattern yeah very annoying okay
oh start to cancel it so next step is
you know we just look at the pattern
itself so new wolm language
code uh I want to take a
break okay so anyway new wolam language
code move South move East wait so move
west
right okay copy that put this back go
here close that go here paste okay
now instead of a function let's simply
try the pattern
okay delete that delete that so here's a
heart of the function replace repeat it
so in fact we just say replace all don't
repeat once we do it one step at a
time okay so this way
okay tell me what possibly where does it
go wrong you know so we can actually see
it this one this is to the replacement
one step at a time okay cannot possibly
go wrong this pattern matching you know
we start with the Matrix we replace
all of this pattern
by
this okay shift enter you cannot
possibly go wrong now this is one single
replacement okay
okay it
returns it returns but it takes a long
time
so that
[Music]
means okay I think maybe I need a yeah
good good so let's try to do some
improvements okay zero or more let's
say perhaps this head is the problems so
let's look at our Matrix the first row
okay the first row is pound dot dot dot
pound dot dot dot
o okay now go back to our the new uh
result our
result our result pound do do do pound
do o what no no
change
what pound dot dot dot pound dot dot dot
o what the F this is
pound dot dot dot pound dot dot do
o okay but it uh so seems like it didn't
change anything at
all I don't understand so now let's try
just the first row okay
so let's try
this
now X
Matrix the first row okay let's have a
look that's that now let's move
west the first row only do
it takes a while you see it
worked wait
pound do dot dot pound o so it worked
but
however is see however if
you do not
specify the first
element but after you did that then you
say you want the first
row shift enter do it then it takes long
long
time this is a problem so the problem is
indeed our
pattern our pattern is very
inefficient very inefficient so that is
you know that that is actually the you
know uh major
issue when you use pattern matching in
wolam
language because it's hard to
determine when your pattern is efficient
or not you see this this move west one
single time wait uh wait we don't want
to move
west yeah anyway so anyway so the W move
west one single times takes
forever now I kind of
know why because you are
doing
yeah okay so this is even taking forever
so what you want to do is that
you don't want to replace all okay
so yeah God I think I need to
stop okay failed today I think I'm going
to stop failed today then I'm going to
delete the video
okay bad video I mean otherwise you have
so many EX videos that's just too long
and boring
okay so thank you guys for watch
watching I'm going to delete the video
and uh this is actually an interesting
problem and in fact it's right now it
becomes a very interesting technical
technicality about pattern matching in
wolam language because we have narrowed
down
to you know using p mat on this and we
we we run into you know the efficiency
issues even running a single
time you see by now it's taking like and
even just move all the balls to the West
it's taking
like probably
exponentially hard to imagine though I
mean that this is a
surprise it came up
for the episode thank you for the
episode yeah thank you uh where you from
zagd are you w I'm coder or are you just
interested in programming in
general uh yeah so if you want to answer
let me know oh it came out so it takes a
long time you see it takes like 30
second 1 minute it takes 1
minute simply to do to move all the
zeros to the
left of a 100 by 100
Matrix it takes a m like you know almost
seconds so but it did come out with a
result so it
means it means our algorithm is very
inefficient with this this this pattern
matching okay this
pattern uh you know this repeat repeat
so how to fix that I know I mean I do
have some ideas I have
some some uh intuition about what part
to change because okay there are like
there are there are like three things we
need to I need to go into okay so one
first of all is that you you want to try
to not use replace
repeated rather you want a
pattern that does it in one shot it
moves all the o to the left okay just
one shot no need to repeat and test if
it's you know still come out different
you know
so it is possible okay I think I'm 99%
not you know sure that it is
possible to remove this replace repeated
instead you just add like two or three
more patterns okay so that's one thing
that will significantly reduce the speed
increase efficiency now the other thing
is that we is that when when we use this
pattern you know this head something
zero or more then any dots then any boss
then tell this pattern is meant to match
a row okay but however when you use
replace or or or when you use replace
repeated it will try to match this
pattern with respect to the entire
Matrix 100 row by
100 uh
columns so so you so instead you know so
instead you want
to either introduce a pattern like you
know either introduce a
pattern
or you use a re you know a map a pattern
to all the
rows so that is possibly that can
possibly reduce the in
efficiency because otherwise wolam
language just try all the possibilities
you
know um yeah so anyway so that's two
things we can possibly fix the other
thing is that we could I could
try to remove this zero or more because
when when you whenever you have zero or
more
items that's
potentially exponential in time
because zero or more means you'll start
to try with zero items then you'll try
with one item then then you'll try with
two items you know until the end items
in a
row so you want to uh avoid this zero or
more pattern
so in order to avoid that you could have
a pattern where you know use a pattern
where you contains the pound side
because all the DOT and
O to the left of them needs to be a
pound sign okay either a pound sign or
the beginning of the
row so you put a pound sign here instead
of the
head somewhere okay you know that will
um possibly
reduce yeah you will I know for sure so
anyway interesting okay bye guys I need
to increase my mathematical capabilities
love today's video struggle upon
struggle just like in real life the
exact opposite of can YouTube explain us
okay should I like should I keep the
this video cuz I'm thinking of delet
deleting it maybe not because that's
real life you know so what do you
think uh let me know or let me know in
comments okay so anyway so we going to
say goodbye so we stuck you know bad
video
okay uh very interesting bye
guys keep it okay fantastic fantastic