good evening everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show and today we are
going to do Emacs and Emacs these
fantastic Emacs and eMac this hello guys
and hello beautiful people
hello beautiful people and good morning
George emily alyn so we got five people
watching so today's juice is apple and
cranberry and and grape so we're going
to do Emacs Lisp I'm going to show you
several commands Emacs commands custom
commands related to image manipulation
such as scale convert PNG to JPEG and
vice versa or resize images crop images
and things like that and we are also
going to code some eMac B's and I'm
going to explain how things work so
hello people hello then hello moe
damn Morris Day Morris where you from so
let let's get going okay let's stop
these concurrent Watchers Nye Nye is a
crowd three times a crowd so okay EEMA
Cleese sad Hawk show sad hop show and go
to this page of course today's talk show
topics first of all I like to thank John
Jeremy Bernhard I think I talked to that
name is familiar to me anyway John he's
a guy who I thank him for donation big
money big money
good morning Kathy so he is a guy who
created this bunch of keyboards butter
stick and and go
keyboard Georgie keyboard and Guinea
keyboard from G industries so we talked
about we did a video on that yesterday
so thank him for sponsoring the show in
other words and so that's one thing and
let's see what's the next thing so we're
gonna do eMac list yes that's so that's
let's begin okay shall we let me check
the comments a bit quick ASM cow okay
let's try that
melodious no is melodious melodious
noise that's right
well I'm going to do a show and and I'm
going to teach you guys how to do eMac
peas okay so ASMR and just in tithing
you max to feel inside stream in chat
that's fantastic okay hold on a second
give me just one second and this I need
to replace my glasses
these glasses got a scratch on it ASMR
so I'm going to put you guys to sleep in
the most pleasant way and we are going
to start now and shall we begin so Allen
says melodious melodious voice does not
need your super fancy as ASMR microphone
that is correct and it carries over the
airway with fine horrible quality not
super annoying clicks or anything yeah
yeah I need to buy us good microphone so
buy me a microphone so let's see what
else and we are going to start for those
of you impatient and you are going to
learn Emacs Lisp in no time you are
going to be a expert
this is already becoming a routine has
anyone tried SMI live programming this
could be exhausted to 1 million
subscribers that's that that that is
good that that that that is good ok
let's begin record your hands doing
Suffolk he is renting yeah text on blog
okay so let's begin
so Emacs the power of Emacs the greatest
editors guys if you are using Emacs you
are using the greatest editor on earth
and if you are not you might give it a
shot
a shot because all the greatest
programmers are Emacs users ok so let's
go to key words let's begin let's begin
five minutes
introduction and we go to keyboards we
go to keyboard blog so today it's going
to be focused on Emacs first so the
first stop is the first stop is damaged
do some demonstration of how I working
on my blog for the powers of Emacs using
all the powers of Emacs into the
internet and new people in the
open-source contributors so on the left
window you can see all the Emacs
commands I call such as moving cruisers
and so on so the first thing I need to
do is to fix this image you see this is
Microsoft trackball Explorer and people
has created a do-it-yourself version ok
so i'm but i learned from jeremy that
this is actually a product you can buy
so you can go and buy it but but now I
know it's a product it doesn't belong on
this page so this page is about
Microsoft trackball Explorer
it's about trackball history so I need
to create a new page
- to properly showcase these
do-it-yourself product okay so go to go
to this page and you can see that's sure
the image oh that's not the page so
trackball mouse trackball Mouse who is
it Microsoft okay trackball they are
here so it's this page showing browser
correct go back here go to the bottom
and do itself so cut cut cut closed save
and back on the keyboard page paste it
showing browser you can see I have moved
the images here now I need to create a
new page so what is this first of all
what is what should be the page named it
should be named as the name of the
product name and the product name is
ploopy PL o o py I believe okay so if
you guys have any questions Corrections
comments opinions flood the chat channel
ok flow the chat box so where is roofie
okay here it is now I don't want some
secondhand website I want the original
website but so it's one of these ok but
actually them let's go to here and
keyboard and Jeremy has posted has
alerted to me the situation this by the
way this keyboard we are going also
going to do today so let me move on fast
okay so Emacs stuff
Emacs stuff so let's go to John ok so he
says wait it's not this one there's
there's many messages I haven't read yet
today and that is Allen's tech
of pressing the control key on the
laptop but okay so did so I'm going to
focus on Emacs okay so let's go to there
so he says okay so this true picot okay
this website requires JavaScript so
let's turn it on so the word will be a
little bit of face and copy the URL we
see that's their website that's
fantastic
we are not going to are go edit for the
moment because we are going to focus on
Emacs stuff so here's a website link
off' i it okay i need to magnify my my
font so before we do that let me take
one minute to magnify my fonts tracking
seconds copy that paste it here magnify
this is the line okay sorry max this mod
magnify this is the line we need to
change middle 14 now manual 15 avow the
code now everything is bigger that's
good that is good so close that save no
codes no safe okay now we have this you
can see we have this website link there
so this is called poopy so let's call it
PL o py track 4 okay and we are going to
create a new HTML page so let's do it
fast it's our new page okay that creates
a web page and you can see we I got all
the templates and stuff ready so close
that now all I have to do is cut cut cut
cut cut everything and open this file
again paste it here
refresh now you can see I have
created a page with the proper product
and photo now let's change the title
because it needs to be the title needs
to be needs to be capitalized proofy
trackball yeah okay so let's name it
prove he trampled and remove this line
and this URL will be where to buy okay
where to hold on a second okay where to
buy now I want to capitalize the
sentence sentence capitalization so
press a key and it's done you see that
command is called sarted okay's region
or line this one by the way all the
commands you see here most vast majority
of them are on my website so all you
have to do is find out the command I
call on the left window and you just do
a google search web search and you'll
find the code then you can put this in
your unit and you will have the same
power now back to Emacs now I have
created this title where to buy make it
h2 title and make this a paragraph so
you go back to browser you can see there
we have it basically I have just created
the page of these this product on my
blog and the second photo should be on
top so showing browser again because the
second I mean this this photo is kind of
you know it is it's got multiple number
of them so so now what we need to do is
we need to okay let me show you some let
me begin to show some of the commands to
manipulate the images so for example on
this page if you go to my keyboard blog
close that okay
showing browser
okay this photo needs to be changed
because this icon now belongs to this
URL not the Microsoft wrapper Explorer
so let's just delete that line go here
capitalize the sentence okay let me show
you okay capitalize the sentence then
then paste it here they make a dive
that's good
showing browser you see now this is good
now I need to create a section like like
that and let's do it so cut that code
the command okay so let's do it again
I want to show the window on the left so
cut that make a section with today's
date and paste that showing browser now
that is Papa okay as far as this one we
need to put back a icon of that page you
know that page also has an icon and we
can do that by going to trackball and
trackball history
copy the URL you can see that one is
there so I copy the URL now I call
command
this command is Excel open file from
clipboard so it will just open this page
and I search for Microsoft rap or
Explorer copy copy that file
I mean copy that text block close it now
go to the Microsoft section basically
paste it and delete that and show in
browser let's go down now you can see
that is Papa now now since we removed
those images from the Microsoft page we
need to put a link to the icon to for
the link to the new page so people when
people browse in the Mac
of trackball explore oh they can see Oh
someone created a do-it-yourself version
I need to go buy it so that information
is available to them there for me back
to Emacs copy this section open the
trackball explore page go to the bottom
and here paste it and do-it-yourself
version ok I'm not sure that's a proper
name you know when you write a blog they
are all these little details like naming
of the title how you should worded style
and all that but I'm going to worry
about that later when I'm offline so
right now let's let me focus push on the
Emacs commands so now anyway so you can
see so people can go through that page
okay so to yourself version what should
I name it through P okay okay yeah yeah
let's just say that for now okay close
it close it go to the blog again and
prepare Apple okay for now I think this
will be it for the page of course I'm
going to work on it right a lot details
like where does this come from how much
it causing you give some general
annotations about this thing these
fantastic thing okay so that will be it
for this page now close that close that
reopen close that I need clothes that I
need to go to the now there's one more
thing okay I'm kind of sidetracked track
a little bit to how I walk on my blogs
but I wanted to focus on Emacs commands
that manipulate images we'll get to that
in a bit
but I'm a bit
you know doing all this explainations I
have to explain what am i doing because
otherwise you may not know what I'm
doing because otherwise you just see me
punching keyboards so what I want to do
is actually the way you see I need to
put this here show in browser you see I
say it says to do putting like put to
index page because that means I need to
put that icon into one of these index
pages so people can find it otherwise
you're just going to have hundreds of
blog articles buried somewhere you know
after a few days you know the blog
entries goes off so you need to put it
on index page somewhere organization
that part is in fact the most difficult
part when you are writing a blog and
when you want the blog to be popular
because from vast majority of people
when you write a blog you just create a
page in a score of next month by next
month nobody will read it so it's kind
of the difference that's one of the
major difference between a blog and
between a website such as Wikipedia so
this organization part is actually
tremendous takes tremendous time ok so
that's a bit rambling of topic thing
about things so we are going to continue
we are going to start to do the Emacs
commands thing so let me take a moment
to read the comments
Tempe so far so good we've been to in 20
minutes we have a lot to do actually so
far so good guys
anyone want to be Betty Sun turns on
JavaScript doing his stream yes hot girl
hi hot girl I see why they copy
Microsoft yes and auto good morning
although now some of you guys I remember
but but not too much I vaguely remember
sorry about that because I do I do write
blog so I don't I don't remember
everyone always yeah so you know Google
censored that line is how incredible it
is you know sure okay so far so good so
no questions so that means I'm doing a
good job and thank you guys for
listening okay so let's go back to Emacs
and let's get on to the main topic where
I'm going to modify this page and we are
going to do a lot image editing on this
page okay so actually there's a lot to
do so open such Kiwi such so let's open
this page and we are going to open some
of the images okay so let me start to
show you some of the commands that I use
for images so let's how we do that okay
so
so that is energy drink now tea
okay we are going to do Emacs commands
to manipulate images let's see how I
want to go about this okay let's let's
begin let's begin to do it so open this
image now I don't let's I don't want
this image okay I'm just going go ahead
and do lots of things let's say I don't
want this image anymore so I call
command I press three geez
that's Scotty lead current file so that
fire is now good you see you won't see
it anymore it's gotten so deleted so
delete that page to open this delete
okay and delete that paragraph open this
delete delete a paragraph open this this
is a huge image okay press a key to
magnify in fact you cannot see so much
because it's a huge image but now I
I call this command it opens in preview
this works in Linux on windows on
Microsoft - he'll open whatever your
image viewer so we saw that we don't
want it delete it
okay so so by the way that command is
opening external app and okay so what
about this image it's big okay so let's
open in preview opening external okay
let's keep this one let's say okay
showing browser now I have you see what
I'm trying to do is I'm going to I'm out
of a modern if modifying this page and
you know to walk towards the way I
wanted reviews and information and were
part of the important thing is to get
the images collect the images and make
them attractive for example and make
them the right size you don't want for
example you don't want a for example
this image right now is humongous four
thousand pick
so spy 3,000 pixels you can see if I
enlarge the browser you know it's it's
it's it's kind of bigger than my screen
so some people are you are on the phone
you know they don't need this huge image
so you need to do you need to get them
to the right size so we are working in
HTML and you know we work with HTML so
for example so this did this image for
example I like to keep I you know I like
to keep so people can see it's great and
and the one thing so right now it's too
big so it's 400 pixels okay so I want to
resize it let's say I want to first
usually I look at the image okay so this
reside resized by 40% okay so I can call
command let me show you okay so I open
this file go to tired this is the file
but before we do anything let's delete
the other backup files we don't need so
select them
press ok delete yes delete no it's clear
so so back to this image go to tired
here that's the image now I want to
resize them let's say 40% so I call
command that's not tired scale image you
can see on the left window so now it's
asked me for a scale let's say 40 okay
do I want to sharpen it yes
okay success so this is the new image
you can see the drastic difference in
file size 10 times smaller so now I open
this that looks good okay that looks
good now I copy the file path close it
close it close it now I paste it here
link off' i
and that's an image you see I press the
enter you can see that image and for the
big one let's show in browser first so
showing browsers so we got two of them
they look the same but actually the
second one is three times speaker like
almost two times speaker so we need to
remove the second one so what what I do
is I want to copy the file path cut DVDs
line okay let me do it again show the
command window so copy this file path
cut DVDs line then go back here paste
then coal command that command is called
a HTML full sized image liquify so that
will create this link so now if I show
him browser you can see that is how I
get people to look at the big image if
they want they can click on that then
they can see the big thing okay so that
is one of the commands I want to show
about about the resize so where is that
scale
okay scale saw tired scale image now if
use web search you can see the code let
me show you the code so use web search
like you can just search for sorry
Emacs scale image so here is the page
and you can see I have actually quite
several of them and we are going to use
almost half of them today we just begin
we just used one of them
so that's scale image that's one of them
you can just copy this putting your
Emacs in it and you will have it too and
you do need the Linux command image
magic okay you do need that command
installed so imagemagick
is a command-line utility that
manipulate images okay actually let me
show you that image magic you need that
installed so keyboard program in general
so so yeah so this is the discord join
my discord okay you can find a link just
by searching for sorry discord now let
me show you sorry
image magic okay
so that is my imagemagick to tobio
imagemagick is a command-line utility
that lets you to convert jpg to be a PNG
or vice versa or scale crop or change
color or transparency or reduce color or
crop images sharpen blue things like
that or by a command or by a command so
you can see you can go to this page and
you know learn it if you are not
familiar with so let's go to Chris our
talk show and let's put that link here
so we have a record of it show in
browser there it is
close back to Emacs close back to
browser copy the URL back to Emacs and
reopen this one I also want to place
this link here so you can showing
browsers so there is my Emacs code so
close close back to Emacs close close
and we are back to this page okay that's
that's one of the command on the Korea
keyboard now this image I don't want for
this image for this page I don't want
all these thing on the background so I
want to crop it so the way I do that is
you
so you actually open the full sized
image you go to Safari and we are going
to crop it so we're gonna cut it like
that but before we do so go back to
Emacs press a key it makes a backup so
in case I want to go back to that so
that command is Samak back up and save
you can find on my website
so now back to the preview the Mack
image editor a simple one so press
control press press command K to crop it
so this is what I want yes there we have
it so this is you know just focus on the
keyboard so close that so go back to
Emacs wait for a second it will refresh
so now we got this image now it's still
too big you know the size is too big so
we're gonna shrink it again so go to
tired here is the file and let's make
let's call the command again so so
here's a file I call the command and
let's type a scale let's say 40 40 okay
40 sharpen yes so it creates a new file
this one so copy the file path close
close close and now go back here paste
it here and link a file now the linker
file command is this one saw HTML image
link a file you if you want that you
have to find it inside tml mod just such
that you will find it he'd seen that
code so now let's show in browser again
so here is our old image here is new we
don't need the old one anymore so open
it delete it and delete the line showing
browser fantastic back to Emacs and for
this image let's see you know close it
okay so I'm wondering okay anyway let's
I'm not going it's not worry about the
details because I'm going to walk on it
how I want my blocks to be but right now
let's just focus on the Emacs stuff so
this image you see the name
that's that - s - s at the end that's no
good
I just want one s so I call a command
press okey
he asked me a new file name so I just
say - yes enter so what this - is that
it will change the file name on disk but
you don't have to go to tire and do that
you just directly working in the HTML so
showing browsers so we got the same
image but the name actually changed so
the link you know everything in one step
so that command is renamed okay so let's
see if I have it here let's see yeah
this is the command we just caught side
Gmail rename source file path and you
can also find that in my excited here
mail dot DL Emacs package on kid on
github so we have done several things
now so Kathy says I wonder how he
managed passwords with dr. ko maybe with
tools like key pass now I don't I don't
I don't use I don't have a count on dr.
ko I just you know you don't need to
create or calm okay so I need to get in
touch with the people here so you guys
how is it going am i doing good
am i doing okay is this the right topic
any comments so we are going to continue
with Emacs list and Emily are you still
here okay let's continue the comments
Emily Emily is a big Emacs user and Alan
is a wimp
I mean evil Mart user right
for UAC on yes bruh
bah la playa very calming hi George
I'm hi ASF what does ask of me okay
let's get back to Emacs so now what is
the next thing okay so what is the next
thing so Cathy am i doing good
anything anything any anything
interesting
posting a chat ok so so we have created
this page we have modified we have
scaled it let's see what else we are
going to do okay let's just just keep
walking on this page now let's go to
discord and he has showed me several new
pages new things it's and I want to use
them several new images this guy who
created that keyboard P via keyboard so
he has created several images we have
used one of them but this this is the
one actually we want I deleted them
before because I started to work on this
page but I want to redo them so I can
show you guys how this work this is a
good example how I use this image
commands so Alan says do you usually
keep archives of full-size original
images no not usually no although these
days I try you know sometimes I do
because they you know images especially
today they get huge very fast when you
have hundreds image it's like right now
Mike sorry Don info is one chica bites
I know chica by one chica by doesn't
sound too much but I I kind of still
live in the 1991
20 megabyte hard disk error 40 megabyte
is the standard hard disk so Mike sorry
info website I tried to keep the image
you know the file size minimal like this
obsession about that but as time goes on
you know the file size they just get
bigger and bigger especially videos
right so but images to today one image
is 500 500 kilobytes or 1 megabyte you
know anyways so for example let's save
this one I want I want this image so
let's save it lets continuing with Emacs
so save it so I'm going to show you
another commands ok so I'm going to save
it starting with the name EE you will
you will you will see why do I do that
in a moment moment ok I talked about
this before
so anyway save it to the download
directory okay now close it now I
possess that image now I go to Emacs go
to Emacs showing browser and I want to
this is very useful for those of you
writing blocks because when you write a
blog you have many photos on the online
you want to grab them you know with with
credit credit you know you've if that
applies so you want to show in your blog
so so in now I saved in my download
folder so typically you go to the
download folder you you try to rename
the image sometimes if you you know
sometimes you want to do that then you
try to move the image file path to your
blog's directory then you create a HTML
to link to it tedious to tedious okay so
I have one command that I call right now
it will grab whatever images in my
desktop directory in my screenshot
directory in my home directory or in my
download directory any any directory you
can specify or document directory any so
any file there if
their name begin with EE then it will
automatically move it to the current
directory my buffer is in you will see
ok so let's call that command so we're
going to call I'm just going to press
two keys so there it is you can see on
the left it says some move image file
that is a command name and that command
is also on my website so you can get a
code so he asked me a directory so I say
I go okay I want to put that in this
directory so press Enter
yes confirm then he asked me for a name
so I'm going to rename it
this is Kiwi keyboard okay and okay
there's a date that's okay so there is a
name at the mini pava you can see at the
bottom so that's the name I want enter
back there you go so it by calling this
command it automatically generates this
nice link for me with for example with
the figure tag for the image tag with
the width and hate automatically created
for you and also the old tag attribute
and also figure caption and caption
based off from the image name so it's
all very nice now let's show in browser
so let's see what it looks like there we
have it so so that is a very useful
command if you write blocks and again
that command is called
za move move image fire oh my god these
commands they fly by very fast so you
have to so far so good
so far so good so quadcore says these
knobs would be better near thumbs in my
humble opinion
yeah that's impossibly so well back then
our images had 2256 colors
yes snobby Navi is from the dinosaur era
2256 colors that's full color back in
1991 and you have to buy a the most
cutting-edge monitor for that with was a
$2,000 Apple RGB monitor it can display
256 colors so anyway so we back on this
and so again I need to crop this image
so okay let me show you several more
commands so by this rate okay hold on
second by this rate I'm not going to get
into the part where I want to modify the
emag Lisp code so it's already 40
minutes very time consuming to do this
technical stuff so anyway so let me show
you some more commands okay so I open
this again so showing external app I
want to crop it now there are several
things I want to do I want to crop it so
remove the background also I want to
crop it so that I show I have image of
just the right hand I think I'll use
that for the primary photo for this page
the icon possibly I don't know because
when you work on blog you don't know for
sure until you do and look so first of
all first of all let's make a backup
copy of this image and make another
backup of this image so that's a command
make backup and save okay now go to diet
refresh you can see you can see these
three lines you know one is the full
version and the other two are the backup
images backup copy so let's show let me
show you this okay let's say shrink a
little bit so you can actually see so
I'm going to press a key that is tired
toggle read-only so now I can start to
rename the file rename my backups rename
my backup so let's say let's call this
one crop and let's call this one right
hand okay I'm done ctrl c ctrl C now I'm
done so so Emacs renamed you know you
can rename file that way very powerful
command so entired you call you that
that command is Targo where is it tired
toggle read-only that is a command oh
you can also call w tired anyway just
just call this toggle read-only because
that's universal you can call that
command in any buffer that will lock the
file to make it read only and you can
toggle so anyway we have created you
know two copies of the same image so
let's so so what we do now okay so go to
the dad go to the crop version open it
okay before we do that you see the
filenames they are named with a space
okay let's magnify now I want to rename
them so that it uses underscore instead
so I have this command I just press a
key now look now watch this file and
this file okay okay let me shrink okay
so let me
I mean try to do these okay so here so
where you are May so this file in this
file
space to underscore so so watch press
okey then okay press the key again done
so what that does you can see now the
names with underscore and that command
is saw diet rename space to underscore
okay let's it's it's here that is also
on my website so that command allows you
to allows you to rename files from space
replace our space by under scope by just
pressing your key which is extremely
convenient because otherwise you would
target iured read then you you you have
to do find replace for every files then
you have to commit then toggle back you
know so so this single key is very
convenient so anyway so now we have wait
wait do we have it yeah so now we have
this crop version again show in image
editor in your local oh s image editor
so let's crop it in preview on a Mac so
let's make that that okay
crop that's what we want close it back
to Emacs close it and also same thing
for the right hand so open opening
external app and for this one I just
want the right hand
okay co-op it that's good
close it that's good backing Emax copy
the file path close it close it close it
open that close it so paste it here
actually paste it here magnify and open
it go to diet again copy the right hand
version close it that is the right hand
version actually so open that go to diet
copy the cop file path close it close it
paste the cop file path here actually
paste it below it here and make link so
that so now we're showing browser we're
gonna do this quickly because these are
our things to do I haven't get to yet so
okay no comments so MSU are doing good
okay so so let's do to do this this is
the picture for the right hand is it
good sighs yeah that's that's good sighs
okay so let's see this cropped version
okay
and let's see the full version the full
version we don't yeah it's got a
background we don't need anymore so open
it make a backup deleted dear it is
block and show in browser
okay so I guess that just kind of
covered several of the image commands
actually I have a lot too
- yet I haven't get to the one I wanted
to show but but now I want to rename
these okay because the name right now
it's no good right hand well okay so
let's just leave it be leave it for now
let's get onto some other things I want
to show so now I have this now I need to
make an icon to represent this page and
the image I want to use will be okay let
let me ask you guys should I use the
first picture image for the icon or the
second one both hands so let me know and
like I wait for your hands the first
image for the icon or the second which
one do you think is better for index
file for example you know like that
let's go to do it yourself so first or
second so you know I need to make an
icon like that
q yeah so I don't have qu here so what
do you think what do you guys think
first looks nice okay let's go with
first George did you change your profile
photo on YouTube okay so let's do first
yes that's a good idea because the first
image is more squarish so so let me so
I'm going to show you another command so
I need to I need to kind of resize this
image now I have you know let's let me
show you so I have a resize command
you've seen before for example let me do
it again so I open it go to diet so this
is the image so I want to resize so I
call the command satires scale so tired
scale image so I type a percentage let's
say 40 okay sharpen yes okay so now it
creates you know it's still too big so
let's do it again delete that refresh
oops so this is image go to diet now I
call scale image let's say 20 20 percent
okay sharpen so now we have okay that
looks right okay but I don't want that
because too many steps tedious tedious
I don't want tediousness I'm using Emacs
4 for Emacs users you can remove
tediousness necess so so what I do is I
want to you see I want to icon of these
so no worry so I want an icon of this
being this image okay so I just call
command a new command now look on the
left window you'll see the name so I
just do it so that name is Sal create
thumbnail image now at mini buffer you
ask me which so 250 is the one I use so
250 with okay pixels so enter there it
is so what it does is it scared a the
image on disk meanwhile it all
create the link to the newly created
icon so that is this one that is this
path so for example I can open it
perfect you know unlike before where I
have to go to diet I have to call the
command to scale the image but then I
don't know how + what percentage to make
it proper you know so I have to maybe
try once or twice but now with this
command it's just one key press so I
have an image here copy the path close
this file
yes close it okay and paste the path
here so you can see here is an image but
hold on a second let me that's showing
this in browser so you scroll down you
can see the kiria okay let's you know
that's that's the old image I'm using so
now we have a new image paste it here
make a link that's that command is sight
female image link vise so it's a link
cut it then move here paste it here then
go to browser refresh now now that's
better
let's pick that you know that I think
the the left picture is better than the
right one so this the creator of this
keyboard is so nice to supply my you
know to give me new images but I think
the left one the issue is that you know
it's a white keyboard on a white
background so it's it doesn't stand out
on the other hand the the left one is
you know kind of more bored but
meanwhile the background is also black
so I you know but it works it kind of
works because then you have the neon
light that that makes a contrast with
the background so this so the left is
better so the right we don't need any
more so
ladies this one press a key to delete it
remove that press a make a break show in
browser go back go down go down go down
there it is we have it so now we have
these I'm kind of done so Oh almost
depends on what you guys think okay so I
kind of done for today I mean that's the
that's the main commands I want to show
the Emacs commands format manipulating
images so what do you guys think any
comments posted any comments questions
and so on and I was thinking to start to
code eMac beasts because there are some
some extra niceties I like to have so if
you guys are I want to you know watch
that let me know so you know so that's
going to be eMac beast coding we are
going to start to look at the code for
all these commands I'd you know we just
showed
then we're gonna modify it and show you
how it works
okay so so far so good
yeah so let's see so now I have this now
I want to go to so actually delete this
entire thing delete delete delete and
remove the section I'm going to move it
to the top so go to the top of the page
search for sections so create a new
section paste the whole thing here
refresh in browser so now it shows on
the top now I need to put this icon in
the do itself index page right now it's
not there so so copy that text block
copy it
now go to do it you're open to it self
keyboard index open it go to the browser
let's see where do I want to put it the
Kiwi ax will be okay it will be
somewhere here so let's put it after
iris 54 so search for iris pays it here
so Kiwi our keyboard back to browser
refresh there we have it now I need to
put the key count because you can see
they are kind of arranged by how many
keys they have so open that key count
now we need to count the keys okay let's
read the comments let's see what you
guys are saying so close that let's see
how long have I been talkin Keowee our
keyboard general and okay so go to
google night people watching one more
hour so I think we stopped now we stop
two or three more minutes something like
that two minutes then we stop that's one
hour long good enough
first because it's more square like so
it might be better for index yes that's
true for the grid space it will be I
think you can see more yes
it used to be brown don't know why it
changed left is much more striking okay
yeah that's good
good judgment okay so that's it about
that's I think that's it for today
let's do random chat for two minutes
then we shut down okay random chat for
two minutes then we shut down so I think
this thief game you know thief game is
like okay thief game George
thief game you know George I was
thinking your your profile photo should
be like that I was kind of looking for
that anyway the thief game is I remember
you know when in 1998 1998 I was working
in a start-up and we have three
engineers counting me total of three
engineers that's my you know one one of
the startup brainpower calm so we have
engineers and he one of them is a gamer
so
thief is a game of that era 1998 and
when come out is like one big news
because oh the new graphics engine some
you know jargons graphics jargons you
know technology jargons where they have
shadow you know some kind of shadow or
with some some sort of light or whatever
and then thief is kind of supposedly a
different new innovation in
in 3d gaming because because supposedly
you know I don't know the game too much
but supposed to the back then you know
you have first-person shooters and
everyone is just shoot whatever you see
but thief is different where you you
don't just go and shoot things you are
actually but you try to be a like a
thief you try to quietly go about and
doing your things and then you have to
assess and people sometimes or something
like that so that's what I remember
about that Kim so this one Starcraft
okay Starcraft I don't know much about
that guy random okay so I think that's
it for today so close that frou-frou P
that's fantastic I'm going to read about
show
is there anything else so let's go to my
talk show page talk show show in browser
and this image is created by Alan this
fantastic image let's see QQ or demo
image commands demo all of them if
possible ok so next time maybe next day
we're gonna Kody Maggie's focus on that
green tea I'm drinking green tea so
green tea black tea oolong I'm drinking
green tea out of a teabag but you know
because because I think of the you know
there's a health green tea for some
reason same thing with red wine you know
because of the California people we are
health conscious and we are always
looking for the scientific technology
that tells us what to eat and what to
drink that can prolong our lives so
green tea has been famous because it has
certain you know chemical things that
whatever that supposed to be an
antioxidant something like that ok this
is some particular ingredients and that
this makes you live longer so that is
partially why I choose screen tea but
you know but that's you know but on
second thought that's ok so I
have been a victim of modern marketing
propaganda ok so but if you if I never
heard of you know the green tea is
beautiful
for your health then among tea I would
prefer Mulan ok ok I'm going to tell you
a little story my dad is actually a tea
merchant
so we actually make tea in Taiwan we go
to the mountains by by the tea Leafs
from the farmers okay then we bring home
then we bake them so so I was like from
10 to 14 when I left Taiwan so we I do
those kind of things t so so I would
prefer actually my preference would be
alone so so you have green tea green tea
is essentially unbaked tea
okay so you I guess you bake a little
bit but anyway green tea is like and
baked then you have along or kind of you
know several you know the tea is like
you know there's many complexities
playing where you you bake it then you
have cool own then you bake more then
you have talk you know like black heat
black tea or something like that so
anyway I I would I think prefer gulong
tea usually but anyway I'm drinking out
of teabags
this is cheap teabags when you drink tea
green tea especially green tea it it's
not good for your stomach okay actually
I can i you know you can feel it because
I think it's because what was it acid or
was it the opposite I forgot but anyway
so nobody you should drink especially
green tea if you drink tea you want to
drink it after me or something like that
but anyway in China and in Taiwan we
change in Japan we drink teas all the
time like geez our water we don't you
know we drink tea instead of water
people are getting baked everywhere in
California what do you mean getting
baked
so let us kind of funny enjoy our yoga
yes and combination day of secular
religion indeed indeed and order anyway
so that's it for today thank you guys
for watching good night have a good
night and that concludes exhausts ASMR
and I hope you guys have been well
asleep
[Laughter]