good evening everyone welcome to another
episode of talk show and today is random
now I'm going to talk about several
things of import it's search for section
oops okay I don't know what I'm doing
but what I know is that first of all I
need to fix the spikes on live stream
yes today is May 28th 2019 and we are
going to talk a nice talk show this
today's topic is about kink Bastian
Ellen Show and oh there is this thing
I'd learned today that is called
[Music]
vocal fry' yesterday I learned about
this vocal fry' thing this vocal fry is
a girl's thing like that you know
pedestrians kim kardashian's they are
rich people they are very rich they've
got money their bathroom is bigger than
my life oh yeah oh my god
their bathroom is bigger than my life
and like yeah I also learned today about
this upspeak you know there is this
thing about this up-speak like everyone
is talking that the way they the what a
speak is is that they raise the okay
okay that's not okay well that's over
anyone near the absurd speak up speak is
like you raise is like that basically
how are you today and how are you not
today okay up stick up speak up see Kim
kardashian-west chatted with Ellen about
her husband Kenya and waist West Kenya
waist
kanya west enjoying life as dad yeh to
their three kids
what is like living the personal drama
between her sister Crowe and her
boyfriend Tipton Thompson on Keeping Up
the Kardashians and what she thinks in
Kyle Jenner's something oh my god no I
feel so bad
trepidation who are you hey break the
loop
hey gloop how come you are here so fast
because I didn't announce it today I
wasn't sure I wasn't certain about this
topic I was just home cooking and this
and this Ellen girl this is this Ellen
girl she is kind of creepy
you know this Ellen girl this this Ellen
Show I've seen her a few times and you
know I watch YouTube and you know now I
see her and she is every time I see her
she I find her very creepy
you know this Ellen show girl this this
whip this woman The Ellen Show you know
I think I think she is kind of a you
know I kind of perceive her to be a
schizoid you know as she's also a loner
type kind of woman and you know she is
very creepy like I can see her you know
just you know her body language is it
seems to me that she is kind of she is
nervous and unsure at all times and so I
wondered how did she became so famous so
popular so successful because because
usually
if you are that type of person you you
know the entertainment business doesn't
fit you oh my god kink Adagio is like
talking so this there is his voice
it's called vocal fry and vocal fry is
like right now this is the voice this is
the vocal fry and King cutta cutta cutta
Seon Kim Kardashian apparently many
girls in America you know American girls
white girls we must emphasize that white
girls okay white and upper-middle class
where girls they they have a kitten it's
an epidemic it's an epidemic about this
vocal fry' thing
so let's look let's look up what is
vocal fry' vo c al f Y so we'll go fry
apparently all the girls are talking
about it I mean the girls they have this
they have the girls thing they have a
thing like so we let's go to Wikipedia
vocal fry register so vocal fry register
also known as post register there in
gene variant gialos Asian postponed
Asian quick Quogue popcorn
grotto try righto righto grottoes grape
Stroeve has straw has Austral has good
morning break the loop are you there are
you still there
okay too big Peter so so this is lowest
vocal register and is is produced
through a loose Grotto closure that
permits air to bubble through slowly
with a popping or rattling sound of a
very low frequency during this formation
the air annoyed cartilages in the larynx
together which causes the vocal cords
vocal folds to compress rather tightly
and become relatively slack and compact
the break the loop says people with
vocal fry' are annoying it is quite
interesting that there is this word this
I suppose linguistic related word of
vocal fry' you know they did a study
speech pattern there is for Saito for
Saito zero is like that and so that is
fascinating
okay
suddenly I'm lost so I'm looking at Kim
Kardashian Kim Kardashian this this this
I have a you know this this they people
you know not sure how to describe it so
she became famous because of a sex tape
and she became rich no of course but
they these people you know they have to
is you know it's not like everyone
anyone can make a sex tape then you
become rich and famous it's not like
that they do have certain talent
basically their talent is being you know
a social butterfly they you know they
are able to manage social situations so
in a sense management skill skill and
also kind of a feminine you know skill
in management and Leo people okay so
okay right now I'm kind of lost when I'm
lost I don't know what I'm doing like
usually like my I'm lost I'm not sure
you know that's when I feel
self-conscious then you know not sure
why and what I'm doing I'm talking about
because well originally I was going on
to talk about to imitate to mimic this
vocal fry' register in falsetto and we
saw we saw okay let's try that let's try
this we saw voice okay the whistle
register is also also called the third
register we saw turn is the highest
register of the human voice lying above
the modal register and for sale
missa this resistance is receiving
physiological production which is
different from the other registers and
so called because the timbre of the
notes that are produced with these
registers similar truth of that no
whistle is some Sopranos the motor
register work of attraction makes and in
the what is usually thought of is the
whistle register now I'm not sure that
is actually the whistle register but
whatever that is then we then we have
the physiology and definition that's we
so register the falsetto the four zero
is just for Seto there is the work
register occurring frequently then a
Korean frequency range above the modal
voice register and overlapping with it
by approximately one half of it is
produced by the vibration of the
ligamentous edges of the vocal chords in
honing part commonly cited in a context
of singing for Saito characteristic of
phonation by both sexes is also one of
four main spoken work register is
recognized by speech pathology
Moda vocal fry vocal fry and sub vocal
fire vocal fry steel oh is it vocal fry
is kind of like this okay be an
apparently there is a fashion among the
girls like the kink Kardashian girls
they sick I'm not even sure how to
describe them they are like kind of sick
and in the past decade there is this
thing about asses you know this women
with their big ass you know and and they
have these talking you know this young
generation of this talking thing you
shake your ass you know I don't find
that or doing
do you and I think particularly in the
black community like they are did this
talking thing and apparently you know
these girls you know these white
upper-class girls they have this do they
have a thing you know they they are
insecure they gossip all the time you
know they are insecure they they worry
about their boob sighs you know the
exactly you know they are as if they are
afraid they cannot find a guy you know
they so this is teen girl thing and on
YouTube there are million billion videos
they of themselves talking about asses
or the this or darrode or drama gossip
this Jesus Kim Kardashian you know this
King she's not really pretty she's not
pretty okay this is not pretty at all
and well you have makeup does everything
but then what does she sell she sell to
girls you know makeup stuff makeup
makeup and sexy and long
ray and the perfumes and what the [ __ ]
feminine doesn't is this [ __ ]
of course it connects to the social
justice the feminism [ __ ] there they
have stem you know they want in recent
years they came up with the word stem
science technology engineering and
mathematics of [ __ ] these [ __ ] you
know you should you know you if you want
the society to be good ok avoid any of
these new feminist new formations this
this you know so what what what's a good
word for stem you know sign this this
stupid idiotic stem science and
technology and engineering and
mathematics the [ __ ] I see if you know
they need you know they need these
subjects together there's a need there's
a vacuity there's emptiness they somehow
they they need this word too you know
they need a word to describe all these
hard core sciences you know if you know
if you need to say something around that
direction just say engineer you know to
be an engineer study engineering or
study math you don't have to be like
specific people know what you mean you
know that very the very fact that you
have this word stem indicates there's
something wrong with society as well
certainly it what is no it is the
progressive you know new type of people
they are you know progressive you know
it's good you know it's good to be
progressive but today's you know these
social justice progressive they are not
they are they are not really actually
just progressive they say they are sick
ok they don't know really what's going
on they empty you know they have
problems they feel you know they are not
full filled their life is not fulfill
their board
anyway stem these girls so these girls
got this damn thing you know they want
you know if you really want girls to go
to you know to study math or engineering
you stop the Kim Kardashian [ __ ] and the
girls magazines you see this you know
remove Kim Kardashian's then possibly
girls will go to you know study math you
know it's funny is it's it's also sad
every time you go to Twitter or
somewhere online forums you type math
then all the other treats you get you
know you cache tag math or whatever then
all the treaty's half of them is about
children like children trying to do math
like oh oh you know what what is the
circle of the area pie with some toys
you know children like it you know
middle school education you know they
teach children math it's supposed to be
oh this is so great
Oh children are learning math oh math oh
it's either that or teen girls bunch of
idiotic teen girls or like Oh math class
my boyfriend's something something so
what I like to see is instead of I like
to see math the real math beautiful
mathematics you know there's this
tremendous you know you know minimal
surfaces polyhedra and you know even
even the graph of a sine is you know can
be beautiful yeah so you know yeah so
you know did this quite this is there's
a sociology aspect to these you see why
do people like why do you go at like you
go to Twitter you type math okay let's
try some math or geometry okay it's just
try to type math then you got this you
know idiotic great school you know like
you yeah fun you know the you know
whatever this is a game a math game plug
this tnw is a [ __ ] website okay tnw you
know okay ads yeah ads okay this one is
fun this this one is good I can accept I
mean this is actually very good but
anyway what am i singing this me when my
math teacher asked why I got a sixty on
my last test yeah this is typical you
know this one yeah it's typical every
time you search math then half of it is
like that from these teen girls me when
my math teacher asked me why I got a 69
on my last day some joke I supposed oh
this is actually about that James
Charles guy a makeup guy who is having a
drama right now like cancelled they are
are there any good math document
documentaries you've watched basically
for that question basically no oh this
document a document documentaries about
mathematicians they are all kind of
production they are fake okay they are
not you know first of all they are
movies for example there's a movie all
the movies about math they are just like
rather garbage okay it's like I watched
an interview with Joe Rogan with with a
soldier you know ex-soldier of the
leader of some some some not FBI that
there's some kind of military you know
you know they kill people you know they
actually they that's what they do
so Joe Rogan is asking so are there any
movie you know using guns you know FBI
busting or some military some you know
see you know param not paramilitary
special trained you know special
military group you know sometimes you
have these five people or ten you know
you you you know they put you into a you
you know you have a special task to do
Europe you must be you know very good so
you have this kind of you know so Joe
Rogan is asking the guy so are there any
movies you know what movies involving
guns or military or soldiers that that
is not that is at least you know
somewhat realistic and the guy says no
no not at what I mean they talk about
several examples basically the yeah the
guy is saying you know all the girl
almost you know like he says every
there's no one movie involving gun you
know military or soldier FBI situation
you know also spy movies not one single
movie that's half realistic that's he
says so in the same way I can make this
same comment up I don't you know for
movies that interview or Amyas that's a
story of mathematicians none of it are
remotely genuine you know they are just
like tall traumatic like there's a movie
called a beautiful mind you know a
beautiful mind is about this
mathematician what's his name what's he
saying the bit of a beautiful mind this
mathematician who studied manifold
geometric manifold then who also studied
what's his name and he also wore no I
think he won economics prize for some
math theory anyway John Nash yes indeed
thank you
Oh John Nash the beautiful mind is that
yes Joe Nash actually he's got you know
he's got a schizophrenic he's
schizophrenic so he see things you know
he see things that's not here not there
he's he hear things that's not there so
schizophrenic is really a problem you
don't want to have that schizophrenic
that's that's physiological you know
it's not just personality disorder
so anyway yes so back to the such math
on Twitter so you either see all these
girls they're talking about their things
you know if it's like this young dis
girl girls have a thing with math for
example let's read this one Molly says
my friend Sophia went from texting me
about Rubick Rubick cubes and how she
wants to solve one of the one of these
summer to meth and Google what and even
I don't even know what Google is smh
what is smh is that smooch like what my
friend Sophia went from texting me about
Rubik's cubes and how she wants to solve
one this summer to math and Google okay
I don't even know so you know girls girl
okay so they have to like this is their
thing immediately somehow they have a
thing with math
so you know anyway you'd use such math
what is this dance glow dance for math
Jam so it's either you know it's
basically all stupid on the other hand
you know it's mostly you know stupid on
the other hand if you want to see real
math let's say you can search for
example OS MH shaking my head okay okay
Henry H E + ry city man this is a
English guy I actually I never met him
but yeah at least this is a guy he
introduced me to second life then I
spent four years in second life day and
night so for example if you want a CV on
math you know you know look at you know
look at his post in this all real math
and real and beautiful one as well real
and beautiful and a lot math and not not
you know trivial math middle grade
school math nothing nothing wrong with
high school math okay but it's just that
we use such the mass everything is a
[ __ ] King kindergarten no girls in
the thing girls talking about math they
ended and their boyfriend
oh yeah I was going to mention this this
is a sociology phenomenon this is just
right you can study why this is so and
that's sociology and actually I have
some theories okay I have some things to
say about that why why you do and you
know note for example girls young girls
do that but you don't see boys do that
you know you will not you know find boys
I say Oh Matt something something like
the way the style the girls are doing
they are doing it all the time and
there's a reason I can I can tell but
anyway for for example this hair is a
German you know you look at his treat
and that's this man that's good thing
and you know and oh yeah and this is you
know some of the things he treat are not
trivial math some of them are unsolved
for example this poor packing okay it
says news feces creates remarked about
any sport hours the including member
this is probably related to sphere
packing which is I believe it's still a
soft problem packing in two dimension is
solved I think pretty sure it's oh no
it's not soft because you have to pack
you know how like how many circles of
the same size you can put into a square
that's a problem for example now in
three dimensions is the is suppose you
know how many balls you can put into a
square into a cube you know you you have
to you know like there are different
arrangements maybe maybe you can put one
more but the the point the difficulty is
that you have to prove you know you know
this is the minimal do this is a maximum
number boy so you can put into a cube
all you have to prove this is the
maximum number of circles of radius R
you can put into a square you have to
prove it but you know if you look if you
look you know just such force fear of
hacking you will find Wikipedia and you
know that and that's unsolved well I may
not be I may be incorrect but anyway
part of some of these problems are not
solved yet and they are they they are
tremendously difficult meaning I mean
they have been unsolved for you know
it's well known problem for a few
hundred
so you know so if you have never taken
math and you are wondering so what does
mathematicians do all day you know like
you don't have this question for physics
because you know obviously they study
black hole they study the Sun you can
see black oh is something in this in the
space you can imagine they study you
know physics they study you know how jet
you know how to airplane works how
helicopter works how gravity works you
can only imagine but then if you haven't
taken you know if you haven't studied
math what does mathematicians study
beyond you know beyond high school
beyond calculus you know that so anyway
usually it's very hard to describe you
cannot describe it because that is the
nature of math because man the nature of
math is you throw away everything
leaving only the essence of things and
that essence usually cannot be described
to a layman you know because it's all
very extremely abstract yeah so I mean
what I mean is that you cannot describe
in English that is what I mean so anyway
so yeah so this for example this is a
good math and also you can you know one
trick is to to know good people to
follow in certain type of subject is
that you find one guy who you who you
value very much for example math this
guy I value very much for example so you
found one guy then you look at what he
who he follows then you can find a bunch
of a lot of other people that is a great
poster for that topic and you know
currently the topic is math you know
this is one technique for example if I
want to find King Kim Kardashian you
know
okay my research into you know American
let's say girl yeah my research into
women then then you know into Kardashian
you know let's say Qaddafi and the
sociology of Kardashians you know like
what did what they do everyday
what you know what what is it they make
that they they have so many millions and
millions 10 million 15 million followers
what what is it you know you can study
it you know in a scientific way and of
course people are to study it they are
so anyways if I want to know what these
girls are doing so I follow them you
know you you you such Kim Kardashian you
see who she is talking to every day then
you follow those people you know you
eventually your have you know group of
people and then you are learn their
lingo you know they have the speeds they
have a particular internation they've
particular styles they talk they their
subject matter is also you know there's
a certain subject matter outside of that
you know they yeah and you know they and
they have like women you have to be
strong and brave she's a strong and
brave girl it seems insecure you know
you know that is actually true
biologically because women statistically
you know they if you measure them by
psychology you have these four qualities
and one of them is called neurosis
neurotics just means someone who is not
very confident you know always have
doubts about things and females tends to
score high on that and we understand
that in everyday life as well because
women usually you know they worry about
you know they you know but however that
is their nature what that was so why are
they like that they are like that
because that maximizes women's
prosperity because they you know
children they have children in their
tummy they have to make sure the
children are born healthy and make sure
the children grew up good so then they
can pass their genes you know so that's
part of the biology of women so
therefore I mean they are different from
men males you know you don't have
pregnancy you are different you you know
you can [ __ ] around and nothing happens
to you
on the other hand women they [ __ ] they
get babies you know you know of course
today you have condoms in communal
contraceptives there's a different story
but you know women you know you have
babies and that changes your body you
get you know you cannot move us you know
you cannot run us before you change
changes your body for a year then you
have to you know feed a baby you know
milk of course the fascinating and you
know so that is and so so so you can see
there's this physiology physical you
know physiology differences so from
thesis point of view you know it's
physical physical differences affects
your everyday life but psychologically
that's it also has affect that therefore
it's different so women neuroses I
suppose you know from some theories you
can read you know from evolutionary
psychologists they you know neurosis
women score high on that because I
suppose because they that that you know
statistically that makes them to have
higher chances for their children to
survive
you know that for FEMA you know for
females that's that's why females has
this trait and you know and you know
where evolution biology for Saito for
zero
so I have enough I don't know I don't
know what I'm doing and I think I'm
going to quit soon because my roommate
she's got me he they got me dinner
dinner I feel good that that I have
dinner and it's smelling good I got
three people watching so how is going
break the loop so are you good I got
three people watching so who are they
guy who are they okay break the loop so
what else I'm gonna you know I'm hungry
for Saito so I was talking about for
Saito so you have this we saw your
official whispers voice with a voice and
for Saito or Seto voice you can't you
know you can speak and raise your pitch
raise your pitch higher so you and
that's you know in fact that this is a
lot trans people to track you know
transgender you know they eat this you
can practice that and I've seen people
do that and if you do this long enough
you will know practice it's like how
they say everything takes practice like
when you play your tennis with more
practice your to better and eventually
you have a voice that's like sounds like
a female right now I'm playing Minecraft
I've never played it before
oh okay I've never liked Minecraft
because just because the fact that you
know in today's video I don't know if
you heard me talking about this before
you know you might have because
minecraft I don't like it because you
know in today's technology you have to
DeGraaf --ax that's you have realism you
know you have all these you know very
realistic images but mank
minecraft is like you have these Marxist
Marxist 2d you know squares and Marxist
that's seems silly to me yeah so no
minecraft for me I never played it
let's see okay so modal voice motor
voices is the normal voice but you know
I find that these speech things I
actually quite fascinating then you have
vocal fry vocal fry Bokova is basically
like this when you're you know when you
lower your voice all the way down so
it's like crackling the vocal fry
register the book of re-register also
known as post you know barabra is the
lowest vocal register and is produced
through a lewis growth or closure that
permits air to bubble through slowly
with a popping or rasping sound or the
very low frequency and we shall and
there are other interesting topics
because such as up talk the high rising
terminal also knows up speak up talk
rising inflection upward inflection or
high rising intonation is a feature of
some variant of english where decorative
sentences crosses and with rising pitch
intonation and here the end of sentences
where a phoneme page she is applied
Millennials they do that you know that
that so from you know if we look at this
from psychological point of view
it is just my random fancy okay it seems
like the it stemmed from an uncertainty
and no confidence you know so he's like
everything is a question hi my name is
Kyle welcome to south talk show today is
May 28th 2019 okay I'm gonna I think I'm
gonna go eat guys break the loop having
that go eat and I guess that's it for
today's talk show I'm kind of just doing
[ __ ] around [ __ ] around have fun
have fun playing Minecraft bye