good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh
today is August 29th Thursday San
Francisco time no and good morning
bathroom you
and today's topic is Emacs HTML mod a
introduction demonstration and other
things
Emacs asked questions just post in the
comments post in a chat box and we get
let's get started so how many people are
watching zero but bathroom U is here so
why does it say zero come on is it wrong
crazy I need to reload the window I
think that's why let's see reload
I still say zero OH - okay so let's pop
this out and do this again
and the CMAs we need CMAs here because
CMAs asked the question yesterday
so Beth um you says it's good by the way
we never see the first 30 seconds of
your stream for your information we
never see the first second 30 seconds of
your stream already oh I think I know
wait wait why is that no because after
the live stream ended I usually you know
go to YouTube after two hours it will be
on YouTube so I usually watch it and I
see the whole thing so what do you mean
you cannot see the first 30 seconds
are you talking about livestream yet are
you talking about
watching livestream are you talking
about watching it on YouTube
after the live stream because for one
thing I know for sure if you watch it on
YouTube after the live stream it's it's
full I mean it has the first 30 seconds
for live stream okay you don't okay okay
so for live stream I I'm not sure why so
I I don't know I have to think about it
no I don't know why I don't so anyway I
think let's let's get started because
people are watching you know you know
let's I want you know I'm getting better
at making videos you know when people
watch they just want they want watching
the main thing not random chat too much
okay so let's today we're gonna show I'm
going to show a demonstration of saw
Emacs aged Emacs HTML mod now this is a
mod for doing for doing HTML yeah it's a
HTML mod obviously so okay let's go -
let's go to my Emacs blog and I am using
HTML mod you can see the name here and
the let me show you the mod name is this
one some HTML mod and you can see you
know right now I'm in it because you can
okay one way to find out what major mode
you are in is called described variable
look at the left window you can see all
the commands I call you see described
variable then you type you type major
mod okay
so basically what you are doing is you
are looking at the documentation for the
symbol major mod then it will tell you
it's value is HTML mod another way is to
click the status bar I think that
doesn't that doesn't oh if you just
hover over the status bar the the mod
line then you tell you made your mod
well actually it doesn't tell you yeah
anyways that the proper way is just
describe variable and okay let me let me
get to my talkshow page and read this
now okay I think we starting to digress
hold on a second okay this white
variable made your mod then type major
mod way to get the major mod name okay
this is what you do described variable
type major mod then you will tell you
this is a proper way because because for
example right now I am in HTML mod but
for example some mods their name may be
different you know there are some many
HTML mods but there is one there is one
Martin name that's like technical name
and to get them our name you just call
this quite variable then type the major
mark then you'll tell you the value and
I have two tutorials on my emails
website it's this go to the ok so why
don't we copy so this is Mike's a talk
show for today I'm going to edit you
know after the video but today but why
don't we I'm going to cut cut cut okay
so right now I'm using side Gmail March
so all the commands you see on the Left
panel you can see how it operates it's
kind of a radio demo so now I go to
bookmark
sorry max block go there and show in
browser you can see today's our talk
show which is empty you know it's empty
yet so I go to the top sad hop show
that's over here I created I put a stuff
here showing browser you can see stuff
there that's what we are going to do
today and I'm putting this on my Emacs
blog so it's more convenient because my
Emacs website anyway so yeah because I'm
a new max website the directory is over
here so then after that after I finished
the video I can then copy stuff and move
it to the talk show page so so for
example one of the feature is you see
this URL this URL is full URL with the
domain name of Emacs you know cuz I HTML
mod but since we are already in the
Emacs directory you know we are already
in this domain I actually don't need it
I don't need the food or man usually I
want a relative link
so anyway right now I want to get the
full URL okay hold on a second let me
move this window over here I want to
extract the URL of this block of text so
I press the key and that command is
exciting I extract URL then I paste you
see it's here then I can think of I you
know I can turn this into a what turn
into a link you see now it's a link you
see now it's a local relative link it's
not full URL and then now I can make it
a list you see list
so now you see this too so you see these
two are actually same thing but but the
the bottom one is relative link now
showing browser you can
see so so yeah let me let me give you an
overview of HTML mod now in Emacs you
also have a default HTML mark so what's
the difference of course I would say
mine is better because otherwise I
wouldn't have created it it has more one
feature okay
this my HTM art is mostly designed for
if you work with html5 pure html5 no no
mixing of CSS or JavaScript but actually
if you want to do that later on let me
show you how to do that okay mixing show
how to modify some HTML mod so it can
also work with mixed CSS JavaScript HTML
ok a lot of people need that that's
practical we can do that because in
Emacs 26 there is a new HTML mod I don't
remember the name right now but we will
figure it out
this new HTML mod has a major feature
and that feature is so you can mix CSS
HTML Javascript all in one file this is
very common so so Emacs 26 finally have
that feature building and but sighs
Chima
does not you know because it's it's
almost like from scratch but however
because major mod are written so that
they are based on apparent mod so we can
trivially within 5 minutes we can make
HTML mod based on the GNU Emacs default
HTML mod so that in the same file you
can have all kind of JavaScript CSS and
they will all be colored I think I think
yeah so keep the comments coming okay
are you talking to us so okay so so what
so so so what is the okay so excited
email much so it's you know it has
syntax coloring for HTML keyboard every
one of them if it's not colored that
means you misspelled it or something I
mean it's it's not a standard valid tag
okay for example you look at this file
all all tags is colored if it's not
colored for example I add something
let's magnify you can see the color you
see this to you er is not colored for
example it's at its magnified you see so
if you say you are the Inspira but
anything else it's not okay it's hard to
see but anyway so it's all colored and
it supports every all html5 tags for
example I can let's make it smaller okay
so for example I want to insert a new
tag I press tab tap and at the mini pub
mini buffer at least all html5 tags so I
can type anything like s then it shows
all all tax that that start with S okay
I can say style is T okay let's say then
you got a style for adding CSS style
needs to be added at the top by the way
so I go to top it needs to be added you
know between the headers anyway so Oh
html5 tags are supported
it has a huge number of commands for
working with HTML okay so I'm gonna show
you that later we are we have already
seen for example extracting URL for
example my cosa is here I want the URL
of these this or this together I select
them I press a key the UI is extracted
now I can just paste you can see in a
mini buffer for example now I open a new
new buffer page you see that's it
for example let's select the whole thing
extract the URL you see here you got a
whole bunch now I go here select o paste
145 links you know they are all
extracted close it
don't save actually we can go to some
you know work on other people's HTML for
example let's try YouTube I'm not sure
this is gonna work way out but let's try
it
so in YouTube in Chrome you want to get
the HTML source code so control the key
used to be control you let's see if that
works ok they removed it you know the
the browser they they improve and they
change you know over the years but now
let's see command you command option you
okay command option you on a Mac there
is the YouTube source code ok so let's
select oh you probably take a long time
it's too big
what's going on yeah it's the YouTube
you know these days this source code is
so huge let's see if we can copy it copy
it go through Emacs open a new buffer
paste okay so we got the text you know
these so these things still dance
Emacs you see these long lines they will
kind of freeze Emacs depending on how
long is the line so this is you know no
good
but anyway
okay just you know like Emacs is not
moving a much anima he max is not moving
much any so why don't we do some let's
break it break the long lines into
smaller lines maybe that walk so I do
find and replace any of that replaced by
any of that with a new line do that
replace the whole file okay then there's
there still a lot long lines but anyway
so this is HTML file now let's switch to
HTML mod okay there it is that's now it
is in XHTML mod this incomprehensible
giant file so what is his style okay
this is this you know million lines of
CSS style so anyway let's try extract
URL select or call the command row
argument type yeah I don't know what's
going on because you know that that that
means it's a bug that that shouldn't
happen that means my code you know it
doesn't matter what it shouldn't give
you a bug drunk wrong type of arguments
but anyway did the Google the the Jenner
the machine generated page is a pain to
deal with
okay so so let's go back and one nice
feature is that it it it allows you to
work with programming source code for
example I can say Python you have this
template I press a key now I mean this
buffer I can save print three okay
vennett it works and let's say x equals
to something okay something plus thing
okay now I print X Jeannette it works
now I close that paste it here and color
it showing browser you see you got the
Python code colored and it can be least
it can be Haskell it can be you be rust
anything so this this feature is like
oak mods Babel
so if I want a if I want to edit the
code I can do several ways I can do this
this way and I'm back here you know I
can modify something y equals to what
and print X first Y for example in it
you know then I got that then remove
that paste back here
color color showing browser refresh or I
can press a key then it just shows shows
the code you know like that press the
key to to make it span HTML colorized
okay so that's that feature let's go
back let's go over the features so yeah
so that the the difference is from the
Emacs one is you know it's syntax color
every keyword if it's not colored that
means you spelled it wrong and it has a
lot of more commands to work with HTML
such as extract URL
working with programming language okay
let's go over the features syntax syntax
coloring based on exact keywords now let
me show you how a max color this is
going to be different for example let's
call Emacs default HTML mod so that is
HTML mod okay okay so now we are in HTML
mod let's see
well I don't see a difference right now
but but I
anyway so this is default HTML xhtml mod
as I know for sure that it does not
color all possible HTML tags but I've oh
yeah okay okay I think I know what what
let's see let's try these okay okay hold
on second let's switch to HTML much
something okay
now let's switch to HTML mod Emacs HTML
mod now you see this tag paragraph tag
now let's change to TTT okay let's
change it to X magnify there it is you
see in HTML mod the the Emacs HTML mod
it colors everything you colors
everything as soon as you have the tag
but this xxx this is not a valid tank
therefore so if you switch to excite tml
mod it's not colored you see it's not
color but but in Emacs HTML mod it
colors everything by that and similarly
in HTML in Emacs HTML mod if you have
something like that it also color it you
see this this is not a valid attribute
HHH but you know if you in such tml
let's see you see it's not colored so we
in such TMI if it's not color it's not
colored it's not standard use you
misspelled it it's invalid or it's
non-standard so things like so so that
so that so that's what I'm saying how
excit me ahmad is syntax coloring
interest tells you something
so if you want to insert any tag just
press the tab key okay press the tab key
it insert any tags so that's a we showed
that before and the tab key it depends
on for example something okay some
something I press the tab key let's say
span I press s oh that's that let's try
it again
tap SP span depending on what tag it is
some tags some tag will wrap around the
current would such as spam some tag for
example let's try again
dive okay it will wrap around the the
current paragraph while some other let's
try P you know wrap around the current
line and also also these that if you
have a selection you can always make a
selection press tab then it says strong
okay then if you have a selection then
the whole tag will be wrapped around the
whole selection so that's about
inserting tanks convert text to table or
reverse okay so suppose I want to
generate some table a B's a P let's say
I have a matrix 1 2 3 so I can call I
can call some HTML make table ok press
ENTER then you will ask me for a
separator let's say space ok enter now
you got a table it's it's show in
browser you see a table so that that's
how you can convert a table let's keep
those there so you can write a table you
can have but you know complicated table
you and so you have that command
okay house so far so good
where is CMOS
so you said in so far so good bathroom
you is an interesting g-tron oh man
getting boring
okay so come on so convert to table
let's let's do this quick reading so I
can also convert lines to HTML lists for
example a be something C okay compared
to at least now it's at least show in
browser you can see I got a list and if
if I want all the ordered list okay so
that's that that converts to a list I
can press a key and that removes all the
tax you know that command is remove HTML
tax and now let's do a let's convert to
ordered list so I press ctrl you first
then called a some same command for
lists then becomes the least ordered
list so you show showing browser so
that's all the list
okay so seamless should okay you don't
do HTML but you code in Python okay but
you don't yeah okay no HTML so that
means you know coding web so let's go
back to the features what what
what's going on one second this is
usually automatic now I have seven
repetition of tags
okay let's go back to HTML command to
edit source code
so we've showed that source code lets
this show another one eMac B's let's
just code some eMac this Saudi fun -
okay eMac this mod - and F F let's say
message message fee let's say insert
something today okay
you don't need that so that's a new
command I evaluated and now I can call
it meta X F F F it inserts something
okay now I'm writing a blog I want to
show this to people
so I copy it delete the buffer and
insert it here now I want to color it
and you know so I make it I call you can
see the command on the left window I I
call the command and he asked me for a
language so emag B's then I got that so
you know it's an eMac based code then I
color it now it's called the showing
browser showing browser where is it
showing browser okay I got this it's
showing the old page I think there is an
update of the with these tabs things
fire apparently Firefox just
automatically updated that's why my
config is all wrong because this plug-in
is for closing duplicate tabs now
usually when I open a new tab for my
from Emacs you just remove the old page
and show the new one
right now it's showing the old page is
not showing the new for example I need
to press refresh in order for this to
show up so some you know something
changed with these oh yeah so priority
keep new attack okay so that that should
be it
so now I show in browser again you see
the emag list code and now go back to go
back to this so so this I can I can I
can call this command it shows the code
or I can go on any any text I can call
this command and it removes all tags or
I can for example I can call alternative
command like this it removes the text
but it also tries to keep the textual
information such as for example let's
see for example I have a Bing here if I
just remove the tag the link is also
good because the link is part of the tag
thing but I can call eternal alternative
command that day becomes this you know
it shows the textual form of the of the
text of the tag HTML so those commands
are called for example remove intact the
command for removing tag is called
beside shame I'll remove HTML tags and
the command to turn it into a text form
is called HTML HTML to text extract URL
we have showed HTML eyes keyboard
shortcut okay so if you you know if you
are like me writing a lot about
keyboards you can for example see X you
know in Emacs you do see X CC for
example to quit
now if you if you type that you know it
doesn't look so good you can you know
what so what you can do is you know I
can call this command then paragraph
showing browser then comes out pretty
like that so what you have is the these
keyboard tags so so that command is
let's call it again okay so that command
is called HTML eyes keyboard shortcut
notation so you got this you know
features and you know so because I've
been using this mostly for myself for
seven years now so whenever I need
something I just added
if you look at my website all these you
know are coded with such - mmm are seven
thousand pages so what okay
another feature is convert charts to
Unicode to edit entities for example let
me let me show you an example okay so
let's see algorithm let's go to
Wikipedia algorithm so here is algorithm
page and what I want is the Chinese page
of this page Chinese version so I click
here okay here's a Chinese Wikipedia
Wikipedia on algorithm in Chinese so I
copy the link at the top I paste it here
you see there's got Chinese characters
now okay this is not what I want to show
but anyway so let's link let's make it a
link okay when you make a link you see
the URL here they become percentage
encoded but the the link text does not
change you know so this is a feature so
in url supposedly by by standard if you
want to follow the standard the you it
must be
is key it cannot contain Chinese so all
Chinese are in percentage encoded into
this thing so and and by the way in some
browsers in some browser if you you know
copy the URL and you paste it
automatically becomes this depends on
the browser you know I have article this
you know each browser behaves
differently you know on one hand you
know with with the direct characters
Chinese characters this is intuitive but
if you really want to follow you know
the suspect then then you are not
supposed to have Chinese characters in
URL therefore some browsers when you
copy it it automatically make the UI are
like that and this is unreadable I mean
imagine if you are Chinese
you know you imagine every URL in
English is encoded like that you know
then you don't know what that is so this
is very bad
and by the way you don't have to for
example you don't have to do that for
example the in this link you can
actually do like that it will just walk
okay let me show you you know so so this
link let me show it like that
this this link and this link are the
same you know even though you know it in
fact you know in browser it works the
same it doesn't for example showing
browser let's let's make it one line and
let's make it a list showing browser and
for all Wikipedia links I color it green
and you can see both link works so I go
to the second one it opens the page now
let's try to copy the URL in Firefox
let's see what we get copy it
pace you see so in you in Firefox it
automatically turns the URL into this
this this incomprehensible encoding
percent-encoding now inside Chima mod
you can convert those encoding so let's
try it I don't even have to select it so
I just call command side TM % okay
decode percent-encoded you are out there
it is new enter there you go you see so
usually my commands when you do not have
a selection you know if you don't have a
text selection
it just works on either the current line
or it works on the current paragraph
separated by blank lines or sometimes it
works on the current word like current
word depending on the command you know
which whichever is more suitable for the
command so like oftentimes in Emacs
Emacs command you have
something-something region that means
you have to make a selection first for
example in this case I have to make a
selection first then I call the command
otherwise it tells you no selection
that's so that's inconvenient command
should be you know just work on it just
you know whatever is appropriate if
there's no selection just work on a
current line or current word or current
paragraph or whole buffer if appropriate
so anyway in this so for example let's
try it again the code for sending code
you are out there there you have it
so you so I have this convenient command
let's close that let's remove it ok it's
it's let's call these commands
okay so showing browser so yeah so you
know this mod has all these convenient
commands Oh then then you have the HTML
entities HTML entities okay so let's see
X greater than 2 let's do something
fancy summation x squared
you need XHTML entities okay so let's
just try random okay X greater than 2 so
ok so if you want to do that you can you
can call char two entities char to size
tml cha ok I'll replace HTML char two
entities Y is you're not showing just to
I think I change the command name that's
why it's copy and see
let's describe function no-match
describe function no match okay I have
changed the name so I need to update my
HTML page okay let's do that
Nitz let's go to the HTML mod page which
is this one showing browser that's the
page okay so just search for child is
these two command the name has changed
and now let's go to the source code okay
cuz excite Shamy Ahmad okay tap go to
the source code and let's search for all
but for at least matching lines cha
let's search for entities enti t okay
okay you got lots of
let's let's let's try it again this
matching line is different okay so you
show all functions then search for en TI
te entities so we have some HTML we
place HTML named entities HTML replace
HTML named entities instead of char two
entities yeah right yeah so that that
phrase is redundant there it should be
so the new name is this so here's the
code HTML replace HTML named entities ok
caveat cosette close close one second
so we need to modify this so this is one
of the command it's demo
first of all let's demo it so I select
that okay so this is a command I I
select that I don't need to select okay
so I just call such tml we face named
entities we want to change unicode to
entities not entities to unicode so
actually so i think i press ctrl you
first control you koib command
no let's look at documentation describe
function okay we face okay so the it's
this just right
Unicode Unicode to
char to unicode char two entities what's
going on
okay so let me let me copy that
switch back to here let's put it here
compare the names so that let's remove
these chart two entities HTML named
entities replace HTML named entities
okay so this convert entities to aged
two characters for example percentage %
emphasis I mean M person a.m. P
ampersand ampersand ampersand greater
than sign okay let's call the command I
don't need to select let's just go I'd
replace HTML named entities yes oh okay
yeah it doesn't replace these two
because okay it gets complicated can you
trust Chinese Wikipedia yes you can well
not for click for political articles not
really
same thing with English Wikipedia of
course but for technical topics yeah you
should usually it's okay but Chinese but
you rather read English Wikipedia
because the English Wikipedia has
100,000 times more or more rich more
articles more detail and more accurate
but if you want to learn something about
Chinese culture like specific Chinese
culture things like Chinese food or all
regions you know
you probably not interested because
that's that's rather very did you have
to be Chinese you know Chinese festivals
you know those Chinese things you can
reach a nice Wikipedia you know if it's
not political topic then there's a lot
things there that's not in the English
actually they even those kind of
articles the ink
Wikipedia is very rich you know you can
actually read the English version
including very esoteric detailed Chinese
history for example if you want to know
modern history or a or even you know
longer you know all the history like
thousand years ago there's the English
version Wikipedia is very detailed I
mean yeah it's it's it's quite quite
good you know there's a lot of people
talking about I mean that that's very
popular top topic you know the you know
I'm not sure I won't talk about you know
even mentioning the words then it's
going to be a problem so yeah let's not
talk about that I have a lot of things
to say and I can again correct
I can probably correct some
misconceptions and that you we are
agreed to you know you were oh you know
you didn't know but let's not get into
that today okay let's talk about that
another day that's where we are now
talking about technical stuff but okay
we got stuck with this entity things
it's very annoying okay so did you know
I'm let me show you okay so they me let
me relax and show you the CSS the CSS
size CSS it and HTML tutorial now if you
don't know HTML CSS for say for example
you are a artificial intelligence
researcher for the past 10 years and but
you never did you know you don't do web
you never done web such as leanness to
votes you know he is the hacker you know
mastered suppose you know he because he
wrote Linux but he oh he know he doesn't
know anything else he knows see you know
well and you know operating how to write
operating systems he's a master you know
that but he doesn't know a thing about
HTML he doesn't know CSS he doesn't know
JavaScript like like like usually
average programmers we do have some idea
like we might have coded HTML for one
hour you know we have some idea but he
some other people a lot in fact a lot of
people they have no idea how it how it
is but they do know I mean of course
they have seen the tags you know they
probably seen the tags but they don't
really know anything more than that so
if you are like that you know if you
never touched it you can check out my
tutorial it gives you a technical
introduction but okay we were talking
about entities so that's an interesting
topic because recently about a few years
ago the html5 group the what what the
group the new html5 group you know
yes split from w3c standard they created
a lot more entities so it used to be
there like 200 entities but now they are
like you know so this is a page you can
see all these entities you know
ampersand something something that and
you shouldn't do you shouldn't use this
anyway so today Unicode is popular in
your HTML file you just go to the top
and declare a declare a charset utf-8
like that okay then just just type
directly unicode not you know don't use
the entities so anyway let's open the
entities page so here is the entity
entities page here's a the source code
for this entity page so you can see and
I'm I'm all using you know exciting AMA
to do this so here are all the entities
for example you know for example this
one long long right words arrow okay so
let's let's try to find it here search
for long
okay their long right words error no way
such long right okay so here for example
there is this entity long right arrow
okay the entity name is long right arrow
so meaning that you type ampersand then
long right arrow then semicolon then in
HTML your show as this you know don't
don't right arrow now that's a Unicode
so so you can either do that we said oh
the turns out they have actually
duplicate entities so long right arrow
you can also write another way too and
you know another entity for the same
character is is is X
ar-ar-ar you know so so named entities
are no good you know they don't use
entities first of all they make it
impossible to read you know you look at
this impossible to read just use Unicode
for example long right word arrow this
unicode character there are several
entities for let's show show matching
lines list matching lines for example
there are you know they are there are
3-3 entities or two or does the same
thing okay the first two are just
leather case difference so anyway so
let's go to one of them so let's go to
this one okay so let's go back so here's
the entities let's copy and it's open a
new buffer paste the entities let me
show you so now switch to HTML mod okay
magnify magnify so you can actually see
the stuff
so here's aunt
soul image you know so entity has
another complexity because if you want
to show because this thing this part
stand for M percent if you want to show
an ampersand H HTML you have to use this
you know ampersand a.m. P semicolon so
anyway so if you want to show the long
ride upward arrow in HTML what you do is
you type this okay that you type that
and it will show it sure like that but
but you don't want to so so what you can
do is you copy code a command exciting
mail replace HTM it replace HTML named
entities that we are converted to the
Unicode but actually will not walk I
know because because this is new ID you
know this this is new HTML they added
you know few hundred entities you know
then so so for converting these entities
to HTML for it to work I have to add all
these you know a thousand or hundreds
into my eMac be smart like a table and
nobody actually you know very few people
actually use these new entities you know
before you only have 100 entities let me
show you okay it's all mixed but anyway
few years ago you only have like 200
make entities that's that's more you
know like entities came from HTML and it
came from sgml so in the concept of
entities is like 30 years old but today
it's not really necessary because you
have Unicode you know you every everyone
supports Unicode directly utf-8
particularly utf-8 encoding so the only
entity you should use is three three of
them and they are special they are kind
of special entities and those three are
these three ampersand less than less
than sign greater the inside
why what do you need these because these
are escape mechanisms for the HTML
bracket especially in XML in XAML it's
very strict when you have these
characters you they must be encoded in
you know using entities so that is about
entities so let me calculate let's close
that close let's paste the link here
okay so so so for example okay let me
demonstrate that command so for example
let's see a R cubed okay so so if we
have an entity that says a cute a R
cubed okay that's an entity now let's
call the command replace HTML named
entities it worked you see now you see a
walks that's how it works now anyway so
let's go back to the features so mm-hmm
maybe it's due to over the a summary now
so one hour any questions
Abdul hey good morning Abdul Abdul Essen
and T overfill so what do you need
entities for if you have Unicode exactly
yeah you don't need it well you you do
need those you know three to us you know
ampersand greater than sign listing sign
to escape HTML okay so I showed you know
I need to update my oh yeah so let's see
yeah
wait so okay so remember we need to
update our page because these two
commands are wrong names charter único
charter entities those are no longer
there so let's update that so we move
that that and this you know and phase
region text where is this came form so
that one is there oh yeah so this is
there so that so this this is the old
paragraph now this is a new so I don't
need those so make it a bracket qualify
it paragraph it deleted showing browser
go down there oh and this entity list we
don't need so actually this this links
to my entities page go back we don't
want that well we want to copy the link
paste it here make Minkoff I put link of
I put a square bracket make it see
deleted move here paste okay then
DVDs showing browser page down that's
what I want
so it says replace region text to HTML
entities by Unicode
yeah that's that's exactly that's that's
what we want then there's a see HTML
entity leaks least so you can see you
know so anyway so so there's a thing we
need to fix we either need to remove
this command completely or we need to
update it so that it works on all these
entities yeah I should update it so
actually why not because you know people
just like features they don't care
anything else hey most people when they
see something they just want you know
they just want to download package with
lots of features that's you know you get
popular they don't really care about
anything else
about details how it works or things
like that
Seema's finally you are here did you
already go over coding external code in
this I joined late yeah Koni
external coding this well that's not
part of HTML like what do you mean you
mean that you mean the syntax coloring
or what would like what you mean okay so
yeah about HTML so what sack if I did
not miss anything you did not do that
yeah no I'd there's no calling external
coding it is
that's a eMac this topic you have a
question about that well typically you
do that by calling shell command
oh well there's a way there's code but
that's another topic and if you are
asking that say it so HTML so this HTML
model it's let's summarize let's see
what I can say so HTML Mahdi's has these
features and let's close it there's
something I want to talk about so demo
let's see so demo syntax coloring we did
that show package dependency okay
install from scratch okay let's do that
let's do that install from scratch so
let's go look at the source code it
actually requires some packages because
this this is a bit this is this is
actually four thousand lines I think
it's a longest you know the let's see
soft like he's okay let's go to self
like he's cassava keys four thousand
lines okay it's this one is also four
thousand lines it's you know because
HTML when you pass HTML this a lot to do
you know there's a lot code to too many
manipulate Gmail stuff and there's a lot
commands we haven't covered for example
how do you do an image that's important
so for example let's actually do one
like that like that so I go to a
directory I is my image directory show
show in desktop you can see all the
images
the rainbow of death okay now it's good
okay so I got hundreds of images now
let's see dodge mod dodge max let's say
such for do GE okay there's a torch max
you know let's dis a big picture so
there it is copy file path close it
close it close it okay
paste paste the fire path here and link
a file
now it's an image showing browser you
see dodge Emacs now suppose I want to
change let's let's do this okay open
that go to the tired here is a file copy
it and it's good X X dog dot PNG okay X
X dog dot PNG open it copy the path
close it close it close it
move down paste here's the path link of
I show him browser scroll down we got
two copies now I want to rename this I
have a command that lets me rename the
file in HTML directly so let's rename X
X let's add a bunch of X okay showing
browser you see same image we named
because sometimes you want to rename
because before it was your name you know
because sometimes you want okay this is
actually for example let me say space
max talk toga toga okay so that's a
proper name and in showing browser so
basically it will it will be named a
file and they will you know use the
change the link properly without going
too tired to do it
so normally you go to diet normally you
go to you open the image you go to diet
then you can be named here for example
it's turn are renamed and something some
dog let say some dog okay done that's a
new name now this is some dark space I
want to change the space to underline so
I go command that's done open you know
so all the commands you can see on the
left window so you know I'm just showing
a lot of commands now so open actually I
don't I don't need this file because you
know we are testing we are just doing
testing so I press a key is deleted
refresh buffer you can see it's deleted
it becomes a backup close enter the file
no longer exists create new no actually
just delete that and we don't need the
doggie magazine anymore
so anyway but however actually okay I'm
gonna show in browser so actually let's
extract URL paste now another way to
insert the link image file is like this
there it is without the figure and
figure caption stuff you know so this
way showing browser there it is you know
when I have figure you can see the
shadow here you know that's CSS you know
you have this shadow sometimes you don't
want but so that's that's that's doing
an image dink so now let's okay now
let's go to the source code HTML file go
to the source code and go to the top you
can see a bunch of requires now all
these are part of Emacs meaning that you
don't have to install anything I do sgml
mod new comments browser browser UI ru R
u T thing at point sequence sub X you
know stupid Emacs and but so these
then you need you you need these four
packages
those are dependencies now the first
three are mine especially this one this
this one is a big one
HTML eyes so what does it do for example
that's that it it allows you to for
example I create the template for
example let me show you so switch to
save the fire okay xx start go okay
that's a :
so go template okay run it it works
prints 33 okay now cut it deleted paste
the code here okay now I want to make
this into a source code so add a tag go
: okay color fire showing browser there
it is : so why am i showing that because
in order to do this it requires the
package HTM L lies the package the
package name is this this guy I know
this guy kind of well he wrote that he
was a he was a X Emacs user he supports
X Emacs he does not like you know
Richard Stallman or the goon Emacs kind
you know politics anyway so HTML eyes
this is this these four packages you
need so I'm thinking let's try to
install from scratch meaning that I
start a Emacs fresh and try to install
everything see if we can do that Thomas
Thomas war hey good morning thank you
valo tomorrow okay so should we do that
let's see how long yeah I'm okay so
let's let's do that right yes should we
because of or something else
like it's yeah let's do some slits let's
try to install from scratch because you
know I have my Emacs or setup so it's
comfortable I'm familiar so everything I
do is very fast but you know someone if
you are starting from scratch you might
run into problems like how do you
install these Oh lots of errors I don't
see those because I'm so used to my own
you know I'd be system so let's let's
try to install from scratch let's see
what way how we go you know if we got
stuck and it takes too long there now
that's the beef there'll be it for today
that's fine let's ease so Emacs q e max
Q so how do we how we want to do is okay
so first of all I need to go through my
okay let's let's do it yeah that's not
that's not what we want okay I go to my
home directory
Emacs so you see this is all my mxconfig
in the if not Emacs 30 now let's rename
it let's rename it
yeah let's rename it right rename that P
10 day okay so we just renamed it so now
Emacs has no in it so let's start Emacs
let's see what happens okay let's start
Emacs
okay so here is the default Emacs now
now the default Emacs I don't have my
key bindings is gonna be it's going to
be almost impossible to use now see so I
so so I need to install sorry max size
HTML much so let's do that
so first of all let's go to a directory
so control X F let's open a file
ergo Emacs yeah ago Emacs Emacs slash
let's say blog dot HTML okay open there
it is this is the default Emacs guna
Emacs HTML mod oh it's a right so we
were talking about Emacs 26 they have a
new HTML mod and that HTML mod is called
HTML plus you can see in the mat line so
let's do describe variable let's go okay
mint meta X described variable okay then
type major my major mod okay now is it
tells me right so the new HTML mod the
mod name is M HTML mod M stand for multi
meaning that you can have CSS JavaScript
HTML and other things like you know like
PHP you know stuff in one file and
supposed to you should proper you know
dude syntax colouring for them so this
you know on the mat line it says HTML
plus but the actual major my name is M
HTML mod ok this this part is annoying
it's ok so that so so this is the
default Emacs so this is the mhtml ma
this is a new ok so so let's control x1
okay then how do you how do you magnify
[Laughter]
it's also alko right now we want to
install HTML mod
okay yeah install everything's from
scratch do you know do you know that now
there is a that that there is is that I
don't I don't suppose you are kidding
maybe you are right it's not talking
about those okay this today this focus
on Emacs so now yeah so we want to
install hmm lon so what what do we do so
let's look at it says go to this github
okay I go to this github and there it is
my mod so click on that okay
and it's just click on raw okay let's do
this the simple way let's not you know
get something something keep for
whatever let's just do this the the
old-school way copy the whole thing copy
it go back to Emacs
now let's go to unit file yeah we need
to create a unit file so ctrl X F enter
yeah that's not what we want yeah sure
XF let's go to yeah so home directory
now Emacs created Emacs directory for
you open there is nothing there author
list is like empty now we need to create
a Emacs init file so ctrl X F in it
I think it's coding it yeah in it are
yeah okay okay but before we do that we
need to create a new buffer okay control
X P something okay then paste ctrl Y
okay now that's the HTM
Maude code now let's switch to meta x-m
HTML mod remember this is the default
Emacs HTML ma now it's syntax colored
it's great page of okay now we need to
save this file okay save ctrl X s type a
name sir HTML
- mod dot DL good oh this is Lisp okay
so go to the so go to so country so
close it control X K opening it again
control X control F so okay open now
this is the HTML mod in Emacs Lisp mod
okay now this is the file we need to
load okay but before we do that let's
follow it
let's follow the direction let's go back
okay it says oh I don't have the
direction here so you see this is my Oh
Maud I've been using for seven years I
did not put it to mapa because mostly I
you know I considered for myself but I
should be okay so after that today I'm
going to start to put this on my Appa
and add you know install instructions
but you can see the install instructions
it's yeah so I didn't you know this I
didn't make it as polished for public
because I didn't even say that you have
these dependencies on a web page so
anyway so now we need to actually
install these others
sorry base pairs socket thinks our CSS
mod
HTML eyes I mean not well the HTML eyes
so so yeah that's we're gonna do a lot
you know that's that's gonna take a
while so we okay so beside sorry pace
pairs okay let's let's do it quickly
let's see if we can do that quickly sod
replace pay us let's see where where
where is the code github sorry pace
payers quick quick this is a fire we
want show raw source code copy cut
backing Emacs new buffer control Y paste
ctrl X s save saw the place pairs start
er save okay now go to tired tired that
directory refresh refresh is G okay then
you need to now all these packages by
default they should be in a directory
named disp that way Emacs will load it
so create a new directory press the plus
key type Lisp yes okay
now split pain control x2 now open the
Lisp pen now you need to move this HTML
mod selected and we praise and we base
pairs move it to this directory okay
that's done
and now next we need to let's go back go
back
let's see what what
what are the other things you need okay
there's few more things you need socket
thing okay so open side get thing there
it is on github and also our mapper okay
the Netscape mapa because in order to
download form ALPA I need to set up the
in it today you know so starting from
scratch is a lot work so let's just
press on with this raw copy your copy go
back here go to the directory meta X
diet yes this directory now now find
file new file sir - get thing dot e el
okay paste ctrl y fo paste ctrl X s save
okay now that's now get thin Daria
correct
okay now close these control X K enter
ug4 refresh okay what else there's one
more thing Kassar CSS mod okay so let's
open up effects our CSS mod new tab
there it is and go to github get the
file this file single file single file
is the best I don't want a bunch of
directories and complexity click raw
copy switch back to Emacs control X F
CSS mafia okay control y paste ctrl X s
save there it is
control X k keeo close ok now go to diet
meta X weight cancel let's see if tired
jump is available so meta X tired jump
enter
oh it's available good because I'm
wondering if I have to load it ok so we
got that one more one more one more
we'll beat that we're hopefully then the
whole thing we are load smoothly then we
will install Safra keys then I can
actually type ok wait and do oh my god
what is undo and do is control shift
underscore ok now we need HTML eyes mod
ok go back to browser new tab Emacs HTML
lies now this is by this guy this is by
this guy where is the github yeah this
guy this guy's from Scandinavian was in
no way or the you know Scandinavia one
one of those faces this guy coverage mix
ik so comments comments people comments
belong followed the MA says it is a
crowd it's a quite interesting question
to try new things in a fresh Emacs and
it is not very convenient to rename yeah
Emacs toddy hood have you tried home Eva
so you says it's not very convenient to
rename that eMac study folder
have you tried home variable home equals
to path what do you mean I mean he's had
a question or just comment what do you
mean it's not convenient to be named
re/max daddy you could rename it I mean
you can rename it in shell or you can
rename it in Emacs tired so I'm not sure
what do you mean it's hard to rename or
you mean you don't well right okay so by
default Emacs
we all recognize the fact that the
directory that Emacs 30 was the Emacs in
it so by default
Emacs looks into that so you don't have
to rename it or you know do you have to
set home directory to it you know home
environment variable if that's what you
mean
so anyway we with the one more thing we
need is this package so click raw select
all copy back to Emacs create a new file
this file will be named HTML lies start
il enter control Y paste ctrl s egg XS
save okay it's done
now what this package do is that it you
know in Emacs you have syntax
highlighting so what that package do is
that it it turns those syntax
highlighting information into HTML span
tags so that's how it works so you know
you have this syntax highlighting you
can turn it you know generate a HTML
with span tags for those colors that's
what this does so okay so we got this
now close it now now I copy the so now
okay close it
refresh go up a directory then go and
then refresh then switch buffer control
X be switched to in it yeah okay
we created a init file in this init file
we want to read we want to load let's
say just let's say load load some HTML
mod ok oh the keys ok so I hope that
should walk hold on a second is a safe
control as X s ok is saved now let's
let's try to run that before you know
now now we can just restart Emacs and
see if it works but there's a shortcut
we can just evaluate this code and see
if there's any error so control X
control e I think ok era of file missing
cannot open fire no such dud ok maybe I
think it's because Emacs has not loaded
the email is smart it's let's control XE
quit let's start Emacs again stop
warning an error occurred while loading
init file is missing cannot open load
file ok ok so let's try to do this so so
control X F dot Emacs dot P in it yeah
and the wind let's let's try the dart
yeah okay I don't think that's a problem
but ok control now
control X control e ok Co fire missing
now let's try the full path okay it's
much easier if I just walk on okay over
here because okay so in it
okay so copy the okay so this knit let's
close this control X see okay don't say
okay exit yes exit yes
okay now let's let's walk over here so
okay so that you see that's what we want
so let's try it again
warning error occurred while loading
that file is missing what what the file
is missing
okay maybe wait this is a full path why
is it file missing
an error occurred while loading that
file is missing cannot open load fire
cannot open load fire oh no such file
directory sorry place payers that's that
is why okay so I know why so okay so
let's dudes it's open let's go to my old
in it so actually let's let's go to
Emacs block let me show you from Emacs
blog so Emacs block you go to the in
each set up then on the first link there
is an explanation of in it files now in
it files you have okay there is a
section about install packages ok this
page is about milpa but we are not using
our path let's look at install packages
manually so this here explains what's
going on what's involved when Emacs slow
the package so you need these two lines
basically you need to tell Emacs where
the packages are I think well I I mean I
think that's what I'm missing so let's
go back to the init file over here so
let's see add to list load path ok so
let's do that and we don't we don't need
that okay so that's what we're going to
try you know what we did is we we want
to tell Emacs that Lisp directory is
where the package lives so let's try
that again control X control C ok let's
start
Emacs again stop yay the power of
knowledge it works ok now let's try
control X control F then then let's go
to let's open wait yeah so let's open
a HTML file let's see it works so
control X control F ago Emacs dog okay
Emacs slash blog dot HTML that's my
Emacs blog it works yeah you see you see
now it says the major mode is saw HTML
you can see so for example let's call
let's call described ba okay let's meet
our X describe ba okay the invariable
major - mod okay now it says the value
is side remark so we are success
successful so that's that's that that's
about that that finishes that let's see
any questions post okay then yeah okay
that's it for today so so yeah so so if
you so volodymyr says if you have
several send boxes to play with packages
in isolation and you want to start
multiple instances of Emacs again it's
different configs okay so if you want to
that to that there's a there are several
ways I can this let me show you one way
okay maybe maybe you already know that
or maybe it's easier
okay yeah so what we did okay so what we
did let's let's see let's so yeah so
this this is successful it's created
let's quit we don't need it anymore so
we installed from scratch now the way we
did it is that we renamed our Emacs
entire Emacs init directory
you know Emacs 30 we named it so so -
Emacs you know it's as if we don't have
unit file so we basically start from
scratch but that's one way to do it we
don't have to do it this way because
right now we can start Emacs you know if
we are if we are load the new init file
we just created
you see you will load this but we can
tear it - not - okay so we just say that
- Q okay this way this way
Emacs you know Emacs began it it does
not load any any file okay but now you
can also tell it tell MX to load a
specific init file so let's try it again
close it control X control C so now you
start - Q download any in it but then
you say - - load then the path to the
new in it which is let's just copy it
from here okay so now second copy
okay so that not Tiesto so - - okay hold
on a second
yeah so that copy so so you can tear it
to load okay this way
Emacs we load the unique value specified
let's try it
yep yep it's working you see the the
background is my color but it's running
into some errors because some paths
other things anyway because so yeah so
this this is a convenient this is a good
way this way you don't have to change
the directory name and all that you can
just use the you know - queue and - load
I have a tutorial discussing that if you
go to Emacs script examples if you go to
Emacs practical eMac this you know this
machinery going on in my neighborhood
very loud I think they are making their
building buildings so let me show you
let me show you the link okay
run Ellie's scripting shell okay yeah so
here you can see all the options for
Emacs to begin you have known that not
long name or you have show name so yeah
typically say load load path they are
loaded particular you need file so
that's it for today thank you guys for
watching if you like my stuff by my
Emacs tutorial ok on my website bye
yeah the the headphone they filter they
do filter out the external sound but
it's very loud to me I need to close
windows well to see you guys