good morning everyone
I'm making myself comfortable and today
I have apple juice and welcome to
another episode of talk show and today
we're gonna talk about interesting
things hello Isaac great to see you
I sac where are you from I forgot
can you hear me
wait my computer is super slow God geez
okay so let's talk let's not talk it hey
new apple juice sponsor hey break the
loop loud and clear great Oh Isaac is
from California California now there are
two departments of California northern
in the southern which which department
are you your computer maybe Stokes nah
but your mind is fast thank you
okay there's something wrong with the I
guess you you guys can see the video
right but what's going on with this you
know god okay so talk show today is oh
my god today is what fourth Oh
today is third actually today is the
second one this is the second one I did
today I did one earlier five five in the
morning okay so let's get on instead of
me like you know wasting time wasting yo
got you guys time that's not good okay
Isaac says North is better is yeah well
I don't know if for sure I mean north of
course but because I heard I heard that
you know that guy that in entrepreneur
what's his name he started PayPal he
moved to Southern California he moved to
Los Angeles area but I always liked the
northern you know the San Francisco a
better area better because the southern
part seems to be well I never lived
around Los Angeles but so I actually I
don't really know but I you know I I
thought you know somehow I have then I
mean it's you know Hollywood and stuff
you know Hollywood fake sleek salesman
kind of people that's what I thought but
yeah I don't really know so today we're
gonna talk about web spam scam blackhat
SEO
action SEO collection so it's about
spamming techniques you know spam and
scam and blackhat you know marketing
it's it's like this these concepts are
all related you know it is kind of just
different aspects you know first of all
you have SEO you know SEO is the word
Google invented you know in the
beginning this suspect and Google was
still considered good you know the good
guys like to know Evo but even back then
this day I think it's they do things you
know on a surface it's like no evil but
actually that's just the marketing to
the programmers to the Nerds to the you
know to to us nuts who are you know very
concerned about privacy and everything
so they started this SEO you know search
engine optimization that is supposed to
be I mean the idea is that you know you
you have such engines in there are
billions billions of websites and you
know it's a good idea so that you that
they publish rules so that as a
webmaster you know many of us
programmers are webmasters we create
websites so that we can adjust our
website so that it's easier for the
search engine to find find us
therefore rank higher you know for the
actually well that that's the pretext
that's a you know the the reason for the
Google began with SEO you know search
engine optimization but it's got but but
actually half of that is that I mean the
half of it is actually just get you to
help them that is the key you know they
are big cooperation money is their thing
money is their game money is there as
core the soul core of you know Google
any corporation in America basically
because America is a captain you know
capitalism country which is very good by
the way
I'm fully supported but
but so so corporations you know they
their goal is to make money in fact they
are public corporation you know we get
into the kindig allottee of enterprises
and corporations and inc and this thing
but but anyway their goal is to make
money and in America you have the public
companies meaning that once you trade
trade on the stock market you know
roughly we you know like you can you you
can buy the stocks you no longer own the
company like nobody is like nobody's
actually owning Microsoft or Google or
Twitter or Facebook okay they are owned
by people like you and me okay you have
money you you buy the stocks you own it
and but this idea is not to most people
do not understand it too well
because we every day we blame Google you
know and and Facebook and Microsoft but
actually you should blame yourself
because that's what people made it you
know all of us made it that way Google
is that way because we made it that way
because you know they are public traded
stocks you know of course many people
may not agree I mean I mean I'm kind of
simplifying the issue but I'm trying to
get to the point like my my my my
opinion like the the gist of opinion
about how things actually are so my
opinion so the thing is you know there
are public traded companies which means
that they are owned by everyone and
their behavior is basically created by
us essentially you know but of course
that's not all I mean we cannot simply
say that if a company is bad such as
Google then we simply blame us that's
that's not quite right as well because
well anyway so Google you know they want
to make money though so they created
this SEO basically the the gist
you know a big chunk part of it is that
to get you to help them make money but
you don't see that
are you here is that yeah okugo is so
great so ethical so transparent they
created this rule so that you know we
can help ourselves you know make our
website ranked on the top but actually
they just get you to play there again
you know to help them create their
search engine better but anyway so and
well that's that's kind of the simplify
story there are a lot spammers and
scammers I mean even before the SEO you
know if you guys don't work on the
website you may not know about SEO or
the website competitions I know because
I've been running website you know since
like nineteen nineties nineteen ninety
seven I have a website the the the the
domain name sorry talk began in year
2000 then then and and you know but all
this time up to like 2010 it's all just
me creating information for free and
it's for fun your friend is room for
myself
there's no you know ads or anything like
that it's you know I just like to write
about things create opinions now where's
my other pain I need my pen because I
can wait wait there's a significant lag
with my video today
is there something wrong you see I need
my pen to throw them okay why is this
too
okay so anyway back to AC SEO stuff
studio mod stop streaming I don't
understand why is my video is lagging
today close fool truth I mean close the
okay so let's get back to the video
preclude the seis break through the loop
says sorry info must have good SEO
because he often no well I guess because
not I tried to do SEO a lot but that's
not I don't think it has much to do with
ranking high because I spent huge amount
of time oil I think well you know get to
the bottom line is that I think rather
because you guys are you know
programmers take people you know so and
I write I read a lot of things you know
opinions on programming that's not like
popular subject so whenever you search
something popular subjects such as such
as list comprehension or closure you
know this kind of weird topics then you
find my website only because only
because they are not really that much
out there you know and you know and
usually if it exists usually it's just
one block you know it's blocks now
blocks is different from website if you
run read essays on website you know over
the years you accumulate that has a
better presence than just like one-off
blog unless you unless you are very
popular blogger and also writing style
for blogs is very different from from
creating a website with good index you
know that you could you know I spent
huge amount of time you know
I mean in the past 20 years I spent you
know five hours a day working my website
every day you they are tricked like
yesterday I just I have to remove 700
links on Google to Google Plus and
reformat and you know you see okay so
what I'm saying is as some of my
articles appear you find it because
really because the subject matter they
are not much out there okay a few
programa do that you know you work in a
company you make 10,000 20,000 a month I
make $1000 a month I mean so so you
don't write it I mean even if you write
a book you know the most popular book we
talked about this year they if you write
the most popular sold you know
JavaScript okay you make only you know
ten thousand dollars tops and you spend
like you know one year full time to
write it so some of my articles are
popular but actually nobody read them
because I know because I have my logs
you know I might you know show you guys
you know and but the other important
thing is about web traffic popularity is
that the thing I really spent huge
amount time working on for example
JavaScript in-depth I spent two years on
basically two years full-time you know
roughly one one to two years full-time
eight hours a day at least on these
nobody there's no traffic okay me well
there's some you know maybe 100 a few
hundred a day but they're there they
have a few hundred articles just by
count of articles we have here andriy
archived articles there but they D
there's no traffic
okay and also for example I mean this
javascript euro is fairly it's it's
pretty good you know okay so and there
are others for example the C programming
language Torrio's Python is my Python
tutorials you know is pretty it's also
very good but
basically there's no readers okay I know
also eMac Emacs this well I got some
well okay that what I'm trying to say is
that for example JavaScript tutorial ok
JavaScript tutorial you search the web
they are quite a lot and they have
traffic they have a lot of traffic but
however their content is not good you
know they like tutorial point you know
if you search JavaScript tutorial they
are turns and you know you know they are
created by by corporations or by income
you know Inc they are so goal is to make
money which is a bit different for me
because I am kind of a nerd I create
JavaScript I want to show you know I
know the stuff in detail and that's one
thing you know that's just my habit my
native intention it's kind of like that
but partly I also make it good so that
you know I wanted to beat general and
you know not you know I have a lot of
ants but in this JavaScript tutorial or
some other tutorials I I don't you know
I don't mix rent so I try to just be
like professional but anyway so no
traffic however on the other hand you
know they are quite a few you know
hundreds maybes web sites that focus on
programming tutorials and they are
content it's not so good but they have
traffic because they they are they are
intention they are dedicated to make
money they have you know PR they have
marking departments departments they
they have Twitter accounts they are post
on Twitter is you know they have data
statistics guide you know about with
what time to post how many times to
repeat it you know how do you Ward it
you know I mean so they have just one
code to make money and so that that they
become very popular and you know
actually I think part of the reason I
blame the Google SEO ok Google it
up you know Google created this and they
become it becomes an industry like
today's Twitter you know or elsewhere
social networks Facebook you know it's
all clickbait Creek Big Creek
clickbait you know with little content
but however they have a lot of traffic
you know they make money you know they
yeah so so that was so SEO you know
Google created the SEO we've been
talking a lot so how many guys are
watching so oh good
is it all good so say something say hi
so let me go back to the topic Google
SEO so we kind of went into that
direction quite a bit and it's all get
back let's get back to my articles so I
actually I got a lot to talk about on
this topic so Google so Google began
with the SEO okay then Google which I I
don't see it as good I see it as you
know rather sinister half half half of
it is not good I mean this is even back
then before Google became you know evil
empire but let's get back to SEO
okay so SEO then then Google created
this let's let's look at its search for
Google okay it's not here Google created
this no no link tag hey no man some
Roman says it's a page rank of your tech
pages punished
due to the more adults no on that aspect
no but you know there are many other
issues about that they do punish you for
example Kesari doggy spend oh yeah
there's a lot to talk about the year a
lot Google has banned me before sorry
Google and okay
google adsense google adsense pan on
asian asian asian goddesses okay that's
one this is another okay there is
another one patron bandsaw gone yeah
that's that's getting very bad these
days you know if you don't subscribe to
the social justice ideas they open you
and and this one i got banned in quite a
lot places because i talk too much
om i wrote viewer that's that's a big
controversy in second life community
like if you are not in a community you
don't know but if you are in some
community such as certain gaming
communities they are literally you know
millions people playing it around the
world you know and they are like
controversies you know like like almost
every month you know big controversies
and you know you know that when you are
in that community for example Emax is
the example there's lots of
controversies every year so anyway so
what so what i was going oh yeah okay so
this one thing i want to say about okay
yeah google ban good google adsense spam
they banned me basically three like
three incidents over the ten years okay
this this one is the second one but i
want to find out original i mean let me
talk about this then sorry google ban
have since been break the loop says what
does it look like when you see view
statistics of your home website like you
can see a ranked list of Devi yeah of
course
you know cuckoo provide that for you
okay so apparently you guys don't know
about this subject you know Google
Google had egg this Google analytic you
know I'm not sure I want to show you
guys because it's kind of private but I
don't think I don't think I care but
it's kind of like private you know
because because the website if you run a
website you know these stuff okay if you
run a website I mean if you run a
website where your goal is to I mean you
survive on the website you there are
quite a lot people do that you know like
medians I mean it's an industry you know
and and and they they it's like cut so
you know you see how competitive you
know you know how politicians are very
competitive you know they do what you
know by all means what they can to you
know kick out their enemies and same
thing with corporations Google Facebook
Twitter you know Google created Google
first because you know Google is fear
you know they are gonna rot away because
you know the social media and they are
not part of the game so they they try to
push Google+ and it turned out a failure
you know a complete failure
and now Google's strategies like they
are saying okay we're gonna do AI a is
the future
you know who is the good at AI controls
the web and stuff but anyway so Google
Facebook Twitter this odd you know
Giants at the top okay but anyway for
small writers like even on Twitter you
can see spam spam every day why do they
spend because there's money there's a
lot money you know there you see these
spammers you know to to nerds you know
because we find it I know
and usually I don't like that you know
typical elite hackers waste the way they
thought they what they to use usually
you know they start to have you know
blacklist Penfield you know like tech
like spy versus spy you know you do that
I do this I think my tech is better than
yours I wiped you out you know they they
do that and it things gets worse and
worse the society gets worse then you
have to you know anyway on Twitter you
see all those spammers you know like all
kind of yeah so I have like a list of
them here I document it but anyway why'd
they do that because they are huge
amount of money involved you know and
fake news fake news websites you know
they they make more money than for
meaning of them and they make more money
then then say if you work at Google okay
and you know yeah so so because the
money so and and Google is no fool of
course Google this giant being powerful
and everything Google pushes it because
first of all you know Google is you know
the money came from ads so they want you
to create website you know well we're
gonna make the BET Award let me help you
know Google has help pages you know help
for programmers help for webmasters how
do you create a big website how do you
you know write JavaScript Coogler has
their own version of JavaScript tutorial
you know HTML tutorial CSS they tell you
the page speed Google page speak
application they help you like they help
you they make the better word actually
all the things they do and even on
YouTube you know like this page like you
know dashboard you know video manager
community yeah you know join the
community channels they help you
analytics here so YouTube has what's
so-called analytic what is analytic
analytic is basically it's an industrial
world for the you know website marketing
kind of community analytic is like
basically statistics logs who is viewing
where your website or video okay who is
viewing it
what time they view it from what country
geography they view it you know and and
which link or which video has the most
viewers which link you know gets you
people start to follow follow you how
many you know it's called analytics you
know Twitter has it too I can I can show
you you so this so Google has analytics
for the YouTube you can see a trigger to
so if you guys you know you are not
surviving on website so YouTube you
don't know if you are YouTube you if you
are a YouTube star you know you know
these things okay so what do you where
did it go revenue okay hope of you okay
big you know my view Tube channel you I
don't have much viewers you know each
video is like hundred viewers the pity
so you don't see much here but anyway so
Anna analytic is a big industry okay
it's a our company is dedicated to it
you know the whole marketing anything
related to marketing advertising it's a
huge industry because there's so many so
much money you know involved it's like
billion dollars you know industry so but
so analytics is it's basically
statistics you know your audience what
you know and they also have page about
your age you know age of your audience
gender and the interest of your audience
like I can show you but I'm not sure I
want to show you the casa website
analytics you know you know which gender
what interest group are they like into
an entertainment tech or you know
education you know categories you know
and and let's look at Twitter ok Twitter
to you you probably have seen it GRI
tteo calm analytics okay
yeah tweeted you know these days is let
me turn on okay let's go to sorry sorry
okay and okay so here's my Twitter and
you are see I'm gonna show you some
example of analytics I'm not sure you
see it now
let's see my tweets now when you use
Twitter do you see these or not let me
know because I'm wondering maybe they
only show it to people who has
significant like post like here okay do
you guys see this window when you when
you log into Twitter let me know okay
guys let me go back to the video
where is my
I want to go back to the video so I can
see how long I've been talking okay I
guess I can see it here 28 minutes but I
don't know how many people are watching
though let's go back okay so go back my
computer is slow look at the CPU basel
fire filed fired hood okay i'm back here
that's right
but 13 watching okay so studying viewers
great so you know so do you guys see
these Twitter but when you're on Twitter
let me know so you know it should so
this is treatise analytics you know they
they began to have these about maybe
five years ago so they tell you you know
which treat you know has how many views
at what time you know it's genuine chav
statistics why because now if if you
don't sell things you don't know
yeah but I create website I know because
because then because they you know all
these tens of hundred thousand people
they need this information because this
is an information where they get they
sell stuff and Twitter itself needs this
information Twitter knows exactly you
know when when when to put ad you know
when to add an ad so it hacks has
maximum viewers you know they don't know
you know they want to know if you goes
habit interesting or that so in this in
the same way a lot you know people who
sell things you know use Twitter as the
marketing you know the so-called
marketing so so Twitter provide this
information for you it's extremely slow
right now because I guess you know
because I'm doing a video but anyway um
my is it cranking strong really load and
also Twitter provide this information so
also Twitter is selling ads you see you
know if I want my summer my treat to you
know to go spread then you know you you
pay Twitter there they'll sell they'll
do that so anyway the marketing is a
huge industry that's that's why all
these spans now let's let's let's go
look at some of them
YouTube's cameras steaming video okay so
this guy so this guy YouTube it's also
very bad on YouTube so these guys slick
reviews
he's basically copy or other people all
these are other people's video reviews
on different things so he copied them
put on onto his own channel and in each
think they have he's got you know Amazon
links so you can buy it and he get a
percentage he copied so one day a guy
who told me who is probably watching me
now he told me so so he he stole one of
my video where is it here let's see so
what this guy do is to copy your video
review videos and put in his own channel
with Amazon affiliate links there is a
ok few days ago he stole on my video but
anyway I got I got him to take it out I
I sent a report to Google to YouTube so
he's doing that oh break the loop so you
don't see those analytics okay so I
think so yeah so i think you know try to
only show that when twitter detect you
know
yeah they you know when they detect you
are someone who is like trying to market
something you know such as me because
i'm posting my website all the time and
the reason i'm doing it because i want
to people to visit why do i want to
people to visit because i got add their
ads there so you know my people may buy
my keyboard or my other ads you know
well you know a lot of you don't because
i mean world for nerds
you know my primary audience the not
technique because you know the sensitive
about privacy and all that and Emacs
users and pro open source free software
foundation all of you guys has already
ads turned off you have adblock
yeah so i thought so but but still
but anyway it's not loading now for some
reason because i guess because i got
my CPU is full but anyway so um so you
got that you know you know they tell you
like you know which treats which time
you know a lot of things but anyway
that's that's that's called analytics in
an industry and this is I mean you know
don't mistake it you know that it's like
really a billion dollars business
because you can you can see there a lot
of startup startups companies you know
doing you know you don't know these
things in general because they are not
like public facing company they are not
like Twitter or Facebook you know for
the consumers they are for business you
know but anyway so so back to so this
guy you know he's a YouTube scam so
let's look at another one this
JavaScript guy teacher I talked about
the other day so let's not talk about
that he is on Twitter with web spam from
2018 so let's look at this one so since
2017 there are tens of scan sites of
deep domain carrying my name back sorry
okay yes so that is that no you know I
also talked about this the other day
so basically okay let's do it then
basically you go to Google like every
day since when since since 2017 yeah
okay since about July 2017 every day
they are like tens of new domain names
containing a page that says spike sorry
okay like every day so you go to google
you search my name sorry okay then it's
important you get this okay if you have
JavaScript on there's a tools you want
to check the past hour and past 24 hours
so if you click that you see let me show
you you see
this this is a scam site you know it's
one of the scans are these two I don't
know what they are but they are like
sorry sorry okay if you look at past 24
hours
so this one is scan this one is
this one is this this scam spam
okay next page spam spam spam spam spam
you know it's like tens of them I
haven't actually tried to count them and
I haven't actually tried to you know
lock them and compare the domain names
to see if they you know just how many
are there but you know every day I do
this regularly you know check my name
check check to see who linked to my
website and stuff so you see another
page then you got you know Tim oh you
know so these are you know you know
spams so that that so that is this
article web spam from 2018 you know
throughout the years like since 20 years
ago you know the techniques changed you
know because the industry changed a lot
good you know and you know ok donate
video the China is PR the injection I
talked about this last time basically if
you are in China and you view my website
which is HTTP not HTTPS then for example
you are see this page now this is my
website viewed from China and on a lower
right you see this ad that's not my ad
so basically the ISP inject their own ad
you know into my website you know so
that's I iced the injection in China and
this one Snopes yeah schnapps is also a
huge scan you know it began it began
like 20 years ago it was good but it
became a scan you know they you know
back then like like 20 years ago you
have this phenomenon called email link
what is called chain mail so basically
you send an email to someone then it
tells you to email other people usually
it shameful things like something
dangerous like your needle in a seat in
a theater you know things like that so
people spread you know they have lots of
techniques to get people to spare so so
you see that email you think oh this is
important this is all I need to warn my
friends about needles in a seat
you know in movie theaters so you you
you send it to your friends and there is
a spread so actually snobs I might be
mistaken is it snobs there's another
website similar
I think it's knobs yeah the other one is
Caesars Caesars answer or something does
anyone remember the name like Caesars
anyway it's it was snobs yeah so the
snob guy they actually run those spam
chain mail farm servers they were
because the more they they create these
fake news okay so called fake news today
then the more people likely to find out
oh is that really true is a is it an
urban legend
then the visit snobs more business and
lately in the past you know few years
they became the social justice can you
know they are you know they do a lot of
things too in that in that direction
straight up yeah straight up yeah that's
the other one I'm thinking yeah but but
the bad I know for sure the snow peas
the you know the one that scam spam and
also a few years ago they they had a law
lawsuit basically they've you know they
make a lot money but they have a
financial fight with another company
basically they try they hired another
company like market marketing a company
to do the marketing for them but then
you know something happened they
disagree and one refused to pay the
other things like that then they went to
hacker news you know to make a
appear like oh we are snobs we you know
thought you know me because I provide
all this good information for you but
today I want to tell you that this bad
guy
you know who is you know not paying us
you know because this these snobs is the
Scots come in the first place then he
collaborated with another scat scum you
know to squeeze money then something
happened between them ending then snob
wants to go to hacker news to tell
people oh the design that Snopes yeah
but how do you how do I know they are
scan you know you you you have to spend
you know hours and days you know take
information you like usually when when
something like this happens
controversial you know you can never be
sure you know do you have proofs I don't
have proofs okay but however the thing
is when you look at something when when
something is controversial or a scam
like you can you know I don't want to
say this in my absolute sense like
hundred percent but you can usually tell
there is you know they are just they are
not good to begin with you know like you
know and they are talking about millions
of dollars not not like you know one
thousand dollars so I need $1,000 to
survive they the Snopes can Snopes
and the other part okay the other part
kind of thing you can tell when a
website is go really bad let's go
through the weight okay let's go to the
full URL so I paste URL here but I want
to make it a this is a local file path I
want to make a website so that's the
website now I just call you in brave
open linking grave okay now I'm viewing
my website in paid now let's turn
JavaScript on so you can see those
movies I mean the view YouTube links
okay reload my computer is like super so
for some reason I don't know CPU OBS is
taking all this time
okay I don't know if that helps but
vt decode X PC servers what the is
that
anyway so snows okay anyway so let's go
to schnapps I'm gonna show you you know
one thing you can tell when a website is
is your money oriented scam is is when
they have they look like pretty like
they have this Java they have JavaScript
full of it you know tracking full of it
and pretty like you know a logo you know
everything and in their language is
always like appeasing like we are here
to help you you know to provide the
information for you to help the American
democracy you know it's you know all
nice and sweet and you know well you
know you see pretty these pretty things
you know when you see what I've said
like that usually you know they're after
you for something that's one way you can
tell okay so let's go back that's so
that snows actually so I have a lot you
know twelve people watching forty-three
minutes I guess we can go on so any any
comments so far any questions any
comments
you see I what I wanted to do show you
is actually something interesting
because somehow some of these scam or
spam tactics are interesting I mean yeah
like you can see for example okay this
one this one is back in 2012 you know
they use Unicode of to a few skate to
confuse you know the spam filters so
they use this small Greek letter Omega
that looks like a W so they replace o W
by by this character you know so this is
you know I highlighted all the ones in
yellow you can kind of tell I highlight
them in yellow you see this word people
that P is not the Latin alphabet P that
p is a I think Greek or something but
anyway there's a name to this this code
Unicode anyway there's a name I forgot
I'm not using you know the jargon but
there's a name for this technique using
Unicode so anyway so so you know people
doing that so this is back in 2012 again
remember that the techniques and
technology changes so you don't see this
anymore because you know after its
popular for a while then Google you know
other sides they they they found a way
to you know detect that so you know this
kind of you don't see this anymore so
this is 2012 and you see all these I
collected they are posted to my to my on
my Google blog website I cured my Google
blogger website wait okay so you can see
you know that is quite a few of them and
look it and and look at this one please
tell me how beautiful I okay so here's a
comment it says hello I've been
following your blog for some time now
and finally
the courage to go ahead and give you a
shout-out from Porter Texas just wanted
to tell you keep up the excellent work
and then it says my website
you know website a link you know this
this this is also a common
characteristics of a common spam you
know they they say something that's
freezing you know where I see this the
first time I thought wow oh wow somewhat
you know like to my you know essays you
know there's someone appreciated my
essays but it's very common you see this
all the time you know in different forms
over the years and people fall for it
because that's like one common human
weakness you know you want to like when
you would you know when when you know
you get praise from someone you you know
you are touched unicode a confusable no
I don't think that's term they use I
mean they they like they have a term for
that Unicode they have a term I forgot
but it's but if we search that I think
we will find it
Unicode okay I don't think no I
it's not confusable its code oh so so
único utility they have a confusable
okay so I guess it's official that's
also a official term now okay but the
the word I'm thinking is is a different
one yeah the word I'm thinking oh yeah
homework life that's what I'm thinking
homo life attack it's such a homo life
and there's a wikipedia website on it
anyway that that was the term I was
thinking okay so Unicode confusable
that's interesting I have to check it
out so there is so that there is this
one spam text collection Unicode of
obfuscated spam okay okay so what's this
one
okay these are collection of bad
comments bad spam comments okay so
lame-o spammers please come back when
your skill is better so let's read this
one so he says I got this webpage for my
buddy who shared with me regarding this
website and at the moment this time I am
visiting this website and reading very
informative articles or reviews here too
long
feel free to visit my web page you know
who wants to visit your page nobody so
this is this is a ineffective
comment spam he failed to be pleasing he
failed to kiss-ass
that's what he is okay here's another
one this is 2014 Twitter it is this this
also named for this one's fav spam it's
like there are people who favorite your
tweets all the time and it still happens
today because now and then I got you
know followers
you know I got followers I look at their
account there is no way you know they
would like you know they are my type I
mean they are different they they are
not programmers okay I noticed for
example I can remember there's a one
woman who sell books
who is custom kind of a book market
marketer for authors for book publishers
okay she followed me I see what way you
know what how could it possible I mean
you know I I cannot see any treats I
make that she would find interesting but
I've noticed she follow me but
you know in the next year she I noticed
she followed me again
so apparently sometimes she unfollowed
then followed again you see so people do
that because when you follow some of my
follow you you tend to follow back I
mean there's some good chance you will
follow back you know because that's
that's a again another human psychology
you know you return the favors you know
so they do that they they you know they
follow you you follow back but after
month they may unfollow you but actually
anyway they don't beat your post at all
you know it's just you know they just
they just to follow so they may unfollow
you but so you end up you follow them
but you don't necessarily check you know
all the time who you you know who and
father do so so they so they appears to
have you know they become they they cut
a lot followers you know
oh by by all these you know techniques I
mean I mean there is a industry I mean
if you are into you know if you sell
sell something you if you are in this
market you actually we all know these
things because there's there's websites
that help you you know all these
techniques SEO you know how to do it
there are websites that tell you what's
the current hot phrases you should use
keywords you know you know it's an
industry and this one span dishes oh
yeah by Twitter followers you know you
get that and and you can buy Twitter
followers you can buy YouTube followers
and you know it's Facebook and also on
Chinese website you have also you know
China they always they have their own
social media they have their own YouTube
website you know quite a lot when very
good as well you know I have looked they
are like I'm just yeah I'm kind of
amazed by you know the going ons in
China so they have like their own
YouTube you know I mean you know like in
USA okay YouTube is basically the only
one I mean they are Vimeo and others but
in comparison to number videos or number
of users it's like 10
YouTube is 10,000 you know a hundred
thousand times bigger you know so
there's no no competition really but in
China it's big I mean the China there
are a few for example let me show you
one Billy Billy Billy Billy okay just
remember the name peedee peedee you'll
find this one
okay there's also Wikipedia you can read
about it
this is a website this is a basically a
video website in China and and the
amount of users the number of videos is
comparable to YouTube now I don't know I
haven't I haven't looked
you know actually who is bigger but it's
possible this is even bigger than
YouTube yeah I don't know for sure maybe
not but I but you know it's it's very
big it's using a seer basically Japan
Taiwan as well you know in China Japan
Taiwan basically the East Asia countries
so and in fact you can you know just
like YouTube like YouTube is so big
today like you don't know where to look
I mean they are oh yeah I mean the way
you to know like everything is this on
youtube so so the way one technique to
find new areas new type of videos on
YouTube is that every day when you when
you think of searching some word try to
search it on YouTube okay don't think
before you do it don't think okay oh
this walkie what is probably not on
YouTube but any anything you know
anything you want to do something you
want to look up time you want to any any
idea you come up you know you might be
thinking try to type the word in YouTube
then you would start to discover yeah I
mean just things you never seen because
youtube doesn't you know there are
billions of videos you know they can
I'll show you you discover them but this
way so anyway yeah so this this PD PD in
China yeah so China also has you know
they are own civil
version of Facebook or Twitter you know
you know they have you know wait way but
lots of them and you can also the
spamming is also happening in China you
this this this ad is telling you to buy
followers you know in Chinese social
network because I was on there for a
while okay they are quite a lot so
actually so are we tired of the the SEO
topic this quite a lot thing going on so
Norman says ever seen the Amazon robots
that gets in pricing war and tried to
charge 100k for a book yeah I saw that
some people do that and I I remember
reading a story that some people
apparently I think he sold a blank book
like for $1000 and you know people I
mean yeah once in a while people do that
and actually they made money like $1,000
for a for a nothing yeah I actually I
have article about that
I don't remember what's the name to
search for the article sorry YouTube
iPhone Apple Store okay yeah so there
there is Apple censorship and yeah so
Apple censorship then this this this is
back in 2010 so this is this is like ten
years old
ever since uh shaped then yeah so into
in August 2008 and an application known
as I am rich was released in the store
work of art with no hidden function at
all with its only purpose being to show
the people that they were able to afford
it as it cost us one thousand
yeah so people bought it you know and
and also Gizmodo okay Gizmodo and coca
they are scams they are the scumbags
you know Gizmodo never visit kiss-kiss
model I'm going to take the link out
yeah they they are like scums so anyway
I was going to talk about something else
kind of so so what's up you guys should
I continue about finish about the scam
and spam or should I change a topic
because I was planning to talk about
algorithmic mathematical art but it's
kind of late for today because because
that one is gonna take twenty minutes at
least you know another topic is what is
crucial explain it
ensuring : javascript item Oh in 3d
graphics Tech yesterday I want to talk
about QuickTime because there is a
technology
sorry quick time there's a good 3d
technology but it never intro to video
codec he never it failed it you know it
shut down I have to find the articles
yeah but anyway that's another topic I
have to find the article it's not this
one this one is when back then back in
2010 I was looking into the video codecs
very complex but anyway what's up with
you guys
so anything ten people watching say say
something guys
let's see say something
so break the loop how's going have you
eaten
so you must have it's 10 o clock 10:30
so normal say it's late night here but
generative art is a fun topic for some
time yeah I don't have good things to
say about generative art yeah anyway so
we can talk about that so I hope so I
hope you guys have a good day
and that that's it for today so thank
you for coming by and I'll see you guys
next time bye