welcome
to another episode of star talk show
today is 2021st
june 5th and today we are going to talk
about
random stuff i'm going to work on
emac lisp emacs
workflow you are going to watch and
uh i'm going to work on my website
random stuff
and if you have questions this is the
right time to post it
um programming on keyboards on emacs on
mathematics on wolfram language uh
whatever topic okay just
post your questions in the chat box
chat box okay uh audio check
video check good so let's begin okay so
the keyboard you are looking at of
course
is the so let me show you
some of the keyboard stuff okay so
keyboard stuff ergonomic keyboard so you
are looking at my kinesis keyboard of
course
just search for saudi kinesis keyboard
you'll find my review
and the the other one is this this
one is the ultimate hacking keyboard
it's the greatest
marker keypad okay so
yeah i'm going to start to do to code
some emac lists
then when people come out and let's do
more things okay
so let's go to talk show today's talk
show
uh show in browser go back
okay turn on the javascript
and then go back and go open the
um open the
notes so these are a bunch of to-do's i
want to do
then let's see what we're going to do
today i'm going to
do some imac this coding
okay this one the first one some move
image file so let me show you what that
is about
okay good morning aaron dodd
okay so for example if you write a lot
of blogs
you know i write a lot blogs let's see
let's let's go to
uh let's see my keyboard marcos
so let's go to twitter the dramatic
drama twitter that's what
twitter is drama
so there is some for example of
this mathematics this guy this guy you
should follow okay this danielle
if you like mathematics and uh
not just you know anyway this beautiful
image
so let's say so if you write a lot blog
you know i want to make a screenshot of
this
so what i do so i press the button
then i select it for example screenshot
okay it's captured now of course it's
captured in the download folder
typically so let's go to download folder
let's show them there
where is it is it here okay it's not in
the download folder it's in the pictures
folder okay so
you can see in this folder now can we
magnify
okay so yeah you cannot magnify
you can but yeah anyway anyway so here's
a screenshot
but it's in a folder that's uh i have to
move this folder to my website directory
so it's tedious so i have this command
i'm gonna show you okay so wait
um go to the pictures
folder okay pictures so you can see
this is the file okay i can open it you
see now i need to move
that file to my uh to my
um web site directory so where is my
website directory let's say
let's go to math blog okay show in
browser so this is my
math blog so which is uh this file
and go to the directory so here is the
directory for my math blog so
at the top you can see here is the path
in the bottom let's magnify at the
bottom you can see the picture is in
this path
so i need to move this into this folder
then i i need to write a you know
tedious
so what i do is i don't have to do
move anything like that i just you know
this is my math uh
blog on this buffer this file i just go
to the place i want to
insert it create a new section
uh let's show it again so see create a
new section
then just watch the pink window okay it
will show the command i call
so press uh one three keys
it says move image two directory so okay
i want to move to the eye directory okay
then just enter enter then it is done
you see it's here now showing browser
fantastic so let's do it again okay
let's do another one okay so i'm going
to uh
screenshot this picture
okay now i just go to the file i want
and
press the key and it's done
now show in browser now we have you see
it's a huge time saver
so that's what this command is for and
by the way it also
um you can see
it also automatically optimize the png
because you know screenshot is the png
auto automatically optimize it
so that command is you can see in this
window
this command because i move image file
so that's a command i wrote in emacs
list
so let's uh let's so okay but anyway i
don't want this picture okay so deleted
open delete the file delete it
delete delete delete delete
show in browser it's gone okay so
now i want to show you the command so
this command is this one okay so
let's look at the source code source
code of this command okay
magnify so describe function
okay describe function paste the
function name
there is the function okay uh
sum of image file to the name move image
to another directory blah blah blah
uh it will automatically search several
directories
it will search in this list of
uh and we'll try to match file name by
this regular expression
so emacs is going to go through those
directories
and try to find the match if it's a
match it will move it
but let's look at the source code okay
so let's look at the source code
open the source code there it is
here is the code
okay 100 lines okay basically
so i need to now go to the
now i have a website for this code open
it
here's the file open in browser there it
is
move image file so you can you know it's
on my website
but however i have
updated this code so you see before
all these directories are hard coded you
know pictures directory downloads
directory
desktop directory document directory and
temp directory and home directory
those are hard coded in here and also
the regular expression to match the file
name is also hard coded you can see
it's here but however i have changed
you know i have updated the code so it's
so
so so the directory list and the regular
expression
list are now custom customizable
variables okay so you can see close that
so you can see let me show you okay so
here is the
define var some move image file from
does
you know so here's a list of directories
you can customize
for your own needs and here is a list of
image regular expression file patterns
for example anything that's named
screenshot
or you know different operating systems
they have different
default naming for the screenshot and
this
regular expression is for example amazon
files and and any file starting with
characters tt also move it so
for example if i want to do a screenshot
of anything
for example this one any anyway i
i don't want to i don't need to uh demo
i already did
hello xetron crazy where is what
okay so let me show you so so what i
need to do is to update so
let's show the pink window so you are
looking at my workflow so
copy copy uh wait starting from here
select them select them select them
select them copy now we go
i copy the whole thing now i want to
open the
um the file that contains the source
code of this
you know on my blog so this is a file i
need to delete this
and replace them with the new code okay
so
go here so we can press a button
okay now you see the source code now is
moved into a
a buffer by itself here you see
now if i refresh the browser it's empty
so now i just go to the
here and just paste
in the new code paste it in i just
copied before now showing browser
fantastic so you can see here's a
directory variable list of directories
and
here's the regular expression variable
and then the main code
okay now those are not syntax colored i
need to syntax color them
press a button done showing browser
fantastic
now i also need to update the last
updated date
you see it says 2021 january 15th
so what i do i press the button
and you can see it's 2021
june 5th go to the browser refresh
so all the commands i've done you can
see you can find them on the pink window
for example this one update article
timestamp and if you search it you'll
find the code
i'm using site.tml mod so most of the
code is in
html mod okay so show in
showing browser okay this is
explanation what this code does uh we
which we i just
explained so i'm going to there's one
more thing to do
so i need to say on my blog
that i have updated this code so if you
for example go to my web blog
i need to add a new entry that says okay
okay so copy the file path use the fast
open bookmark eb for emacs blog
open then go to the section here
so here is the section you see in the
browser
so i go to here add a new section
paste the file path linkify
it make a paragraph and go back here
and say break line break okay
updated code okay showing browser
there it is click on that fantastic
go back now i need to update also the
atom
the atom file you know the you know the
web
feed the rss
okay so move the cursor here
and press three buttons there it is
so you got this new entry emac smooth
image file
updated code okay close it yes
showing browser again fantastic we are
done we are done with this
uh this thing except you know we still
have the code
uh you know this temp code just delete
that file okay
so we are done with that any comments no
comments okay
so then let's move on to the next
thing we're gonna do of course i need to
sync my browser so press the button
launches the powershell the best
shell in the universe from microsoft
far better than bash and stuff i've
talked about i did a video on that
and you can go to my powershell tutorial
just go to xari powershell
powershell tutorial uh yeah i should
talk about this they are
quite i worked on this for several days
so there's quite a lot updates
in particular you want to look at this
example common
examples okay now powershell i talked
about before in in my in the past month
or two
uh is a much better you know
shell than all the unix unix shells and
two bags
bash t-shirt tcsh uh
kong xiao and and crap and set oak
you know all that find xox you know so
anyway powershell examples
this page is the is basically what you
want
uh the most okay uh it
gets you start to learning uh create a
new file just type in i file name create
a
new directory make the same as unix
actually it's a function
anyway so you know uh copy directory
uh copy file size and so on and
and uh find a command in unix which is
which you know which command name in
powershell it's get command or gcm
and print file cad for example unix card
drawing file
unzip these files you know find all
files that
has zero length these empty files
list backup emacs backup files list
files that's not the directory these
files with creation date
by the way unix even today linux
this is a question you know you ask any
of those unix
administrators or today called devops
you asked them
you know they they worked with unix for
five years or ten
you asked them how do you get the file
creation date
you know they don't know they will say
oh do it this way
if you know something dash c in fact
that's wrong
in unix including linux file creation
date is never recorded okay
that's a that's one of the eunuchs
pestilence
uh all the unix idiots they don't know
they think they know but they are wrong
you know try to ask you know ask of the
some
linux you know expert you think you know
maybe you think you are
how do you get the file creation date
okay it doesn't exist
it doesn't work it's not the dash
c okay
today okay so back so
so powershell fantastic okay so here is
a you know a bunch of examples
then there's more detail i cover how to
use powershell to
uh manipulate environment variables and
also by the way powershell is
cross-platform you know microsoft now it
is becoming the biggest giant
the biggest open source corporation
in the world you can measure it by
counting lines of code open source lines
of code or counting the github
repositories or project numbers by
microsoft that's a
microsoft is not the biggest open source
corporation and okay so i was going to
say the
net you know microsoft invented.net
which is a systematic
uh programming language environment they
invented that back in 2002
okay around 2002 and it's windows only
but starting about three or
four about five years ago okay they
moved everything now.net is now open
source
entire.net is open source so c plus plus
and f sharp you know f-sharp is a
functional programming language
comparable to haskell i would say even
more powerful than haskell
f-sharp which is a borrowed from ocamo
which is the lineage of meta language
ml okay so okay so let me show you my
face
since i'm talking so how many people are
watching
six miss v6 okay so let me
let me let me um
okay so we talked random powershell
let's see so this so i'm using this
mouse currently this is my
eye patch this mouse um and
you see the spin wheel is fantastic
spins you know why is it fantastic
you go to you go to for example you go
to
uh you go to one of my blog that has
lots of pages then now look at look at
the spin
spin okay this this is not long enough
you know if you are on twitter you know
for example twitter just spin
okay let's go to a math okay let's go to
profile
uh lists now i made my lists
private okay so let's go to math
so here's a my private math list so you
can just spin
and trader is gonna this is uh infinite
load
spin
you know so spinny mouse is what you
need
okay now let's go back let's um
yeah i still need a
camera holder i need a proper one
and i need a camera as well probably
okay so spinny mouse is fantastic okay
and you should buy let me show you
actually there's another one
this one is wireless okay also a
spinning mouse okay
so you see you see
it can spin for like 30 seconds
fantastic if you spin it fast
30 seconds
okay what's uh so let me go on to the
next topic
seamus yes indeed stream mouse you know
so so look at
you so i have reviews here let me let me
show you let me talk about the mouse
the mouse is okay so you go mouse here
and here is a spin mouse and there's a
video i recorded you can watch it
okay it's gonna spin for like 20 30
seconds
uh and uh yeah so about mouse you know
so i have so right now i'm using this
one fantastic
uh one of you know but it doesn't have
that many buttons okay there's
like two one two three four five kind of
five extra
buttons on the side but that that's not
enough actually
so why is it not enough uh i have
reasons okay i have lots of articles
about
why why you need
um why you need 10 button mouse okay
it's all detailed here
but anyway so that's one of the mouse
and here's the other
mouse i just showed you now which one is
better now this one is wireless okay uh
actually so let's go back to mouse okay
so both of these both of these this one
also
has a wireless version um
so which one is better well this one is
got you know
much more buttons one two three four
five six seven eight eight
on the side on the other hand this one
is only only one uh one two three four
five
so three more here um
they are slightly you know they
i would say either one is good okay
either one is good
uh this one the wireless one the main
buttons
are quieter okay so these
two buttons are the left and right
buttons are quieter
but however the mouse is more scooped
down
so can i show you
so if i can show you
yeah okay so let me let me show you the
mouse
since i'm talking about the mouse let's
see
let's see if i can do
okay so you can see now
so the buttons here it's
more like scooped down downwards
and this one is flatter okay so this
as far as the the slope goes this one is
better this one
because when you press it it's kind of
flat okay
so you can just press it like and this
one
your fingers have to curve down a little
bit but but however this
the buttons here on this one is quieter
i don't know if you can hear it let me
try okay it's not turned on
turn it on
now where's my okay i need to switch
so it's both bluetooth and also uh
bluetooth and also uh usb
wireless so now it's on so you can see
okay so now
uh so what what so the but yeah the
button
you can let's see if you can hear it
see this one is a bit louder but however
the side buttons you know it's got six
here
and it's got just one two three here
uh the side buttons this one is easier
to press
this one is a bit harder to press so
for the buttons i actually kind of
prefer these
okay that's that's about that
okay so let's now put the camera back
and let me turn off my alarm clock on
the
this thing alarm clock is going
uh what's your opinion on the new mi
apple chips
and uh is on the future i think so
you know because you know i i don't know
much about
cpus but however i have looked
hold on a second let me turn off the
mouse and i have to
i i have looked you know so so there's a
lot of youtube reviews of the m1 chip
and let me show you which video i
watched it's truly
fantastic apple okay um
so let me show you which review you know
this guy is
uh very popular but let me show you
the one i watched okay now this this
guy is a chipmunk you know this
this guy didn't lean us
review he is the classic millennial
generation gamer
idiot you will be really good at
petty petty and small and you know and
and
he needs to talk fast and he needs to
use jargons
to to kind of like
one annoying chipmunk
okay so but i want to show you the one
the video
that i liked okay not not this idiot
look at look at this millennial
generation these reviewers you know what
why are they doing review
you might be wondering why are so many
people like doing in
in these face is all over the place
you know look look
oh it's so you know he's funny
he's gonna put the you know faces the
idiots
these these are the millennial
generations and why are there so many do
you know why
because money you know google youtube
they you know these ads
uh ads makes the world go around okay
so anyway i want to find i want to show
you the one i watched
uh so the m1 chip the apple m1 chip is
truly amazing
you know i i'm you know i
okay i uh there's a lot of history you
know i used to be a mac
fan you know because my first mac is
1992.
i started to use mac since 1991
okay my well in 1990 you know i'm using
someone else's computer so
that's a ps2 ibm which is a high quality
computer but anyway my first
my the mac i bought myself mac 2si
is uh beginning 1992 and since then
almost every every every few years i
have a new mac
up to until 2000 anyway i stopped using
mac
in 2009 i talked about that before
anyway
so i'm going to say i was going to say
uh the mac the mi chip is truly
fantastic okay
uh so let me let me show you the
code fusion okay this this is the one i
watched
code fusion okay uh watch you know you
might check out this guy
now code fusion he's an interesting guy
okay so
he has a like not just one he has a few
let me hold on second
i i need i want i need to put on my eye
patch
because i have a little bit cross eye so
anyway you watch it so anyway the
bottom line is m1 chip is truly amazing
and i also learned the intel is a scum
okay intel you know the intel chip
inside is just gone
they produce very bad cpu but
they use their power to you know to push
so everyone thinks
intel is the you know best not really so
today
you probably want to buy amd okay amd is
much better
just don't don't don't buy intel and
then you have the bleeding
heart you know that that that that
that eunuchs and see idiots
they created that problem unix
unix philosophy and c and c plus plus
those
those those type of people and trust
they created that problem
uh you know you know what i'm talking
about so
guys who is watching say something okay
answer
seven people okay bleeding
uh bleeding what's the problem bleeding
bug cpu i forgot what's the name
heart bleed okay
[Laughter]
i'll bleed
okay let me finish uh so hard lick
bleed is one of the major uh
design bug in cpu
okay and why does that design work
happens because
because the c idiot the c programmers
you know and uh those people who love
rust
a lot of my uh people who watch me okay
let me show you my one of my article
okay
saudi.info now this okay
uh okay let me let me talk about that
programming okay programming
so by the way recently i did it i did a
new design of my home page
so now most of my articles can be found
directly on the you know home page
so let's go to
let's go to
syntax soup this complement pervin
semantic noodle let's go to semantic
noodle
okay so this is a collection of essays
related to programming language
design that and related to uh
semantics issues not syntactical issues
okay
let's turn on javascript so you can see
my
you know my video i talked about before
i did a video on that
so you want to go to um
so i have article this is important
uh let's see where uh
yeah programming language and their
machines okay
so you might be this is about if you are
interested
in programming language design and their
relations to the hardware
so what so the question is for example
what is the relationship
between algorithms and and cpu
what what is the relationship you know
is
algorithm you know tell me you know you
if you know programming you think you
know c or what whatever you think you
know unix philosophy you think you know
stuff
answer the question what is the
relationship
of algorithms and programming languages
and the hardware
you know the hardware can be abacus can
be a
quantum machine quantum computer can be
a
cpu gpu can be uh you know
those are all hardwares so the in the
most general sense what what is the
relationship
try to come up with an answer what's the
between a programming language and
algorithm
and uh hardware okay hardware can also
be tuning machine
can be uh lambda calculus you know the
these are
models foundations of uh
computation okay so the article i will
actually
i want to show is um this one okay
programming language and its machine
okay so first of all there is this uh
fantastic article c
is not a low-level language you know if
you are
if you code in c uh c plus well plus you
should read this okay
and by the way my i anyway anyway so
so here so anyway i don't know much
about
cpu stuff i don't know much about
low-level programming stuff
but i started to learn about them in the
past five years
from a you know mathematical and
theoretical computer science background
that's what i have
so this is my kind of my my essay and
also my note to myself
and i think it's informative
for many of you guys to watch okay even
if you are
you know industrial programmers you know
you have 10 years
experience coding c blah blah blah i
think this
will still be informative to you this
article
and especially by this guy okay this guy
uh
c is not a low level language okay so
anyway so you try to read this article
and you'll see
you'll start to understand the
many of the issues about cpu design and
and and and and what what what is that
bleeding
you know heart bleed why does this
problem occur
what exactly is the problem now this
this problem is kind of
advanced so you might read other places
lots of blogs
talks about it but you may not quite
understand it
so you might try you know give my
give my essay you know my article a try
then you'll start to understand
many of the issues about cpu design and
things like that
programming language and its machine
okay instruction
set architecture what are they and micro
architecture what are they
cpu design and random notes okay so this
is my
kind of my take you know complex
instruction set computer and reduce
instruction set computer and so on so
anyway so
and okay so i actually i have okay so
yeah
so i wrote an article about apple m1
chip i forgot this is just my notes
so you go you know just search for um
actually i'm not sure you can find this
article
because i don't think it's a popular
article so
sorry apple m1 chip
yeah you okay you can find the article
so
so watch these videos okay this one is
by
max tech and this one is by
that code fusion so apple m1 chip is
fantastic
it's a breakthrough it's truly a
breakthrough and what i was going
to say is that i would i have been you
know i
i've been i've been around i was a fan
of apple
apple transitioned from you know
motorola chip
then transitioned to risk chip power pc
in 2005 then transitioned back to intel
around
in 1995 apple transitioned from motorola
to
power pc chip then in 2005
apple transitioned from power pc chip to
intel again
then today in 2020
also apple transition from intel to the
their own m1 chip which is a risk
ri sc chip okay so again you want to
read my article to understand
uh hold on a second uh where's my
article again
that looks lost my article so let's show
let's show it again
uh so code you go
to xr code semantic noodle
then you go to
uh programming language and its machine
okay so you read
this article you can kind of understand
and also uh these videos so apple m1
chip is truly a breakthrough it's not a
you know apple is known for marketing
gimmicks
but mri chip is truly a breakthrough in
cpu
you know and i think they have a great
future
but then again but but again i mean i
mean that's
that's good aspect of apple okay but
apple has also
many bad aspects for example whenever
they have a new iphone
they make they use software to make your
iphone slower
so you you buy a new one you know that's
a
that's a scumbag practice apple apple do
a lot of that
today and apple create their computers
so everything
so it cannot be fixed you have to you
know you just have to buy a new one
and meanwhile they pretend you know they
say they are the greeniest company
they are all support for diversity green
earth and crap
okay that's about that no comments
so m1 chip is great okay and also
yeah it's great okay so watch this video
and read this article okay
bleeding heart yeah that's uh you know
the the the
problem uh and code fusion is an
interesting guy okay he
he makes a lot interesting videos you
know
uh you know he's one of the popular
popular youtuber
almost three million followers
uh so one day you know like who the
is code fusion i'm very skeptical
when i watch youtube you know i because
i think most
most most people are dummies so
i you know so i did some research
you know i just looked up who is he and
he has an introduction about himself
uh turns out he's a a guy in australia
and uh you know yeah he's a good i
so i would recommend i recommend code
fusion
videos he talks about a lot of things
related to technology and innovation i
think mostly
okay so that's about that now
does that answer your question honza
okay so now let's go let's
let me go random then let's go back to
random
emacs blog so we did that
oh yeah powershell so powershell
uh yeah so let's go back to powershell
and now
i show you
now i'm gonna sync
yeah go over my notes but are you going
to buy your apple
it's actually you know the apple the the
new machine
you know apple is so you know they they
squeeze money
a lot you know for example like
everything
memories for the pc let's say it's 100
for something for apple it's 200 or 300
they charge you twice or three times
small
what can you do but you know
uh so anyway so i just
synced my you know my changes on my
website
to my server so now if you go to xrd
emacs so go to my emacs blog
so you can see today's code updated
there so you can now copy this
put to your init file then you have the
same
power okay so that's
that
oh so you are saying uh and you are
going to wait for a year or two
wait for a year or two you know in a
year or two things will have
been changed you know yeah
yeah because technology space they move
fast so
who knows what will happen in two years
you know amd
intel they are all competing you know
very
uh harsh very hard
but as of now you know apple m1 chip is
truly a great thing
but that you know they they are going to
raise the prices you know when they have
more sales you know the market you know
the more sale
their goal is essentially every company
apple intel
or amd just basically every company
especially in america the the home of
capitalism
you know when they have more sales
they're gonna raise their prices
um you know they make money is the
main thing so
uh what what else uh so emacs blog
so let's copy okay so
copy this path go to my talk page
uh go to today's top page paste the file
name
okay close emacs log and i talk about
this mouse
also paste the file path here and
i talk about this mouth and also paste
the file path here
and i talked about the spinning wheel so
let's click on that copy it
back to emax paste it here so we have a
record of what we talked about you see
so close that what else we did we talked
uh you know so next topic we can talk
about
keyboards and okay no but nobody's
comment you guys comment okay
okay no comment i'm just gonna work on
my website then
another emacs workflow okay
so let's see notes
uh powershell yeah so we talked about
powershell
uh powershell yeah so
okay let's copy powershell here
oh no not here so go to talk show
here paste it here
show fantastic
now let me decide what to do next
so i've been talking for wow
54 minutes already oh
um i want to do something
else i think
uh
so this item is no longer they should
should not be there anymore because we
did it
so copy the file path go back to emacs
open the file and here is that line
deleted okay back to the browser refresh
let's see what's the next thing i want
to do html youtube
and
html youtube linkify okay so
so i have a custom emacs command that's
called
html youtube linkify and you can see the
source code
here so the issue here is that i need to
add it to my website
so that other people can use it okay
okay so let's do that so
you know you go to so what's the use of
these so you know
again if you are a web blogger for
example you go to this
yeah this fantastic fantastic video you
know if you are a blogger you write a
lot of blogs so you want to put this
embed this youtube into your uh
into your blog so what you do copy the
file path
you know let me show you okay let me
demo so go to the go to
keyboard okay so here's my keyboard
block
so you go to the top add a new section
paste the file path you can see there is
a file path go back to browser you can
see refresh
so that's a youtube link so you want to
embed it so press the button you can see
that
go back to browser show and you see
how easy it is you know as opposed to
as opposed to you go here click share
then you click start ad or whatever then
you click
embed then you
then you copy the code ugly code by the
way
then you press it paste it here so you
see that
so instead of doing that you just all
you have to do is copy the url
go to your file and press a key
that's it okay so
this command is called saw youtube uh
let's see where is it youtube
start youtube linkify okay so uh
so i want to so yeah so i want to put
the code on my emacs blog again so so
people can
okay go to emacs blog show in browser go
back here
uh go to emacs blog let's see first
thing is to decide where do i want to
put it
so go to emacs tutorial at the bottom
there is a section on html
so so this function will this command
will
turn a youtube url into a embedded
youtube video so where do i want to add
it
let's see you are to link url to link
with date
citation to link word to wikipedia link
wikipedia url to link amazon url to link
okay image path
to link okay okay let's add it after
that
image path to link okay
so copy that i mean click on that then
copy the file path
then okay add a new section
paste it here make a list okay
so copy that paste it here so this
one will be elise you
tube okay
link
embed youtube video okay
let's name it that
okay this is a new file we want to
create
now how do we create it i want to create
it by copy this one okay
so xsa html copy
okay wait xr copy html
by link okay enter now
i can open that file this is exactly
the same content as the the other file
so now
i just edit it update the date so let me
just do it fast
showing browser empty that's good oh so
we need to
okay so showing browser that's good so
close that
back to emacs close it uh
open that so the command we want is
you youtube
linkify okay so here's a command
describe function open it
here's the code okay so
i need to update the code i need to put
so
so here is the inline documentation for
the for this command
and i need to put a url
so that whenever people use this in
their init file they can find my home
page so the home page now is this one
new
so copy that paste it here make a
make from relative link
to to the url real url link
and type that and do that that
that that that that that
update the date added here okay
so here we have a link of the of the of
this command's home page okay
now copy the whole command copy it
oh wait so wait here wait wait
this shouldn't be here so this is wrong
hold on a second
yeah okay oops uh
okay so now copy the command
put the cursor on this link press a
button press a few keys to open the file
go back here oh wait
we got the wrong url not this one
block this one okay copy it
this is the local file path turn it to a
fully qualified domain path url
and okay
so there it is here's a
correct link now
copy the code
open it
add a new code tag
paste it showing browser
fantastic here's a result now it just
shows that because the
because you see these parties has you
know those
has not been encoded they need to be
encoded to
you know the html encoding encoding but
let me do okay so press the button to
syntax colored so you can now you can
see
now they have been encoded now back to
browser refresh
fantastic syntax colors and code and now
we need to add
some description about what this command
do okay
this command turns a youtube
url into a embedded
youtube video on
your blog okay showing browser
essentially that's it so you can grab
this code if you are a blogger and you
emacs user you can grab this code and
use it
comments comments
we are you by a kinesis 360
yes i think so i'm not going to buy it
but
i think they i'm gonna ask them you know
i'm gonna
review it for them see if they um
you know they i i don't want to say but
but you know they they might send me a
copy for review then i
review it for you guys
why are you wearing double glasses
because i'm getting old
this one is for near-sightedness this
one is for
um for you know for old men's
you know for seeing things uh close
and i talked about that a few times were
you from
honsa
kinesis so if you don't know kansas is
360. it's a new keyboard from kinesis
they are coming out
um i'm not sure at what stage they are
in yet bet alpha or beta or whatever i
don't know
so anyway
i don't know you know there's no much
not much information yet they just
announced it
like a week ago so there's not much
information on how it looks what how it
is designed
uh you know and they are you know so
maybe i will review it
okay so embed youtube video so we need
so we created this page
now we need to add a link to this
navigation box
because in this navigation box it's all
articles
about creating a link you know citation
link
word to wikipedia link uh with
pdr url to a link amazon url to a link
you know things like that so we need to
add it here
let's do okay so let's do so let me show
you how you do it
so you go down
so you can see this section correspond
to this
box okay so now copy that
you know this requires more explanation
but i'm just going to do it
youtube url to
embedded video okay let's let's say that
okay now find and replace
for all of them
now youtube let's do that
replace all okay let's change all the
files okay
now refresh there it is so you can click
on that
you can see this navigation box is
working
every page has it
okay so we we just added a link
to all pages navigation box
and we also need to do it here on the
left side
uh so where do i want to add it
again let's add it here okay
by the way the command i'm using is
uh the command
i was using is saw find
okay there that one start find replace
text a fantastic
extremely efficient command you should
use it
it's on mailpad just search for it
uh let's just say embed youtube video
okay copy that okay
okay so now it has changed tensor files
okay
now go to the browser go to the bottom
if we refresh you'll see a new link
between these two
okay so now let's refresh refresh
there it is embed youtube video
and
and i also want to change your name here
okay youtube url to embedded video i
want to change the name
so we are essentially doing find replace
on all files in a directory
okay so these are changed files
close it close it back to browser
so now you can see the file name change
you can see
it was youtube url to embedded video
now refresh embed youtube video so it's
simpler
okay show in browser there you have it
now we need to add this to my blog
again copy the file path close
close wait did we update the date
yes june 5th yeah
so uh
so copy the file path close close go to
emacs blog
and there it is a new command
delete that so showing browser
so we just added a new entry embed
youtube video click on that here's the
code you can now
put in your ini file now again we need
to update to
update the
rss you know the web feed okay
press the button done close it yes
showing browser go to powershell again
rsync to my web server
okay so powershell
yes you see all these changes you see
you see all these emacs files changed
tens of
you know like 50 files changed why so
many file change
because of the
because of the navigation bar because
every file contains a navigation bar
and we just changed them so now
there you know okay so that
that fantastic we did two
great things i've been wanting to do so
now back to
so what's the next topic let's show this
again
keyboard let's go to let's show what is
this one uh this
is to do oh wait so
we open to do so you see this one
html youtube linkify add to emacs blog
so we just did remove that
so this one it's got re refresh okay
we just finished another thing
okay now what's next
am i gonna quit or am i going to
continue on
we've been talking for an hour and
10 minutes
any other questions now
yeah kinesis 360 no function keys that's
uh
you know that's a problem uh
i'm trying to you know if i have the
opportunity i'm going to try to convince
them
you know put the function keys back
you know the kinesis you know like
i don't want to you know they are still
beta so i'm not sure i should talk to
yeah i
i don't have information but i mean they
just
now you know it's actually it's public
info it's on their twitter
for example
okay you can see on their twitter
uh wait not that one kinesis
keyboard
uh is that the one why is that
yeah so kinesis keyboard you can see
so this is their official uh twitter
and they are announcing this
you know they they are designing a new
keyboard let's see what is this
google yeah so they are oh i haven't
seen this before
oh no i have yeah they are trying to do
a survey
you know asking you whether you think
where should escape key be positioned
you know
things like that you know i i'm not sure
there's a
you know it's still in in the design
stage
and and and seems like they are not
going to have function keys but if i
have
opportunity i'm going to tell them you
need function keys
according to this uh what do you mean i
don't get
the joke uh okay what else
let's see
maybe that's it for today yeah so today
is mostly emacs
and i've been talking for 17 minutes
already so
thank you guys for watching yeah that's
that's it for today
and
okay if you like my stuff go buy my
stuff okay
click click
you can patreon me you can amazon gift
card me
you can paypal me or you can bitcoin
me or you can buy my fantastic
tutorials javascript in depth
and emacs this tutorial and emacs
tutorial
that's the tool i charge it's free
online any but but
you know if you like it you probably
should
think about you know paying for it
okay that's it for today thank you guys
for watching bye
you