hello guys welcome to another episode of
soundtalk show so today i'm going to do
wufang uh wufam language coding so i'm
going to work on my website i mean not
let me show you okay wolfham
language
so this is some packages i've written
some 20 years ago
and i'm going to work on them update
them
so let me show you okay so
uh i'm going to work on
para plot okay
so let's open that
so you are looking at wolfram language
um let me show you so there it is wufang
language you can get it for free
let me magnify
so you can see this is the package i
begin it began in 1994 basically 1994 to
1999 and i'm going to update it you know
so it's 20 years old code and lots of
code
so wolfram language let me give you so
what did what does this package do you
know you can look at if you just search
for special playing curve a visual
dictionary of special plain codes
or
most almost all of these graphics are
done in wufang language like 25 years
ago
so this is one of my one of my most
popular website it was linked by
like over a thousand
websites universities mostly math
department you know 20 years ago 25
years ago it was high tech high
technology you know on the web you don't
have wikipedia yet so all these images
are generated most you know almost over
them yeah basically all of them are
generated by
my
uh language package it was called
mathematica back then
um
and special plain curves is fantastic
very interesting you know so
so that's what i'm going to do basically
just work on my wolfram
uh my package wufang language okay and
uh let me uh let me give you a basic
intro what wufang language is you know i
talked about that a lot in my past
videos
thank you cortes
happy hump day i don't i don't even know
what is hump day
[Laughter]
i have to look up so anyway but i i'm
going to focus on wolfen language today
okay so
um
and it's probably gonna be boring for
for you guys you know if you um
you know because i'm just this is a
working session i'm just gonna code
wufang language you know
let's see par para plot okay so
uh you are looking at my keyboard this
is kinesi kinesis advantage too this is
ultimate hacking uh let me show you
quickly okay
and uh yeah i have a lot to uh
so let's go to today's talk show
so today's talk show let's uh let's
write down what we're gonna do so that
way it's more organized
intro okay what is wolfram language okay
that's one thing we're gonna cover
and what is open language
what does
my parallel plot package do
uh package too we already explained that
uh and okay
so it's gonna be
live recording of wufam language
okay live cody and wufam language what
does my package do paraplot that's uh
what you have seen
and
let me give you a short introduction of
wufam language so you just go to sally
wolfram land search for it you'll find
uh it and i've been working on this
tutorial
you know
over the past year so i've done over 10
videos let's turn on javascript so you
can see my videos so if you are
interested in language go learn it okay
in my opinion it's the
most high level artificial intelligence
language by far you know there's nothing
like it
the nature is very similar to lisp
because it was it was heavily borrowed
from lisp
uh so i have you know
cried a lot you know i did 10 over 10
videos so watch those for like basic
introduction and you can get it for free
you know just download the wolfram
engine for free
and you are set so i recommend for you
guys to learn wolfram language
especially if you are not a professional
programmer you know if you are a
professional programmer you code c c
prosperous java golan
or web dev javascript
especially the low level you know
professional you know you write kernels
you know linux
embedded services real time you know or
game engine you know
writing games you are probably
not that interested in wufam language
wufam language is mostly designed for
mathematicians and scientists and
engineers in particular engineer
engineering of all sort of fields you
know electrical engineering mechanical
engineering architectural engineering
you know military
nasa you know science space exploration
when you do those kind of you know if
you are a scientist or engineer you are
not a programmer
but you need computers to work with so
in those kind of roles typically are not
programmers
you know then you need a lot of
mathematics and you need to you know you
don't want to get into detail of the
programming language technicalities you
know what's you know float int
object oh you need to make this a object
your object hierarchy and inheritance or
you know
monkey patch typing or whatever type
check it you know you don't are not
concerned about that you are an engineer
you need to
you know design a bridge you need to
find what's the optimal way optimization
you know lots of those so most uh
mostly
applied mathematics or even pure
mathematicians you know then wolfen
language is the
supreme so if you are not a professional
programmer but a lot of you i know i
mean you are not an engineer neither you
are not a scientist neither but however
you are a technical person especially a
lot of you young guys you know you play
games you know
you know lots of uh you know modified
games or windows uh whatever pc you know
you you know the technicality you know
you know the computer you know you know
video editing for example lots of you
youtube youtubers you know video editing
audio editing you know so you are
technically um competent person you know
computers well
and many of you use linux so for these
but you are not a professional
programmer you know you might know some
bash commands emacs you know but you
don't
you know you you don't actually have
like
professional programming experience for
the for for you guys
then i highly recommend wufang language
because you know you use it as a tool
that
you know out of the box there are six
thousand you know close to seven
thousand functions you know so
uh you don't have to be bogged down
about
learning you know computer science or
programming just get things done
process files you know uh automate
things things like that okay wufang
language i recommend for a
lifelong
learning experience you know in fact
that's what i've been doing you know for
10 years in 1990s mufam language i've
been working you know coding with
language uh every day
you know that got me a job at wufang
research you know
and
so why i wanted wufang language why did
i begin to learn it was actually my
first language you know the first
language really makes a great impression
and it you know
so and then i start to tell a story in
my you know my personal story why i love
this language how i got into it you know
and my involvement with lisp you know
this is basically my programming the
story of my programming life you know
because
in
in in heavy part because of wufam
language you know wolfham language is
heavy it's basically a lisp
so you know i wanted the best tool i
wanted to be the the best mathematician
and so i looked around i researched
there's no not much internet back then
but you read books or you you go to
online forums talk to other people so
wolfham mathematica is uh you know
supposedly the best tool you know
so i bought that you know back then you
know you spent money to buy software i
bought that i bought that and read the
you know the 1000 pages the of the
documentation
word by word from cover to cover
three times over 10 years like you know
so
so anyway wolfen language so i you know
so it's um i yeah i recommend it so what
so introduction okay uh so you can read
my tutorials you know i wrote this you
know in past half a year uh
that can get you started you know
there's so many
by the way wufang website they have like
like some medium pages you know
but my tutorial focus on
um
you know most you know wufam research
will fund you know woofam.com
you know they have a huge website you
have you know you might get confusing
because they have
like a medium something like a million
pages you know they they but essentially
their only one and only product is wufam
language mathematica okay
so but you you go to their site you know
they have lots of tons of documentation
and guides and so on
and stefan wufang also wrote a book uh
wufong language tutorial now that
tutorial i can recommend but that
tutorial is for people who never
had any programming experience before
you know fun let me show you okay yeah
i'm starting to give an intro instead of
working on my website
i mean working on my packages
so let me expand this um
so select all let me just show you some
code for now okay so expand all the
sales you know what's a sale so for
example you see this on the side
that's a cell you can expand it and you
can shrink it you can have um
it's almost like html or org mod you
know it's a markup language but when you
when you display it in a um
in a woofah notebook uh interface you
can like collapse the cells you know
like headings
and so on
so those are code you know
and this code uh
and i can turn this
to a
two dimensional mathematical formatting
okay press ctrl shift n
you see that's fantastic
okay let's undo okay let's see
undo
let's make copy
and press ctrl shift n you see these two
are exactly identical the same code 100
equivalent except that
you know this way this uh this one
displayed in a
very nice automated
3d you know two to two dimensional
mathematical formatting
you know not not like tech or latex you
have to you have to backslash and type
all those things and render it you know
this is all automated and and also you
know notice when you shrink
you see it's automatic margin you know
formatting auto wrap you know like
in emacs or in python you know these
idiotic programmers oh your line is too
long more than 80 characters you need to
feel column so that so that each line is
no more than 70 characters that's idiot
idiocy
so you see
this wufang language code
it's not just two-dimensional display
mathematical formula you know from you
know mathematical display
rendering of the math formulas
type setting mathematical type setting
but it also it's you know automatic wrap
you can see this is not trivial to do
you see
uh
okay it kind of is stopped okay this i
guess this is uh
i can i you know i can consider i don't
know if you should consider the bug or
not because this should be two lines
let's do it again
uh ctrl shift n okay now it's better
yeah so i was trying to tell you about
this automatic wrapping of things so but
once you wrap into too short then it
doesn't go back to the you know
the fraction
okay so press ctrl shift n to do it
again
okay so
so let's make sure let's get back to
work on wufang language okay i want to
um
i want to focus on today so i'm going to
work on this code okay
so what did i cover things i need to
talk about um
[Music]
yeah so wolfen language they have a lot
stefan wufang's
tutorial okay but anyway
my tutorial is focused on
it's focused on not using language as a
giant huge calculator that's a lot of
people do you know you just type
something and get the answer but however
i i try to teach you
how to actually program wufam language
like a programming language you know
like most of you are no you know if
you're a programmer python this has got
how do you actually code things and i
teach you the principle of wufang
language how does it work what is a term
rewriting system how does it actually
work symbolic computation you know
symbolic pattern matching
now this symbolic pattern matching is
different from pattern matching of
haskell or camo or any other language
you find you find
here you have
symbolic pattern matching which
essentially you know which is a turn
term rewriting engine
so the closest analogous
in programming languages industrial
programming languages is
is this
macro okay of you you know these
phonetics you
are excited about these markers you tell
you you know you talk about these
markers all day
you know wufang language is the
basically the entire code almost just
about you know every line of code you
write is a smart quote that's
one way to put it okay so term symbolic
term rewriting system
what does that mean it basically means
that
whatever you type okay i'm i'm gonna
start to work on wu from language so
what what so what that means is that
whatever you type
is a sequence of symbols
and when you define a function such as
here okay so let's look at here okay so
for example a parallel layout dot gp so
here's a function it takes three
arguments and these three arguments you
can see that that's actually a pattern
so this is how you define one of the way
to define a function okay so and here is
what you what the function does you know
module is like lisp sled
you know that declares local
variable um
lexical with lexical scope so that's
macho module in wolfram language in this
it's let okay so
here you are defining a
a function
and you know then you say you know local
variables and what it does and what they
return you see map very very similar to
this okay almost identical
so but this is actually
you know in terms of lisp this is
actually a marker you know this is not
it's it's it's
practically speaking it's a function but
however
what you are actually doing is you are
defining a
rule a trans as a syntax transformation
rule such that whenever
you know somewhere else whenever
language sees this pattern you know this
pattern
you know beginning by parallel dot gp
and followed by three things whatever
those things are when it sees this
expression this pattern this sequence of
symbols it will automatically transform
it into that that
okay so this is a this is what called
term rewriting
uh
basically general you or you can think
of it as a
more elaborate
lisp macro okay
at least marker works in the same way
so okay so let me read the comments a
bit and i'm going to start to code and
hopefully you know by the end you know
this is probably going to be a long one
an hour
or two by the end i should have i'm
going to show you some of the graphics
okay like like what does this package do
so let me show you some of the okay so
let me go to it
so parallel plot power plot examples
here is the documentation for the
package so let me magnify
and you can see
you know this is introduction and you
know it
tells you what this package do in
several examples so let's select all and
press ctrl shift
um
left square bracket
to expand them all
you know and notebook again this is
similar to oak mod you know you have
headers you have headers sections
subsections you can you can move them up
about
so again
what i'm trying to say here is ufam
language is similar to lisp in many many
you know in fact it's one of the least
in one the video i talked about
and also you know the note notebook
format is on you know basically it's
just like oak mod okay and you can look
at the source code of this notebook it's
just it's just wuffing language code
like lisp okay so anyway so here is the
result of some of the images you see
these images are a bit mapped so you
know remember this is
20 years old notebook okay so these
images are bitmap you are um
are they uh
no they are not actually okay they are
fantastic okay so that's a result
yeah it's not it's not bitmap actually
it's a scalable
fantastic okay so
if i just run the code right now it
won't work uh probably won't uh we can
try okay so let's try it
okay i'm gonna select all and run it
okay do i want to eval init files no
okay let's just say none okay so it's
here some errors there's probably some
anyway so
that is done now let's go back to this
you know this examples page let's try to
evaluate it okay
so put a cursor here evaluated do you
want to automatically evaluate all the
initialization cells in the notebook no
okay you see it doesn't work
it doesn't work because i know why it
doesn't work because one of the
one of the
external package i called here
is
is gun
it has you know this package you see
these filter options this this thing
this
utilities
filter options that is a external
utility package
now the functionality of that package
has become part of
wufam language
in around 2010 i don't know what
2015 or 2010 or early i don't i don't i
don't
i have a i have a note about when it
changed um
but anyway so anyway one of the package
is gone the functionality has become
uh part of the wolfram language so you
don't
so you know so that's why
you know this is not working let's can
we undo yeah
is you you are supposed to see this uh
you know if it works
now what's the significance of these let
me tell you okay
so we are plotting you know we are doing
a parametric plot
parametric plot of a circle and the
parametric formula of a circle is cosine
sine okay
a parametric formula is basically just
two functions
and each function takes one variable
and as the variable changes the variable
goes from
t goes from zero to six
as a variable changes you have different
values of the function so you got two
values
and two values and one of them is the
coordinate for x-axis well the other one
is taken to be the coordinate of the
y-axis
so as time goes from zero to six you
have different
pairs of points each you know each
number is a each pair of number is a
point in the plane so once you apply
this you get you know basically you get
a circle okay
that's mathematics you know go study
your calculus
so but
but why am i you know
you know for example let let me do this
why am i writing a function to do this
because it's a building function okay so
let's
uh let me show you
uh magnify okay
so you want to do parametric plot
parametric
plot okay so you can do that evaluate it
uh you don't want the semicolon
semicolon usually suppresses the output
okay so you can see it's a circle you
see
now this is a building function so what
am i doing with my power plot well you
can see
you see the color
you know it start from gray
then becomes increasingly
blue
so this my package this function allows
you to see
where the curve begins and where it ends
you know like you can trap you know but
on the other hand this one you don't see
you know you don't know if it's going
this way or that way so that's one of
the enhancement of my package that's the
point of my package that's power plug
and it does other things for example it
can do for example this one this is
optics this is called uh
you know caustics
you will see this very often
when you for example cars
cars headlight you see this
pattern of mirror or you see
uh radars you know military radars you
know they have parabolic shape so
the property of this curve this is a
parabola one of the property
is that if you have a point
there at the focus of the parabola you
shoot the light and they reflect it will
become parallel so
you know this is one of the property
so let me show you yeah so perhaps i i
show you my website too about that
because that's a interesting one
okay so if you go to parabola so this is
parabola okay so let's you know
here is the definition this is like the
definition of parabola
by geometric means you know this is a
geometric definition of parabola
uh well i'm not going to explain but i
hope you see the purpose of this
animation is that when you see it you
know watch it closely
then you can understand
it so you can understand the definition
visually so that's that's kind of my the
point of my this project 20 20 years ago
visual dictionary of spatial plane
curves
okay
so that's the definition of parabola so
by definition parabola is defined from a
geometric point of view you can define
it by
given a line and given a point such that
such that um
a parabola is a curve such that every
point on the line
have equal distance to the to the given
point and the given line in in
um
in a certain way but anyway so
and then we have many properties of
parabola one of them so you can see this
is a car
headlight you know this is actually my
car 20 years ago honda civic you know
you can see so that mirror is parabola
okay so you know so
you are seeing applied mathematics you
know the curve parabola is known
in greek times like 2 000 years ago
but you know you but many of mathematics
you find uh applications after a
thousand years of after 2000 years but
anyway so that's one of the applications
you know
then you can see a lot of other
applications for example uh
for example this
solar power
solar power parabolic trail you know
they focus the sunlight onto this pipe
so
they deflect the sunlight into this
line
and this line becomes super hot that's
how they generate energy you know one of
the ways you know so you have a few huge
field you know form of you know of this
thing one this is one of the way to
generate you know for solar uh energy
of course then you have you know
different things again this is parabola
you know so to me these are beautiful
and of course you also see radars you
know
shaped in a similar way you want to you
know raise from the
from the cosmos outside of us
hits earth and you want to focus all
those energy into a point
and from that point so you can kind of
you magnify the signal so you can know
whether there's a
extra
terrestrial aliens out there
so radars and you know so
so that's fascinating you know that's
why i did you know and
so
this package power plot allows me to for
example i want to draw these lines given
a curve you know for example here is a
formula for a parabola
a parametric formula for a parabola and
i want to say
i want to draw this you know optical you
know reflections from a point so i say
caustic origin at 2 1 you know then i
say caustic line length 5
and you draw it
ok so it can apply to any kind of curve
and many of these so they have
fascinating properties for example here
you are looking at the elisp again elise
has fascinating uh optical properties
you know from one focus to the other
and hyperbola you know so um so that's
one of the you know of my goal
of this package is to draw these things
and here you are looking at this
function this uh
parametric curve
and we are not drawing the curve we you
know this is for decorative purposes
then you have other uh you have other
kind of things uh they are not
reflection but they are for example this
is called uh normal lines you draw
you draw lines
wait this is conic this is
concord
anyway lots of applications okay so
yeah so this example is the you draw the
normal
you draw the normals of a curve so this
curve is called as
asteroid okay let me show you
uh
interesting things
uh where's the
okay so let's go back
so let me show you the asteroids so i'm
kind of digressing but that's okay
because
maybe this is more interesting than me
coding uh just coding it any questions
comments
so let me show you the astral chord
asteroid curve this curve is beautiful
you are seeing the so-called the
parallels of asteroids so the asteroid
curve can be generated when you roll a
circle
inside other another okay
or
there are many different ways they
generate the same curves you see this is
the asteroid
and then you have so many properties and
you know and you can also generate this
way
by sliding a stick
you know by
and this mechanism is called trauma of
archimedes this is this mechanism is
known like
two thousand years ago
tremor of archimedes
you know so what happens is that when
you slide a stick you know around
around two perpendicular
track the stick will form this envelope
you know it's called envelope this shape
and that's an asteroid so you see
so that's so that's why it's fascinating
so one way to generate asteroid is
rolling or cur rolling a circle inside
another
uh and actually the inner circle can be
different
size
you know but another way is to slide a
stick
and then
then you can see here over here this one
it's connects
to the relationship to a
to a family of uh
family of ellipses
you know all these these ellipses you
are seeing
they are they share a uh
property they are all
okay all these this ellipses the the sum
of their major and minor axis is
constant
so when you have this family of ellipses
again you form the
asteroid
and again more properties this is
evolute okay evolude is the centers of
escalating circles okay that god
you know this topic you know it's very
fascinating
uh the
okay so look so what is evolute okay
well that will take
five minutes to explain so let's skip
that
and again and another property of
asteroid is that if you shine a light
like parallel lines
onto a
deltoid and their reflection will form a
their reflection will form a asteroid
okay so you might be wondering so what
is the deltoid okay so let me show you a
deltoid so this is a deltoid this curve
is called a deltoid okay and it can be
generated by rolling circles again you
know you draw a circle a smaller circle
inside a larger circle the radius of the
smaller circle is one third of the
largest circle then you get a
deltoid okay
and then you know deltoid has has lots
of interesting properties but one of
them is that
if you shine parallel lines onto a
deltoid
their reflection is a asteroid
fascinating this is extremely
fascinating actually
i've never to this day you know it's
been 20 years you know it's been 25
years i wrote this
animation
to this day i i don't think i have a
clear understanding why it happens that
way
so
you know on my website you can also see
the
geogebra so let me show you so you see
it allows you to do things interactively
so you can see in the middle is a
deltoid and this is a if i drag this
this is the um
this is the
line direct the ray direction light
direction okay so if you if the ray
comes from different
positions you can see they all form
deltoid you see this this
shape i mean asteroid
so you shine you shine parallel lines
parallel
rays
onto a deltoid and you get a
asteroid
fascinating
okay
so um
yeah and and a lot of other properties
you know just
incredibly fascinating this is another
way to generate a deltoid okay
so that's you know when i was a student
a calculus student you know i was so
fascinated by all these relations you
know this fascinating plane curves and
these are just plain curves you know
two-dimensional easy to understand
so i you know i wanted to be a
mathematician
but i'm also very interested in
programming so i
that's how i you know about mathematica
and rule all these programs
so all these you are seeing here you
know we talked about
that's basically all done by this
package okay
okay now i'm gonna read comments and
let's code and see where we get
let's see am i still going
okay
so cortes thank you
one can get mathematica for free in the
on the raspberry pi that's true one can
also connect the raspberry pi's
methodical notebook front end to a
wolfram engine yeah great fantastic
uh
do you think learning a chinese language
is similar to learning
uh advanced math no
they are completely
different have nothing nothing to do
with each other
oh the difficulty of learning
uh mathematics is more difficult that's
for sure because mathematics has
okay the question is is chinese learning
chinese more difficult or learning
mathematics well that depends on
uh what
what perspective you know you take
for example if you are learning chinese
you know
you can
you know so there are two things i
okay i want to digress maybe should i
digress
uh
yeah that's a bit digression about
learning chinese versus math you know so
there are two things about learning a
foreign language one is the
listening and speech
aspects you know listening skills and
speaking skills
and the other aspect is reading and
writing you know learn the writing
system now these two now
remember
learning and you know speaking and
listening is entirely different has
nothing almost basically nothing to do
with with the writing and reading skills
remember that okay that's the first
thing you want to know about learning a
foreign language
so depending on what's your focus you
know you can learn to speak
read and speak that's more practical
actually or you can focus put more focus
on learning the reading and writing and
vocabulary you know
which is more academic and nerd kind of
thing you know but if you go to a
foreign country i mean learning you know
reading and
uh
i mean listening and speaking is a far
more practical thing that's i mean
that's the essence that's the origin of
languages human language
speak and listen
not
not writing and read okay that comes you
know a few thousands years later
so
so there are different things okay
depending on which one you wanna you
know you you wanna uh focus on
but anyway so
listening and speaking chinese you can
you can learn in a year okay you study
three let's say three hours a day in a
year you're pretty good at you know
um
at small conversations you know you can
ask where to go with the bathroom you
know
but mathematics is uh yeah so
mathematics is far more difficult you
know you spend a year calculus you know
and before that trigonometry basic you
know uh
analytic geometry and basic fractions in
you know high school algebra then
calculus calculus take you a year or two
then you have group you know that's far
far far
deep okay
that's about that
okay so let let me let me let me start
to code okay i think i talked about
enough i think i already talked for what
an hour already
um
so let's see
where am i
1 10
4 yeah so i i talked for 40 minutes okay
so now i want to code okay so
yeah let's go okay so
beginning from the beginning so let's
see
so first thing i want to i need to fix
is speak this thing i don't need it
anymore so i need to take notes here so
i paste it here
okay
and on the pink window you can see all
my emacs command cores and uh
and the
function names okay
i'm not gonna go over that
so begin package i don't need this
anymore so remove so but i need to find
all my codes for filter options i need
to change them to the
okay so let's um
what am i
oh yeah that's just parametric plot what
am i doing here okay so
i want to
yeah so i want to
right now i want to find out what is the
replacement for this package because
that package is um
is
is now part of the wolfram language so i
search search my notes
and not here so go to uh
go to firm language
and search for it
a few options well not there okay go to
my computer blog search for it
okay so yeah so here it is filter
options become filter rules
so this is shown in browser this is one
of my notes i written 10 years ago
about some changes
so
filter option is obsolete now it's
replaced by filter rules okay so let me
make a note of that
go back to talk show
today's talk show
okay
let me write that down
and here's the notes
shown in browser okay
so okay i need to do find replace on all
these so now
delete this
uh okay here is my documentation for
programmers you know usually i document
my code extensively so you can see in my
package i even write the documentation
for
for what i'm doing with this
okay so
so how am i doing any questions comments
i'm thinking maybe i you know i just
stopped today because
uh yeah i'm thinking
just stop today oh do you guys uh want
me to see me work on this because
working on this is
you wouldn't understand you know because
you wouldn't understand
much
of what i'm doing because you know
there's a lot of wolfram language code
so what you are looking at here is
basically documentation for each
exported symbols you know
uh you know i have complete
documentation so let's skip them
but basically okay so let's try to find
the filter options okay so because
copy so find
filter options
find next
okay so here is where i'm using that
function
and see where do i
so
one place to place three place okay
i've used that function in three places
okay let's fix them
so i'm thinking maybe our goal is to get
some of these run okay then that's it
for today
so i need to understand so field option
is offset and replaced by filter rules
so let's look at
the documentation for field filter rules
yeah
there
okay turn on javascript
okay filter rules so basically what it
does is that it takes uh two arguments
the first
argument is a list of rules you know
again like i talked about transformation
rules
and the second argument is a pattern and
it just return
it just reduce the list into those that
matches the pattern
so for example filter rules a1 b2 c3
yeah so basically you just want um yeah
okay so got it so this is
filter rules okay so now i need to
replace all my calls of filter option to
filter rules okay
now again let me
you see this is kind of ascii code
you see all these the gray you are
looking at that's ascii
formatted in ascii
but now let me press the button and
reformat them into a two-dimensional
math formula so let's copy that
new buffer i mean new window paste it
here
so here's the old code
copy it
press ctrl shift n
so now this is a new format okay
okay it didn't go to two-dimensional
much because there's no
fractions in square root
but anyway you see the syntax highlight
oh there is there is one of the uh you
know
and you see this is derivative you can
see
this is a
you know function f x f derivative twice
second derivative
there
here is a fraction
so here is
options so options needs to be replaced
by filter rules okay
so wait
so let's search for
filter options
oh wait uh
okay so filter options
let's delete the first part
okay
find
so one occurrence so filter options
okay and
search again
so one
two three okay
filter options
okay so
[Music]
it's
i'm trying to find out exactly how
should i change the code okay field
options parametric plot options okay
filter options graphic okay so i now i
know what to do
copy it
yeah so basically
what i need to do is let's show here so
whenever you see code like that
you need to change it to
um
yeah i don't want this
i don't want the sale box
so you need to change it to let's copy
you need to change to options
okay
so
so let's try this
as whenever you see something like that
you need to change it to options a and b
let's
let's uh
see
how did you die
let's see
i think so let's i'm not sure but let's
let's see so what is art
so
so yeah so i'm right now i'm coding so
opt
opts is the list of rules okay
so
obts is a list of rules
so for example here it means
plot involutes
replaced
by this transform using this list of
rules
then ah god i have to think about this
okay jama
molina says
do you have useful wufang language to do
something in your web how difficult
would it be to do something like stefan
wufang writing writings page
uh i have not
really use wufang language for writing
my website
well except
you know so well yeah i
so in 1996
to about year two
so for
close to 10 years i have used wufang
language to create my website
but that's the early days of my website
my website began in 1997
and
xavi.org domain begin in year 2000
exactly
so
for about seven years i have used
language to
create my website
uh but now my website has been 20 years
you know since 25 years
uh but most of these years since 2005 i
have not been using ufo language because
i don't have it
you know
life events
circumstances i don't have with my
language i you know i became very poor
so
for 20 years i haven't used language
almost
for 15 years something like that i
haven't really coded wufang language
so
all the tools i use for wufong language
is emacs emac lisp perl python golen
you know in javascript so no wufang
language
uh
so that should answer that
question
thank you
oh flamio i'm gonna answer your question
okay so the
so i my website you know i used wufang
language you know you know for 10 years
20 years ago but
not today i don't have it you know
because i already have tools built for
my website working on on my website
mostly emacs emacs list okay but for
stefan wufang's website you know i can
tell you i can
let's go to stay from woofer you know he
so again like i said before
he's got
tremendous number of blogs you know
thousands of articles and you know let's
go to his blog okay latest writings
uh you know
i i talked about this many times i he is
one of the guy i admire
uh
but
also
the way he
think about things in particular
mathematics
physics sciences
i tend to be agree with okay the kind of
the point of view i agree with very much
okay so anyway his website you know so
he's got you know his own blog and also
the entire woofer language website they
are all written in wolfen language
okay i can tell you that okay ufam alpha
the entire wolfram website
they are all written in language you
know
and they they they are written basically
they have a system like systematic you
know generates the whole thing so
uh
but don't take don't take my word for it
okay so i don't know exactly i think he
he might have talked about it how he
wrote his blog you know he's he's got
tremendous number of blogs okay like um
like okay let's go to recent okay let's
go to uh let's turn
javascript
let's go to uh recent categories okay
you know categories artificial
intelligence big pictures that's you
know he again you see he has a category
called big picture
you know
so i just you know why
why i tend to see eye to eye with him
because one of my
the way i look at things doesn't matter
it's a programming language or politics
you know i like to view it from an
entire human history's point of view
that's important you know let me try to
tell you guys this
mentality and i think that's a great tip
doesn't matter what you what issue what
you are looking at politics you know
news programming languages is python a
good language is goal and good israel
you know
whatever issue whatever issue i tend i
want to put it from a whole human
animal history perspective okay so for
example let's say you have a new
language haska or whatever you know
so i want to know what is the
significant significance of this thing
with respect to entire human history
okay
so that's why you got you know so stefan
wuffen a lot of the way he sees things
is similar i would say to to me okay so
he see this category of big picture
multi-computation a fourth paradigm you
know in the past few years he's starting
to do like what's meta mathematics
you know
you know so i read a lot of his stuff
uh big picture okay so the the big
picture why does universe exist
some perspectives from a physics project
you know he's getting getting into
lots of these uh in the proper uh field
is philosophy
it's you know
uh
semi science okay not exactly math you
know he's getting also you know he's
also getting meta mathematics like like
so what is method mathematics like when
you do proof proof theory you know when
you would uh want to
use computers you know programming
languages haskell you know haskell
type checking you know so on
when you actually want to use them to do
proof mathematics there are many
theories you know logic you know first
order logic second order logic
sequential calculus lambda calculus you
know they all you know uh combinatorics
they are trying to basically they are
basically they are all all of them are
trying to do proofs you know or
investigate what does proof mean you
know
very deep okay but
once you use all these you know theories
you find you you'll find that
you'll find that
it's like get getting more and more
complex like you are not going anywhere
like in theory
you know we have programming languages
and we have you know computers that can
do billions and billions of calculations
per second we should you know in in some
sense we should have a theory of the
universe already you know just just that
google's machine you know machine farms
just compute you know find out the
ultimate answer to the universe why not
but we don't have that we don't have
that because all the mathematicians you
study into logic you find that
this tricky you know
oh yeah it's great you know if your
language can have static type checking
but if you add that then you're gonna
have run into infinity problem you know
infinite recursion or never exit
so how do you fix that you trick the
type type system then you got other
problems you you got other you know
deep
rabbit hole to dive into so
this logic you know all these logic you
know the proof systems and category
theory is part of it
you find that
they kind of like
they are not what you might expect
like one final logic system that can do
them or it's not like that you you find
into so so then you have you know lots
of different branches of logic you know
so then then you can ask the question so
okay so we have all these proof systems
what's the point what what's going on
is can we have a
you know can we have a big picture like
a big picture what's going on with all
these logic systems you know he's trying
to do that so then you get into meta
proof systems like if a philosophical
view of what's going on with all these
different uh proof systems
so anyway i think that's it for today so
oh yeah so uh
so um so
okay to that question you know so stefan
wufang's writing i'm pretty sure it's
written uh in mathematica
uh yeah he he has a system of doing it
doing that i'm not sure exactly
anyway so next question julio
so radiology
you know radiology i believe is a jargon
wolf and invented okay i'm not too fond
of that thing um
ludiology okay he
you know like some people doesn't like
stefan wufang because he's a mega
maniac
and he's you know creating things
so anyway radiology is of a term he
created okay
in the past three years
so essentially it's about it's
so what's the question have you been
following radiology not not much okay
i mean he's he's done a lot of talks but
it's not a standard
uh
term in mathematics or science
essentially it's something he
created he believed that it's you know a
new kind of science you know
and we don't know for sure we don't know
it's actually
something
important or something
critical it's just something he created
okay so let's go to his you know his
blog on radiology okay so there's a
category of radiology so
so i haven't been you know diving into
details but i know what he is trying to
do so you know in his project you know
in his physics project he's trying to
come up with a
he's trying to uh model
the universe
by
a
kind of a
rule
based transformation of
networks okay so
maybe i can try to explain that you know
yeah i don't i don't i you know i'm not
a physicist i don't know this
subject too well but i think i can give
a give you an overview what is he's
trying to do
yeah so
you know when you think about you know
physics so he's you know he's a
physicist when he was even when you know
when he was a teen he's a well-known
accomplished physicist when he was 19
so he's a certified genius okay so
anyway
[Music]
i want to see what's the ultimate theory
of physics okay the um what um
what they say the
uh what they say i forgot what's the
what's the jargon theory of everything
okay so here it is okay so in physics
you have this
you know this dramatic phrase
theory of everything basically the
physicists are trying to find a
one final
most most fundamental theory that
describe the entire uh universe you know
right now we have many theories you know
like quantum theory
that's part of it you know we have you
know quantum theory is about
subatomic particles you know quantum
theory very strange so quantum theory
you have theories about
i don't know you know i don't know
theory i don't know physics much okay so
you have quantum theory you have gravity
you know theory about gravity basically
we don't know how gravity actually works
exactly
you have
theories about
mass and energy
and
then you have theories about i
einstein's relativity
uh i'm you know i don't know physics so
i'm not sure how how they relate exactly
you have you know
so all these theories about you know
fundamental theory theories of physics
but there are many holes
so far so we have very uh we have
several different models yeah unsolved
problems in physics you know we we don't
have one
single equation you know a single
consistent theory to
to uh describe all of them together in a
consistent way
so that is
you know we need a theory of everything
and
okay so
one of the thing is about cosmology okay
it's not really really related to
theory of everything but um
okay cosmology is basically the study of
universe okay so let's see model okay
uh yeah so we have the lambda cd and
model i don't know what is that
lambda cdm
okay lambda code dark matter model is a
uh is a
parametrization of the big band
cosmological model okay so anyway in
cosmology you know um
there it is the big bang the where does
the universe came from
you know where does the universe came
from you know it said
again i don't know physics okay so
so i'm just
i'm just kidding i'm just doing a talk
show you know i can kind of give i can i
can kind of give you like the overall
hand-waving explanation of what what are
these so big bang is the theory the
universe is the theories that long you
know many long time ago the universe is
just a kind of a point or something then
it started to expand and then
you know we don't know if it's
continuously expanding or it's starting
to shrink or something so i mean there's
a lot of questions and solved questions
you know what so what happens before the
big bang and things like that
so basically the big bang theory is a
is a theory about cosmology the origin
of the universe or what happens you know
what's going on in the universe you know
so it's it tries to answer those
questions and uh you know it's one of
the model or theory yeah it's a
you know big
big band the big bang theory is the
prevailing
cosmological model explaining the
existence of the observable universe
from the earliest known periods through
the subsequent large-scale evolution
okay that's what big bang is
so anyway so
remember it's a cosmological model of
the universe so it's it tries to explain
some aspect of the universe
okay now stefan you know so stephan
wufam has a physics project okay and the
goal of that project is trying to
explain
basically another he's trying to give a
another model of the universe it's
called um
he has a blog of that
of course i mean he's got so many blogs
okay i read you know like about five
years ago
he wrote a blog that that begins to talk
about this idea basically essentially he
thinks that you know you know all the
atoms in quantum you know atoms and
atoms you know he thinks that
at the most basic level they are um
they are
how do you
well i don't okay i don't know but
basically he think it's just a bunch of
networks okay like dots connected by a
line okay
a three-dimensional network okay
then
you have certain
very simple rules that
says
how the network should change like if
you have a line connecting two points
if the points are such and such then
in the next evolution in the next step
the line should be removed something
like that okay so you have a network
basically a bunch of points connected by
lines
then you have certain rules very simple
rules that that says which line should
be connected which
you know which two dots should be
connected and how they evolve you know
that says how their network evolved by a
very simple list of rules
so
this is his model of the universe so
that he in his theory the universe is
just this
you know these
dots connected by lines
and at each step discrete step they
evolve you know the line the connection
changes at each step
so in his view
again it's like a meta theory you know
we don't know you know you know some
physicist would say this is crap this is
this this is pseudoscience you know
literally some some some well-known
physicists believe you know this is this
is just garbage
but some some some has some other people
believe this there's a potential you
know this is maybe this is ultimate
automatically this is a good model of
the universe you know some some others
might believe that
so anyway that's what he's saying you
know the universe is just a bunch of
dots connected by lines and they change
how the lines how the dots connect
changes constantly
in a discrete way discrete way in each
step they
according to certain very basic rules
so so you have this massive network that
evolves so he in his opinion this
can explain
newtonian physics but can also explain
relativity and can also explain quantum
theory you know he's beginning to
explore it and there are other
um
physicists you know working with him to
to trying to um
to polish this
this idea this thought so that's
essentially
as far as i know that's what essentially
rudiology
is about
it's a term he created
because
you know he's using wufang language to
model this network
um you know because if you look at his
um
his blog you know
there's a tons of you know let me show
you one of his um
yeah so
you know he's his vlog has tons of these
images graphics networks of networks
created by wufang language you know
very complex you know this you know one
of the you know this is you are looking
at the power of
language you know you can you can create
this actually for example let's see this
one
uh no i don't have the i don't have the
code for the function so
can we do that actually
uh yeah i'm trying to maybe we can run
the code and show you the graph
but you know just for this feature of
language you will not see anywhere else
like today you have javascript oh it can
draw this
powerful you know visual.js 3d you know
d3 dot js you know
compared to wolfram language
those are all the crap
okay
so anyway so
let me you know so he's got this huge
you know you know history of the graph
and uh mo
you know he's
trying to explore
what happens when you change the rules
of the graph evolution things like that
okay
yeah so here's a very typical you look
at this one okay this graph
is very typical of his like model of the
universe thing
uh
you know then he explores all different
so what what is this
and it gets more and more accomplished
like this one you know so what is what
is this article uh multiple
multi computation with numbers the case
of simple
multi-way systems okay
so multi-way system is basically
you know remember we are talking about
the networks
uh give a network that evolves evolves
you know change the connection by
certain
simple rules
so
then then he gets into multi-way it's
meaning that
instead of one set of rules what what if
you have
many set of rules
and you see how they
evolve concurrently
that's what that's what he's talking
about multi-way computation so
multiple you know so that's what he's
what that's what he mean multi-way
system so he's trying to explore
from a pure computational point of view
you know most of you will be interested
because we are programmers
pure computational point of view what
happens we if you evolve a
network
with a bunch of a set of rules
that that says how you how the network
should change but instead of one set of
rule you have multiple going
concurrently
what happens to them what
you know that's what he's talking about
multi-way so
again the radiology is part of it you
know it's about rules
it's about yeah something like that okay
that's what i know about it
okay i think that's it for today oh yeah
so let's go back and maybe i should uh
go back to how many people are watching
two people
so uh
i want to change
can i fix this
okay i fix this code today
okay that's it for today today yeah i'm
not gonna you know i already talked for
70 80 minutes
and
we
were going to
you know get this to work
okay that's it yeah good thank you
coffeehouse
bye guys
uh
so you wanted to okay um
everything okay
now i'm you know i'm thinking at least
to get something to work with this um
well the reason you know my live view
doesn't much have many people because i
you know i um i don't announce in
advance usually it's like three hours in
advance but
the time changes all the time
unpredictable so
and the topic changes unpredictably you
know whenever i feel like today oh it's
going to be moving language you know
you know in three hours in advance so so
that's the situation yeah anyway i think
i'm gonna quit today
so and what you know
work on the code uh offline so okay bye
guys