monie everyone welcome to another
episode of Zatoichi Oh today is October
2nd Wednesday nanocloud a.m. San
Francisco time in sunny sunny California
good morning Bartholomew so you send me
an email I got an email is it about is
it about jobs so what is today's topic
if no topic I'm going just going going
to go random ok lots of topics to talk
about random stuff so let's pop these
out why do I have two of them shut down
one of them shut this down pop it out
again and and I am Alive ok and stop
this video from playing and let's just
talk about things ok go to the talk show
page showing browser scroll down and
let's start now if you have a topic any
time just say hi say good morning Kathy
so Kathy any interesting things to talk
about
any anything you like to me to talk
about ok so so so talk-show so let's see
the hum phone so yesterday we did we did
a talk show that is that is fantastic
well it's you know it's it's it's pretty
focused so yesterday the topic is the
rise and fall of XML and with this
mantra that PP conservative in what you
send PB broening what you accept now
that is the most damaging mantra from
the UNIX from the tech geek earth from
the hacker type of people programmers
and you know
so yesterday I post this on Twitter you
know after my talk by the way let me
tell you guys so if you are watching
offline
not live you can always play my videos
at one point two five speed or 1.5 speed
that's usually better because I don't
talk you know i it's better okay and
also also because also what i want to
say you know feel free to jump around
and also yeah okay
so after the live talk after live stream
usually after two hours it will show up
on youtube with the chat and usually
after about four hours I will add the
description in the description box like
all the links we talked about in a video
like you know for example this is my
website I have a link
you know several links we talked about
story of XML and Marquis blink tag sv
and tutorial things like that you know a
list of topics and usually I put that in
the youtube description as well so if
you watch my past videos you can see it
I just begin about three minutes ago
good morning cool too cool for school
too cool for school c'mon easy Tron
crazy how are you doing how is your
study so it's close that reopen why is
it okay so close I'd reopen some talk
show that's right we are going to talk
about
so yesterday I did you know I started to
do NPM stuff so let's see go through my
tab so they go through my tabs
programming blog dev blog okay yesterday
I was I did this I think it's okay so
your schoolwork is okay great
now if you don't if you have issues with
math homework as you know I am a seer I
can help you well you are German you
know German people are also where long
as you know
you have the so called stevia type of
being smart you know German people have
you know so there are stereotypes of
different people of course but that's a
kind of that's a sensitive topic you
know in USA in in in this white
countries they they they oh my god they
they got things to say anyway so back to
back to MPN MPM is a circus
[ __ ] you know npm and not jails okay not
yes is you know from technology point of
view not jeaious is not that good okay
but however it's it came at the right
time where you know do you guys know why
not Jas is popular it was become
becoming all over the place not jeaious
do you know let me explain
if you don't know I can do explanation
of that so six people watching good
morning people
okay sorry not J's okay not Jays
I have several articles about not Jas
from technical to fun so not jazz Maggio
not jazz tutorial not jazz module what
is is about
I don't remember let's look and this
annoying article I'm about I'm about as
good as dead
now this is as I mentioned before this
is this happened around 2013 now it's on
Hacker News and it's also on my website
and it's everywhere like every time you
search my name that link will just be
the first why because that's dramatic
everyone you know like people who don't
know what who who I am you know they may
they may run into my video sorry right
and so they search you know who is this
guy
sorry and and Amanda answers you know
I'm on the Google results or whatever
they will see this
they stink I'm about as good as dead and
that they will click that first that's
why that link remains on top you know
forever why do they why do people click
that because that's dramatic you know
that's oh you know that's dramatic and
it's kind of annoying because it you
know it's kind of annoying
similarly for you know I have a nude
picture of myself now I mean I'm sure
some of you know about that you know and
and that's you know that's just that's
the that's the only almost it's like
these dramatic things that's the only
thing people know about you they talk
about all the time and meanwhile you
know meanwhile and they ignore all the
other things you have for example on
your website you know I have for example
on my website I have a few thousand
articles but for example let's say you
it's not say me let's say you because
then good morning Matt so Matt do we
have a topic let's say you okay so you
create a website you write blogs for ten
years okay and you have let's say five
thousand articles you've written now if
there's one of them just one of them one
of your blog post that that that has a
nude picture of yourself okay you are
talking about something and you show a
nude picture of yourself now that that
one will be the most visited page you
know like the other page might have 100
views but that page will have 10,000
views and everyone whenever people talk
about you it will be that page you look
at it look at that guy naked there you
know is the [ __ ] idiots
this is phenomenon this is a general
phenomenon of human animals okay this is
natural this is this there's really
nothing wrong with it okay it's just the
way things are natural because people I
mean including myself everyone they
yeah in check you know you just ends up
you know you want to look at dramatic
things you know alarming things dramatic
alarming or you know things like that
that's just human nature okay and and it
has evolutionary reasons because for
example alarming things like people are
crying especially girls you know people
are crying or girls are crying or
someone got beaten those are alarming
things because that that threaten new
news like that threatens your safety you
know your survival so you want to know
about it you if someone is crying or
someone you know they say a guy got
beaten or some girl is crying you want
to know about that because that's that
interest you and I said you know I
suppose for women too you know if you
are women you want to know some other
girls you know you know crying because
maybe you you need to worry about that
as well for safety you know for survival
so that's just natural behavior that's
you know that's we can say there's
nothing wrong with that but however with
today's technology you know the
communication the Twitter social
networks and and also because the way
they they want more traffic and you know
a bunch of reasons like that therefore
this kind this kind of things went out
of proportions you blow blew out of
proportions that's why today on on
social network Facebook Twitter and
other places every day you see is just
angry stuff it's like oh brain angry
anger dramatic or clickbait memes
brainless things and they get the most
likes you know they get the most likes
anything that's of substance you get
nothing so so this is one aspect of
human nature that got
that got that got what's the word
magnified there's a word I want to use
that forgot that got you know magnified
200 times by because of technology now
we now this part the second part that
technology magnifying some certain
rather not-so-good aspect of humanity or
behavior that part is a bad part okay
that part we can do something about we
can change but you know it's it's
getting worse because these news
websites you know this commercialization
they you know they want to make money so
they do all things they can including
using psychology to create more
traffic's therefore more ads more money
for themselves Twitter Facebook you know
that okay so let's talk about why not
Jas is over the face and let's catch up
with the comments morning morning
Justine I only know you for Lisp and
Emacs stuff in your Twitter okay great
map says country having a nice pumpkin
soup I'm here to look today pumpkin soup
I don't think I ever had pumpkin soup
but I have I like pumpkin pie dough Punk
pumpkin pie I like pumpkin pie because
it's cheap you know you can usually
around this time you know Halloween is
coming so around this time you have
pumpkin pie like this you can buy in a
local local shop Safeway over here and
it's you know it's as long as it's not
too sweet it's pretty healthy you know
it's just made up pumpkins so we gonna
let's talk about not J's okay the story
of Nadia's not Jas modules
what is is oh yeah not just modules this
article is about the library system in
JavaScript extreme complicated [ __ ] the
evolution of JavaScript and in
particular the evolution of library
systems and namespace in JavaScript it's
it's completely [ __ ] up and and this
Arco is not just tutorial okay
I studied not just for for like one year
and it's pretty simple so I did I wrote
this in 2013 it's pretty simple okay
notice I you can write a server you can
write a web server or chat server in
like 50 lines 50 lines of code so I did
that and I wrote a chat server he you
know I wrote a chat server so you can go
to a website it's not up now though do I
have it somewhere here so you know you I
have a web server you go to Kesari dot
in forward slash something something I
forgot where then you can chat to people
you know you just go there and chat
maybe we can do that sometimes you know
so you guys can go there and we can
start a chat but however I haven't this
is back in 2013 so it's like five years
I haven't touched my stuff but okay but
but but we are talking we are going to
talk about why not J's become popular so
you know this is not a this is not
something this is actually something a
lot of people know because not just
become very popular around 2008 ok 2008
to 2010 it becomes hugely popular you
know we shoot into the sky and the
reason is that because not years at a
time
not jeaious introduced to the world the
idea of
how do you say that oh my god I have the
syndrome of not not able to think of the
word or phrase whenever I'm talking I
think that's a problem with me because
this moment I'm talking I've to people I
forgot the names of phrase or things but
not okay not jazz is popular because it
popularized the idea of a paradigm of
programming where where you have a
synchronous a synchronous how do you say
that what's the phrase anyone can
describe that like the number one reason
not J has become popular
there are basically two reasons okay one
is that the it introduced introduced a
synchronous programming I think there's
a proper term for that but I forgot so
that's one of the reason yeah and the
other reason is server-side JavaScript
okay silver side JavaScript
so that's a two reason so popular
server-side yes Pablo says and panel
says concurrency it's not concurrency
okay it's it's a that's not concurrency
now that's another topic very confusing
you have concurrency you have parallel
programming these two subjects are very
different
okay parallel programming is just
running you know programming in parallel
like you know for example 10,000
computers that's parallel programming or
run in ten programs at the same time
that's also parallel programming or you
know I'm running a browser I'm running
YouTube you know I'm running Emacs
that's also parallel program that well
that's also parallel computing okay but
so that's parallel programming parallel
you know you mostly yeah you know you
run things at the same time like that's
parallel programming now concurrency is
related to parallel
programming but however is entitled
entirely different concurrency is about
set it is about solving one specific
problem by using parallel programming
okay but it's about solving one problem
for example wait how do I say these
concurrency is about solving yeah basic
basically you're solving a single
problem by parallel programming now why
is this different from just parallel
programming because when you solve a
single problem as you know let's say
find all the prime number so a factor of
prime number or all serving website you
know any any problem okay when you solve
a single problem using multiple
processes or thread okay let's not
mention those those are more that's
because those are also very complex
concepts okay but anyway when you want
to solve one problem by using multiple
you know CPU or multiple computing
resources
that's called concurrency and that's
that's different just that's different
from just running you know several
computers because because concurrency
usually you have the timing issue like
for example let's say let's say let's
say you want to sort a list of numbers
okay let's say you have a list of
numbers 1 to 100 in random random order
you want to sort it now if you use no
more programming okay non parallel
normal programming you just you know go
you know you try to sort it there are
many algorithms sort the numbers you
know you compare two numbers which one
is bigger move the small smaller one to
front to the front then you compare
again you know things like that you know
that's that's sorting in a normal way
now if you want to do this in a parallel
way you know you
you immediately you begin to see a
problem because you have to coordinate
your you know different CPUs you need to
coordinate for example one way is that
so you have 100 numbers at least of a
hundred numbers you you split the list
into two lists you know so this is 50
numbers here and this is the list of
another 50 numbers then you run your
algorithm on each one so you can have
both of them sorted but then then you
need to merge them you need to merge
them back into at least then you need
you you still need to show them you see
that's a problem it's not trivial we
when you have an algorithm for some to
solve some problem solving equations
sorting a list sorting files or whatever
you cannot simply you know if you have
ten CPUs you cannot simply just say do
it on time CPUs you see this sorting
problem shows the example you can't just
do it you have to in fact you have to
change your algorithm almost entirely
you have to be righted it's not going to
be the same algorithm so so so so this
is about concurrency can concurrent
programming okay that's a problem that's
actually that's the difficult part
concurrency concurrent programming and
and likewise today we have concurrent
programming languages from I mean
languages that that has features that
helps with concurrent programming such
as closure closure has that goal and has
that in other languages ok closure goal
and that's to two big examples
so in summary concurrency programming is
about solving one problem using multiple
multiple programs meanwhile parallel
programming is about simply you know
just just doing multiple programs
usually solving
as well okay right so I did I did I make
that does that make sense so I'm back to
JavaScript so back to not J's so I was
saying not J's became very popular for
two reasons one is that it interview
arised the idea the concept of the
concept of what so what I again okay so
right so so not just introduced
popularized the concept of God what's
the word I just used before not just it
a synchronous okay
synchronous not jeaious became popular
for two reasons one reason is that it
popularized the concept of a synchronous
programming okay we can explain that now
the other reason is because it's a
JavaScript on the server it's it's a
webserver it's a it's JavaScript
designed to learn to write web servers
now why is that important you know you
can write a web server in C++ in Perl
Python was whitewash why would anyone
want to use JavaScript because now if
you if your server is also written in
JavaScript then your front end and the
back end or in the same language that
has advantages because you know it has
several advantages for example all your
programmers can can work on front end
and back end at the same time you know
and also this less less communication
friction you know they say you know the
hacker types say arms impotence have you
guys heard of that that phrase
om how do you say that
om friction basically like when you've
tried trying to convert over P to
function of programming or vice versa
or between different languages in the
same system you have arms impotence
not impotence but it's another word guys
do you guys know what I'm talking about
help me out to say type it omz okay
Oh om z not om z but something it's an
electronic it's it's it's a term from
elect electronics where you have you
have voltage you have currency and you
have omz
or something like that that I don't
remember the terms the Ponemah did it's
not it's it's what what are we saying
yeah so we was talking about JavaScript
not jeaious we were talking about Why
Why is it advantageous to have to use
the same language in both front end and
server because then you have less
friction you know one language for
everything but there's a word it's not
omnipotens okay input impotent impotence
yes I am PE DNC I am PDA and see okay
now we can try to such that we will find
it OMG speaker impotence
okay speaker in electric electrical
impotence impotence impotence electrical
impedance
and that's measured in om okay so I mean
oh yeah Oh hm this one okay so here here
it is let's see
om this one Omega symbol you see you see
this part this this this part okay
Oh H M um so the so you have this phrase
um impotence impotence among the hacker
types you know who these are the people
who are talking on Hacker News already
all the time they tell you what to do so
they have this phrase um impotence
impotence let's see okay you need to
type programming okay programming then
you start to see articles that using
that phrase know is that okay maybe
yeah I'm not finding no article but
anyway I saw that this jargon sometimes
about maybe five years ago I I don't
think I've seen it these days okay so we
were talking about why not J's was
populist so two reasons
you know JavaScript as a server language
and also the popular
popularization of a synchronous
programming okay sing or nurse
programming okay
such a browser or synchronous
programming Microsoft what is a
synchronous programming now so so back
to the topic so we were talking about
parallel computing we were talking about
concurrency concurrency okay
this-this-this concurrency programming
versus parallel programming that's a
frequently asked question I give you
such these Yosi lots of articles and I
have a article as well so this is a big
topic so if you are not familiar you
should get familiar with it because it's
a very very common question and also
it's kind of advanced because is it's
likely okay for all your life in
programming you will not run into that
issue you will not be doing concurrency
programming you will not be doing
parallel programming okay although these
are things you know you see them talked
about all the time because it's dramatic
it's like oh the future whatever you
know the function of programming or
whatever but but in practice it's it's
not a calm
and think you have to worry about
parallel programming or concurrency
programming yeah but it's traumatic
that's why so closure Oh closure is
designed for concurrency you know you
hear that and go lat
but in practice as an average programmer
that's not something you have to worry
about unless of course unless you are
working on some swish some some some
project that requires that and it
becomes more and more common because you
know today for the past ten years the
CPU has not being able to be faster you
know because the the transistors in CPU
has become smaller and smaller to
basically reaching the limit it cannot
be no longer be can become smaller
anymore
and so you know like in from 1990s to
2010 the CPU speed increases every year
you know every every year two years you
know you have you have 1,000 Hertz then
100 you know then 2,000 Hertz 3000 Hertz
and today we are pretty much stuck with
3000 Hertz so the cpu speed does not
increase any more but however you
started to have more CPUs you know so
you have like they call it core like
multi-core you know basically one CPU
but you have actually several course
cause our basically our CPU unit so
Emory Berger has a good recent talk
about these okay I don't know who is
that
I don't mind such a good morning to for
okay so what are we talking about I
wanted to show you yeah okay so
concurrency programming and parallel
programming there are different things
okay
in fact there's also a Wikipedia article
and actually I have an article I want to
show you parallel programming problem
asked so this actually this problem is a
good example of good example of a task
for
programming and in fact it's a it's it's
concurrency issue as well so you can
like read it but I wanted to show you
the article where I talked about
concurrency and parallel programming
it's this one okay now guys steel guy
steel now we digressed we haven't got
into the article about the not J's
there's a funny video I want to show you
yeah okay so hold on second so we have
multiple digression topics here okay so
you explain that so so first of all this
article guys do okay so and I want to
talk about I want to show the article
about not Jas video ok of a synchronous
programming okay there's a very fun
funny video and and that that went viral
about 10 years ago and okay meanwhile
and let's go here let's go - let's go -
fine this is a goal and script this is
my goal and script and that's type
that's such in this directory let me
show you over here let's move it here so
let's show you exactly info directory we
want to search for not Jas okay let's
see hmm
actually we don't want to search all the
file names so actually just go through
my my directory so this is sorry info
find magnify actually of a new window
saw start command log mod
so you see all my Emacs command course
there fine name
nod okay HTML any file that contains not
which then we will find it and meanwhile
okay this actually not not too many
okay Ryan Dow on history of not J's
very interesting Ryan Dow is a very
interesting guy I talked about this a
few times he is the inventor of Nadia's
and he is a mathematician he is a you
know PhD student you know he's a real
mathematician so he study K theory
something very esoteric so he's a
mathematician and he he says he's he's a
great very powerful very capable guy and
he just dived into programming and he
just created not years out of blue like
within two years of programming
experience and you know he's a very
bright guy he was studying PhD and he
got bored you know when you study math
when you study math when you dive like
this beyond you know when you're doing
PhD at that level basically the things
you are talking about nobody understand
okay you you can't even explain to
people because you can kind of explain
but they nobody understand it 202 to
actually convey some minimal degree of
real understanding takes you know takes
takes like a few days of talking you
know if for example you know yeah so
that's that's math you know so he was
studying math nobody understanding it's
like that when you study math but
however the subject matter is kind of
extremely beautiful you know you just
you just live in it that is why many
mathematicians are kind of this mad you
know guy so anyway he was a
mathematician and he his ideas about
programming are very interesting I like
him
with his views and similarly he also
flames you know like like the technology
the programming languages we have the
UNIX system that's all crap okay what we
have every day you work with that's
that's extremely complicated
[ __ ] you know it's a it's a [ __ ] up
[ __ ] system that was possible that's
what he says exactly that is my opinion
as well and then you have this you know
these hacker types that tells you what
to do they think oh everything is great
oh you should use you know no chairs or
functional programming or C++ the UNIX
facts UNIX people you know that that's
like that okay so anyway I highly
recommend you know you watch you know
Ryan tau he is now working for Google on
some machine learning AI stuff so what I
want to show okay history of not jeaious
okay that okay we got so let's go to
talk page and we and D here is today we
let's link Phi that article and let's
show some of the others navigate not not
J's tutorial oh this one wait yeah this
one this video that's the one I'm trying
to find okay I'm going to show you let's
go to the talk page paste it here and
there is another thing I want to show I
think this this one yeah so paste it
here link of Phi okay
close close the shell and show in
browser yeah so there are a few videos
I'm going to show you
so not jeaious I recommend his stuff
okay I mean the Ryan doll
not-not-not J s okay Ryan Dow I
recommend his his videos you know
whenever he's got a video go watch him
that's what I do i watch his videos you
know I respect his opinions you know
things like that but not just is not
necessarily good thing you know okay
yeah we wanted to expand the idea of a
synchronous programming so what is it
what is a synchronous programming okay
you watch this video this video is very
interesting okay this video happened
around 2013 it went viral
okay so it's how do you you may already
have seen it so let's let's show you the
let's show you the URL okay so now let's
go to that URL okay then this watch that
well I'm not gonna play the whole thing
you might have seen it but you know but
you just go to this URL you can watch it
okay but
okay so this video the whole video is
like that it's a kind of a 3d animated
cartoon so these two bears are talking
they are talking about Apache versus not
jeaious versus ng nude ng INX that's a
web server okay basically they were
talking about you know not just
introduce the idea popularized at least
the idea of a synchronous programming
and you know that is that is kind of
what the big reason that not J is become
popular and also it's a dramatic reason
because because that concept you know
it's like one of the jargon all the
programmers are talking about it is it
really good you know so you have like
half programmer saying oh this is the
greatest invention since sliced bread
then the other half a programmer says no
that's the worst thing that's you know
that's what compilers are for you know
things like that
and so this this video it's kind of a
comic video that captures the humor you
know the debate so okay so that that is
what I wanted to talk and talk you know
that that is the video I want to show
and actually so these two bears are
chatting you know back and forth it's
very funny and I did a full
transcription of their dialogue okay so
for example you know the bear you know
the the red lines are from the black
bear okay and the the the yellow Beier
is talking about Apache you know like
any okay so he's giving a lecture and he
has okay any questions then comes up
this brown bear brown bear ask ask you
know what about not yes you know and the
the the bear tries to answer oh that's
good but because you know so Apache
don't use that or something
that prom payer kept saying things you
know it's like the way when you have a
new jargon in programming community such
as so many examples over the past 20
years 30 years you know in Perl you have
you have ten tens of jargons as you know
you know laziness laziness you know the
language was you know human language
like English you know who of what's
somehow being a good thing you know and
baseness is a is a good property or
programmers things like that that's from
Perl then you have then you have
patterns you know programming patterns
Oh programming is like architecture you
know the you know patterns then then
later on you have anti patterns you know
these [ __ ] jargons factory pattern
those whatever patterns snake all your
pattern you know pattern is no good okay
it's a worse [ __ ] it's a it's a code
though I don't I don't do anything I
don't do anything with the patterns [ __ ]
it's a it's a entire nonsense okay
programming patterns I can't you know we
can talk about that some other day for
one our programming patterns but you see
Wayne Wayne is popular poem patterns is
popular around year 2000 okay 2000 to
2010 it's everywhere like every
programmer is talking about pattern so
oh you should pattern this pattern that
oh that is called pattern something
something today you don't hear it much
anymore you know you come and go oh
these programming [ __ ] and so patterns
then you have extreme programming pair
programming agile so extreme programming
came first it started around year 2000
okay then you have pair programming is
all part of extreme programming then
extreme programming evolved into agile
it is it's pure garbage okay then then
oh yeah then the unit testing [ __ ] okay
the unit testing it's a it's crap okay
it's a snake oh yo you you almost never
never do unit testing okay
you know that that should not be taken
literally now I'm not saying when it
comes to unit testing
you know forget first of all forget
about the [ __ ] jargon unit testing
test your ass okay yes you can write
programs to to test your software that's
good okay and that's that's sometimes
necessary in big big project and also
that is very suitable when you have
certain software very suitable for
example when you should spaceships to
the to the moon you need to you can use
lots of that Mathematica for example
Mathematica wolf and research they have
you know testing you know software that
test software back in 1990s I know that
you know the entire system build system
test system to test math math
Mathematica whenever there's a new
version coming out okay before that's
before you have the child and unit
testing [ __ ] the unit testing okay
because first of all [ __ ] the jargon
okay don't don't ever don't don't buy
into the jargon unit testing because
jargons often it's a case when you have
a coat you jogging is one of the
elements one of the pillar that that
pushes the code that grows the code so
typically almost always code always have
lots of jargons associate associated
with it so joggins usually you want to
avoid similarly that guys i talked about
this many times in haskell you have
monad you know in a monad kareem in in
scheme bees you have tail recursion you
have code CC in Common Lisp you have
Marcos you know Marcos and all the time
Marcos everything is Marcos the whole
universe is [ __ ] Marcos then in
notches for example JavaScript you have
a sink programming you have this
callback function this is all idiotic
then agile of course unit testing you
know so first of all when whenever you
see jargons that's popular you know Rosa
in programming
it's probably bad okay that's probably
bad and it's probably likely associated
with code in emacs for execs for example
in Emacs you have meta meta [ __ ] key
you know if it's almost like when you
think of that jargon then you
immediately think of the thing it's
associated you know so meta key Emacs
and and also scratch buffer Emacs and
those two are no good it's no good okay
so so jargon so if we were talking about
unit testing
okay that's test means good unit testing
testing is it's not bad idea but not the
way you know not not the way average
programmers perceiving it because y-ye
becomes a code because money you know
these you have you have thousands of
corporations that sell that try to
consult or sell help help your company
do agile you know so it is them these
these usually small corporations like
thousands of them they are pushing agile
they are push on Geo to make money for
themselves so they tell you that is why
a spread it becomes a code that's why
you know the HR people say oh you should
do this this this you know it becomes
you know it's spread they they spend
money to advertise you know that's what
it washes your brain that's why H is
zero value okay I just say it bluntly
zero you know it's it's the the way you
the way you should okay if you like to
follow my opinions the way you should I
say that the way you used the way you
should react to agile or is that you
should you know it's it's like treated
as a crime like okay so when when your
friends say Sarge agile you say that's a
that's a criminal that's a quiet there's
no no year to it okay that's you know
that's about agile okay now of course
when when this kind when coats become
big okay it's often often your friend
will be part of it because like like
online you know you sometimes you talk
to your friend and sometimes yeah and
your friend will say oh actually no
actually actually and Joe is not bad
actually I like it very much so you got
the problem you know your friend is
saying that Oh for example my my friends
my acquaintances and followers a lot of
them you'll be into UNIX philosophy they
every time something comes up the hotel
oh you should do it this because snow is
beautiful because kiss you know keep it
simple stupid you know this bunch of
jargons so there's nothing you can do
there's nothing much you can do it do
with it be you know coats you know they
spread just like politics you know
politics you always have someone your
friends who does not believe what you
believe
similar with religion now let's now also
remember these topics there's no
absolute answers okay so there's no it's
not it's not absolutely true that you
know whatever you believe is correct of
course but anyway the back to agile it's
it's just it's a it's just a snake oh yo
okay
in my opinion okay so we talked about
this article we we are synchronous
programming yeah a synchronous
programming now this is important to
remember a synchronous programming a
synchronous programming the way it not
Jaso JavaScript is doing they have they
they have nothing to do with concurrency
or parallel programming a synchronous
programming is not parallel programming
at all okay at all you know it's this is
a important issue and this is also you
know is it's frequently talked about
issue so you
need explanations about that I have
explanations about that you know because
this is a big confusing issue too many
JavaScript programmers now okay here's
the thing here's the answer in
JavaScript and also not jeaious okay
javascript doesn't matter it's running
on notches or running in browser
JavaScript is so-called
single thread okay single thread so at
no time it's not parallel at all no time
it's parallel therefore it's not it no
where is it concurrent okay it's it's no
nothing like that
then what what is a synchronous
programming so the JavaScript a
synchronous programming is kind of it's
just for example for example let me give
you examples when you have a program you
need to when people log into your
website right they type a login name you
know email address and password then you
take that unit you need to query the
database you know you you send a query
to the database to see if that user
exists right so you send the query to
database you have to wait for it to come
back you know everything else stops your
program stops your the whole software
stops wait for the answer from the
database then a database come back with
you know send back the username password
then you then you start to run again you
know check if it's valid or not okay now
this is no more now in a synchronous
programming what do you do is that okay
you got the name and password you you
could now you query the database but you
don't wait you don't wait for the
database to come back okay you don't
wait for it rather you continue you
continue what with whatever you have to
do with your program then when when the
database send back the result you have a
function that takes that result and do
whatever it's supposed to do
that is that is a synchronous
programming actually we can we can show
some code in JavaScript to show you how
that works
but anyway anyway that's about a
synchronous programming okay so remember
it has nothing to do with the parallel
programming is it it is not parallel
programming and also in JavaScript
everything is single thread so-called
single thread meaning everything is just
running running in sequence at no time
it's running two things at the same time
okay then but but how do you we you know
I just mentioned you wait for the
database to send you a result how does
that work okay it works like so you have
to now we have to explain event loops
that's another very interesting topic
that that that would take some time to
explain so but essentially okay the the
code ID the the reason that you could
have a synchronous programming you know
a synchronous programming the reason you
this is possible the the mechanism
behind a synchronous programming is
event loops now that that's another
thing we we have to explain okay so let
me see so comments questions posted okay
and now if you don't get if you want to
keep explained something you know just
questions just post it okay so we are
about one hour so we talked about okay
so that's okay we I you know that's
that's about that so okay back to this
article on this in this article Castillo
Castillo is the very famous you know one
of the most popular this expert he he
created scheme Lisp yeah and he you know
he's a among Lisp programmers he's a big
shot he wrote several books and so on so
at one time he giveth
and you can read this article and also
okay here is parallel computing versus
concurrency problems okay
so note that parallel come note that
parallel programming and concurrency
problem are related but not the same
thing
parallel computing is about writing code
that can run that can use multiple CPUs
okay
concurrency problems is about problems
of concurrent computations using the
same resource or time yes and you have
the issues like race condition fire
locking you know final arcing you you
understand for example if if if I'm
going to yeah let me explain one problem
of concurrent concurrent problems in
programming so I'm going to write
creator editor okay I'm going to create
an editor I'm going to create an editor
on a web so so people can edit it the
same document at the same time you know
you have Google Docs that does does that
okay so if I go there and I edit and you
go there you also edit then you have a
problem I mean if we are editing the
same sentence what will happen it will
become garbage right I type something
you become garbage that is a problem of
concurrency programming you need to so
you see you have this kind of time
conflict like like who is doing this who
is doing this thing at the moment and
another problem is spanking for example
banking so so so suppose suppose I'm of
you know I have me and my brother for
example share the same Bank
so I deposit meanwhile he is withdrawing
at some other location which one comes
first you know if if I deposit if he
withdraw first there is not enough money
but
you know so if I deposit first then he
can withdraw but what happened is if
they happened at the same time which one
you know is supposed to be first that's
kind of the problem with a classic
problem of concurrent program concurrent
programming problems is fire fire
locking okay so okay so so let's see the
comments
some accelerator says when you do shop
scripting do you use eMac B's or would
you use Co for system administration
scripts ok that that kind of depends
okay basically I would not I do not
recommend eMac miss for shell for for
shell scripts rather you use Python Ruby
is far better you can also use : but
it's not as good as Python or Ruby so so
shell scripting use Python Ruby pearl
okay that's much better and you can also
use spash you know the only reason you
want to use smash is is for example if
you want to have a installer program
then you use bash because other people
don't have to install Python Perl Ruby
you know usually they have bash you know
in you know that is why but other than
that if you don't care about if it's not
an installation script then don't use
bash okay bad she is no good so use Perl
Python Ruby okay / Python Ruby
now colon is also good colon is also
pretty good bite but I I realized I
realized that colon code will be twice
twice as much lines than Python or Ruby
you know that's for my experience
because I started to use : for all my
scripting needs for example I have this
I have this golden script this is 160 60
lines of code and this script what it
does is it find fine strings for example
let's find out yes okay not just you
know let's find string not just in this
directory and that directory has like
30,000 files among which it has about
5,000 you know 4,000 html5
so anyway let's run it you know so we
are searching all files or HTML files or
HTML files in this directory searching
for this word this word not yes it's
done okay no it's not done yet
okay so now it's done okay here's here's
the answer is it's a stun at the bottom
you see now let's call so find out put
mod
so it's colored now I can you know now
so here here are the result you know so
it's written that is written in : you
just you have seen this this script 160
lines of code in : and it's pretty fast
you know we we have searched 5,000 files
okay and you can jump to it you know you
can jump to for example I just open that
then here is the here is the occurrence
of that word not just showing browser
okay so it's my blog in 2013 cursor back
to you know so you can jump to yeah so
here's a result you can go down to the
next occurrence or go down by fire but
next file next file so you see so I have
lots of files that mentions the word not
yes so now in Emacs we can do list
matching noise okay let's do this
matching noise okay this matching is saw
slash web so now you see all the files
that contains the word and their
occurrence so for example this file has
16 occurrence of the word not GS you
know so that's :
so what I'm but I was saying that in :
by the way you can find this script
oh my goal and tutorial page you can
find it here ok examples find/replace
okay
so here's a script in Golan that does
find and replace okay so this one is
more that it's more it can be placed
things they mean type it in my in
Microsoft Hawk show page okay so what
I'm saying is that in : typically I
realized that the lines of code the
number of lines of code will be at least
one point five times more than Python so
in Python if it's hundred lines in colon
is 150 guys or double or 200 lines so
that's kind of annoying so if you are
writing shell scripts to manipulate you
know do stream processing or manipulate
files directories Perl Python Ruby are
better but Golan you know colon is
faster you know so if you don't mind
extra line score lines okay but what
what about emag whisp I do not recommend
okay because for for about five years
five to ten years I think I may I may
have talked about this you know older
video for about five to ten years I have
the mindset where from now on I'm going
to write all my shell script in a Mac
this okay I did that for ten years I
have a lot of articles about that a lot
of articles I have like three three
articles at least about that somewhere
somewhere here okay it's somewhere in
emag base miscellaneous where I have
written down my experience it's easier
if you if we just search for sorry eMac
a shell script don't use images for
shell script why because first of all
it's going to be five times slower than
Python okay five times so the slower
than any a Python Ruby pearl and it's
ant it is and and the regular expression
in Emacs Emacs this is a pain in the ass
because if you do shell script you
typically you are often used regular
expressions in eMac this you have back
slashes too many of them it's very
annoying
yeah so in general these two reasons so
I do not recommend eMac this at all
and also eMac this if you really
consider it compared to other languages
it's like ten times worse okay now I
have a video talking about how eMac this
sucks this that's one hour about you
know it's truly it's no exaggeration
let's say two times three you know its
worst is by a magnitude you don't have
libraries you don't have name space you
don't have nothing
okay max the reader okay so any other
questions address to me I'm trying to
avoid treated okay so okay I think
that's it for today oh I got eighteen
people usually it's more and more people
when when I'm about done okay that's it
for today I think let me finish the
comments few more minutes so what did I
miss anything
let's see if we can find granny Mac be
scripting shell yeah that's a tutorial
about how to run a Mac miss script as a
you know the same way you do learn in
Python Ruby pearl how to run JavaScript
which language to learn pro Python Ruby
batch script to
they'd match in brackets okay for
example let me show you a Emacs script
that creates a sitemap actually I did
that in my past videos so it's not you
know I have that in in colon and also in
emag disp okay close that Castillo
we talked about guys do alright so if
you are a lisp fan okay read this page
this is a very good article I mean
mostly it's by Castillo okay he gave a
talk about get rid of counts you know
counts it's another lisp fanatism thing
they want cause you know in fact it's
the worst it's a word it's one of the
most damaging idea in computers in
programming okay comes this comes you
know if you don't know least okay now in
other languages such as Python Ruby
pearl JavaScript colon you have a data
type you have a type of the language
it's named array in colons named slice
or in Python Ruby it's just arrays
sometimes it's called least okay
basically just you have a list of things
now and usually it's usually you can
change you know you can add more items
so you know so it's not fixed array like
in C okay so you have this list datatype
now but in list in list I mean in Lisp
this programming languages when you have
a list they are actually in this in this
programming languages they don't
actually have a list datatype rather you
have what's called can spare okay this
is the most idiotic [ __ ] in the entirety
of programming technology the most idiot
idiotic oh [ __ ] the dispersed and here
I'm showing you the article by Castillo
knock sorry not the idiotic
sorry okay not not the truck sorry but
guy CEO guy steal this honorable person
tells you the least lucky [ __ ] this
phonetic [ __ ] get rid of course
okay now i'm borrowing his article to
show my opinion i've written about this
before i have written quite a few
articles about this these cons okay so
in in lisp languages you don't actually
have at least wherever you have at least
however you act what you have is this
counts okay what so what is a cons cons
is basically like a pair okay so think
of think of a data structure like a list
however you have a limitation where you
can only have two items okay so you just
have two items okay two items that's
that's a data structure that's called
counts okay so what but what if you want
three items you want to list with three
items okay what do you do is that you
nest the counts in a particular way this
way okay opal opal right this way so you
have a cause the second element is
another cause okay then in that cause
the second airman is another cons this
is how you have a list okay like at
least okay so that's that's that that's
what happens in Lisp programming
languages you use cons to create a list
okay the most [ __ ] idiotic technology
in programming languages to this day the
lispers don't get it right like they say
they see this article you know like the
dis programmers you know so they are
expert you know some of them know you
know better than me for sure they they
know comment is I don't know comment
it's been for example they know many of
them know eMac B's better than me okay
no doubt I don't question that
but however but what happens if you have
them reading this article so what
happens if you have list phonetics who
are also these experts who read this
article
what happens they are just brush it away
the way they push it away is like the
UNIX philosophy phonetic [ __ ] when
they read some article by that
criticized Linux for example they will
just push push it away like they will
find reason so that's not important you
know they read it and they forgot by
tomorrow they'll totally forgot about it
we are not registered in their brain
like this article ok so so you have a if
you have you know ask you it you know if
you have at least phonetic who is also a
list but expert ok if he read you know
this guy Co helical you just brush it
away ok yeah yeah you say like oh yeah
it makes sense yeah but by tomorrow you
forgot all about it then by next day
he'll tell other people yeah this cost
these cons is the greatest thing since
sliced bread you know you should use
cause that's what they do
same thing happens in religion in codes
you know in programming languages you
know you have this you just you don't
you don't you don't see things that's
you know that's that's not that doesn't
benefit you you know so yeah this is
this not let me talk about this a little
bit ok now some of you okay yeah let me
talk about this ok so in Lisp you have
counts
ok you can see is a purine type of the
Lisp language which is used to build
lists okay now this is this happens in
Lisp
now now in the subject area of computer
science in the area of data structures
you have you also have something called
list or linked lists okay usually we
just say this but usually technically it
means linked lists okay
now what is a linked list linked list is
kind of just like cons okay you know
here we are talking about memory
addresses we're talking about memory
addresses and you know so we have a pair
of address the second address the
content of the second address holds the
address of another pair of things and
that pair the second elements holds the
address of another pair of things
okay that's basically that's that's
that's linked list now remember we the
linked list is a concept in computer
science okay in Inc in kind of a it's
not it's not even mathematics it's kind
of a hardware it's an implementation
issue you need a CPU you need a fourth
first of all you need a computer
hardware to talk about linked lists okay
anyway so it's a computer science area
computer what practical applied computer
science think linked list now the cons
in these languages now that's a language
design kind of thing that's a historical
you know in the you know why does this
have concepts because back then in 1960s
you have hardware that's actually counts
okay Hardware not today you know but
back in 1960s you have hardware at least
machines okay actually you have counts
okay that I mean like correspond to
memory you have a memory of you know
things like that anyway so remember
these are two separate things
one is a type okay a data type a boolean
data type in your programming language
counts the other concept is more general
it's about implement implementing or
list the data structure list in a in in
you know of a programming language in
hardware okay
vingt beast
the the to concept of it entirely
different okay similar somewhat similar
but they are separate so what I'm saying
okay so for example let me tell you an
example in Python in Perl
in Python Perl Ruby JavaScript this four
language I know I can see on these in
these four languages you don't have cons
you you don't have in these languages
you don't have a data type that's just a
pair of numbered pair of things you
don't have that well in Python you have
topo that's a different thing anyway
topo can be you know two or three items
or more anyway so you don't have cons in
these languages but however if you want
a list if you want a linked list the
concept of the computer science applied
computer science concept of linked list
data structure you can't what do you do
you can you can you can you can
implement it in many ways for example
you can just use at least you know array
or whatever you call them you know in
Python for example you can use the list
of two items then the second item linked
to a variable that's another list of two
items things like that so you can you
can implement least linked list in any
language okay so it's okay so anyway so
I think maybe I should stop today I want
to say what I want to say is that this
you know people get confused about cons
and linked lists okay they are two
entirely separate concept for example
Haskell people then they some Haskell a
DDS okay basically they haven't studied
the issue you know typical I'm talking
about the most average programmers they
will say for example has come
programmers when they see these they all
say oh no you are wrong because even in
Haskell list is made of cons payer no
you don't have fuss you don't have you
know that's that's wrong okay
yeah yeah so I need to explain this
explain this but I'm thinking I should
stop today so yeah one hour and 20
minutes I should stop today I could
explain this encoding you know in this
is important because so anyway just
remembers implementation you have
several different concepts okay Haskell
don't have cons okay
you'll be Python Perl they don't have
cause you if you want at least you can
have at least okay it's building in the
language you know at least whether it's
linked and by the way they aren't
usually not implemented as a linked list
they are implemented as a smart array
okay which means when you have when you
add element that's beyond the current
array size the compact that it will
automatically create a new array that
have more empty slots you know and but
however it pretends you know it doesn't
show the empty start it hides the empty
stock so anyway it gets into details
about implementation okay but anyway in
Perl Python Ruby Perl Python Ruby
Mathematica JavaScript at least in all
these five languages they have at least
you know the jargon depends on the
language you can cover the list or array
basically smart array okay so so that
basically means you can add any items
you can add more items if you want oh
you can shrink you know remove items you
can do that without having to you know
without having to create a linked list
yourself or anything you you know you
just add items to the item a pen a pen
though you know truncate you know it's
high level high level you don't have to
worry about how it is implemented you
don't have to worry about cons okay you
don't have to worry about all that so so
let me just finish by saying you know
this odd just let me
by saying yeah this different constant
you know you look into detail study into
detail you know try to formalize try to
you know then you understand you know
what all this confusing concept cars
linked list implementation array what's
exactly their difference which one
actually in tells the CPU memories to
architecture you know like if some of
this concept they are related to actual
machine you know some odd some of them
are not you know they are just about a
language for example when you talked
about linked lists usually it's a it's
we are talking about implementation on
some hardware linked Beast the you know
the link to about memory addresses they
are usually not about for example in
Python just you know implementing or
lengthy list yourself anyway there are
many issues okay just that's that's that
about that okay so okay that's it thank
you guys for watching if you like my
stuff support me okay put money in my
pocket
you go to patreon you go to okay let me
let me show you this you go to you you
use Bitcoin
okay Bitcoin Bitcoin me so I got Bitcoin
here my paypal my patreon and Amazon
gift card or stuff Thank You Kathy thank
you you guys bye