Hello, good morning everyone. Good
evening. Welcome to another episode of S
talk show. We are going to code Emac
list today of course the most powerful
editor and the most powerful programming
language for processing text. So we so
there's a news uh there is a new native
built-in JSON library. So in EMAC now
you can uh you know you can export and
import
uh JSON data format. Okay. If you are
here say hi if you are watching this
offline watch at 1.5 speed minimum.
Okay. So there's new uh JSON library. So
let me give you so so the functions are
JSON serialized that is you give it an
argument of list list or array or hash
table then it will create a JSON data
format you know it will speed out the
string so I'm going to demo that then
there's JSON insert that just uh that's
like JSON serialize but also insert the
text in the buffer then there's uh JSON
pass string which takes an argument of a
JSON data format then uh then pass it.
Okay. So let me show you what is a JSON
uh data format. So if you don't know you
you should know because it is the most
popular uh JSON. Okay. So wait
uh pop-up data. So where is my JSON
file? JSON. Okay. So not see it there.
So, let's go to keyboard.
Uh,
oh, I think I did I remove it.
Incredible. So, uh,
uh, search data.js.
So, okay. So, yeah. So, this is actually
JSON. So, JSON, uh, file format looks
like that. Okay.
Um and anyway, so you got this function
JSON serialize and JSON pass string and
JSON pass buffer. Okay, so most
important is serialize and pass string.
So they became native in EMAC uh EMAC
30. Okay, so I need to so I you know I'm
going to write a tutorial
uh
EMAC block. I'm going to write a
tutorial for that. So you go to Emacs
and Emacs list this basics. So we're
going to write a tutorial for it. Okay.
So the the this functions was new in
EMAC 27. Okay. Emacs 27 that is from
year 2020. So 5 years ago. And then
in EMAC 30 uh 2025 this year just
released a few months ago they made it
uh native. So before it depends on a C
library. It depends on the existence of
a C library. Now it it doesn't need that
anymore. So it's very good. Now before
that there is a library for uh importing
and exporting JSON and that is from that
is written like 20 years ago.
Uh that is uh do I have it here? No. So
so let me let me let me show you. Okay.
So uh talk show. So what is this page?
Emacs block close close uh talk show and
uh describe function JSON read string.
Okay. So if you look up that function
you'll find the library that is JSON.
Uh which is written in 2016 uh I mean
2006 beginning 2006. So this library
it's part of Emacs is now basically
obsolate because now you have built-in
functions. So let's see defend. So here
are the functions defined in library. I
was using it but I'm going to uh change
update my code uh to use the to use the
building you know uh these are written
in C JSON serialize. Okay. So that is
the basics. So the news is that you got
this new library and the native uh in
Emac Bisp. Okay. Then the rest of the
show I'm just going to start to write
the library for it. Okay. So okay.
So let's see defend I want to know I I
need to uh find the function so that can
lead people to find this library. So
JSON read string that's the one we want.
read the JSON string at point and um no
not JSON read string. So wait. So defend
uh list uh so list JSON uh functions.
JSON print JSON read JSON read from
string. That's one. Read the JSON object
contained in string. Yeah. So that's one
of them. Copy it. Go to talk show. Uh
yeah. So let's just p let's just put
that there. Okay. So that is from that
is basically importing JSON and also you
got JSON read file.
Uh okay so put it there. Then you got um
okay so let's go back. So JSON is the
library. Okay. So open it and uh and
this is the library. Okay.
And uh let's see then what what what is
a function to
um
what is the other function check
position okay so
so if you have comments hello meet
JSON print JSON read file JSON so that's
for import
uh export so print I suppose print and
pretty print buffer. Okay, so you got
pretty print buffer. So this this
library is even though we have this
building functions but I suppose this
library is still useful sometimes
because because then you can um
because you have functions like um like
pretty print you can preprint pre-format
the JSON file. Okay. So anyway, let's
close that. Close that. So So make it
that that that. Okay.
So Okay. So let's begin to write a
tutorial. So Okay. So go to and we going
to I'm going to demo. Okay. So emac this
basics. Yeah. So copy the file path. Uh
paste the file path there. Link it and
go to the file and search for hasht.
Okay. So in here, let's create a new um
import export export import JSON. Okay.
So yeah, let's put that there. So JSON
um then we going to
uh basically copy.
So we can do so um
clone file in link. Okay. So now you got
the file cloned. Paste it here. Let's
rename this file. Rename. Right now it's
a link. So open it. It basically just a
copy of that hasht page. Okay. Now uh
rename the file.
Okay. So we want to rename
emac this JSON. Okay.
Yeah. Okay. So there's no conflicting
files. So
uh and add a title. My convention is you
got this emac list
uh export import
read uh import export JSON or should it
be read write JSON? I think read write
JSON would be uh
more intuitive.
Okay. So JSON or capitalize. Okay. Copy
the file name. Uh actually I mean copy
the the the link text. Okay. So
copy and make a link that jump to the
string. Open it and uh
rename the file JSON read file. Oh, we
forgot emacisp. Okay. Uh
okay. So you can see the file name got
updated. You know why do I want to
clone? Because in on each page you got
several uh JavaScript files special just
for that file. Some files don't have
that I mean link to JavaScript. So
therefore you can you know hoover the
mouse pointer to a function name it will
pop up the inline documentation. That's
why you want you know clone for example
on keyboard pages
uh on trackboard pages or keyboard pages
you don't have that you know JavaScript
so so uh it's a good idea to clone a
file when you work on HTML it's kind of
similar to um in Unix you have processes
you know what they call um fork process
okay so anyway so go back Any comments?
ACP. Hello.
Oh, your volume sounds higher. Thank
you. Yeah, because you said that then I
looked into Yeah, I adjust things. So,
now it works. Uh, that's kind of tricky.
It's an interesting question because uh
because so you go to systems, then you
go to systems, then you go to uh sound
somewhere. Okay. So, so sound then you
go to um
uh
you know windows sucks so so much you
know it's very complex like you have the
preference settings then you have the
control panel [ __ ]
control panel okay for for example so
this control panel is but now they got
system settings but however they didn't
update the control panel So now you got
like two places, two version. You got
100 ways to go to the same place to set
the sound. You need to use one but some
other uh you know configuration you need
to go to the other. Okay. So anyway, so
you go to systems system preference uh
system settings then you go to sound
then you go to uh not that uh you go to
sound control panel. Yeah, you need to
go to control panel. Then you got this
20 years old Asian tiny claustrophobic
[ __ ] you know. Then you you then you
switch tab to the go to the recording.
Then you pick up your pick the the item
that is your microphone,
you know. Then then then you click on
properties. Then you go to the tab of
levels. And here is where you set the
so-called input gain you know kind of
silly you know because they call it gain
because each you know engineering
engineering or different field they have
like particular particular jargon. So
they call this uh typically microphone
gain
uh which
you see there is a gain button there as
well. So, can you see? So, you see,
but anyway, that is the gain.
Check. Check. You don't want it to be
too high though. So, right now, it might
So, anyway, that's how you set up the
microphone.
So, cancel cancel complex. [ __ ] On the
other digression, Google now banned you
block or engine. You see now you cannot
turn it on anymore. You see today I just
got it you know like right now. So let
me make a screenshot of this uh to make
a recording of the what happened so that
10 years later you will know oh this is
this is when Google did this. Uh okay so
what I want to do is control that. Okay,
I got a screenshot.
You block or engineer now is banned by
Google's because Google become so
extremely scum and uh um and deep state
you know they do many things very nasty.
Okay. So, I try not. So, I recommend if
you don't know, I recommend you use the
Braay browser. Brave browser or um
or what's the other one? Uh
don't use Microsoft Edge. Edge.
Microsoft Edge. Okay, that's also
very bad. Okay, don't use Google Chrome.
Uh I recommend use Brave. Okay. So,
Brave, it has um
it has uh blocking building. So, when
you watch YouTube, there's no ads. I
don't have any ads. Okay? So, you guys
donate. Okay? Don't forget you guys
donate to me. Go to sudi.info. I'm going
to repeat that later. So, meanwhile, let
me recommend. So, you can use Brave
browser. Also, use uh Brave search.
Okay? Set your, you know, default search
to Brave. And also uh and in fact these
days I use guork guork.com I highly
recommend it. Okay, guork.com you can uh
for all your search or question needs in
your life or coding needs. I it answer
tremendous amount of tech very technical
uh programming stuff
you know in the past two years. uh
typically you cannot find the answer
even in Stack Overflow or you know so
anyway so so I recommend and and I do
not recommend Firefox they've been
extremely evil as well it's very much
deep state tide okay but so uh I
recommend Brave and I also recommend uh
what's the other browser I can recommend
so what do you guys think
uh there's something. Anyway, I forgot I
have to look into I don't have the link
here. I have it installed, but
I forgot what's the browser name. So,
anyway, let's go back to uh Emacis.
Okay, JSON write file. So, right now
it's about hasht. So, you need to delete
them. Okay, so so update the date and
okay, so that's today's date. This file
is completely new. uh add entry remove
entry check. So I'm using kai HTML mod.
So that allows me the luxury. You see
this paragraph you see that's one
HTML
semantic unit. Okay? See and this color
paragraph that's semantic unit. I press
a key it'll expand. I press a key, it
expand to DD which is definition uh mean
uh definition and and expand again.
Okay, I already uh pressed some other
key. So select expand expand. So the
entire definition list is selected. I
can just press a key to delete it or I
can undo it. You see undo, select,
select again. You see undo or I can just
put a cursor here. press a key that
entire thing is gone. So you can see all
my commands is shown on the pink window
there. Okay. S HTML
um mode. You have to pay me to get it
because for 10 years it's free. Nobody
give you a [ __ ] Okay. So you see all
these blank lines. Press a key. It's all
gone. Now press a key. Press a key. So
show in browser. So now it's down to you
see uh down to that. So delete that. Uh
this is related topics. Uh I I'll add it
later. Okay. And data structure. Oh,
okay. So let's add that here. Okay. So
um copy the file path, paste it. Linkify
JSON read uh read JSON read. Right.
Okay. Make a list. Delete the URL and uh
delete that and uh put it here. So it's
related to data structure uh list vector
because JSON is a data structure format
I mean data structure data type
okay so now so show in browser so now if
you go to list
uh at the bottom you got the same data
structure box but there's no JSON you
see now you go to vector go to the
bottom there is no JSON you need to add
it so let's add that. So, press press uh
wait press.
Okay, it's now it's all done. Uh wait,
press press. Okay, now it's all done.
Now, go to the browser. You can see the
command I called is HTML update topic
boxes.
Okay, now watch here. Refresh. There is
JSON.
Go back to list. Go to the bottom.
There's JSON. Fantastic. Go to JSON. You
know, so this related items allows you
to easily navigate within a specialized
topic.
Okay. JSON read file and what is this uh
key value collection. So that box we
don't need you know that's you know. So
okay. So that that okay. So now let's
open a new window.
uh new huge giant box window and uh
let's make it this background color. Set
background color
to
sea shell. Fantastic.
Okay. And let's go to talkshell. Switch
this one to talk show. So what is this?
Showing browser this basics. Uh search
for JSON. Did we have it? No. We need to
make a change. So, we need to remove
this.
Uh, also we got a extra space. Remove
back here. Refresh. Fantastic. Are you
guys seeing what I seeing?
Okay. So, I'm going to answer the
questions in a bit. Okay. So, so JSON
file close that and update the title.
Uh,
okay. It's already good showing browser.
Okay, let's switch to what is this? Talk
show. Okay, so this page is talk show
and I want to move the items here to my
um
to my from for from my talk show page to
the JSON page. Okay, let me show you how
to do that. Okay, split the window. Uh
split the window. Go to go keyboard
block. Close. Uh go to talk show index
index. Close. Close. Close. Go to JSON.
So this is a JSON file. Now move the
cursor to where I want it to be there.
And go to this talk show page. So you
can see there's a section, you know, or
these bunch of things. Now go to the
top, search for section
uh there. Okay. So, select it. Now, the
entire section semantic unit is
selected. Okay. Now, press press
uh wait press
that's the right key.
HTML move text to uh move text block.
HTML move text block. Okay. So, now you
know the entire section got moved. You
see now talk show is empty. Go to the
JSON file show in browser. Now the JSON
file is populated.
This this is very useful. It is not the
same as if you just like copy you know
copy here cut it and paste it. It's not
the same because all the links
get
updated correctly you know from one page
to another another because especially
when you you know uh when whenever you
have relative links in one directory and
you want to move that you know text to
another page the relative links may
change. So so this function takes care
of that.
Uh kasa kasa something something
something kasa something okay too many
so many commands okay anyway so
uh so what is this page uh yeah so
there's few more things I want to uh
change okay so uh emac this JSON copy it
close it and let's just let's just paste
there okay we are writing this on the
fly okay cut it back to Emacs JSON page
and uh and what is this? Okay. Read. Uh
yeah. Okay.
So, so we are working on this now. This
JSON data structure. Paste it. Okay.
Show in browser. So, let me clean up
uh serialize. Okay. So, these are new.
So, how do you read? So, this is a
tutorial uh to teach you about how to
read. Okay. Yeah. So actually I got one
of that. Um
so this is a reference. We need
reference. Okay.
Reference. Okay. And uh cap and
capitalize it properly. Wait. Yeah. So
make it H2. Okay. And uh cut cut. Now
split go to the bottom and uh put the
reference section here. Okay, now that's
the reference. Now go to the top.
Uh let's see. So this this part about
hasht let me explain that later. Okay.
So
okay. So that goes to talk show.
This is what we going to do. uh import
export right the tutorial. Okay. And uh
and
paste that. Join the list. Okay. Undo.
Showing browser. You can see now join
the list. Join uh wrong key. Join the
list. Showing browser. Okay. That is the
talk show. Now back to the JSON page.
Now serial. Okay. So, what I want is So,
let's let's um
cut cut.
Okay, now move back here on the top.
Show.
Fantastic. Getting better. Now, this
state section, this section, let's
remove the section. Okay, remove the
date. Remove the to-do
and this this format hash table. Let me
explain that one. Okay. So, so I was
format hash table. Okay. So, let let's
copy that. Go to the talk show and uh
let's paste it there. So, I have a
command called format uh hash table. So,
that allows you to print hasht line by
line. Okay. So I was thinking uh maybe I
should update it you know just create
another command that says print hasht so
you can print hasht line by line okay so
I was going to do that then I was
thinking uh since we have JSON export to
JSON you know serialize soal serialize
that's another idiotic jargon from the
industrial coders you know serialize
what does it mean basically you want to
turn a data structure
you know typically internal data
structure into into string okay into a
text representable as a text so so
that's what this jargon serialize mean a
very extreme idiotic jargon from from
the industrial coders I don't know
what's the origin of serialized but I
suppose I blame it on the C C++ idiots
okay it's always these idiots create
They create lots of bad jargon in jarens
and concept in in in computer
programming. Okay. They idiots serialize
the idiocy
the idiocy of the jargon.
Okay. That jargon is used I know in
Java. That's when I first heard of it
like 20 25 years ago. But I don't know
how you know where does it begin. So
does anyone know uh the the the jargon
serialized when you know was it in C or
C++ like when did it became popular or
what you know what uh let me ask let's
ask work okay
what is the origin
uh origin oh I don't have a brief of the
jargon
of the programming I mean
uh
okay let's ask gu.com
what is the origin of the programming
jargon serialize
let's see okay you need to magnify
control scroll up scroll up scroll up
scroll up
okay
am I good you guys is is interesting
So the programming jargon serialized
come comes from the concept of
converting complex data structure or
objects into a linear sequence of bytes
or characters which can be stored,
transmitted or reconstructed later.
Okay. The term derived derives from the
English word serial meaning arranged in
a series or sequence rooted in the Latin
series. Okay. Or raw chain or sequence.
Okay. Origin and evolution early
computing 1960 to 70. The term emerged
in computer science as data needed to be
converted into a format suitable for
storage or transmission over networks.
For example, early databases and file
systems require data to be written in a
sequential serial form to save to disk
or tape. That's right, tar. You know,
glue tar
still in use today. Idiotic from the
Unix idiots.
Okay. So, 1960s7s
you need data to be in a linear format.
Okay. Then then what? Then serialization
in programming by the 1980s as
objectoriented
that's the origin of the [ __ ]
[ __ ] okay from the C++
idiots in Java
the worst paradigm in programming
industry okay so by the 1980s as
objectoriented programming and complex
data structures became common
serialization referred to flattening
objects like graph or trees into a
stream of bytes.
Okay, this allow data to be saved to
files or send across systems with d
serialization as the reverse process to
reconstruct the data. Okay, now I I get
it. So where does the serialization
[ __ ] in end jargon came from? came
from the objectoriented
oriented [ __ ]
Okay, these [ __ ] idiots,
you know, because they they you know
they create this in end jarens that's
misleading because because when you if
you are a programmer you know I suppose
most of you you know when you learn
programming the first time you started
to learn oh serializ so for most people
programmers professional programmers in
the industry they have no idea you know
they serialization is natural natural
word to them because they just you know
they just know the meaning you know oh
you have to because you know fire file
and linear and it's a sequence there you
know that's why serialization it's it's
very natural because but it's it's
actually a misleading very idiotic
misleading concept you don't want to
think of you don't want to think of data
structure representation as like you
know one version of it is serious
realized like sequential then another
version is not you know that's that's a
[ __ ] idiotic misleading
concept okay that tense your brain what
you want to think of instead is that you
have a data structure and you have
internal representation you know bits
like for bit didas you know C or C++
whatever your language you know wam
language Mathematica or function has you
know but anyway
for digital electronic computers you
have to have them in certain form in
electronic you know in you know in in
memory bits and the bits and byes then
but but often times you want to
represent it to programmers visually.
Okay. So so data structures have
internal representation forms and uh and
also textual forms. So the proper term
to think of this serialization [ __ ] is
textual representation. Okay, that is
the proper way of thinking. Not the
serialization [ __ ] This C++
Java industrial coding monkeys. Okay,
that's their problem.
Okay, that's a digression into this
topic and I suppose that's a good one.
That's you know I have lots of friends.
I so I explain to you guys what I'm
thinking, you know, I'm telling you and
you can be you you can judge, you know,
you can judge whether I'm correct or
not.
Okay, let's read some comments. Uh so we
we started to write. So we we actually
so um let's let's actually we haven't
demonstrated this yet. So how long has
it uh you know I've been talking for 30
minutes already. Okay. So we haven't
demonstrated that there's a issue I want
to resolve about if what happens when
you have a unic code in the uh JSON
string but let me read the comments.
Uh thank you for adjusting Yuck. Yes,
thank you ACP
for alerting me of my live stream
issues.
Google is sucks. Google is evil based. I
already used Brave and it will be very
sad day when YouTube stops supporting.
Yeah. Uh when YouTube stop stops
supporting Brave. You know what YouTube
did? When Microsoft 10 years ago came up
with Microsoft Edge browser okay let's
digress. Okay. Because this you know I
don't I'm not sure that many interested.
Let me talk about you know random topic
because that usually is colorful and
fun.
So you see you got this Microsoft Edge
you know Microsoft is very evil of
course but anyway but Microsoft started
the Edge browser you know as a
replacement for their internet explorer
that's another you know history
so that is very good because they have
entire new JavaScript engines entire new
uh HTML engines you know everything is
new and it's very good competitive to
Google, Google Chrome or Firefox. These
three are the primary primary three
browser engines. You know, Google Chrome
which by now is called Blink, you know,
Blink engine. Uh you got Firefox,
uh which they have engine, they have,
you know, the engine changed, you know,
in the past 30 years. So then then you
got Microsoft then well then you got the
Opera. Okay. opera is also kind of evil
by this by this uh was it Norwegian or
you know these [ __ ]
a a extreme Microsoft hater that's who
also created CSS okay by what's his name
you know havagan some you know something
some uh northern Europe Scandinavia some
some guy opera by by now it's kind of
dead you know nobody even know what is
opera
browser. It It's still It's still around
though. Anyway, so Microsoft Edge, you
know, they started a new brand new
browser like 10 years ago or was it 15
years ago? So extremely good
competitive. Then what Google started to
do is they they trick their websites
like YouTube like Google search you know
that because that's uh most people visit
them. They trick it so that so that if
you are using Microsoft Edge browser
it'll be slow or you got some problems
the formatting doesn't work you know
they trick it secretly
and then like Microsoft you know you
know there's like very competitive you
know there are websites that compare you
know YouTube speed between browsers uh
JavaScript speed you know so Microsoft
Edge is number one but all of a sudden
now it's no longer true because the
YouTube [ __ ] you know they they trick
their code to tremendous degree you know
like they you know like for example
let's say uh what Cortana what the [ __ ]
Cotana
you know suppose I you know what uh wait
I got a Windows keys on
okay so suppose suppose this this line I
can trick it you know I can like use
JavaScript to join you know you know
like um well let me show you you know
you can
so for example let's say let's add a
span there you know like like that you
know you can see the difference but they
are you know like these two looks the
same but actually the code becomes
different so that's what Google is doing
you know to YouTube code so it [ __ ] up
you Microsoft
then Microsoft tried to fix it you know
by by by a reverse engineer you know
they try to find out what YouTube is
doing so they they try to fix it then
YouTube start to do another thing you
know they they change again so this kept
going for a while so that is how evil
the Google Chrome is you know every time
they do that they pretend oh oh I'm
sorry oh by mistake who you know we
didn't Oh,
but the repeats year after year,
you know, so that's uh how scum they
became. People don't know. So, you know,
search search.info
Google crimes.
Okay. So there's a index of of what
Google has done
um you know in in the past uh 15 years
or so since I started to write this. So
you can see uh so if we search for
Edge uh Microsoft there it is Google
tricks YouTube to make Microsoft browser
slower. Okay. 2018
the big giant chapter of history. Okay.
So, but let me post the link here
uh Google crimes. Okay. And uh back to
browser. Copy the link. Paste it there.
Linkify joining those two
uh AI and cut it all here. Paste. Okay.
Showing browser. So, we got a record of
what we talked about.
So back to Google. So Google, so how do
I know this detail? Because they are
Microsoft employees, you know, they know
because you are coding, you know, you
are, you know, you think, you know, you
you work hard to get your browser to
become the best fastest. Then the next
day it doesn't work anymore. Then you
look into, oh, Google is doing that. You
know, imagine how much, you know, hatred
when that happens because Google is
doing something nasty.
You know, you work your ass, you know,
to create the greatest, you know, great
engine para JavaScript, you know, or
that HTML engine, then Google is like
doing something nasty
and nobody knows. Of course, you tell
people like, "Oh, is there a proof?" You
know, like like you know, all these deep
state things on Twitter, you know,
1,000, you know, influencers and bots, 1
million.
So, but on hacker news, you know, some
you'll see this kind of insider info,
you know, they they'll tell you and of
course they got proofs, you know, you
because this this is not something you
can hide, you know. So this is one of
the incident of the what the Google [ __ ]
become the extreme scum is doing and
there's lots of others lots other so so
what happened so so it's very
interesting this incident so m so
Microsoft
decided they're going to they they're
going to um they're going to stop using
their own engine uh their own uh edge
edge browser engine I forgot you Look,
look up Wikipedia, you'll find out. So,
they did they stopped, you know, they
they they um what's the word? They um
abandoned
the entire fantastic browser engine.
Then they just adopted Google Chrome's
engine, you know, because Google
supposedly opensource very uh that's
another story. Okay. the origin of the
Chrome browser,
you know, it was from it was from um
okay, it's been a while. uh uh what's
the engine of Google Chromes engine it
was from a open open source one okay I
forgot which one
you know open source by the Linux people
then they then then you know after 20
years there's too many changes so uh
similar is for Apple I believe they
adopted Apple's uh Safari so Apple
Safari be about 20 years ago they
started the Safari browser by Steve Jobs
they they they they uh borrowed the
open-source engine from
the Linux um from the Linux um
uh what's the what's the what's the
Linux desktop you know KDE
I think you know if I remember correctly
I have blogged somewhere
long ago you know 20 years ago or 20 20
years ago so Safaris started you know
Apple started browser Safari based on
the open-source engine from the Linux KD
uh one I I I forgot the name exactly I
think. So anyway, Apple then after se
you know so after several years they
became uh split apart because you know
corporations their code usually not
going to be compatible with open-source
goals. Then I think then Google Chrome
started their browser. I believe
originally is borrowed from uh Safari's
code. Okay, you can look up all these
are in Wikipedia. Okay, so
Safari browser. Okay, let me let's find
out. Okay, Safari browser. Uh what is
this? Change not saved. Cancel. Are you
still here? Yes, I'm still here. Where
are you?
Your chat will be deleted after 5
minutes. Okay. Why
stupid? I want to save this. I don't
want delete. Okay.
Uh,
okay. Hold on. What is the origin of the
programming jargon serialized actually?
So, let's just copy that. Okay.
Now I have a record screenshot.
Screenshot is great for record keeping.
It doesn't prove
much but it's uh kind of you know
essential anyway. So let's go let's go
uh let's copy again.
So anyway now let's go to the Wikipedia.
Let's see Safari. Uh, this is annoying.
Safari browser. Okay. Safari browser.
Then you got history, background,
history. Okay. Uh, blah blah blah. Uh,
uh, Cyberdog. Yeah, I I I've used all
the browsers including Cyberdog.
You know this. So, this is 1990 1997
and IE for the Mac and so on. Background
conception Safari one WebKit. That's
right. WebKit from uh KHTML.
KHTML is a project from the KDE desktop.
One of the two actually the first one
the first original desktop for Linux.
Okay. Then the Richard Stoman gan
created Gnome as the and they are
anti-KD because the you know
technicalities of the open source
license you know these open-source scums
open source people and free software
people they are also scums you know in
corporations they fight for money but
the open source richman because they
cannot fight for money because he you
know he based on his principle on
morality but they fight for power and
fame which is can which is um a form of
money. Okay. So, so Richard Stman
created you know he and this is long
history and they they eventually they
broke apart they they hate each other
the Gnome Foundation and the Richard
Stman you know they hate each other long
story lots of complicated things so the
the open source KDE created you know KD
is the first elite Linux desktop okay
which is the and then then the uh free
software foundation sponsored or partly
sponsored or kind of together they
there's a Gnome uh was created you know
so Gnome and KD are enemies to each
other in the beginning so this is 1999
also
uh so so you so KHTML is from KDE that
is where Safari got their engine in the
beginning 19 so so this is 2003 okay so
now let's see Google Chrome okay Chrome
So safer. So um
so Google Chrome can so Google Chrome.
So let's open Google Chrome. I forgot.
So let's check where is the engine came
from. History of Google. Uh Google
Chrome.
So they began in 2006. Okay. So where is
it?
public release. Okay. Something
something something something
uh development. Okay. Something
something something.
So comments
Olivivera. Oh hi Oliver. So Olivivera
knows the story. Khtml. That's correct.
Apple forkbit. Yes. To become WebKit.
Yes. And uh so what is the but what is
the origin of Google Chrome?
Yeah. So there's also a version on
Google Chromium. Yeah, I mean yes
Chromium. Uh I should I should probably
switch to that. So what but what is the
origin of uh Chrome engine? I forgot. I
believe it's WebKit, right?
So let's you know I can find out of
course if I read it carefully but but
let's search for web kit.
Oh yeah. So exactly. So it was
originally
stolen from Safar's engine you know
Google Chrome we going to make a
browser. So back in 2004 2008 Google is
still pretty good company. You know they
are one of the greatest actual moral
opensource corporation today. They are
the one of the most evil in fact if not
the most pro it should be the most the
most evil scum deep state lying through
their teeth and and so powerful you know
they are more powerful like in they are
more powerful than USA kind of actually
you know lying through their teeth
especially what happens what's happening
in the past two years I shall not talk
about that you know so deep state you
know so extreme extremely bad. So, so
Google Chrome
began by taking over, you know, taking
Safari's code.
Okay. So, anyway, so then Microsoft
started their Edge browser, you know,
had which is their uh very good, you
know, then Google [ __ ] with it, you
know, by changing YouTube. Then
Microsoft eventually okay
let's just be practical you know Google
is going to do that forever of course so
let's just you know we are just going to
use Google Chrome engine you know so the
same engine you can't [ __ ] it
meanwhile the Microsoft [ __ ] the
Microsoft scum
you know so Microsoft Edge is a victim
of Google but but of of course Microsoft
is not good boys, you know, they they
do, you know, they do whatever things
they can [ __ ] you as a user, you know,
they every time you click on something,
you know, they they start Microsoft Edge
and I delete it. So, you know, you can
delete the application, you know, let me
show you. Uh I was actually I was
enthusiastic using it for I used it for
six months but eventually it's just too
you know they just too much problem so I
delete it okay so you go to applications
okay apps so you can you can find
Microsoft Edge here
Microsoft Edge okay I delete it then it
came back match magically. Okay.
And after a year or two, it is not
impossible to delete it. Impossible. You
know, it don't it won't you know, you
see un uninstall button is uh
is grayed out. The [ __ ] scum. So all
these are you know this scum scums and
versus scum in USA in America. We became
it wasn't so bad this this bad but it
became very bad in the past 10 or 20
years especially the past 10 it became
very bad. It's like these rich people,
these rich mega elites, you know, scum.
They all playing games and you zoomers,
you know, you zoomers know nothingness.
Every day you are just
your brain is already washed clean by
them since you were born. You know, you
go to, you know, your phone, you go to
the website, you know, like, "Oh, Kasan,
Kasan, why don't you have how come your
website doesn't have HTTPS? It's not
secure. You need to do that [ __ ]
idiots.
Today's Zuma generation because they
they they you know like including HTTPS,
Google like force you to do that. It
became very bad gradually and today you
know they automatically prevent people
from visiting your site unless you you
go to one of their centralized control
of the certificate. You know that's what
they want to do. They want centralized
control of the certificate.
But you'll just say oh but you know HTML
is invented to be you know free for all
for everyone. No censorship. So I don't
I can I don't have to use HTTPS because
my website doesn't ask for credit card.
But they're going to do it anyway. So
now so they they going to say no. Okay.
They're going to auto upgrade whatever
website you use to the HTTP version,
HTTPS version. And if your website
doesn't have that, sure, your website is
basically banned.
So they in this way they magically
banned like millions. You know, you can
ask I asked it before. How many website
doesn't have HTTPS? Like millions and
millions. Magically banned. those who
doesn't register now it's like no if you
want to publish information you have to
register with their so-called free oh
free you know let let's encrypt how
sounds so nice let's encrypt and you
know it's free
these [ __ ]
okay I think I talked for one hour I
think um the Jason uh so we were writing
the you know we were writing in the JSON
uh tutorial. I'm just going to write it
offline. Okay.
Okay. My alarm clock is going off.
iPad.
Okay, that's it. Do you guys enjoyed the
show?
Uh, now this show is sponsored by you.
Go to kxi.info like right here. Click
kasali.info and go to all the way to the
bottom and I ask you to donate.
Now the standard
proclamation is that if you working a
job, you should pay $100. Okay? Why not,
you know, pay me once a year or
something, $100
uh if you have a job. Otherwise, you
know, you can pay me uh $9, $6,
whatever. Uh so I can get a burger,
hamburger, the American white man's
food.
Thank you very much. Okay, you got
Patreon, Amazon gift card, PayPal.
Okay, let's read the comments and I
think that's it for today. Let's see.
Tape drive uh suggests use instead
serialize. Yeah, so text textual output
text output, you know, just output text
or export text. Okay, that's what I
recommend, not serialize.
you know the the the thinking you want
is that data structure has many
representations. So typically in a
programming language you have internal
representation of data structure
uh usually called objects you know or
blob.
Uh but you can but even blobs can have
many different representations in memory
in in in in the memory cache you know or
on disk you know but uh on the you know
you know b you know binary
representation even binary
representation there are many for
example you can have native comp
compiled eagbis or you can have bite
compiled emac similarly for java you
know bite compiled or whatever so the
that so the what you want to know about
the JSON so-called serialization the the
proper concept is representation of the
data structure okay data structure is a
concept in computer science
and in computer engineering
which is the practice of computer
science that's called computer
engineering that's what we are doing
okay so computer engineering we have
data structure you know data structure
you know a practical thing hash table or
called map or dictionary or array vector
depending on the language you know so
they have representations as a binary
blob you even have different
representations or you have you know
textual uh representation so the proper
way so the thing to remember is
representation
okay and this serialization just means
textual representation
okay or another in other way so Another
way of representation textual
representation I mean even textual
representation have different formats.
So JSON is one of the format of textual
representation such that it is kind of
universal for every different languages
like we agreed by happen stance. You
know we every language agreed to
recognize this particular specific
textual format
of data structure called JSON. Okay. But
however each language also have their
own textual representation for list, for
array, for hash, table or map you know
and they are different. Python's
represent textual representation of a
list or array is different from list
representation of list or array.
Similarly for Java and so on. Okay. So
representation
that's what that's the that's the
concept you want to understand not the
serial serialization. [ __ ] [ __ ] the C
[ __ ] the objectoriented oriented
programming idiots. [ __ ] They
create damage to the computing industry.
Yes. ACP says uh is it appropriate to
call it a textual representation exactly
if the serialization function output
nonprintable characters?
Uh yes of yes of course because even in
a file system I mean even in even in
files right now we have nonprintable
characters like like right now this
character describe character
called the function describe character
and you can see that character my cous
is CJ control J which is called point
uni you know ask as code point10 and
also unicode co.10 10 or in uh
octoisimal representation or in
hexadisimal textual representation and
what is this CJ uh which has the name of
old name old unic code name for that
character is called line feed
and the asky name for that character is
called also line feed okay so this this
what is this line feed that's invisible
character that is the end of line you
see that's that's there And you can show
it by um
uh white space mod. Okay, I just changed
the key. So let me ink softly keys. Uh
wait. So what is the key?
Okay. Uh backspace. Yeah. Okay.
Backspace and space. Space. Okay. So
backspace and space. So now you can see
you made that invisible character
visible that's uh you know that's called
line feed character which is a control
character which normally it's you know
you cannot see it and similarly is a tab
so let's insert a tab control Q tab you
see now tab is represented by a triangle
because of my configuration so that
character is a tab so how do I
called describe character. So you can
see this is called 0.9 which is another
invisible character. So close that. But
if you don't show white space control
and space space how do I know you don't
know it's invisible you know it's
invisible and unicode has like tens of
it.
Uh so
so so
what what if the serialization function
output nonprintable that's acceptable
you know I mean every text file got
invisible characters okay and sometimes
you know depending on what's the purpose
sometimes this tab is significant for
example in goland in go language let's
let's show example go uh
So here is a go language code I talked
about many times find and find replace
okay go language code you can open it in
the browser you can get the code and run
it this is like grab okay so this this
you know they got invisible characters
there you know even the representation
of source code require okay notice
require not optional not oh I prefer
space I'll just Use space. No.
Well, actually space actually works as
well. But anyway, paste it and turn on.
Why space? So, you can see it's uh it's
tabs. If you change it to space, if you
change all these tab to space, let's say
uh replace tab by space. Okay. But when
you call go format, go change it back to
tabs again. Okay. So in go language they
they want you know this tab invisible
character has special meaning
anyway and also for make file I believe
the Unix idiots make file they require
tabs.
Have you heard of the new Ladybird
browser? Oh yeah I heard of it. and that
they are under massive attack. I believe
so I believe Ladybird browser is the
idea that you know all these deep state
their browser is creating you know is
not good we don't want this deep state
complicated browser you know why Google
Chrome you know like the open source
idiots they will say oh just use uh
chromium you know because open source it
removed open source it removed Google's
code the [ __ ] idiots these zoomer
open source fanatical [ __ ]
Okay, their brain has been washed.
That's precisely what Google wants you
to do to do. You know, they want you to
create this faction of people. You know,
first of all, you need to spend 10 years
in computer engineering to understand
what is, you know, HTTP. And then so
they create this tiny faction of people
like you guys, like us. Okay.
To to so this little group of people,
they think, oh, we are the freedom
fighters, you know, we we are anti the
deep state. So oh in this situation you
need to use this browser. In that
situation you need to you know config
your DNS server. Okay this is this this
way we will win this tiny fraction of
people like one in 10,000 one in million
in the population. So they create they
create they brainwashed and created you
guys. Okay. And you guys are happy, you
know, like we gonna do, you know, you're
gonna use Linux. So now you have to use
Linux. Go this and and configure that
in, you know, and you'll be good. No,
you know, no privacy uh no privacy um
intrusion and stuff.
So they create this little tiny f
fraction of pe people in population to
make you feel good. You think you are a
freedom fighter but actually you are
doing nothing.
You are just tdling your ass
[ __ ] And my followers are this
type you know because I'm a nerd. My
followers will you just fight with me
like Mo, you know they will fight with
me every day. You are wrong. You are
just wrong.
So, so the whole society got censored
and censored and censored. They don't
you know most people most people are not
coders but this this this these little
[ __ ] these open source fanatics
they are helping Google to to to create
this situation. you please, you know,
you should upgrade to HTTPS and what
whatnot. They don't see this evil, you
know, like like when we talked about how
Google is doing all these nasty things,
you know, uh you know, quite a quite a
lot, you know, Google Google, you know,
Google Jimny
AI technology, you know, please draw a
pope. Oh, yeah, sure. There you go.
There's a image of pope you know please
draw me a white knight you know the
medieval European white knight oh yeah
sure let me show it you know
this this
you know so so that's one of the uh
situation you know there's lots of
others and in some cases the APM scam
that's a big one they got sued
uh you know
okay that's it for today.
Now, donate to me. Okay, that's what I'm
asking.
Uh, okay, that's it.
Bye.