Hello guys. Hello girls. Welcome to
another episode of Ex Talk Show. We are
going to do mathematics geometry.
Uh so I'm going to talk about what is
geometric inversion. So let me show you.
So these are geometric inversion.
Uh and we are going to code wam
language. We are going to recreate this
image. Uh so geometric in inversion is
beautiful. It's uh fantastic. Okay, all
these graphics you can see. Can you see
me? Voice check, video check. So, if you
are watching offline, play at 1.5 speed
because I talk slowly and composed
and I ramble. And if you are watching
live, say hi. Love to see your comments.
Okay, so these are geometric inversion.
Fantastic subject. Okay, let's start
coding. So let me so what so um yeah so
let's begin. So we are doing wuam
language you can download it for free
wam language the most advanced highle
programming language ever uh just search
for.info info download it language
tutorial in depth.
Ching Hank again. Thank you, Hank. Happy
666. That's today's execute 666
uh the white man's thing. 666 number of
the beast
uh episode. So uh wam language. Yeah,
you can download it the full tutorial
here. And uh if you are Emacs users, I'm
going to code Wuam language in Emacs. So
you can get this package. It's also
free. Kasaw Wuam mod. Kasawu mode. You
know, since I started to do live stream,
I learned mode is major mode. It's
pronounced mode, not mod.
Um I've been pronouncing it mod for like
20 years. And I'm using softly keys for
Emacs users. Okay. the most efficient
key binding. So you don't have to press
control or meta.
Okay. Circle inversion. So what is do
graphics demo? Okay. So let's do a
graphics demo. Let's see. Okay. So so we
we're just going to code. Okay. It's
about maybe 40 minutes. Um okay. So go
to this page. Open it. Showing browser.
That's a page. There's a wam language
notebook there. This is like 20 30 years
old. So let's open it. Let's see what we
get.
So I have written a package to do
inversion. So here is the package and
continue with updated style. So you can
see this is like 30 years old. Okay. Uh
and what okay so but we going to just do
this graphics. So I wrote this package
but the code to do this circle inversion
is actually uh not too large. So it's
going to be like 10 lines maximum. So we
can extract it. Okay. Okay. So what we
going to do? We going to regenerate this
graphics. Um
then I need to look through this code.
This 30 years code. God, this is too
old. Um okay, that's probably not the
best place to look. So I have written a
package. Let's see. Um,
GitHub
um,
Git Directory
inversion.
I don't have inversion. Damn, where's
the code?
Um,
let's see. Wra language plain tiling
inversion. Did I not?
Okay, I'm kind of um
I am V E.
Okay, there's no inversion. Where where
did it go?
Hang says, does that mean Python is the
second most advanced high level
language?
Python is not is not even the second
most advanced. So Wuam is the most
advanced most high level by a magnitude.
The second
the second best is like a magnitude
behind Wuam language. Okay. So the
second what would be the second uh
I wouldn't I mean Python well Python is
a lousy language very extremely lousy.
However, it's got this thing going for
it because it's got this huge amount of
math linear algebra libraries and AI
neural network libraries because of
Google because Google is using Python
and since like 15 years ago they ch out
Python libraries you know big data and
so on. So Python
first of all it's one of the worst
programming language. However, it's got
this huge now, you know, by now it's
got, you know, huge amount of library.
It became hugely popular. So, yeah, it's
usable.
But if you want a better programming
language for doing scientific
programming like mathematics,
statistics, neuros neural networks,
artificial intelligence,
uh Julia,
F or camel, they are much better. Okay,
much better than Python and much faster
than Python too but they don't have the
you know they don't have this huge
amount of library as Python you know so
anyway that's the thing okay so I mean
so you know in practice you always have
to like um you know that's just reality
okay so anyway so
okay so I want to get the uh I want to
do this code and uh looks like I don't
have the code. Okay, hold on. So, hold
on a second. Okay, so hold on a second.
Let me um
let me see if I can find the code. Okay,
um
display capture. Okay, let me turn off
dis display capture for a moment and let
me just search for my code.
Okay, I'm keep doing. Let me try to find
the code. So, um,
GitHub.
Okay, desktop. Uh, wine packages. Oh, I
don't have it now. Okay. So let me get
back the uh video my screen so you can
see. So I'm at I'm at desktop the
desktop folder. So I have this inversion
circle um
code.
Okay, I'm not doing so well because
because for the past five minutes it's
been boring because one thing about live
stream is that you want to keep doing
interesting things. you don't want to
spend time looking for file and so on.
So anyway, here's the inversion uh
package from 1996.
Okay. So what um okay the package is
very short. Okay. Make a backup. So
anyway, so you're going to learn some uh
mathematics and also learn some wam
language coding. Okay, that's what I'm
going to do. So this package export the
function invert circle. Okay, it's only
one uh function. Okay. So inverse circle
blah blah blah. Okay. So let me explain
what is inversion. So inversion is very
simple. Okay. So let's go there. Okay.
So you can see all you can see other
images of inversion. So you begin with a
rectangular grid. So inversion is a
transformation of points in a plane. So
given a plane and given a point.
So inversion is a function. So given a
point then you you apply the inversion
function then that point will be
somewhere else. Okay. So if you begin
with a grid you know grid is like lots
of points then you invert each point you
apply the function to the grid then you
then to the grid points then you get
this. Okay that's an inversion.
So uh and you can look up. So anyway, so
that's some of the pictures of inverting
a grid. Okay. Um, and another way to
think of geometric inversion. By the
way, this is called geometric inversion.
So the idea is very similar to 1 /x.
In fact, it is exactly the same thing.
So it's just 1 /x. Okay. Uh, and uh, so
that's another way to think of it. And
uh another way to think of it is if you
know complex numbers then the inversion
is basically the function 1 overx where
x is a complex number and if you plot it
it looks like that. Okay it looks like
that. In fact it looks like like smooth
smooth circles
you know in this image you are seeing
these uh edges.
That's because we are inverting the grid
points the intersection of the grid. But
however we we are not doing to each line
point each point in the line. If you do
them smoothly to every point in the line
in the grid of the grid then you're
going to what you get is like a bunch of
circles. So similar to this one okay
even this one is not smooth but I I have
a smooth one uh version. somewhere here.
Okay. So there are some other examples.
This is the example of if you begin with
a bunch of lines, vertical lines and you
apply inversion, you get this you get
these nested circles. Okay? And if you
begin with the a bunch of circles on a
line, the blue circles and you if you
apply inversion, you got these red
circles. Okay? So inversion is
fascinating this function because
circles become circles or lines lines
become lines or circles. So circle and
lines remain the same ba basically
and there's also angle conform it's a
conformal map so lots of properties.
Okay. Uh anyway so so here is yeah so if
you begin with a grid like that rainbow
colored grid then you apply the
inversion function you get like that.
Okay so let's magnify. So all these are
these images are generated 30 years ago.
So you you can see kind of like jacked
edge. Okay. So that's inversion. But
let's show uh so in inversion is
beautiful by the way. So all this this
is also inversion. We did a live stream
of this like uh two years ago 2023
February and uh this is also inversion.
We did this in 2023 February live we
created this image. So this this image
is uh inversion also working works in 3D
three dimension. So if you begin with a
cage a grid cage like that you apply
inversion it looks like that okay so
it's like fascinating beautiful okay
so that's geometric inversion okay so
and also uh you can create decorative
patterns based on inversion we also did
this one uh 2023 some sometimes around
there 2023 February
uh you know this this decorative pattern
is based on inversion. So it's a tiles.
So if you have a home you can build your
own uh decorative patterns in your
garden using this kind of uh technique
scheme.
Okay. So that's about a lot about
inversion. So yeah. So but let me
explain exactly what it is mathematics
mathematically. Okay. So for that so
hold on a second. So copy that um go to
talk show go to today's talk show show
in browser that's today and let's paste
the link here. So we show that's
inversion. Okay. So let's open that and
we want to show the definition. Okay.
The exact definition. So,
so here is the definition. Okay. So,
given a plane
and suppose O is origin. So, O is X = to
0, Y = to zero, you know, called origin.
Then given any point P in a plane could
be anywhere. Okay. So, let's say it's
here P. Then the inversion of that point
P is a point Q such that it lies on a
line from O P. So if you draw from the
center of the circle to the line to the
point P, you got a ray, right? A line.
So the inversion of the point P is
somewhere on the line such that
such that the new point the distance
from OP
times the distance from OQ is equals to
one. Okay suppose the radius of the
circle is one. So let me repeat maybe
it's um confusing. So inversion
you start with a circle uh you know you
you you um
let's see uh let me just read it okay
geometric inversion is a transformation
let P be a given point
let C be a circle centered on O origin
and radius R assume the radius is one
okay so the inverse of P with respect to
the circle C is a point Q on the line OP
such that distance OP * distance
distance OQ equals to R squared. Okay.
So if R the radius of the circle is one
then R 2 is just one. So basically it's
a you know one distance times another
distance equals to one. Okay. So you can
think of A * B equals to 1. So what is
B? B is one over A. So you can you can
see it's a just diversion you know one
over A. So that's an inversion. So so
but how does it can we visualize it?
Yes. Via this uh great application
called G algebra. G Algebra I recommend
if you it's on my website. If you search
for plane curves GGbraasi.info
you can see lots of these interactive
applications. Okay. Hey, if you ask here
say hi. Okay, love to see your comments
any questions you have. So, G algebra.
So, let's go back to inversion.
Uh, so that so you can see can we
magnify? Uh, let's see. Can we mag okay
so given a point P
and the Q shows the inversion. So if P
so it's always on the same line. Can you
see? So if P is further away outside of
the circle then Q is close to the
center. If P is closer to the circle
then Q is also closer to the circle.
Okay. Now if P goes to inside of the
circle Q goes to the outside. You see P
and Q are kind of symmetric. You see? So
this is a very interesting function
because when you apply this inversion to
to any picture or any point you know any
any like set of points in the plane what
you get is like all the points outside
of the circle
becomes gets into the inside of the
circle and any points inside the circle
they become outside of the circle. Okay.
So it's kind of like a mirror but it's
like swapped things outside to the
inside and inside to the outside. Okay,
that's the geometric inversion. So you
can think of that. It's like you know if
you have a piece of paper
you punch a hole in the middle. Can you
see? Um you know a piece of paper you
punch a hole in the middle and you grab
it. you know you grab it the hole and
you swap it inside out. Okay, that's in
that's kind of the you can think of that
inversion is like that. Okay, that is
why you see a rectangle I mean a grid it
becomes like that
um you know like you swap inside out
okay like a mirror but you swap inside
out around the circle
and mirror is actually you can think of
mirror as a special case of inversion I
mean mirror like reflection okay
reflection
why because when the circle's radius
become infinite that you know the circum
the the circle basically become a line.
Okay. So it becomes just reflection. So
the special case is that when the
circle's radius is infinite then this
inversion just becomes reflection you
know just like flip flip.
Okay that's the interesting part.
Uh and that's the mathematics of
inversion. Okay. So again you can also
think of uh it as the complex number 1
over Z where z is a complex number okay
it's exactly the same well except they
flipped it upside down as well anyway um
so you you can look into okay and of
course there's Wikipedia articles you
can look up for geometric inversion
Wikipedia will give you some um you know
explan explanation
okay so We covered the math
definition of inversion and their
geometric
how it looks like in geometry and uh
inversion is actually critical because
it's just like 1 /x. So this huge amount
of properties
and you can work out in analytic
geometry you know exactly you know given
a point centered on x y
then if you apply inversion what exactly
is a new coordinate you know you can
you know it's basic uh it's basic
trigonometry and distance and
pythagorean
formula so you can find out you you can
work it out. It will be interesting if
you are a math student in high school or
college.
Okay. So you know so um we derived the
formula here. So lots of properties. So
now let's get to the code. Okay. So
today actually I want to create this
this this code. Okay. So I got the code.
Go to desktop. open in operating system
desktop
wam language packages. Okay. Then one of
them is invert circle. Okay. Invert
circle that. Okay. So, so the so yeah.
So, and here is the code and basically
there's just one function inverse
circle. Okay.
Uh
okay. So that is the code.
Okay. So now we just coding. Okay. If
you are, you know, if you don't know Wam
language, you don't want to, you know,
then you can just
uh stop watching.
Hi, I hope your day is well. Thank you,
Dosey.
Okay, so how long have I been? Let's
code for like 30 minutes. Um yeah.
Okay. So this um so okay so so let's
double so I need to uh concentrate on
working on the code now. Okay.
So inverse circle. So this package just
export this one single function. So
let's highlight it. Okay. And the
parameters for the function is
okay uh that is inverse of C1. So the
argument it takes two parameters. The
first argument the first parameter is
the uh center of the inversion circle.
Wait.
Uh, returns a circle or line graphics
primitive. Okay, let's let's clarify.
Uh,
that is the inversion of circle C1 C2
with respect to circle that. Okay. So
this the second parameter is the
inversion circle. Okay.
So anyway you got that function. So
let's see
and uh okay so then you also can do
line.
Okay the second argument can also be a
line. So if it's a line then it's just
reflection. Okay. Um
so this package only does circles
inversion. So
yeah c circle lines. So circle become
circles, slime become lines. This
package, this function just take
you know two arguments
either one can be a circle or a line and
uh it returns a circle or a line. Okay,
that's a math property of this.
Okay, so so where is the definition?
Here is the inline documentation.
Okay. So, here's the inline
documentation.
Oh, okay. So, actually there's another
function. So, this is nested inversion.
Okay. I don't want to do Okay. So,
that's more advanced. So, that's about
you know if you want to do inversion and
if if you want to repeat it that you
know that's that's when you have nested
inversion. Okay.
Uh so then here is our code. Oh my god.
This this is optimized code. You see
optimized or coordinates manipulation
shouldn't be that complicated. Okay.
Uh so what what do we have? Input
initialization
go. Okay. So
input initialization
um
okay so you got that
inverse circle so
oh actually you can do a list of circles
go so this function is more powerful
than I than I imagined
you can actually do a list of circles
like invert a circle with respect to
many circles one shot at a time.
Uh and uh what about this one uh inverse
circle? So the code is like hard to
understand uh you know so we can go to
wam language open a new one paste it and
uh you can kind of like copy it again
and paste it back so you got more
um better code. Okay, same thing here.
Paste it. Okay, then copy.
and you paste it, it's kind of more
readable.
But if we want readability, we can open
this notebook.
Uh
here I have them readable. And so let's
magnify. You can see 150. Okay.
Yeah. So here is message definition and
symbol declaration. Okay.
Okay, I need to like I need to like just
focus on generate this image, extract
the code, make it simple, generate this
image and that's it for this video.
Okay, let's focus on that
uh
body of inverse circle. Okay. So, um
this one, this two, this one,
what outer? Yeah, you kind of apply.
Okay. So, you So, here is the main code.
Yeah. So, you see all these equations.
Here's the main code.
Okay. Let's copy that.
Copy that. So that is one. Then here is
the one that works online. Okay. So you
also need that.
So
do you guys follow me? Like do you guys
see what I'm doing? So the first case
both of the parameters
in the first case
both of the parameters are circle. Okay.
So this is inverting
a circle with respect to a circle. God
with respect to this circle. Okay. Now
the second case is inverting a line with
respect to a circle. Okay.
Now it's complicate. You know this may
seem complicated. That is because
that is actually because I'm doing a lot
of optimizations.
You know because if you just go by
formula it's very simple the okay so
then this case is a circle first
argument
uh then a line second argument okay so
circle circle line circle okay circle
line this is just reflection then line
okay line reflected by another line okay
so got it
Okay. Again, these are written 30 years
ago.
Today I would do
differently uh better I suppose.
Okay, let's copy the code. Okay, one,
two, three,
four. Okay, let me you know let me do
explanation so you actually understand
for those of you
language
coders or beginners. Okay, copy it.
So, we go back to today's talk show.
Open it. Showing browser. Good. Back
here. And let's add code
language. Okay. Paste the code there.
And showing browser looks like that. And
pop the code out. So you got circle
inversion code for inverting
circle. Okay. for for geometric
inversion.
Okay. And what does this code do? Um
let's explain. Let's type them out
slowly. Okay. Inverse circle takes two
arcs.
Okay. Such as
a b. Okay.
A and B. A can be a circle
or line
circle. Both
are graphics
primitives.
Okay.
Same thing with B. B can be a circle or
line.
Uh
okay. So what does graphic primitive
mean? That means just uh you know I can
show you. So for example let's say
graphics. Okay. Then that's allows you
to draw a graphics. Let's magnify.
Okay. Then inside is just graphics
primitive. So you can say circle and
circle centered on let's say uh wait I
don't want that
uh circle centered on
uh let's see
what god okay centered on 0 0 radius
true okay then you can say axis
true. Okay. Shift enter. That just show
a circle and you can change it to you
know centered on uh 1.5
and zero. Okay. Show it. You see? So
that circle that function that thing is
uh called graphics primitive. You also
have like point line rectangle ellipse
uh things like that. Okay. it it is the
primitive to build graphics. Okay.
So what this inverse circle do is that
it takes one of these circle line
graphics primitive returns a new one
that is the inversion. Okay.
So um and we are writing the code for
it. Okay. So but just for this case
you know so so we can define it. Okay.
Clear. Uh okay. So let me just show you
some of the basic. We can clear it first
and define it. Okay, let's let's focus
on the most simple case first. Okay,
let's forget about lines and stuff.
Let's just say circle and circle. Okay,
so here's a code and this code can be
much more simplified. Okay, so but let
me show you. So here's a code. Define
it. Okay, now we can call it. Okay, so
call it. Let's see.
Uh let's call a code. So circle let's
say um
let's say C1 center one S1 and this is
the second parameter. This circle is the
inversion circle. Okay. So if you do
this like that it's going to return
symbolic result. Okay. I think
so that is the beauty of Wufam language.
If you just call that it's going to
return symbolic result. You see you can
just replace C1 C2 S and O1 O2 uh R and
you you get a number. Okay, but let's
not do that. So we don't want so but
what about the you know uh numerical
results? So let's say the first circle
is centered on one and two and radius
let's say three. So you want to invert
that circle with another with respect to
a circle centered on let's say three
let's say 1.2 and uh 3.3 and radius 10.
Okay
there you go. So it returns a circle.
You see
um approximate result because you got
approximate number there. If you want
you know so if you if your input is all
integers then you got you know symbolic
result. Okay. So here is a circle you
want to invert this this circle with
respect to that circle you get that.
Okay. Now another thing we want to do.
So usually the inversion circle is
radius one
and uh uh radius one and centered on
zero and zero then it's much simpler you
see.
So why why is the inversion circle
always centered on 0 0? I mean typically
why is that? Because
if the circle is centered somewhere
somewhere else, you can always just um
uh let's see can we go? If if the circle
is centered somewhere else, you can
always move the point, you know, like
move the circle to the center and shrink
the radius to one. Then do the
inversion. After that then you then you
scale back you know whatever radius you
want you multiply the new point expand
that by that scale by that new radius
then you move back to whatever the
point. So the so so
the radius of the circle and the
location of the circle does not really
is not critical. You see the critical
concept of inversion is just the is just
one /x you know the the swap
you know but if you create a function
for it it's convenient to to allow you
to specify where is the circle and
radius because that way saves you doing
the translation you know vector
translation and scale you know thing.
Okay, but let's just um but for now
let's do a symbolic result. Okay, so we
want the inverted circle of XY
uh of what radius R with respect to
this. Okay.
Oh god, this is still okay. This is um
you know this is a big result because
because I'm trying to do uh because my
code is actually doing some
optimization. So
yeah. So that's not so good. Okay. So um
Okay. So anyway, I need to fix the code.
Okay. So but
can we actually just quickly do this? Um
where's our where's our thing we want to
do? Uh
well to do this one this one is a bit
more complicated because you got
so so what is this one? This one is you
begin with a image like that. Okay like
that uh seven circles
laid out in a hexog.
Okay. Then you invert each circle with
respect to every other circle.
Okay. Then then you got many circles.
You you got seven more circle like uh
yeah you got seven more circles. Then
you repeat you invert every circle with
respect to every other circle. Okay. You
do that three times. You get this. Okay.
So this is nested inversion of 6 + one
circles inverted four times. Okay.
Yeah. So you begin with that then you
just repeat uh h okay so maybe that's it
for today but I was thinking you know we
actually run and get this code but
but to work out you know to to like
rewrite my code here it's going to take
a while because
you know let's so for example shift
controln to make a type set this is our
function for inversion.
Um
yeah, so all these are analytic geometry
and this is kind of a hack because
you see that line 1 10,000 that's that's
basically um
that's that's trying to emulate a line
of infinity. So 30 years ago, Wuam
language doesn't have a graphics
primitive to represent like a infinite
line
but instead you always need like
beginning point and end point. So that
is why you multiply it by 10,000 to to
like emulate a infinite line.
Um and uh and this end make it numerical
that's also kind and this test end you
know this is also a hack to make it
faster.
So yeah so if I am going to rewrite this
code to kind of like improve it it's
going to take 10 minutes. Okay.
Uh so maybe let's not do that and you
know it's going to be
it's going to be a lot coding and
explanation but can we quickly just like
do these graphics like demonstrate that
it works?
Yeah, we can um let's see let let me
just try that. Okay, so uh put it back
syntax at today's talk show. Okay, then
go back here. Go to the desktop.
Okay, go to the desktop
and open my Wam package inverse circle.
And is there a example?
Uh yeah. So I need to update this
package here. Okay, there it is. Open
it. Okay, so now here is a package.
Let's say
125. So you can see it.
Okay. And now we just load the code.
Okay. What is this? Close. Don't save.
Go back here.
We load the code. Okay. So what is this?
Uh okay. So to load the code you need to
open that.
Okay. So that well okay so
wait open it. Why is it 14? Okay. Yeah.
Okay. We got a code here and let's don't
worry about anything. Just copy it and
shift control evaluate the whole thing.
Now,
now let's go back here. Let's see blah
blah blah blah blah documentation and
illustration of the inversion.
Okay. So, you see this blue line inverts
to this red circle and this red circle
inverts to that blue line. Okay. And uh
and you can also do reflection. Okay.
But um can we run this? Okay. Let me
just try
run it. Do you want to automatically
evaluate? Um wait. What what are the the
code?
Do I want to auto evaluate? Not really.
Okay. So let's go back here. Let's let's
run this. Okay. Shift enter. Auto
evaluate. No.
Okay, it's done. Now, for example,
delete that. Shift enter. Fantastic. And
beautiful.
Delete that. Shift enter. Fantastic. So,
these are test test examples. Oh, fancy
one. So, delete that.
Shift enter. Fantastic. So, these blue
lines inverts to these red circles. The
green circle is the inversion circle.
Okay, they swap.
Uh, and this one. Okay, delete that.
Shift enter. Fantastic. This this
horizontal sequence
of circles lying on a line inverts to
this sequence of red circles. You can
see beautiful. You see when the point is
outside of the inversion circle such as
this they goes to inside the circle you
see like that. So but the parts that's
inside the circle they become outside
like these two you see.
So now you got more examples. Let's do
it. Okay. Okay. So but now let's you
know so this now now here we start to
get nested inversion. So you begin with
two circles. Invert the right one with
respect to the left. Invert the left one
with respect to the right. Then you got
these two smaller ones. Okay.
Then you invert each other with respect
to all the other circles. Then repeat.
Then you got this. Okay. So graphics
gallery. Now let's do Okay. Yeah. So now
we are generating more interesting
things. Okay. Uh okay.
So there's a lot code I need to like go
through in order to like can we show
this? Yeah, that works. And can we do
this? Yes. You see? Delete that.
Shift enter. Fantastic. Then we're going
to invert that. Okay. So
wait, where's the Anyway, so there's
that one. Shift enter. There it is. Um,
delete
shift enter. There it is.
Yeah. I Okay. So then here you create a
grid. Then you create Yeah. So that's an
inversion. Okay. So actually pretty good
code. Pretty good. Uh, shift enter. Then
delete that.
Shift enter. Pretty good. Now where
where is the oh oh this one is beautiful
okay uh let's not evaluate where where
is the uh nested oh this one beautiful
can we just run it somewhere okay so
okay so why is there so many code shift
enter
then shift enter fantastic
okay I think that's it
this this this this beautiful. So you
see now so now I'm going to replace this
old image by this new one. That's it for
today. Thank you guys for watching. Did
you guys enjoy it? Did you guys learn
any interesting mathematics? Do you find
this fascinating?
What is your keyboard? You must be new
here because I repeat that in every
video almost for the past four years. So
this one, so let me answer it. Why not?
Okay, so this one is glove 80.
Fantastic. This one is ultimate hacking
keyboard too. Okay, I have a YouTube
video review
on YouTube. In fact, I have more than
one for each one of them. Okay,
so uh hello. That's it for today. Okay,
you guys donate to me. Okay. Hypo cray
touch some grass bra. Do you get
profile or something? Are you making
game engine something? Hey bra. Okay.
Bunch of zoomers.
Thank you Hank again. Uh yeah. So for
those watching offline I guess uh donate
to me. Okay. If you like my stuff go to,
you know.info.
You got like 6,000 information pages of
information on programming. study.info
on programming, on mathematics, on
technicality, you know, logo design in
software industry. Uh, you got like
6,000 pages of them. So, you are asking
about keyboard. There it is. Keyboard.
Okay. Glove 80, Kinesis 360, and so on.
You know the there are like over 1,000
pages on keyboard and mouse
uh on layout on all sort of you know
everything you want to know about
keyboard on programming languages wam
language emacs emac this unic code
technicalities what is unic code and all
complete list of emojis and technical
symbols uh such as astrology and uh
and uh
alchemy. Okay. A chemical symbols. This
is Asian symbols. Okay. So, you got you
know um then you got a list of all the
arrows you ever wanted to know in
Unicode. There are hundreds of them. So,
Unicode documentation and you can search
and then go back. Uh oh, yeah. And
there's technical like what is character
set? What is encoding? What is UTFA? the
best simple explanation you can
understand. I hope for you programmers.
So that's unic code. Then uh then
JavaScript visualiz you know like 6,000
pages
at at the bottom is mathematics. So
today we are we were like kind of doing
part of these special plane curves
uh and uh three-dimensional geometry
interactive geometry
symmetry groups. So in the past four
days or uh in the past week so there are
two more three or more videos on wam
language um coding geometry. Okay,
beautiful. Check them out on YouTube.
If you like them, so pay me. Okay? $10,
$100. Okay? If you work in a job, if you
are coder, $100.
Thank you.
Bye, guys. Bye.
Close.
So I'm going to work out you know I'm
gonna you know update my website you
know update all these 30 years old
graphics with a new and uh then publish
my package on GitHub probably
update the code. It still works. I mean
I mean it all works. I think I worked on
it a bit last year but you know so all
works.
Uh bye guys.
Oh, I forgot to turn it back to video. I
mean to my screen. Okay.info.
Okay.
Then you can see all my uh Yeah. So I
were talking about ergonomic keyboards,
glove at Kinesis 360 and then you got
then you got uni code stuff.