Hello, good morning beautiful. Welcome
to another episode of Kasan Talk Show.
We are going to code emacisp today. And
here is my website kasardi.info.
We are going to code uh HTML to markdown
and inverse markdown to HTML. So wait, I
got a spelling error here. Markdown M A
R K D O W N. So that's what we going to
code. So this is for Emacs Lisp fans. So
if you don't know anything about Emac
Bisp, the programming language. Uh this
is probably not interesting to you. And
if you are here, say hi. EP Choker man.
And if you are watching this offline,
play at 1.5 speed because I talk slowly
and rambles over. So skip around. Okay.
So we begin coding. So this is going to
be a starting a serious session. Coding
make America great again by technology
not by talking and influencers and
lawyers and crap. You got to do tech.
Okay. So so let's begin. So markdown. So
what what what what the hell is
markdown? So I got a tutorial markdown.
Markdown is you know if you are a coder
everyone knows you can write this simple
text and uh and uh it can be uh
translated to HTML you know headings
inline code block you know things like
that. Okay. So and the other thing is um
the other thing so HTML so you are
looking at HTML right now. So HTML is
one form of markup and the markdown is
simpler. You know it by the way the name
there's a long history about all these
markups that there are tens like over
like almost 10 of them back then like
about 20 years ago. There's a mark up
war, you know, everyone is creating
their own mark up version, but
eventually markdown won't. And markdown
the name is just a mockery of the
markup, you know, like normally this is
called markup, you know, because you
mark up you, you know. So, for example,
one pound sign at the beginning of a
line indicate that this is a header.
Two pound sign mean indicates that's a
second header you know second level
header
and you can also have bold and uh you
know like if you want a list then you
put asterisks
in front of the line so that indicates
it's a list so you can translate to HTML
or other format so it shows us a list so
anyway so that's markup you know that's
in general general called markup
language such such as HTML stand for um
hypertext
markup
language HTML which came from SGML which
stand for uh SGML
okay SGML
HTML came from X uh HTML came from SGML
okay so what is SGML not stocks
Okay, it it is HTML stand for standard
generalized markup language. Then HTML
means hypertext markup language.
Then we have XML means extensible markup
language. So they are all basically in
the same family. Now remember they are
all called markup. That's what it means
in English. You mark it up. But then
comes the maverick, you know. Oh,
everyone is named Markup. I'm just gonna
name my name my my my my my stuff Mark
down. So this guy this guy is cocky.
This guy is a kind of a Okay.
So
So uh
what is Markdown? So let's you know
let's explore Rambo a little bit about
the history of the markdown. you know,
he he's a kind of assho guy.
John Gubber in 2004, you know, that's
like 20 years ago in the early days of,
you know, internet era. So,
so they, you know, he created his
version called and he called it
markdown. Then about 10 years ago there
is a uh effort
um by the Stack Overflow guy creator the
guy who created Stack Overflow to um to
make it standardized. So the syntax is
well specified well defined you know to
make it rigorous so everyone the web you
know whatever programming languages can
implement it and in a uniform you know
in agreement
so the stack overflow guy
they uh okay it's the same link okay
standardization Jeff Atwood and John
McFaran
Faren, you know, they they they created
John Atwood created Stack Overflow. Uh I
don't know who is the John McFarland
guy. Anyway, he Jeff Atwood wanted to
standardize to have a specification for
the markdown. So they talked to the John
Gubber guy who created Markdown and John
Guaba refused kind of refused
refused to standardize it
you know so that that was a big um
controversy you know lasting over a year
so now so they he refused to participate
because he don't want you know I don't
know exactly what is his reason seems to
be He don't he you know he he think that
it should not be standardized because it
should you know it's simple something
like that. So then eventually they
created you know so they created their
own version kind of the so-called
standardized version called common mark
okay by by the Jeff Atwood and so on. So
anyway there's you know lots of fights
and war ugly in technology sector in
programming sector too.
Okay, we digressed a lot. We uh we we
want to code this command. Okay, so
let's begin coding the EMAC list. Hello,
Huang. I'm a Emac hater. I don't think
you are. Hello Hank. I like markdown.
Yeah, markdown has become standardized.
So, you know, it becomes became
universal.
You know, I learned about two years ago
that the entirety of Microsoft
documentation today like then.net is
huge. I suppose 10,000 or 100,000 pages
you know. Net is the programming
platform from Microsoft.
So the entiretnet documentation
including C language including F
language including uh whatever Microsoft
technology PowerShell they are all the
documentation are all written in
markdown okay you know in this simple
markdown
and uh not just net but the entirety of
Microsoft documentations for example the
envir environment variables or Windows
you know Windows operating system like
the entire Microsoft documentation they
they use markdown okay then it convert
to HTML so you know like I can show an
example
PowerShell okay so let's go to
PowerShell PowerShell documentation okay
learn my that's the right link
PowerShell okay you need to turn on
JavaScript in order to have you know a
bunch of links and panels and stuff
Okay. So you can see here's a PowerShell
documentation standard shell on Windows
and let's let's go like let's go to one
of the you know actual um page Windows
PowerShell docs uh guide PowerShell
support cycle I don't care uh
docs overview editorial
yeah it's easier if I just start a uh
look up a PowerShell function so
PowerShell kasar powershell mode and
type the press became get children and
actually let's let's let's do this um
abbreviation so you know so you can look
up get children press a key that's
powershell mode allows you to code uh
powershell in eacisp you can see
so we go to uh powershell get children
okay so here is the documentation
So you can see get children blah blah
blah blah and if you go so how do I know
it's marked down so you go all the way
down there's a GitHub link you know so
it's all open source today the entire
net from Microsoft now it's open open
source so now you got open source so
wait
uh that's another doc uh essay history
of the HTML script tag ugly history okay
I fight among the the factions among the
programmers. On one hand you have the
Unix
idiots. They insist you must follow
standard for like 20 years. Not so much
today. Today the Zuma generation they
don't know a thing.
They don't they don't chant about
following standard standard um standards
anymore, you know. But for past 20 years
like in the 1990s and 2000s they chant
the Unix usually from the Unix fanatics
the Unix fanatics they tell you you must
follow standard HTML valid HTML W3C and
all that and you you got this ugly
history you know you can see you know
that anyway that's another story let's
go back to the markdown okay so markdown
you look at the Microsoft uh PowerShell
documentations supporting cycle. I don't
care what the is that. So, here is
a PowerShell documentation and you go to
um
provide product feedback. No. Open a
documentation issue. No. Our contributor
guide. Oh, collaborate. Okay. There. So,
how do I go to the um
uh collaborate on? Okay. Let's click on
our contributor guide.
Oh god, this is can I just go to the
GitHub
and you know GitHub got bought by
Microsoft? Of course I you know let
let's just search for
pwsh
github you know go to the homepage of
the powershell source code. So there it
is.
Uh then you need to okay docs. So you
click on the docs.
Then you need to turn on JavaScript.
Since about three years ago, GitHub now
requires JavaScript
uh and so they can know where you live
and stuff. So uh so here is the
documentation and uh how powershell get
whatever community uh okay where's the
documentation for for one of the
documentation but anyway you can see MD
okay maintain let's uh go where is it
tools docker tools
uh xml build comment so where is the uh
I want uh just a page of the
documentation for get children for
example.
Uh
okay, click on powershell
and click on
docs. Okay, so building command. So is
this the documentation or do they have a
different page for documentation? But
anyway, my point is see it's all MD. So
you can see here MD is the file name
extension for markdown MD markdown.
Okay. So so that's what I'm saying you
know the all the source code. So if you
for example they already formatted. So
copy row copy wait. So you know you
click row. So you are looking at
markdown. Okay. So you can see it's just
plain text.
then you format it to HTML like that.
Okay. So that's what markdown and
history of markdown.
So what I'm saying is that the entire
you know 100,000 pages of all Microsoft
documentation is now using markdown. I
learned I learned this about three years
ago. Uh quite interesting. Okay. So let
open that. So let's put it back and
showing browser. Showing browser. And we
don't need that. um today's talk show.
Okay. So anyway, let's let's start to
write
let's start to write um B Magnus. Hello
J Dugger.
Jay Duggar. I know you as J Bugger not
typing on H uh Ultimate Hacking Keyboard
80 yet. No, not yet. So I did a review
two days ago on my YouTube. Uh not yet.
I haven't, you know, I haven't got the
time to set it up because these days,
you know, I'm kind of, you know, so I
need to change my keyboard and setup.
Then it's a whole thing about setting up
keys, you know, a new you need to adapt
uh to a new keyboard. So, take a takes a
while. Okay. In about a week.
Uh as well as info pages, man pages
needs to be rewritten in markdown.
That's a good recommendate
recommendation as well as Emacs info
pages. That's right, Hank. I'm surprised
you know you know these things. Um,
hello Emily. One of the things I like
about Markdown specifically is that it's
designed to be readable in its raw form.
So, it doesn't need to always be
converted. Yes. Okay. So, let let's
let's go get to focused on writing a
markdown. Okay. I already have like
there's already packages you can you
know people have written it but but I
wanted to write my own because because I
you know I can do it why not why not
it's actually easier so I have full
control and I can uh enhance it so I
don't need to like otherwise
you know check dependencies like likely
they they will load the the the the f
and dash and whatever bunch of
dependencies like bloated and then you
you know it's easier for me to just
write my own. So actually I already have
it kind of written. So something for
example let's say print three let's say
this is code. So I press a button they
become this code then press a button
they become paragraph. So now show in
browser. So you can see this print
three. So that's so the command I call.
So let's try again. Okay. print three
then let's say I'm writing a tutorial so
press a key you could do that okay so
let's magnify magnify magnify okay so
you got this corner bracket bracket okay
search for corner so so you can see the
name of that character is left corner
bracket this and here is a French quote
called um angle quote. Okay. So, let's
search for the name. So, single left
pointing angle quotation mark used by
the French.
So, you got the text like that. Make a
paragraph
showing browser. So, you see that there
back to Emacs. Now, press the key. Now,
look at the pink window. It'll show the
command I call. So, press press. It
becomes that. And the command is s HTML
bracket to mark up
bracket to markup. Okay, that's kind of
it should be named bracket to uh HTML.
Anyway, now showing browser. So you can
see print and variable green that
indicates it's a variable. Okay. So I so
so let's um go I kind of wasted so much
time talking. I need, you know, this is
something I need to do. So, so let's um
Okay, let's look at the source code for
that command. So, we can base the source
code. Wait, not not there. So, wait,
what is the key? Uh describe key
and uh
that's the command. Okay, that's my
personal command. HTML bracket to
markup. Okay, so go to the source code.
That's here is the code. Uh, let's copy
it. New buffer. Paste it. And let's save
it.
Save XX today's date. Then the command
name. There it is. Then X
UTF abbreviation to turn it into lexical
binding. uh and uh
and UTF encoding. Okay, so now we got a
code. So this is just 112 lines. So what
did um Okay, we got a code. So So what
is it? We um so save it. Go back to talk
show page.
Okay, to do close that. Um,
okay. We got now, now on my screen, the
font is huge. Uh, you need to do that
when you do YouTube, but to me it's
like, oh my god, huge.
Um, so, so there's two things about
markdown. Okay, so you need to write
kasan htm
html
markdown to html. Okay, that's one
command. Then you need to do one for uh
HTML to markdown. Okay, let's bracket
them
make it into HTML code.
So showing browser actually I already
have one of them done markdown to HTML.
So let's look up that command I actually
have written. So copy the command name
describe function paste a name enter. So
here is my source code in SA HTML mode.
Okay. So let's copy it and the new
buffer. Paste it. Get the name. Save it.
XX to a state the function name EL and X
UTF abbreviation. Okay. So that's the
code HTML markdown to HTML. Okay. So now
70 lines of code. Okay. So let's let's
kind of um improve this code for the
basics like it's pretty simple. It's
like find and replace. Okay, find and
replace. So first thing you want to do,
so here's the documentation. Replace
markdown text to HTML in current block.
Block means
like a block of code separated by empty
lines. Okay, by block or selection if
you want to, you know, select it. So for
example, let's try it here. Okay. So
here are a bunch of markdowns. So copy
the file name. Now I mean the program
name. Do I have a do I have a shortcut?
Uh
okay. You need to be in HTML mode. So
let's go back to talk show.
Uh
describe function markdown to HTML. Do I
have a Oh, I don't even have a keyboard
shortcut. I need to add it. Somehow I
missed it or because this command is not
complete.
April. Okay. So, okay. So, now let's get
back to the code. So, um close that. So,
this this is bracket to markup. Okay.
Now, this so let's try it first. Let's
see.
Okay. So, let's move the cursor here.
Call it HTML markdown to HTML. Do it.
Did it work? Not exactly. It Well, it
did, but it kind of incorrect. So, undo.
Copy the block. Paste it here. Call the
command. Do it. So, we can compare over
here. Original and this. So let's see.
Uh yeah, I started to write this. No,
now I remember. I started to write this
in a live stream in April this year, but
it's not finished. So bold bold is
correct. Italics correct. Heading is
incorrect. So this um
Yeah. So okay, you need to fix it. So
this is just fine. Replace. Okay, you
can look back. Look back at my previous
live stream if you want to see, you
know, that all this uh mundane code how
it works because I I I I done hundreds
live stream coding this uh selection and
you know Emacs basics, Emac Bisp.
Okay, so let's see uh heading. So
something is wrong with the heading for
sure. Okay, so let's just search for H1.
So go to the point beginning of buffer
while regular expression search for
word. If the beginning is a pound sign
followed by space
then anything not a a line.
Okay. Then you change it to
that.
Okay. So why is that? So this this this
block of code
should work.
So split the window go to the previous
occurrence. So why did this become
H1? Now this is two pound sign. So
apparently it uh
okay so you need Oh yeah. So you need
that's that's why it's wrong. You need
uh you need you know you need to add
back the line ending. Okay. So let's so
let's add back that. Okay. So that there
that there and H3 there and H4 there.
And let's just add H56.
Yeah. This is inefficient because you
can com you can can you combine them
kind of let's just do the inefficient
way. Okay.
For live stream. So uh so what do undo?
So add a pound sign. So that's one two
three four five. So this going to be
five
five and six. So HTML support H1 to H6.
So you need one more. So we just going
to do this inefficiently. Wait.
Uh okay. So,
okay. So, predine the code. Now,
432. Okay. Evaluate it. Now, go back to
the top. Cut. Paste and paste and remove
that. Okay. Now, let's do it here. Call
the command. Do it. Fantastic. And
beautiful. Now missing heading four.
So why is the H4 not working? Because
H3.
Uh why why is it not working?
Did anyone of you spot the error? So um
wait
oh because when you when you call it
without selection it's missing the line
ending. Okay so you need to make another
fix. So one way to do it is you know you
copy that paste it. Now you make a
selection. So you select here to
including the line ending. then you call
it do it. So you see because that that
command is checking the our command is
checking the line ending. So that should
be fixed.
Uh we we don't want you know we should
it should be either um
line ending or end of line. So what is
the regular expression in EMAC list for
end of line character? I believe it's
dollar sign. Okay.
Yes, I think so. So,
okay. Let's let's try to do it. Find and
replace that.
Okay. Wait. Find replace that by
Okay. Not not in. So trying to replace
that by
dollar sign.
Okay.
Do it.
Oh, wait. So if you if you do it there,
then you don't want the Okay. So Okay.
So let's do it. Wait.
Um, wait.
What?
Yes. No. Yes. No. Yes. No. Yes. No.
Okay. Now
do it again, but this time you need to
um
you need to just remove that. Okay. Do
it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it. Do it.
Let's try. I don't know if it works.
eval the buffer. I'll go to the top. Am
I good? Am I good? I'll I'll read the
comments in a bit. Okay. So, copy that.
Paste. Call the command. Do it.
Fantastic.
My intu intuition is correct
because I've been coding eag for like by
now 20 years. Starting in 2016.
No, 2006. Yeah. So okay so this so we
got it correct. So we got the headings
um and uh currently not support H5
H6 that's incorrect.
So and what about
then you got low line for bold and
itallic and list. Okay so you also need
to do list.
Okay let's do the list one.
Okay, this is inefficient code, but
let's just live with it. Okay, so so
what you want to do with list is that
you know the the list um
in markdown is such that so let's show
that. Okay, so where is it? Um,
okay. Show. So, where is my markdown
tutorial?
Copy it. Back to Emacs.
Uh,
paste it here. Showing browser. So,
markdown tutorial.
And, uh, when you want to list, you got
these forms.
And you also got older at least. Okay.
It's a bit tedious. It's not actually
it's not trivial, you know,
you know the meaning meaning that it'll
take me like, you know, 10 hours, you
know, over
several days to actually get the whole
thing correct. Um,
and when you have nested list, that's
more complex
to turn this into HTML, you know. Uh, so
well,
so okay. Well, so, so anyway, there's a
error here.
Wait, block quote precede each line with
greater than. Okay, there's I got an
error here. you know amperand encoding
error that's likely to happen when you
have like HTML within HTML or regular
expression within regular expression or
string quote and escape within string
quote and escape like when you want to
pass a string into shell from emac to
shell then you got the escape hell you
know it's um uh I did a video about last
month on the string
escape
syntax design issue. So watch that one
because I think that's one of my great
uh work for the past 10 years. You know,
a new string syntax for that fix fixed
all the programming language problems of
the escape.
It's called rock string. Okay. A month
ago. So anyway, now what we going to do?
So if you want to process the list um
you know close that reopen so if you
want to process so wait let's we need to
fix the markdown
okay so what so let's yeah so this is
error so yeah this this is this this
came from let me let me tell you guys
the story this quotation mark convention
came from the Unix idiots. Okay, this
this inflexible
hardcoded
markdown
markup notation for quotation when you
want to quote something extremely
nasty, you know, like you you you are
prone to create lots of errors,
especially when you have nested quote.
Then the line gets too long, then you
got you got complete
This is a damage to computing industry
from the Unix and C Okay, the
Unix They are
because they you know they they insist
they are the best you know this is the
best way. So th so this contaminated the
entire programming industry
uh in emails in you know it became a
standard convention to like you put in
the beginning of line you you put a
greater than sign to indicate it's a
quotation you know that it's a huge
damage
instead what you should do you know
instead for example uh let me show you
what should happen okay something
something like that. Okay. Something
like that. You you you want you you
don't want hardcoded. You don't want to
do it with each one each line. You want
some kind of markup that uh for example
you can have a random uh
character here. Okay. So you can so so
this way you can mark up the this this
text
you know to mean quotation or whatever
and you can nest them there's no problem
in processing it but if you do it this
way one line by line and you know
because line line oriented way of
thinking that's from the Unix
okay everything must be a line that
creates lots of problems for the past 30
years so that is why that's part of the
reason you see
well that's actually not related you
know this this is another thing amp%
escape in HTML anyway so let's fix this
code okay so now put it back and now
syntax code so back to the browser and
refresh did I fix it yes
okay so this is a quote block quote Uh
okay. So let's see. Let's see the
comments.
H4 is not working because Oka here. Uh
were you uh were you away at a very
expensive European vacation? Not really.
Um
are you guys still watching? Is it
interesting? Nice shirt. Yeah, this is a
Mario Brothers mushroom something.
You are welcome Hank and the line or
file. Okay. So no comments.
So are you guys still you're watching me
coding list or or uh yeah. So let's
let's let's let's get on to the list.
Okay. So what do you want to do?
So how do you process a list?
Okay. So at least you know each line
begins with a asterisk.
Um and uh
okay. So
you can Okay. So you you so how you know
so first of all so some it would be
something like um
something like let's let's type it up.
Okay. Text.
So,
dog cat
uh dog cat bat. Okay. And let's add
let's add asterisk in front. So, this is
supposed to be a list. So, what you need
to do is you check
a block of code beginning by a empty
line
and uh end by a empty line. Then for
each line if they start with an
asterisk.
Okay, let's do this part. Okay, when
this part is done, that's it for this
video. Okay, but let's do this this
part. Um,
okay. So let's search for um
yeah okay so how do you do it that's the
question uh close that
uh HTML
bracket to markup now close that okay
yeah let's go back here so go to char
point beginning while let's just search
for um let's just search for
asterisk. Okay. Then all the way
uh then you know so what you could do is
just change them to that you know this
is kind of simple but then you need the
URL.
So once you do that so let's you know we
can do is that
rock
Okay. A block of code. Delete that. Move
it in.
Pify.
Okay. So, so this will go to the
beginning of buffer. Then process this.
So once we did that we could
search for you know one way to do it is
then then you search for
a new line then
a new line then followed by L I
this this is not robust. Okay. Something
a new line followed by Wait, that
doesn't work. Um, two new line. You
know, this is a hack. This This is not
going to be good.
So, if you see that, then you do UL,
change it to ul then
li. Okay.
Then that's that adds the URL. But this
is not
the right way to do this will create
problems I think. But let's just try it.
Okay. So then also at the end
so when you have a li followed by two
empty lines
then you replace it by
that.
Okay. So, actually uh you need that.
Okay. Need that. Okay. This is not a
good way to go, but let's just try it.
Okay. Evaluate the buffer. Done.
Eval buffer. You just call the command
eval buffer. Now go to the top. Now,
let's try some list. Okay. We we we
already have a list here. Okay. cut,
paste, paste, and call the command. Do
it.
It's It's missing It's missing the uh
end of line. So, let's let's make a
selection and try it. Do it.
Wait.
Why is it not working?
Oh. Oh, because you need uh markdown.
Okay. So, you need select. You need to
select the empty lines before and after.
Call the command. Do it. No. Uh maybe
you need more lines.
Do it. Do it. No. Okay. Problem with our
code somewhere.
So
Oh, you you forgot to go to buffering.
Go to buffering. Go to buffering. Go to
the beginning. Okay. Evaluate the
buffer. Go back here. Call the command.
Do it. No. Okay. Now, but you you select
extra lines. Call the command. Do it.
No. Okay. Uh maybe you need to select
more lines. Okay. Like these two. Call
the command. Do it. Okay. You got the
beginning URL, but you are missing the
end URL. So, what is the problem?
Oh. Oh. Oh, obviously uh this is that
you're missing a slash.
Okay. And uh then
yeah. So yeah, evaluate the buffer. Go
back here. Delete that. Delete that.
Copy it.
Okay. Now select call the command. Do
it. Fantastic. and beautiful.
I think let's call it a day for this
video.
Uh,
is it good?
How long have I been going?
An hour. Okay, I think that's that's
good. So, put this back.
Syntax color. That doesn't work. Okay.
So, delete that. Syntax collect showing
browser.
So, let's show the code, shall we? Let's
show the code. So, here's a code. Let's
um remove that. Remove that. Uh there's
a lot to do though. So,
so list kind of
works, but I'm pretty sure it's it's
going to you're going to run into
problems because this is not the right
way to do it. Okay, but let's let's just
copy it.
Okay. So,
copy it and go to
uh today's talk show and
add emac this year. Paste the code
syntax code show in browser.
So, here's today's code. You know this
um
ugly but
okay. So, I think that's it for today.
Thank you guys for watching.
It's good. Fantastic. Okay. So, yeah.
Um, so there's a lot more to do. You
know, markdown is pretty simple, but
even, you know, simple text processing.
So, you covered headings.
Uh, inline code is pretty easy to cover,
but except Oh, Jesus. Two back ticks.
So, you got this special case of two
back ticks.
That adds a lot complication
and I think you also can allow three
back ticks. So it's lots of code lots of
coding to deal with that case.
Then code block. Okay, code block is
another complexity because it uses the
same markup as inline code but now you
have you know extra
line end character. Okay.
So then you need to do uh code block and
then alternative this is annoying part
about markdown because you have so many
different varieties of marking down. So
now you use a prefix,
you know, indentation.
Very annoying. Then you got italic and
bold.
Asterisks for italics and two asterisks
for bold. Okay, that should be simple.
Then you can also do low line. Okay,
it's get complicated.
Oh god, thinking about this, I think,
you know, I'm no more discouraged.
And this quotation block is similar to
list. Okay. Um,
okay. You know, so then all the list is
more complicated because you need to
keep, you know, the counter, you need to
keep the state of the counter for each
line.
Uh but you never know a simple way is
just ignore the order you know like if
says two two you know you just check the
beginning of line is a number dot space
a number then dot then space then you
consider it it um
does that work? No actually because you
you need to remove the numbers to put
them into L for order line. So
yeah. So it's this is kind of problem.
Uh
link. Okay. So I think actually what I
should do maybe in next video is
actually use existing code. Let's let's
look at existing code. Okay. Because to
write this is going to take like 10
hours. So this packages let's see. Yeah.
Let's continue. Let's see if there's
already something. Um, what we want is
markup to HTML. Okay, so
markdown list matching lines. Let's see
what are what is 1,000 of them. Denote
markdown eel to markdown. What?
Convert commentary of e files to
markdown. Okay. My flight check. Uh,
ham mode. Markdown change log.
Okay. Markdown. Solar. What the are
all these?
Markdown format. Format. Markdown. Using
markdown format. Jesus.
Markdown. Read me. Markdown formatted.
Read me for your emac list.
Uh god markdown ox hugo whatever ox poly
poly markdown holy mode for markdown
mode
vmd
mode fast github flavored markdown
preview
what the
major mode for markdown formatted text
but but that doesn't convert to html So,
so what is the preview mode?
Markdown preview. Do you guys know what
is the package to convert?
So, you got here we got HTML to
markdown.
Okay, that's that one that I need.
Um,
okay. I'm I need this anyway. So let's
just install start to HTML to markdown.
Okay. So open that. Let's see who wrote
it.
Require CL lib. Okay. That's in EMAC.
Okay. Bruce Corner.
Oh god. Bruce Corner. Is that a guy?
Oh, okay. So this is good. Mala Baba.
Malaba guy. I kind of know the guy.
Uh so I can trust this package.
So HTML to markdown.
So let's install it. Okay. So install.
Yes.
So let's let's try it. Okay. In HTML to
markdown. Okay. So uh describe function.
Okay. So
convert content of current buffer from
HTML to markdown. Okay. Let's try it. So
open the source code. Here is a source
code. And how many lines total? 500.
Okay. Go to the top. Starting in 2015.
Oh, interesting. Look at the package
version uh
format he's using.
Okay. Written by author Malaba
and uh why is Bruce Corner? Okay, that's
his real name. Something like that.
And uh
okay, so HTML. So let's just try it.
Okay, copy the command name. Close,
close, close, close.
So this is S talk show today.
So we got lots of code this span and
span. Okay. So copy it, make a backup.
Go to the directory and uh let's just
rename it xx
html. Okay, rename it. Open it. Now, um
let's let's
Okay, now save it. Now call the command
HTML to markdown. Let's see what I do.
So there's a string version, right?
What?
So there's a string version
and there is a buffer version.
Fantastic. So let's just do this one.
Okay. HTML tomark. Do it.
Wrong type argument character PT.
Okay,
it's okay. So, let's look at uh look up
the documentation.
So,
so there are several versions we
noticed. So, let's look at what are the
versions. Okay. So, let's put the names
here.
Um,
God. So,
wait. So,
HTML to markdown dash string and this
buffer. Okay. So,
So actually describe function just go to
the package and uh define list matching
lines
and uh
buff uh so let's let me just put it
there. Okay then what are the other then
there's two string version.
Okay. So,
okay.
And uh let's try describe function the
buffer version.
Okay. Except erases the current buffer
and insert the result. Okay, that's not
good.
Convert content of current buffer from
HTML to markdown.
Okay. So is it interactive? Yes,
autoloaded interactive. So I should be
able to call it. But why can why am I
getting an error? Interactive views.
Okay. Okay. So the list views.
Okay. I think there's some design
issues.
There's uh yeah I think there's a design
issues with this function because
when you say markdown string that means
you take a string
then but this this buffer string is so
that buffer you know this is very bad
documentation you know you don't do it
like that so buffer string is a function
it returns the buffer text into a string
okay then you pass this result into this
function. What does that mean? So I mean
if you have a function that takes a
string then you just say string here.
You don't say buffer string.
Uh
you know so this is this documentation
is bad.
So HTML markdown. So what but why is it
not working? So I got a HTML page call
HTML to markdown do it. It says wrong
argument type. Now let's turn on enable
debug on arrow. Let's call it again. Do
it. So you got error
HTML find close while passing
Neo chart to string T.
Okay, bad impression. You know, this
this is why I say when you use other
people's packages,
you um
what what what
Okay, this what is this? This is uh talk
show. So, it's just a bunch of lists.
Uh
validate it's valid HTML. So I don't
understand why it's
um let's delete the main show in
browser. So now it's almost empty.
So now HTML to markdown error.
What the is the problem? Wrong
wrong type argument character P
HTML fine. What? What? What? What?
A bad impression.
Okay. So, it it seems it can only pass
limited
Is that right? Only limited number of
tags. Okay. So, it's remove the link,
remove the meta,
you know. So, you know, so do it.
Well, save it first. Do it.
Wrong type argument. Okay, let's remove
the doc type. Uh, save it and call it.
Now, it works.
So very bad package. It's you
know
you see when you have a doc type this is
a valid and required for HTML 5 when you
have that it it says error you know
let's try it again do it
wrong type argument okay now delete that
doc type it again now it works okay now
you go here so
HTML ML markdown output.
Wait, it's supposed to convert HTML to
markdown, right?
HTML, but that's not this is not
markdown. What the is going on?
Very bad impression.
Oh god. So that you know so I would be
better if I you know I I have a version
for example
for example this document select all
then call um
s html to text okay it's not marked down
by two text but it does failed
why is why am I fail What?
So it works. Call it do it. It works.
But uh but on the whole thing it do it.
It failed because God. Okay. My pro my
program also failed. Um
is it because of that? No. Uh
okay. We got issues anyway.
Okay. So, anyone still watching? So, so
what is the uh
so HTML to text that works? Okay. Now,
yeah, that works. Oh, I know why. So you
need, you know, I know why. So undo,
undo, undo, undo, undo, undo, undo,
undo, undo, undo, undo. So we got back
here. So if you call So wait, wait, save
first. Okay, save. If you call HTML to
markdown, it chokes.
Okay, now if you Now, if you call now,
you need to put the cursor at the end.
If you call SA HTML to text, it does the
job beautifully. You see, it's trivial
to make this into markdown. Okay, so to
turn HTML to markdown,
is it easier than the inverse? I think
they are pretty much the same, but
anyway, I have the command. Okay, so
undo.
So if you do call markdown, it fails. It
chokes. You need to remove the dot type
then you call it then it works but I
don't understand why is the output
like this you know like you know all it
did is convert this to list that's the
only thing it converted so the package
sucks
you know you're supposed to deal with
HTML you know not not not just like
five tags
describe function
go to the source code
it only deal with these tags so this bad
okay
god okay
okay bye