good morning everyone welcome to another
episode of saw talk show today it's 2020
June 16th Tuesday 8 o clock in the
afternoon San Francisco time and today
we are going to do Emacs
and Emacs demo and Emacs Lisp coding so
let's go to San talk show page and show
today's content so this is basically
what how we are going to do today Emacs
and he emag list coding and I'm going to
show you some demonstration of me
walking on my website HTML so first of
all let me show you this fantastic local
ok this is the background picture today
this is Lisp sticker actually someone
sent me this sticker someone from Duncan
home he's from Scandinavia I forgot
which country exactly but I think his
Scandinavia so he few years ago 2007
2007 or something
I think it's later than that he sent me
you know I made this list logo and he
sent me a sticker so he actually went
out and printed the stickers so that is
today's background and we are going to
do so let's start to code he Magnus
let's see what we are going to code okay
we are going to begin and if you have
any questions I love comments ok if you
type comments in in the chat box any
questions and comments
good evening Cortez my good humans
indeed so what are we going to do let me
show you this etymology of tablet you
see I have a collection of etymology you
can see etymology a pet of history you
know when you look at Adam ology
etymology meaning meaning the history of
a world the origin of the world so I
have compiled several etymologies and
these are words usually used in blogging
technique you know when you write about
programming for example compilation we
talked about compilation actually the
word came from pillage you know pillage
robbing stuff that that is the
compilation that's the etymology of
compilation so when you are compiled a
program a C program was the prosperous
that was language you are actually doing
pillaging that's the original meaning
and you have etymology of tablet you
know so I mean I have a Microsoft
Surface tablet and
every time I write about you know I'm
using a tablet I find a word annoying
you know like why would you call it
tablet you know it's you know I thought
it came from table so why not say slab
you know digital slab computer slab I
thought that word is more fitting
turns out the word tablet is actually
the oldest and the most fitting so
anyway I have a collection of etymology
stuff you know tablet analyze screenshot
you know where does the word screenshot
came from you know it's it's kind of not
intuitive you know screen that is
intuitive but shot like what the hell
like what well I understand it's a
camera you know you take a shot but why
is it a shot
so you have several at Amala g's and
underscore you know we program us we use
the underscore all the time so we want
to know why would you call it underscore
why don't you just go it low line
because that's what it is so it turns
out this you know there's interesting
histories so etymology is a plate of
history that is my my sound byte very
interesting you via etymology you have a
glimpse of history indeed because when
you for example when you look at the
word underscore you can see it's began
from counting from making some marks on
a wooden stick you know each score is
means 20 it's counting
so underscore then execute this word I
hate the most you know when you talk
about programming you want to say
execute this program or execute when the
function executes that's very annoying
word why would you want to use the word
execute and its associated with you know
you know I don't want to say that was
because Google censorship you know
Google is going to say my video is not
good for advertisements so but anyway
you have the word execute a very
annoying word so I wanted to find out
why you know the etymology of execute so
so that's about etymology so what what
have all these have to do with Emacs
well let me show you okay so I'm going
to work on okay etymology so you see
when I click a word let's see
etymology of tablet you know so this
this page is actually from this source
there's a great guy who created
etymology online this website as a hobby
you know he's a hobbyist so it and you
know he made this etymology from various
sources this website existed for more
than more than 10 years so I've been
using this suicide so I link to this
website but what I want is okay let me
start to do a demo let me show you show
me and I'm going to show you what am I
going to do okay hello attach - I
remember you before a long time ago in
hello Chhagan low -
so - is a JavaScript library for
functional programming do you actually
use it you know with JavaScript es2015
you don't need it anymore
sticker looks awesome
yeah you want one and I could send you
one but I don't have a car so it takes
some trouble to mail it
he sent me like a few like three or five
so I don't know we can talk offline
hello
Altaria meet miss key so anyway let's go
back to Emacs okay so what are we going
to do so if you look at my a technology
page I have this link you click on that
he will go to the link okay wait wait I
mean let me try it again so go to
etymology then click the link you see
but what I want you just go to that page
and you can go back and return to
previous page I want to open the link in
a new page but let me show you the
command name okay let's say we want to
know the the etymology of the word
command okay that would be interesting
because command is a common you know
it's frequently used in programming by
the way on the right hand side this pink
window you will see all the commands I
call in Emacs so if you find something
you don't know what I'm doing you can
just look up the commands these shows
the commands in the key I used for that
command I'm using soft like keys and
black keyboard layout okay
so type command we want to know the
etymology of command okay so I can type
core command
some item ology okay
The Fool common name is Awards awards
word etymology link of I enter you see
it becomes it becomes that and add a
paragraph showing browser there it is
you see here but what I want to do so so
that is the command that is the saw
etymology link of I know it's not
okay when you call MX command who does
not show in this window but let's show
that so here is a command ok saw words
etymology link of I and so that's that's
the command and you can go to the source
code go to the source code so here is
the source code
okay so here is the source Awards
etymology lingo file and you can find
this command at okay this command is in
my Emacs in it hunk it hook yeah if you
want you to use this command you can
find it on my github Emacs sorry max in
it just search for that so we have the
command that makes a link to the
etymology on a second let me show you
okay so so so that now there are two
things I want to modify this command so
that he will add when I quickly will go
to open a new page how do you do that
let me show you so now we are going to
talk about HTML okay I don't have a I
don't have a tutorial for that but let
me show you how it is done so here is
the original and let's magnify okay here
is original what we want is we want to
add target equals to target equals two
underscore blank so copy that we want to
add it to here you see target underscore
he goes through blank that's how you do
link that opens to in another window so
showing browser so you can see we have
two of these etymology of commands so
the second one we are open in a new
window you see close that you see you
see that's how it works so it's
fantastic so that's what we want to do
so there are two things I want to do one
is to modify my Emacs command so that
you will order automatically at that the
other thing is I want to I want to
change all my existing links on my
website to you know so that they have a
blank they add a blank let me show you
how to do that
okay to two jobs okay am i doing good
any questions so far let's see okay
comment so they keep the comments going
and let's see if I'm still doing talking
anything broken
okay good let me know okay so let's do
it
so which one to do first let's let's
modify the command first
okay so let's modify the command so the
command is Star Wars etymology link of I
okay describe function copy it describe
function and let me show the window okay
describe function okay then go to the
source code open magnify okay and we are
going to modify this code first of all
make a backup copy in case we made a
mistake then let's go previous buffer
what we want is add this target equals
to blank thing okay go back to the next
to the code
so here the code we want to add it
somewhere here okay so here actually
it's very easy
just had it there and backslash in Emacs
string you need to backslash to escape
double quotes so there it is we just
added that target equals to bank now
modify the version date
so today's you know so today's 2020 July
June 16th so the new version date make
the current word into an etymology
reference link that's right now evaluate
this code ok evaluate this code it's
done now save it ok actually copy the
code close it go back here make a eMac
based code template paste it here
showing browser there it is our new code
now press the button ok I'm going to
call this command which is HTML redo
syntax color buffer
actually the command should be this one
cuz I'd wait wait okay okay let's
just do this okay we do saw HTML
reducing tax cut above so showing
browser now you can see I have seen tax
coloring so this command you can you
know if you do web search you'll find
all these commands if you like to use
them so here is our command now let's
try it out okay close this list below go
close nice etymology go back showing
browser okay go back now let's try this
out okay so let's type command okay
now call the command somewhat etymology
link off' i okay it's done now you can
see there is the target equals to bank
so we are done successful now showing
browser you see this is a third one
click on that it opens a new tab
fantastic job done okay job done now
that's one task that the next thing we
want to do is to change your existing
HTML links on my website they are about
maybe 50 of them
so far so good okay any questions okay
so should should I explain how the
command works before we it's this the
the command is pretty simple
okay let me explain just a little bit
what this command do so okay so here is
this code so we define a function then
we say let okay and let there are few
variables we define few variables local
variables P 1 P 2 which is position
position 1 & 2 / 4 positions in the word
the current word you want to grab the
word in a buffer and look up for the
etymology then you want the URL for the
etymology reference website so that's a
local variables by the way I have a
dollar sign in front that is just my
personal convention you don't have to
have that it has no meaning
it's just a naming convention I use when
I use that you can see the color you
know the word the you can see all the
local variables become screen because
I'm using say Emacs Lisp sorry least mod
so he will color any words that start
with a dollar sign to be green it's just
my personal preference okay so hold on a
second
okay so so we declared several variables
then we then we say if use region that
means if there's a region highlighted
then set P 1 and P 2 and set P 1 and P 2
to be the region beginning and region
end now if there is no region
you know selection then we want to set P
1 and P 2 to be the beginning of line
and end of line
why is that because let me show you okay
so for example if you want to work look
up the word command okay let's say yeah
command so if you normally you know you
have to select it then call the command
then it knows you know what's the word
you want to look for but it's convenient
to not have to not need to you select it
you know because you can automatically
grab the word under kusa but however
sometimes you have two words let's say
let's say you know you want to look up
etymology of a phrase
why do you say word that is consisting
of towards let's say caught point okay
cool point is a common technical word
that is that means the hexadecimal of a
Unicode character so so anyway you want
to know the a Tamala G of code point in
this case it's not just one word so you
want to make a selection so in this case
you can do that okay so now you have
etymology of the phrase code point I
don't I don't think it will work because
anyway that that's that's the reason I
have this use region it's convenient
then once you have the beginning point
and end point of the word you want then
it's easy to grab the word you just say
buffer substring on properties and give
two points buffer positions then it will
return you know the word between those
two positions then once you have the
word you want delete that region
delete that region then all you have to
do is just insert the link so we say
insert then format in etymology of
something you know
then the word the URL the word URL in
word which which let me show you okay on
a second
which shows you this line okay that's
how the command works now let's do the
second task task of changing or existing
things to have to have the target equals
to blank okay so to do that let's go to
my word eve log okay that that is my
English
etymology linguistics writing related
blog which is this page from the hottie
emotions of lexicons holistic concerns
decipherment of grammar and idioms
linguistic ality literature and logic
allottee oh these are related subjects
so anytime I want to blog about
something about writing about etymology
about idioms about grandma about
literature classic literature such as
Shakespeare or linguist linguistics you
know I put in here and and why logic
while illogicality because when you
often when you talk about linguistics
there's a lot to do with logic such as
passing you know generative grammar
you know when if you're a programmer you
know what I'm talking about and and
formal languages you know the komoroske
hierarchy of syntax grammar a lot of it
has to do with logic and also form you
know formal logic actually
so it's very interesting topic so so now
I'm on my wordy blog what I want so yeah
so let's click on homology of tablet so
here is several links of etymology so
let's go there okay let's go there okay
and let me show you okay so we want to
change for every file in your directory
any link of these formats we want to
change the okay let's see what we're
gonna do
so strip of hope and a new window let me
show you so it's clear
okay so whenever we see something like
that we want to change it to
let's go to the talk show we want to
change into that okay so how are we
gonna do we're gonna use a regular
expression is that right yes okay you
ready
let's do regular expression in Emacs
okay no comment comment guys okay
regular expression so what do you do
25 minutes okay let's let's move on so
regular expression what we want we want
to yeah so let's do the regular
expression here we have let's use so we
I have a abbreviation for this regular
expression pattern this pattern means
this pattern means such anything until
you reach anything that is not a double
quote until you reach a double quote and
you want to find the minimum minimum of
it you know so this part means anything
that's not a double quote and and this
plus I means one or more then this
question mark means
for the previous pattern make it minimal
that is if you know don't go all the way
you know once you find it you know make
it minimal non greedy you know the
technical jargon is not greedy now the
regular expression is a big topic so if
you don't know regular expression I
highly recommend you learn it and I did
a talk show about regular expression so
you can search for Saudi regular
expression or Saudi regular expression e
max this OMS Emacs I have a lot articles
tutorials on that so anyway I we want
this pattern to be here okay so the
beginning is the etymology website then
whatever anything until the double quote
okay hold on second even copy that so we
want to find okay then repeat this
pattern repeat this pattern here
backslash 1 now backslash 1 refers to
the previous pattern you just captured
by your parentheses which is nice
ok so we want to find a link you know a
bracket
the URL will start with this etymology
online.com then followed by whatever
until the double quote then over here
it's the same thing over here it's the
same thing
then the backslash 1 means the previous
pattern which is this part ok that that
is a regular expression we want to use
and the
the replacement regular expression we OB
will be this one let me show you okay
one one so you can see so this is the
replacement regular expression is that
correct double check yes I'm pretty sure
so we got a regular expression but what
command we are going to call we are
going to call I have a command called
let me show you Casa find replace text
rejects okay that is a command let me
show you describe function so here is
the this is a command cause I'll find
replace text which rejects this command
we oh it's an interactive command you it
will ask you for a regular expression
and replacement stream then it will ask
you for a directory and also a pattern
for files for example Oh HTML files and
you can replace it will replace in one
shot every file in a directory very
useful
this command is part of the package so
find which is so here we have the source
code okay and you can find it on my Appa
okay Safa and yeah so let me copy that
and let me show you let's go back to
okay so here
here is the command we want to call and
it's available in that package okay
showing browser
okay so we are going to call that
command so let's do that
first of all I want to go to my worthy
blog okay my English woody blog we are
going to work on this directory so
called kind of command ah find/replace
rejects regular expression
enter and is asked you find rejects okay
the find regular expression is gonna be
this one paste it and he asked you for
replace string the replaced string is
gonna be this one
paste it enter and he asked you a
directory yes this directory let's say
what in English okay then he asked you
for a file path regular expression so I
say dot HTML that means Oh HTML file
enter do I want to change to file no
because I want to I say no because I
want to see what are the changes first
to make sure we are doing this correctly
let me ask you Fiske fixed case in such
yes Fiske fixed case in replacement yes
show context before after in output yes
make backup yes okay now it's running
fantastic now done let me show you okay
here is a result let's go let's magnify
the buffer so I mean you can see the
whole thing so you can see now you press
left arrow to go to the changes you can
see I can I can press left arrow I mean
left or right arrow to go up or down so
the pink lines means the file you can
press up/down arrow to go to the file so
that means in this file in this file
they are one change so originally it
looks like that and now the changed form
is this screen now let's double check to
see if it's correct because when you do
a regular expression find replace on
hundreds of files you don't want to make
mistakes because once you make mistake
all the files are changes changed it's
problematic it I mean it's tedious to
change them back typically you can use
get you know get to a commit make change
if you made a mistake you can revert so
that's one way to do it by anyway so
let's double check if our regular
expression is correct
so for example here we have a etymology
of the word firmament which means heaven
under heaven which is kind of a Chinese
idiom so that link becomes this link
let's double check if it's correct looks
like it is target equals to blank okay
and now let's see the next one stir ball
the etymology of the word stubble okay
looks like correct the next one the
etymology of the word cool you know it's
so cool which is a slam so anyway so the
pattern it looks good okay so we are
going to close this book actually so
there are so many changes you can see
you can see the the cruiser I mean the
window widget on the right they are
quite a lot pages how many pages are
there you know let's do least matching
lines saw slash web there you see so we
have 59 pages you know some page for
example this page has 10 changes and
this page has 20 to 22 changes so let's
open that open the page so when your
cursor is on one of these pink or green
or yellow you can just hit enter you
open the page so this is a fantastic
command package so now showing browser
wait
showing browser so this page is history
of English in ten minutes
annotated there is a YouTube by the way
so there is a YouTube on the history of
English so I watched it and I kind of
annotated it and made my notes and study
of it so you have a lot of etymology
links there it is so drag you see
etymology of drag
then etymology of ransack etymology of
die etymology of give etymology of take
give and take and die in Vikings
you know so it looks like regular
expression is good we made so many
changes now we want to repeat we want to
call this command again with the same
argument and this time we are say right
to fire okay do go ahead and right to
fire so close the output okay now here
is the new trick I'm going to tell you
okay a new trick when you want to call a
previous command you called when you
call meta X you know the you know
metallics and you want to use the exact
same arguments interactive arguments
there is a convenient command to do that
so you so you don't have to type the
arguments again remember before we typed
up a whole bunch of arguments the
regular expression the replacement
string then yes no yes no you know the
directory path we don't have to repeat
that so that command is called describe
key let me show you okay this command is
called replaced repeat complex command
okay so we are going to call that
command let me go to then go back to
course our talk show and let me let me
show you the let's type the command sort
of show
so so that is a command so so I'm going
to call that okay so because I have a
key you see my keys DDT DDT and actually
this is anyway so so then yes so I just
off arrow then here you can see can you
see at the bottom the mini buffer you
see this part okay
it's the fun it's kind of small let's
see if I can increase it now I cannot
how I can actually I can actually
increase it okay you see so I call me I
call what's the command I just called
repeat complex command then then it asks
me you know prompt we do so this so this
is actually the command in this format
you know so fine we replace text rejects
so I want to go here and say true to the
to the argument that one that argument
is about do you want to change to the
whole thing I mean right to fire okay so
I say yes enter I just press Enter
now it's done you see let's magnify now
it's done so you can arrow down you can
see all the changes now enter and you
will jump to the page and show a history
of English okay let's show another page
okay so this one show wait okay so this
actually so okay so this one is big okay
so this page this page show okay so here
so here is flower was flower the finest
part of meal that is the etymology of
flower which is the you know you use
flour to make bread and that has the
exact same pronounciation of the flower
of the plant you know the beautiful
flower smells good why because that is
ethnology the finest part of the meal
that's that's where the flower the word
flower came from so now if you click the
etymology link it will open a new link
let's try it indeed you see that's
fantastic we we did what we wanted
so that concludes that finish the job
that's that finished job so close this
output close this and go back to talk
show let's see
so that actually we finished that and
let's see if there's anything else we
want to talk about any questions
Cortez's dad can you tell me what a
solar eclipse is dad no son that's
that's good
so we talked for how long we've been
talking
I think that's it for today now we can
do some random chat we talked for 40
minutes yeah so what else is interesting
let's see
there okay so there is more okay
basically we are done but I can show you
some more examples
very similar examples let me show you
okay it's same thing so for example I
have a Chinese blog now this is
literature and linguistics about Chinese
for example about you know Chinese is
very interesting like when you study
English you have all these issues about
etymology about we talked about you know
etymology writing style accents
vocabulary lexicon literature
linguistics you know all these are very
interesting and very deep you know
depending on you can you can study this
for 10 years 20 years or your life you
know you can become if you focus on
vocabulary you can become a
lexicographer
which means someone collects words like
dictionary compilers there is the word
compile again you've become a dictionary
compiler or you can be your etymologist
you know if you saw the etymology aloud
you you really get to know history you
know so it becomes it's not just
etymology it not it's not just the words
you know you actually got into deep
about history of humanity because for
example let's say what's the a Tamala g
of meat meat you know the the meat the
pork beef you know we kill
pigs we eat their meat so what is the
item ology of meat
let's look up showing browser the
etymology of meat now you see the okay
is big so it says Middle English Middle
English food nourishment sustenance
paired with drink item of food animal
food father also meal we passed you see
you are learning history but you are
also learning vocabulary so you are
learning a word repast
very interesting word we don't see that
what use much anymore today
we passed so it's from proto-germanic
Marty something something and you get
into linguistics you get into
comparative linguistics you get into the
history of linguistics you get into you
get to learn German language then source
also old Frisian old saxon and old nose
in old high german umbrella in gothic
food middle dutch german something
something type of sausage
okay so meat came from type of sausage
and from high route mad moist wet oh now
it gets getting interesting so meat came
from somewhere meaning moist and wet
also reference to food qualities okay
Sanskrit Sanskrit Indian
oh then we got to pig you see so the
word meat originally came from pig
okay now narrower sense of okay so in
general so we can see the etymology of
meat in general just means food so when
we say so you see you saw so here is
some kind of logic coming out of this
you see when we say food you know food
is actually very abstract term for all
edibles you know we're getting into
technicalities the add up edibility of
something for food means something
that's suitable edible for human
consumption so that is a very abstract
word you know but you can imagine
primitive people they don't have these
abstractions they just say you know you
just say pig pig you eat pig you know so
that's the rangin of meat they narrow
sense narrower sense of flesh of
warm-blooded animals killed and used as
food is attested from circa 1300 earlier
this was flesh meat okay so before they
say flesh meat you know because
apparently from 12 century apparently
because the meat just means food so you
if you want to describe the
you know meat of an animal you have to
add flesh flesh meat you know so
entomology very interesting you know
then you know so when you study
etymology you are you depending how deep
you go you become a historian in fact
you can become a historian even more so
then then then with you by having a PhD
degree in history because when you study
etymology is quite general so anyway I
am talking about English
etymology but now you know in English
etymology and literature and linguistics
and writing style you know how
programmers you know the idiots
programming nerds
you know they like to talk about English
style you know they they like to talk
about writing styles when you when it
comes to writing they get excited for
example they will talk about grammar
they will start to mouth and drivel
about split infinitive is
programmer idiots you know they will
talk about spirit spirit infinities and
and in particular the UNIX people the
UNIX and Linux philosophy these idiots
it's which is good you know linguistic
so very interesting but but when you
study in linguistics once then then you
go to into Chinese Chinese the
linguistics of Chinese is entirely a
different story
and in fact it gets much more in general
okay it's very different okay but it's
in some sense it's much more deeper and
more difficult when you get into Chinese
linguistics writing styles of Chinese
the history of Chinese characters you
know look at this
oh these Chinese which are Greeks to you
most of you if you haven't studied
Chinese because Chinese is very
difficult so when you get into you know
the linguistics of Chinese the and
associated things such as Chinese
writing style Chinese grammar Chinese
function or or Japanese you know
Japanese Korean they also use Chinese
characters it's it's kind of deeper and
you know in a different way so Chinese
also have etymology the etymology of
Chinese phrases or Chinese characters
which is you know different thing from
English etymology from the English
etymology let me show your example so
let's say so you know I have a Chinese
blog which is about all the interesting
Chinese stuff okay let me show you some
interesting things okay let's see which
character we want
okay this one so this Chinese heart you
see you see this this I just copy and
pasted a Chinese character sure
now that word in Chinese is pronounced
shear and that word means a hole a hole
or some kind of a hole okay like a toe
no turn oh oh oh and it also means by
the way it also can also means vagina
okay so we actually have a passage about
which is we have a passage here from the
from the classic one of the great
classics one of the four great classics
of Chinese which is Journey to the West
that's the English title Journey to the
West one of the great classics fantastic
fan tax fantastic mug Oracle tale about
this Monkey King and you know this they
fight monsters fantastic you know it is
very interesting story anyway in these
classics they have a passage you know
this is a big you know these hundred
chapters okay and they have this passage
which is describing
seven spider how you say monsters okay
spider how you say
hmm let me try to remember the water you
know in Greek mythology you have God and
goddesses and you have hey King herring
you should wake up in normal times I
know hey Jeff chose I've never have I
seen you in my life show before we are
talking about Emacs but we digressed so
Jeff Jeff Shaw says let me let me finish
your topic about one more thing at that
time
okay so I'm saying in these Chinese
classics Journey to the West there's a
passage rather you attic passage
describing several describing seven
spider in Greek mythology what what so
you know in Greek mythology
there's a word describing female kind of
demigod okay demigod but yeah okay
demigod so Tami God and not fairies okay
what's the other word anyone
once in a while so jiff you must know
these so in Greek mythology what's
what's some more describing female
demigod I should know anyway so in
Chinese this passage is you have this
erotic passage describing these seven
kind of monsters okay female monsters
they are spider okay I mean if you play
games you know in Japan Japanese you
know lots of Japanese games you have
this foxy lady so it's you know it's a
female but you know a fox phone that
came from Chinese okay that's a classic
Chinese mythology a very common you have
this Fox Fox shaped female monster so
but here you have this spider shaped
female monsters they are said there
ourselves seven of them they are taking
a bath you know it's this is this is a
fantasy story but so you have this poem
in this classic describing how they are
taking a bath in a open river very funny
so anyway this character let's let me
show you it so I call command etymology
okay actually Chinese ok so words
Chinese link of I that's a command okay
on a second
I call it make a link so it becomes link
showing browser and page down so you can
see this a wait that's not the command I
want and do and do
okay that's that's what I want so go
back to browser showing browser reload
you can see magnifier you can see it
becomes like that so then you have
translate Wiktionary and history links
so let me click on them Wiktionary so
you can see what Google translates say
about this Chinese character so this
word means a hole and you can also click
on pronunciation you know okay and
you know and then you can go through the
wiki wiki Wiktionary on this character
Amy magnify okay then he'll give you you
know the meaning derived characters
references Chinese or ancient you know
so we are getting into the etymology of
the character so you know a thousand
years ago it's written like that and
different variations phonetic series
okay you know lots of information and
how it's pronounced in Mandarin how it's
pronounced in Cantonese and other
dialect and how its in definition okay
ho ho grave or cave or den lair exactly
then you also have you know different
phrases compounds then you have how
Japanese use the word so it you know
very lots of information about Chinese
characters
then you have this website by this guy
which is white guy he studied he is an
expert on etymology of Chinese
characters so he you know so anyway my
point is just that I have this Emacs
command where whenever I want to blog
about or if I want to know the etymology
of a Chinese character I can just type a
few keys and it gives gives me the link
very convenient so anyway so that's it
for today I'm just going to read about
what you guys are serious saying okay so
several suggestions nymph okay
nymph is the word I was looking for yeah
kind of link tie rad dyad triad actually
I don't know that word triad actually
interesting something I learned today
triad okay triad is a tree nymph oh
that's interesting Greek mythology
okay that's cool so back Mews
yeah Mews is also but you know I love
Greek mythology you have all this and
then you have succubus now I believe
succubus is not exactly Greek mythology
I think it's not the mythology but a
very interesting yeah I love these words
spider lady and then the sirens sirens
is a big chapter in Greek mythology so
anyway I think that's about it for today
about Emacs yeah so we've been talking
for 57 minutes okay anything else
anything interesting questions then we
will say goodbye we close down in two
minutes
how is house going Jeff so hey Jeff have
you is there any Emacs meet up in San
Francisco going on you know we have
kovat 19 in the past three months so I
guess not but I don't know if there's
any new so maybe there's a online
version I haven't been paying attention
lately so you see any news about that
that would be interesting so we can do
you know so Jeff runs you know if you
guys don't know Jeff Jeff runs the San
Francisco Emacs Meetup I I went to
several times
you know you just search for Emacs meet
up San Francisco you'll find it so I
actually I haven't been having out of
loop of Emacs happenings because I think
I'm getting old but I think Jeff you are
about the same age as me right oh yeah
GC GC seems fast fantastic website Jeff
says I have to learn it I mean what what
do you have to learn about it it seems
you just go there and it just works yeah
so Jeff runs you know some has Cisco
meter I went to several times and it's
fantastic you know so we have a YouTube
channel
indeed so let me just show it let's see
Emacs meet up san friend
so there it is the meetup.com website
then you have jeff has a github page
about San Francisco minute meetup then
there is also a YouTube okay uh okay I
actually I talked about it before so one
of my YouTube turned up but anyway you
if you go to youtube you can see it if
you search on YouTube
so here is 488 people yeah
yeah so the last one is February you
know then the kovat 19 hit you know Cove
igniting is such amazing and incredible
you know it it just happened and over
sudden it crippled the entire world
so anyway anything else anything
interesting glad to see you saw on your
YouTube thank you start diviner okay so
okay that's it I think that's it for
today we talked about Emacs okay thank
you guys for coming
hope to see you again next one
krishna and the gopis now what is
krishna krishna is a indian goddess
right or am i totally wrong okay yeah so
let's see mythologies of the world you
know it's all very interesting Krishna
you know so Indian you know Indian they
are the or engine of Buddhism and
Hinduism of course and so but in China
China is mostly Buddhism so China the
Buddha so much of China came from India
and in fact that is what this journey to
the West is about the entire you know
Journey to the West that West means
India back then so you know back then
you don't have we don't you know you
don't have airplanes you have cause so
it's a tremendous travel to India you
know take a year go to so we have you
know one of the classic Chinese about
you know there are monks these are a
bunch of monks they are traveling to
India why because they want to get the
engine of Buddhism scriptures which is
which is conceived you know like like
the Bible which is considered you know a
huge thing you you need to get the
original scripture so it's this is a
story about you know they go into India
Journey to the West colloquially this
story is also known as The Monkey King
it's they are very popular they are you
know in Asia in China Japan Korea they
are more popular there was popular as
Mickey Mouse in western society
they are as popular as yours you know
like you know like the foundation of
Western society sewers the the god of
all gods kind of so so you have cartoons
you have comics you have movies about
these every few years you have you know
drama and this story so teacher early I
mean by the title they are Journey to
the West you know they are actually a
bunch of monks but the story is more
like Arabic Arabian Nights where you
have a bunch of monsters I mean it's all
about monsters in gods they are fighting
how they so it's a fantastic tale let me
show you
literature in classics you know like
Arabian Nights you must have heard of
okay anyway um okay thank you guys for
coming and hope to see you again
bye guys
but he saw the copies yeah so I don't
know what his copies let's see let's
look at copies
copy agape let's see how how it's
pronounced oops
Wikipedia's the slacking of Wikipedia
they did not provide a pronunciation in
in IPA I found a flaw
so copy agape egg I suppose is a
Sanskrit word originating from the word
capella Kabbalah referring to a person
in charge of a herd of cows referring a
person in charge of a herd of cows in
Hinduism especially the name Caprica
feminine form of copy is used more
commonly to refer to the group of cow
herding girls Oh famous within version
of ISM for their unconditional devotion
to Krishna has described in something
something very interesting that's the
that's the fruit of discussion with the
different people we always learn things
thank you guys bye