Hello guys, good evening guys. Welcome
to another episode of S talk show. We
are going to do some drinking
drinking and introduction to classic
piano piano music. Okay, I'm just going
to talk random for a change. Uh my
keyboards, this is ultimate hacking
keyboard 80 UHK80 newly trackable and
this Hang
um tablet. Okay, let's switch my screen
to the ones that uh that there. Okay, so
and here. Stop that. Okay, so let's talk
random. Okay, I'm just going to talk
random. And okay, so first of all, let's
get a drink.
This uh Keto one cocktail. This is
supposed to be um Keto One cocktail.
Espresso Martini.
So,
apparently it's coffee flavored um
something
now. Coffee flavored. Uh is it vodka or
coffee liquor made with keto one vodka?
Okay. So, it's like
coffee flavored vodka.
Okay, that's good.
Hello guys. Hello. Who are you?
The fast. Hi, Kar. Do you mind if I ask
a rather elementary math question? Yes,
go ahead. Yeah. So, today we're going to
talk random. Okay. Random chat. So, you
guys can ask me anything.
Uh, elementary math questions. Cheers.
Okay. Uh, am I live? Yes. Stop that.
Okay. So, you know, I've been, you know,
I've been want I I wanted to be a
pianist when I was younger, among other
things. So, Oh, [ __ ] Uh, by the way, I
have a major problem with my website. So
my website has not been updated for a
week for some reason. You know the ring
failed. Uh I think they the the my
server my uh web provider had some
problem. So I have not been able to
update my website for about a week. So
whatever you see is like one week old.
So I'll need to fix that. Okay. So you
are looking at my music blog on
kasadi.org
But uh but you know but that's uh one
week old. So let's go to my music blog
uh bookmark Emacs the most the most
fantastic um editor Emacs the most
powerful editor. Okay. Showing browser.
So this is my current uh version of my
music kas music blog on kasali.org.
Okay. But my the website is one week
old.
So let me tell you guys this story.
Okay. Like when I was about 20, I wanted
to I you know like I want to be a
pianist among other things. I also
wanted to be a millionaire. I also
wanted to be a greatest mathematician.
Um yeah and I al also wanted to be the
greatest juggler. So I was kind of
ambitious too ambitious real unrealistic
unrealistically.
Okay. So the greatest juggler, the
greatest pianist, the greatest
mathematician and a millionaire. That
was what I wanted to be.
Uh and in general I kind of failed. Um
but anyway, so that's how things are.
Anyway, so when I was younger, so you
listen to piano music and I I just I
love p piano music, okay? Not others. Uh
so one of the thing you want to do or
you can do today or you can do it 30
years ago is that you want to know you
want to listen to all
classic music that has been ever
recorded for piano. So like listen to
them all. So you have so you have an
idea so you can have a like you can
judge which pieces you like what kind of
piano music you like. So I I was kind of
trying I try I tried to do that
somewhat. Okay. So let me show you my
list on my uh music blog. So I had some
um
you know like some some list you know I
wrote this like long ago like 20 30
years ago. So you know so
you guys may not know because today you
know you younger generation everything
is different you know you can go to
YouTube you can listen to almost every
piece almost uh you can go to you know
you got CDs you got you know actually
CDs dead you know it's not like today so
today you can go to Wikipedia and you
find all this information but 30 years
ago back in 1995 let's say That's when I
started to write this music. Um, let me
show you some um some of the um list.
Where where is my list? Okay, so um
so I got lots of list. Wait, where where
is my list?
Can you guys see me? Uh can you guys see
me see my screen? Everything am I doing
well? Like alive? Okay, I'm going to
answer the question in just give me a
minute. Okay. So, but let me show you uh
I wanted to show you um my list of all
the like songs and my ratings for them.
Uh where are they? What the [ __ ]
Okay, hold on a second.
I think I removed the link of my list to
it. What the [ __ ]
Okay, here. Uh no not there. So classic
classical classical keyboard music list.
Yeah. Okay. Here. So you can see so
some years ago I separated into
different composers. So you can see here
is all box pieces I've listened to.
Uh
but actually there are more. Okay. So
there's more than that. Okay. So there's
Bach, there's least uh which is uh the
pianist, one of my favorite least in
fact is my favorite list and Bach. Okay.
So anyway, so so there's Bach, there's
least, there is Shopan
uh and Shopan. And there's Sherbet and
then there's Mosart. I don't like Mosart
at all. I think he's like idiotic
Mozart. Sherman and Beethoven. I don't
like Beethoven neither. So in summary,
my favorite piece of music is Bach.
Okay, let me show you there. There are
several there are a few like two
specific pieces. Okay, so but every but
anyhow my favorite composers are Bach
and Le. Okay, list you know B you know
each one of them got biographies and
stories you know but least is one of the
kind of uh more uh
more dramatic stories about least least
is
uh I I I think I share the mentality of
with least a lot. Okay. List and Bertron
Russell. Bertron Russell is the English
English mathematician and philosopher.
Okay. So anyway, so but I so I wanted to
show you guys mostly today uh my
favorite piano pieces. Okay. Uh there's
there's quite a few. Okay. So of all
music like I ever listened to in my life
of the past, you know, 50 something
years, uh my favorite pieces are piano
music. Okay. Including rock or pop or
singing or whatever opera or concertos
or concert or symphonies or including
pop songs like um you know dance songs.
Actually I I like dance songs a lot. So
here's my music blog that song songs of
human animals. Okay. So, so, so, so far
there's my analysis of about 500 songs,
human animals, songs of human animals.
You look at their lyrics, you can tell
what they are thinking, you know, what
what what is their brain, what you know
what what they doing. You you can kind
of do that. And among which you know
there's piano music which is called uh
or symphony or you know concerto or
instrumental so-called but anyway of all
these music my favorite uh piano music
still so of all the music I have
listened to and there are two like there
they are just like uh let's say four
pieces okay
one is bach so one is um let me just
tell you now bach welltempered clavia
book one fugue number four okay that's
one of them now you can you can listen
to them I have collected some of the the
the better ones the best ones okay um
but but there's a lot to talk about but
like which one is the best why and so on
which rendition you know which pianist
play them is the best anyway but let me
just focus on which are the pieces
that's my favorite um pieces okay So
Bach welltempered clavia book one fugue
number four and fugue number eight. Okay
these two pieces are the my favorite of
all music in the entire world. Okay
these two now
now there there are some others. Okay
now others are
so that's Mark the other two are least
transcendental attitude number 12. Okay,
this piece and the other one is least
transcendental attitude number six. So
these four pieces
generally speaking I would say is my
favorite of of all music ever written.
Okay. I mean this that's it's you know
it's a bit too it's a bit of push to say
that because you you can it's very
difficult to claim you know only these
four pieces is the best you know so
among piano music there's quite a few um
that would also kind of you know depends
on you know but anyway anyway if I have
to pick four you know then then those
are the four okay so let me answer the
question let's Um, how are you? I'm
good. Bukansa, thank you.
Actually, I haven't been feeling good.
I'm physically well. Um, and I'm
healthy. And by the way, I quit smoking.
If you guys haven't heard of that, I
quit smoking about
by now three weeks now. Uh, no, like
there's no cravings. I just quit.
cold turkey. So, I've been smoking for
the past like 20 years. Uh, but I quit I
I I for the past uh let's say since
when? Since um maybe 2010 almost every
day, like every day like five, six
cigarette.
Yeah. Starting about 2010. So I I've
been smoking for like uh
15 years you know so I quit. So that
that's a big uh thing. That's a good
thing. So but in past week I haven't I
didn't feel well and physically well. Uh
financially I'm okay. Uh but I wasn't
feeling well because
because all my life you know I'm I'm a
nerd. Okay. So I just like every day I
have to code you know I write as you
guys may know those you of you watch me
you know I code you know I spend almost
the whole day coding writing about
mathematics or computer programming
computer science or or related topics
such as linguistics philosophy academic
subjects that's what I do okay I'm
obsessed about it but in in the past
week I haven't done any of that and all
of a sudden like You feel like what what
like what do more normal people do? Like
what the [ __ ] does a normal people do if
you don't write about computer and
mathematics? Like what?
[laughter]
That's interesting. [snorts] Okay.
Actually, let me get to uh read the
comment. I don't came from I don't come
from a math background and was reading
about lambdas because I work
because I work in Excel and chanced upon
lambdas in Microsoft's documentation for
my understanding lambda is
like a anonymous formula
okay so let me answer your question so
for my understanding lambda is a like a
anonymous formula where we have syntax
that can neatly encapsulate inputs
expression
uh I'm trying to understand in a
practical scenario when is lambda useful
in mathematics okay versus just
functions okay also I'm not a programmer
in that matter okay and okay so so
then bench says
Lambda calculus is about computable
functions. Not all functions are
computable.
For example, sin x where x is a natural
number is not computable. But
2 to x is computable.
Yeah, that's true. Uh but is is it
technically true that sin x is not
computable? No, sin x is computable. I
think you I think that's a technical
error. But anyway, Buken Sha's answer is
kind of more technical. So I think I can
I can tell you exactly what I can answer
your question. Uh the answers, okay,
because you are not a programmer.
[snorts] Uh
okay. So first of all, the easy answer
is that ignore it. Okay, you are not a
programmer. You don't have to worry
about it at all. Like whatever you hear.
So, so I'm answering the question from
the f okay so you are coding spreadsheet
right and you came upon lambdas and you
are you know from from your
understanding lambda is like is like
anonymous formula but it's but is it
like you know it's it's trying to
encapsulate input uh but is it like a
function how is it different you know
your question is like that. Okay. So my
first
the first practical answer to your
question is just ignore it. This is the
most practical and correct way to
understand it. Okay. When you hear
lambda ignore it. Okay. It's like it's
academic mumbo jumbo. Okay. That's one
thing. Now the second thing when they
say lambda lambda the full name is
lambda calculus. Okay. So what is lambda
calculus? It was created about in the in
the 19 uh
[snorts] 1930s or something. Okay, like
early 1990s, 1900s. It's for answering
the question about mathematical
foundation. Okay. The question is is it
is is it possible to like is it possible
to prove is is it true that every
mathematical statement can be proven
kind of like that. Okay. That's when the
so-called lambda calculus got created.
people were trying to answer some
fundamental questions in in in fun in in
in in the in the um
math foundation. Okay. So this this is
this is kind of question if you really
want to understand it it'll take someone
like 10 years. This is about math
foundation. Okay. That's what lambda
calculus came from. That is what it is
about.
Okay. So it it's answering fun like math
foundational questions like logic like
it's pure logic. It's like mathematical
logic. Okay. So this is a
that's that's what it is for lambda
calculus which is commonly uh associated
with you might have heard of chewing
machine which is another kind of model
for computation. Okay. So, lambda
calculus. Um, so what is it? Well, it's
it's kind of a syntax, you know, you you
you
could read Wikipedia, but uh actually I
would recommend just read uh read this.
Okay.
Uh
Stephan Wuam
lambda calculus. Okay. Read Stefan
Wuam's article on lambda calculus.
Actually, that's not the best one. Um
but well it is it it is far more better
than whatever you would read from
Wikipedia like if you don't know
anything about it you we you read
Wikipedia you'll be totally confused.
Okay so anyway so let me let me get back
to the question. So first of all it's
you know it's a lambda calculus is a
it's something that try to answer some
math foundation questions okay about
like about like is it true that
everything can be proven
in mathematics it it turned out no and
that's a big surprise okay
and uh so how is it how is it different
from a function now so a function Fun. A
function is an idea in mathematics. It
basically just means that some input
comes in one unique output comes out.
This is a concept of a function. Okay.
Now, lambda calculus is a function. Um
well you see you you you know it's it
would be misleading to try to understand
like what's the difference between
lambda calculus and function because
the better way to understand is that
lambda calculus is a syntax okay it's
just a syntax it's a pure it's a formal
language okay
which means it's Uh
oh god [laughter]
it's a formal language. Okay. So okay
they they try to explain YouTube. I'm
not sure you can trust the YouTube
because there's a lot YouTube these
days. Some some some you know a lot of
them you cannot trust it. They are just
like [ __ ]
So anyway let's go to Wikipedia. Okay.
Wikipedia is at least um more sound. It
may be hard hard to understand and
misleading but at least it's
academically more sound. Okay. So lambda
calculus is like a formal language. It's
basically about it's a given syntax
about rules of transformation. Okay.
very strict and because of these rules.
So it allows you to
allows you you to basically do find and
replace of strings transform strings.
Strings you know strings means like text
um and you want to answer questions like
is there some text that via this
transformation that will never occur
something like that. Okay. So it's like
a kind of a practical
uh a practical way of u modeling. Um so
anyway formal language okay formal
language search for lambda
calculus and you can you you go there
uh and lambda calcul okay okay is so
it's it's like a syntax. It's it's a
syntax with a bunch of rules
that if you play this game, it can kind
of you can try to answer the question
like will there be some text that this
rule will never be able to arrive at
that text? Something like that. Okay,
this is like outline you know it's an
easy way to understand what lambda
calculus is. It's just like text
replacement. Okay, text textual
replacement. So you got text like Alice
in Wonderland. So if you follow certain
rules, they have like a bunch of rules
about how you can replace certain text
by other text. So if you are given Alice
in Wonderland if but and but given these
rules, is it possible to have some other
text come up or is it not possible?
That's what lambda calculus is about.
Okay. So it's like this text
replacement. That's kind of easy way to
understand it.
But but each of the lambda you know it
is a function you know you can each each
of the lambda replacement it it is a
function because you know you can think
of it is like you it takes a input
string and output some other string okay
so that's the definition of a function
some input and some output comes out
okay so so that's kind of the over
overall view I don't know if that's
helpful I you know to me I think that's
fantastic answer that answered your
question. Okay is that is true.
Cheers. Now this is red wine.
So lambda calculus very interesting.
Okay. Now so so if you are more
interested in this topic um
I would recommend
Stephan Wuam's uh article. Okay. So I'm
very interested in these topics and
there's actually a lot more for me to
study as well. Uh very deep of course I
mean this is like this this about lambda
calculus and it's ongoing research. It's
about proof theory and uh uh category
theory, proof theory, model theory and
also set theory but set theory is old.
It's about to die. is about to be
replaced by this, you know, and also
logic, you know, the theory of logic,
first order logic. Um, and and and of
course computational theory and theory
of computation
actually they are different things and
computational complexity theory and
theoretical computer science. Okay, so
this lambda calculus is part of this
subject matter. Okay. But I would
recommend you to read Stefan Wuam. Okay.
So, and there is logician Kurt God. Curt
God, one of the top, you know, related
to the lambda calculus. Uh, anyway, so I
I want to recommend you to read uh
Stefan Wuam's article. Okay, he's got a
series of them. Let's search
uh not that. Okay. So I have like um
so I read a lot of Stefan Wuam. Okay. So
um wait
combinators. Okay. Combinate combinators
combinatorial exploration of algebraic
structure. Uh no
um
not okay. So,
[sighs] uh, I I just want to recommend
Stefan Wuam's article. Okay. So, let me
quickly try to find the page because I
have a blog about it.
Okay. Here. Okay. So, so, so here is my
collection. So, just you just you just
search for Stefan Wuam the article
rulology of lambda. So in this article
he's talking about lambda calculus but
he's talking about in a way that he's
trying to um
explore the pure like the pure like
replacement the rules of the lambda
calculus replacement and and what would
happen if you try all possible ways.
Okay that's his perspective. Okay. So
you you can try to read it. You'll
understand a lot better than Wikipedia.
Okay. So Stefan Wuam. Okay. That's one
of the article. But the other one I
think is it's actually more important
than Bambla calculus is is combinators.
Okay. So try to search for it. Stefan
Wolf combinators uh centennial view.
There are three articles about it. Okay.
So read that. So if you are interested
in the you know this lambda calculus I
highly recommend that you just read that
okay this so altogether there are four
articles each one is like each one of
these blog is like uh 100 pages or few
hundred pages okay so it's like a mini
book okay so I just highly recommend
this this these four articles
okay so uh I was going to so so um I
think maybe that's it for today okay So
let's see now this annoying like every
time this Google um you know this Google
live stream chat every time you click
left click it pops up this this this
popup very annoying like normally you
get that with right click. Oh okay so
when you right click you get this you
know browsers um pop up so you yeah very
annoying. Anyway,
drinking Chinese poor uh tea. That's
great. Poor tea. Uh [snorts] poor tea.
That's you know Chinese green tea. uh I
think sin x itself is not computable but
but one can approximate it using
computable functions like polomials okay
in fact no transcendental function is
okay so you might be right you know
that's very that's you know that's the
technical very technical topic so we are
talking about computable functions you
know you know so That's that's deeply
related to lambda calculus. So uh so
what is the computable function uh
you know so
computable function you know we can just
ask AI like we can ask AI is sin x
computable? AI will AI will give you the
I think right answer but
but that's kind of I mean that's useless
if you don't know what computer function
is you know you have to like be reminded
computer function are basic object of
studying computer computability theory
informally a function is computable if
there is an algorithm that computes the
value of the function for every value of
its argument. Okay.
Yeah. Because uh because of lack of the
precise definition of the concept of
algorithm, every formal definition of
computability must refer to a specific
model of computation. Okay. Anyway, I
think I think science X is computable.
you know it's like it's you know you
just like
I think by definition sinx is computable
it's just that you don't have you know
you lack infinite precision but however
it is computable
um but there are some numbers that's not
computable meaning that that
there's no there's like there's no even
algorithms to to approximate
It's something like that because the for
example there is this omega number.
Okay. So um omega number or that gues
you know that guy uh
anyway the very interesting okay so this
is very deep uh I I'm learning it much
of it. Uh
very interesting. episodes but I wanted
to tell you about
you know that
Chiadin I think that guy's name is
Chiadin number okay that's not
computable
uh
provability blah blah blah anyway so a
common function so anyway so this uh
komoga row of complexity chadens
constant Okay, that is not computable
uncomputable functions and unsolvable
problems. Okay. [snorts]
So there
um yeah so there are some examples I
think you know anyway very comp very uh
advanced topic you know like people who
talk about this topic in a solid sound
way those people are basically PhD at
least PhD PhD students okay so this
about this computability and uh chhattan
chat Chattton's constant. Chhatten is
like an interesting guy, very old like
by now he's like very old. Um but Stefan
Wuam has an interview of him you know
like you can you can look um
like you know today is very interesting
because today
lucky you guys you you know you got
YouTube you got like thousands of
interviews. So you can see all these
famous people you know chatting he's on
YouTube okay so like uh chatting okay so
this guy named after Gregory Chhatton
okay
so like before like 10 years ago for
example before YouTube you know before
you know 20 years ago I I heard of this
guy right I heard of this guy oh he
created oh this you know chat and um
stuff you know like
but omega number but you don't know much
you know like it's it's hard to find
information you know you you you
discover it in a book you know in
computer in some computer science book
right but you you cannot but you don't
know like who is this guy but today like
you can go to Wikipedia there's a photo
of the guy you know photo of the guy and
age 78 and you go to YouTube you search
you can find interviews okay but
But one thing disappointing is that when
you you know watch these uh videos they
are like too old. Okay, YouTube is too
late. So when you watch these videos
they are like just an old man. They like
they they talk about oh you know 30
years ago I created that but I don't
remember that much.
Something like that. Funny but yeah. So
um but yeah so there's so many to watch
you know. There's a lot of these
um you know like I haven't seen this you
know but I've seen one interview I think
I I think Stefan Wuam had one like
interview with a guy something. Yeah
there a conversation between Gregory
Shatton and Stefan Wuam. Okay that one I
watched few years back.
Computer functions f. Okay. So uh what
was the problem with set theory
professor? Well set theory
you know the problem so the problem with
set theory is that set theory was
created
to be the foundation of mathematics in
the 1800s you know because calculus is
thriving. Oh, you can do derivatives.
You can do this. But then, but what is
the what the [ __ ] is limits? You know,
like infinitely small a number such that
it is infinitely small. Does it even
exist? What the [ __ ] you talking about?
Like what what can you logically say?
What is a number that is infinitely
small? Like there's a smaller number
than that, but there's actually smaller
that there's no limit. Like what is it?
How can you logically define it? Are you
talking about ghost? You know there's
like one guy in in history of foundation
of mathematics philosophy his name is
Berkeley. He made a joke that that the
derivative you know is the ghost ghost
of departed source you know like today
you can easily find the such quotes you
know b r ke k e l e y derivative uh
calculus okay
departed source. So he made fun you know
he made a famous quote about
the phrase ghosts of departed quantities
is a famous critique of early calculus
coined by bishop George Berkeley in his
1734 work the analysist okay he used it
to mark the logical inconsistencies in
Newton's method of fruxians and Lebanese
infot statistimos. Okay. So you see
calculus in the 1800s 17 in 1700s you
know they are thriving because oh my god
you can find the area of some random you
know leg shaped you know things or
whatever but then like logically what
the [ __ ] is it you know
so that there's a lot so so there be
there came a need for the foundation of
mathematics like you need to logically
say what it is you can't just based on
intu intuition you know there's some
quantity that just infinitely small and
if you add all these infinitely small
things they they came out a number you
know that's what calculus is about you
know limit and you know integrals and
derivative you're talking about
infinitely small things then you add
infinitely number of them you can come
out with a number so
so we needed a foundation like you you
need to logically say what it is. Okay.
So then then came out set theory
basically that is a history of set
theory. Okay.
But set theory basically you know so it
it's it's nice and uh it has its own
history you know we went into problems
you know we got Bertron Russell's uh
paradox about the set of all sets there
exist a set that is the set of all sets
now does this set belong to itself you
know that's a question Bertron Russell's
paradox you can look it up. Okay. So
then people try to fix it by type, you
know, that's when you have type theory.
That's when you start to have type
theory. Okay. So
so and by the way all these are related
to lambda calculus. Okay. So this all
these all these are related. So set set
theory you know went through evolutions
got problems became you know then simabi
tried to uh fix it. Bertrron Russo tried
to fix it. You started to have type
theory which is hierarchy of types. So
in the same level you cannot talk about
set of sets. You need to go to the next
level to talk about the whatever things
in the previous level. So you started to
have hierarchy of types. Okay.
Then then uh okay. So but basically what
happened? So, so the the major problem
with set theory today in the computing
era is that we wanted to you know we
have computers which can compute you
know thousand billions you know times of
computation per microscond you know we
can compute trillions billion mega pab
billions you know computation right and
but when you want to prove do proofs in
mathematics it it turns out very
difficult by set theory because
you you you need to model the set theory
in programming language that turns out
to be extremely difficult. In fact, it's
a major discovery that it turns out to
be a major problem. It's just basically
no go. Okay, basically the guy you know
people found out
that when you want to do mathematics
with computers to prove things okay not
just by brute force computation to to
prove in the sense of mathematicians
proof okay you cannot use the theory
okay so um so um
so I have some um
like I I think I have some notes about
it. Okay, so this there's this this guy
uh homotopy type theory. Okay, that's
that's the origin of homoti type theory.
Okay,
so this guy discovered
this guy. So this guy this guy's the
guy's name is um
Vadmar
Vodski.
He discovered
set theory is just a problem. Set theory
it was great foundation for math but
it's basically not suitable
for computers. You can you can you can't
use state theory to do things. So he
made a major discovery like major major
foundational discovery in mathematics in
2014.
Okay. Say set theory set theory is just
[ __ ] You can't do nothing with it.
Okay. If you want to do like proofs of
mathematics using
you know with computers help then set
theory is just no good. Okay. So this is
a major discovery in 2014. Then you
started to have homotopy type theory.
Okay. And of course this relates to the
discovery of type theory of Bertron
Russell. So it's not just him it's like
several
you know se several um discoveries by by
many mathematicians.
So that is a problem with set theory.
Okay. Basically it's not suitable for uh
if you want to do it in a computational
way. So the computational way relates to
the foundation of mathematics called um
intuitionist
philosophy of mathematics. Okay. So if
you look up philosophy of mathematics
you there are three major classic branch
there are uh the logicism of Bertrron
Russell which means every
which means mathematics is just logic
okay there's nothing other than just
logic just logic like the you know uh
like I think therefore I am something
you know that's uh That's silly. But
logicism and formalism
which we were talking about formal
languages that's from
Hilbert. Then the other one is
intuitionist
which turns out to be very interesting
which turns out to be computational.
Okay. So let me um so by the way do I
make sense? I don't think so because I
because there's too much and I went too
quickly. Okay. So, so philosophy of
mathematics, there are three classical
branches. Okay. One of them, by the way,
you you can't trust Wikipedia these days
because they the social justice war
[ __ ] They they try to like add
lots of [ __ ] into the article. So
anyway, so but but I just want to tell
you the three major branches of
foundation philosophy of mathematics are
um
logicism. Okay, mathematics is basically
just logic. Okay, that's Bertron
Russell's thought. Uh formalism that is
mathematics is meaningless. It's just
symbolic symbol manipulation. Okay, it's
just like lambda calculus. Lambda
calculus is one of them. It's it doesn't
mean anything. It just basically certain
rules about transforming sequence of
text into other sequence of text. You
got bunch of such rules. This is called
formalism.
Okay. And such this this you know text
and rules it's called formal language.
Okay. Mathematics is nothing just but
except just this rules. Okay. Formalism.
This is how like when you do like high
school algebra, you know, x² equals to
two. Okay, you need to remove the square
use square root square root both sides
by by this rule. So you can just apply,
you know, you just transform.
So you remove the square on the left
side, you you add a square root on the
right side. That's what formalism is
about. Okay? This is basically find
replace
text replacement. Okay.
And so logicism, formalism, and the
other one big one is intuitionism. Okay.
This one, this one when I learned it
like 30 years ago, I think it's idiotic,
you know, like what what do you mean
intuition? You mean like like oh there's
a god or something like [laughter]
but it turns out this one is actually
the most important today kind of
intuition isism that basically it just
basically just means computation. Okay
if you not if you cannot write a program
to do it doesn't exist. That's the
essence of this intuitionism.
Okay. It's it's incredible because
because 20 years ago you wouldn't know
this.
Anyway, that's it. I think I think
that's it uh for today.
Um Stefan Wuam. Yes, I have met Stefan
Wuam. So the first time is 1995. The
second time is two years ago.
Uh we we met we meet up in San
Francisco. Okay.
Uh I have tried to find videos of
Richard Sman talking about programming
but they are only one or two. You know
Richard Sman is not like a programmer.
Okay. I mean he he he was he was a great
one of the great programmer you know
like 40 years ago but he quickly stopped
programming he's more about you know
this free software foundation philosophy
thing
social activist that's right philosopher
yeah that's right less of a scientist
that's right he was you know when when
he's a teen he was one of the you know
He he was a very talented programmer
but that but he didn't go you know he
didn't continue doing that.
Okay bye guys. Bye guys. Thank you guys
for watching.
Um so yeah that was great. You know I
enjoy talking about this you know
foundations of mathematics. In fact,
today's questions all tied together
because we were talking about lambda
calculus then
then somehow we started to talk about
set theory. Yeah, you know what what is
the problem? What is the problem with
set theory? You know, you you can you
can so
that's a good question because you can
know that that's a good that's a common
question because if you look at just
search for search for category theory
then you you realize all the like all
the answers why people think there's a
problem with set theory. Okay, I was I
was saying that
set theory got a problem with
computation with computers. That's true.
But but actually the more fundamental
problem with set theory is
is the is the rise of category theory.
Okay? Because category theory
tries to capture the foundation of
mathematics mathematics by
by like more
meaningful like like more more more more
easy to understand like but set theory
is more like sets you know you just okay
you got a set of things uh then you got
other set you know it's like less
intuitive anyway so category theory okay
basically cate category theory
started to replace set theory
And when you wanted to do anything any
form of mathematics with computers like
to do proofs you realized set theory is
just not won't work. That's a great
discovery because I I myself tried to
you know I had I had the experience of a
struggle because I I started you know
I'm so much into math. So 30 years ago I
started to use wufam language you know
which I you know talked you know coded
so much you know but I ran into a
problem like when you when you want to
prove something you know I think you
know 30 years ago I was a young you know
I was a young you know teenager actually
20ome I don't know anything about you
know I don't know much about math
history and you know I don't know much
so but I want you know I I know about
wer language I
code but I can't prove it like like I
run into issues like like what you know
what is a group like can you define a
group prove that this is group how do
you represent a group with computers
it's like I find it you know you you
can't how do you like represent you know
in mathematics you have a definition you
know you have a group a group is a set
and an operation if this is you know an
operation If this operation satisfy this
properties this thing, this set with
this operation is called a group right.
So you want to do you know so I mean two
computers you know wam language you know
but how do you how do you like
prove something is a group but first of
all you you have to like you have to
represent a group in a programming
language. How do you do that? It turns
out you cannot you cannot it's not
possible if you go by the ways of the
set theory because if you go by the ways
of the set theory one of the
definition of a group is that you must
have a identity element like there exist
an element such that a * b a * i and or
a * you know i * a equals to a itself
there exist this element
in this set. Okay. So,
how how how do you represent that in a
programming language? Like there exist
like what [laughter]
what does it mean there exist? How do
you represent something there exist? You
know, there exist an even number. Let's
say
how how do you show that? How do you how
do you write a function or something
that that that shows that there exist an
even number from one to one to 10?
Um
well maybe well for for 1 to 10 you can
do that because you can just go through
every number but anyway so that that's a
that's a major problem of set theory
when you started to try to do proof
theory you know proofs in computers
that's when
that's when the homatopy
type theory came up okay homotopy type
theory okay anyway that's it bye guys
Um,