Hello, good morning. Welcome to another
episode of Ex Talk Show.
We are going to code Wuang language
advent of code 2025 day one problem two
take two. Uh so about two days ago we
did day one problem two but we run into
a bug and this video took me 3 hours 4
hours and we didn't resolve it but today
we going to
so uh let's see uh so let me copy so let
me just update so if you are here say hi
love to see your comments hello said tag
in mot
uh if you are watching this offline play
at 1.5 speed okay 1.5 speed advent of
code programming racket versus sky
scheme list this uh some some comments
we have uh discussions about programming
so uh hold on a second so let me do this
um open this so that this is um
this is talk So day one problem two
episode
721 that was two days ago and today is
723. So copy that show in browser let's
add to the topic box. Okay random code
2005.
So uh
there
showing browser go to the bottom. So you
can see we added today's uh into the
topic box. So refresh or close. Now show
today's talk show. There we have it.
Today's
Okay. So uh let me So let's begin. Okay.
Watch at 1.5 speed or higher and say hi.
And we going to uh start. Uh am I good
to go? Video check. Audio check. So
let's see this window.
Okay, we need to close this one so that
you can see it.
Uh,
okay.
So, talk show. So, so, so let's grab the
code from the other day. So, let me tell
you what is what was the problem. Uh, so
this that one showing browser. In fact,
we can just copy uh
copy that.
Okay. And the start code here
language paste the code show in browser.
So the problem is you have
uh god um you guys know the problem
right? So let's see the problem is that
you have this
rotational dial
and uh so at any point so there's a 0 to
99 numbers around a circle
and uh at any point there's a index
pointing to one number. So usually the
number is at the top you know imagine
this is a uh combination lock rotational
and so the problem is given it's you are
given a bunch of left and right left and
right rotation instructions like that
rotate right 20 means clockwise rotate
left 11 means counterclockwise 11 times
So given this rotational log 0 to 999
and given a starting number and given
this bunch of uh instructions rotate
left and right
you uh then you want to find out
how many times each rotation
uh passes zero either pass zero or end
up at zero. Okay, that was a problem
summary. Now if you haven't done this
you you watch previous episode or just
read the advant of code website. Okay.
Uh so that's a summary. So so the the
gist of the algorithm is a function
which we have written here x operation
given the current number and given the
rotation. So when you rotate left L
something L a number that can be
considered as a minus a negative number
right and uh R is a positive number why
because we are doing uh modular
arithmetics. So can we see u
so let me show you this uh this diagram.
So the the numbers are arranged in a
counterclockwise way. So when you rotate
left
what rotate left means rotate
counterclockwise.
So in effect it decreases the number.
When you rotate right in effect it
increase the number.
Okay. So the heart of the operation is
this function. So this function
here's a documentation uh here's a
documentation operation current number
rotate count returns a list
uh cd uh
rotate n
can
uh can be negative okay returns a list
cdc is the number of times it pass zero
and d is a
is a new index number meaning that after
the rotation what is the number at the
top. Okay. Uh but this function has a
bug which took us four hours
uh the other day and still not resolved.
So we're going to resolve it today. So
everything is good.
Okay. So let's just pay attention. Okay.
So you just uh so what we did is
quotient we call the function quotient
rem remainder. So what this what this uh
what this function do is for example
let's say uh 10 uh let's say
10 / 3 it will return the quotient and
it will return the remainder. So if we
evaluate this you'll return 31.
[sighs and gasps]
So meanwhile let's start. So you can see
here's the result
and I'm using uh wufam mode that allows
me to code wam language in Emacs. So if
you don't know watch my pre previous
video I have introduction on the wam
language on where to download for free
and kasan wu mode. Okay let's start wam
language meanwhile
so far so good so far so good any
questions you have on wam language you
can ask me. Okay. So, three shift enter
to evaluate it. And uh let's increase
the font size. Okay.
So, quotient remainder. So, you can also
run it here. Run it.
Okay. Now if you say four
10 / 4 it will return two and uh two two
because
quotient is two remainder is two 10
divided by five let's do it this again
ctr L to copy the previous input let's
say five shift enter to evaluate to zero
so you see you see so this is the heart
of the algorithm this should tell
Because when you rotate left or right,
how many times it pass past zero
and or
ends up at zero. But there's a bug. So,
so, so it should it should be something
uh more than this. Okay. So, let me
think uh let me think about this.
So we need to So um
so it is this bug that we spent like 3
hours uh and didn't
didn't figure out.
Okay.
Okay. Nobody nobody's here. So let me
just think about this.
So you want to know the number of times
it passed zero whenever you rotate.
Okay. So but first of all if you do this
quotient remainder it will give you a
number
uh and and this can also be negative for
example -3
uh wait
10 -3 becomes -4. Okay. So,
that's
Oh, okay. I think that's the problem. We
will like um
wait
Uh
let's let's think about this 10 -3
why is it returned four why is it -4
okay I think
right so Wait, you got it. So this is
out, right? So yeah. So um
10 / -3.
So that would be 10 divided by a
negative number is equals to 10 divided
by a number. Then the whole thing uh
multiply by a
negative sign.
So
wait, so I don't get this because I
think this should be -3
one. So let's look up the documentation.
Uh we got into another problem,
another issue about edge cases of the
design of the quotient remainder
function.
uh
to to think about this issue is going to
take half an hour. So uh question
remember is also known as a ratio and
quantity left over from diversion n by n
ratio and quantity integer mathematical
function suitable for both
symbolic and numerical manipulation.
Okay gives a list of quotient and
remainder for division. So in wufam
language the because it's symbolic. So
what you can do is actually use uh
symbolic answers
I mean uh
to
anyway never mind.
So here the quotient remainder is all
positive numbers. It's all using
positive numbers uh in this wam language
example.
But in our case,
maybe it's just because we
so this this is troubling. So this part
is troubling. Why is it return -42?
I mean -4
uh
yeah this part is troubling. So
wait
shift enter.
Okay. So if it's negative negative okay
what what if it's um
-10
5 2 0 ne 10 5 2 0 10 -5 -2 0 That's
expected -105
2 0 that's expected now
uh now what about -10 10 five that that
should be -2 0.
Okay, that's all expected.
But now
but now this this this
10 -3
is not expected.
Let's see
is 3 1. That's correct because 3 * 3 is
9. There's one remainder. Okay. Now 10
-3 should give you -3 1.
But it's not.
This is personal to me.
Oh god, we stuck into a we went into
this math issue. Quotient remainder.
Does it talk about negative number?
Let's read carefully. Gives a list of
the quotient and remainder from division
m by n. Okay. So if you have this uh
three so this also works out.
You see uh over here it's 3 * 3 is 9 + 1
is 10. Now over here
3 -3 * -4 is 12 positive positive 12 - 2
is 10. That's also work out. But if you
have -3
if the result is -3
that should also work out. You see if if
the result is -3.
Do you guys see what I'm saying? So if
the result is -3 1
you see -3 * -3 is 9 positive
and 9 + 1 is 10. So this should also be
uh the result. But why is it returning
that instead?
uh you know so we are going
we are digressing into this design of a
mathematical function issue
and uh to dive into this issue could be
one hour or more.
Uh so here are the examples. You know
one thing annoying about Wuang language
documentation is that they have they use
images so you can really enlarge it.
Okay. Anyway,
so plot the sequence scope quotient
remainder works over integers. That's
right. Rational numbers in exact real
numbers. Okay, that also works. Exact
numbers. Okay, you can also use
symbolic numbers such as pi or
exponential um oiler number. You can
also use complex numbers.
It also works. Compute for large
integers. Okay, huge integers also
works. Quotient remainder threads
elements over lists. Okay, so you have a
bunch of list you just apply to the
bunch of list.
Now it didn't mention ne negative basic
applications.
Plot a quotient of a number of division
by five. Plot the remainder of a number
division by five. Plot the quotient of
two integers.
Number theory. Okay.
Uh then you got number theory.
Use flaw to compute a quotient for
integers.
Okay. Demonstrate how division works.
Count the number of positive integers
less than 1,000 divisible by two or
three but not divisible by six. Okay.
Some examples. But you did not mention
negative numbers. What if you have the
input is negative.
Okay.
It did not mention negative numbers.
Okay, I think this is a flaw of the
documentation. Can you guys see what I'm
seeing?
You see the quotient remainder
10 over 3
returns 31
but 10 over 10 and -3 it returns -4 and
-2 but I would expect it to return -3
and one that is the problem
and the documentation did not talk about
What if your arguments are negative?
Yeah, it it's it doesn't say
interesting is interesting because this
Let's just write it out. Okay.
Okay, that's
interesting. Okay, now
now let's just copy that. Okay, let's
create a new.
Okay, today's talk show that's a
question.
Let's double check our logic.
That's very interesting question and the
documentation does not talk about it.
Did we miss anything?
Okay. So let's move on. So okay, keep
that in mind. Now let's move on to our
problem.
Okay. So the problem we want to know the
number of times it passes zero. So,
so you can just take the absolute. So,
let's just make sure when we call
quotient remainder,
we we always make it positive number so
we don't get into that this
unpredictable issue. Okay,
I'm still a bit sick from code.
Check video check. Am I am I going well?
Okay. So,
okay. So,
so now so
you got this rotational. Let me just
think
quotient remainder
current number rotate and
rotate can be negative. Okay. And uh
when you do that,
[snorts]
you see you want it to
you want to make sure this part is
always
positive.
Now in this case is it what what if you
say
you see that also returns -4
you know I expecting 31 but it returns
42 two it's not desired.
So you just want to make sure when you
call this function
what what if you call the quotient um
okay there is a related function which
is just a quotient maybe over there they
will explain n
let's see quotient gives the integer
quotient m and n use an offset quotient
is also known as ratio or fraction okay
integer mathematical function gives the
greatest integer no larger than
oh okay there it is quotient mn gives
the greatest integer no larger than m /
n that is why it returns negative four
instead of three. when you have a
negative input
that's why
so
yeah so wam the quotient remainder is
just to be consistent with this quotient
Now we can look up Wikipedia for
curiosity sake to see how other
programming languages or how traditional
mathematics deal with this issue when
you do a quotient and one of the number
is negative.
Um
because you know when one of the number
is negative you have this issue. You
have to decide
um
so that's like a separate research
problem.
Okay, let's write this down, shall we?
Uh,
I'll be dead.
greatest integer no larger than m / n.
So if it's 10 over 3,
then
that's 3.33
something. Okay. And uh in this case
it's negative
negative 3.33. So it says uh gives the
greatest integer no larger than that.
So you have a choice of
-31
or -4
2.
So you don't want to be larger than
you don't want to be larger than -3.3.
So -3.3
then the larger number is three. The
smaller number is -4.
That is why it returns -4.
I feel like this is our choice. So
because
you know so but anyway that's how it is.
Um
okay let's document it.
Let's just um
copy that.
So,
and you have
10 10
C.
Okay, this is interesting.
The value of m / n is
3.3
33 33 Okay.
uh is negative.
smaller
in
the greatest
integer no larger than mm
is
there
for
negative
four
that's the reason okay that's the reason
this behavior.
So we explained it now showing browser.
So you see our problem is we run into
this quotient remainder when you one of
the number is negative it returns kind
of odd result and test
10 over three you know you can see it
there it returns -4 -2
and the reason why is because it follows
to be consistent with the quotient
function you see the quotient -103 it
returns is -4.
Now, so,
so why does the quotient make that
choice? According to the documentation,
it gives the greatest integer no larger
than m /n. Therefore, when you do
quotient 10 and 3,
the value of m / n is 33.33
negative. So the greatest integer no
larger than that is is -4. So that is
why it returns that result and therefore
that is why quotient remainder returns
um you know -4.
So
so that is the reason okay so that that
is like a short digression about this
thing. So let's
uh let me just clear that up.
Okay. So,
Okay.
Okay. Now we understand that part. Now
let's go to Now let's uh go to work on
our problem.
Okay.
So now when we want to call this we want
to make sure
this part is not negative
current number plus rotate n. So
now rotate n can be very huge can be a
huge number.
So yesterday
I mean the day before I think that is
why part of the reason
our solution is incorrect. It's kind of
tricky because of this. So the
now let's look at the input. Do we have
the input here? No. So topic. So let's
go to input.
Okay. So here is a bunch of numbers we
got.
So if we copy that, make it new one line
per number. So you want to look for huge
numbers. So you can see 528.
So that's like five five times over.
So when you So L so when you minus that
number
current number minus that number you get
the minus you get the minus number.
So you want to uh yeah this so this is
bad. So
let's see. So what are some of the large
numbers?
Okay, you got 750
789.
Okay.
Three digits basically mostly. Okay.
Close it. Close it. Close it.
showing browser.
Yeah. So now
we know what is the problem. Okay. So,
so what we can do is just here
times
one uh 100
times a big number let's say 99.
So it becomes very big number and it
won't be positive. We don't want to we
you know we we want we don't want
negative. Okay. So basically this part
we don't want it to be negative.
So that will will that solve the
problem.
Uh,
let's run it.
Select all. Paste. Just run it.
Oh, wait a minute. You can't
you can't just add a big number there
because
the quotient gets huge.
[laughter]
Oh god.
Because the quotient is a number of
times it rotates. Okay. So you can just
add a big number then.
Okay. Another way to do it is if you add
a if statement.
Oh god, this is
getting very annoying now. Now this is
going to take another long time. Hello
dose
do
in expert or
don't say bellow my expert
expertise. is
okay. We run into issues.
Uh so
so so
such a trivial problem. So what you how
about let's just solve the problem
number plus rotation the rotation can be
negative
so when the rotation is ne okay so you
don't want that so let's copy select all
paste
run it so this is a new function okay
So
separate it. Separate it.
Okay. Uh 0 0 and C
five.
>> [laughter]
>> What are you coding for? Advent of code.
Look at the YouTube title.
Uh,
I want to solve this. Okay. So you want
this number of times it passed zero. So
when it's negative, so you could have a
huge negative number.
Okay. Well, the easiest way is to is if
you actually start to do like coding if
expressions. Okay.
Uh
check the sign that is
so negative
is
minus
positive. Rotate right is positive.
Rotate left is negative.
And uh
rotate left is negative. And
so let's just think about rotating left.
So rotating left.
It's negative number.
So you want so current number rot left.
So,
so what you can do is
So that will give you absolutely
quotient absolute
that will
you know that will avoid running into
this negative input problem. Okay.
So if the current number is one, you
rotate left twice,
then you get you also pass zero.
So
So you want to first
the distance
very annoying.
Okay, the number
the left hand side the the first
argument
is always positive. So this doesn't make
sense.
It's just
You know this this other question is
bugging me about quotient.
So so
that question is bugging me about the
quotient.
So for example that like that.
Okay. Let me ask AI.
Okay, if you ask AI this question, it
will start to explain
that will lead to different programming
language or math convention.
There it is. It start to explain.
So control
magnify
in many programming languages in
mathematics libraries especially
Python's math quotient or similar
function in other languages the quotient
function per performs integer diversion
that rounds towards
negative infinity, right? That's another
way to say it.
Okay. So,
oh, okay. It's simply just like it's
simply just do a floating division and
rounds towards negative infinity.
Kind of sloppy.
You see if math convention
does this that's because it's easy to do
sloppiness.
Is that is that right? Something.
[sighs]
So if we truncate towards zero like in
C, Java, JavaScript or simple in
division in some context we would get
-3.
Right?
So there are two choices.
Okay. So yeah. So you got two choices in
this quotient thing.
Now
Let's ask uh what is the more popular
what
What is the math convention
for
quotient function to return
that to return negative? 3, -3 or -4.
Okay, there is no single universal
mathematical convention for how integer
quotient should behave with negative
numbers. Mathematicians in programming
languages have historically chosen two
main camps.
Yeah, obviously two main camps. But
which one? That is my question.
What real mathematicians usually do in
pure mathematics papers when people
write quotient and remainder for
integers they almost always want the
remainder to be non negative.
Okay the remainder to be ngative that is
classic ukidian division definition
to satisfy that the quotient must be
flawed.
Oh,
so it it um truncates towards the
negative infinity which is wam
mathematica behavior.
[sighs]
Wait, both of these case is uh what
So most number theory textbooks and
essentially all modern abstract algebra
text implicit implicitly use flaw
diversion.
Okay. So their result is -4.
Why do they want that? Because they want
the remainder to be the negative.
Now
that still does not explain. And you can
also return -3 1 where the rem remainder
is the negative because -3 * -3 is 9 9 +
1 is 10. So -3 and 1 is also I mean -3
is also a um
solution.
So quotient should return three not ne I
mean negative -3 not -4.
What?
However, in elementary school arithmetic
in many countries and in some older
programming languages, teachers and
students are taught to ignore the signs,
divide and put the sign back which
effectively give trun truncation towards
zero.
This is actually more intuitive.
That's what it should be. Okay. So which
is the mathematical convention uh
number theory of strct algebra -4
ISO standard for programming languages
since 2010 -4
Python Julia Ruby modern C++4
C Java JavaScript PHP -3 Three.
[laughter]
My primary school curricula many primary
school curricula negative3.
Okay. So I think -3 should be the better
answer. Okay. What the Uh but but
wuam language returng -4. So so here's a
question. Now cut it. Now let's put it
back. Okay. Let's put back the um uh
investigation into this question because
this is actually quite interesting.
Okay. So,
copy that.
We didn't solve the problem but we into
this digression
uh this what quotient
of a negative input should return.
Okay. And it mentioned JavaScript. So I
wanted to check out
to test JavaScript. So, JavaScript uh
JavaScript JavaScript object reference
uh and math.
So, what is the quotient function?
Uh math math math. We have uh max mean
random sign absolute ceiling floor round
if round trunk power square
cube square root
uh
is there actually a quotient function
I don't remember.
So what is what are you talking about?
So you are saying that
OC Java JavaScript PHP truncation
towards zero.
So you are saying that
uh but I'm not I'm not seeing a quotient
function.
What?
I don't think there's a quotion function
in JavaScript. Okay, let me double
check. Math operators
uh mod. Well, you can do mod which is
similar.
Okay, so
Okay. So now 10 uh
wait
10 over three
console log. What you get?
Three.
What?
One.
What
did
we run into? Another problem.
What?
Why is it returning one? Are we running
into another problem?
Oh, remainder. That's right. It doesn't
um
That's right. It gives you the
remainder, but we want the quotient.
But as far as I know
how to get integer
quotient in JavaScript
as far as I know there is no such
function.
So that's right. So either you you know
you have to manually do floor or ceiling
or truncation truncation.
Okay. So in JavaScript there is no
quotient function.
That means this
gu AI result claiming about JavaScript
is incorrect.
Okay. I verified.
So now let's put it back.
The Gork AI
saying that JavaScript truncates towards
JavaScript quotient
function truncates toward zero is
incorrect
because
in JavaScript
there is no
quotient function.
No integer quotient function. Okay.
So this is you know careful deep dive on
AI answers that is incorrect. Now it got
JavaScript wrong and you might you know
it may may actually not
get C or Java result correctly. So,
so what about Python?
Okay. So, Python's got math quotient.
Okay. So,
okay. So, let's do Python. Let's just
double check. Uh so math I suppose you
have to import math then the math
quotient
10 uh
three then you have to print it.
Uh math is not has no attribute
quotient.
What is the Python? Uh
Q o t i n t.
What?
How to do integer
quotients in Python?
I don't remember.
So
let's look up.
or
let's go to my Python tutorial.
Number number separator, floating
number, binary, hexodimal, complex
number, exponential, number operators,
uh number operators, addition,
subtraction, multiplication, power,
divide, integer, quotient. There it is.
slash slash
This gu AI is wrong again.
A stupid gu AI. Guac AI. Okay. So in
Python there's no uh this just slash
slash. Okay.
Uh slash slash. Okay. that will return
three.
Okay, that's correct.
Uh
now if you say -10,
it will return -4
there it is
not satisfactory
choice of result. Okay.
So um
so we got that. So okay so that is uh so
now we need to show a example of a
programming language where it actually
returns -3.
You see there is none.
Okay, we digress long enough.
Double pin spinning action. That's
right.
So, back to our question
about solving this issue. So,
so do we need to still need to solve it?
Yes.
Uh,
okay. That's Python.
Okay, now let's back to coding this
issue.
So the quotient function if the input is
negative then then you got a issue.
Python or you see they got the
interesting did did they have a new
color of their logo
that looks like a new color of their
logo?
Was it python.com or python.org?
Okay,
let's see. You know it.
So what are we doing? So that's
JavaScript. Uh so we want to
we want to get the uh
this thing.
So the easiest way
is
you just do if statement. Okay.
So to the easiest way to
to write this function is you just like
manually code hard code.
Then you figure out some trick to make
it fit into this one single function.
But
but to start from beginning you you just
manually code it.
If so you can you can what you can do is
um
[sighs]
so first of all you got this number.
Okay, let's write
block is a um
local variable. Okay. So we say
okay
So first we'll get the overall pass
absolute. Okay.
Then
then then you do if
if
um rotate is greater than
zero
less than zero.
If it's less than zero then um
wait if if um
Python best land.
I don't I don't think so.
Python is the worst land.
Um, [clears throat]
yeah. Got a very annoying
problem.
rotate
left and rotate right.
If this
almost works
such simple almost works.
So why is why so code is so great it
actually works.
It only doesn't work when the current
number is zero.
Right? The only reason it doesn't work
is the current number zero.
So
because
yeah tree does um
one.
Okay.
So it's negative rotate left.
And is less than is negative.
I'm very um
not concentrated and uh
and I gotta go.
This is so bad.
Day one, part two. Six hours on it and
not done yet. But I think I gotta go.
Oh god.
So, what are we doing?
Yep.
So
you know you you just need to cons
concentrate thinking about this
uh
or just do trial and error. So last time
we found the exact bug. So it's like
some first one or minus one will work
but
trying to model this correctly logically
needs some more concentrated thinking
and uh I'm not up to it. So maybe I
should stop stop today.
But we did find
a interesting
thing about the quotient when the input
is negative.
Okay, I think that I think that'll be it
today. Okay, I gotta go.
I gotta go and then we'll do it. Um
maybe I'll just code it offline because
offline that's the best.
Um then we got a day two and other
things to go. Actually recently I've
been looking into Julia the programming
language Julia and F
um
and also G scheme and Racket scheme and
Hascal. It turns out F
is more popular than Haskell and G
scheme and Racket scheme combined.
F is more popular than them all.
And it turns out Julia the programming
language functional programming language
is more popular than F.
So that's a very interesting uh finding.
So that made me want to also learn Julia
because right now I'm on track to learn
F.
So I've been wanting to do
you know with AI help I can do problem
one
uh with F or maybe Julia too. So you
know there's a lot coding. So anyway so
today you know let's stop here. So
because I'm not going anywhere.
Uh okay. Thank you guys for watching.
Bye guys.
End stream.
Okay. It is very embarrassing. You know,
they